There's really just one last thing we have to take care of.
Let me give you a quick demonstration of a bug that our current implementation has.
If I go back over to test out J.S. I'm going to wrap this council log inside of a set interval statement
and then as the second argument I'll put in 1000.
So this is going to make us console log out by there once every second.
Let's now save this.
I'll go back over to the terminal I'll do watch it test.
Dot J.S. and there we go.
We get once a second by their so now I'm gonna go back over to test out G.S. and I'll change it.
Hi there.
Save it.
Go back over and there's the issue.
Whenever we make a change we do in fact start up the new copy of our program.
But we do not terminate the old one terminating the old one is definitely key because otherwise we're
going to end up with possibly 50 or 100 copies of the same program running after some number of changes
are made to a program so to do so we're gonna go back over to our next dot j ust file.
I'll go down to the start function that we were just working on and we're gonna take a look at that
spawn function.
Now if you watch the last video that was a hundred percent optional I said very briefly towards the
end that when we call spawn it returns an object called a child process.
Let's go take a look at the at no documentation.
Once again and get a better idea of what that object is exactly.
So I'm back at the no documentation at the child processes section I'm going to find the spawn function
and click on it and then scroll down a little bit to where it says returns so when we called spawn we
get back a child process object.
We then click on that.
We can take a look at the different functions that this child process object has.
Then scroll down a little bit and inside of here we're going to see a function called Sub process dot
kill.
So as you would guess if we call the thing it's going to kill the existing process and just terminate
it entirely go back inside of our code when we call spawn right here.
Well we really have to do is save a reference to the process or the child process object that gets returned
and then the next time we call start.
We'll just make sure that we call kill on the previous process.
That's pretty much it.
So to do so right above start are going to first declare a variable called proc short for process.
We're not going to call it process because remember in node process is a global variable.
So I'm going to call it proc instead then whenever we call spawn I'm going to assign the child process
object to that variable and then right above it before we call spawn we'll check to see if proc is already
defined.
If it is we'll call it proc dot kill.
So now when we first start up the very first time we start our application proc will be undefined so
we'll not try to kill the process well then start up our process assigned to that variable and then
the next time we call start we'll check to see if there is a process if there is we'll kill it all right.
So let's say this file.
I to go back over I'm going to stop are still running process here with a control C and then do you
watch it.
Past J.S. again so once again I see.
Hi there.
If I go back over change test not j ust to say by their now the HI THERE IS DONE AND I ONLY SEE BY THEIR
instead loving the last little change would be kind of nice to have here is to have just a console log
from our program anytime that we kill the existing process and replace it with the new one so that would
just be assigned to you and I or the user of our program that hey we are now have a new version of this
program running so that we could just do a very simple console log inside of our index dot J as file
and say something inside of here like right before we call spawn of the console dot log arrow arrow
arrow change detect how about starting process just keep it simple.
Starting process they'll save that go back over let's try it again I'll do watch it test out J.S. and
I see starting process if I go make another change to test out J.S. and save it I see that same message
and then Hi there.
Hi there.
Hi there let's say that definitely looks good.
The only way that we could improve this at this point maybe would be to add in some coloring to that
text just to kind of differentiate it from the normal console logs that our program is issuing.
So you might recall that we added in some color console logs earlier on a previous application so we're
going to do the same thing here.
Remember back on NPM J dot com.
We can look up the shock package the shock package we used to really easily add in some coloring to
console logs that end up inside of the terminal.
So let's install it chalk once again and we can call chalk dot say blue or some other color just to
make sure that the hey we are restarting your process message stands out so once again I'm going to
stop our process to an npm install.
Chuck
looks good.
I'll go back over to index dot J.S. at the top.
I will require in
and then down at that console log that we had just added on right here.
We will wrap that with Chuck dot.
You can do bold or you can do a color remember it's totally up to you.
Last time I did bolt because I said I don't know what color background terminal you have.
And so I didn't want to pick white and then have like white text on a white background.
This time I'm just gonna go ahead and use blue.
I'm going to assume that you can figure out hey if the text doesn't show up you've got to change the
color yourself.
It's all say this once again last time I'm going to run watch it test dot James and I see that in that
nice dark blue I can go change test out just once again and there we go.
All right.
Well I would say this looks pretty darn good.
That's pretty much it for this application.
Again the really high points here were to just make some use of some other NPM modules beyond the one
chalk one that we had to use previously and just get a better idea of how to install them and make use
of some of these very different modules inside reprogram.
So I think we did a pretty good job of that overall.
So let's take a pause right here and start on our next application in just a moment.