All right we've got our link put together right here.
Now we need to put together a rep handler to receive a request coming to this your l going to go back
to my editor.
I'm gonna go to my roots admin products dot J.S. file you're just right here and then down the bottom
the file I get put together a router dot get.
So that's what's happening right now.
Whenever a user clicks on that link remember that is making a get request.
So we're going to watch for request to admin products.
And now right here we need to reflect that we want to receive the I.D. of the product being visited.
Obviously we don't want to put together every combination of product I.D. possible because we are randomly
generating that I.D. and we don't really know ahead of time what the possible range of product ideas
are.
So we do want to put in something like that and just hope that we lucked out into typing in the correct
I.D..
So instead we're going to essentially put in a wild card.
Second right write right there.
Colon I.D. and then slash edit This means that whenever a request comes in to admin products slash anything
any characters whatsoever slash edit it's going to match up to this root handler we're then going to
receive whatever string of characters are right there as a variable on our request object.
So inside of our root handler we can reference our request object and see exactly what I.D. was provided
when it user came to this root handler.
It's now put on my rec Andrés and inside of here right now I'll just do a console log of rec dot prams
dot I.D..
So this is what is going to capture or give us whatever value is right there inside the euro let's save
this.
I'm gonna go back over to my product listing.
Going to click on any of these edit buttons as soon as I do I'm just gonna see a spinner because right
now our server is not doing anything that with that request.
But if we go back over to our terminal we'll see a console log of that product's I.D..
So it's clear that we captured that part of the url and it is available to us again on the erect prams
object we can go back and try clicking on a different link.
Now we'll see a very different console log and once again for this third product and I'll see the idea
of that product appear okay.
So we are definitely now capturing the appropriate I.D. and so we know exactly what products we are
trying to show this edit form for it's now the next thing we're going to do inside of here.
Once we know the idea of the product we want to show the form for we need to retrieve that product out
of our products repository is again we want to show some different attributes of the product we're trying
to edit inside of our form.
In other words we want to get the title we want to get the price and stuff them as the default values
into our edit form itself so to get access to the product we're going to use our products repo which
we have already required up here at the top.
Remember that our repository if we go to repositories dot repository or repository dot J.S. one of the
different methods we have inside of here is get one.
Now if we call get one with an I.D. that's going to give us back the I.D. or something just the record
that corresponds to that I.D. it's back inside of products such as.
Here's the get handler I'm going to mark the enclosing function as async because we need to run some
asynchronous code and then inside of you I will say Conte's product is a awaits products repo.
Get one and we'll throw in the idea of the product that we're trying to find which is wreck dot prams
dot I.D..
So now remember that a user might come to this root handler with some invalid I.D. right there.
So in other words a user might manually try to type in some I.D. So like admin slash product slash whatever
slash edits and they might try to visit this link.
And so that idea right there might not actually correspond to a real product maybe a user wrote down
the URL of some product they want to edit and they are typing it back in and they accidentally make
a typo.
Or another good case is a user might bookmark a page to edit a product and then tried to visit that
link at some point in the future after we have deleted it.
So it is entirely possible that we might not find a product corresponding to that I.D..
So we first need to check and make sure that we did actually find a product.
So I'll say if there is no product if we did not just find one let's return early and we'll do a resort
send product not found then only after that down here do we feel safe to say OK we found a product and
we need to render a template with it.
So we don't have a template for our form just yet.
So we'll throw in some boilerplate code right here of what we probably know the template function is
going to look like.
Well then take a pause and start to implement the template in just a moment.
Down here we'll do something like resort scent and then just like we did before we'll call some function
like products new template or something like that local products edit template and as usual I'm going
to pass on an object that contains the product we care about and as usual identical keys and values
so we can get dense it down to just product like so so then at the top let's try to require in this
template.
Again it doesn't exist yet.
We're going to work on it in just a moment.
Well it's just add in the require statement.
So the next video we can just start working on the template directly at the very top right after the
two require statements for templates where we have all due products edit template and require that from
up one directory up another use admin products at okay.
Now if we save this as is we're going to see an error message specifically over at our terminal because
again we have not yet to find that template.
Let's take a pause here.
We'll come back in just a moment and we'll start working on that template file to make sure that we
can edit a template or headed a product.