All right.
So let's refactor this relatively ugly code and even if we're not making it easier to look at and understand
let's make it more reusable so I can make two different tables or two different wells for each team
with a different perspective or I could make this work with any data.
It doesn't have to be hardcoded for warriors and I don't want to have to just duplicate this code to
make another table or another.
Well with a bunch of allies that we're calling a table.
So the first thing I would do is just wrap it in a function.
Let's define a function.
I would probably call it like.
Make chart like that.
And then pass in the data.
So I'm going to define my function.
I'll go with const make chart equals a function that accepts game data or games and then that will be
an arrow function doesn't have to be.
But that's fine and I'll start by just putting all of this code inside the function and the way I'll
write my function is I won't have it actually append the chart it will make the chart but then I can
dependent wherever I want by calling it.
It will return the well let's get rid of this extra counseled dot log.
So we're making this.
Well parents at the end will return you as a parent and that will contain all of the allies all of the
data.
And then I can simply append it or prepared at the end.
So I'll make my variable I'll call this chart 1 equals make chart and then document our body dot and
prepare and chart 1.
So I'm just moving it into a function.
Now I could call this twice if I wanted to.
Assuming we don't have any errors it looks like we do.
Data is not defined.
I need to pass in the actual name of this.
It's not called data.
It's called Warriors games
and then I do need to update my loop here.
The parameter is called games.
So for a game of games I don't want to hardcoded to be this particular data structure.
We want it to be whatever is passed in and there we go.
So now I could just make another table easily just duplicate this code.
It will be identical but I now am able to do it twice.
There we go.
All right.
So we've made our function slightly reusable but now I want to break it up a little bit.
This is still kind of it's kind of a lot to do in here.
So what I would probably break it into is a function to determine the interior the inner text.
This stuff right here and I'll call that.
Get him get content or get get text get score line maybe equals function we'll figure out what it accepts
in just a moment.
And I want to call it like this if I have my ally that I'm making right here I want to call game ally
dot inner HCM l equals get score line and then I'll just pass in the entire game so I'll move this content
that is getting the D structuring home team in a way team variables this line that is making the team
names the away team at home team I'll get the score line the point stuff all of this right here.
Cut it out and move it over here and we're passing in the entire game where are you.
Right here and I'm going to d structure from that I'll get the home team and the away team which is
what I did right here but I'll just pass the entire game and d structure it here inside of the parameter
definition okay.
Now we need to make sure we return something and what I want to return is this line right here we'll
walk through it in a moment
okay so we've made this function called Get scoreline.
We pass in the entire game.
It will extract or unpack.
Home team and away team.
And then further unpack each team a team H points eight points.
It creates the team names string.
It creates the score line string and it returns both of them combined into team names score line into
one string and that one string is returned from here and I'm setting game allied at Inter H GMO game.
Ally represents each ally.
Each one of these.
So I just wrote a function to generate this for me.
And almost always whenever we move stuff around and refactor into new functions I'm sure we'll encounter
something.
Yep.
What is it now.
Each team is not defined and the line that is causing me trouble right now is right here.
Warriors equals.
Each team will each team is gone.
I moved it into this function so what I would probably do is to start just come at this logic out let's
make sure our last version worked OK so we are getting the correct text on the inside of each ally.
Now I'll probably make a function called Get winner or winning team or something like that.
The way that I want this to work I should be able to pass in the team that I'm making the table for.
So Golden State but I should also be able to do it for Houston instead but I'll start with Golden State
so I will accept a parameter called Target team and then I want to check if for each game the winning
team was a target team.
So if it was Golden State.
So this stuff that I have here I'm probably going to move into a new function and I'll call that function
and see how would I want to call it maybe is winter and then I could pass in game and Target team.
OK so that doesn't exist.
We'll define it.
Concept is winner equals game target.
Team
Arrow function or just a regular function and we'll check in that game.
We will do the same thing we have here.
So I'll just move this single line for now down here.
We'll replace Golden State with Target team and I think I'll D structure the same way right here on
game so we get home team and away team we're unpacking those values so we're passing one game in and
we're passing in the string.
Golden State for example and all I want to do is find where Golden State is if it's a or home and check
if they are winner if is winner is true.
So I have home team away team and Target team.
I'll just check if Home Team dots team equals Target team.
If that's the case let's make this a variable just called Team targets and I'm going to return target
dot is winner so this line is just to find the correct team home team or away team.
So I could have done away team doubt team equals Target team and then just set that to away team.
Either way it works.
I'm just trying to identify target which object actually has warriors as the team and then I'll return
that object's winner or is winner property.
And then here where I called it is winner I can use that now to decide the class and I could put it
right here.
Just do it in one line.
We'll see how ugly it is or isn't
so we'll call is winner for this one game with the Target team.
Let's say it's Golden State if that returns true will add win if it returns false will add loss is it
going to work.
We probably have some other bug.
Now it seems like it worked.
So let's try switching it around this time instead of looking for Golden State.
Let's look for Houston
Hey it's working so we can see.
Houston lost the first one they won the second one and so on.
So we've now made this actually reusable and we can have a different target team each time.
So that's kind of all I want to do here.
We've got our function make chart.
It has two other functions get scoreline is winner it doesn't have them but it relies on them.
And we can call make chart multiple times.
It does not append anything itself.
It returns the chart element that we then append on our own.
I could probably refactor this here.
I'm okay with it but we we could take advantage of is winner and just reuse that function.
There are more ways we could refactor this but it's already been a significant chunk of time here.
So we're not going to go too crazy on this.
We have lots of projects coming up and you'll talk a lot about refactoring that.
So I think this is good enough.
The one thing I would do as we're displaying this is maybe add a title or two so we can see what's going
on.
Maybe in our index I'll just add two sections.
So the first one we'll have an H2 that says warriors.
How about Golden State Warriors
and this section will have an idea maybe of G.S.
and then we'll have a second section with another H to this one will be Houston Rockets.
And the idea will be I guess I'll just do Houston Rockets G.S. and H.R..
Now I'll append my charts into here and I'll have a heading for them which will make it a little bit
nicer to see what's what.
So over here I now can select those two elements.
So I'll call this contest warriors section maybe G S section equals document dot query selector or document
I get element by D.
Use the hash sign for G S to get the idea of Jesus and then I'll do Houston section equals document
that query selector.
I don't want all I just want query selector of H R so I have those two sections.
Now I can make my two charts so we'll go with Golden State charts and Houston Rocket chart and I'll
change the Target team to be Houston and then instead of document dump body dot pre prepared I'll do
G.S. section dot append child this chart the G S chart that we made with the perspective of Golden State
Warriors and then we'll do the Houston section.
Dot Penn child and we'll add in the chart chart and let's see if that works.
So we make two charts one from each perspective one looking at it from Golden State's point of view.
We append that to the Golden State section that I added.
Then we do the same thing for the Houston Rockets.
That perspective we passed in Houston and we use that and append that chart that we get back to our
Houston section and I added some H 2s so that we have some Tex to look at and we know which chart is
which.
And we're good to go.
So that's it.
So a lot of work but we are dynamically creating these charts here.
There are not tables it's just allies but we've got a couple of elements we're creating we've got bold
tags we've got allies we're adding classes we're changing the inter HMO
we're using a ton of the stuff we've seen so far.