In the last video I mentioned the chai assertion library.
So that is how we're going to make sure that this dropdown doesn't have that is active class name.
Let's go take a look at the documentation for chai really quickly inside of a new browser tab.
I'm going to do a search for chai J.S. we'll find that Chai GSK dot com I'm going to be honest with
you.
This library right here I can just about guarantee you that you're not going to like it too much so
just a little bit ago we saw that in node there is that a search library and I had just that or that
module and had those like ten or twelve functions inside of it that allowed us to very easily try to
prove something in a given test the chai library does the same thing.
But the reason that it's a little bit complicated is that it gives you three different ways of doing
the exact same thing.
So right here inside the official documentation you're going to see a style of writing out some assertions
using the should syntax the expected syntax and the Assert syntax is all do the exact same thing every
single one of them is a matter of fact each line of code you see inside of here going from left to right
is 100 percent equal they're all doing the exact same check.
The only reason they offer these three different styles is just for developer preference and so hey
I assume you've got a preference right.
I mean I don't really but perhaps you do or I should say maybe other developers do.
So we have to essentially pick one of these three different styles of syntax and use it to actually
write some assertions inside of our code.
Now I want to repeat here we don't technically have to use Chai to write these assertions we could do
those if statements but they just end up being so ugly so instead we're going to try out this expect
syntax.
So we're going to use this expect function to check some different values of whatever we're working
with and if it's not quite what we expect the expected function is going to throw an error and that's
gonna show up as a failure on our test it's gonna click on visit expect a guide right here that's going
to take us to a quick guide on how to make use of the syntax here's the general idea we're going to
first get access to the expected function we're then going to call expect and then pass in some value
that we want to test we then chain on some series of little words like that so to dot be a sweet to
not be dot a and then something to compare it against what makes expect really confusing is these little
two dot blah blah blah things inside of here because it's essentially a sigh are kind of an art and
a science to memorize all the different combinations and figure out how to actually effectively use
them of course you can take a look at API appear at the top right hand side and then click on expect
slash should and this will show you all the different ways you can chain these things together.
There are a lot of examples inside here to help you understand how to use them but as you start to look
at this item about you yes if you're feeling like this is overwhelming hundred percent yes totally without
a doubt this really is kind of overboard and it's really hard to get into when you first start doing
testing that's why take a look at that assert node module was really great from the get go because it's
pretty clear of oh yeah there's this function we use it there's only like twelve functions that's all
we really need to know.
So Chai if you're feeling a little bit overwhelmed this totally fine OK so we're now going to make use
of Chai to actually verify that the dropdown does not have that is active class to use Chai.
We first have to go back over to our test each email file over here right inside of this script tag
with a class of Moka dash in it after the mocha dot check leaks.
We're going to add in a concert expect equals Chai not expect.
So that's how we're going to get at easy access to that function.
We don't technically have to write this line of code.
It just saves us from having to write Chai dot expect everywhere inside of our test file it's going
to save the Test each documents.
I'll go back over to the autocomplete test and then inside of here in order to make sure that the class
name doesn't contain is active we'll do expect dropdown dot class name not not to include is Dash active
they might be kind of curious what is with all these little dot things.
So we have to throw inside of your will in theory it's all about making your life as developer easier
by adding in not to include Chai is going to do a very specific series of checks.
It's going to make sure that class name is something that can include value.
So in other words it's a string or an array or something similar.
It's then going to automatically pass that thing and see if it includes the string is Dash active and
then because we added on it dot not right there.
That's going to make sure that is active is technically not contained inside of class name.
So again the theory here is that this makes your life easier but it really doesn't get easier until
you start to memorize those things.
All right.
Let's save this.
We're gonna go back over to our test suite and see how we're doing.
So can come back over here.
I will refresh and now I can see shows and autocomplete is passing let's try to get that test to fail
because remember as usual it's usually good practice to see the test fail at least once to make sure
that's actually working and doing what you expect.
So I going to find the expected statement right here and I'm going to remove the nuts.
So now I have class name closing print dot to dot include.
Now we are trying to make sure that the dropdown starts off open.
This test should fail.
So if I say this go back over there we go.
Now it's failed.
That means that the test is working as we expect to come back over at on the dot not save it.
And that's it.
We should be good to go OK.
So I know that this expected stuff right here.
Yes it's kind of nasty and I don't really expect you to look at this and be like Oh yeah I until I understand
what's going on.
Unfortunately it's something where you just have to work through his documentation over time and get
a better idea of the different matches that are available.
One other thing I want to mention is that if you're watching this video and saying to me like Steven
why are we using Chai at all.
This library is bad.
And there's some new library that's better.
Remember at the end of the day all this stuff is exact.
It's just all the same.
There are other testing libraries out there that we could use besides Chai that might be slightly easier
to understand.
But at the end of the day it's doing the exact same stuff.
So if you learn one you learn them all might as well start with Chai because it's extremely popular
very well used in industry.
All right.
So that's my little motivation speech.
Let's take a quick pause right here when we come back the next video we're gonna start to write out
a couple more tests around our autocomplete.