We've seen that we can fill arrays with all sorts of values.
We can put Nolan there could do undefined.
You could put out a number can put a string regular number you can put whatever we want.
Well not whatever we want but out of the valid values in JavaScript we can use them all instead of an
array.
We can also nest arrays inside of arrays.
So here's a couple of examples of how you might do that and what it looks like.
It's as simple as Array brackets.
And then each element could be an array.
In this case I have pairs of colors.
So we have red and then crimson purple orchid blue navy blue.
So the first color in each array is maybe the lighter version and the second version or the second color
is darker.
Doesn't really matter in this context.
Once we learn objects you'll see that most of the time we end up combining arrays and objects for more
complex data and that objects would probably help us organize this data a bit better because what's
hard about this is looking at it you don't really understand what is the significance of the first color
versus the second.
Is there an order.
Well there's the default array order but is there a reason that red comes first or green and comes before
all of.
But if we put that aside the main point here is that we can store arrays instead of arrays.
We could do something like animal pairs.
Be an array and each element will be a sub array and nested array inside and we could just have empty
arrays instead of an array.
There's nothing wrong with that but I'm going to fill it with strings.
So we'll have female and male versions of animals.
So we have dough for deer and then a male version of buck or a stag.
It's never clear on that.
And then we just add a comma afterwards and we can put another element like twenty two if we wanted
to and then true and then another array.
It's just treated like any other element.
But I'll do a couple nested Arrays I'll fast forward through this.
There we go.
So we have three arrays nested inside of one array and let's try to access some data out of animal pairs
so I'll clear the console refresh the page and I have animal pairs.
If we inspect it in the dev tools you can expand each nested array.
But let's start by trying to figure out the female version of Peacock So how do we get p hen out of
this animal pairs array.
It is in the third element of animal pairs so 0 1 2 index of 2 animal pairs of two.
And that gives us this entire array and then to access the first element we use INDEX OF 0.
And we just chain them together like this animal pairs to zero.
That gives us P hen animal pairs to one gives us Peacock animal pairs of let's go with one one.
Sure gives us ram it gives us the first portion animal pairs of one gives us this whole array and then
we're accessing index of one in that child array or in that nested array which gives us RAM and we can
update elements as well.
Let's say I was wrong about Buck and Hatch actually stag which I'm not sure about but if it was actually
stag we could update it.
It is the zero with element this array is the zero with element in the main animal pairs array and then
we want to change index of one and set that equal to stag.
Now we look at animal pairs and you can see that change was made.
Okay.
So this is still not a really good example.
And the reason for that is that it just doesn't really make sense why would you store these pairs in
an order in an array.
Why is Doe and book First In P hen and Peacock is third.
Why is there an order an array is usually the best choice when there is an explicit or an important
order that needs to be preserved not just random pairs of data but it does technically work but here
is a much better and much more common example of nested Arrays.
Here we have a tic tac toe board but you could use nested arrays to model any sort of board a chessboard
checkers board a grid in candy crush any grid we could use to nested or not just two nested arrays but
two levels of nested arrays.
So here we have tic tac toe and this graphic on the right is represented by the array on the left.
So we have the first row which is one array 0 no and X or Oh no index.
I use Noel to represent no move being played an empty square and then the next row is no X and 0 and
then x 0 and no.
So multi-dimensional arrays which is the fancy term for what we're doing here where we have arrays instead
of arrays.
They're really common when you're working with boards.
You can continue.
You could have a three dimensional array.
This is a two dimensional array.
You could have a three dimensional array if you were modelling a Rubik's cube for example.
You can continue to invest further and further I won't spend too much time on this example because it
works exactly the same as what we saw here.
We're just using different data.
So for a three by three board we would have three arrays each element or each array has three elements
itself for a 10 by 10.
We would have 10 arrays nested instead of the board and they would all be 10 elements long.
So that's pretty much it for nested arrays.
The main point here is that we can put arrays instead of other arrays.
We could continue and have a bunch of arrays.
For example if I was confused about Buck I could put Buck and stag here and now we have three levels
of arrays and we would access Stagg via animal pairs.
0 that gives us the first array.
This entire thing and then I want this element.
So index of 1 0 1.
So I chain that on and then I want the last element which is index of 1 again chain that on one more
time.
Yep that's it.
We just continue to add square brackets over and over to access or to update information.
I'll change it to stag in all caps and I think that's a good place to stop with nested arrays.