All right.
Like I said at the end of last video several times we're not gonna start to put together our products
edit templates before we do so however I just wanna mention really quickly that for our GET request
right here for the form let's make sure that we add in a require off middleware so that a user can only
access this edit form if they are signed in.
OK.
So now instead of our views admin products directory we'll create a new file called edit dot J.S. the
form we put together inside of here is gonna be very similar to all the other forms we've put together.
So let's get through it rather quickly.
At the top we will get our layout
will then do our module dot experts and we know that this thing is going to be called with an object
that has some product inside of it that we want to edit.
So we want to take some information out of that object and show it inside of a form as the default values
for some inputs so I'm then going to return our layout and remember to show allow layout we show layout
with an object that has a content property
well then put in our multi line string that will contain our actual HD email so we'll show a form with
a method of post
or then show in input with the name of title.
And again we want to kind of preload or pre populate these different inputs so to do so we can assign
the value property and we'll assign value whatever the current product's title is.
It's all say product title once again make sure that you've got some double quotes around the product
title because when we put product title in there by default there will be no double quotes added in
and usually whenever we add in H.M. attributes and they're supposed to be a string they do have to be
wrapped with double quotes.
Now it can duplicate that for the price as well so product dot price also show a button on here to submit
the form
let's go back over.
I'm going to click on any of these different edit buttons and I should see the title other product and
the price default values inside of these two inputs so I can go back to one of the other edit forms.
See that title in price and that title in price as well.
Deftly works out.
But of course we probably also want to show some kind of input to edit or otherwise change the product
image so to show a product image and allow a user to edit it.
We can try to use the same kind of input approach.
I'll do an input with the name of image a type of file and then we will try to take the value and throw
it in as product dot image
and unfortunately this is not going to work out.
Remember when we add in a input of type file recently going to take a file off the harddrive throw it
into that input and then upload that to our back and server when we got it to our server.
We took the contents of that file and encoded it as a base 64 string so the downside to this approach
is that we've now got some representation this file.
It is not at all equivalent to the original file the original file was an actual image file and we have
a base64 encoded string so not only can we not take that string and kind of represented back inside
this input.
In addition we are not allowed to kind of preset the value of a input of type file as well so we can
try this right here.
Don't get me wrong we can refresh but we're going to see of course no file chosen right here so we can't
really kind of pre populate or preselect the form or see the file inside that input.
So I'm going to remove the value property off their So how are we going to handle this.
Well we're just going to say that if a user ever adds in a file to this input then we're going to assume
that they want to change the image that is tied to a product.
However if a user attempts to submit this form without choosing any file right here whatsoever we're
just going to leave the image as it is for our product and we'll just attempt to instead update the
title and the price okay.
So this looks pretty good.
Good start.
Let's now go back over to our products roots so roots admin products at the very bottom will add in
a post request handler to receive the submission of that form we'll do a router post to admin products
and again we need to encode that we don't know what the idea is going to be right here so we'll do colon
I.D. slash EDIT Once again we're going to require off in order to get access to this root handler and
I'll put in the actual callback function itself so req and rez and I'll make sure that I annotate that
as being async because we're definitely and have some async code inside of here okay.
Now let's remember that we are doing a form submission here.
We're also doing a possible file upload so we're going to go through all the same steps we've been doing
for all of our different form submissions.
We need to make sure that we possibly handle the image upload we need to have some validators we also
need to make sure that we handle any possible errors as well.
Let's do another quick pause.
In handle all that stuff in the next video.