All right now that we understand what we're trying to do let's go back over to our next hour J.S. file.
We're going to iterate over our file names array right here.
And for every file name we're going to run that El stat function will then decide whether or not the
file is a file or a folder and then do the appropriate console log.
So to get started I'm going to remove the console log file names right there.
We're going to start to write out a little code here.
Now before we write any code I want to tell you right away that I'm going to show you how to do this
the incorrect way with L stats.
So I going to write out some bad code here.
The reason I want to show you this bad code is that I can almost guarantee you that if you were working
on this project on your own.
As we get her you might write out some code very similar to what I'm about to show you.
So I going to first show you the bad way of doing this stuff and then we're going to point out why this
code is bad and then very quickly refactor it into a way more appropriate way.
So I just wanna be really clear that bad code is starting right now because I know it's really annoying
if you ever hear in a video like write out a bunch of code and then you hear oh yeah we would never
actually write out code like this it just makes life really confusing.
So we're gonna start bad code right here and I'm going to be very clear in telling you where we are
done writing bad code.
Okay.
So let's get to it underneath that comment.
I'm going to iterate over my file names array with a for of loop.
So I'll say for let's file name of file names and then inside of here I'm going to make use of the L
stat function.
So we'll say F S dot l stat I'll put in the file name and then the second argument which is going to
be a callback function that gets invoked with an air object if one occurred and our stats object which
is that instance of the class that we just took a look at a moment ago then inside of here I'll say
if air let's just do a console log of that error again we're going to take the easy way out here otherwise
I'll do a console log of the file name and whether or not it is actually a file or a folder so I'll
do a console log of the file name and then the second argument to the console log I'm going to print
out true if this thing is a file remember we just took a look at that stats object a second ago we saw
that it has years FSI dot stats we saw that it has the is file method on it.
So that's how we're going to print out either true or false.
This thing is a file or not it's all say stats dot is file okay.
So that ends bad code I say like bad code complete.
So we're going to run this code we're gonna see why it is not quite working as intended.
We're kind of not as intended and we'll very quickly start to refactor it.
I just want to point out here that what we've written so far.
Kind of like in general looks reasonable right.
It doesn't look that weird and that's why I specifically want to show you why this is not super ideal.
OK.
So going to save this I'm going to go back over to my terminal and I'll run an L S so now I should see
each my file names and other false or true next to it.
I do correctly see false next to empty folder because that is a folder not a file.
But then each of my three files have true so it looks like everything is working.
OK but I'm going to run the NL s command several times and I'm going to start to see some really interesting
behavior so I'm going to run it again one more time and about one more time okay.
Now I'm going to show you something interesting about this output you might not see the same output
on your machine Your machine might have no problem whatsoever but I want you to take a close look at
what is going on on my machine and you're going to see something weird here.
Notice how the first time I ran an L S I first saw a console log of empty folder then package lock then
package shapes on that index touch us.
Then the next time I ran it just a couple seconds later I saw those console logs occur in an extremely
different order I first saw index J.S. then package Jason and package lock then empty folder the exact
opposite and then the third time I went to empty folder and now index such a s with second as opposed
to last on the first time.
So the point here is that every single time that I run my program in general I'm seeing some very different
order of console logs again on your machine it might look like everything is occurring in the same order
but clearly that is not the case for me.
So what is going on here and how does this relate to the code that we just wrote a second ago.
Like why is this causing this very oddly ordered output.
Well let's kind of get a better idea of what's going on behind the scenes with L stats.
OK so quick diagram over here.
This is a timeline diagram.
Time is passing in the vertical direction.
So when we run our program we run that for loop and when we run the for loop we run all oracles to that
l step function in very quick succession.
In other words we call each those functions within like microseconds of each other.
The important thing to understand about the L step function and just about every function inside the
no just in the library is that it does not run the callback instantly.
In other words that callback right there.
It does not get called immediately after we run l steps instead what goes on behind the scenes is we
run the for loop.
We then call the El static function for every iteration of the for loop.
So again in quick succession again and again and again we call El steps then behind the scenes no J.S.
looks on the hard drive.
It takes a look at the file it reads in some stats about it and then it comes back to our program and
it calls the callback at some future point in time with the information about that file so the problem
is that reaching out to the harddrive takes some amount of time.
Maybe it's just milliseconds but it does take some amount of time regardless and it also might take
some slightly different amount of time for all the different files that we're trying to look up.
So the order in which these callbacks get invoked is completely unknown to us.
We have no idea what the ordering is going to be.
So that is the big problem with our current implementation right now.
We don't have any good way to kind of add some code inside of here that says hey don't do any console
logs until we have all the callbacks being called because if we ever want to do some ordering or alphabetized
some of the results here we kind of have to wait until all the callbacks get and vote and then kind
of collect the feedback from each of them and then do a console log at the very end with our current
implementation.
That is just about impossible.
So now we kind of see what is going wrong with this current implementation.
We'll take a pause right here come back the next video and we're going to start to remove just about
all this code and replace it with something that's going to allow us to get all the output from these
different El stat functions at the same time.
That's going to allow us to do some sorting or just make sure that we at a bare minimum always print
out the same order on the screen every time.
So we'll take care of that in just a moment.