Let's move on to part two of our post request handler around dealing with carts so inside of here we
need to take a look at the cart that we have a treat.
We're going to take a look at that items array.
We're going to see if there is already an object inside there that has the same product I.D. as the
product that we're trying to add right now.
If we find that same record or that same product I.D. then we're going to increment the quantity.
Otherwise we're going to add a new product to the array itself so that we can use a very simple find.
Statement it's going to delete that council log and I'll say const existing item is cart dot items not
find.
So we're going to use the find helper to take a look at all the different items inside the items array.
So we're going to put in a function here we're going to iterate over each item and I want to return
true on the first item that has an I.D. to the wreck dot body dot product I.D. property.
Because remember when we submit our form we're going to get a wreck dot body dot product I.D. property
that is the idea the product that we're trying to add to our cart so I going to say keep on iterating
through until we find an item with an I.D. property equal to rec when it collapses just we can see a
whole line wreck dot body dot product I.D. l zoom out just we can see that entirely
okay.
Alex Good.
Now after that we're going to take a look and see if there is an existing item.
So we'll say if existing item then we need to increment quantity and say and save Curt otherwise we
need to add new product I.D. to items array.
So that's our two cases so we'll take care of the first case right your first so existing item just
be really clear is going to be an object that looks like this like that thing right there.
So it's gonna be an object that has the I.D. of the product that we've added and the current quantity.
So essentially going to take that object existing item and we're just going to increment the quantity
by 1.
So easy enough we'll say existing item not quantity plus plus
then after that we can handle the else case.
So this is the case in which we are adding in a brand new product.
So we want to take a look at that items array and we want to add in a new object that looks like that
right there.
It should have an I.D. equal to our product I.D. and a quantity by default starting off at 1 so in that
case I'll say carte items that push I'll put in an object with an I.D. of rec not body dot product I.D.
and a quantity of 1
and then after either case.
So either we update the existing item or we add in a new item altogether.
The last we have to do is save this record.
So we need to take this entire cart that we have and we need to persist it back into our repo now for
that.
Unfortunately things are going to be just a little bit challenging here.
So we're going to do something like a wait hearts repo that updates.
Remember this is the only method we have to make an update to an existing record.
So we're going to pass on the I.D. as the first argument and the second is going to be the very specific
update we want to make.
So essentially a new set of properties.
So the reason I say this is gonna be all a bit hard is that we're just going to make sure we pull out
the items array take whatever update we just made and save that as the updates so we'll end up with
something like cart dot I.D..
So that is the record that we want to update.
And then the update we want to make is to the items array and we want to save Harcourt items like so
because we've just made a change to cart out items inside this if statement.
Whoops sorry about that.
We made a change to cart the items inside this statement.
Either we updated quantity of an existing item which is an element inside that array or we change the
array altogether and added in a new item okay.
So this looks pretty good once again.
So let's save this and we'll do another quick test.
So I'll go back to my browser.
I'll go to my product listing.
I'll hit add to cart.
I see product added to cart.
Now the question is how do we test this or how do we actually make sure everything worked.
Well it's really simple.
Remember we've got the cart stopped Jace on file so we can just open up that file directly and take
a look at our cart and make sure that it has an appropriate item with the appropriate quantity on it.
So I will open up cart start Jason.
Here is my cart right here.
So I can see the idea of my cart which is again the FBI 1 E6 I can see that it has the items array there's
a single thing inside there right now.
So this represents the product with ideas 6 to be blah blah blah.
And currently I have quantity of 1 it's now to really test this thing out.
We can go and try to add some other products multiple times.
So I'm going to try to add the gloves a second time when I do so I should see that existing record right
here.
Whoops looks like I've got a typo somewhere.
So I have quantity instead of quantity.
So that's definitely a typo on my part.
Good thing we tested this really quickly.
I'm gonna go back over to my code.
There we go.
I said quantity plus plus it should be quantity plus plus it's going to say that really quickly I'm
going to delete that property right there that shouldn't be in there at all.
Say this again and I'm gonna try that out a second time so I'll hit add to cart for the gloves.
And there we go.
Now I've got a quantity of 2 I should also be able to add in a totally new item.
So for example this little hat thing right here if I click Add to item I should see a new record inside
this array.
So here's the idea of that hat and I get a quantity of 1 Okay.
So overall I would say that our cart adding logic is working out perfectly.
So this is looking pretty good.
Now the last thing we do while two last things we need to make sure that we can list out all the items
in the cart and we need to make sure that we can delete items in the cart as well.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.