In the last video we started to take a look at the Jamestown library.
Let's now install the South the terminal and then get a better idea of how we're going to actually use
it inside of our testing framework so I can go back over to my terminal.
I'm once again back inside of my TMC project directory inside of here.
We're going to do an npm install J.S. Dom to make sure that you're running that new install command
inside of the TMG project folder because that is the project that we want to add this new dependency
to.
All right.
So we've got that installed.
Let's take another look at the documentation and understand how we're going to actually use this thing
so if I scroll down a little bit I'll see basic usage right here.
So as usual we're going to require it into our project.
Now I just want to point out these two lines right here in particular when we require J S Dom into our
project we're going to assign it to a variable that by convention we usually call simply j ust on all
lowercase.
This variable right here represents the entire library.
There are some different helper functions included on that j ust on variable one property that is included
on that variable is capital J ust on like so.
So you'll see that they are right here d structuring off another variable called all capitals.
J ust this right here is a constructor function.
Or essentially a class of sorts.
So we can use to create an instance of a browser.
Again fake browser inside of node.
So the only reason I point out these two lines right here is to just point out we get access to the
library and then we're gonna pull off just that one property that we actually care about once we get
access to that all capitals just on property we'll use it to create a new document.
So we say new j ust Dom and we pass in the H T mail that we want to use for the fake browser that we're
going to load up.
We then assign the result to a variable called simply dumb and that Dom object right there is going
to be what we used to essentially get access to the entire Dom running inside of our fake browser so
that's the general idea of how we use jazz Dom and a very basic and simple fashion but it doesn't really
answer how we are going to use it for testing how are we gonna use this for testing anyways as a quick
reminder.
Back on our testing framework requirements over here.
Remember I had said that I wanted to be able to test the whole application not just one little widget.
So the real question is how are we going to use j ust on to test the entire application like all the
functionality of it.
Well we're going to figure that out in just a moment but I think first we should try to create a little
sample project that we can run some tests on.
Just we have something to work with and it's going to help frame how we're going to use J.S. Dom to
test a web project in general.
So in this video we're going to do a very quick little detour.
We're going to put together a very quick little simple web project and then figure out how to use Jamestown
to actually test it.
OK so back inside my coat.
Ed I'm going to find my team directory and inside there I'm going to create a new folder called sample
web project.
So we've already got sampling project.
We're going to create a new folder called sample web project inside there.
We're gonna create a new file that we'll call index each team L so inside of here we're gonna write
out some little simple application we might have a javascript file to pair up to it and we're going
to eventually try to write some tests around it.
So right now let's first begin inside this index not a single file with just a little bit of both a
plate.
So at the very top I'll do my doc type I'll get my each e-mail
I head body and I'll add in a script tag for a source of index start J.S. like so it's now the question
is what little sample project do we want to create here let's just create something that shows a form
to the user and maybe receive some kind of input like an email and we're just going to try to run some
validation of that email and then print up the result on the screen.
So just a very simple application so I going to create a form element inside there I'm going to show
a label
that says enter email then an input and a button that says summit it's now inside of the new index not
just file that would create.
Right now we're going to write out some code to watch for the fun submission events.
We're going to take the input whatever's inside there.
Will there verify and just validate that it is an email or something.
Looks like an e-mail.
And then if it is we'll try to show a message on the screen something you just says OK you have valid
e-mail or not.
We're going to eventually write some tests around us.
So inside of my sample web project directory I'll make another new file called index J.S. inside of
here.
We'll set up a quick event listener so I'll do a document query selector on the form I'll add an event
listener for the submit event
I'll receive the event that we get through that and call it event dot prevent default.
Remember we're doing that just to keep the browser from trying to submit that form.
Then let's select that input element.
We'll get the value out of it and try to do some validation on it.
So we'll say const value.
Notice that we're doing some destructor in here.
We'll come from a document query selector.
Now we'll do a quick check to see if this thing is a valid email and we're gonna say they're valid email
or email is valid.
If it simply has an app signs like the app character it will say if value that includes at then it must
be valid.
Else must be invalid.
So we need something that's going to somehow communicate to the user whether or not we consider their
email to be valid.
Let's go back over to our e-mail file.
We'll create a empty.
Each one element and we'll stick others some text into it that says hey this is valid or this is invalid
depending upon how that validation worked out.
So inside of index dot HDL right underneath the form I'll just put an empty H1
okay.
So then back over here read about the if statement let's say header is document query selector.
Each one and then if the email is valid we'll do a header dot inter H e-mail.
I'll say looks good otherwise if the email is invalid we'll do a header dot enter H CML invalid email
OK.
So again very simple web project just something and so we can have some ability to understand how we're
going to actually use J.S. Dom because what we just looked at inside the documentation is not really
immediately clear how we can use that library to effectively test an application.
Now let's test this outside of our browser really quickly.
So I got to open up that index each e-mail file that we just created.
All right there's my input.
I'll stick in some valid e-mail and it is valid again because I've got the at symbol right there.
I'll submit it and it looks good.
But if I delete that and just put in some gibberish like so without any at symbol in hit submit.
It says invalid email so that's it.
That is our very simple very straightforward application.
So now we've got something that with our classic approach like when we are using Moka just a little
bit ago everything inside of here it would be really really challenging or just about impossible to
test very easily.
So let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back the next video.
We're going to discuss how we're going to use J.S. Tom to effectively test this application that we
just put together.