In this video we're going to figure out how he can get Express to give us the CSX file that we're looking
for.
So right now I'm inside of my laptop J.S. file there is the link tag right there.
But clearly inside of our browser if we look at the network we request app that's the ISIS file is not
getting loaded up which is why something's inside of here.
They'll look quite right just yet.
So how are we going to fix this.
Well as usual let's take a look at a diagram really quickly okay.
So here's what's happening inside of application right now.
Our browser is going to make a request for a route like Slash sign in to our Express server right now
on the Express server.
We have a route handler that is a dedicated javascript function to receive that incoming request.
Process it and then send back some handcrafted HDL.
We've got the same thing for Slash sign up as well.
So now we need to add in a very different type of root handler.
In this case rather than receiving some incoming request and having that execute some javascript code
we instead want express to try and find a file called may not see SS and send that file back over to
the browser.
So in other words we want our Express application to serve up some files or really just make some files
available in our application to the browser.
Let's figure out how we're going to do that.
Back inside my browser I'm going to find my root project directory and inside there I'm going to create
a new folder called Public this public directory.
We're going to expose to the outside world.
So in other words any file or any folder inside this public directory we're going to make sure that
a browser can freely access all the different files and folders inside there.
So the public directory really means public.
This is public.
It is available to the outside world inside this public directory.
We're going to place any CSF files any images any fonts any javascript code that we want to make available
to our browser.
It is very important that we never place any files inside there that are secret or really just important
to our application.
So for example you and I are never going to play some javascript code inside there that is intended
to be used by our server in general.
We always want to hide the code from our server and not allow outsiders to see it because who knows
our javascript code that runs the server might have some secrets inside of it or something like that
that we don't want the outside world world to know about however we will place JavaScript files inside
the public directory that are intended intended to be executed by the browser so inside this public
directory I'm going to make a new folder called CSX so to better organize this directory I will eventually
make separate files called CSX fonts images J.S. and so on just to make sure that's really clear where
every type of file lives inside their I'm then going to open up that directory using my file explorer.
So here's the CSX folder right there.
And we do icons.
You can see a much larger them on the darn thing.
There we go.
Here's public.
There's the CSX folder.
I got to open up that CSX folder and then I'll copy over the main dot CSX file that we had downloaded
in the last video.
So I going to place it in there like so now.
If I go back over to my editor and open up that CSX directory I should see that main file inside now
just placing these folders inside of here it doesn't actually do anything.
In other words if we go back over to our browser and refresh the page no change whatsoever.
We have to specifically tell express that we wanted to make this directory available to the outside
world to do so.
We're going to go back to our index dot J.S. file and find where we create our app right here.
Remember inside the index not just file.
We have wired up several different middleware.
Some of these are coming from outside libraries like body parser and cookie session there is another
middleware that we're going to wire up inside of here.
And this one is coming directly from the Express library itself so we're going to say right at the top.
The first middleware that we're going to wire up will say apps that use Express dot static and then
we're going to pass in a string of public.
So this is telling express to take a look inside of our current working directory find the public folder
and make everything inside there available to the outside world.
Now it's kind of interesting about this line right here is that it kind of changes every single request
that's going to come into our application every request that now comes into our application is going
to be handled first by this middleware right here.
Express is going to take a look at the route of the incoming request and it's going to see if there
is a file inside the public directory that matches up to the route that the request is looking for so
in other words whenever someone now makes a request to CSX slash main dot CSX Express is going to take
a look automatically every single time inside of this directory that's going to see if there is a folder
called CSX and then it's going to see inside there if there's a file called Maine dot CSX.
And if there is Express is going to take that file and send it back to whoever made the request if there's
not a file inside there that matches up to whatever the user or the requester is looking for then Express
is going to continue on and run all the other middle tiers and route handlers that we've wired up inside
of application let's now save this we'll go back over I'm going to refresh and now I will see a little
difference on the header I can see that the link for products is at the right hand side.
And if I open up my network request log I'll also see that we are now successfully retrieving that main
CSX file okay.
So that's pretty much it.
We've now got some good styling inside of here you'll notice that everything works just about identical
to how it worked before around our form.
So for example if I put in some invalid e-mail to sign in and hit submit we're still going to see that
same kind of validation stuff.
If I put in a valid e-mail but a incorrect password I'll see invalid password and so on.
We should have all the same behavior around our sign up form as well.
So if I tried to sign in with an e-mail that already exists I should get a validation error and so on.
So this looks pretty good.
Definitely good styling improvement.
So quick pause right here and continue in just a moment.