Well our timer is all done for right now.
I said at the end of the last video that we're gonna start working on the border.
There actually is one last very quick thing I want to do right now.
Our next stop jazz file has a lot of different code inside of it so it has our timer implementation
at the top then had some queries selectors and then where we actually create the timer as well just
to clean up our project a little bit.
I would like to extract the class definition for the timer into a separate file just so that our index
not just file a little bit easier to read.
So to do so inside my root project directory I'm going to make a new JavaScript file called timer dot
J.S. I'll then go back over to my index dot J S file I'm going to select the entire Timer class so going
to highlight the entire thing.
There we go.
I'll get to the bottom of the class definition.
I'm going to cut it.
I'm gonna go over to timer J and paste and I'll go ahead and save it then find.
Finally I'll go back over to index dot G.S..
Just do all that reformatting.
Just to make it look nice.
The last thing we need to do is open up our index dot each file.
We're going to make sure that we get a script tag for the timer DHHS file that we just created inside
of index HDL.
I'll find my script tag I'm gonna copy it paste a duplicate and I'll make sure that the top script tag
is going to get our timer dot J as file because we need to run timer dot J.S. before we can safely run
index dot J.S. to the first one right here I'll make sure says timer dot J.S. like so.
All right let's save all these files save all the changes we just made.
We'll just do another quick test just to make sure everything still works.
Yep no errors that means everything is good to go okay.
Well this looks pretty good.
So another quick pause right here and we'll actually start working on that border in just a moment.