We've now got our request handler put together.
That's going to eventually show a user a list of all the items they've added to their cart.
Now at the end of the video we put together this cart show template right here and we passed in the
list of items.
I made a small mistake here.
There is no items variable inside this function.
We want to say that items is going to be cart items.
My mistake.
So items is cart items let's now start to create the cart show template to do so we're going to create
a new folder inside of our views directory.
So I'll make a new folder called carts and then inside there I'll make a new file called show dot J.S.
so inside of here we're going to put together a function that's going to take the list of items iterate
over them and generate a line item or essentially just a little snippet of each team L for every item
that was added to the cart to get started at the top of the file.
I'm going to require in my layout that j ust file so I'll say layout is required up one directory layout
well then do a module dot exports we're going to receive that object that's going to be passed in with
our list of items then inside of here we'll say something like rendered items we're going to do a map
statement over our list of items I'm going to receive each item and then inside I will return a little
snippet of each email we'll start off very simple.
Right now I'm going to show a div that has the items title I want to show the quantity and the price.
Now I want you to recall what this item object right here really is back inside of our request handler
we found the associated product and embedded it inside this item object.
So the item variable that we're working with right now is essentially this big thing right here.
So we've got the quantity we definitely care about that.
And then nested it inside the product property is the title and the price.
So those are the three different properties we're going to try to print out quantity product title and
product price so inside this div I'll do a string interpolation.
So dollar sign and curly braces.
So we'll do item dot product that title and then how about a little dash then item dot product stock
price then a dash again and we'll print out the quantity so item dot quantity.
Because remember the product doesn't know anything about the quantity it's the item that has been ordered
added to the shopping cart the records the quantity
OK that looks good.
Now remember when we map over a list of elements that's going to give us back an array of strings because
we are returning a string inside of here so we don't want to render out or send an array of strings
to the user's browser.
So we're going to chain on a dot joint statement at the very end.
We're going to join on empty string to take the list of strings and condense it all down to one single
string then right after rendered items we can return our layouts and remember when we create a layout
we're going to pass on a object with a content property inside of here.
Also in each one it says heart items or something like that that works just fine and we'll just print
out our big list of rendered items okay.
That should pretty much be it.
So I going to say this I'm going to go back over to my browser and do a quick test to back over here
I can see carte items.
I've got winter gloves a price of nineteen dollars and I've got two pairs of gloves I got my winter
hats a price and I've got one D1 for that well I'd say this definitely looks pretty good.
Looks like everything is working as expected.
So now we should yield to go back over to our products listing.
We should build to add in a new item to our cart like let's say khaki pants for thirty nine dollars
if I click on Add To Cart I'll see product added to cart I'll go back I'll go up to the header I'll
find the cart button and I can see I've added in khaki pants thirty nine dollars one D1.
So I'd say this definitely looks like it's working out.
The only downside is that the styling right now is not very good.
So we're gonna take a pause right now.
We'll come back the next video.
I'm going to once again give you a template file that just has a lot of additional each T.M. that's
going to be placed inside of our DOT j ust file.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.