In this video we're going to take a look at solution number two.
This is definitely getting way closer to the right way of doing things but there's still going to be
a pretty big issue inside the solution.
So with this approach we're going to continue to do all this else that stuff but we're going to wrap
the L stack call in a promise remember A promise is another way of handling asynchronous code.
It is much more convenient in general for us as developers to work with than callback based functions.
So we're going to take the L step function wrap it with the promise so we can essentially interact with
Alstead with a promise we can then use the async await syntax to process the L Stat call one at a time.
So in other words we're gonna end up with this in a scenario like this right here.
We're going to make L stack called Number One and we're going to wait for that thing to be resolved
before we get our callback invoked.
In this case there's not really any callback per say we're essentially just getting some data back from
LC at and we'll move on to Step number two three and four and then finally at the very end we can somehow
keep track of each of these different statements all the data that's coming back and then do our console
logs at the very end and we'll always know that we are doing all these different calls in the same exact
order okay.
So let's give this a shot.
I'm gonna go back over to my editor.
We have a lot of code inside of here from the number one solution.
None of this stuff is really relevant anymore so I'm gonna take everything after where everything inside
of the Read dir function right here is everything from all stats I can go down to just about the bottom
and delete all that.
Now all I have left is the FSA require the read directory the if statement and that's pretty much it.
Okay.
It's now inside of here.
We need to somehow wrap the L stat function inside of a promise.
So we want to take that l start implementation and give ourselves a interfaced or a promise based interface
to it.
There are several different ways we can do this.
And.
Well we're gonna take a look at all them.
So option number one is for us to manually take a look at the L step function and wrap it into promise
ourselves to do so at the very bottom the file.
I'm gonna say const l stats is never going to receive our file name that we want to run the L stat function
on and then we're going to immediately return from this a new Rama's object.
Remember that a promise we're going to pass in a function that function is going to be automatically
and instantly invoked with two arguments that we refer to as resolve and reject then instead of here
we're gonna write all of our code to run our actual l stats.
So I'm going to call f s dot l stat I'm gonna pass in the given file name and then our callback with
the air object in the actual stats data that we care about so then inside of here we'll check to see
if there is an error if there is.
That means that something did not go right.
And so we probably don't want to do anything else.
We want to reject the promise to make it really clear that something went wrong.
So inside of here I'll say reject e are like so otherwise.
If we do not enter that if statement that means that we do have some stats data.
So I will instead resolve the promise with the stats object okay.
And that's pretty much it.
So that is method number one of wrapping l stat inside of a promise.
Now just because we are doing this right now I'm going to show you the other two ways of wrapping l
stat in the problems very quickly.
So method number two I'm going to come at this thing out met the number two we would go back up here
at the top and I would import or some you require in a library or a module from node called you till
I'd say require you tell let's go take a look at the documentation for the utility module.
Really quickly so I'll go back over my browser on the left hand side again to scroll down to the utility
section
and then inside of here we're gonna find that there is a function called promise of fi the promise of
fi function.
Well hey look at that.
That's actually kind of interesting.
They've got a demonstration right here of pretty much the exact function we are trying to use.
So we can use the utility promise if I function we can pass in some other function and it's going to
give us back a version of that function that interacts with a promise based interface instead of the
usual callback based interface.
So essentially the promise of five function does exactly what you and I just wrote out a second ago.
It wraps the given function in this case l stats in a promise automatically.
You of fi function only works correctly if the function that we're trying to wrap takes a callback as
the last argument and has a error and value kind of style callback as well which as we mentioned before
is just about every single callback in the node J.S. world.
So we end up being able to use promised fi in many different locations okay.
So to use this function we would say up here const l stat is you still dot rom mystify and we would
pass in the function that we want to wrap in a promise.
So that is FSS dot l step
okay.
So that is method number two right there.
But a comment says that the number two I'll go back down to the bottom one just for administrative purposes
and mentioned that is method number one.
Now the last way that we can interact with L start with the promise and this one is by far the easiest
if we go back over to the documentation for the file system module we can then do a search on this page
for F S dot promises we might have to hit enter one or two times.
So this is what we're looking for we're looking for F S promises API.
So it turns out the the F S module itself has a sub kind of module in it available as F S dot promises
it has just about all the different functions that the FSA module has in a promise based interface so
everything at the top up here as we scroll through this big list of F S functions just about everything
inside of here.
There is an alternate implementation of every single one of them instead of taking a callback.
The ultimate implementation return promises and that's how we interact with these other version these
functions so if I scroll down inside of this top section a little bit I'll eventually come to F S promises
API and we can scroll through here and we'll see that there is for example F S promises not access and
copy file and open open dir reader stat l stat right there.
So these are all the same functions but they just return a promise instead of taking a callback.
So just a different way of interfacing with them.
That is option number three for working with L start with a promise based approach.
We could do something like method number three would be const l stat is F S promises l stat or alternatively
we can use a little bit of D structuring here but some curly braces around the variable and then remove
L stat at the very end.
So I know that's probably a little bit more than you ever wanted to hear but it is important to hear
this at one time or another at the end of the day whenever we're working with all these different.
No j J.S. functions that take callbacks as the third arguments we can turn them into these kind of promise
based implementations either by doing it ourselves very manually using the built in Rumsfeld function
or seeing if there actually is a promise based implementation of the function that we are looking for.
In many cases there are still modules inside the node standard library that do not offer this kind of
promise based interface.
So sometimes we do have to fall back to method number one or bet the number to OK.
So the section has gone on for just a little bit.
Quick pause we'll come back in just a moment and continue implementing solution number two.