In this video I want to write out just one more very quick test just a real basic one to get one last
example in and after that that's where fun things are gonna start to happen after this.
We're gonna start to put together our own testing framework that's gonna work so much better than what
we've put together so far.
I honestly guarantee you're gonna like this.
So let's get through this last little test and move on.
It's for the last test I want to do is just to make sure that we print out a number of movies right
here equal to however many that we returned from our fetch data function right here.
So our fetch data function returns three movies.
Let's just write out a test to make sure that three movies get displayed at the end of the day.
This is gonna be very similar to the test we just wrote because we're going to want to put something
into the input dispatch and event wait for some stuff to occur and then go ahead and actually do stuff
all right.
I'm going to define another statement down here.
We'll say after searching displays some results.
Then inside the first couple of lines are going to be exactly what we had before.
So I'll just take that stuff directly copy it and paste it in.
Then after that we can do a query selector all to look for elements on the screen with a class of dropdown
dash item.
That's what each of these different elements has for a class dropdown dash item.
We'll do a query SELECT her all and just make sure that we get three results.
So back over here I'll say const items is document dot query selector all we're going to look for dropdown
dash item.
Don't forget the dot in there because we're looking for a class name
and then we can do an expect items dot length we can take a look at the child documentation if we want
to figure out how to essentially compare direct value.
I'll give you a hint it's simply too equal.
So we're gonna say that this value is going to equal three because we are showing it three different
movies.
All right.
Let's say this and do another quick test.
I'll put back over did I make the same mistake again.
Yep definitely did.
All right enclosing function market as async and remember that one of these days.
Okay.
So let's refresh this.
And there we go as usual.
Let's try to make this test fail because we usually like to see a test fail at least once it's let's
say two equal four I'll save it go back over refresh.
Yup it definitely is correctly correctly trying to find three elements.
I'll change it back to three and I think we're good to go okay.
So that is it.
With mocha in the browser now I don't know about you but I personally thought all this stuff was rather
painful.
Chai was definitely not fun because you gotta remember all these to be and whatnots putting together
all these different or the test out H.M. file was kind of nasty because we had to mainly add in these
script tags.
We also had to throw in some of these like got to know that actual test file itself.
We had to throw in some extra stuff inside of here just to get the autocomplete to work in general.
So we had to really understand how the autocomplete worked and even the fetch data function we put together
wasn't actually reaching out to the API and finally everything we've done inside of here has just been
about the autocomplete.
We haven't even begun to test anything else around our application so we haven't even considered anything
like hey by default the application should show this big message on the screen.
And then when we search for something it should go away.
That is something that you really should test but we don't have any ability to do that right now.
Of course we could add it in but it would just be a lot of additional work to wire up some more script
tags and all that kind of stuff so it's clear that while this approach works kind of lacking and that
is the segway into this we're going to write our own testing framework.
It's gonna be way easier to use than what I just showed you.
I think you're going to like it a lot so quick pause right here.
We'll get started on that in the next video.