In the last video we authored a render function and made it available to everyone who ran our test framework
by signing it to the global dot render variable.
So now it's time to actually test out our testing framework to do so we first need to make sure that
we have some tests that involve the sample web project that we just put together.
So to get started inside of sample web project I'm going to create a new folder called test and then
inside there I'll make a new file called app that test dot J.S. inside of app dot test at GSK.
We're gonna write out some tests very similar to the ones we just put together a little bit ago around
that for each example so inside of app dot test out J.S. I will write out it has a text input that's
gonna be the focus of this first test that we author remember we are attempting to load up that index
dot e-mail file and we're going to get a direct reference to essentially all the each email that is
inside of it and we can interact with that each smell as though we were inside a browser.
So we're going to write out a test that's just going to make sure that the small file has a text input
like the one you see right there.
So to do so we first have to call that render function to take that index on e-mail file and load it
up inside of J.S. storm.
What we get back should be an object that represents all the each level that's inside there and then
we can start to inspect it and write our tests.
We just made the render function available inside the global scope so we don't have to require anything
in or anything like that.
So inside of these it's statement I'll say const Dom is render and then I'll pass in the path to the
indexed dot Asian I'll file that I want to execute.
So that would be indexed dot Asian like so now remember render is an async function.
So I'm going to mark the enclosing function as a sink and put a weight right in front of render the.
Now let's just do a quick console log of Dom and see what we get okay.
I'm gonna save this.
I'm going to go back over to my terminal.
I'm going to change into sample web project.
Make sure you are inside of there as well and I'll execute Tumi and there we go.
We get a really big console log right here.
Take a look at that though a lot of information.
You'll notice a lot of the stuff looks like stuff that we would see inside of some kind of normal kind
of document or like normal web page.
We see a lot of different event handlers we can setup and whatnot.
So it definitely looks like this is at least somewhat working correctly right now.
We can kind of see some browser related stuff but now the question very quickly becomes how do we actually
kind of reach in there and really access the Dom and somehow mess around with it.
Well to do so we could take another look at the Jamestown documentation so back over here if we go to
the very top and scroll down a little bit.
Remember here it is right here that second example we get back the dumb object inside there.
We can reference window then document and on there we can have all these different queries selectors.
So if we want to just make sure that our e-mail file has some text input inside of it we could write
out some code that looks like this.
I'll say const input is Dom dot window dot document dot query selector and I'll look for an input.
Now if we do not have an input in our test is failing the input variable right here will be null.
So we could do something very classic like what we first wrote out we could say if there is no input
let's throw a new error.
We spoke about that at great detail but remember a better way of writing out this if statement right
here would be to instead use that a module that we have access to inside of node so I can remove the
F statements at the top.
I'm going to require in asserts like so and then to make sure that the input actually exists.
We can simply assert input if we just directly call asserts in passing some value a cert is gonna throw
an error if this value right here is false.
Some of the words of input is equal to NULL.
This is gonna throw an error in our test is going to fail right away.
So let's now say this and try it out again I'll go back to my terminal or ran to me and looks like okay
now of course as usual we always like to make our test fail at least one time so I'm going to go back
over to my e-mail document and I'm going to delete that input right there I'll then save this go back
over to my terminal run team again and I can see a nice big error message being displayed so that's
awesome It means that we can now effectively load up all this h t mail and test what is going on inside
of here and eventually we can also test to make sure that we start to interact with these elements.
We can make sure that they do the correct thing based upon the javascript code that we authored inside
of that index not just file as well.
That's it.
That's pretty much proof that we can get this thing working and we can run some arbitrary JavaScript
or some javascript that is meant to execute inside the browser in a node jazz environment instead.
So it looks really good.
Well as we solve a lot of stuff to do so let's take a pause right here and continue in just a moment.