In the last video we had a very long discussion about how we generally handle authentication inside
of a web application.
So we're going to use a cookie based authentication flow after a user successfully signs up to our application.
We're going to create a user in our user repo to represent this person we're then going to take the
idea of that person and we're going to store the idea of that user inside the user's cookie so in other
words we need to take the idea of whatever user we just created inside of our repo.
And we need to somehow set that Ireland on the user's cookie so that that cookie gets included on follow
up requests.
Anytime we receive a follow up request we're going to look into the cookie.
We're gonna take the ideas that is inside of it and we're going to use that to identify the person who
is making a request to us.
So that's the general idea let's start to write out some code and implement these two steps right here.
So the first thing we need to do is to create a user inside of our users repo.
Remember we already required in the user's repo at the very top of the index such as file.
Make sure you've got that require statement up there as well so we can now use a user's repo back down
here I will say await users repo not create and then we will pass in the identifying information for
this user that we want to store.
So that is going to be their email and their password that were submitted inside of these sign up attempts.
So I'll call a user repo Doc create with the email and the password that they provided.
Notice that the key and value here on both properties are identical.
So we can condense it down to just email and password so now whenever we create a new user we need to
get back the I.D. of the user that was created because remember we don't know what I.D. is going to
be assigned to them.
We randomly generate an I.D. every single time that we create a new record in order to get that idea.
We need to open up our users repository.
We need to go back to our create method inside of here.
So make sure you scroll down to the create method.
We need to make sure that at some point we return the I.D. from create.
So we know exactly who we just made or to me what the idea is for the user we just created to do so
we can just return the adders object entirely from the create method.
Remember we assign an I.D. to that adders object.
So I will return adders from create.
Now whenever we call create we're gonna get back an object that contains the idea of the user.
We just made it's now back inside of index dot J.S. would we call create.
I'm going to assign what gets returned to a variable that alcohol user.
Now on this user object right here is an I.D..
And that idea is what we want to store inside of our cookie.
Now we just need to figure out how we actually interact with the user's cookie at all.
There's two ways we can do this.
We can either figure out how to manipulate a user's cookie ourselves manually using express and some
of the different API that it offers to us or alternatively we can use a third party package to manage
the cookie for us.
That is what we are going to do.
We're going to use a third party package something that we're going to install as a library to our project
and that is going to automatically manage all the information inside the user's cookie.
The reason that we're going to use a third party package for this rather than doing it ourselves is
that managing cookies is notoriously tricky.
They are very complicated.
They're very easy to get wrong.
We can very easily put in some mistake that exposes a lot of information about our users to malicious
people.
And so rather than take all that liability on ourselves we're going to instead use somebody else's library
and have it do everything for us.
So even though it'd be really interesting to write out this code ourselves highly recommend in every
scenario you always use some outside library to manage cookies so to get access to this library that
we're going to use we're going to go back over to our terminal and install this other library as a NPM
package by using the NPM command line tool a back in my terminal.
I'm going to stop my server by hitting control C. And I'm going to do an npm install cookie dash session.
So that is the name of the library that we are going to use it's all a run that and then very quickly
we'll get it installed.
I'll then restart my server with NPM run Dev okay.
It looks good.
Now let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back in just a moment we'll start to wire up this library and then store the user's ideas
and style inside of a cookie so quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.