All right.
Let's jump right in.
We're gonna start with comparisons being able to compare values is really important when making decisions
as a really simple example something like The New York Times or any Web site where you get a certain
number of free articles a month they track the number of articles you've read each month when you're
not logged in and then they have a maximum whether it's 10 or five they're going to check.
Has this user seen more.
Have they seen fewer than the allotted or the allowed number.
So that's a comparison where checking is one value less than another value other comparisons that are
really common would be things like equality checking to see if something equals something else.
So this is a list of the different comparison operations we have in JavaScript.
There's quite a few but there's a lot of overlap and we're going to skip over the bottom for those all
have to do with equality not equality strict equality strict non equality.
We're just going to focus on the first for greater than less than greater than or equal to and less
than or equal to.
So let's play around with them.
I'll show you a couple of examples over here in my console.
Let's try something like is negative to greater than one.
You can see we get a boolean back a false boolean value.
Remember billions are just two options.
True or false every single one of these operators we see here all of these on this page return true
or false one or the other.
So that is greater than we can also do less than we have things like is 10 less than 9 9 9 9.
Without that period there we go.
That is true.
10 is smaller than 9 9 9 9.
We also have things like less than or equal to and greater than or equal to.
So we could do is to greater than or equal to two.
That's true is to greater than or equal to 5.
That's false to greater than or equal to 1.
That is also true and less than or equal to finally.
Hopefully these are relatively straightforward at this point.
Doesn't seem that useful on its own to just do something like fifty five point one less than or equal
to fifty five point five.
We know that we're typing it but just to let you know where we're going.
We're learning these operators first.
Then we'll see how we use them to make decisions.
Right now we're not deciding anything we're not changing the code that runs based off of these.
We're simply evaluating these to be true or false.
So most of the time when we do comparisons involving less than or greater than or less than or equal
to or greater than or equal to we're working with numbers in some form it might be the length of a string
might be something like this.
Hello Dot length.
Greater than or equal to Hello Dot length
usually those would be variables but you can see this is false because this is actually larger there's
an exclamation point that length is longer than this one.
But the point is we're not usually just directly typing hardcoded values.
We know the answer already.
We're usually working with variables things that are coming from a place that we're not controlling
where we don't exactly know the values.
So anyway numbers are really common when we're dealing with greater than and less than we can compare
strings.
And it's it's not that common and you'll see why in a moment the way that strings are ordered it's not
always the most intuitive.
But I can give you a quick example.
Let's start with lowercase a and compare it to uppercase a.
So from this comparison we can see uppercase A is less than lowercase a as you can see here.
Now what about uppercase B.
How does that compare to lowercase a.
So uppercase B comes before lowercase a which is not really the standard alphabetical order most people
would assume.
So all uppercase letters are less than any lowercase letters.
Then we also have confusing things like dollar signs and symbols and punctuation and accent marks spaces.
If you're curious how it works what the algorithm is or what the comparison is actually behind the scenes.
It has to do with something called Unicode all that you need to know is that every character in JavaScript
when it's in a string has a unicode representation it has a number behind it and you can see them here.
There's a long long article on Wikipedia that details all of the different codes.
Per each letter character symbol so you can see for example the very first code very first character
is zero.
And if we look at two other let's go with hash sign and dollar sign.
We can see the hash sign comes before the dollar sign.
So it should stand to reason that hash sign is less than dollar sign.
And that's true so this is not something you need to know and memorize.
I just wanted to explain how it works because I've seen a lot of students just assume it's all alphabetical
order which would make sense if we were strictly dealing with letters.
But when we deal with a whole bunch of other characters symbols and accents and punctuation it's more
complicated.
So comparisons at least the ones I've shown so far are usually done between numbers but we have this
whole other group that we haven't talked about around equality and non equality.
That's coming up next.
I'll see you then.