OK.
So let's start with creating objects.
How do we define a new object.
The first thing you've probably already noticed is that we use curly braces.
So instead of the square braces that we use for an array we use curly braces to signify an object.
Technically this syntax here is known as an object literal.
We'll learn other ways of creating objects later on in the course.
But this is the only way we'll see for now.
So if you hear objects literal if you see it online it's referring to this syntax right here.
So this will make us an empty object with no properties in it no key value pairs probably not what we
want.
So let's turn this data I've put it in a comment.
Turned into an object much like with arrays actually.
Just like with arrays when you store an object in a variable it is a reference to that object.
So we can use const and we can still change the information in an object as long as we don't reassign
the variable to a completely different object or something else entirely.
So people use const all the time with objects as well.
So we'll call this Fitbit data and we simply associate a value and a key I should have said it the other
way round key and a value.
So first is the key.
We'll talk more about what keys can look like what they shouldn't look like in just a moment but here's
our first example.
So we write the name that we want to store it under and then a colon and then afterwards the value and
it could be anything we can have values like I said that are strings numbers billions.
Even arrays and other objects which we'll get to later on we can put whatever we want as a value for
now we'll just work with this.
So we have a number.
Three hundred and eight thousand.
And we need to make sure we add a comma in after each property.
So total steps.
Colon some number and then comma and then we can begin with our next property.
We'll talk a little bit more about commerce at the end of this video.
Then we have total miles and total miles is two hundred and eleven point seven.
We have average calorie burn and so on.
So when we add them in we follow this pattern.
The spacing here is not crucial.
You'll see when I save I have a preference where it aligns to Collins a lot of people hate that it is
not something that you have to do.
It really depends on your preferences and also companies have their own style guides and we'll make
a decision on this.
But the main point is that the spacing doesn't matter.
You just have to have that colon.
So some key name then a colon and then some value.
All right.
So we have average calorie burn workouts this week which is a string five of seven and then average
good sleep is also a string two hours and 13 minutes.
OK.
So we have three numeric values and two string values.
If I save and run this code I'll refresh my page on the left let's look at Fitbit data.
You can see I expanded just like an array and we have our key value pairs.
If you look at the order my elements or my properties are displayed in it is different than what I wrote
here.
They are just alphabetized at this point.
Remember that order is not the point.
If an object we don't use an object to encode order we would use an array.
So it shouldn't matter.
OK.
So our information is in there.
We have different types of values.
How do we get anything out of there.
Well the first thing we'll see is that we can access information using the dot syntax.
So we've already done this before we have a string dot length.
This is the dot syntax.
It is different than executing a method like a SD dot to uppercase.
We use a dot and then parentheses.
It's actually the same underlying concept but when we're accessing a property we just use dot so to
access total miles out of Fitbit data.
We could do Fitbit data dot total miles.
And that gives us that piece of information.
Now there is another syntax to access data out of an object using a key and we'll talk about it in the
next video because there are some nuances to when you would use it and why you would use it.
But for now the dot syntax works so we'll access a piece of information out using a dot let's do Fitbit
data dot average calorie burn.
We use the same dot Fitbit data dot something we've seen that we can use whatever we want as a value
whether it's a number a string an array as I used this example.
What about the keys.
What are we doing here.
This doesn't look like any sort of valid javascript primitive or a type.
It's not a string or doesn't appear to be a string.
It's not a number.
Well when we create an object when we make a property the keys are automatically converted to strings.
So that means if you try and use a number there's nothing wrong with it but it won't be stored as an
actual number.
It will be turned into a string.
There is one exception to this something called a symbol which we haven't addressed yet.
And they're not that common they use except in this one scenario with object keys.
But we'll come back to that later.
So let's play around with it.
Let's say I wanted to add in the property forty.
And set that equal to the word forty five.
So let's refresh the page and run it and see what Fitbit data looks like.
OK.
It appears that our key 45 is in there.
But if I try and access Fitbit data dot forty five it doesn't work.
It tells me unexpected numbers.
So it's stored it just fine.
But behind the scenes it did turn it into a string.
It might not appear as a string it might not display as a string but it is indeed a string.
And in the next video we'll see another way of accessing properties of getting values out of an object
where we don't use this dot.
And we use something else.
Let's quickly talk about commas.
And when we need them versus when we don't.
If we define an object with a single property in it we'll just call it data and my properties will be
super boring just to make it short.
We'll do a is one I don't have to have a comma if there's only one property.
Javascript knows there's nothing after that.
It doesn't get confused.
So I can run this code refresh the page data works.
Data.
Whatever you pronounce it as.
But I also can put a comma there.
My editor will remove it because I have it set to do that to remove unnecessary commas but if I came
over here and did light stuff equals B is too with a comma it works just fine javascript knows that
this comma means that property is done.
It's hit the end of a property declaration.
Now there's nothing afterwards.
So it doesn't matter.
But when we do have multiple properties those comments are a must.
So if we have B is two I have to have this comma here in order to tell JavaScript or for JavaScript
to know this property is over with because we could have a longer property right we could have one plus
one.
So there's more stuff that could happen as part of the value.
As long as I put the comma there it knows we're moving on.
So we'll go a one B to C three run it over here.
It works great.
You can put that trailing comma in it's totally up to you.
Also you can put them on different lines as we've seen with longer objects and longer properties.
I definitely like to split them up.
But this object is so short it doesn't really matter.
OK.
So that's kind of it.
You can put commas in if you want.
At the very end the very last property that trailing comma is optional but every other comma separating
the properties is not optional it has to be there in order for JavaScript to know what's going on.
And then if you only have a single property you don't need that comma.