All right.
Let's discuss how we're going to design and create this data store thing so our data store is going
to take the form of a couple of different individual classes each individual class is going to manage
its own collection of objects.
So for example we're going to have one class that manages all the different users of our application
and another class that manages all the different products of our application.
So lumping this all into the term of data store is only from a kind of conceptual standpoint at the
end of the day.
It really is going to be like two separate objects for managing both those different resources.
We're going to call these different separate objects repositories.
So for example the object that matches the list of users will be called the user's repository and the
one that manages our list of projects will be called the products repository.
So let's discuss how we're going to design both these different repositories the design them are going
to be just about identical.
So I guess what I mean to say is how are we going to design a repository in general.
I sat down and thought up all the different methods that I would probably want to have a repository
to own.
So in this case we're gonna think about the design of the user's repository.
So again this is going to be a class that has a bunch of different methods attached to it for working
with all the different users.
We intend to create inside of our app we're going to eventually have something just about identical
for managing all of our products so we create as well so some different methods I expect this repository
to have I think a lot of them will be kind of obvious in nature or at least somewhat obvious.
So I think that we should have a get all method that will return a list of all of our users get one
that will find a user with a given I.D. it'll be provided as an argument I get one by that we'll take
some number of filters and then find one user that matches that given filter and we will of course discuss
exactly what filters are we should have methods to create update and delete some stored users a method
to generate a random I.D. and a method to take all the different users we have and save them to some
file on our file system.
So for us that's going to be like a user start JS on file that we're gonna store all of our users into
so we're going to create a class that implements all of this behavior right here and then like I said
eventually we'll create something very similar.
As a matter of fact almost identical for our products as well before we start to write any code.
There's something one to mention about this style of approach of having one class to manage all of our
different users in the world of JavaScript and kind of server design will really server design and data
management in general especially around Web applications.
There are two very popular approaches for managing data.
The first is called the repository approach.
This is what we are following inside of our application.
This is where we're going to have a single class that we refer to as our repository that is going to
be responsible for all the data access to one type of resource like all of our users or all of our products
or all of our whatever else all the records that we're going to be working with.
So like each individual user or each individual product is going to be stored and used as a plain javascript
object.
It's like a normal object literal that doesn't have any methods attached to it whatsoever so in this
scenario a repository is responsible for all of our interaction with our data.
It has all the functionality all the methods all of that kind of stuff is wrapped up in this one class
for managing one type of data the other popular style of approach is called the Active Record style
and this is definitely not an official name.
You're only going to see some number of places refer to this style as the active record style.
I really in my research couldn't really find a distinct scheme or her distinct name for this style of
coding or setting up a web application.
But in this kind of active record style approach which is named after Ruby on Rails which relies upon
a library called active record every record or essentially every user or product or whatever else is
a instance of a model class.
And so each of these different records have their own set of methods to save or update or delete or
whatever else that particular record that we are working with.
So it's really a question and these two approaches of where we are locating all of our code are we tying
all of our code to kind of a gatekeeper that governs access to our raw data or are we keeping all of
our code with each individual record and associating all of our functionality and centering all the
functionality around each individual record or this first dive into everything we're doing.
I think that the repository approach makes a ton of sense because we really can't sit down and imagine
just like off the top of our heads all the different ways that we would want to work with our data.
You know in this scenario yeah we would want to get all of our different records we want to go to get
one.
We want to be all search for one create update delete and all that kind of good stuff as soon as you
start to get the active record approach things start to get a little bit more hairy because each individual
record is going to have its own set of methods.
There are some methods that don't make sense to allocate to each individual record for example with
the active record approach something it gets a little bit hairy is where to locate a method called like
get all this is a method that is supposed to operate or do a kind of search over a collection of different
records and hopefully return an array of different objects.
And so if we were associating all of our functionality with each individual record well where does that
really make sense to put a method like this.
It just starts to get a little bit more harried to think about a little bit more challenging.
And so I think when you're first getting started using this repository approach makes a lot more sense.
OK.
So our goal right now is to create a new class.
We're going to implement all these methods right here and at every step along the way after we make
any kind of update with say create update delete or whatever else we're going to make sure that all
of our data eventually gets written out to a users not just Jason File and that's how we are going to
have some level of persistence.
So let's get started on our users repository in the next video.