Before we start writing code and getting our editor all set up I want to start with a quick discussion
around terminology.
So if you're brand new to JavaScript one of the first things that might confuse you along the way are
some of the terms I have on the left side of this slide javascript ect my script is 20 15 16 17 18 yes
five Yes six.
What do all those mean are they all just JavaScript.
Let's talk about it.
So javascript like most programming languages continues to grow new features are added but the way that
that happens is pretty different than most consumer software or operating systems.
If you think of something like Windows or iTunes when there's a new version or new features are added
you go and download that release everyone has that release or everyone who downloads it and you get
those new features.
It's sort of a bundled package thing you go and download it and you've got it.
JavaScript is a little different there actually isn't a single javascript there isn't a one javascript
download link that you go to like there might be for Windows or for iTunes instead.
JavaScript is implemented by all the different browsers out there and it's up to those browsers to implement
new features.
So the way that it all works is that there's an organization called Emma ACMA.
They have sort of a bleak Web site.
And Emma is an international group that is in charge of all sorts of different standards not just for
programming.
They come up with standards for things like acoustics and electromagnetic compatibility and electromagnetic
fields information storage near field communications and then there's this one right here Emma script.
So Emma script is a specification for a programming language.
You can think of it as almost like a reference.
It's a text document that says Here is a specification for a programming language.
It should behave this way.
It should have this feature.
This thing should work like this thing.
I don't know.
That's a horrible explanation.
It's essentially a document that describes how a language should work but it is not itself a language
you can go download and use.
It's only a description and this is it right here.
There is a website and you can go to to view it.
This is the specification for a language called Ekman script named after the organisation Emma.
And if you just take a look at really any piece of it you won't see much code at all.
It's mainly text explaining how different pieces should work how things are related what keywords need
to exist in the language.
So it's a set of rules.
Then it's up to the browsers like Safari or Chrome or Internet Explorer to go and follow those rules
and implement them as javascript.
It gets kind of technical here.
There's a committee called T.S. 39 at this Emma organization.
They're the ones who are in charge of evolving and maintaining this massive document that describes
how Acme script should work.
And every year different delegates on this committee meet up they listen to presentations they debate
to figure out which new features should be added to this specification.
So when something is added to JavaScript what really happens is that it is added to this specification
as a piece of text usually a lot of text explaining how the new feature should work.
Then what happens is that browsers have to go and implement those changes.
Now as far as the naming here this can be a little confusing to beginners the way that updates quote
unquote or new features used to work with Acme script was not on an annual basis.
There were batches of updates or batches of new features that were added to the spec and they had names
like iOS 5.
There was actually no iOS for it was cancelled but there were these these groups of new features that
were added and it took forever like a bunch of years in between these updates to the spec and after
iOS 6 was released which took about six years.
The committee decided to change things up and just annually update the spec so naming started to go
by yes for a script and then instead of a version number like four or five or six it's now a year.
So yes 2015 yes 2016 yes 2017.
So all of these terms over here on the left are referring to well except for JavaScript they're all
referring to this specification document iOS 6 is the same as iOS 2015 and it all boils down to this
one document that we saw in Texas being added in to describe how a feature should work.
So what's what's kind of annoying about all this.
To be honest is that since there is no official download or an easy way just to get JavaScript as a
language and update it automatically because it's all implemented by separate browsers.
This means that different browsers will support different features at any given point time and there
are Web sites that exist specifically to help you understand this.
One is called Can I use dot com.
And if we search for some feature on here which if you're brand new to JavaScript it doesn't really
matter what I type in here but I'm going to look for something called Aero functions.
And here we have a compatibility chart telling me which browsers support aero functions and when they
started if they started aero functions are a newer feature in the spec they're not supported by Internet
Explorer at all.
They were added to Firefox and Chrome a couple of years ago.
So a chart like this helps you understand that not every feature is going to be available in every browser
and that all boils down to the nature of JavaScript.
It is not one language necessarily a bunch of implementations of the same specification.
Oh what a way to lead the course off.
I know it's not it's not the most exciting topic but I have to get this out of the way because a lot
of what we're going to talk about in this course are newer features things that are exciting and worth
knowing about.
But I'll say things like this feature is not supported in Internet Explorer and I want you to understand
why that is.
Why do some browsers have certain features and others don't.
Okay enough of that.
Let's get started with setting up our environment and then dive into code.