Next up let's talk about our third primitive type string.
Strings come up all the time early on I talked about this form and how we might represent the data in
JavaScript.
All of this text information the review the name the email we would store that or model that using strings.
Strings are just textual values pieces of text or strings of characters.
And the most important thing to remember is that we wrap them in quotes.
Single or double quotes so you can see some examples here.
This is a string Ziggy using double quotes.
Here's another one a longer string.
Here's one with single quotes.
This is problematic where we're mixing a double and a single we're never closing the string.
You can use either.
What's really important is just to be consistent within a single application or single file.
You don't want to have some strings that are using single quotes and others that are using double.
It's not a problem for your code.
It won't cause any errors.
It's just confusing for other developers.
So as I said we can type strings instead of quotes.
That's a string.
We can do it with single quotes.
We could even put numbers in there.
This is a string not a number.
I haven't shown you this yet but there is a special operator in JavaScript called type of.
I have no idea why it is not capitalized.
The Oh I'm sure there's a good reason for it hopefully but type of is an operator where we pass in a
value like eighty seven and it tells us that's a string versus if I got rid of the quotes.
That's a number.
So strings are text they can contain all sorts of characters not just letters and numbers but also special
characters.
As long as we remember to close the string.
So if you do something like this and we don't close it we get an error Invalid or unexpected token.
That means that JavaScript encountered this opening quote and thanks.
All right we're on a string string Len string you hand string land and then it just ends and it was
expecting a quote at the end to let it know the string is done.
We can also use quotes inside of other quotes.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's say we had an example of he said and then I wanted to use quotes inside of this because somebody
is talking hahaha.
This is totally valid.
I have single quotes on the outside and then double quotes on the inside that works.
And I could do it the other way around as well.
He said Elwell valid as well.
What does not work is if you tried to use double quotes she said and then double quotes again like that.
What's happening here is that we start a string off and then we close it prematurely and then we have
this just LMG hanging around which doesn't mean anything in JavaScript.
Give us an error and then a quote which opens a string and a quote that closes a string and it just
contains a space so unexpected identifier it doesn't know what AMG is supposed to be.
So those quotes have to be there but you can mix them up if you do need to have quotes inside of a string.
Of course you can make variables with strings.
Let's go with let.
First name equals.
We'll just use Ziggy as we've already seen in the notes.
So we have first name and then let's also do last name.
So let's.
Last name.
Let's do Ziggy cannery face.
That's a very unique last name.
And what I want to show you here is that we have some operations that we can do with strings.
We can do something like first name plus last name.
Now this is very different obviously than mathematically adding them even though it's the same operator
or the same symbol.
It has a very different meaning in this context when we're working with strings.
We are going to can cat Nate the strings together which means shove them together into one string Ziggy
canary face.
And if we wanted to we could go further and add in a space between the two like this.
So first name plus a space plus last name.
Now we have Ziggy canary face and we could save that to a variable like full name equals first name
plus space plus last name.
And we have full name as Ziggy canary face.
There are some quirky things.
If you start mixing types like hi plus one one is going to be turned into a string and we end up with
high one or concatenate them.
We don't have similar operators for minus.
So if we tried to do high minus H that doesn't work and thinks that we're working in mathematical realm
so we get not a number.
Same thing with division we try and do high divided by age not a number.
There's quite a bit more to talk about with strings which we're about to do but I won't leave off here
for this video we've seen that strings are textural value strings of characters and they need to be
contained within quotes double or single.
It doesn't matter as long as you are consistent and you close them correctly.
So you have an opening single you need to have a closing single and the same goes for double quotes.