In the last video we establish that we're not going to be able to do our image upload using the same
strategy that we've been using so far for form submission.
So in other words whenever we tried to submit an image all we actually got on our back and server it
was the name of the image.
Nothing about the actual image data.
So in this video we're going to do a deep dive on to form elements and get a better understanding of
how we can make a form except a file and upload that file to our back end server.
Some of the stuff I'm about to tell you has been stuff that you've already heard inside this course
several times before.
Nonetheless we're going to do a review of how forms work to make sure that you really understand how
our data or how the file is going to be transmitted.
So let's get to it to get started going to first go back over to my editor.
I'm going to find inside my views directory the products new template.
So here's the form that we're working on right now.
Now we've used forms throughout this course in many different fashions.
We first use them as just a simple form element like so at some point time.
We then started to add in this method of post and that changed how we were submitting this form to our
back and server so I first want to focus on what method is really doing for us here.
After we understand what method is really doing we're going to talk about another property that can
be added into a form element and how that changes the form.
The first thing I want you to understand is that when we're showing a form by itself like so there was
a default value of method that was being used.
So if we don't provide a method the browser is going to add in a default value for method of get instead
the method property right here is describing how the form is going to submit information or how that
information is actually going to be communicated to the back end server if we provide a method of get.
That means that the browser is going to take all the information of the form add it into the URL of
a request and then make a request to the backend server.
With that your URL.
And as we saw if we change method to post it's going to take all the information out the form stick
it into the body of a post request and then make that request to the back end server.
I want to review both these really quickly.
I'm going to update this to a method of get going to save it.
Go back over to my form refresh Internet title a price and hit submit and lo and behold we can see that
we made a change the url all of our foreign data is now inside there and as soon as we hit submit.
Not only was the URL updated but we also made a new request to the backend server.
So that's why our form values cleared themselves out if I now go back over change form back to post
or form of method to post.
Now we're going to take all the information put inside the body of the post request.
It's going to go back over refresh the page put in the title and a price hit submit.
If I inspect the request was issued I'll see if there is a forum data down here.
So that is all the information that was inside the body of the request and that's how it was communicated
to our back in server.
So again the point that I'm trying to make here is that the method property communicates how to share
information or how to transmit this information to the back end server.
The other thing that I want to point out once again is that if we do not provide a method option right
here there is a default that will be used and that is the default of get okay.
So now that we're kind of up to par we've got all that and reminded fresh in our minds and I want to
tell you about another option that we can provide to a form element.
The other option that we can provide is E and C type this stands for encoding type whereas the method
describes how to transmit information and type describes how to take information out of the form and
get it ready to be transmitted so it describes how to encode this information or how to kind of bundle
it all up to make it safe to transport in some style.
If we do not specify encoding type the default value that is used is application slash X dash w w w
form your URL encoded.
So again this is the default value that is used.
If we do not provide an encoding type if we save this right now and then tried to use our form again.
We're going to see that no behavior has changed because we're just passing in the same value that is
used by default.
So for example I can go back over really quickly enter in a title and a price hit submit.
Look at the request.
Yep form data.
Data is still right there.
When we say form your URL encoded we are literally saying take all the information out of the form.
Specifically the inputs.
Take a look at the named properties of each input.
Take a look at the values of each and put them all together in a query string kind of format.
That is what your URL encoded right here really means.
It means take this form information and make it safe for transport inside of a URL so if we take a look
at our form data right here and click on View Source we'll see what our information is actually being
transmitted as inside of that post requests so we'll see that it has that same kind of query string
format that we saw up inside of our your l just a moment ago.
So again your URL encoded means take this information make it safe to be transmitted inside of a euro.
Now the problem here this is the core issue around using these default settings of encoding type with
an input of type file.
The problem is that when we tried to upload a file a file might have some data inside of it that can
not be safely or even efficiently transmitted into a U.R.L. safe format I'll show you that very soon.
So again the issue is we might have files that have data inside them that we can't simply turn into
a string in any fashion.
And so we can't transmit a file with this kind of you URL encoding scheme.
And that's why right now when we tried to submit an image the image is not transmitted whatsoever is
because the form is saying hey you know what.
I see you've got a file but I've got no idea how to turn that file into a you're all safe string.
So I'm just going to ignore it and I'm going to instead just transmit the name of the file.
So again the whole issue here is the default encoding type that we're trying to use.
That is why the form is not being transmitted.
So as you might guess in order to make all this stuff work rather than using an encoding type of you
URL encoded we're going to simply use a different encoding type one that can safely transmit raw file
data so in place of this default value of your URL encoded.
We're going to instead replace it with multipart slash form dash data so that's the secret.
So this is going to change how information is taken out of our form and turned into some format to be
sent to our back and server when we use multipart foreign data.
That means take all the different pieces of information out of our form and for each separate input
send each little part to the back end server in a different little part so to speak let's save this.
I'm going to save this file so new DOT J.S. and then going to go over to my root handler for the post
request.
We're going to add in an additional console log and we're going to see how encoding type right here
of multipart form dash data is going to actually transfer all the information inside of our form.
So inside of roots admin I'll find products not J.S. says the file we've been working on.
Here's our post request handler.
I'm going to remove the console log of errors and you might think that at this point time we could simply
do a console thought log of wrecked out body and see that image.
Now unfortunately no that's not the case.
If you recall way long ago at the very start of this project inside of our index dot GSA file we wired
up that body parser thing right here when we wired a body parser we specifically said body parts are
dots you were all encoded.
So that told our body parser to take a look at any incoming post request and if it had a U RL encoded
body pass it for us.
So the current middleware that we're using right here only works with default forms.
It's not going to work out of the box with a multipart form which is what we're currently working with
so I want you to think back to when we were talking about all this body parser stuff.
I want you to think about how we were kind of getting at our form information before we were using that
little middleware.
You might recall that we wrote out some code that looked like rect on data takes that data and do a
console log of that data.
And in this case you're also going to call to string with it.
So again we had some code like this before we wired up that middleware.
So this was saying OK we're going to take each little chunk of data that's going to come into our server
every single time that we get a chunk of data we're going to console log out whatever data we just received.
So this is going to show us the raw data that isn't being included with our post requests.
Now let's save this I'm going to go back over to my application.
I'm gonna make sure they refresh my form entirely and then I'm going to do a file upload once again.
They're really important.
I encourage you not to do a file upload right now.
Do not try to upload an image.
If you try to upload an image right now it's an credibly possible that you're going to lock up your
terminal entirely because we're going to essentially console log out all of the raw data of an image
between the last video and this one.
I took the liberty of getting a really really small image.
So this image right here is one by one pixels it is eight hundred and eighty one bytes in size the code
image that I had is one hundred and seventeen kilobytes.
So if I try to console log out one hundred and seventeen kilobytes of raw data well I might end up locking
up my terminal.
So again I encourage you not to try to upload a file right now.
I'm going to do a file upload with this very small image so we can very easily see what data is inside
of that post request OK.
I'm going to try to upload small submit now going to go back over to my terminal and see what got console
logged OK.
So here's the body of the post requests that we are now receiving it's going to scroll back up to the
top of the request tonight you'll see that the content inside of the body this request is significantly
different than what it was before when we had that default encoding type of your URL encoded and we
had the default type of your URL encoded we formed up that query string and that was all that was sent
from the browser to our server.
But now with the multipart encoding type we're saying take all of the different inputs inside of our
form split them all up into separate little parts of this request and then send them all over one by
one so you can see inside of here.
I've got one little section right here where the input that had a name of title and there's my title
I then got another little section right here with the name of price.
And there's my price and then right here.
Here's the important part.
I've got a name of image.
I've got the name of the image where the actual file name I see the type of image that it is.
And then the raw image data.
So this is how that RAW image data is being communicated from my browser to my server.
Remember how I said just a moment ago there is no safe way to take some raw file data and convert it
into a string and have that string being sent to the backend server.
Now we can kind of see why there are some characters inside of here or some raw data inside the image
that clearly cannot be safely turned into a string and even console logged out inside my terminal let
alone transferred as a you're all safe string inside the body of a post request.
So this is how we're going to receive a actual file inside of a post request we use a multipart form
data submission now last kind of interesting thing I want to show you here.
Last part and this is a kind of a long video.
If I go back over and take a look at the request that was actually issued and click on it I can go back
down to the form data section and now there's nothing down there.
So whenever I start to use that encoding type of multipart form data Chrome is no longer going to try
to tell me what data is being placed inside the body of the post request.
So it just doesn't even print out the form data section down here even though there technically is some
information being communicated in the body of that request.
The only reason Chrome doesn't do it is because it is for performance concerns and you can actually
look that up online.
That's why we don't see anything about that post requests body down here.
The other interesting thing if you take a look at the request header section you'll see that the content
type header says multipart foreign data the content type header is telling our server about the format
of data that it's about to receive.
So it's telling our server in this case it's about to get a multipart forum submission.
It also gets this boundary property right here the boundary property is a string that describes exactly
what is separating all the different fields inside of our form.
So if we take a look at it it says Web Kit form boundary and then some random string of characters right
there.
If I go back over to the council like I just got we'll see if that is the boundary right there between
every different input from my form.
So whenever my server sees web get form boundary that essentially means hey here's another like chunk
of data or another input out of the form.
And then here is another and then here's another.
In this case the last one is the actual image itself.
So hopefully this kind of like behind the scenes look I know some of this was like very quickly that
went through it but this is essentially what is going on with image submission or really file submission
to our back end server or even while file upload I suppose.
So we've got this multipart request every part represents a different input out of our form the last
one is the actual image that is being uploaded.
The reason we have to use this multipart form submission is because our file contains some raw data
inside of it that cannot be safely turned into a U or L.
The other big issue is that the middleware that we're using right now for automatically passing our
post requests is only currently configured to receive a U URL encoded post request at this point.
We no longer have a Euro encoded plus request instead we now have a post request with an encoding type
of multipart phone data.
So the existing middleware that we have right here is not going to work for us.
All right.
That's it.
Hopefully that kind of outlines what is going on and what the issue is and hopefully it also makes you
think about what we have to do to actually receive this file now.
Yes we do like technically have the file on our server but just like we saw before when we were talking
about this body passing stuff this format of data right here.
Well you and I can't really easily access it right.
Like we can't really very easily reach in here and get at that image and actually work that in some
meaningful fashion.
So as you might guess in the next video we're going to get another middleware specifically intended
to handle multipart form submissions.
It's going to reach into that form submission it's going to pull out each piece of data.
So the title the price and also the image and it's going to give us the image in some way that we can
actually work with it.
All right.
That's it.
Stick a pause right here and start to tackle all that stuff in the next video.