OK.
So our autocomplete definitely looks great but like I just mentioned there's a couple more things we
need to do for it.
So first off we need to make sure that whenever we fetch a new list of videos we clear out the existing
ones inside there.
That's gonna be pretty straightforward.
So let's take care of that task first.
So the big question here is when should we clear out the existing list.
Well remember inside of on input we are making a request to fetch our data right here after we fetch
some data.
We should probably clear out any existing items before we attempt to add any more in the right above
or we have dropdown class list.
Add let's add in some code to take a look at our results wrapper.
Remember that is the thing that is going to eventually contain all the different rendered results that
we get the right above dropdown class list.
Add I will add in results wrapper and to clear the thing out we could do a simple enter each CML is
empty string like so let's save that.
I'm going to flip back over do a refresh and I'll search for Avengers and I'll do a search for Dark
Knight and there we go.
That's much better.
Now one thing you might notice as I search for Dark Knight and you might see this or you might not.
It looks like the last result in here has a broken image and inside my console I also see an error as
well.
So you might not see that.
It really depends upon the movie that you are searching for.
Let's take a look at the API response so we're getting inside of our network request tab and try to
understand why we are seeing a broken image there.
So I'm going to open up my most recent request to the API.
I'm going to take a look at the list of results we get back.
I'm going to select dark knight right there.
Do you notice that in this case we have a poster property of an eight.
Which means that there is no poster image available.
Normally that poster is going to be the link to the actual image.
The reason that we're seeing this error is that we're essentially throwing in the string and a as an
image source and we can actually confirm that by inspecting that element inspecting the image you'll
see that the image very plainly has an S or C of N A.
And that's why we're seeing this nasty error down here.
So to get this fixed and again you might not be seeing this yet but you probably will eventually.
We just have to add in a check or an A essentially and make sure that we ever see it.
Well we probably just don't want to show the image at all so to do so I'm going to go back over going
to find where we create the inner each team L for each individual option.
So that's where we create the image right there so all we have to do is add in a quick check beforehand
to decide whether or not we want to show this image to do so right after we create the option.
I'm going to say const image S R C like so and I'm going to use a little ternary expression here.
So going to say if item dot poster remember the capital P is equal to N slash a then I want to assign
a value of empty string to image s RC.
Otherwise if it is not equal to N A.
I want to you assign item dot capital P poster to image as RC instead.
So again this is a Turner expression.
We're going to first evaluate that expression right there.
If that is a truth the expression then we're going to return whatever is between the question mark and
the colon.
Otherwise if that is false C we will assign item not poster over to image that s RC.
So now we can use image as our C in place of movie poster.
If we show an image element with an empty string it's essentially just not going to show up inside the
dom.
Well it's going to technically show up on the dom but it won't show up on the screen which is going
to solve this issue.
Going to put image s RC inside there like so.
All right.
So going to refresh I'm gonna look for dark knight again and it looks like I probably made a typo inside
there.
Sorry I called it item it is not item it is movie that is better.
My mistake.
That's better.
I'll do Dark Knight and the last one down here.
Don't have an image fully fine.
That's life.
There is no image to show but we are not trying to show some like non existing image and showing a broken
image ranking like that.
So this stuff looks good.
I think the last big thing we have to take care of is to make sure whenever user clicks out of the input
like I'm clicking over here right now we need to make sure that we close this thing up.
So let's figure out how we can do that in the next video.