Now that we understand the dash Ray and dash offset properties.
Let's understand how we're going to use them to actually implement this animation.
I want to first begin by taking a look at the finished product one more time.
So this is what we are going after.
We want to have the entire stroke starting off as covered so that would imply that we're going to begin
with a dash Ray with whatever our perimeter value is.
So for us it's red round five sixty five and we should also have a dash offset starting at zero.
So that's how we're going to get that full aero or that full border excuse me starting up when we first
start our application.
Now here's where things get challenging.
Take note of how this animation plays out.
We're starting from the very top edge and we're going to show white space going in the clockwise direction.
That's kind of counter to what we were just discussing remember the default behavior is to draw the
border starting from right here as opposed to anything up at the top and then the dash offset is going
to add an additional whitespace going in the counter clockwise direction.
So this final product has the spacing or the whitespace going in clockwise.
What I just showed you around dash offset is going to add space in the counter clockwise.
So in other words if we use dash offset as we know it right now and we start off at zero and let's say
one second goes by and we change that to 20 OK we're going to get that gap.
Then if we go to 40 we're gonna get that gap.
And so on.
So again it is playing in the opposite direction of what we really want.
So how are we going to fix this.
Well as usual it's just a little trick dash offset.
We're just gonna make it negative here.
That's pretty much it.
Providing a negative value of dash offset is going to add in that whitespace in the opposite direction.
So it's going to start to go in the clockwise direction instead of the counterclockwise that we saw
in the last video so if I change dash offset to negative 40 we're going to get the whitespace right
there.
And then as we start to take that number more negative it's going to start to go in a clockwise direction
we're going to see more and more whitespace like so.
So you can imagine that for every second that goes by we're going to change dash offset to be slightly
more and more negative and that's what's going to give us whitespace going all the way around the outside
edge until it eventually comes back to the same right hand side.
Now the last big question is how are we going to actually get the animation to start at the top like
up there as opposed to the default behavior which is to have the entire border being drawn right there
on the right hand side.
Well once again a little trick usually how it works out.
So the little trick we're going to use we're just going to rotate this entire circle negative 90 degrees
so you can take the entire circle rotate it negative 90 so we're gonna take it 90 degrees in a counterclockwise
direction counterclockwise do that rotation we can add on an additional property to our circle element
we're going to provide transform is rotate negative 90 and this will also take two other arguments.
When we call rotates we're going to pass in 100 loops.
One hundred.
One hundred may expand this just we can see it more easily so as you would guess the first argument
to rotate is going to be at the amount we want to rotate in the direction that we are rotating in a
negative value means that we're going to rotate in the counterclockwise direction the second two values
right here define the origin point of the transform.
So by default usually a transform is done against the top left corner of our SPG element by passing
in at one hundred one hundred.
We are saying that we want to rotate this circle around what happens to also be the center point of
the circle.
So we're going to rotate around that point right there.
Let's save this refresh and now if we start off with the data or me a dash offset of 0
we start up right there everything is matching up on the top and then as we start to make this number
more and more negative so go to negative 10 it's going to start to give us that whitespace as they go
to negative 50.
Give us more as we go to negative 100 and we can start to see how.
As we start to make dash offset more and more negative we're going to get that whitespace around that
outside edge going in the clockwise direction just like we saw on our finished product over here.
So that's pretty much it.
That is the secret.
The secret is to use the negative value of dash offset.
We're going to use a dash array value equal to the entire perimeter of the circle.
And then finally we're going to transform this circle as well to implement a rotation negative 90 degrees
OK.
So now that we see like the general idea essentially what we're trying to do here the last thing we
have to do is essentially take this entire strategy.
We need to make sure that every single time we tick our timer so like over here with on tick every single
time that happens we need to make sure that we start to make dash offset right here.
More and more negative we're also gonna add in a little bit of code to kind of adjust these values of
dash rate and like calculate that value on the fly is obviously putting in the parameter Ursa near the
perimeter right here.
That is a calculated value we have to do two times pi times the radius.
So rather than encoding the dash array right here we'll instead set that programmatically.
So we'll read the value of the radius of the circle calculate the perimeter stick it in and then every
single time we get a tick we will update dash offset.
So now that we've got the full story.
Quick pause right here and we'll work on our implementation in the next video.