There's one less fix I want to take care of very quickly.
Right now if we do a search for something so like I'm going to search for Avengers.
Whoops I accidentally lose it.
There we go.
And then I delete this the input stays open or excuse me the dropdown stays open but with nothing inside
of it.
Which is definitely not appropriate.
So we just need to make sure that we do a little check inside of our code and we say that if we get
back no results at all from our fetch data function we should probably close the dropdown.
So we just spoke about how we open and close the dropdown so that should be pretty straightforward back
up right after we check to see if we are swimming right after we get some data.
Let's take a look at movies.
We're gonna say that if there are no movies whatsoever.
If we didn't fetch any data let's just return early and not run anything else inside of here so I'm
going to say if not movies star link.
So if there are no movies then let's make sure that we close the dropdown.
So going to do a dropdown class list dot remove is Dash active and then we're going to return entirely
from this function.
We don't want to try to render anything or even open the dropdown back up or anything like that.
So that's pretty much it.
Let's do a quick save and a test.
We want to once again search for Avengers and I'll delete it.
In the dropdown goes away All right let's say that's looking pretty good.
So our autocomplete widget is now in a really good state and there's really only one last major interaction
we have to add.
We need to make sure that a user can actually click on a video to select it.
Right now we can click on a video all day but nothing is really happening so let's take a quick pause
and handle that last major interaction in the next video.