There's one last thing I want to do inside of our program right now.
Our analyst program only will print out the current working directory or the files and folders inside
the current folder but the original L S command can print out any arbitrary directory if we pass in
some path as an argument to the command.
So for example I could say get the files up one directory or get the files from my root directory or
the files from my home directory as well.
So I want to update our MLS command and make sure that it can receive some additional arguments that
we pass in some additional argument.
I want to print out the files and folders at that folder instead of our current one.
The first two we have to do is figure out how to receive some arguments into our program when he gets
removed from the command line to do so.
I gonna go back over to my next dot James folder right above.
DIR.
I'm going to add in a console log of process not a R G V like so I'll then save this we'll go back over
and I'm going to run MLS by itself and I do so I'm gonna see a array of strings PRINTED OUT LIKE SO
START RUNNING THAT AGAIN.
BUT NOW I'M GONNA ADD in some I don't know just random string of characters after an L S and now when
I do so I'm going to see that that additional string that I passed in is added as an element inside
this array.
So the process start a r GV array essentially has some information about how our program was executed
and in reality it is command line arguments that are being passed into our program so if we want to
somehow receive a directory that we should be printing out we can take a look at that A.R. GV array
and get the element at index 0 1 to if we have some element at index 2 inside that array.
That means we should take a look at that folder and try to print up some information from it instead
of whatever current directory we are working in okay.
So I'm gonna go back over I'm going to remove that console log and then I'm going to replace it with
a different variable instead I'm going to call it target directory.
Or how about just target dirt to keep it short so then we're going to have this come from process dot
a GV at 2 and then if nothing is provided there.
So if that is an undefined result we get back then instead I'm going to default to process dot current
working directory so if we provide an argument great let's use that.
Otherwise just use the current working directory.
So now we can take that target dir and pass it in as the first argument to reader.
Like so now the code that we have right here is not going to work right correctly.
Nonetheless I want to save this.
I want to run it and just see what happens.
So I'm going to go back over to my terminal.
I'll run any less.
Okay.
Everything still looks good.
Now going to try to print out the files from one directory above my current one if I want to do that
with L S I would say l s dot dot and that's gonna give me everything from up on directory but if I try
to do it with MLS whoa I start to get a really nasty error.
So in this case the error that I see here is no such file or directory l stat d s store.
Well that's a little bit mysterious.
Let's take a pause right here we'll come back in just a moment and figure out exactly why we're seeing
this error message.