Let's start to focus on making sure that we can show a form to a user that they can use to create a
brand new product.
So this is the form that we eventually want to create.
We should have an input to receive the product name the price of the product and we should also have
a button on here that a user can use to upload an image as well.
And of course a button to submit the form so to create this form right here.
We're going to go back over to our editor.
Remember because we want to generate some each team all to show this form.
We're going to create another file inside of our views directory.
This file is going to be responsible for creating all the h t mail related to showing that form.
So inside of my admin directory I'm going to make a new folder called products and then inside there
I'll make a file called new DOT J.S..
The reason I'm calling this new is because we are using it to create a new product then inside of new
J.S. we're going to first require in our layout for the admin pages which is up one directory.
I know that we're going to eventually have a forum.
And because of that we might eventually need to show some validation messages to a user as well.
So I'm also going to get that get error helper method we put together from that helpers file inside
of our route views directory.
So I'll say get error is going to come from up one up to helpers
after that will then do a module that exports we're going to export a function that's going to be called
with possibly some errors object or some object that contains an errors property.
And so once again this is going to be some errors object that is going to have some possible errors
that occurred when we tried to create a given product and instead of here we will return we want to
show some H email inside of our layout and remember our layout function is a function.
So we're gonna call layout we're gonna give it an object that has a content property and that will be
a string and we're gonna put all of our each t Mel to show the form to the user inside of this multi
line string.
Once again remember multi line string.
So you need to have some back tricks on their okay.
So then inside of here let's start to put our form together.
Now let's again just like we did before the first iteration this form is going to have essentially no
styling tied to it at all.
There going gonna be a very simple looking form to show to the user.
Once you put this entire feature together will then come back and apply some styling to it inside of
your old display a form going to make sure that I mark its method as post because we want to make a
post request whenever a user submits this form as opposed to the default behavior which is to make a
get request an inside I'll place an input with a placeholder of title that is the one little bit of
styling that we will do because we're not going have a label in this case.
I'll do a name of title then do another input.
I'll give it a place holder of price and a name of price
we then need some kind of input to receive the image that the user wants to upload to correspond or
represent this particular product they're trying to create in order to allow a user to upload a file.
We can place an input with a type of file and then I'm going to give the thing a name of image.
Now we're gonna go into pretty good detail around what that input right there is really doing and how
to work with a file upload.
So right now we'll just kind of leave this as is.
But we are going to come back and explain much more about what is going on there.
And then finally we need some kind of button to submit this thing.
So I'll just place a button and say submit okay.
So there is our form.
Now we can take this template.
We can go back to the product's root page that we were working on just a moment ago.
We're going to require in this template file and make sure that anytime that someone makes a request
to receive that form we're going to render this template and send it down to them.
So I'll go back to roots admin products dot J.S. and once inside of here at the very top I'm going to
get products new templates or something like that.
I think that that's a reasonable name.
So we're talking about products we're trying to get the template to create a new product.
So products new template.
I think that's pretty reasonable.
Then to require that we're going to have a pretty deeply nested requirement statement here.
It's gonna go up one directory droughts up another to the project directory.
Then I'll go into View's admin products new.
OK so now last step we're going to make sure that whenever a user makes they get requests to admin products
new we tend to show that template right there or produce some e-mail using it and then send that back
down to our user so inside of this request handler will do a red dot sent products new template
and once again we're going to provide just an empty object here.
Eventually when we call product's new template from our post request handler to receive the form submission
we will pass in a possible heirs object inside there but right now we'll just do an empty object.
All right.
So to test this out we're just gonna make sure that we can get some content on the screen.
So going to save this all then go back over to my application I'll go to a local host three thousand
admin products new and there's my form so yeah looks pretty ugly right now but hey it's at least a place
to get started so we're going to eventually enter in our title our price and then select a file using
this thing and then submit it to our back end server.
All right.
So good place to get started.
So let's take a pause right here we'll come back the next video we're going to put together our post
request handler to handle a form submission.
We're going to make sure that we validate these inputs and also start to discuss how we're going to
handle image uploads as well.