Well we've got our information working but there are two big issues with it right now.
Whenever we run the animation it's occurring and it's real.
Kind of like blocks segment.
Second by second so be really nice to have a much smoother animation.
The other big issue is that because we are always subtracting by 50 units for our offset value we're
always going to end up either overshooting or under shooting.
Having the animation finished at the very top point right there.
Let's take a look at this.
I'm going down to nine eight seven.
Ideally the animation would stop right there and even not even really right there because we still have
that little segment visible but the animation to be really correct the entire border should disappear
right when it hits zero.
So again we need to make sure that we somehow get a better subtract subtraction right here than the
negative 50 let's first focus on the animation however.
So let's make sure that we can show a really smooth animation as opposed to the big blocky thing to
make the animation a lot smoother.
We can just choose to run our timer much more frequently so let's take a look at our timer implementation
once again back inside of our timer dot J File.
If you take a look it starts right here.
You'll recall that we are running the tick method once every one seconds or 1000 milliseconds so what
we could do to make our animation a lot smoother is run the tick method way more frequently and every
single time we run the tick method rather than doing the 50 unit update right here.
We could do a really small update like one pixel.
So if we only do one pixel update at a time it will make the animation a lot smoother to make this happen.
Let's go back to timer J us.
We're going to find where we set up our interval and rather than running tick every one seconds will
instead run in every 50 milliseconds that's going to be way more frequent and let's make sure it down
inside of our tick method as well.
Right here where we update the value of time remaining rather than subtracting one second because we're
going to run tick so much more frequently we should instead only subtract point zero five now so that's
a 50 milliseconds and matches up perfectly with the interval timer that we have right there
okay.
Let's now save this.
I'm gonna go back over to my index dot j ust file.
I'm going to find where we've got the 50 and I'm going to change that to one instead.
So now every single time we have a tick I'm going to update the current offset by just one unit or one
pixel I'm going to say this I can go back over refresh and hit start again.
And so now we can very easily see that the animation is a lot smoother but there's another little issue
that's cropped up.
Take a look at the text input right here that shows the current value of the timer.
It definitely has the like seventeen point whatever it looks like it's counting down.
You'll notice that there are a ton of extra nines inside of here.
So how could that be.
We're only ever adjusting the timer by over here.
Point zero five units.
But for some reason we're getting all these extra nines inside there.
Well the reason we're seeing this is because mathematics in Javascript is a very imprecise science all
the subtraction addition multiplication all the stuff that we do uses a system in JavaScript called
floating point operations.
And math inside of JavaScript sometimes gets subject to these really strange rounding errors.
Let me show you a really common.
Very easy to reproduce rounding error inside my console right now.
I'll say one point nine minus one yeah.
Didn't really see that coming.
So of course the results of that should be just point nine.
But because the way javascript handles math and actually to be honest most programming languages handle
math we end up with this really weird results.
And so because of this floating point error that is the same reason that we're seeing something really
funky inside of our input right there as well.
So we can fix this up pretty easily.
We're just going to do a little kind of a rounding operation when we set the value inside that input.
I'm gonna go back over to my Ed. find the timer dot J.S. file and I'll find our setter method for time
remaining at the bottom.
So here's the setter.
So we'd take the current time that has been passed in to time remaining and throw that into the value
or the input value property.
So it's this time variable right here that has all those extra decimal points inside of it.
So it makes everything work out nicely.
We can just call to fixed on this.
That's going to essentially around the decimal under there just two decimal places.
So we're going to drop off all those extra little values that we see inside all the actual decimals
so I'm going to save the update.
Go back over refresh it start again.
That's definitely better.
So now we just see the first two numbers and the first two decimals okay.
So overall I'd say that this was a good fix.
It's not the last big thing we have to do inside of our index not just file subtracting by one right
here.
Still not appropriate.
We need to make sure that we adjust the current offset by some appropriate value so that no matter what
our timer is running for we will always end the animation at 0 seconds perfectly at the very top of
the circle.
So we have to figure out some way of handling that.
Let's take a pause right now and discuss how to do it in the next video.