We've got our forum put together.
So now we're gonna start to focus on validating and sanitizing the inputs that a user provides to us.
We're going to first focus on just sanitization and validation of the title and price and we'll come
back and think about the image in just a little bit.
Firstly I want to remind you is just a moment ago when we put this forum together and created those
two input elements we provided name properties of title in price.
So that means that our poster quest handler that is going to receive this form submission is going to
get some properties called title and price.
So those are the two property names that we're going to want to validate.
We're going to make sure that they are present.
We're gonna make sure that the title is maybe of some particular length of string.
We'll make sure that there is a price we'll make sure that it a number and so on so in order to do all
this validation and sanitization logic will again go to our roots admin validators start J.S. file remember
that is where we are placing all of our different validators so we could easily reuse them throughout
our project if we decided to do so so inside of here we're going to write in our two validators for
title and price will then require them back into our products such as file and validate the incoming
form we previously wrote out our validators directly inside the roots file.
But I think that we've got a good idea of what's going on now.
So we'll just put them directly into this file from the get go okay.
So at the very top of this object I'm going to add in require title so we're going to check out the
title first.
We'll do a check of the title property.
And again remember it is a string of title right here because that is the Name property that we assigned
on that input inside of our form.
Then let's think about all the different validated validations and sanitization so we want to do on
a title well on the title it's gonna be pretty straightforward.
The first thing we'll do is chain on a trim.
Remember trim.
Make sure that there are no leading or trailing spaces which is generally seen as an accidental typo
on behalf of the user.
Next we will do is make sure that a title of a minimum and maximum length has been provided.
So I'll say is length and I'll say that all titles must be at least five characters and at most 40 characters.
So a 40 character title is pretty long if you wanted to obviously you could condense this down to just
like 40 or something.
But I think a 40 character title is fine by me that's pretty much it for the sanitization and the validation
of the title.
So now we can do the price as well so add in a new Kiev require price.
Don't forget the comma at the end of the previous line.
I'll do a check of the price property and then for this one we'll do a trim as well so we'll trim the
price and then to make sure that this thing is a number we're going to call two additional methods we're
gonna say dot to float and dot Is float and two is float going to passing an object with a main property
of one.
So what's going on here.
Well the first thing to keep in mind is that whenever we submit a form no matter what we type into that
form like this input right here no matter what we type in our server is always going to receive this
value as a string.
So even if you and I type in what is clearly a number here that number is going to be wrapped up inside
of a string and that is what our server is going to receive.
So at the end of the day our server always gets a string.
So if you want to interpret this as though it were a number we can call one of two methods right here
either to float or to int to float or to int is going to take that string and extract a number whether
we used to float or two int depends upon the exact nature of the number that we're trying to work with
the term float refers to a number that has a decimal attached to it.
So in other words a number like One two three dot 0 1 0 or whatever else.
So the decimal right here that makes this number a float.
If we do not have a decimal.
So if we have just one two three by itself this is an int or an integer so we can use the sanitizer
right here to say that we either want a number with a decimal or we want a number with an integer if
we call to int and there is a decimal inside that string then the decimal is just going to be left off
and we'll only get everything before the decimal point.
In my case I'm building my e-commerce application to work with U.S. dollars and U.S. dollars has since.
So I can have like ten dollars and one cent so in my case I definitely want to have prices that are
floats.
But if you want to design your product to work with some other type of currency that does not have a
decimal in it like so like no sense or whatever then you might use an integer instead and say like just
1000.
But I think it is if you're from say Thailand or what have you but for me like I said I can go with
a float.
Then the second method I bet you can guess what that does.
That's gonna make sure that we actually have a floating point number.
So it's entirely possible that a user might accidentally type into the price field right here a string
if we did that and then called to float on it.
We would knock get any number out of it but the two float method right here is not going to throw an
error or anything like that.
It's just gonna do its best that it can to actually get a number to actually make sure that we successfully
got a number out of that operation.
We then are going to do a validation step right here and say okay that previous step did we actually
get a number.
And then if we did we're going to make sure that the value is at least 1.
So for my application I'm essentially saying that every product has a minimum price of one dollar.
So that's what's going on with those two lines right there.
It's now that we've got these validators put together let's say this file we're gonna go back to our
product Scott J.S. inside the roots admin directory there it is right there we're going to require in
those two validators we just authored and then wire them up to a new post request handler do we need
to write inside this file to deal with these forms submission at the top I'll first get require title
and require price or require that from the validators file.
Remember it is dot slash validators.
Is that file is inside the same directory as products
then.
Right after our current get request handler I'll put in another one of router post with admin products
new.
So this is the root handler that will deal with the actual form submission.
Remember get is going to retrieve just the forum post is going to be the user trying to submit information
from the form and the second argument will be an array with all the different validators that we want
to run.
So right now we have required title and require price then as a third argument will put in the actual
callback function.
So this will be called with req Andrés and then inside of here right now we'll just send back something
like resort send submitted and to test out our validation.
Let's also do a console dot log.
Remember in order to get all those errors off of the incoming request after it's gone to require title
and require price we have to require into this file that validation result function from the Express
validator library.
Let's go back to Oct J.S. in just review that very quickly.
So inside of J.S. at the very top we've got a require statement right here for a validation result from
Express validator the validation result function is going to take in a request.
So like right here and it's gonna give us back our heirs object.
So then it's up to us to check and see if that heirs object is empty or not.
If it's not empty we're going to want to send back the same form once again with that erase object so
that the template can show all the errors inside their let's make sure we do that really quickly.
Just the validation result part that the top allowed in a require statement for validation results from
Express dash validator
Well then use that function down right here.
Right about the console log.
I'll do a const errors is validation result on the wreck object and then we can do the console log of
errors
okay.
Let's say this and do a quick test it's all flip back over I'm going to just refresh the page really
quickly I'll put in no title and how about no price we'll just start really simple.
Now of course it says submitted because we're not actually do anything with that ear's object just yet
but if we go back over to our terminal Rigo we should see Okay we've got invalid value for title and
we've got an invalid value for the price as well.
So clearly we probably need to customize these error messages which we can certainly do really quickly.
But let's also make sure that if we put in some valid inputs like let's say a title of some sufficient
length and a valid price as well like say 10 0 1 and submit it now I should not see any errors at all.
And if I go back over Yep errors is an empty array okay.
So this is a good start but like we just saw we'd probably need to customize the error messages.
We also need to make sure that we possibly do some validation or otherwise handling of the image that
gets submitted as well.
So let's take care of all that in just a moment.