Next we have to do is to make sure that we adjust our dash offset value by something more precise than
negative one.
So let's take a look at a couple of diagrams and really understand the math that we have to do.
OK.
So here's the general idea when everything first starts are in our side of our information we want our
dash array value of our circle element to be equal to perimeter.
That is what is going to give us that big round circle.
When everything first starts out when the animation ends we still want the dash rate to be equal to
perimeter.
But what's really going to change over time is the dash offset the dash offset.
We'll start out off at zero.
So that's what's going to give us the kind of nice circle right here.
And then over time we want to make it more and more negative as the dash offset gets in more negative.
We're going to get additional whitespace from the top.
Going around the clockwise direction.
So by the end we want to have a dot dash offset equal to negative one times perimeter.
So the real question here becomes how do we start with a dash off set of zero and then effectively over
the span of our entire timer and in very equal increments go from the value of zero to negative parameter
to make that happen.
We're essentially going to say if our perimeter is say a circle of 100 units and we have total 50 different
tic events then each individual tick would need to adjust that offset by negative one times 100 divided
by 50.
That gives us negative 2.
Let me show you a better diagram to really illustrate how this formula works.
So here's the formula that we need.
So we're going to calculate offset.
This is going to be how much we're going to change that stroke dash offset property for every tick.
That's the general formula we can start to plug in the start and end values inside of it to figure out
or and make sure that actually makes sense.
So our offset at the very start would be P times the time remaining which would for us be 30 seconds
divided by the total duration.
Which would also be 30 seconds and then we would subtract by the perimeter the 30 divided by 30 would
turn into one.
So we'd end up with P minus p and so offset at the very start would be equal to zero and so that matches
up with our initial requirement over here then at the very end our dash offset is equal to zero or that's
simply our dash offset.
We want to be equal to a negative perimeter.
So at the very end we're gonna have a time remaining of zero divided by 30.
So we get zero divide by 30.
That's going to end up zeroing out and we are left with just negative P and that once again matches
up with what we just discussed over here this is pretty much the formula that we have to increment or
implement inside of our on tick function.
There's just one problem with it are on tick function doesn't really have any idea of how much time
is remaining or the total duration.
That's not a big problem.
Kind of let me show you a real small change that we can make to our code to make sure that the on tick
function that we have.
So this function right here can get access to the time remaining if you want to do that we could go
back over to timer J.S. I'm going to find my tick function here is right here inside there I'll find
where we call on tick and inside of it when we call on tick I will simply pass in this dark time remaining.
So now back inside of our index dot j ust file on tick is going to receive the time remaining so that's
not bad.
So we now have one of these values inside of our formula that we need to determine what the offset should
be at each tick.
Now there is a second problem here and that is the total duration value we need to know the entire duration
of the timer.
So if we set it for 30 seconds and Head Start we need to know that starting time right now there is
absolutely nothing inside of application to track that value.
In other words there's no input there's no value inside of our timer class nothing that tracks the total
duration of the timer but by using one that callbacks we implemented we can start to track it ourselves.
So we're gonna say that whenever we call on starts we're going to pass in an argument that represents
how much time is going to take for this entire timer to run will then receive that argument right here
and store it.
So then later on INSIDE OF on tick we can use that value to figure out what the total duration is going
to be let's write out some code because I know this is confusing.
Let's write out some code you're going to see where we got this really quickly.
So I'm gonna go back over to my timer I'm going to find where we call on starts which is inside these
start function.
And when we call it I'm going to pass in the value of this time remaining.
So when we first start our timer this time remaining that value is gonna be how long the timer is going
to run.
In total so in on starts we can receive that as an argument that I will referred to as total duration
so then it's back over here rather than storing something like current offset right there and going
to delete that and I'm going to make a new variable called simply duration and it will set the value
to toll duration whenever the OnStar function is called so we'll say duration is total duration so then
finally inside of on tick we can actually implement the correct offset when we update the stroke dash
offset so we no longer have to make a change over time.
So I'm gonna delete that line instead at every tick we're going to take the time remaining.
We're going to take the total duration and we're going to take our perimeter and we'll use it to figure
out exactly what the offset value should be.
So going to delete current offset right there I'm going to give myself a little bit of space and we'll
write in our form formula.
So remember right above we already defined our perimeter so we'll say perimeter times time remaining
divided by the duration and we'll subtract from that the perimeter and that's it.
Now I know this like explanation of all the math is really nasty but when really comes down to it this
is what's really going on.
It's going to save this and we can do one last test.
We can make sure I save both files of course put back over it starts and now we can see the timer working
as expected either way.
The animation is always going to play a little more smoothly if you close your console so closer.
Chrome console if it seems like it's a little bit laggy now we can wait for this to count down all the
way to zero.
And when it hits zero we should see the animation finishing like right there at the very top end points.
So nine eight seven.
Well you can count.
So I'm going to wait for this thing to finish up and make sure that it finishes at the correct location
and there we go.
So by the time I hit zero we have cleared out that entire circle perfectly every time.
Now of course I can always update the timer to say three seconds head start and it's going to play it
again OK.
Well let's say this looks pretty good.
Now the only thing that we might change here when I use three you'll notice it still looks a little
bit choppy.
So if you want to you can always go back over and adjust the interval that we do this update at.
So instead of 50 right here we can always take it down to say 20.
But if you update it right there Just make sure that you update how much we change time remaining by
for every tick.
So if we take that to 20 we would want to subtract point 0 2 from time remaining.
So I'll save this I'll refresh.
I'll try again with three seconds.
Yeah that definitely looks a little bit more smooth OK.
Well this looks pretty good overall.
So now the last thing I do is just a little bit of styling to make sure that the input the start and
pause button all that stuff shows up inside of the circle.
So let's take care of some styling in just a moment.