Now that we've done all these calculations for the horizontals array we can repeat that same process
for verticals.
So we're going to essentially do the same exact thing we did in the last video but we'll do it way faster.
Since we now understand essentially what we're trying to accomplish here.
So underneath the horizontals for each I'll add in a verticals for each then inside of here.
Once again we're going to receive each row and we'll get a row index then inside of here we'll do a
row for each and on the row for each.
We're going to receive the Boolean value which will again refer to as open and we get the column index
so we're currently operating on as well then inside we can say if open is true then return right away
otherwise we want to create a wall segment.
So once again we'll do const wall is bodies dot rectangle so all we really have to figure out is the
different arguments to pass to bodies dot rectangle this time around the math is going to be just a
little bit different because we are operating on a different direction.
So let's once again go take a look at diagram and figure out how to calculate the center point to the
x and y coordinates for each wall segment in the vertical direction.
Okay.
So here we are again.
I'm going to imagine some data for my verticals array so in this case I'm going to have three rows and
two columns and I'll remind you why in just a moment.
So in this case I'm going to throw in some imaginary data here I'll do.
True and False false and true and true and false so we have the three rows in this case because we're
talking about that set of all segments that set and that set.
So essentially this this this this this and this and then we've got two columns because there's only
two lines of those segments on here so if we consider the different TRUE and FALSE values inside of
this array I'm going to a race wherever we have a true value so we want that to be open.
So no wall there.
We want that to be open.
No wall and we want that to be open as well.
So once again let's imagine how we're going to calculate the x and y central points for each of these
different segments.
Well first start with this one on the top right hand side.
And we essentially want to get the x and y coordinates of that X right there.
Coming from our top left origin point at 0 1 0.
So we need to determine that distance right there and that distance right there this time around I'm
going to basically give you the formulas as opposed to trying to demonstrate exactly how they get calculated.
They'll save us a lot of time.
Essentially the same thing as last video we just need to calculate that center point right there as
a function of the arrow and column that we are currently operating on.
And the unit length as well so for the x direction that x component right there we're going to have
our column
index times unit length
plus the unit
let's try out the math for this.
So in this case we have a column index of 0 than one.
So our column index is 1 times 200.
That is our unit length plus 200.
And that is 400.
That's definitely what this should be.
Because remember we're essentially saying go over cell one cell 2 and then right there.
So each cell is two hundred units.
So we get two hundred and 200 over and that takes us to right there.
So 400 definitely correct.
We can repeat that for this next segment down here.
That would be a column index of 0 times 200 was 200 is 200.
Yep that definitely looks right to me.
And then the last one down here on the bottom right is actually going to be identical to that first
calculation.
They'll be the one times 200 plus two hundred equals 400 OK.
So that definitely solves this in the x direction.
So now we get to repeat this same process but in the vertical direction instead they'll do some erasing.
I'm going to again try to find that segment right there.
Well let me just redraw some the stuff just so we can get some actual clarity in this diagram
like so like so and like so now we'll find the y component of that element right there.
So just eyeballing this it's essentially going to be we're going down half the length of one cell.
So I'm going to expect this to be about 100 units.
So the formula for this will be our row index
times the unit length
plus unit length divided by two.
Now we can easily plug in some numbers to verify that that is the case.
So right here are row index is currently zero.
I'll throw those on right now.
So we get zero times 200 plus 200 over two which gives us the 100 that I definitely expected.
Then this one right here we're talking about going half of one cell plus the full length of another
cell.
So again just kind of guessing I'm going to say it's probably supposed to be three hundred.
Let's throw the numbers in.
So now I have a row index of 1 times 200 plus 200 over to yep there's my three hundred.
And then finally for this one right here I have two full cell lengths was half a selling so that will
be hopefully around 500 in this case by row and indexed as to so do two times two hundred plus two hundred
over two and yep that is the full five hundred all right.
That's it.
So we have to now add in that formula and the one we saw just a moment ago where the x and y positions
it's going to go back over to my editor.
We'll do a column index times unit length plus unit length and we'll do a row index times unit length
plus unit length divided by two.
And I got a little typo here.
I'm going to fix.
And then finally we need to provide the width of a wall in the height of a wall.
So remember the third argument is going to be how wide the wall is in the x direction.
So now we're talking about like if we have a really wide wall that looks like that right there.
What is this x direction.
So we'll once again use some like arbitrary kind of small number to give ourselves a thin wall and then
the height of the wall which is the fourth argument is going to be a unit length.
So that's gonna be like a full 200 so as the third argument I'll do a wall width of whatever we had
before.
Looks like he was 10
and the height is going to be the full unit length then finally as the last argument we'll throw on
that same is static flag.
And then finally underneath the wall we'll do a world dot add to our world object.
And I want to add the while we just created OK so that's a lot of code.
Let's say this once again put back over refresh and there we go.
Here's our maze so we can refresh a whole bunch and we'll see all the different bases that we create
in every scenario we should have like a solid continuous path we should to visit every single cell and
there should never be a blockage of any kind.
And as I refresh the whole bunch indefinite definite looks like that's the case now I know doing these
formulas in the last two videos was really tedious but the benefit to taking this approach is we've
now got this kind of configurable calculation going on there are very few static numbers inside of here
besides the wall with all eventually abstract that out.
So that means that in order to drastically change our maze we can just manipulate these values right
here.
So for example if I want to have a maze that is five cells wide five cells tall I can change cells to
five and then everything else inside this file should automatically update appropriately.
Now I can refresh and now I've got one cell to cell three cell for cell five and something in the vertical
direction as well.
And we can start to really play around with that number a lot more so I can go up to say 10 to make
a much more detailed maze.
There definitely is a limit to the number of cells you can have practically I think that it's going
to max out around 100 or so.
I do 100 OK maybe slightly over 100 since we're doing some recursion we're going to eventually exceed
the maximum call stack size which means we are doing too much recursion.
We could see that once we have way too many cells.
Well the maze is basically unusable anyways so it's not really that big a difference.
Let's try like cells 50.
OK.
That's a little bit too much.
About 30.
That's a little bit not quite useful but we could very easily make it usable by adjusting our wall size.
So that is the 10 right here in the horizontals and the 10 inside the verticals as well.
So we can change those to like about five to five right there in five right there.
Save refresh and now it looks a bit more like a maze than it did before.
So this is great.
We've basically got a proof of concept for our maze.
I am going to take it back to cells of three because that's really nice for testing purposes.
It looks like everything is pretty much working as we expect.
So pretty much the last thing we have to add in here is the ball that the user is going to control.
We need to add in the success area down here at the bottom right hand side and then make sure that we
can control the ball with some keyboard controls.
So quick pause right here and we'll continue in the next video.