Now that our timer is working pretty well we need to apply a little bit of styling.
Just make sure that everything shows up inside the actual timer.
The first thing I want to do is replace the start and pause buttons with the icons for like pause and
or start and pause right there so to show those icons.
We're going to use a free icon library called font awesome.
I'm going to open up a new browser tab and navigate to font awesome dot com.
This is a free resource that we can use to show tons of different icons inside of application.
The first thing we have to do is wire up this library to our app to do so we're going to open up one
other page.
I'm going to go to C.D. J.S. dot.com once here.
We can search for font awesome and we'll see a link right here.
So notice that this is a CSX file.
That's how we make use of fun awesome inside of our project.
We're going to hook it up as a CSX file.
So going to copy that link will then go back over to our HCM l document.
Here it is right here.
I'll go to my head and I'm going to add in a link tag.
So I'll say link.
We're going to use a rail of style seats and then an H riff and we can paste in that link that we just
copied
okay.
So now that we've wired up font awesome we can take a look at the fun awesome documentation and figure
out which icon we want to show so I'll go back over to the font.
Awesome documentation on the top left hand side is a little search box.
So when you first get sort of icons of course you're probably going not going to know exactly what the
name of any icon is.
So it's really up to you to just kind of take a guess.
When I look at these icons the words that come to my mind are play for that right there.
It's like a play icon and pause.
So I'm going to take a guess and I'm going to search for play when I search for play we're going to
eventually see some results.
Here we go.
So these are all the different icons that match that search string.
Looks like that one right there looks pretty good.
So I click on that one to figure out how to use it sometimes sometimes font awesome Web site is a really
slow.
So I'm going to give this a second to load up.
Hopefully it resolves quickly.
OK.
Very good.
So now you actually make use of this icon you'll see right underneath play is a little eye tag right
there.
So that's the e-mail that we're going to show in order to show that icon.
So I clicked that thing to copy it.
I'll go back over to my HMO document.
I'm going to find my button that says start I'll delete the text it says Start and replace it with that
I tag so I can save this.
Go back over to my browser refresh and I'll see the play button right there OK.
So that's definitely good.
So it could definitely repeat the same process to get the pause icon as well.
It's all search for pause wait another couple seconds to for it to load.
Yep.
That devil looks good.
So click at
and click on the eye tag again.
I'll go back over to my e-mail document find where we have paws inside the button.
I'll delete it and replace it with the dog as well.
Yes I'll say this the second time refresh.
OK.
Well that looks pretty good.
All right.
So for the rest of the styling I'll be honest with you it's really just a bunch of CSI s and whatnot
that we're going to throw into our anal document.
We're going to take a quick pause right here in the next video attached to the video.
You're going to find a zip file inside that zip file is going to be an HMO document and SPSS file.
Make sure you download that zip file.
It's going to be called something like timer 0 2 5 templates or something like that.
So make sure you download that zip file and find the HDL and CSF file inside it.
So make sure you grab that and we'll start to integrate that or merchant into our project in just a
moment.