All right let's keep writing out some HCM L to show all the stats underneath this movie.
It's a back inside my coat.
I'll find the movie template function.
We will go down to the bottom and we're going to add in just a little bit more each female here.
So after the closing article element I'm going to place another article I'm going to give it a class
of notification and then a space is Dash.
Primary and then close off the article and inside of here I'll do a paragraph tag with the class of
title was it off and inside there we're going to reference movie detail dot awards.
So this is going to be a string summary of all of the different awards that this movie has won.
We'll see exactly what it looks like in the dorm and just a second after that.
I'm going to put in essentially a label for this statistic.
So I'll do another paragraph element with the class of sub title and inside of there I'll say simply
a words like so OK.
So this right here this article element we're going to essentially duplicate this down several times
and inside of every duplicated version we're going to be referencing a different property off of movie
detail and b giving each them a different label as well.
So I'm going to take this article element.
I'm going to copy it and I'm going to copy it down four times.
So here's one to read and for now we'll go through each of these and update some the different properties.
I'm going to go up find the first one I'll go to the second one and I'm gonna change the second one
from awards right there to box office I'll change the label right underneath that to box office as well.
Next up I'll go to number three.
I'm going to change that one to awards to medal score I'll change the label to Metta score.
So again this is like a rating essentially of the movie the next one.
So a second last one I am D.B. rating.
Notice how in this case I has a lower case as opposed to all the other property names that start with
the capital a label will be I am DV rating.
So this is the rating of the movie according to the website.
I am D.B. and finally on the last one will change it to.
I am D.B. boats and I am D.B. boats.
That's the number of votes that this movie has gotten on.
I am DV By different users of that platform.
That's pretty much it.
Let's save this.
We've got five different properties here.
Like I said a couple added beyond just the two that we had mentioned over here back in our original
mockup.
I'll save that file.
I will refresh a look for Avengers like it.
And there we go.
Now I see the Avengers.
I see the awards that this movie has won box office take metal score the rating on I am DV in the number
of votes that the movie has gotten on I am DV as well.
That's pretty much it.
That's like stage 1 of our application.
We now have the ability to search for a movie.
We've got some autocomplete functionality in there.
Once the user selects the movie we show a lot of information about it on the screen.
So now we essentially just have to do a lot of duplicate work.
We essentially need to duplicate everything we just did and show a second auto complete on the right
hand side of the screen and then once we have all the same functionality for that auto well then just
need to make sure that when we search for two different movies we compare all the different statistics
and highlight the higher ones in each category.
That's some pretty good progress.
Let's take a pause right here and start on this next phase in the next video.