At the end of the last video we discussed how the phase one of our application is pretty much complete
user can search for something see some statistics so normally we would now move on to Phase 2 where
we would show a second autocomplete on the right hand side.
Allow a user to do another search and then compare some statistics between the two movies.
But before we do we're going to take a look at our current code base.
It turns out that the code that we've written so far has some kind of serious issues inside of it.
So I want to take a look at the code you've written so far.
I want to point out some really big issues with our current implementation and I want to figure out
some ways that we could fix that stuff before we move on to Phase 2 of our app.
So in other words we're going to start to do some really big re factors and the goal of these three
factors is to help you get an idea of how to write some more reusable code naturally at the start of
this application.
I could have just shown you the right way to build this application from start to finish.
I think that you can learn a lot more effectively to see kind of the wrong way so to speak to build
out an application which is kind of what we've done so far and then see a better way to write it.
Now don't think that everything we've written so far is awful.
Don't get me wrong.
The code we've written so far is 100 percent ok and if you went to some job or like an interview or
your first junior position as a javascript engineer and you wrote code like what we've done so far this
would 100 percent be OK.
There's not anything that's like inherently wrong with a code that we have.
I just want to show you some quick changes we can make to our code base to make it even better than
it currently is.
And it's all themed around making our code more reusable so that in mind.
Well let's take a look at some issues inside of our current code base.
So here's the current overwhelming issue with just about everything inside of our project so far.
I would say that just about all of our code touches everything.
In other words just about every function every block of code everything kind of reaches around to other
variables inside the file and other functions inside the file.
Let me give you some practical examples of this.
Mostly focused around the autocomplete widget and you're going to get a better sense of right now how
our code is just reaching around referencing a ton of different variables all over the place.
So a good example of that is the autocomplete widget.
Remember the autocomplete widget was supposed to be reusable.
We spoke a little bit ago about how putting a bunch of HCM l inside of our each HTML document would
lead to making it more challenging to reuse the autocomplete logic over time because if we ever wanted
to reuse all this autocomplete stuff on another project we would not only have to copy over a bunch
of javascript code we would also have to copy over some each team email inside of our HCM documents.
In other words if we had all the autocomplete H.M. inside each HTML document we had that really strong
coupling between those two files.
Again it just made it more challenging to use so as we start to think about how to make the autocomplete
widget actually reusable it's going to involve the process of making sure that the code inside there
doesn't touch everything.
Again let me give you some practical examples of this.
The first way in which our autocomplete and all see me first way in which the autocomplete widget kind
of touches everything is that it has knowledge of exactly what a movie object is.
So let's go back over to our code base and let me show you that inside of the on input function right
now.
We have a for loop right here and inside that for loop we have a couple of different lines of code that
take a look at that movie object right there.
And in doing so specifically on line 43 it is very clear that the current implementation of our autocomplete
stuff knows exactly what different properties a movie object has.
So on this line of code it's clear that the autocomplete stuff knows that a movie object has a poster
Prop. the autocomplete logic is going to behave very differently based on the presence and value of
that poster property.
So I would say that if we consider all of our autocomplete stuff right now like everything from Conte's
root right there all the way down to our ad event listener right there for the document.
If we look at just this code block we would say that this autocomplete widget knows exactly about the
structure of data that is working with it.
Why is that bad.
Well it's very simple.
Again imagine that you wanted to reuse all this code on another project.
And let's imagine for just a second that maybe you did not want to try to have to like go into all this
code right here and change a bunch of different variables or property names in order to get this code
to work on another project.
So let's imagine that in a perfect world we could just copy paste all the stuff reuse it right away
if that were the case then.
Well having these direct references to properties inside the movie object would not be good at all because
maybe our other project doesn't work with movie objects maybe instead it works with say like recipes.
A recipe probably would not have a poster property instead.
Maybe a recipe object like a cooking recipe would have some property called like I don't know recipe
image or something so if I wanted to reuse all this code on that other project I would have to go through
it first and update all these property references that sign.
Number one that we don't have reusable code just yet.
The next instance of this is that our autocomplete has knowledge of exactly what to show for each option.
So again inside of our for loop right here we are setting the inner each team El on option.
So this right here this image that we're placing and the titled The movie once again means that our
autocomplete code has perfect knowledge and perhaps too much knowledge of what to render or what to
display for every option.
Maybe once again if we were searching for recipes on some other project maybe we don't have any images
to show at all and maybe we would not want to show that image element.
Instead we would want to show something just like recipe dot name or something.
So if that were the case again we would have to come into all this code.
We would have to find where we set the inner city for the option and we would have to update that stuff
right there.
So that again is another sign that our code is not reusable in order to change the way in which each
option looks.
We have to modify the source code of our widget.
Finally the autocomplete stuff has knowledge of what to do when a movie is clicked.
So again if we go back over take a look at the four of loop take a look at the click event listener
that we set up on each option you have a direct reference right here to some function called on movie
select again for the third time.
Imagine we took all this code and moved it to a new project.
This code would not work correctly if we did not have a function inside our file called on movie select.
So again if you were working with recipes we would have to go into the source code.
We would have to find that function call and change it to en recipe select or something and then we
would have to have some function inside this file called on recipes select if we moved all this code
to another new project after that that worked with maybe I don't know blog posts we would have to change
this to you on blog post select.
So again the overriding point here at the point I'm trying to make is that if we wanted to reuse all
this autocomplete stuff on any other project we would have to copy paste all the code and then go around
to all these different lines and update each one of them to work with this new kind of resource that
we wanted to use the autocomplete with the other big issue with our code right now and specifically
around the autocomplete as well is that we have have many different global variables that are referring
to specific elements.
Now the reason this is a big problem is that it's going to be really really hard right now to show a
second autocomplete on the screen so let me show you why that is the case.
If we go back up to the top of all of our autocomplete code so about right here.
Remember we have a query selector for some element with a class of autocomplete and then just about
everything else inside this file.
After this is working with this root element we have many references back to the root variable.
So what would we do now if we wanted to show a second autocomplete on the screen.
Well to be honest we would probably going to zoom out for this just so you can see this little refactoring
about to do don't make any changes.
I'm just gonna give you a very quick example here in order to show the second autocomplete we would
have to take all this autocomplete related code just about all of it.
I think all the way down to like right here or so you'd have to copy all this but another code section
here for like autocomplete number to do a duplicate all that stuff and then go through here in autocomplete
Number Two Section and update all these references so that the variable names wouldn't conflict with
the earlier autocomplete that we defined.
So for example for autocomplete Number two I would have to do a query selector for a totally different
element like autocomplete Dash 2 or something and then because I have all these variables that are inside
of the same scope I would have to change route right here to like Route 2 and Route 2 dot inter H L
and then for these variables right here.
Again they're defined earlier up inside the file so we'd have to do input to dropdown to results wrapper
too and then repeat the entire same process with all the other variables inside of here.
And so I bet you can imagine really quickly that this is a really really bad way to approach this problem.
And there's got to be some better way to tackle this than having to duplicate all the code and then
just arbitrarily change all the variable names in order to just show a second autocomplete okay.
I'm gonna delete that copy paste I just did very quickly and go back to what I had before and there
we go.
Okay.
So again that is the big issues with our current implementation.
It's essentially all revolving around our current autocomplete widget.
It is not at all reusable.
And the reasons for that is that it knows exactly what properties a movie has.
Which means we can't reuse this with a different kind of resource it knows exactly what to show for
each option which means well if we ever want to change that representation we would have to mess around
with the internal source code of the autocomplete the autocomplete knows exactly what function to call
whenever a movie is clicked.
And that means again that our source code would have to have a function called on movie select or something
similar.
And then finally if we ever want to show multiple instances of that autocomplete Well we would have
to duplicate all that code and change a bunch of different variable names so that is the big issues
with our project right now.
Now I want to repeat one more time that the code rewritten is not the worst in the world and we did
not just waste like an hour of our time putting together the first implementation this project.
I am just suggesting that perhaps there is a better way even better than what we've written out so far.
So with all this in mind now we understand what is wrong with our project.
We're going to start to refactor all this stuff in some very significant ways so quick pause right here
and come back the next video and discussed how we can essentially solve all these issues in some really
nice fashion.
So I'll see you in just a minute.