All right.
So in the last video we saw that we could add an event listener by using an on click or on some attribute
in line which I said I'm not a fan of because I don't like writing javascript in a string in our HMO.
And then we also saw that we could do it in our javascript by selecting an element I'll call it El.
I haven't actually selected it.
And then setting the on click property or the on mouse over or on Double Click property whatever the
name of the property is on something.
And I also mentioned this is not great in my opinion either but I didn't go into a ton of detail why
I'm going to show you quickly why it's not great and then we'll see the alternative which is called
Ad event listener.
So if we add in something to select a simple button we'll do a button click me and then select it over
here so document that query selector button save it to a variable.
And I set the on click to be some function nice and simple will console that log you click me.
All right.
So this is review.
It should work.
And thus I mess up any syntax here.
Let's refresh the page and it does work.
Now if I wanted to have a second quick listener I don't have that option with what we've seen with on
click.
It's a single property just like if we have some object constant thing equals this object.
If I set thing dot color equal to purple if I'd try and change thing dot color instead of equal to some
other it could be a function.
It doesn't matter.
Only the most recent value is there.
I don't have purple anymore.
It's a property and we're doing the same thing here.
So if I were to add a another click listener button on quick equals function this time will console
dot log.
Second time let's try it all we get is second time I'm not getting the first event listener or this
function is not running because we overrode that property.
Now it seems stupid to do two different council dot logs based off of a click but there are times when
you might want different listeners or multiple functions to run on a given event.
Sometimes you want them to run dynamically so you may not have both of these functions running every
single time something is clicked.
But you could have it turned on and off if that makes sense.
So it's possible you could have more than one handler running for a given event.
Now that doesn't work with the two options we've seen but we have a third option which I've been hinting
at a lot.
It's called Ad event listener.
Now our event listener is great because for one thing it's one method and it will attach any type of
event listener you want to click a double click.
What do you call him mouse wheel scroll.
That's not the official term a drag a mouse over any of them.
A prince before Prince for some reason you needed that event and also it will attach as many as we want
to a given element.
So if we want to use it we select our element and then we call the add event listener method.
We have it on all elements that we can select.
So I have my button I've selected I call button does add event listener and if I hover but there's over
100 different options here you can see it.
It's been condensed.
It says 81 more or 91 more.
So what I can do is pass in one of those event names.
Now I don't pass in on click I pass in click and instead of on mouse over I would pass in mouse over
as a string.
So let's do a quick start there and then I have a second argument which is a function and this function
will execute when this event occurs.
So I'll do an alert clicked and save.
Let's check it out.
I click the button and we get our alert.
I could add a second event listener if I wanted to to the exact same button.
Also listening for a click and all console that log.
Second thing let's see what happens.
So we get our alert and I get second thing printed out.
So what we're doing here is not setting the on click property.
If we actually look at a button over here button dot on click it's not set to anything.
We are attaching an event listener which we can have multiple of for a given event on a given element.
So I could attach as many as I want.
It's probably uncommon to do that at least to do multiple clicks.
So let's try a different type of event.
How about a Mm.
What should we do a mouse over so button Dot had event listener mouse over again not on mouse over which
is the name of the property we could set but mouse over and a function and you can do an error function
although I'll show you times or a situation where you wouldn't want to use an error function.
It has to do with the keyword this but we're not there yet when this happens.
Why don't we change the inter text of the button so button dot in our text equals stop touching me and
save zoom in for you.
There we go.
Now as soon as I leave it still stays because I'm just listening for the mouse over and I'm permanently
changing the inner text.
Fortunately we have a another event we could attach which is a mouse out so mouse out and I'll change
the text back to what did we have originally we had click me originally.
So I'll do that here.
Click me and save.
Let's see if it works.
I hover.
Stop touching me.
Back to click me.
Back to click me if I click it.
We get our first click function running.
And the second one runs as well.
At event listener is our Swiss Army knife for events.
We don't have to set individual properties.
We don't do it in line.
Instead we can just use the exact same method but we pass in the type of event we want.
We can have multiple of the exact same event on one element and then we give a callback function.
This function will run when this event occurs on this button.
So I've got a mouse over a mouse out a click a second click.
Why don't we try one more something that is a little different.
Not a mouse event so not a click or a mouse over mouse out.
Let's try a scroll event when we work with scrolls.
We have a couple of options as far as where we attach the event to.
We can listen for a scroll on the entire window.
So that would be you know a scroll bar over here.
I don't actually have enough content to scroll so I could quickly rectify that by adding a ton of H
ones and if I now do it I do have a scroll bar on the right side.
We could also listen for scrolls within a single element.
So if you had like a text box that was very large or an eye frame or some element that you could scroll
inside of then you could add a scroll event to that.
But I'll do it on the entire window.
I'll also move my button to the top so that it's easier if you are just coming to this code and trying
to figure out what the heck's going on.
So to add a scroll event to the window I have access to the window I just open up the dev tools.
I can just type window so the global scope of the global object in the browser and JavaScript window
dot add event listener and the event is scroll and then I'll add a function.
And in here why don't we just cancel that log stop scrolling
same exact pattern.
Select something.
Or in our case with window we don't have to select it.
We already have window available and then Dot had event listener.
What kind of event what to do in the event of a scroll on the window.
So we will refresh and I'm going to scroll.
There we go.
So you probably noticed how many times this is printing out one of the most common things to do with
scrolls is to do something called throttling.
You may not want to run this function every single time you know the scroll event happens.
It will fire if you just change your scroll position by like a single pixel.
Usually what I've seen at least is there's some position you want to scroll past and that will trigger
something maybe an animation if you get down to the bottom of the page something will happen but you
normally don't want something to happen like 100 or 300 times in the course of scrolling from the top
to the bottom of the page but that's beyond what we're talking about here.
All we need to know is that we can use an event listener to attach all sorts of different events you
pass in the event name and a function to be called and that function will run when the event occurs
on that given element on the window on a button.
And also remember not only is this nicer to write in my opinion one method but we can also listen for
multiple events of the same type on one element versus with our old fashioned on click either in line
or through javascript.
We don't have that flexibility.
So our event listener is your go to way of adding events definitely five out of five stars recommended.