We just had a really long discussion about file submission inside of our form.
So the net result of all that discussion was essentially inside of our index J jazz file the body password
that we're using right now is not sufficient to actually reach into the request and pull out the image
that we're trying to upload.
That's all because the body parser only cares about your URL encoded post requests.
So how we gonna fix this up.
Well let's go take a look at the documentation for body parser itself.
The body parser library I've pulled up the documentation.
You don't have to pull it up there's really just one very specific thing I want to show you inside of
here.
So inside the body parts documentation says very specifically this module does not handle multipart
requests.
So instead they recommend using one these other little libraries so instead of using body parser to
handle this file submission we're going to instead use another little library called melter.
So I gonna click on that.
We'll take a look at the documentation if you want to find the documentation yourself.
You can go to NPM J ask.com and search for multi-year
inside of here.
It's a pretty straightforward and easy middleware to use.
We're going to first install it after that.
We're going to find the post request handler that is going to handle this form submission that contains
the actual file upload.
And then as a middleware inside there we're going to call upload a dot single and then the name of the
image that we expect to come in.
When I say name a domain name of the image I mean the name of the actual file or the field inside the
request.
So for us if we take a look at our template once again our file input right here has a name of image.
So we're going to call upload dot single and we're gonna pass in a string right there of simply image.
Again that's going to say look in the form find the input with the name of image.
Take that data and give that to us as a file so then inside of our callback function the wrecked dot
file property is going to be the actual file that we want to save and the wrecked out body property
will continue to hold all the different text fields or all the different text inputs such as the title
and price that we're used to working with.
Anyways the other thing to be aware of is that when we make use of motor it wants to save the file to
some specific location inside of our project.
So in other words when it receives this file there is the possibility that we might be getting a really
large file upload for us re handling images that might be kind of small in nature but we might eventually
start to receive files that are like tens of megabytes or hundreds or even gigabytes large.
It's a multi-year wants to have some location to actually store this file as it's being uploaded to
our server and then hold onto it essentially as we are waiting to do something with it inside of our
request handler.
We're gonna have a longer discussion about what all that means in just a moment.
So for right now let's just add in the code to install multi-year make use of it inside of our post
request handler and just get a handle on the file itself and we'll talk about what this kind of destination
stuff is really talking about okay.
So to get started going to first go back over to my terminal I'm going to stop my running server with
a command C and I'll do a npm install melter I'll let that do its thing really quickly and then I'll
start my server back up with NPM run def.
It looks good.
So going to go back over to my root handler inside the product start j ust file I'm gonna go to the
very top of the file and right after our require statement for Express validator I'm going to add in
a required statement for Mr..
Now one thing about a mention on the side here knows the kind of structure that we have inside of Oliver
require statements inside this file.
I have grouped together all the require statements that are getting something from an external library
and I've also kind of grouped together the require statements that are getting access to a file that
you and I authored and then only after all those are you gonna start declaring different variables and
working around with these variables so in other words I'm going to do might require a statement from
vulture up here but then only right after where we create the router am I going to do what the documentation
says which is to create that kind of upload variable right there where we actually make use of Walter
it's a right after we create our router.
I'll say const upload is molten we're gonna pass in an options object inside of here we're going to
say storage is multi-year dot memory storage.
As I mentioned just a moment ago we're gonna have a deeper dive on what the storage stuff is really
talking about.
But right now just bear with me in saying memory storage okay.
Now upload is a middleware function we can make use of inside of our post request handler so I'll go
down to right here and then right after our array of validators I'll put in an additional argument here.
I'm going to put in that upload variable.
Let's say this.
I forgot one thing.
We have to call upload dot singlet and with the name of the file.
My mistake.
So upload dot single and the name of our or the field name is image.
Okay.
That's it.
So now inside of our post request handler I'm going to delete the record on stuff that was just to show
you where this actual information was from and then to actually get access to our file.
We'll do a console log of simply erect file and we'll see what we eventually are working with.
Okay.
Now let's save this I can go back over to my browser I can go back to the form I'll refresh put in a
title and a price and then I'll upload any old image this time I'll do submit and then go back over
to my terminal and see what I get and there we go.
Here's an object that represents the actual file that just got uploaded.
So we've got the field name.
That's what it was inside the forum.
We've got the name of the file itself.
The encoding the type of image that it is.
In this case I uploaded a PMG and then we have this buffer.
Remember we've said several times that buffers are essentially arrays that have some raw data inside
of it.
In this case you'll notice that says here one hundred and seventeen thousand more bytes.
You might recall I mentioned that the size of this coat image that I'm working with is 117 kilobytes
which is one hundred seventeen thousand bytes.
More or less.
So this buffer right here contains the very raw information out of my file so that essentially is the
information that we want to somehow store.
So we can eventually show an associate an image with every product at some point in time.
The future is looking good.
We clearly have access to the file now.
It's now the last part of all this discussion.
We need to have is.
Well we've got the file.
Now what do we do with it.
So that's kind of part of the discussion around this storage property right here.
So let's take a quick pause.
We're going to come back on the next video.
Now I want to give you kind of a broader overview of how it image upload really works in general in
a professional style application and how we're going to do it in our application as well.