Next up let's talk about function arguments arguments is really a fancy term for inputs to a function.
And right now our functions don't expect they don't accept any inputs they behave the same way every
time.
So we wrote that silly Grumps function and this is kind of what happens here visually at least if this
is the function we don't pass any inputs and we just call Grumps the exact same way every time and we
get the same output those three console dot logs.
Now I didn't write them here because they took up too much space.
So we get this little grumpy kid instead.
But it's the same output every time the same three lines that are printed.
Here's another example.
A function that I'm calling green just type it up very quickly and all it does is console dot log Hi
every single time.
If I run it and I call greed we can't impact it we don't pass anything in it works the same way no inputs.
Same output.
Now this doesn't necessarily mean we'll always get the exact same output as we saw with our roll die
function.
We did get a different output because we're using random numbers but we're not altering the behavior
when we call it we call roll died the exact same way every single time.
We're not impacting it we're just saying roll the dice and it picks random number but it would be nice
if we could specify if this was a six sided die or a 12 sided die or something like that and we would
do that by passing in an argument.
So those inputs that we pass in as I've already mentioned are called arguments.
Here's an example of an updated version of Grete where we could pass in a value for someone's name.
So if we call greet and then we pass in Tim the output could be Hi Tim.
If we did it with honor we could get the output of high honor still very simple stuff.
Here's another example a hypothetical function called average and it takes multiple arguments two or
four maybe ten and the output will be the average.
So it will sum them all together and then divide by the number of inputs.
So twenty plus twenty five divided by two twenty two point five.
These four numbers divided by four gives us four and we've already seen arguments quite a bit in the
built in methods we've been working with something like two uppercase expects no inputs we don't pass
anything in it just uppercase is something it's kind of like our initial version of Greek it does the
same thing but then we have things like index f or includes or splice or slice where we have to specify
inputs we have to tell it in the case of index of what string we're looking for in hello and we get
different behaviours and different outcomes if we pass in an h index of 0 if we pass in an oh we get
index of 4 we're specifying additional information so how do we make our functions expect arguments
and use those values in the code in the function body it's pretty simple All we do is instead of our
function definition instead of empty parentheses we add in some variable name.
So this has to be a valid javascript identifier it can't have spaces it can't start with a number but
otherwise we can name it whatever we want.
And just like with a for of loop where we had for let x of some array let's say the array 1 2 3 this
X doesn't matter what we call it at all but it will hold the value each time through this loop of one
of these elements we kind of do the same thing for a function if we wanted to update our greet function
to accept somebodies name I would go maybe with nickname or person and we put that in the parentheses.
This does not do anything on its own it will only work if we pass in a string or a number or some value
when we call green.
But let's constantly log nickname nickname will hold the value of whatever is passed in JavaScript doesn't
care what the type is if it's a string or even an array it just cares that it's the first thing that
was passed in and it will be assigned to nickname.
That's just a sort of a placeholder name you want to give it something that makes sense a name that
is logical so nickname is fine let's see what happens now I'm printing out nickname on the first line
let's call greet and then pass in Tim there go.
You can see the first count start log says nickname which is Tim so nickname had the value of Tim because
that's what I passed in if I pass something else in like a no nickname has that value it could be an
array about an empty array we consider lug empty array and what if I don't pass anything.
In some languages this could cause an error in JavaScript it doesn't care.
It says there's no value it's undefined but it doesn't break anything it's just not their nickname just
didn't have a value so let's rewrite this just to be slightly nicer we use back ticks and we'll greet
the person high and then dollar sign nickname and maybe an exclamation point afterwards run it again
greet Tim Hi Tim.
Okay so we're confident logging something different based off of the input the input has a direct impact
on what the function actually does.
Next up let's try modifying roll die or throw dice.
These two functions.
Let's pick one.
How uncommon.
Them both.
Let's go with throw dice.
So right now throw dice always calls roll die six times if I call it over here throw dice it rolls six
dice it calls roll dice six times but what if we could specify a number of times how many times we actually
want to roll.
Maybe we're playing a game where you have two dice but maybe we're playing another game like Yahtzee
where you have five or six.
I don't remember how many it actually uses but it's more than two we could pass in an argument and let's
give it a name.
We'll talk more about terminology here.
Technically the variables we write here are called parameters not arguments.
Let's go with times or NUM roles.
Maybe that's better.
Num rolls and then in here we'll use this to repeat roll die.
So how do we repeat something.
We'll use a loop so we'll loop for we'll just do a for loop.
Let's I equals zero.
Well I is less than num rolls I add one to AI each time and we'll call roll die.
So if we pass in five we'll go from zero and then up to five.
But not including five.
Or we could go from one and then less than or equal to num roles.
I'll just go with zero because we don't care about what I actually is we just want a certain number
of times.
So let's see if it works throw dice and I do need to pass in a number like three we got three rolls.
How about five.
We get five rolls.
It combined two of them because they were identical.
Thanks chrome counsel nine we get nine rolls.
Now we've written it so that we can impact the way it behaves based off of a single input.
All right.
So that's good enough for now.
In the next video we'll see how we can have multiple arguments how the order matters and we'll start
writing some more complicated functions.