Well let's get started with our project setup.
So we're going to go through the steps you see right here inside this video.
So to get started I want to go back over to my terminal and once again at a workspace directory of sorts
inside of you're going to create a new project directory that I'm going to call AECOM short for e-commerce
all that change into that directory.
And then inside there are gonna generate a package dot JS on file.
Remember we can do so by running NPM in it Dash y
that will create a default package not just on file and I can see the contents of it printed out at
my console right away then inside of here we want to immediately start to install one or two dependencies
into our project to install these dependencies.
We're going to run npm install and then I'm going to list out the different dependencies that I want
to add in.
So in this case we're going to add in one dependency called Express and another called Node mod we'll
discuss exactly what these different dependencies do in just a moment.
But right now let's just go ahead and install them okay.
Site installations can take just a couple of seconds.
I'll let it do its thing while that's running.
I'm also going to start my code editor inside of this project directory as well.
I can now open up that package dot Jason File and very quickly as soon as that installation finishes
we'll see a new section appear inside of here called the dependency section.
Remember that records all the different dependencies we've installed into our project and the versions
we installed as well.
And there we go.
I can see them up here right there.
So what are express and Node man express is all about helping us create a web server.
We're going to very quickly get very familiar with Express.
So I'll just hold off on explanation of what it does right now Nordmann is very similar.
Well really identical to one of those projects we just put together that command line tool called Watch
it essentially node man is a little development tool that will automatically restart our web server
anytime one of our project files change.
This is a very handy tool to use and I expect you're going to use it on just about every single node
project you ever work on because if we don't have a tool like that it means that every single time we
make a change to our code we have to go back over to our terminal stop our running application and then
restart it manually which gets very tiring very quickly now that we've got these two things put together
are going to create a route JavaScript file for my project.
So inside of my code editor I'm going to create a new file called index not J.S. and inside of here
I'll just do a little console log of hi there
I'll then go back over to my package not just on file and then inside of you're going to find that script
section.
So we're going to add in a script that is going to automatically start up our project for us.
The script that we're going to write is going to seem very simple and very basic in nature.
You might think Steven why aren't we just running our application ourselves directly from the command
line.
Why are we instead writing out a script for this.
I'll tell you why as soon as we write that script so inside of here I'm going to delete the section
that says test and I'm going to replace it with a set of double quotes that say def and then another
set of double quotes with a colon in between and inside that second set I'll say node man index dot
J.S. so this right here is intended to get our project up and running if we want to run this script
right here and start our project up we can go back over to our terminal and inside of our project directory
we will run NPM run Dev the run command right here tells NPM that we want to execute one of the scripts
that we define inside of our package not just on file.
And in this case we want to run the script called Def so when we run NPM run Dev what it really does
is execute behind the scenes kind of invisible to us node Mohn index dot J.S..
So again you might be curious why are we creating the script right here as opposed to just directly
running something like node man index dot J.S..
The reason is very simple.
Anytime some new engineer might start working on your project they can very easily open up this package
start J some file and use this script section right here to understand very quickly how to manipulate
or work with your project.
So traditionally even though we can start up projects directly from the command line by running commands
like node indexed dot J us or whatever else.
Instead we will very frequently define some these different scripts you see inside of here and the whole
goal is just to communicate to other engineers how to start up our projects.
Now if we want to start off our project we're going to run NPM run dev so I'll execute that all very
quickly see hi there appear once again node man is a tool that's going to automatically restart our
application every single time there's a change to a file inside of our project.
So in general as we're working on our project when we first get started we're going to execute NPM run
Dev pretty much one time and that's pretty much it until we decide to stop this process and maybe go
on holiday or it's the weekend or whatever.
When we come back on Monday we're gonna open up our terminal again and run and run Dev a second time
if you ever need to stop this process you can hit control C on your keyboard and that will kick you
back over to your terminal and then to start a backup NPM run dev so as you're taking this course and
as you're working through this application which is going to be a pretty good amount of time I do expect
that you're going to take many breaks throughout here and have to stop working on the project.
Just remember any time you come back and you need to start the project backup you're always going to
come back to your terminal go to the project directory and execute NPM run Dev.
And that's pretty much it okay.
So now that we've done a little bit of basic project setup we'll take another pause right here.
We'll come back the next video we're gonna start to understand what this express library is by writing
out some code inside of our index such as file.