OK so now we've talked about Ajax.
We talked about Jason.
We've gotten all that stuff out of the way.
We can move on to making our first requests using the o g method of sending an HBP request through javascript.
It's called X L H GDP request.
So these are objects in the browser we can create that have different methods and we can use them to
fetch data from an API to send data somewhere.
Basically they generate an HDP request and it's confusing.
It does say XM all in the name.
That's just a relic from when X M.L. was the standard we can use X Excel HDP request also known as x
h rs to fetch any sort of data from an API.
It doesn't have to be just X amount.
So this is the original way of doing it.
It's clunky it doesn't support promises so we end up with a lot of callbacks.
If we have nested requests things where if we want to make one request get information back and then
make a second request which we mimicked back when we talked about promises a couple videos ago we made
that fake HDP request function that we used.
So we send one request.
We have some callbacks then within those callbacks we could send another one and we end up nesting things.
So no promises are supported also.
This is always driven me crazy.
Why is it capitalized this way.
Excel is an abbreviation it's all caps each GDP is two but it's not capitalized except for the H.
It always trips me up whenever I have to type these myself.
And the most important thing that I don't like about X jars and nobody really likes is the syntax.
It's hard to remember.
I have to reference it all the time.
I guarantee you in the making of this video the very one I'm recording right now I'm going to have to
pause at some point and reference some other code because I can never remember it.
Fortunately we have an alternative these days which we'll see very shortly called fetch which arose
out of the fact that people hate making X a charge.
It's just annoying.
But let's see how we do it now that I've made it sound horrendous.
Just remember this used to be the only way so it's not like nobody used this ever.
This was the only way of making a request.
What we do is we make a new object that object is created by calling new XM L H TGP request with parentheses.
Then we provide two callbacks one to run if the request loads.
If it's successful one to run if there's an error.
So we have once again once again that branching path.
Success and failure.
Then what we do is we call the request object which I called my request dot open we tell it what type
of request we'll make a get request and what you are able to send the request to we'll come back to
the headers in just a moment.
Then we finally send the request.
That request is then sent after this line is encountered.
If it's successful there's no problem.
This code will run if it's not successful if there's an error.
This code runs.
You can read more about it on MDA.
I really like their documentation on it and what I'll do to help myself out.
Probably more than this actually helps you to copy this over into my file where I'll paste it in as
a reference.
OK so let's make a request somewhere.
We're gonna use this simple starburst API to start it's free.
You don't have to sign up for anything or register.
There's no authentication.
Let's look at what do we get if we go to slash planets.
Send a request.
This is just a little viewer.
It doesn't like that.
Is there a list of planets.
How do we see all planets.
Okay well let's go to documentation.
Where are the endpoints.
Yeah.
We can just go to slash planets.
It should work.
Okay.
Here we go.
So we'll try making a request to get all of the planets which is swap eco slash API slash planets.
So I'm going to copy this you are all over and we'll try sending a request to it.
So the first thing I'll do is make our request object.
We'll call this first request equals new X AML H2 DP request like that then we have a couple of different
ways of attaching the callbacks.
We can do what I showed in the slides where we use on load and on error or we can use at event listener
so either one works.
In general you know I've already mentioned this when we're working with the Dom and adding click events
and other sort of event listeners.
I like to use an event listener so I guess we'll go with that.
Even though I didn't put it in the slides like I said I pretty much never use this.
So we'll do our event listener for load.
This is the code that will run let's just do an arrow function.
If things go well I will just cancel that log it works and then we'll duplicate this entire thing here.
But listen for the error events.
So in the event that it doesn't work something went wrong will counsel that log error.
OK so we're just attaching these to event listeners.
We haven't even sent the request we haven't told it what you are ready to go to.
So that's the next part.
First request Dot's open and you would think open would actually send to send the request but it doesn't.
We have to explicitly send it afterwards.
So I'll put my you are Ellen here.
This is the you are well I want to send a request to then we'll call first request dot sent.
Remember this takes time.
Which is why we have to add our callbacks.
If I put something afterwards just like with a set time out all the stuff we saw in the last section
javascript moves on.
This request is handled by the browser.
One of the web API is just like set time out so javascript doesn't just pause like it does if I put
an alert.
It pauses and just waits and waits and waits that doesn't happen here because javascript is not sending
the actual request it's done through the browser.
So we'll consider that log request sent down here and this is what we should see appear first and then
our request hopefully comes back successful.
We'll see this if it does not come back successful.
We'll see this.
Who knows what will happen.
So here's my page where I have it loaded.
Request sent.
It worked.
I guess we just have to trust that it worked right now.
But if we put some you or Alan here that we know does not exist.
Well I hope that doesn't exist.
Try it again.
There we go.
Request was sent and we got an error.
So our two branching paths did it.
Bode was everything OK or did it suck.
Did it not work.
Was there an error which we just deliberately caused to make sure it worked.
So that is the first part in making a request object and ex H.R. X AML GDP request we make it.
Then we attach our callbacks then.
Well actually you can attach the callbacks after you open but before you send what's most important
is that you send after you've configured that object so the object represents an HDP request.
It's just a javascript object that has different methods.
It has properties where assigning a load in an error callback we tell it what type of requests we want
to get request telling it where to send the request to telling it to send it.
Now what about the data that's coming back from the API.
The whole point of this is to send a request and get something back.
Right now we're not accessing it.
We don't even know if we get the correct information back.
We just get a console dialog the way that we access that data is by referencing this dot response text.
Well what does this refer to.
It refers to the request itself.
So why don't we just look at that request.
I think we called it first request.
Right.
So after this finished which it already finished we can see that here if we look at first request it
contains a response and it contains this response text.
If we copy this response text and see if I copy it correctly okay.
This right here is a whole bunch of Jason everything we see is Jason.
It's not regular old javascript but it's a string of a bunch of JavaScript looking stuff.
You can see it enter the quote.
It begins with a double quote.
So if I save right now and my auto formatted tries to run it's not going to be happy with me.
It's not considered javascript but we have a way of referencing it so I'll get rid of that massive monstrosity
down there and let's try referencing the response text on first request.
So when my slides.
What I did was this dot response text but that won't work here.
Why not.
Any guesses here.
It has to do with the fact that I'm using an arrow function so an arrow function remember does not have
the same rules of the keyword this.
So this will not refer to first request if I use an arrow function.
So I have two options I can just reference first request dot text contra.
What is that response.
Text we could counsel that log that refresh the page.
Hey all of our information if I instead tried to do this we will get undefined.
There is no response text because this is not set to the first request.
If I instead rewrite this as a standard function expression.
Now I can use the keyword this so in this case it probably makes more sense to use a standard function
expression because we want the value of this to refer to the first request object.
So this gives me this massive thing of text it is not javascript it's Jason.
So the next step is to turn it into actual javascript.
So here we go.
We have a special method called Jason dot pass and we pass into that a string of Jason like that and
we can save that to a variable to call this data and then we can console the log data let's see what
we get now.
Hey check it out.
This is now being presented to me as a javascript object.
It includes things like count how many results we got back with the next pages.
So it looks like it didn't give us all the planets at once because there's a lot of them.
Instead it gave me the first but the first 10 and then instead of results we have all of the different
planets that we got back 10 of them and they contain tons of information and this is an actual javascript
object so I could do something like loop over the results and print out each planet name.
So I would need to access data dot results loop over that.
So why don't we start there data.
So let's do four let planet of data that results.
We now have this awesome javascript object.
It wasn't javascript before we converted it and we want for each one of these to print out the name.
So we'll do a console that log planet dot.
Name refresh awesome.
We are now sending a request getting information back as Jason converting into javascript iterating
over it or doing something with it somehow manipulating it and then printing data out.
So with what we've seen so far it wouldn't be a stretch to instead display the information on the page
or do something visual for a user.
It would be the same sort of stuff we've seen before creating an element appending an element selecting
element styling them with classes all of that hopefully by now we're pretty comfortable with.
But this this is kind of a lot of code and it has some drawbacks other than the clunky syntax which
we'll go into in the next video.