Our first test worked out pretty well so let's continue on with this refactor.
I'm inside of my index dot J.S. file inside of here we've got the three create auto complete function
calls in a row.
We don't really need three different auto completes.
I just did that for testing purposes so I'm going to delete the two right there and we're going to go
back to just one call to create auto complete I'm also going to go to my index dot HDMI file and remove
those two extra Divs.
All right so let's continue on with this refactor.
I want to continue to add in some additional functions to that config object that we're passing to the
create autocomplete function.
We're then going to refactor the function to make sure that it uses the functions we had provided instead
of locating all that logic directly inside of the Create autocomplete function.
So I think the next one we should try working on is render option.
So this is going to be a function that is going to be called.
With each different option or each kind of object that we're getting back from that API we're going
to pass it into this function and that function needs to return some kind of string that's going to
be the h t email that shows up inside of the dropdown So in short if we go back over to autocomplete
J.S. year create autocomplete and if we go down to our for of loop right now right about here essentially
where we're setting the inter h t melody option.
Remember we had said that this is assuming 100 percent that we always want to show an image.
And then the title right next to it but we might decide that we want our autocomplete to work in some
very different way.
Like for example maybe we won't have an image at all.
So right now.
This would be really challenging to customize because this is code that is located inside of our autocomplete
file which we want to be as reusable as possible.
So instead I want to extract the logic that decides what this thing looks like to a helper function
on that config object.
We're going to assume that that helper function is going to be called with each movie object we are
iterating over.
Now I know you see the variable movie inside of here quite a bit still.
And like I'm still using the term movie we are going to eventually refactor the terminology inside of
here to not refer to movie anymore.
I just want to throw that out there really quickly.
So back inside of our next j ust file and when to find where we create the autocomplete I'm gonna pass
in a second property into this object I'm going to call it render option we could make this a function
like so we can also assign it as an arrow function no difference whatsoever we can really use either
syntax so passed into this function I'm going to expect to receive some object like each individual
object that represents some possible movie or whatever else and I'll just refer to it as movie then
inside we're going to generate some H CML and return it and this will be the H SYMBOL to get shown for
each individual option we're going to have to extract all the logic we had around that it's not only
the HMO right there we also have to extract that line where we got the image s our C is remember in
some cases the poster link was an A and we needed to make sure we handle that as well so I'm going to
take the image s our C line right there I'm going to cut it I'm gonna go paste it back inside of render
option I'll then go and get the inner each team mail that we had created right here.
I'm gonna cut it go back over to render option I'll paste it in here and return it.
So now we have extracted all of our rendering logic into this render option function and it's going
to be called many times automatically with each movie that the autocomplete fetches.
Now we just need to make sure that the accrete autocomplete function references this function to figure
out what each option should look like so to do so we'll go back over to the other file I'm going to
go up to the very top where we're going to make sure that we d structure off the render option function
and we'll go back down to that same or of loop.
It is right here.
I'll find where I left the option enter HCM CML so to generate the H CML to show for this option we're
going to call render option with the movie that we are currently iterating over and there we go.
Now once again we've extracted some custom logic that is only appropriate for this movie related stuff.
And if we ever decide that we want the autocomplete to look very different.
So if you want to generate some H team mail for each individual option we only have to update the render
option function back inside of index J Yes it's all now save this and do a quick test makeover here.
I'll refresh.
I'll look for Avengers and I still see the same thing.
Let's try making a change to the render option function just to see how easy it is now to make a change
and get something looks slightly different as a quick reminder inside of the data that we get back from
our API.
It contains the year that the movie was created.
So let's try printing out the year that the movie was created next to each option as well but to do
so I no longer.
This is the entire key right here.
This is the part to like listen to in other words I no longer have to go hunting through and searching
through all the source code of the Create autocomplete function to figure out how to change what each
individual item looks like.
Instead I can look at my render option function right here which is very appropriately named.
I see that name.
Chances are I would think to myself Oh this is where we decide how to change what each individual option
looks like.
So then inside of here right after the movie title I could put down like maybe a set of parentheses
and an inside their print out using dollar sign and curly brace.
Movie dot yea so we can save that.
Go back over refresh look for Avengers again and now I see the year on there.
So hopefully this change is a little bit more meaningful when we start talking about all this refactoring
and add a reusable logic stuff.
It is the presence of this function right here that will make it really clear to other engineers how
to customize and get some version of the autocomplete that works for their particular application.
I'm sure you can imagine that if we wanted to make even more changes to how each individual option looks
we would just make some more changes to render option and that's it.
So hopefully now you're starting to get a little bit more sense of the purpose of this whole refactor.
Those take a quick pause right here and continue in the next video.