The last thing we need to extract is fetch data.
So fetch data is being used inside of our autocomplete J.S. file right now directly.
So if we go to auto complete J.S. find out on input callback right here we're calling fetch data when
we call fetch data right here.
That is a reference back to the fetch data that gets defined inside of index not J.S..
So this means that we have a direct link between these two files autocomplete J.S. is directly referencing
this function right here.
So if we ever deleted this function or renamed it or even just commented it out our autocomplete would
no longer work correctly.
So we definitely do not want to have such a tight coupling between these two functions.
We're just going to essentially take this function right here and we're going to throw it as another
argument or another option into our create autocomplete config object rather than going to update our
autocomplete file and make sure that it references the fetch data that has passed on that config object
instead of over this like direct global scope between the two files but to do so I'm going to take just
the function I'm going to cut it I'll delete the function name at the very top I'm going to add in a
new key value pair to my configuration object call it fetch data I'm going to put a set of parentheses
and then paste the function.
Now I definitely have some mistakes on syntax inside of here so I'm gonna make sure that it fixes up.
First off we need to make sure that we mark batch data as being async so I'm going to delete the async
keyword right there and put it right in front of fetch data.
Well then make sure that I take the search term and add it as the argument to fetch data.
And then finally I can remove the fetch data right there and the arrow and it should be good to go.
Make sure you triple check your syntax right there because definitely very easy to make a little typo
I'm also gonna do a quick change or fix to the syntax or indentation.
There we go OK.
So now you're passing the fetch data function as an argument into our create autocomplete configuration
object.
It's now if we go back over to autocomplete us at the very top.
Once again we will D structure out the fetch data function.
Now there is no direct kind of window scope access between these two different files which is definitely
a good improvement.
All right.
So I think there's just one last thing for us to take care of.
We need to go through our autocomplete J.S. file and we need to find any reference to a movie in order
to actually make this code generic in nature and reusable.
We need to not make any big assumptions about the kind of data that we are working with.
We just have to go through and change the words movie or movies to some other kind of appropriate term
so inside of your I first see movie on our label says search for a movie.
I was gonna change this to just a search or then go down a little bit.
So inside of on input after he made a request we called what came back.
Movies.
So again not appropriate to have the term movies inside of autocomplete J.S. anymore it's I'm going
to change the term movies throughout this file.
Two items this kind of reflects that we have a collection of different items so we want to show inside
that dropdown.
So now we can go through and update every reference to movies to items instead.
The first one is inside the if statement I'll change that to items the next one is right here on the
for loop.
I'll change that to items and I think that is about it inside of here.
Let me do one more search.
Yep that's it.
Now inside of the for loop itself will change the term movie to item singular so on the for loop will
do.
Item on render option I'll change it to item input value right here I'll change it to item on option
select I'll go to item and I think that is just about it we'll do a search for movie and nothing to
make sure inside of autocomplete J.S. you do a search for movie and if you see the weird movie inside
of here that is wrong we should not have any references to movies anymore.
All right.
And that's pretty much it.
Let's save this and think we're ready for one last test.
It's going to go back over to my index H team L or refresh I'll search for Avengers again and everything
works correctly the search occurred and I should be able to click on that and still see something appear
if you see any errors inside of your console I can just about guarantee you that you still have a reference
to movie or movies somewhere inside of autocomplete J.S. to make sure that you find that remaining reference
and update it to the appropriate term okay.
So at this point in time we now have a fully reusable function called Create autocomplete we can take
this function right here and we can use it on any other project we can think of and we'll get the exact
same behavior as the one that we currently have inside of application.
All we have to do is call the function and pass in these appropriate different properties.
So we need to specify where to render the autocomplete to how to show an individual item what to do
when someone clicks on one what to kind of backfill inside of the inputs after user clicks on one and
then how to actually fetch the data.
As long as we put all that code inside there then we're going to get a fully functioning autocomplete
ready to go.
So I know this last bit of the refactor is a little bit of a pain but I hope that at this point a little
bit more clear why we went through this pain and I hope you can recognize that the code that we now
have is quite reusable in nature.
So let's take a pause right here and continue their application in the next video.