All right.
Now that we've got these better each cell structure we're going to go back over to our index not J.S.
file and make sure that we show two separate auto completes one that's going to use left auto complete
as a route.
The other is going to use right auto complete as a route.
Back inside my index digest file at the very top.
We are calling create auto complete we're passing in a reference to a div with the class of auto complete
which doesn't exist anymore.
So I want to change that query selector to pound right.
DASH So let's do left versus left dash autocomplete.
I'll go ahead and save this.
Now if we flip back over and refresh we see one auto complete on the left hand side.
So now we need to essentially do the exact same thing to create the auto complete on the right hand
side as well.
So you might be thinking that that means so we essentially have to duplicate all of this code right
here just to have a second call to create auto complete with a different route.
We don't have to we don't have to duplicate all of this config.
Let me show you what we're going to do at the very top of the file.
I'm going to create a new variable called auto complete config and I'll make it an object and we're
going to go into our current auto complete config so like this object right here and we're going to
take out every option inside of here.
So every key value property every function that is reusable between our two different auto completes
we want to show well if we look through here every single function inside is reusable except for the
roots element maybe that maybe will go down a line realize that it's not 100 percent reusable but for
right now I think that we definitely can't reuse just about everything except for that root element.
So I'm going to take render option I'll go down to the bottom of fetch data I'm going to highlight all
that I'm going to cut all of it.
It's now the only thing that's left is root I'm going gonna paste all of it inside of auto complete
config.
So now inside of the Create auto complete function call right here we're going to essentially say create
a new object take all of the properties inside of auto complete config that we defined at the top of
the file and then add in this new property of route and then take that whole object and pass it off
to create complete.
So to do so we're going to write out inside of here dot dot dot auto complete config and then a comma.
So the dot dot dot right there means make a copy of everything inside that object or essentially take
all the different functions inside there and throw them into this object and then add in this root property
as well and that's it.
So what we have right here is a hundred percent equivalent to what we had just before but now since
autocomplete config is its own separate object we can repeat this process as many times as we want and
create additional auto completes with the same configuration object so to do so I'm going to make a
copy of create autocomplete config or something create autocomplete just a function called paste it.
Now all we have to do is update the query selector.
So instead of saying LEFT TO SAY RIGHT IT AND THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
I'M GONNA SAVE THIS I'M GONNA GO BACK OVER refresh and now I see the two separate auto completes I'm
gonna make sure I don't have any errors nope nothing inside my console.
Now if I do a search for Avengers looks like the left hand side is working and if I do a search for
dark knight on the right yep that's working as well then click that Avengers click that yep looks good
now if I click on those I PROBABLY GONNA SEE AN ERROR down here because we deleted the element that
showed the actual summary your only call just a second go to update the H single file so I think that
the next obvious thing we have to do is make sure that once we search for something we need to hide
this kind of tutorial element right here and show a summary on just the appropriate side of the screen
let's take care of that process in the next video.