All right.
So in this video we're going to implement our run comparison function.
Now as I mentioned just a moment ago implementing this function is going to be just a little bit challenging
because the metrics that we're comparing here aren't always just play numbers.
In this case we've got some strings.
So we need to figure out how to compare these different values.
There's actually another reason and this is kind of a challenging little problem.
Let me tell you exactly why I want you to think about the exact logic we're kind of ordering in which
we would run the comparison inside this function.
The first statistic that we print out down here is the number of awards or that whole award string and
then the box office and then the medal score.
So it's clear that we need to somehow reach into the Dom we need to select this element on both sides
of the screen because remember there's really two of these elements on the screen one for each movie
we search for.
So we need to find this first element like the first element with a class of notification is primary
and a article tag.
And we're going to essentially assume that that is of type awards are displaying the awards stepped.
So we might end up running some code inside of here that looks like this is can give you a very quick
example maybe something like find the first article elements for each movie then run a comparison on
the number of awards then apply some styling to that article element.
The key thing here is that we're just looking for the first article for each movie and we're assuming
that that first article element represents the number of awards statistic if we start to write some
code like this.
We're going to very quickly end up in a bad spot.
Let me tell you why if our code just looks at the first element and assumes it is awards we could break
our application super quickly by going back down to our template and just changing the order of statistics.
So in other words I could take this first statistic block cut it and move it underneath that first one
or the second one.
So now the award statistic is second in the list.
So if I ever wanted to reorder the different statistics that I'm showing here I would also have to make
an update to the run comparison function because now the first article in The list represents the box
office amount.
So we'd have to update this code to run a comparison on the box office value instead.
And then it kind of follows that the second comparison I would have to update from box office to instead
take a look at number of awards.
So in other words we don't really want to encode the order of statistics here and try to read it out
of our each team T.M. to figure out what order we're going to compare these different statistics in.
So that kind of grows that approach out the window.
So how are we going to like actually fix this.
How are we going to actually approach it.
Well I've got one kind of crazy idea that's going to kind of solve a lot of the different issues that
we're going to run into upfront particularly that other issue around like comparing strings versus strings.
I think that when we run the movie template function we should add it in a data property to each of
these different articles and we should make the data property a number version like an easily comparable
version of each of the different statistics that we want to show.
So in other words I think would be awesome.
Whenever we run movie templates for each of these different articles on the article itself I want to
put in like a data value property and maybe set it to for this first box office value something like
six hundred twenty three million I'll say something like data value is six hundred twenty three million
or so then later on we decide to run our comparison rather than trying to look at the order of articles
and figure out that we first have like box office then awards then met a score or whatever we can just
read that data value property and compare it against the data value property for the first article on
the other side of the screen.
So in other words we're throwing the idea that this is like the box office statistic out the window
inside the run comparison function.
The only thing run comparison will take care about is that data value property.
So we can just take a look at the data value property on each pair of articles and then take a look
at which one is greater and apply the appropriate class to each one to color that notification as either
green or yellow.
Now this is yet another scenario where I know as I explain this it probably sounds crazy and a little
bit complicated.
So let's once again write some code as soon as we do I think you'll get a good idea of why we're doing
this.
So quick pause and we'll start to implement this approach in the next video.