Next up we're going to talk about why this pattern a factory function is not commonly used and why instead
we use something called the constructor pattern or constructor function.
So let's start with what you probably have seen at this point.
We've seen this new keyword occasionally like new example age GDP request I hate typing this but we
run this if we need to make an Excel HDP request we're not using fat.
We're not using axes.
Check out the requests section if you're not sure what the heck I'm talking about.
This makes us a new object following a pattern.
Also we can make an array with this syntax new Array.
It's definitely lengthier.
It's not commonly used at all.
You could do new String.
Notice I'm using capital letters.
What is that new keyword.
It's actually an operator and we'll get to it and we'll talk about why it's preferable to this approach.
But let's start with understanding the shortcoming here.
It's not a huge one but it's important to understand.
Every time I make a new color object we start with an empty object.
We have three unique properties right there added directly to the object that makes sense.
But then these functions they're recreated and a unique copy is added to each color object.
So each color object has its own R B function.
Yeah the values are going to always be different assuming that the colors are different.
We have different RG and B's.
We can end up with a different result but there's no reason to have a unique copy of the function itself.
Just like if we were to write a regular function called RG b out here function RG B we could reuse that
with any inputs.
We don't need to have function RG B2 and RG b 3 and RG before.
Anytime we want to pass and different values we just make one function that is not what's happening
here and I can show you that I have two colors I've created using make color I have first color and
I have black they have different values that I passed in so we get different objects right.
We have black Where are G and B are 0 0 0 and we have first color not a very original name.
Thirty five 255 150.
Notice they have their own copy.
Well looks like they have their own copy of hex and RG B and we could verify that in a bunch of different
ways.
The simplest would be if we compare black dot let's take hex and compare it to first color dot hex they
are not equal.
Triple equals for a reference type is going to check and functions are reference types as a reminder
it will check to see if they are referring to the same function.
In this case and they are not.
But if we compare that to something like a string any string high dot what's a good method to use.
How about we use dot slice.
I'm not going to call it just high dot slice triple equals by dot slice.
Two different strings.
Notice that we get true.
What's happening here is that the slice method is not defined on every single string or if I had worked
with an array.
Know if we look at some array one two three four the methods are not defined in this individual object.
Arrays are objects.
A weird part of JavaScript they are considered objects.
Instead they are defined on the prototype.
Remember we started this section off with prototypes.
Every array gets its built in array methods from one prototype array object.
This contains all of the methods and functionality that we're used to using a radar pop array that can
cat.
Same thing with strings.
These string prototype contains the methods.
So instead of having their own copy this array does not have its own copy of pop.
This string does not have its own copy of Slice.
Are referencing one function and it's located on the prototype with what we've set up here.
We don't have an easy way of making that work so this is where the constructor function enters a constructor
function is kind of a kind of a weird part of JavaScript.
Honestly it's pretty different than most other programming languages I've worked with.
But don't let that scare you.
It's not too bad if you go to M.D. and there's a nice little explanation of this new operator which
we will use.
But first take a look at this code right here.
We have a function.
It's starting with a capital letter which is just a style choice but inside the function.
There's never a return value and we're referencing this directly in the function.
We're not in an object like we had here right.
We created an object color and we reference this inside that object on a method.
Here it's just a function.
This dot make equal something this stop model what is going on.
Well let's try it out.
So on the docks we had a function and had a capital letter which is really just a way of indicating
that this is a regular function.
It is a function that helps you create objects.
It's a constructor function.
Function color.
We pass an R G and B and then what they did on MDA and was this thought R equals R.
This dot G equals G and this dot B equals B okay.
Well let's see what happens when I call color when they come over here refresh my page and then execute
color and pass in.
I'll just do 2 5 5 0 and 0.
I didn't get anything back.
Doesn't appear to be working.
If I save that to a variable I would just see undefined.
What if we print out this console log.
This gets printed out at the end.
After we've added those properties are G and B what do you think this is going to refer to.
Who refers to the window.
Why is that.
Well if you remember back in the Secret Life of object section we talked about the keyboard.
This and how it behaves in the scope of this function.
It's not inside of any other object.
This is going to refer to the global scope.
The nearest object which is the window object.
So then why on earth would the docs talk about making a function like this and referring to this in
your function not returning anything.
Well the secret is this new operator when we call this function but we call it with new before the function
call it behaves differently.
These are the steps I guess I'll just copy these over and show them to you here.
When we call this color function with new new color and then we pass in values 255 40 and 100.
Just like that.
It's going to create a blank plain javascript object.
OK it sets the constructor of this object to another object will come back to that passes the newly
created object from step 1 as the.
This in this context.
So it's going to make us a new object and it will set this to that new object.
So we'll be adding our G and B to that new object.
Then it returns this at the end.
So it's kind of doing what we saw earlier.
Concept let's just call it o equals an object and then this would be referring to this object and then
it adds these properties to that object and then at the end it would return.
Oh but it's doing it all implicitly behind the scenes for us this behaves differently here than it normally
does.
As we saw if we don't use a new keyword this refers to the window object but when we use new it's just
how javascript works.
It's the magic of this operator.
It will be used to create a new object for you based off of this pattern.
So why don't we try it now.
When I copy this over go back to my code refresh.
If we just call color like that.
Not good if we call it with new.
All right.
Take a look at this.
We get an object and this object has properties on it that we assign to using this.
I never told it to make an object explicitly and never said return an object.
It did that and did something else.
If you look under Prado here it has a constructor property set to color.
That was the first or the second thing links or it sets the constructor of the object to another object
using whatever we named this function.
So it sets the constructor to this color function.
What this allows us to do is now we can add methods not to the individual objects not to the instances
but to the prototype.
So if I copied what we did earlier like this RG bee method and I put it in here I have to uncommon some
of this and fix it up.
We would have something like this dot RG B equals that function and we can access this.
It should work fine.
This is not new.
This is kind of what we saw earlier.
Let's see what happens when I call new color again instead of color.
It still has RG be defined on the individual object.
It's not defined on the prototype but we have a workaround rather than doing this.
We would define that method on the prototype outside of this constructor function.
It's kind of odd but that's how it works.
We call color dot prototype Dot.
Our GDP equals this function so it's a little clunky.
But we saw this syntax already.
We saw how we could change a red out prototyped up pop and overwrite it to be some other function that
did nothing.
Same idea.
So we have now made this constructor function for color anytime we call it with the new keyword it makes
us a new object.
It sets the constructor to color of that object and then it sets the value of this to that new empty
object.
We can add properties to it.
It returns that object.
So if I call you know new color 40 50 60 I save that to a variable costs color one.
I now have an object here that has RG and B but not only that if we take a look at color one it does
not have that method.
RG be defined on it self on the actual object.
It's defined on the prototype so I can still call color one dot.
RG V which is the very important part.
If we couldn't then it wouldn't be worth doing.
But I don't have a unique copy of it here.
I can still access it from the prototype object just like with an array or a string.
So this is now better or more efficient than our factory approach where we returned a new object every
time it was called.
And on that object we added in individual methods that were unique each time.
Now I could have two colors color one and color two.
It could be totally different this one could be 0 0 0 0.
And why don't I add in a second method.
We'll do color dot prototype dot hex equals function and I'll just copy the code from right here.
I have to tweak it a bit.
Don't need that.
Don't need that uncommon to save and everything else should work.
We still have access to this instead of these functions.
This will be set to whatever is on the left side of that dot.
So color one dot hex color one will be the value of this.
If I do color to color too will be the value of this.
Even though the function is defined as a method on the prototype so let's verify that color one dot
hex is the same as color to dot hex because they are on these shared prototype object rather than uniquely
defined on each instance.
So we've defined a recipe for a color we've set every color.
We'll have this one prototype that has RG B in hex and we need one copy and one copy only of those methods.
Let's test it out.
So we have color 1.
I can still call dot hex color to dot Hex.
I get different results because the value of this is different.
Inside those methods.
But then if I call color one dot hex triple equals color to dot hex hallelujah it's true they're pointing
to the same thing and we can verify that also.
Just open up this object here in the dev tools.
We don't see hex and RG be defined here.
They're defined on the prototype.
So a key distinction from what we saw earlier.
All right.
So why don't we end by adding one more method in this method will be our GPA which I could call like
color one dot our GPA and I can pass in a number from zero to one like zero point five and this should
give me an RG B color or an RG be a color which follows the same pattern here but it has a fourth channel
a alpha which is in charge of opacity so I would define color dot prototype dot our GPA equals function
and while I'm doing this an important thing to note you don't want to use aero functions for this.
Remember that they behave differently with the keyword this so you can run into trouble.
So use traditional standard function expressions like I'm doing here.
So we could duplicate this line to get RG and V.
We also want the parameter for the alpha channel.
Why don't we give it a default of 1 if nobody or if it's not passed in.
We'll just do a full regular color and won't have any translucent Alpha will be 1.0.
Then we have to return our string template literal and it should be RG B A.
And then we interpolate are we interpolate G we interpolate B forgot the dollar sign and then finally
we interpolate a and we also need the closing Perrin.
So let's test it out here.
We've got color 1.
Let's see what color 1 looks like.
I don't even know.
Color 1 dot our GV gives us this color is it at all.
Interesting.
It's going to pasted in here and it's pretty ugly.
Why don't we change that to be much about much greener.
We'll try again color one dot RG B gives us this let's take a look.
Okay very bright green.
Now if I want to use that somewhere let's just do document dump body dot style dot background color
equals and I'll use color one dot our GP.
There we go pretty green.
Now let's try our RG be method.
It has a default parameter so it should be the exact same color but now if I pass in a number like zero
point eight Oh it's getting more translucent.
Go down to zero point for zero point two zero point one.
There we go.
So we've made this one method defined on the color prototype and it works across any instances of color.
Anytime we ran new color that's the main takeaway here.
The new keyword does these mysterious operations.
It's very confusing when you're starting out because if you look at this function on its own it seems
like it shouldn't do anything it doesn't ever make an object it doesn't ever return anything but you
put that new keyword in front when you execute the function and it changes how it behaves entirely.
And then we saw that we can add methods to the color prototype so that they are only defined one time
rather than on each individual color like we had up here.
So as you can see the syntax is kind of annoying and it leads to these long files where things aren't
really grouped together right.
We have our color definition here.
But then all of the methods are defined separately.
This is why the class keyword in the new class syntax was introduced which is what we'll see right after
this.
Another way of achieving the exact same outcome but a prettier syntax.