All right.
The very last thing we do on our products list or the admin panel overall is to make sure that we can
delete an existing product.
So we need to make sure that whenever we click on this button we delete the appropriate thing out of
our big old repo of all of our different products.
So to get started on this we're going to find the template that renders this HCM out.
So you might recall that that is inside of our views admin products index such as file it's inside of
here we can scroll down a little bit and find our delete button right there so in order to make sure
that clicking on this thing actually deletes the appropriate product we're just going to wrap it inside
of a form element.
It's going to wrap this inside of a form.
We're not going to give this thing any kind of input or anything like that recently just using the submission
of the form as a sign that we want to delete the appropriate product.
It might be kind of curious why we are doing a form element right here for deletion as opposed to like
a normal anchor tag or something like that.
Like why don't we have an anchor tag that wraps that button and then whenever we click on the anchor
tag we visit a route that deletes the corresponding product.
The reason for that is pretty simple an anchor tag.
Whenever we click on it is going to make a GET request to that you're out.
We instead want to make a post request.
In general we consider a POST request to be a sign that we want to modify some data in some way just
so you know we've been using get requests and post requests quite a bit throughout this application.
There are other types of requests that are technically more appropriate for this operation.
So there is a type of HDTV request called a DELETE request which.
Yeah without a doubt totally appropriate.
The issue is that a form element only some only supports get requests and post requests as the means
of submission so we cannot use a form element to actually make a DELETE request.
We technically can by using some really tricky magic but that's something that's very much outside the
realm of this course.
So we're not gonna worry about it too much.
We're just going to rely upon a POST request from this form to actually do our delete okay.
So on this forum I'm going to give it a method of post and I'm going to give it one other attribute
as well.
I'm going to give it an attribute of action.
So this action tribute right here specifies the URL that we're going to make the post requests to usually
by default the action property is equal to whatever the current you URL is.
So if we clicked on delete right now we would make a post request to admit slash products.
The issue is that with that we don't have any easy way to communicate what the I.D. of the product is
that we want to delete.
So we're going to instead add the action actually right here so we can manually specify the URL that
we're going to make our post request to the we're going to make our post request to admin products product
dot I.D. slash Delete.
It's now in every click on that button POST request to that you URL right there.
It's now all we have to do is open up our different root handlers around our products and add in a post
request handler to watch for a request that you are El.
Let's do that right now.
I'm going to go back to product stop J.S..
So this is inside of my roots admin directory.
I'm going to go down to the very bottom of the file and down here I'll add in a router and we'll watch
for a post request to admin products I.D. with the cold in front of it.
Because remember we don't know exactly what this idea is going to be.
It's essentially a wild card of sorts.
Flash delete then as usual we want to do a require off to make sure that only someone who is authenticated
can access this route and we'll put on our rec and Our rez with our actual route handling function inside
of here.
We need to reach into our products repo and delete the appropriate post because we're going to reach
into our repo.
Well that's definitely going to be an asynchronous action so I'm going to mark the enclosing function
as async then if we again take a look at our repositories repository DHS file inside of here you'll
recall that we put together a delete function.
Here it is right here.
So all we have to do is call delete with the appropriate I.D.
a back inside of our handler.
We can do in a products repo not delete and the idea of the product that we want to delete will be at
risk dot prams.
That idea.
Remember racked up prams is how we get access to the I.D. out of the incoming request in the URL.
Then finally after successfully deleting this thing we'll send the user back to our big list of products.
So that'll be another rez redirect slash admin slash products
that should pretty much be set.
So let's save this.
I'm going to go back over.
I'm going to refresh this page and I should be able to click on delete and see that product go away.
Delete goes away.
Delete it never and left with an empty list okay.
So that's pretty much the full functionality we've got the ability to create products we can edit them
we can delete them.
And of course we can list them out on here as well that that is pretty much it for our administration
panel.
It's now the last thing that we need to really take care of is our ability to list out all of our different
products to our user and allow them to add those items to a shopping cart as well.
So as usual quick pause right here and we'll start all that stuff up in the next video.