All right.
So this is great.
Very short an easy way to wait for an asynchronous operation to complete before running the next line.
But what if the asynchronous operation if that promise is not resolved.
What if it's rejected right now it's working out.
I have Internet.
I'm not requesting an invalid you are.
But if I change that this end point should give me a forum for iOS is going to reject the promise.
I don't have a catch.
I don't have any sort of error handling.
What happens.
Let's see some uncut and promise error request.
I don't have any code that I'm running either to catch that error maybe to make a different request
to tell the user something went wrong.
I am not handling it at all.
We have a couple of options.
The first is to chain on a dot catch to might get planets call.
Remember get planets is an async function.
It returns a promise.
If I catch get planets error console dot log in catch and then let's console that like the error as
well.
Let's see what happens now.
OK.
There we go.
And catch here's my error.
I caught it.
We have another option though.
If you don't want to have to use dot catch and pass it and callback can come comment that out in my
async function.
I'll keep this original one I can add a try and catch block which looks like this.
Try something otherwise catch the error.
So here's what I would want to try and if something goes wrong.
If an exception is raised if there's an error don't freak out.
Just run this code and I'll cancel that log in catch comma or e not error.
Let's see what happens now.
Need to call get planet still get planets.
Great.
Let's try it out same output.
Well we said in catch.
I think what we have before in catch with three exclamation points this time we have one.
So we get the same behavior but these are technically different.
They're different because this is going to catch any errors any issues within this one async function
here.
I could have multiple functions that are returning promises I could have got vendors and as we've seen
before the callback in our DOT catch will run for any of them if the promise is rejected.
So when we have one function we're calling it doesn't really matter.
We're just doing one thing.
There's one place one promise where the error could be raised.
So it's not a big difference but there is a difference.
This is more of a backup to catch multiple potential errors here.
It's more specific to what we're trying to do.
And we can be more detailed in how we handled it.
But I'm not going to deal with that right now.
Next what I'd like to show you is how we can make multiple requests or multiple asynchronous operations
in a single async function using a weights and async async await.