So far we've been defining our functions using what are called function statements where we have function
and then some idea let's go with ADD and then we return something or we do something in here.
But the pattern is function and then a name and then curly braces.
Now I'm going to show you a completely different syntax although I say completely different.
It looks very similar but it is different.
It's called a function expression.
This is a another way of defining a function.
These functions will work just as well just the same as the function statements we've been writing.
But there's a key difference here.
If you look at this function it's stored in a variable.
The function itself does not have a name.
It's not function square then parents I'm saying function no name and I'm storing it in a variable square.
Now how am I able to store a function in a variable.
Well it works because functions are objects in javascript functions are objects which means we can put
them in a variable.
We can store 10 of them in an array.
We can even pass them around as arguments which is something we do all the time.
And it's mainly why I'm introducing this to you right now.
So I have a variable called Square.
It could be holding a number.
It could be holding an array but instead it's holding a function which is just an object and to call
it a reference to the name of the variable square.
And I pass in an argument just like I would for any function named square.
The main distinction here is that the function does not actually have a name.
It's stored in a variable but we haven't provided a name so let's try one of these out on our own.
We can write a regular function statement first so function we'll just do add.
I know it's boring but X and Y two parameters and then we'll return x plus y.
Now let's define a function expression that does the same thing.
So we could write it with no name.
I'm not going to store it in a variable first.
I'm just going to write function parentheses x come away.
Return x plus y.
Now this on its own is not valid.
If I save we can't call this we have no way of referring to this function.
There's no name I haven't stored it in a variable.
This is called an anonymous function and we do use these a lot but not just on their own floating in
the middle of nowhere.
We usually pass them into another function but I'm getting ahead of myself.
So let's store this in a variable I'll call this one some instead of ads so I don't have to add and
I'll save.
So to execute add I just reference head and I'll pass in some numbers like four and five I get nine
to execute some.
It's the same thing I just reference some.
So some nine and three gives us twelve.
They work exactly the same way but we declared them in two different formats to different sin taxes.
There are some differences between how these behave which is something we will address in time.
We'll talk about something called hoisting.
But for now all you need to know is that this is a nother syntax to define a function and that functions
are objects which means we can store them in a variable pass them around put them in arrays they're
just like any other object.
Now this also means that we can inspect them if I do a console that DVR which we may not have seen very
much of them may not have seen it yet at all.
If I do console that dear of some it's going to print out the object form kind of reveals the underlying
object and I can see things like the name of the function.
Also we can just tell it's an object we have key value pairs.
If I do the same thing for console that desire of ad this is kind of like proof that it's an object.
It's not.
It's just the chrome console showing us some data.
But we can see the underlying key and value properties here.
OK.
The last thing I'll show you is that you can add in a name for a function when you're storing it in
a variable.
It doesn't have to be anonymous.
So this function right here the part I have highlighted has no name.
We're storing it in a variable called sum but the function itself does not have a name.
I can write another function let's call this one product meaning multiplication equals function and
then I can give it a name still.
Multiply x and y return X times Y.
So this is valid here.
This is still a function expression but it's a named function expression.
This is anonymous.
We'll talk later about this name and if it really means anything if it's useful ever.
There's a couple of situations where it might matter but the point right now is just that we can add
a name and to call this function I still call product product of 3 and 5 gives me 15 if I try and call
multiply my console doesn't know about it's not trying to autocomplete 3 and 5 it doesn't work but don't
get too caught up in these details I just hope that the one takeaway here should be that you can define
a function using this format where we write a function expression we store it in a variable and we're
learning this right now for a reason because we're about to see how we can start passing around functions
to other functions how we can use them as values.
There's a lot that we can do because of the fact that functions are objects we can pass them around
we can store them and this is just the tip of the iceberg.
So a function expression is another way of defining a function the syntax is almost identical but we
use a variable equal sine function we can optionally leave off the name.
Otherwise we still write our parameters we still use them we still return something and we still call
them the same way.