In this video we're going to start to identify a couple of different deficiencies with our project right
now.
So a couple of things that are kind of technically working but not working as well as they possibly
could.
So the first kind of issue with our project I want to show you.
Open up your browser go to locos 3000 slash.
Sign in.
Then we're going to open up our chrome console find the network request tab and then refresh the page.
Once we do so we should see a request being made to look at those 3000 slash sign and write they're
going to click on that and then take a look at the response tab on the response tab.
We're going to see the exact content of the request or the response we're getting back from our server.
So right now we are sending back a response that has just that H smell right there for our sign in page
which totally makes sense because that is what we're calling that red dot send method with inside of
our root handler so that is the only HCM elf that is being sent from our browser over to the server.
What I want to show you something interesting.
If we go back to our elements tab we can see that there is an HMO element.
We can see there's a head a body a div and then inside the div is the form that we are generating with
our different inputs inside of it.
So the thing that is kind of interesting here is that we are only sending that div and everything inside
of it down to the browser.
But when we look at the actual HMO document that is being shown on the screen we see an e-mail element
a head a body and then all the stuff we send down.
So where's that each element coming from.
Where's the head.
Where's the body.
Where are those different elements coming from.
Well it's very simple.
The browser is going to receive the HMO that we are receiving down or sending down.
So that day right there in the browser is going to interpret this as being a partial HMO document.
In other words the browser recognizes that we are not sending a full valid e-mail document.
In other words we don't have the HDL head or body elements.
So your browser is going to automatically creates an HMO element ahead a body and then stick all the
content we set down inside of that body automatically.
So is this a bad thing.
Well I would say yeah it kind of is not the best thing in the world.
We are relying upon the browser to kind of fix up this deficiency inside the H symbol that we're sending
to it.
If we wanted to really do the right thing here we should send down a entire each e-mail document every
single time that we want to communicate some information to the browser so in other words are two views
that we have put together or these two template functions we have put together are not really complete
right now rather than just sending down a little snippet of each CML.
In both cases we should instead send down an entire valid HMO document that's gonna be the first little
thing that we're going to try to fix up.
This might sound like a real easy fix but.
Well let's start to write some code and along the way you're gonna very quickly see that one or two
little issues start to arise so I'm going to first open up my sign and J.S. file again I'm inside my
views directory your sign and J.S. we're going to start to add in some additional HDL here to turn this
thing into a valid HDL document so at the very top inside the string I'm going to say Doc type it CML
I'll put down my each CML elements and wrap that entire div I'll put in a head I'll put in a body and
make sure the body wraps that div as well like so okay.
So now we can say this we can go back over refreshed the page now if we go to the network tab we'll
see that we are now sending down an entire valid each document.
The nice thing about this is that now is a lot more obvious where we could add in some script tags and
whatnot or some linked tags to a CSX page or a title inside the head all that kind of stuff.
A lot more obvious where we're going to put those different elements so now we can repeat the same process
over in sign up.
So go to sign up J.S. and inside of here I'm going to do doc type HCM CML H CML head.
And you know what.
As I'm typing this I'm very starting very quickly starting to realize that I'm going to have some identical
text inside of sign up j ust as I currently have inside of sine in J.S. In other words these two different
files are gonna have the exact same each similar structure.
So we're just completely repeating ourself here.
And remember one of the number one rules of programming is don't repeat yourself besides just kind of
duplicating this each e-mail between these two different files I can really start to think of some interesting
issues that might start to arise if we just throw an entire each HTML document inside of here each time.
For example let's imagine that inside of every page of our application we want to add a script tag to
get some javascript file to run inside the browser to do so.
We would have to go around to all of our different view files find the head element and inside there
add a script tag like so now let's imagine that we accidentally forgot to add that script tag to the
sign in J.S. file so in that case we would have half of our application right now getting that index
dot J as file simply because we forgot to open up that other file and had in that very simple script
tag right there so clearly trying to read duplicate or rewrite this entire e-mail structure separately
for every view that we create inside of application is probably not going to be a very good long term
strategy.
So I know we just wrote out some this HDL but I'm going to immediately delete it.
We're going to figure out a better way to handle this problem so inside of sign up J Yes I'm going to
delete all stuff I just added right there.
I'm going to go back over to sign and J.S. I'm going to delete the doc type the H2 e-mail head head
body and delete the closing each melon body at the bottom as well and then make sure that I fix the
indentation like so OK so how are we going to fix this problem and how are we going to somehow only
write out all this each small stuff in one location.
The idea is that we're going to create something called a layout file.
The idea behind a lay up file is that we're going to have one single file that contains all of these
standard HMO elements that we expect to have inside of our document inside of here.
We might have a head element and we might also throw inside there's some script tags or some links and
maybe our title as well so the benefit of having this kind of layout document is that we have one location
inside of application where we can put all these different tags that need to be on every single page
of our app then any time that we want to show some content to the user.
Like actually send them a page.
We're going to display the layout.
We're going to pick a different template that we want to display like say Sign in or sign up and we're
going to essentially stick that template right there in the body.
Like so then if a user navigates over to sign in we're going to throw in the sign and template instead
so we have one layout we can't have multiple layouts inside an application and our application actually
is going to have multiple layouts.
But for right now we're just going to have one layout.
It has all these very repetitive elements inside of it and we're going just good.
Excuse me.
We're going to just swap out the body of that layout whenever we want to show a different page to the
user.
It's now we have a better idea of what we're going to be doing here.
Let's take a pause and start to implement this layout in the next video.