OK so we established that JavaScript is single threaded.
That means it's doing one thing at a time like a human sneezing.
A human does one thing which is sneezing.
It's very very difficult to also talk while you sneeze or eat while you sneeze.
Although I guess I have been driving and sneeze and I continue to drive but I basically just prayed
that I wouldn't crash because all I could do is sneeze.
So javascript does one thing at a time.
As we mentioned in the last video a lot of the time we do things that take a lot of time.
That's a bad sentence.
Commonly we do a lot of things that take time whether it's getting data from a database or an API or
trying to save something or even to set a timer.
How does something like a timer work in javascript.
So here's a simple example.
This is not exactly full code that would work.
I've made up a function called save to database.
But imagine we're we're doing something like this.
A user type something into a form it submits.
We want to grab value from the form save it to a database and that could take a couple of seconds.
It could take half a second could go really fast.
It could take 10 seconds and fail.
Does this line just not run until this finishes.
Well we have a workaround.
We've seen this a couple times before we've actually seen it a lot for these processes processes that
take time.
We pass a callback function and those functions will be executed at the appropriate time after this
interval has passed in the case of a set time.
But this doesn't really answer the question of how does it work or why does it work.
We know that this does work.
Set time out for three seconds.
We'll wait three seconds before running this code.
But how is javascript going to know.
How does it set a timer for three seconds.
If it can only do one thing at a time.
That is what we're going to talk about here.
If we go back to this example where we had our first constant log and then the alert blocked everything
else javascript is fully focused on the alert until it's gone then we move on to the next console dot
log.
Why if I replace this with a set time out pass in some function where we console dot log I happen.
Third and then an interval or a delay.
Three seconds three thousand milliseconds.
Why does this work seems like it shouldn't look nothing different is really happening except we're passing
in some some function to be called later but based off of what I've told you it seems like this should
run then javascript encounters this line which says set a timer for three seconds.
That should just take up java scripts full capacity to focus on anything it should just be setting a
timer.
How can javascript keep track of three seconds and remember to do this or call this function while also
moving on to this console dot log.
Remember that is printed out immediately and then three seconds later this is going to print out.
So if I have other code down here I could have a whole bunch of other stuff that's all going to run
assuming that it doesn't take more than three seconds that will run before this doesn't seem like it
should be able to work.
Seems like Javascript should have to focus entirely on keeping track of three seconds and knowing when
to actually execute this.
But we have a workaround.
The trick here is that the browser does the work.
JavaScript is not the same thing as your browser.
JavaScript is a language that is implemented in your browser.
But the browser itself like Chrome Safari even Internet Explorer.
Our good friend when I say good friend I mean worst enemy.
Those browsers are written in usually C++ a different programming language in the browser itself is
capable of doing certain tasks that JavaScript sucks at or things that take time.
They're handed off to the browser.
So javascript says here is this thing I need you to do for me.
The browser takes over.
And then when it's done it reminds javascript.
OK your turn again.
So this is a really key thing to understand.
JavaScript is not setting a timer or keeping track of how many seconds have gone by.
JavaScript is not sending a request to an API.
The browser actually handles it.
And this is something that honestly I went a long time without understanding about JavaScript and it's
not crucial to be able to make a request or use that time out.
You've already done that in this course.
But I think it helps a lot to understand why we use callbacks and why we get to things like promises
and async functions.
So browsers have a set of these API is called Just generally web APIs and they can handle certain tasks
in the background like making a request.
That takes time set time out which we saw here.
That takes time.
The browser is capable of doing those things in the background.
So javascript is going to encounter certain lines of code like this line javascript knows how to do
that then it gets the set timeout and it's going to pass it off to the browser and say please remind
me after three seconds has has elapsed or hey browser you set this timer for me.
And when you're done give me this function back.
So that's why we pass a callback.
It just keeps plowing along.
It hands this off to the browser the browser is in charge of keeping time and then it reminds javascript
Hey here's that thing I want you to do or you wanted me to remind you of.
So javascript doesn't get hung up its single thread is blocked by this set timeout because it's passed
off to something entirely different it's passed off to the browser then that callback function in the
case of said timeout when it's time when three seconds has elapsed the browser is going to take that
function the one that just concerned that log something and put it on the call stack.
So this is where the calls that comes back in.
So let's take a closer look with some diagrams here.
We have similar code I think different text.
I print first I print second seven ahead.
Yeah.
Okay.
I capitalized it here.
It doesn't matter.
So javascript is represented by this javascript logo.
It's going to encounter this line the interpreter sees this line.
It knows how to handle it.
Constant log I print first it runs at then it gets to set timeout set timeout.
It's something that the browser will do for us or it will do for JavaScript.
So this is my personification my browser.
Can you set a timer for 3 seconds.
The browser says Sure thing.
So remember this is separate from javascript.
This is the browser itself.
Setting a time.
Keeping track of three thousand milliseconds.
So then javascript is free to continue on.
It doesn't have anything in its call stack that has to do with that timeout.
Instead it moves on to console that log ie print second so it prints that out and there's a little time
icon over here that signifies 3 seconds have elapsed.
Now the browser says time's up javascript.
Make sure you run that callback now and it places the callback.
This function right here.
I use an arrow function in this example.
I just use a regular function expression here.
It places that function back in the call stack so javascript knows oh I need to do this thing.
So javascript does not keep the time same thing with making a request.
Javascript does not make the request itself the browser and its Web API is handle they manage all of
that and they simply tell javascript they add to the call stack when it's appropriate.
Here's the next thing for you to do so javascript then now has a new function in the call stack and
it executes it and it considers logs ie print after 3 seconds.
So understanding this relationship will help a lot.
Once we get to promises and actually making requests JavaScript can only do one thing at a time it's
single threaded but in special cases when we are doing things like setting a timeout requesting data
or adding an event listener to whatever it div and ally.
Javascript isn't going to sit there and just listen nonstop to see if something has been clicked.
That's handed off to the browser and the browser is in charge of deciding when to actually add a new
callback or a function to the call stack for JavaScript to execute.
Here's this really cool website I found that helps explain how this all works so you can type code over
here.
If you do play around with this it's called loop.
It doesn't work well or it doesn't work at all.
If you use error functions or any of the newer javascript syntax so just stick to some basic stuff but
here's what it does it actually slows down or mimics the execution and what happens behind the scenes
with JavaScript and the handoff to web API.
Which is what this box over here represents.
Here's the call stack.
Here's where the API is so javascript is going to encounter this line.
The interpreter it can run this immediately and it will constantly log.
Hi everyone.
Then it hit set time out and you'll see visually that the web API is takes over and you'll see visually
that the set time out the interval or the delay is being kept track of over here for 7 seconds.
It's what this one is set to and then another set time out.
This one for 3 seconds will also be handled over here and in the meantime javascript will move on.
If I add in let's do at least one more console that log console that log by.
For real everyone javascript moves on to this and then when the browser the web API is over here decide
or calculate that the time is is up 7 seconds or 3 seconds they add the callback here not directly to
the call stack.
They added to something called the callback queue.
We don't have to get too far into the weeds here but essentially this is a place where callbacks are
added and JavaScript will draw upon this cue.
It's a way of it of javascript to know OK what's something that I need to do next.
That is coming back from the web API.
OK so let's see what happens when I click save and run.
I'll pause first thing call stack now has one function call constant log.
Hi everyone.
OK.
Simple enough so it does that.
Now it gets to this set timeout function that is added to the call stack but javascript realizes oh
this is one of those things I can handoff to the browser so it doesn't take charge of this it hands
it to web API.
The web APIs there you go.
So it doesn't run the code it doesn't run the callback.
How I just broke it.
OK let me pause again at the right moment.
There we go.
There's a timeout that is being kept track of over here and JavaScript moves on to the next line which
is another set timeout.
So the same thing happens.
It's added to the call stack for a moment javascript then passes it off to the Web APIs and says OK.
When when that interval or the delay is over.
Give me that callback back and I'll executed at the right time.
So we resume javascript moves on to these two console dot logs.
That the first one.
The second one.
They both run and then the three second time out finished.
Now there's only one over here the seven second one the three second one finished and it added the web
API added that callback here which is supposed to console that log.
Oink oink.
It added that to the callback Q Which javascript will now draw upon and you'll see that it did not click
resume.
There we go those functions are then executed one at a time.
They both console that log and we're done.
So let's do it one more time.
Just quickly I want pause you can see the web API is take control of those timers javascript moves on.
It has one thread it keeps going and then it draws upon that callback cue when the web APIs have placed
one of those functions in the callback queue that relationship is very important to understand.
So let's pause and now I'll have my console open so you can just see the whole thing as they get printed.
So we get hi everyone.
Then the next line which will be by everyone then by for real everyone.
Then that first callback three second one is added to the queue we get oink oink.
And then the seven second interval or timeout finishes.
So we get move.
Okay.
So I'll stop here.
Like I said this is a very fundamental part of JavaScript.
This is why we use callbacks all the time.
This is how we get around the fact that JavaScript is not a multitasker.
It does one thing at a time.
So when we pass a function as an argument as a callback function two things like set time out which
the web API handle those functions are not called right away.
Javascript doesn't worry about it javascript just passes it off and continues on its merry way until
the web API is at some point place that function in the callback queue where javascript then draws upon
and says oh OK you want me to do this thing I guess it's time.
So it does not do the hard work of keeping track of time.
It doesn't do the hard work of making a request and that's why we use callback so frequently for these
asynchronous things.
These these functions that take time and I need to make that clear because now we're gonna go more into
async J.S. we'll talk about how we make requests and that takes a lot of time and sometimes it sucks
to write a ton of callbacks which is where promises come in.
So this has been setting the stage.
I think it's very important to do.
I have taught promises and async functions without really going into detail of how this works.
But I think this will help.
I hope.
And please leave some feedback if you think I'm just confusing you or it's not really relevant because
you absolutely can learn this stuff without understanding what the web apps are.
And the call stack but I think it will help maybe.
So let me know.
All right I'll be quiet.
And next we'll move on to talking more about callbacks some of the problems with having a bunch of callbacks
and how we can get around them with promises.