Now that we've seen code sharing an action I want to go into some of the behind the scenes details to
give you a better sense of what's really going on here.
The first thing I want you to understand is that any time that we use no J.S. to execute a javascript
file we're not just directly executing the code you see inside this file.
Technically the code inside this file is being wrapped automatically inside of a function and then executed.
So in other words if we run it node index J.S. Right now node is going to find all the contents inside
the index dot J S file and then it's going to wrap it inside of a function.
So the function looks like this is just a simple function declaration that has some number of arguments.
This function is then going to be automatically invoked by node what's really important to understand
here is the different arguments that are being passed into this function.
In total there are five different arguments that are automatically provided.
One thing on a mention is that this process is kind of invisible and we're never going to really see
this function being declared with our own eyes.
However there are some ways we can kind of detect that it is being placed inside of our code.
I'll show you that in just a moment.
I first want to tell you about the five different arguments that get passed into this function automatically.
The first argument is something called the exports object.
This exports object is basically equivalent to the module that exports property that we just saw a moment
ago.
We can assign different variables or functions or objects or whatever else to this exports object to
make it available inside of other files.
Now we almost always use module dot exports as opposed to this first argument of exports.
The reason is that there's kind of a little corner case around using this expert's variable.
So to be honest with you it's best to just kind of forget that this first argument or this X experts
thing exists altogether.
Instead we kind of just pretend that the only way that we share code between different files is module
that exports.
That's it.
Now I'm sure as I go into this that sounds really confusing but don't worry I'm going to give you a
lot of examples of this.
Very quickly let's move on to the second argument.
The second argument is require this is a function that we can use to load up a different file and get
access to all the different variables that get exported from it.
The third argument is called the module argument.
This is an object that defined some different properties about the current file that is being executed.
So in the case of say the index not J.S. file that third argument of module would contain some information
relevant to the index dot J.S. file the fourth argument is underscore underscore file name.
So notice that there are technically two underscores right there.
This is a string that is the full path plus the file name of that file.
And finally the last argument is underscore underscore once again to underscores their dir name.
And this is the full part like the directory that the current file lives in.
Now I want to show you or I just mentioned a second ago that we can kind of detect the presence of these
different arguments.
So let's go back over to our index dot j ust file.
We're gonna make a couple of modifications to it and in doing so we're going to kind of detect that
these different things exist okay.
So back inside of index dot J.S. going to delete the code I have inside of here right now and I'm going
to replace it with console not log arguments.
Now you may have learned earlier on INSIDE the course that we can reference all the arguments that are
passed to a function by just declaring the special variable arguments.
So in theory if our code inside of index dot J.S. is being wrapped inside of a function then arguments
should it print out these five different arguments that I just said were being passed to this kind of
imaginary or invisible function.
I'm going to try saving this file to go back over to my terminal and I'll run node index dot J.S. once
again when I do so I get a big console log here.
This console log is kind of hard to read but we can kind of walk through it and get a sense of what's
going on you'll notice that we have an object and it has some indices of 0 1 2 3 4 inside of it.
So this is really an array of all the different arguments that were passed to this invisible function.
The first argument or 0 right here is the exports object and again we're kind of going to just ignore
that that even exists.
The second argument is that require function if we go down a little bit you'll see the argument at index
2.
So the third argument is that module thing and this has some information about the current file that
is being executed and then finally the fourth and fifth arguments are first.
The file name which is the full path plus the file name of the file that's being executed.
And then finally the dir name or just the directory that that current file is in now printing all this
stuff out with that arguments variable is kind of confusing so let's just go through very quickly and
console log out some of these different individual variables.
So I could do a console log of require again.
We don't really see that function being declared anywhere inside of index dot J.S. but it is technically
here because when this code gets executed we can imagine that a magic function or an invisible function
automatically is going to wrap our code and of your one of the arguments is that require function.
So we're going to save this.
Run that file again and we'll see just that console log of required.
So that's the entire council log of the required function and we can do the same thing with module can
save that run again.
And we see the entire module object.
Again this has some information about the file that is being executed then we can do underscore underscore
again notice that there are two underscores here.
File Name will save that and run it again.
That's the full path plus the file name of this file.
And then finally we can do underscore underscore dir name save that and we'll get just the directory
that this file lives in.
You might be thinking that understanding or getting access to the file name and the door name is kind
of pointless.
But there actually are some really interesting use cases around no J.S. where it's very handy to understand
the name of the current file or the directory that it's in for the most part.
Whenever we are running some node code the only really are real arguments we care about they're being
passed in to each of these different files is as you might guess they require function and the module
object OK.
So now we understand that there's some kind of invisible arguments being passed into each of our different
files.
Let's take another quick pause and we're gonna start to focus on how node actually shares code between
these different files through the use of the require function and the module dot experts object.
So one more quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.