Well I may have just lied to you.
We're not quite a variables.
We have one more very quick topic to discuss with numbers.
Something called NASA.
It is a special value in JavaScript.
It stands for Not a number.
And it is a number in JavaScript.
It's considered a numeric value that represents something that is not a number.
So there's a couple of different ways you could arrive at not a number.
Here are two simple ones.
If you try and divide zero by zero you'll get not a number.
If you try and take not a number and add a number to it.
The answer is still not a number which makes sense.
You couldn't take not a number and add five to it.
The answer logically would be not a number.
So you can type not a number like this.
It is capital N A N if you did and and like this it's not really going to work.
It needs to be capitalized correctly.
It's a very special value in JavaScript and it is a number as I mentioned already.
If we do zero divided by zero we get not a number.
If we take not a number we add five.
It's still not a number.
There are two other values I mentioned we have infinity which we can generate by doing something like
1 divided by zero javascript just has a way of representing a value of infinity.
There's no way to store that as a number an actual number that you could see.
So we have a special value called Infinity.
There's also a negative infinity as you can see here.
And we also have zero and negative zero which sometimes throws people off negative zero is its own value
in JavaScript as well.
But the point here is really about not a number.
If you do encounter not a number it is a value that means this is not a number.
It doesn't necessarily mean something went wrong.
Sometimes you you have code where you're expecting not a number or it could be a possibility.
So it's not an error necessarily but it means this is not standard math or JavaScript is going to have
a hard time representing this number or this value as a true numeric value.
So that's an and not a number.
Now we're actually going on to variables.