You've now got the full sign up process put together so a user can go to the form right here see the
form on the screen submit the form and then create a brand new account.
But there's still two other interactions we need to put together.
We need to make sure that a user can sign out of our application.
We also need to make sure that once they sign out they can sign back in as well.
So let's get started putting that additional functionality together.
The first thing I want to do is first add in some different root names.
The two routes so we currently have.
Right now we show these sign up form at our root root.
It's going to change the initial abduct get right here to sign up instead.
Now whenever a user goes to local those 3000 slash sign up they'll see the sign up form also change
the submission right here to a app dot post slash sign up as well.
Now if we save that and we go back over and I try to navigate to Local three thousand we'll see an error
message.
So moving forward if you want to sign up to our application you have to go to slash sign up once I go
there I can still see the original form okay.
Now we've got some better you or else put together.
Let's also add in some sign out functionality so to sign out.
I'm gonna go down to right above our app don't listen line and I'll add in a app does get sign out and
points.
So if anyone ever makes a request to slash sign out we're going to try to sign them out of our application
and then we will redirect them back to the sign in roots or something like that so inside of here if
you want to sign out our user all we have to do is essentially tell the user or their browser more specifically
to forget all the information that is stored inside their cookie.
Because remember the information side the cookie is what alone proves that someone is authenticated
with our application so in order to log them out we're going to receive reckoned rez then we're going
to say it record session is equal to no.
That essentially is going to take whatever their current session object is and more or less forget it.
So now whenever cookie session takes a look at the rec dot session property remember we are using the
cookie session for managing our cookie.
It's going to see that we set it to null and that is a sign that we want to forget all the information
stored inside the cookie so when a user makes a request to slash sign out the response we sent back
is going to have a set cookie property inside of it that says clear out any cookie data you currently
have in addition to saying the record session right there we'll also send back you are logged out here.
Let's test that out really quickly.
I'm gonna go back over and navigate to a local host 3000 slash sign out.
It's now told you are logged out.
Also very interestingly if you have your network console open you can click on the request we just made
inside of here you'll see Response Headers and we now have a set cookie that says Express call in session
equals nothing.
So we are essentially telling the browser we now want you to store no information inside the cookie
at all.
So that's how we're going to sign out.
If we now go back to our sign up route so slash sign up will now see that our ideas undefined because
we no longer have any session information about the person who is making requests to our server.
Now let's also put together these sign in route that I'll go right underneath our sign out and I'll
add in an app not get sign in so remember just like sign up.
This is going to be a two step process.
We first need to send a form to the user that they can use to enter their email and password when a
user submits the form.
We need to create a post request handler to handle that form submission.
So inside of it getting sign in right here that means we want to show the form to the user.
So inside of here I'll do a resort sent we'll do a multi line string so don't forget your back ticks.
Then go up to our current form and I'm just going to copy all this HD e-mail right here.
I'll go back down.
I'm gonna paste our HD in I'm going to delete the line that says your I.D. is blah blah blah.
I'm also going to delete the password confirmation as we don't need a password confirmation when we
are just signing in.
And then on the button element I'll change the text to say sign in instead of sign up
okay.
That looks good.
Let's save that.
Go back over and test it out so back inside my browser I'll navigate to slash sign in and there's my
sign and form.
It's now let's make sure we also have a post request handler to deal with this form being submitted
so I'll also put inside of here an app post flash sign in I'll receive rec in RES we're probably going
to have to look up some records inside of our user repository.
Second mark this function as async and then let's take a quick pause right here and we'll start to fill
out the implementation in just a moment.