Next up we'll see the second use case for spread.
If we go back to this paragraph of gibberish from Indian spread syntax allows an interval such as an
array to be expanded in places where zero or more elements for array laterals are expected.
So we can use those three dots instead of an array literal.
We just saw how we can use it in a function call in an array literal.
It does something very similar.
It takes an automobile and it spreads it out.
It takes the individual pieces and in the case of an array it copies them over into a new destination
array so we can use it to combine arrays to make a copy of an array.
There is a whole bunch of situations where you may end up using spread.
So let's check it out.
I have a simple example over here.
I have some arrays of really cool animals.
My favorite animals out there.
We've got several pods which are basically squid cuttlefish not Alice's.
So there's a couple examples in here.
We've got gastro pods.
Giant African Snail variable neon slug a really cool animal and Nigeria which include things like jellyfish
and in corals and Hydra and a couple other things.
Anyway we're going to combine them in a few different ways.
Also stick around at the end.
If you want to see some photos and videos of these some of them are pretty cool.
But I won't waste your time in the middle of the video with that.
So quick biology lesson in both of these right here several pods and gastro pods.
They're both considered molluscs.
So if I wanted to make an array with both of them called molluscs or mollusks I think it's the correct
Latin term I could use spread like this stuff several pods comma.
Dot dot dot gastro pods and this will make me a new array with both the contents of those arrays combined
into one.
So let's take a look.
What do we have over here.
Malaysia has six elements.
We had three from several pods and three from gastro pods.
Notice the order.
I put several pods first so we get those three elements first and then gastro pods afterwards.
In the original arrays are untouched.
We're just making a copy or actually a new array with copies of both arrays inside.
If I instead did it the other way around and I did three dots with gastro pods first and then three
dots spread with several pods for low pods.
You can see the order is different now so we have the first three from gastro pods.
Second three from several pods.
The order does matter.
Also we could add in other elements if we wanted to that weren't present from these arrays.
I could add in upfront which another mollusk we could add if I wanted to add at the beginning a garden
slug it would look like this.
I just added as an element and then comma and then spread comma spread more and then we go.
I could also combine more than one array.
I could do all three of these arrays.
They would be considered invertebrates.
So const inverts equals and then dot dot dot.
Let's do an idol area first.
Dot dot dot.
Gastro pods dot dot dot.
Need my comma dot dot dot.
Several iPods.
And if I look at inverts we now have an array of eight elements all of them combined.
Spread is great.
In situations where you need to combine arrays but it's not doing something we couldn't do before.
We have already seen how to use can cat.
So for example several pods dot can cat gastro pods.
It gives us the same result that we had from this line where we're taking the data from several pods
and combining it with gastro pods.
And if we look at the originals they're still unchanged.
This is just a shorter syntax it's easier to see and easier to reorder as you like.
And we can add an element wherever we want to.
We can do multiple arrays combined there's a lot we can do and one of the most common use cases for
spread is actually just to make a copy of an array.
If I just want a second version of Nigeria actually let's go with several pods.
Nigeria is annoying to spell.
I could do const self copy equals array literal brackets.
Dot dot dot several pods and if I look at self copy I now have the same data and they have unique references.
So they are not triple equals to each other self copy triple equals several iPods is false versus if
I had just made an array like concept or it made a variable concept copy equals Sevilla pods copy triple
equals several pods will be true as we've seen before because they are referencing the same reference
they're pointing to the same reference but when we use spread here it is going to make a clone a new
array in memory with a new unique reference but that does not extend to nested arrays or if we had objects
inside of the arrays those won't be cloned.
The references will remain the same.
So it does not go multiple levels deep so we can do this with arrays.
We can also spread other types of data into an array.
There's not many that you would do it with but one example would be a string.
If we wanted to get a string like let's say we had a b c d e f g imagine this is the whole alphabet
and I wanted an array where each character was one element I could do dots split which we've seen already
and you pass in an empty string saying split this string on nothing split on every character and it
gives us an array just like that but I can also do this.
ABC TFG and spread it One two three.
And it's the same idea what we had here with an array when we spread it.
We're telling javascript to iterate over this interval and for each item in there added as an element
in the array which is what we did earlier with a different array rather than a string but the same process
so we can spread strings.
Probably not that common that you would spread a bunch of them into one array but we could we could
do a b c comma D E F comma hello and then spread these guys.
And that's what we end up with ABC DCF and then hello at the end.
So that's pretty much it for spreading into an array literal.
Same idea as spreading into a function call.
We're taking an honorable and breaking it into pieces and moving them or copying them to a destination.
In this case it's an array that we're creating.
And as promised I'll show you some of those animals if you want to check them out.
Some of my favorite guys on earth guys favorite animals.
We've got the Dumbo Octopus.
Very adorable tiny octopus very cute giant African snail horrifyingly huge snails they're giant as their
name tells you.
Quite quite intimidating would not want to hold one of those in my hands.
Then we've got a really cool animal called a variable neon slug.
It's a species of new to brink these really cool flat worms that live in the ocean.
Lots of them have beautiful beautiful colors.
You can see here.
And then finally my favorite the flamboyant cuttlefish.
They're tiny adorable little creatures with incredible skin and ability to display these patterns and
change their the shape of their body.
Very hypnotic anyway.
So those are some of my favorite animals.
Thanks for joining me on cults animal.
Our back to JavaScript.
That's coming up next.
More spread.
Wait wait.
I forgot to show you the best part.
Here we go.
The way that they eat this appendage comes out horrifying and then snaps back.
OK that's it for that.