All right.
Let's get started.
So the first thing we're going to need to do is to make sure that we can detect whenever a file changes
inside of some given directory.
So again for that we're going to use that choke in our package.
We first need to make sure that we install this package into our project.
So to do so we can go over to our command line.
I'll make sure that I'm inside of my project directory.
And then once inside of here I can automatically install that package by executing npm install stroke
ADR I'm probably pronouncing it differently every time I say the word.
You get the idea.
So very quickly we're going to install it.
And that's pretty much it.
So now we can go back over to our Ed over here.
We'll see that if we open up our package not Jason File.
We now have a dependency section side of here that lists out that depends.
Dependency that we just installed will also see that there is the node modules directory that was created
that contains the code for the dependency that we just installed.
So there's choke it out right there.
Once again we can see that there are many other folders inside of here as well.
These are other dependencies that are required by Chuck in our.
All right.
So I'll go back over to my index not just file and we'll figure out how to use this joke in our thing.
So inside of here I'm going to first delete the console log.
I'm going to require Ian choke it out so I'll say choke it out is require
an inside of here.
We can start this thing up really easily and tell it to start to watch the current directory using something
very similar to the code snippet that we saw just a moment ago on the read me page so I'm going to say
choke it are dot watch.
I'll put in a dot to mean.
Watch the current working directory and then we can either change on a event listener and watch for
all that's going to essentially call our function right here.
Anytime any event happens.
However if we do that there are some other events that are going to be emitted by the choke in our library.
Besides just when a file is added edited or deleted.
So we're going to be a little bit more specific and we're going to tell chuck it are that we want to
run some code only when one of three different things occur.
So I'm going to remove the dot on I just added and I'm going to go down to the next line indent in and
then chain on a dot on statement.
Notice that I did not put a semicolon on a line above the inside of here.
I'll say add and I'll put in a function that will do a console log of file added or then indent again
onto the next line.
I'll do on change I want to do again do a console log of file changed and then finally I'll do an on
unlink I'll throw in a function and once again do a console log of I'll unlinked OK.
So let's save this.
And without really saying anything about the code we just wrote I'm gonna go back over to my index dot
J.S. or something to my turtle and we're going to run our index dot J.S. file.
We can either run it by doing node index dot J.S. or by running the watch its command directly.
Right now it doesn't really make a difference because we don't have any CLIA arguments to pass in or
anything like that.
So go ahead and run this and right away I can see a ton of spam right here saying file added.
Again and again and again and again.
So what's going on here.
Before I explain that let's try going back over to our Ed inside my project directory.
I'm going to make a new file called Test dot J.S. as soon as I create that file.
I'll then go back over to my terminal.
I don't really see a change here just yet but whatever inside of test dot ust are going to do a console
log of test and then save the file if I go back over I can now see a council log file changed and then
finally if I go back over and delete this test at J ust file
and go to my terminal once again I'll see file unlinked.
OK so let's talk about what all these console logs really mean to us.
All right.
So inside the next dot j ust file we added on three different event listeners.
The first one was at I bet you can guess what that means.
The ad callback right here is going to be invoked whenever we create a new file inside of our project
directory.
But that's not the only time that it gets called the add function or the ad callback gets called anytime
that a file is created or when choke it our first starts up in sees a file inside of a project directory.
So you noticed when we started up our program we immediately saw a ton of different console log statements.
That's because choke da saw all the different files inside of our project directory it saw indexed at
J.S. and package dash lock Jace on a package lock and also slot everything inside the node modules directory
as well.
And so every single time that it saw one of these new files that it started to track it invoked this
ad event right here or triggered the ad event and invoked our callback function which is why we saw
that spam of file added right away.
Next up as soon as we changed a file like when we made a change to the test dot J.S. file and saved
it.
That triggered the change event which means that we changed a file inside of our project finally when
we deleted the test J.S. file.
Well we think of that as deleting but internally chuck it out refers to that as unblinking a file.
So this unlink event right here means that a file was deleted inside of our project directory.
So that's the meaning of these different events the change one is really the only one that's kind of
obvious.
Hey if I was change it again unlink means that if I was deleted ad means that a file was added or it
means that choke it out is starting for the first time.
And it's kind of seeing all these different files for the very first time and registering their existence.
All right.
So now do we understand these different callbacks.
Let's take a pause right here.
Come back the next video and I want to mention something kind of awkward about the behavior of this
ad event.