OK so that was a quick taste of XM L H GDP request.
It's a mouthful both to say and also to type especially once we get working with a bunch of callbacks
and nesting things it becomes very messy.
So this is where fetch comes in.
Fetch is the newer way of making requests via javascript.
It is something that essentially was created because XY chars example HDP requests were just obnoxious
or difficult to remember clunky things got messy with callbacks I don't support promises so fetch is
the solution.
The only problem with Fetch is that it's not supported in Internet Explorer.
If you take a look on MDA and can see under I'm on the page called fetch API down at the bottom browser
compatibility what we care about is this part right here.
These are all more advanced features but this part here fetch in general no support in i.e. the main
thing.
Aside from the cleaner syntax and easier to remember terminology the main advantage is that it supports
promises which we spent a ton of time on.
I hope by now if you if you made it through the promises section you can understand why promises are
useful especially when we're making a bunch of requests so let's see an example.
This is what it looks like we call a method called fetch.
We pass in some U.R.L. then that returns a promise and then of course the promise is either resolved
or rejected.
If it is resolved the value is resolved with is a response object.
It contains information about the response.
Otherwise we can catch a rejected promise.
If for some reason the fetch didn't work for internet was just not connected for some reason that would
be one example.
This code would run.
So why don't we go back to our app J.S. This is what we had from the last few videos.
Let's rewrite this using fetch.
This is done with creating a new X AML HDP request.
I'm going to copy the URL from the very first request we send right here so we can recreate this and
then I'll comment it out.
Okay so we're going to call fetch and pass in that you are.
So if I just ran this code in my browser I'll save it to a variable so we can check on the status of
the promise.
We'll call this.
Well I don't want to go with promise how about prom.
If we look at prom.
No not promo.
Well it's now been resolved.
If I just pasted in and run it immediately it's pending but eventually it's either resolved or rejected.
And really all I want to show you here is that we're getting a promise back from that fetch method.
So in order to run code when it is resolved we need to use then in order to run code.
If it's rejected we need to use catch so we can change on our dot then dot then it will be resolved
with a response object.
We can call it response and if you want to learn more about the details of the API.
If you go to M.D. then there's pretty there's a lot of articles actually about it.
We've got this overview using fetch fetch basic concepts very useful stuff.
But here's the key thing that you should know.
The fetch method takes one mandatory argument the path that you are well that we're trying to fetch
and it returns a promise that resolves to the response to the request.
So the value that we would have that is passed in to our callback when this fetch promise hopefully
resolves is a response object and if we console that log that response object you'll see it's a little
different than what we've seen from X jars.
I'll try running this.
Refresh my page.
This is what we get back.
A response object it contains a status code 200 which means.
OK that's good.
It also has things like the you are all that we requested and then the data that we want is located
in the body but it's not as simple as reading a property from this body.
If you notice what it says here it's a readable stream without going into too much detail.
If we take a look at the response page the response referenced on empty n this is a response we get
back.
It's resolved with a response object you can name that parameter or whatever but it will be a response
object if we read a little bit more about it.
Scroll down somewhere on here.
Whereas body here's body it is a readable stream.
Now what is a readable stream.
It is a stream of byte data and this is one of the key differences from using x ray charles.
Aside from the actual syntactical differences when you make a request you get a response object back.
The content of that response is included as a readable stream and a stream is a way of accessing data
that could be super large it could be a massive amount of data and you can access it and process it
as you go.
Now for us that doesn't really matter.
We're not accessing extremely large things.
We're doing simple request and just did get some data from an API so it doesn't really matter except
that we have to be aware of how we read that stream.
Fortunately if we go back to the response object we scroll down to methods.
There's a nice method called Dot Jason.
It takes a response stream and reads it to completion.
So right now our response has not actually been read to completion.
It's a response object but the stream has not been read.
Fortunately we have a very very easy way of doing it.
As I just showed you response dot Jason the only downside to this is that it takes time it's asynchronous
that stream could be very very large.
And reading it fully could take a while relatively compared to something like Jason dock pass.
So because of that this Jason method returns a promise.
If we consider that log response stopped Jason this is what we get.
It's another promise so we have a promise returned from this and then another promise from this.
So if we actually want the data we need to do another dot then and it will be resolved with the data
that is read and passed.
So now we could counsel that log data so it's an extra step.
We compare that to what we did up here.
All we had to do was Jason that pass the response dot response text.
Here we call a Jason method and then when it finishes it's resolved we can have access to the data and
there we go.
Now we have our API data with the results and we can do whatever we want with them.
So why don't we do something simple like print out each planet.
So we would have data inside of this dot then callback after we've read the Jason data dot and then
response no results I think is what it was.
And we'll loop over that for let planet of data dot results.
We can double check this data is this whole thing.
Results we'll do what we did earlier counseled out log planet dot name run it again.
There we go.
We're getting every planet's name at least the first ten planets that we're getting from this one API
call sending a request to this you url.
So this is the first part of fetch when things go right.
We don't have any errors or if we do we don't know about them.
So let's put a catch in here.
If fetch returns a promise it's resolved or rejected.
Right now we're not catching it.
So why don't we catch and do something where we console that log.
Something went wrong with fetch and then we can console that log error as well.
Let's see what happens right now.
Nothing should happen.
We should still see the same result.
But why don't I try fetching some you are well that doesn't exist if I visit this you around myself
just in the browser
this page is not the page you're looking for.
This is a forum for error page.
And when we got to 4 0 4 with XY chars with this approach our failure callback ran this on error callback
was executed.
However Fetch is different if we try and send a request to this you URL which I am telling you now will
give us a forum for let's take a look huh.
We did get a 4 or 4 but our catch never ran uncut in promise.
Unexpected token.
So what's happening here is that we're actually getting the H team out for a four page back and we're
trying to pass that as Jason.
But it's not Jason.
So why don't we start by just consider logging the response in here
because it seems like if the status code is for a four then the dot then should not run and that seems
like an error where our catch should run but that's not how Fetch is set up.
If we look at the response status is for a fourth but it still worked it still ran our DOT catch the
promise was resolved.
So what's going on.
Well this is just how Fetch is set up if you take a look at this paragraph here on the using fetch overview
and MDA on the promised return from fetch will not reject on error status or HDP DDP error status even
if the response is a 4 or 4 which is not found or 500.
Instead it resolves normally and it will only reject on network failure or if anything prevented the
request from completing.
So this catch is not going to run.
The promise will not be rejected just because the server responded with not a 200.
Not an OK status code because we still got a response.
So that's all that this cares about.
This code runs whenever you get a response whether it's the one you wanted or not unlike our ex H.R.
where the failure callback would run the error callback did run on a 400 error or 4 or 4.
Excuse me.
So fetch will only return a rejected promise in the event that your internet's not working.
The request can't be made at all and we just don't get a response.
And I can show you that if I turn my internet off.
So that's what I'm going to do.
Okay.
It's off.
Let's refresh now.
It's actually running that catch callback.
Something went wrong with fetch type error failed to fetch so it didn't get a response period.
So the then callback was ignored.
The promise was rejected and this runs.
So instead of this callback here if we want to ensure that we actually got a status code 200 and OK
before we try and read Jason before we do anything with it what we can do is check if response Dot.
OK.
That is a property on the response.
Well we don't see it here but we did see it earlier.
If that's the case then we can run this code.
Or another way of doing it would be if response is not OK then we could console that log something error
not status 200 hundred and then we can wrap this in an.
Else because we only want to attempt passing if the request came back.
Status.
Two hundred.
If instead we got a four or four we'll just print this out and we could also console that log response
dot status.
So now if we tried again here we go error not status two hundred we got four or four and this code did
not run.
So this is one option but we also have a way of using this catch.
If I throw an error instead of a dot then it will trigger the callback in my dot catch so I could rewrite
it like this.
Throw new error if you've never seen how to throw an error.
It looks like this will say status code error
and then interpolate using dollar sign instead of a string template literal.
I'll put response dot status here.
Okay so let's test it out.
This U.R.L. should give us a 4 or 4 if we try and visit it in our browser it gives us a 4 or 4.
Earlier we saw that we got a 4 4 status code which means not found then the promise will still be resolved.
This code runs up until this point.
This will be true because it is not OK.
So then we throw a new error which should trigger this callback and the error will be this error we're
passing through when we throw an error.
We have access to it here in our catch so let's see.
There we go.
Something went wrong with fetch status code error for 0 4.
So this is the basics of fetch.
I wish that you didn't have to worry about the status code but that's where Acciona comes in which is
another improvement upon fetch.
In my opinion this is still better than what we saw here although we were making two requests here.
But as you can imagine with promises which we automatically get from fetch it's pretty easy to change
and make multiple requests in a row which is what we'll talk about in the very next video.