Last video we spoke about something called a layout.
So let's start to put one together right now.
Remember the goal this is to have some reuse of the different each HTML elements we want to have on
every page of our application so to get started I'm going to go back over to my project directory.
I'm going to find the view's admin folder then inside of admin I'm going to make a new file called layout
that J.S. as I mentioned just a moment ago an application commonly will only have one layout.
So that means essentially at one H.G. it kind of scaffold or skeleton that gets reused for every page
in an application for our application.
We're going to have two different layouts eventually we're going to have one layout that is customized
for the administration panel.
We're going to have a second layout that is customized for the actual user facing side of our Web site
which is the product listing Andy cart so the reason we are creating creating this layout file inside
the admin directory is that this is going to be the layout files specifically for the administration
side of our product so then inside of here we'll do a module that exports.
This is going to overall look very similar to the view files or the template fold files that we just
put together.
So I'm going to expect that we're going to call this function once again with an object and I'm going
to expect that it will have a property called Content.
Content is going to be a string that is essentially whatever we want to put in this body tag right here.
So inside of our string template that we're going to return from this function we're going to write
out all of our very common each small elements.
And then inside the body we're going to do some string interpolation and throw this content argument
inside there.
So that's how we're going to essentially inject the contents of sine and template or sign up template
so inside of here we'll do a return to line string lock type.
It's simple I'll do my each team T.M. I'll do my head
the body and then inside the body will do some string interpolation.
So remember that is our dollar sign curly braces and inside there will throw content like so it's now
in order to make use of this layout.
We're gonna go around to all of our different views which right now is just our sign in and sign up
J.S. files.
We're going to require in this layout function and we're going to wrap that each smell that we are returning
inside of each of those different functions inside a sign in and sign up with the function right here.
So I'm going to go to sign and J.S. at the top I'll say layout is up one directory layout and then rather
than directly returning the string I'm going to instead say layout I'm going to pass in an object it's
going to have a content property and the value of that is going to be the string that we are.
Where were returning right here.
Well then close off that object on the other side along with the setup parentheses.
And I'm going to fix that multi line string just indented to make everything kind of lineup like so.
So again recalling layouts we're passing in an object that has a content property the content property
is a string.
So then inside of layout J.S. we're going to receive that content property but all of our typical H
channel structure together.
And then through the content inside the body now we can repeat that same process inside of our sign
up J.S. file.
So I'll find sign up J.S.
again at the very top of this file I will require in my layout function well then call me out right
here.
I'm going to pass in an object with the content property or close off the object and the parentheses
for the function on the other side.
Save it and we end up with something like this right here.
Okay.
So this looks pretty good.
Now if we ever need to make any change to the kind of root structure of our e-mail document we will
open up our layouts J.S. file and we can make changes to this thing directly right here.
So if we ever want to make sure that every page on our Administration panel has say a script tag or
link tag or whatever else we can add that directly into our layout right here that we'll make sure that
every single page gets that little snippet of each email.
That means that we don't have to duplicate the stuff all over the place inside of our app.
Let's save this and do a quick test so I'm just going to go back over to my sign and root refresh.
Yep everything still works.
I'll go to my sign up out everything still works okay.
So that's definitely a good improvement so that's gonna fix up one big deficiency inside of our project
but there's still one other big ticket item I want to discuss.
So let's take a pause right here.
Come back next video discuss the other big issue.
This is going to be the last big thing that we have to fix up inside this before we start to focus on
the product side of our application.