In the last video I gave you a general description of the breadth first search algorithm.
I now want to add on just a little bit more to that and describe how we're going to adapt this algorithm
for our purposes.
So I had said in the last video that we start off at say movies we take a look at the children we take
that big list and we throw it into this array.
We then start to iterate through the array and take a look at each individual item and then for each
item we find all of its children and critically I said we would take all those children.
So in this case the children of s RC because that's the first element and we would add them all into
the array.
That is how a normal breadth first search works.
But we're gonna make a little change to that.
We're only going to add these children into this array to iterate over if they are folders in this case.
These are not folders that we're working with.
These are files.
So if we're working with the file if we find that all the children of this thing are files then we're
going to take a look at each file.
We're going to see if it has the test dot J.S. extension and if it does we'll add it to our other array
of files that keeps track of all of our different test files.
But if it's not a test dot J.S. file or a folder then we're basically just gonna throw it out and ignore
it.
So for our implementation of breadth first search in reality what would go on is we start off with movies.
We take a look at s RC We don't take care anything about s our C so we would then move on to test so
then side of test we would take a look at app test J.S..
Okay that's a file we care about so we'd save a reference to it but we would not add it to the array
down here because we don't need to go into it and start to iterate because a file is never gonna have
any children so then the other thing inside of test would be widgets.
So we would add widgets to that array so that's the only change that you and I are going to make to
the breadth first search algorithm to adapt it for our purposes.
Okay.
So with all that mind let's flip back over and start to work on this thing.
So back over here at the very top of the file I'm going to require in the F S module from the node standard
library then inside of collect files we're going to Amelia mark this thing as async because we're definitely
gonna end up with some asynchronous code inside of their and I'm also going to add in a argument to
this thing to collect files of target path so target path right here is going to be the folder or the
entire absolute path to some folder that we want to investigate on our local machine so in our case
if we wanted to take a look at the movie's directory and find all the different files and folders inside
there the argument to collect files would be the absolute path to this movie's directory.
So just as a quick example target path if you were on a Mac OS or Unix based system you would end up
with a target path of something like users your user name documents maybe like projects movies or something
like that.
So that's what we're going to eventually pass in to collect files all right.
So now inside of here we're going to use the FSA module to take a look at that target path and find
all the different files and folders inside there.
So that's like step one of our algorithm where back over here we said we're going to look at the root
directory and find all the files and folders immediately inside of it just to get a quick reminder on
how to do that.
Let's take a look at the no J.S. standard documentation so once again at no j ust dot org slash API
and I'm inside of the file system section inside of here.
We're going to do a search for read Dir.
Remember the reader function has a couple of different flavors.
There's the callback version which I'm looking at right here see as the third argument of a callback.
There's the synchronous version and if we hit enter again we should eventually go down to the F S promises
section.
So this is the promise based version of reader.
That's what we want to use inside of our code because using promises and async await is a lot easier
than using callbacks in general.
So I gonna click on that and take a look at the documentation so when we call reader we pass in the
name of the folder that we want to take a look at and then it's going to return a promise that's going
to be eventually resolved with the names of all the different files and folders that are inside there.
So in other words when we call reader we'd say the path the movies we would get back in array that has
the words source and test inside of it as a quick reminder.
This is like an imaginary directory structure right here so it's not quite what you and I are going
to see but close enough it's let's go back over inside of collect files.
I'll say const files is a weight F S that promises not read dir and we'll pass in the target at all
right.
Now immediately after that let's do a return of files right away just so we can start to test this stuff
that we're putting together inside of here in order to test this code.
We have to make sure that we go back over to our index not just file.
So back over inside of index dot J.S. Let's require in the runner file that we just authored.
So at the top I'll replace the console log with const runner is require runner or then create a new
instance of the runner
and then I'm going to call the collect files function and remember collect files as async.
And chances are right now you are running a version of no JFK.
That does not support top level await expressions in other words we can't say a weight runner dot collect
files right here with the version of note that you are probably using right now.
Any a weight statement has to be wrapped inside of a function so we're going to instead define a little
helper function just for the purposes of making use of async await so I'll say about run I will market
as async.
And then finally inside there we can then say maybe like results is a weight runner dot collect files
will then console log the results and call run at the bottom and then one last thing we need to make
sure that we pass in the correct path to collect files.
So it's going to be the path for whatever folder we want to read all these files out for.
Well I want you to think about this for a second.
What directory do we really care about getting all these files from it's probably going to be whatever
folder we run our little t test T M E program front.
So in other words if I'm inside of the movie's testing directory and I run TMC inside of here I would
want to find all the files and folders inside of that directory.
So we need to somehow get a reference to what directory our program is being executed from to do so
we can call process that see WD which stands for current working directory.
So whenever we now run our team program that right there is going to return exactly what directory our
program was invoked from.
All right.
Let's save all this and we'll do a quick test I'll go back to our team directory I'll do the test from
inside of here.
You can do it from any folder on your machine it should be fine.
And I'll run TMC inside of here and I should see all the different files and folders located inside
of me.
I can go to another directory on my machine as well so I'll go back to a workspace that I use on here
called me and I'll steal the files and folders that I have on here as well okay.
So it looks like step one is working out just fine so let's take a pause right here.
When come back the next video we're going to continue to implement our breadth first search algorithm.