Just like with a race where we could nest an array instead of an array we can do the same thing for
objects.
We can fill objects with kids that are arrays or also keys that are other objects.
And we do this all the time because most of the data we work with in the real world is generally a combination
of list or ordered data as well as key value pairs of data.
So here are a couple of examples.
I have an object called student and a student has a first name or last name key.
We have a strengths property which is set to an array and then we have an exams key and the value is
another object.
So we have the midterm score and the final score two different exams and we could play around with this.
Here's a quick little quiz.
How would I access.
How would I add together midterm and final and then divide them by two.
How would I find the average.
You don't have to use some fancy shortcut to average things but just access this number.
Access this number and add them together and divide by two.
So here's how I would do it.
Student dot exams dot midterm plus student dot exams dot final and that will give us the combination
so we'll just call this.
We'll go with average and then surround them with parentheses because we want to make sure we add them
before we divide by 2.
Add in our equals sign.
Let's refresh and see what average looks like 90 and that seems right.
So we're using the dot notation multiple times you chain them together first to get exams then to get
midterm if we wanted to access art it would be student dot strength and then square bracket one because
its index of 1 and we could keep nesting as far as we wanted to.
On and on and on.
Another really common format is where we have an array in each element in the array is an object so
we get the order where we have the top level array but rather than just storing a string or a number
we can store a bunch of information together as an object to this would represent a simple shopping
cart for some sort of e-commerce checkout where you have a product with a name a price and a quantity
for each element in that array.
So there is an order.
Most cards have an order thing that was added first is up top.
The thing that was most recently added is down at the bottom.
It displays the price the quantity.
We could easily multiply price times quantity for each element especially once we talk about loops and
then you could print that out and then total it all up and have one subtotal.
So this pattern you'll see all over the place as well.
An array of objects.
Here's one more example.
Remember when we talked about arrays and we saw multi-dimensional arrays where we were representing
a game board like for tic tac toe and each row is represented by its own nested array.
So we would have three rows.
I'll just duplicate this.
We'll do X here 0 here and keep that as X and then this one.
Let's do no o comma x.
So we have our game board which is stored in a single array but we may want other information about
the game itself.
And if we were storing or we're trying to represent an entire tic tac toe game in one object or in one
variable we could put this in an object.
We could do something like this.
We have an object.
We would track player 1 and we could give them a name say Player 1 is my cat blue player 2 is my other
cat.
He doesn't really have a name I call him muffins and then we'll also have the game board so we could
do board and paste that in there and then let's make this into a variable contest.
Game equals.
I'll save my board gets kind of messed up the formatting because of my preferences for V.S. code.
This isn't long enough to trigger three separate lines but that doesn't really matter.
So now we have a little more information about player.
Player 1 player 2 and the board but then looking at this we might want more information about each player.
How do we know who is 0 and who is x so for Player 1 instead of just storing a name we could make that
an object and the object could have username as a key and then what would we call that x or 0 character.
What do you call that team.
Let's go with playing as and Blue will be X and then we could do the same thing for Player 2.
So Player 2 becomes an object where we have user name and then we have playing as 0 and we have to make
sure we add those commas correctly.
So when we take objects and arrays we put them together.
We can model most of the information and the data we need to for any given application usually by nesting.
And sometimes it gets a little crazy with the nesting but just those two structures really give us a
lot of flexibility.