We've now taken a look at several different ways of storing images.
Now we need to figure out how we're going to store images inside of our application.
Like I said earlier we're going to do things that is not quite the best or most optimal way but it's
in a way that's going to work for our application and it works in the context of this course.
So it's not something I would recommend that you do in a production professional application but there
are some scenarios where our approach is going to work just fine.
So what we're going to do is take the file as included or the file that's been uploaded.
We're going to turn it into a string that can be safely stored inside of our products not just on file.
We're then going to take that string that represents the image and create a new record out of it using
our products repository which in turn is going to save it into products stored.
Jason So we first need to figure out how we can take the image that was included with this file upload
request and turn it into a string that can be safely stored inside a file to do so.
I'm going to find the console log right here.
Remember rect file is an object that has all different properties about the file it was just uploaded
the RAW image data is stored inside of the buffer property we're going to take that buffer.
We're gonna call to string on it and we're going to encode it as a base sixty four string bass 64 string
can safely represent an image in a string format so we're going to do a quick console log right here
and see what that actually looks like it's going to say this go back over to my browser I'm going to
enter an a title and a price and then I'll upload a file.
Now once again this console log that's going to end up inside of our terminal is going to be a very
very large.
If you upload an image that's something like my coat right here of 117 kilobytes.
So I would recommend that you just take a look at these small image that I upload right now so you can
see it more or less what the base64 encoded string is going to look like so I'm going to select my small
image submit it and then check out my terminal then over here I can see as big string of all these random
looking characters.
So this is a base 64 encoded image.
It's essentially a string that encodes some raw data when we have an image in base64 formats.
We can very easily distribute this string and essentially send the image around to people who are asking
for it.
What's better is that this string can be safely stored inside of our products not just on file.
So this is a reasonable way for the context of our application to handle and store images.
It's not something that I would highly recommend you do on a production application but once again there
are better approaches to take in that scenario okay.
So now that we've got this image in some workable fashion I'm going to remove the console log but keep
around the base 64 bit stuff I'm going to assign all that to a variable that I'll call image and then
going to also get access to the title and the price from wreck dot body.
Now given the title the price and an image for some particular product we're going to use the products
repo that we required up here and we were working on just a little bit ago to create a new product and
save it into our products not just on file.
Remember to do so all we have to do is call that create method.
Here it is right here in passing an object with all the properties we want to save
so back down.
I'm going to call a wait products repo create and we're going to pass on the attributes we want to save.
So title price and image I'm using the awake keyword here so I'm gonna make sure that I mark the enclosing
function as async okay.
That's pretty much it.
So we are ready to do a quick test here before we do a quick test.
I want to mention that there is an extremely subtle bug in the code we have right now very very subtle
really hard to detect until you actually run this code and realize that there's something kind of funny
going on.
Nonetheless we're going to run this code see what happens and then tried to diagnose what is currently
going wrong.
It's going to save the file.
I'm gonna go back to my form but in a title and a price I'm going to once again use my small image right
here and submit it I see okay it's as submitted.
So it seems like everything went OK.
Now I should be able to open up my products dot Jason file and see all the saved information around
the product that was just created so open it up and there we go
so it looks like everything showed up your correctly or I should of put some emphasis on here it looks
like everything showed up correctly but there actually is a very subtle bug like I mentioned.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
We're gonna come back the next video we're gonna start playing around with our request handler a little
bit more and we're going to very quickly realize that even though it appears that everything is working
correctly there is something just a little bit wrong with our setup.
So I'll see you in just a minute.