Now that we understand the subtle timing issue around the ad event let's talk about how we're going
to solve it by using a package off of the NPM registry again.
OK.
So I'm gonna go over to NPM J S dot com once here I'm going to search for lo dash dot D bounce and we're
going to find a package named load Ash dot D bounce so this package contains exactly one function.
The function is intended to solve the exact problem that we have right now.
The issue where we are going to try to call some function in our case a callback function way too often.
So the demon's function is going to implement this sort of limitation right here where choke ADR is
going to emit an event and try to call our callback function but rather than invoking our callback function
right away we're going to force it to wait for 100 milliseconds to go by without any event occurring
before we finally actually execute our callback.
Let's make use of the load Ash dot de bounce function right here.
You can take a look at the documentation if you want to on this page.
The documentation for DB ounce is kind of hard to understand.
You can give it a read if you want to.
But once we add in this package and make use this function I think it'll be pretty clear exactly what's
going on so to get access to this package we are going to once again go over to our terminal and run
npm install and we're going to get load Ash dot DB outs.
I'm gonna go over to my terminal.
I'm going to stop our running code with a control C again.
I'll do an npm install low dash dot D bounce
it once it's installed.
I'll go back over to my editor at the very top.
I'm going to require in DB ounce
and we're going to require load out load Ash dot DB outs like so.
So now whenever we want to stop a function being from being called too often we're going to pass that
function into this D bounce function that's going to return back to us.
A new version of our function that cannot be invoked too often.
So let's just do a very practical example here.
I'm going to define a new function right above where we try to get access to choke ADR.
We're going to call it.
How about starts as eventually we're going to use us to start up a user's code inside of here.
I'll do a console log of starting users program
and then I'm going to wrap that ERO function right there with DB outs so I'll say D bounce and pass
in that era.
Function it's now we are assigning a version of our function right here to the start variable that can
only be invoked so many milliseconds to specify how much time has to pass without this thing being called
we're gonna pass in a millisecond value as the second argument to DB bounce.
So right here I'm gonna put in 100 to indicate that I want 100 milliseconds to go by without seeing
the ad event being triggered before our function should actually be invoked.
So now I can remove the callback that we're passing directly to the ADD event listener and replace it
with start notice that we are not invoking start right here.
There's no parentheses we are giving a reference to that function.
So we're just giving the name of the variable okay.
Let's save this now.
We'll go back over to our eternal I'm going to once again run watch it.
And now we're going to see starting users program up your only one time it looks like it worked perfectly.
It is exactly what we just saw inside this diagram back here.
So choke it out tried to very quickly emit that ad event like 20 30 40 times in a row.
But because we added in that debate its function it limited how often we could actually call our start
function.
So we waited essentially for 100 milliseconds to go by without seeing that ad event before our start
function actually got invoked.
So it looks pretty good now that we've got a good solution here and we're going to make sure that we
don't start up our users code too often.
Let's take another pause.
When come back the next video we'll do a little bit of code cleanup in here and then start to make sure
that we actually will run the user's program so quick pauses I'll see you in just a minute.