Now that we have a better idea of what is going on inside this file.
Well let's continue working on our application.
The first thing we're going to focus on is the admin panel.
Sign up.
So we need to make sure that we have the ability to show two different forms to the user one to sign
up and want to sign in for user comes to sign up.
They should be able to see an input for an email a password in a password confirmation.
So in order to show this stuff to the user a first step to understand just well how to show some HDL
in general to do so I'll go back over to my editor.
I'm going to find our root handler right here and I'm going to replace the rest sent or at least the
string that we pass in with a template string instead so note that this is a template string that is
a set of tactics the character till after to the one on your keyboard and inside of here I'm going to
place a div that contains a form inside the form I'm going to show.
One would only need any more divs inside there.
Let's just do some inputs directly.
I'll give this first one a place holder of email and then going to duplicate that twice the second one.
I'll give a place holder of password and finally password confirmation.
Then after those three inputs I'll place a button with some text of submit or better yet how about sign
up
at all then save this flip back over refresh the page.
And there we go.
So I've now got three inputs that are being displayed to my user.
You'll notice that one of my inputs right here has this little icon inside of it.
The only reason I have an icon there is because I'm running a password manager inside of my browser
called last pass last pass automatically detects any time there is an input that looks like it should
be a kind of logging thing and it adds some icons to it.
So you probably don't see that icon right there which is totally fine now.
Above all I want to point out that we now have a form being displayed to the user or more correctly
that the browser interpreted this thing right here as being some H T email that needed to be displayed.
It did not take this string right here and decide instead to just show it all as plain text as we had
a moment ago when we were returning the string of hi there so express into browser work together to
take a look at the information that you're trying to send back if the information you are sending back
looks like each time all the browser is going to treat it as such and it's going to take all these different
e-mail elements turn them into real H.M. elements and then display them on the screen of your browser.
So now inside this form a user could enter in some email password and password confirmation then click
on sign up and they do so all those different inputs kind of clear out and we don't see anything inside
there anymore.
So you might remember that earlier on INSIDE THIS COURSE we discussed exactly what a h T.M. form does.
But now it's going to start to be really really really critical for us to understand exactly how an
HMO reform works.
So quick pause here.
We're going to discuss in just a moment what a form really does inside the browser and how we're going
to use it to eventually submit an email password and password confirmation to our backend server.