Already so in the last video we saw how using a bunch of callbacks and nesting things can get really
out of hand quickly.
This code is just long and difficult to understand when we're passing in to callbacks to each function
call here and they're all nested.
There's a term for this sort of a playfully loving term in JavaScript called callback hell and you can
see another example of this here on the left.
Lots of nesting lots of functions that are nested functions are being passed as callbacks.
This is just not very fun to write and it's especially annoying when it gets really long and super far
nested and indented and it's just hard to follow.
So this is where promises come in.
Promises allow us to write a synchronous code that is much easier to read and understand.
It's usually shorter but even if it's not actually shorter in terms of the number of characters it's
much flatter.
Often it's not so nested.
So here is where we'll end up.
This code written or rewritten to use promises looks like this a whole lot flatter much easier to look
at on your eyes much easier to fix or debug something if it goes wrong.
We don't have to figure out which callback we need to update.
We don't have to find the corresponding fail callback for this success.
Thankfully I have this bracket matter which helps me but it's really obnoxious.
So this is where we're going and we'll take a moment though because we need to talk about the basics
of promises when we work with promises.
There's really two different things you need to understand.
The first is how you create a promise.
How you could create a function that returns a promise and then the second is how you consume or interact
with promises which we do all the time.
Even if we're not writing the promises ourself we might be making a request from a library or using
a library like axioms which is something we'll see in just a bit.
It returns a lot of its functions return promises.
So we need to understand how we work with those promises.
So we'll tackle both of those creating promises from scratch and then also just working with promises
that someone else made.
OK so let's talk about the basics.
A promise is just an object.
It's a javascript object which represents the completion or failure of some eventual process something
that can take time.
Usually it's something that takes time.
Otherwise you probably wouldn't need a promise.
So a promise is a way of promising a value that you may not have at the moment.
Think of a promise in the real world.
When I was a kid I really wanted a dog.
I asked my dad.
He said You know I promise we'll get your dog if you get good grades.
I got good grades and while he didn't follow through on the promise until he had new kids and then he
got them a dog.
But other people's parents would probably follow through on those promises and actually follow through
and give them a dog.
Give the kids a duck so a promise is different than saying here is a dog right now.
It's just a guarantee or a supposed guarantee of an eventual value for a dog or whatever we're talking
about.
So in Javascript promises are objects that represent an eventual either failure or success of some task
that takes time.
You make a request if we use a library like axioms which we will shortly that returns a promise because
that value.
If you're making an HD GDP request I could take time and that value may never come back.
It might be a failure or it might be successful and you might get some data back from an API but it
takes time.
So the object that is returned in the meantime is a promise and what we do is we attach callbacks to
that object.
We don't pass in to callbacks or a single callback to a function and nest a whole bunch of things.
Promises are objects that we can attach callbacks to instead.
This may not make sense at the moment but why don't I start by showing you how it works and it should
click after a bit of practice.
So the way we make a new promise in Javascript is like this new promise with a capital P..
I'll save this to a variable.
Let's go with this idea of my parents promising me a dog concept will get you a dog equals new promise.
And when we create a promise we pass in a function and this function has two parameters always these
two parameters.
We usually call resolve and reject and these are actually functions and at any point inside of this
function here is function that we pass into new promise.
If we call resolve be promise we'll be resolved.
If we call reject which is a function like this the promise will be rejected.
Now what does that mean for a promise to be resolved or rejected.
Well why don't we just start with doing neither.
We just have our promise here.
New Promise.
That's it.
And we're not doing anything in it.
Let's see what happens if I take a look at will get you a dog.
I'll refresh my page will get you a dog is a promise object and see that it has this one property called
Promise.
Status which is set to pending.
So the promise is it is a promise but it has not been resolved or rejected.
It has not been fulfilled or it has not been broken.
If we are talking about this idea in the real world of a promise when someone promises you something
we would say the status of that promise is pending intel.
Either they break the promise or they follow through on it.
So if we don't reject or resolve a promise its value or its status will be pending.
So the pending state of a promise is frequently what you will see initially when a promise is first
returned.
If we're making a request and that takes ten seconds which would be horrendously slow during those ten
seconds we don't have a response.
We don't know if it's a failure or success.
If the response went to the right you RL If the server was up if your enemy was working so it would
be pending.
But if I immediately call reject which is a function.
If I just write reject here it's not gonna work.
I need to execute this function reject refresh the page take a look uncut in promise we have an error
that we didn't catch and our promise.
Status is rejected and if I instead resolve like that refresh take a look at we'll get you a dog.
Promise now has status of resolved.
So still not very useful at this point but this is the most fundamental part of creating a promise.
We call new promise.
We pass in a function and this function has two parameters resolve and reject.
You can name and other things but this is standard and when you call that first function which should
be called Resolve it resolves a promise it fulfills it and the status is set to resolved.
And if we instead reject it the status of that promise is rejected.
Okay.
So now why don't we make something slightly more interesting.
We have will get you a dog.
Why don't we write a promise that is randomly resolved or rejected.
So that's pretty much the logic my dad used to decide if I was actually going to get a dog.
I'm pretty sure he just picked a random number and decided nope there was no real rationale here so
why don't we pick a random number we'll do const Rand equals math at random and then a friend is less
than zero point five.
We will.
Let's do resolve.
Else we will reject.
So now this promise.
Every time I refresh the page should be one of these states either immediately resolved or immediately
rejected depending on that random number.
So this time it was resolved.
I tried again.
Resolved.
OK now it was rejected.
So this is the first part.
This is how we create a promise the next and also extremely important part is how we actually interact
with the promise.
How do I run code.
If this promise was rejected versus run code.
If this promise was resolved this is where we meet our friend.
Dot then.
So every promise has a then method.
So we could call will get you a dog dot then and this dot then method will run if our promise is resolved.
So I have my dot then and I'll pass in a callback.
This code will run when this promise is resolved and we'll console that log yay we got a dog.
So let's see if it works.
Okay.
So it was rejected.
This code did not run refresh again this time.
If we take a look it was resolved and our callback instead of dot then was executed tried again rejected.
We don't see this code.
There's no yay we got a dog so we have another method we can use with every single promise we have not
then and another one called Dot catch.
Well it's not called Dot catch.
It's called catch and we could just change it on like this.
We could also do will get you a dog dot catch.
This code will run if the promise is rejected.
We'll console that log.
How about a sad face.
No dog.
So if the promise is randomly rejected this will print out.
If it is randomly resolved this prints out no dog.
It was rejected.
So you can see status is rejected once again rejected rejected.
There we go.
Resolved.
All right.
So what we've seen so far may not seem that useful or revolutionary but we've seen the two basic pieces
of working with and creating promises to make a promise.
We call new promise every single time we pass in a function and that function has two parameters resolve
and reject within this function.
We can then call resolve as a function to resolve the promise.
We call reject as a function with parentheses to reject the promise.
And if we do neither the promise we'll have a status of pending until it's either resolved or rejected.
So that's creating a promise.
Then we saw the dot then or the then method and the catch method whatever we pass into then will automatically
run when a given promise is resolved and whatever we pass into dot catch the catch method will automatically
run whenever a promise is rejected.
So these are two methods on a promise a promise is an object.
So this creates a new promise for us.
And then here where we're using two existing methods on those promises or on this specific promise we'll
get you a dog.
These are the basic building blocks of promises.
And we're going to continue to build on these.
Remember we will be refactoring some code that nasty callback hell we saw this at the last video.
Plus we'll see how to make requests.
This will all start to make sense if you're if you're questioning it or if you're lost it just doesn't
seem that useful.
This is not that great.
I totally recognize that but we have to start somewhere.
So next we'll continue on our promises journey.