If you remember back towards the end of the erase section and how arrays are reference types the values
in an array are not actually stored in a variable.
The variable has limited space available to it.
So it stores a reference sort of an address.
Think of it as an arrow in that diagram I showed you an arrow to the actual array and objects work the
exact same way.
So if I have my object I'm calling palettes and I create this variable.
Remember that palette is storing a reference to this object.
If I made another variable called palette 2 and I said it equal to palette both of these variables are
pointing to the same object in memory neither of them store the actual object itself.
They are referencing this object.
So if I change one of them let's do palette to dot.
Let's add in green.
I don't have a hexadecimal color code off the top of my head so I'm just kind of make one up here.
E b f 8 7 6.
It kind of vaguely green some more yellow.
But anyway if I do that and I save I'll run my code you'll see that palette has been updated as has
palette to they're referring to the same object the same thing in memory.
So objects are reference types.
That's really the main takeaway here.
Just like arrays and because of that you'll often see people use const as we talked about with arrays
we use const when we want the reference to stay the same like we always want to be pointing to this
one object but the contents can come and go.
We can change the values we can add properties we can empty it out as long as we don't reassign palette
to something entirely different.
In that case we would need to use the.
But if we're simply keeping the same reference in changing the contents use const and most of the time
that's what we end up doing so for arrays and objects we use const far more often than we do with numbers
and strings and primitive types because we cannot change those if we have a concept and it's storing
a number.
It actually has space in that variable to store the entire value the entire number so we can't change
that to be anything else.
In the case of an object or an array a reference type all the variable stores is that reference so we
can change what's inside that object or that array.
We just don't change that reference.
So that's pretty much it.
Objects arrays both reference types we use const.