Well we can show a link to the user but now it's time to figure out how we're going to actually make
the link right here.
Something that some other user can visit and actually see some message appear on the screen so to figure
that out we need to understand how we are going to essentially take that string and encode it into a
urinal and make sure that that you all can actually be visited by someone else and just you know for
this first version this application we're going to be building.
The only other person who's going to be able to visit this link is you on your own computer.
We'll eventually get a version put together that someone else on another computer can access.
But right now you're really the only person who's going to be able to access this link.
For now okay.
So let's figure out what we're going to do.
We first need to understand the different parts of a your l in general so I have a example your URL
right here.
We're going to divide it out to four different parts.
The first part is the domain.
So that would be like message dot com or Google dot com eBay dot com or whatever else.
Immediately after that we're going to have what is called the path the path can be arbitrarily long
so it can be slashed index dot HDL or slash my slash messages or whatever else at some point after that
we get a character sometimes not always of a little question mark and then a collection of some word
equals another word we refer to this as the query string it is used to communicate some number of options
to a back end server.
So for example I might have colored equals red.
We can imagine that the query string right here is like an options object or kind of like a job script
object really so we can imagine that the word color is like a key and red is like a value.
So inside of a javascript object it would look like
only at the very end we have a hash character or a pound symbol and in some arbitrary value after it
we refer to that as our hash or fragment part of the you or L now out of the entire year l there is
really one part of it that is really dedicated or intended for usage by the browser specifically so
the browser can kind of manage its own information and that is the hash or fragment here at the very
end.
So typically you and I ask developers if we ever have some information that we want to somehow store
in the URL and it is only relevant to the browser and not relevant to some back end server.
We will usually store that inside the hash here at the very end.
Give you a more practical example of what do you Well it really looks like we can really take a look
at the URL of the current page that I'm at right now to really get a sense of what these different parts
are talking about so I'm at a Web site called draw dot IO and I use this to put all the diagrams together
for this course I took that you were L right there and broke it up in the same fashion.
So the domain is draw out Io the path is simply forward slash and then we've got a query string and
a hash fragment the query string.
In this case is sending a message to a back end server and it's telling the back end server that I want
to run the draw down Io application in the get hub mode which means that any diagrams that I create
are going to be synchronized to some GitHub repository that I own that's some information we want to
communicate to a back in server so that the back end server can send me a version of this application
that's going to interact with GitHub but then the actual repository that I want to sync all this information
to is something that is only concern to the browser because from this point on once I get this application
running inside my browser the browser is going to communicate with GitHub directly and figure out how
to sync some information up.
So inside of the URL or excuse me inside the hash or fragment I have the entire link to my get hub repository
and the file inside that repository that I want to sync this diagram to.
So again domain the query string which has some parameters so we want to send to it back in server and
then the hash or fragment as we call it that has some information relevant to adjust my browser and
not really anyone else.
So with all this in mind I think that you might be able to understand that we probably want to install
that cryptic string inside of the hash or fragment at the very end because we want to store some information
that is really just relevant to a user's browser and not really relevant to a back in server or anything
like that.
So now we understand where we might want to save our little encrypted string to communicate with someone
else.
We want to throw it into the hash.
Let's take a pause here come back.
We're going to figure out how we're going to update the URL that we are visiting whenever we're looking
at this application and stick that little hash inside of it.
Don't click pause and I'll see you in just a minute.