We just put together our create function inside there.
We wrote out some code to take our big list of records and save them onto the hard drive inside of a
file.
There was actually a goal of this right all method down here so really quickly.
Let's take that one line of code that takes all of our files and saves them to the harddrive and extract
it into a new helper function called Write all back inside my editor right after the create method I'm
going to define another async method called Write all we're gonna call that with some list of records
that need to be saved and I'm going to take that line that we have right inside of create that we just
put together.
I'm going to cut it and put it into right all or then make sure that I call that from create so I'll
do in await this dot right all and I'll pass in my list of records.
All right.
Let's do another quick save and test just to make sure this still works it's all save run again.
You still get some out but they're very good.
And before we call it quits right there there's other one other quick change very quick change I want
to put together inside of our users not just on file I've now saved many different users.
And unfortunately you can see it they're all being printed out on the same line which makes this file
really hard to read.
There's actually a little trick we can use to make that file a bit easier to understand back inside
of users dot J.S. I'm going to find right all.
Here it is right here.
I'll find where we call Jason dot string ify as the second argument to that right after records.
I'm going to pass in null.
And then as a third argument I'll put in the number two.
Like so I'll save this and without saying what those arguments are doing.
Let's run this again really quickly so I'll do another node.
Users dot Yes and if I now go back over to the users dot Jason File inside my repositories directory
I'll see that now all the contents are kind of pretty printed inside of here.
So what's going on with these arguments.
Let's second argument to Jason string ify is a custom form matter essentially for every record that
we turn into a string or every kind of property that we turn into a string.
We can actually pass in a function to customize how that thing is evaluated.
In this case we don't want to do any custom format or some putting in a value of No.
The third argument is what we really care about.
If we put in a number there that designates the level of indentation to use inside of our string that
we create.
So that is really changing the indentation of the string not of the file.
The file is just a representation of the string that we write out.
So now with every deeper level of nesting we're getting two spaces being put down well definitely a
lot easier to read than what we had before.
All right.
So that's the right all function.
Another quick pause.
When come back we're going to move on to our next method.