The last thing I want to show you around the basics of Nogales is how to debug a node program.
So as you can probably guess we can run console logs inside of node.
All we want.
Anytime we do a console log we're going to see some output at our terminal.
However there's definitely some more robust ways of doing debugging that just console logs.
In fact we can use the same debugger that you're used to inside the browser with node J.S. as well.
Let me show you a couple different ways of debugging.
Just give you a better sense of what's going on.
All right.
So here's a quick summary so we can start up a debugger in one of two ways.
And in one of those ways there's kind of a different flavor of doing it the first way to start debugging
is to run a node inspect and then the name of the file that we want to run.
This is going to start up a debugger S.L. I the CLIA is essentially running inside of our terminal and
we can use it to debug our application wide inside the terminal.
It's easiest to see this thing in action to give you a better sense of what's happening.
So I can go back over to my terminal and run node in SPECT index dot J.S. so when we run this command
we're going to see some output like so execution of our program stops on the very first line of code.
So we're essentially waiting for our program to start right here.
We are then given a prompt that we can use to manipulate the current state of the program or step through
execution at this prompt.
There's a couple of different things that we need to be aware of.
First off there are some different characters that we can enter to manipulate the execution of our program.
If we enter see like just the letter C that is going to continue execution of our program until the
program ends or we hit a debugger statement in our code can it end to run the next line of code as to
step into a function or 0 to step out of a function.
Let's try using some of these different commands right now and go into each first try running.
Simply How about n to run the next line of code we'll see that we have now essentially advanced from
the cons declaration right here to actually add the require statement.
The next thing that's about to happen here is we're about to run that require function.
We know that because it is highlighted in green at this point we can either run and again to go to the
next expression or we can run s to step into the execution of the require statement.
Let's try it as really quickly so I'll step in and then we see some kind of strange code right here
that doesn't really look like anything that you and I wrote.
So we're essentially stepping into the internal implementation like no JSA is implementation of the
required function.
Now we know that because we can see the current file that we're in is something called internal modules
helpers Scott J.S..
So this is definitely not any code that you and I wrote so we might decide to now step out and say I
don't really care about what requires doing so to step out of the execution of required we can do oh
so enter o it enter.
And now we have advanced past the execution of require.
Now at this point we can try to inspect the counter object so I can run counter objects like so excuse
me we can't do that just yet.
We have to enter into the rebel first so we're gonna put it in rebel.
One.
I forgot to mention in that diagram the rebel commands is essentially going to start up an execution
environment where we can reference the different variables inside of our program.
They'll do rebel.
There we go.
And now we can do counter object and there's the counter object.
So we've got the increment counter function and they get counter function.
So I could manually checkout counter object and get the current value of counter where I can even manually
increment the counter as well
and I could do it a couple times and then get the counter again.
And now it's at six.
So at some point time if we've satisfied ourselves with debugging inside this old rebel we can take
control C we're back at our debug prompt.
Now we can once again either continue until we had a debugger statement run the next expression step
in or step out.
So at this point I think we've seen enough.
I'm going to hit C to continue execution and essentially we have now completed execution of our program
and so it's just waiting for us to disconnect or essentially add this debugging session which we can
do as usual by adding control C.
All right so as you might guess using that ripple is kind of nasty.
I'll be honest I don't really expect you to be using that on a daily basis.
However it is really nice because you can start it up very very quickly and once you start getting used
to it you can really advance through your code and test things out rather fast much more user friendly.
Are these other two options.
So these are far far easier to use but they also take just a little bit longer to get started with.
Let's first take a look at the bottom one here node dash dash inspect dash B R.K. index dot J and to
go over to my terminal once again and run that command
once I run that command we see I print up right here and this print up doesn't really convey a lot of
useful information what we have to do here is kind of hidden from us.
So this is a little fact of knowledge that you really have to keep in your head in order to connect
to this debugger and actually make use of it.
We're going to open up our browser specifically the Chrome browser.
So if you're not running Chrome right now unfortunately you can't follow along with a step.
This is only going to work with Chrome browser so in my chrome browser I can open up a new tab and navigate
to Chrome colon slash slash inspect I can do that right now I'll go to Chrome slash slash inspect and
here we go.
This is a interface for connecting to that running node instance right here we see something it says
remote target.
This is essentially saying that there is a running no J.S. process specifically the index dot J.S. file
and we can connect to it and start up a debugger.
We can do that by clicking on the a little link right there that says inspect once I do so we're going
to see the classic chrome debugger up here the one that you are probably very used to by now.
And if you take a look at the code that we're debugging it is everything we have inside of our index
not J.S. file.
So now I can use the console right here to inspect different variables I can use the same controls to
continue execution step in step out and so on.
So I'll try stepping over to that next expression.
Now we have defined or required in the my script J.S. file.
Now I can inspect that counter object by using the console down here by the way if you don't see the
console hit escape and I'll pop it right up.
Of course you can also at the console tab at the top as well.
Now I can take a look at counter object and just like you saw at the terminal but had a much easier
to use fashion we can you cannot object increment counter pilot a couple of times yet the counter and
there we go then once all done we can resume and we see the program run as usual.
That's going to do the console logs into our debugger directly as opposed to the console which we saw
previously as you might guess.
This is a really handy thing to use way easier to use from a user perspective or us as developers than
doing that command line debugger.
However as you might guess well sometimes it's a little bit annoying to have to go to Chrome Poland
slash slash inspect.
In addition every single time that we want to restart our program we have to refresh this thing hit
inspect again and essentially open up the debugger again now last thing on it mentioned here is the
difference between dash dash inspect the arc and just dash dash inspect the beer K is what I probably
think that you're going to use for the most part when you're doing debugging especially when you're
starting out with note the real difference here is that when you add on the dash dashboard R.K. that's
going to start up your program but it's going to pause execution on the very first line of code dash
dash and Specht is going to start up the debugger but it's also going to simultaneously run your program
it's going to run your program until you connect to it with a debugger and hit a debugger statement.
So usually the dash dash inspect is only going to be used when you are running a very long running process
like a server if you're running a very small script that's going to complete execution in a matter of
like milliseconds which is the case with our current program we're always going to be using dash dash
inspect the arcade to be completely honest with you I would almost just forget that this variant of
the command even exists.
And just remember this one right here OK.
So that's how we're going to debug our note programs again very similar experience to debugging inside
the browser because we are pretty much using the exact same debugger now that we've got some basics
of node down.
We understand a little bit about modules in a little bit about debugging.
Well let's start to do some interesting things with node in the next video.