We are now taming that ad event so to speak with that D bounce function so we're not going to call anything.
Once the ad event is triggered many times in a row we've got that put together.
Let's get back on track and continue driving our program forward.
The next thing that I would really like to do is to make sure that users of our command line tool or
THIS WATCH IT program get some nice help whenever they use our tool.
So to do so we're going to using that capital program or that capital package.
Let's take another look at the documentation for that package and just get a better idea of what it
really does for us.
I'll go back over to NPM J dot com once here I'll search for capital and go to the documentation for
it.
So again one of the purposes of capital is to show that kind of nice help screen to a user whenever
they tried to interface with our program.
I can go to that screenshot that was down here towards the bottom.
Here it is right here.
So capital essentially is going to generate a lot of the information that you see on here.
The other thing that capital does for us.
I didn't quite mentioned before is automatic validation in handling of arguments that are passed into
our program.
So for example we can tell Cooper all that we expect our program to be called with some kind of argument
that designates a file name if a user doesn't provide that argument.
Capital will automatically show them an error.
Let's install this package.
We're going to start to use it inside of our project going to go over to my terminal.
If you're still running the watch it program right now remember you can stop it by hitting control see
on your keyboard and then over here we'll do an npm install HEPA roll all right.
So let it do its thing and it installs rather quickly so I'll go back over to my ED and we're going
to first require it at the very top.
And one would be required this there's going to be something kind of weird on this line but just bear
with me I'll tell you exactly what's going on.
I'm going to say constant program equals require happy roll.
So what's weird here.
Well the weird thing is the name of this variable you'll notice this is actually a really good kind
of juxtaposition right now or comparison between these three different libraries.
We have haven't used kind of wildly different naming conventions for these three different modules that
we have required.
The first one was chuck it out.
We required and choke it out.
And we assigned it to a variable that has the exact same name as the library the next one that we added
was D bounce.
We required in a package called load Ash dot D bounce and we assigned it to a variable called g bounce.
So my question is why do we call this D balance and not something like low dash de bounce or something
like that.
And then finally obviously the weirdest one here is Capriles.
So I just required it.
And if I was following the same pattern as with choke it out we should have done something like CPL
not crap all.
I'm sure it's a fine library.
So if you're following the same kind of pattern we would have assigned capital to a variable like that
but instead I did program which is wildly different.
So what's going on here well at the end of the day the convention in all scenarios for naming a variable
that gets assigned or that is receiving assignment from a require statement is to name that variable
directly after the library that we are requiring it.
So the choke it art requires statement right here.
This is perfect convention and this is what we're going to do it in the vast vast majority of scenarios.
So why did we not follow that convention with DB outs.
Well just you know the DB outs function is one tiny little function that is included in a much larger
library of helper functions that much larger library is called load ash.
This is an extremely popular package that has millions and millions and millions of downloads has a
ton of different functions inside of it.
One of those functions is called DB outs so the reason we just call this thing de bounce is that well
we are only accessing this one very small function called g bounce and so it just doesn't really serve
a lot of purpose to try to call it something like load actually bounce like that doesn't really add
anything for it.
For us it doesn't really do anything or clarify what the DB bounce function is it makes just a little
bit more sense to simply call it G bounce and leave it there.
Now what about capital.
That logic sure doesn't apply down here.
Well the first reason that I would give you for saying that we are calling this variable right here
program as opposed to capital would be to go over to the documentation to back in the documentation
for capital if we scroll down to the first example right here you'll see that they chose in the documentation
to require in that library and assign it to a variable called prog frog as you might guess is short
for program I call the very variable program just to make sure it was clear what the name of that variable
really meant.
If you're not a native English speaker the word frog might not make any sense at all.
But even then why did they choose to call this thing prog as opposed to capital.
Well let me show you why the vast majority of libraries that we use we usually are going to require
a library and get back some kind of class or an object that has some functions inside of it that we
can use to do whatever the library is intended to be used for however in the case of capital whenever
we require it in we get back some object that doesn't really represent the library.
Instead it is an object that represents the program that we are trying to build.
So besides the fact that the documentation just plain recommends you closing program.
The idea here is that we're getting back an object that represents the program we are putting together
as opposed to representing the capital library or anything like that.
I know that might sound like a really silly reason but it's honestly the best I can give you so at the
end of the day when we have these require statements wherever possible we just named the variable after
the library unless it's a really not long name for a library in which case we're going to just kind
of shorten it or if the documentation specifically specifies something else we're going to follow that
convention instead OK.
So I know that's a lot to talk about with the naming of these variables but it's something that I found
a lot of beginners kind of get confused by.
Like why are we using these different names.
So let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back the next video and we're going to get a little bit more in-depth with cap rule and understand
how to use it.