We've now got a starting implementation for a class timer put together.
Now unfortunately in this video and the next one we're going to have to go into a very quick side topic
this side topic is something that's a little bit painful in javascript but that's why we're going to
go over it right now before we get too deep into this application.
So the little issue that we're going to discuss is around the value of this inside of a class.
This is something it was covered earlier on inside this course.
But I was going to give you a very quick reminder right here because it's going to be very relevant
for us as we develop our Timer class so honor.
I want to first begin with a quick demonstration.
I'm going to find my start method.
I'm going to remove the console log inside there and I'm going to replace it with console dot log this
like so now remember our start method is going to be invoked right now whenever we click on the start
button because we wired it up with an event listener.
So that is one way in which we can invoke the start method and then good to go down to the bottom of
the file right after we create our timer class and I'm going to call timer dot start directly as well.
So there are now two ways in which the start method is going to be invoked.
It's going to be called one time automatically when our application first loads up inside the browser.
It's going to be called a second time whenever we click on the start button directly.
Now I want you to recall that in general we want the value of this inside of a class to be equal to
the instance of the class that we create because this is how we refer to different instance variables
and methods that are defined inside the class.
Let's say this really quickly we're going to go back over to our browser.
I'm going to refresh the page in right away.
I'll see the first console log.
So that is from the method called we added down right here so when we call it timer dot starts the console
log of this that we see is the instance of the Timer class we created.
This is the result that we want.
In general we always want a console log of this to result in the instance of the class because this
means that we can access the different instance variables so we defined on the class and the different
methods as well.
So this right here is a very good result.
And that is what we always want to see however if we try to invoke starts using this other way of invoking
it by clicking on the button we're going to see a very different result so I'm going to find the start
button and click on it.
And when I do so I'll see a console log of the button we just clicked on instead.
So that means that the value of this inside of the start function whenever we click on the button is
very different than if we just call start directly through the instance of the class that we created.
This is a very bad thing seen this console log right here.
That is not good at all because it means that whenever a user clicks on that start button we will not
have access to any of the instance variables inside of our class or any of the methods as well.
Let me show you a quick demonstration of why this is so important right after the start method.
I'm going to define a new method.
I'm going to delete this very quickly.
This is just a quick demonstration.
I'm going to define a new method called important method to call.
So we're going to imagine that this is a really important method that we have to call when ever Stark
gets invoked so then inside of starts I'm going to try to call that method.
So I'll do important method to call like so and then maybe just to make sure that we do successfully
call it all out in a console log of like.
Important thing was done OK.
So let's now try to save this.
We're going to go back over and refresh the page once again and I made a typo.
There we go.
Important method to call my mistake.
I can say that again refresh.
That's better.
So now whenever we call the start method directly through the code we have right here we have access
to all the other methods we defined inside of our class.
Once again this is good.
This is what we want.
However if we tried to click on the start button we will see an error.
And that is because when we click on the start button the value of this inside of START is going to
be different than if we just called start directly.
So again this comes back to the idea of the value of this inside of a class.
So in order to fix this up and in order to make sure that we can actually use a button like this right
here with an event listener to invoke different methods inside of our class we need to make sure that
the value of this inside the start method is what we expect it to be and for it to be what we expect
it to be.
We need to get a better understanding of the value of this inside of a class.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to get a quick review on how we can determine the value
of this inside of a class and how we can change the value of this if required as in this case it definitely
is required to click pause right here and we'll continue in just a moment.