All right.
So we just talked about the arguments object and some of its shortcomings.
It's been around for a long time.
It's doing the best it can.
Now we have a new nicer syntax in rest.
So rest is three dots.
One two three.
Just like we used for spread.
But we put it inside the parameter list of a function definition and what it does is it collects all
remaining arguments into a 100 percent real actual array not an array like object not an array imitation
a real array.
So earlier we wrote this function called some using the arguments object we had to convert it into an
array.
If we want to write the same function using rest what we do is we put three dots right here and then
we decide on a name.
And that will be the name of the array that contains all of the arguments in our case.
All arguments will be collected.
So let's go with numbers and then we can start by just counsel about logging numbs we need to match
that name that we gave it here.
Let's call some on 4 5 6 7.
And it's an actual array.
It's not an array like object.
It's a real array.
So I could implement the same functionality where I return using reduce on numbers.
So numbs reduce.
And then we have our reduced function which will be total and then current Val I use an arrow function.
And we just want to return total plus curve Val let's check it out.
It works.
We get twenty two.
So this is the simplest way to use rest.
We're collecting all arguments everything passed in whether it's 20 the first one the last one they're
all combined into the numbers array but we can also use it in a different way.
We can use it to collect the remaining arguments which is what I wrote here.
Collects all remaining arguments so not just every argument no matter what.
Instead it collects the remaining arguments that have not been matched with a parameter.
So if we go back to that example where I had full name and I wanted a function where we have a first
last and then a list of titles I could use rest right here to collect the remaining titles first last.
Those will be their own parameters then everything else is collected here.
So I'll start by just canceled out logging first with first and then I'll do the same thing for last.
And then one more time for titles and if I call full name where I'm passing.
Tom as first Jones as last and then a bunch of arguments to be the titles you can see what we get first
is still Tom last is Jones but titles only contains the remaining arguments when we tried the same thing
with the arguments object it contained every argument including first and last or Tom Jones.
But in this case it is only collecting the unclaimed arguments if that makes sense.
So we have them collected in titles and it's an array and I could use titles to do something I could
iterate over each title but I'm not going to bother with it.
I just wanted to show you that we have a way of separating them out.
We have first last and then everything else because of the way rest works.
It collects everything.
You wouldn't have multiple rests javascript wouldn't know what to do because the logic here is combine
everything that has not been put in a parameter already into the titles array.
So how could we have something afterwards if we just claimed everything before it into the titles array
you can name these whatever you'd like.
As we've seen and along with that the order definitely matters if you tried to do this.
It's not going to work last would never have a value ever.
And if you tried to do it this way titles first last let's see what happens.
Mm hmm.
Risk parameter must be the last formal parameter.
So javascript doesn't even let you try.
It's telling you it has to be the last parameter.
That's the only option.
And then the last thing that is nice about it is that we can use it in an arrow function.
So I could rewrite functions some this function statement the declaration I could rewrite it as an arrow
function just copy this and defined it down here.
Let's go with multiply actually.
So const multiply equals our arrow function and we'll call the parameter number the rest param that
accepts everything into an array and then let's do an implicit return.
So we don't need to say return anymore we'll do numbers stop reduce and then multiply instead of add
and we can use a double implicit return if we want to just do it on one line.
OK so we have our aero function here where we're using rest recalling the array numbers and because
it's an array we can call reduce.
And then I'm just returning total times curveball in my reduced function.
If you skipped over the reduced videos I really recommend you check those out.
I know they're a bit painful.
Trust me I had to teach it.
It's not it's not that exciting but it is something that you'll use all the time anyway.
Let's make sure it works.
So we'll call Multiply multiply about four or five six seven and we get eight 40.
Let's do something we can verify easier.
Two three and four gives us twenty four.
Great.
So we can use an arrow functions which we could not do with the arguments object we can use it as an
array because it is an array unlike the arguments object where we had to convert it to an array.
And lastly we have more discretion over what it collects.
We can tell it to only collect the remaining arguments after certain specific parameters.
Hence the term rest versus the arguments object just contains everything every argument no matter what
so when I say that rest is kind of like the opposite of spread.
Maybe you can see what I mean.
We are collecting elements or collecting arguments into an array.
We're not copying them over we're not spreading.
If we do something like this where we are using spread we're taking a single element and breaking it
up into multiple pieces into an array.
We're copying it over one element at a time versus when we use rest.
We're doing the opposite.
We're taking multiple disparate elements arguments and combining them into an array.
So the syntax is the same but that's why we have a different name rest versus spread.
I guess there's a world where it could have just been spread but it's called rest.
It has its own page in the docs because it behaves differently and it's sort of the opposite.
So that's it for rest.
We have a couple more new features in JavaScript.
One of my favorite is coming up called D structuring.