In the last video we saw that we could have a variable like score let's say it starts at zero.
We're making some sort of board game or Tetris or something in the browser.
We have a score variable to keep track of the user score and we could updated by doing that score equal
score plus let's say 10 for user scores 10 points.
Now score is 10.
There's also a shorthand for changing the value of a variable without having to reference the name again.
So instead of score equal score plus 10 we can do score plus equals let's go with one.
This is the same as saying score equals score plus one plus equals is just going to update score by
1.
In this case so score is eleven.
Now we could also do it by something other than one.
We could add 10 again score plus equals 10 score is now twenty one.
Now we can also do the same thing with subtraction and other operators like score minus equals say that
the user did something bad in the game they lose points minus equals one hundred.
Now score is negative seventy nine.
Let's reset it to let's go with 150 and then let's say we had another variable like bonus which we called
multiplier.
That's kind of long about bonus malt instead of multiplier.
And this will be three.
So if we wanted to multiply the score by three year by whatever this multiplier is you get a star in
the game or something that multiplies your score.
We could do score times equals.
And then I just want to show you can use other variable names to do this score times equals bonus molt.
We now are just saying take score and multiply it by whatever this variable is which is three and then
save that new value to score.
We also have divide equals or slash equals most the time you'll see plus and minus.
And a lot of the time you just want to increment by one or decrement by one and there's another shortcut
an even shorter way of doing that because it's done so commonly.
Often we're doing things where we have a variable and no need to add one to it and then later add one
more and one more like a counter for example to keep track of certain things how many times they happen
or how many times you want something to occur and let's do an example of that.
Let's counter.
Equal zero.
If I wanted to add one to it instead of plus equals one there's something called a unitary operator
unitary operators are operators where there's only one side.
This right here has two sides counted plus three.
Right.
The left and the right.
This has one side and this is just going to add one plus plus we'll add one to counter.
So now counter it's one and we can do the same thing let's do it one more time or three more times.
Who knows.
So we have counters that to four I can spell it and we can now do the same but decrement ing it counter
minus minus will subtract one.
So counter right now is for right to counter minus minus.
We end up with three cool.
So someone to show you those.
You'll see them all the time plus equals minus equals star equals.
But then also the unitary operators plus plus and minus minus.