Let's get a better sense of how a browser treats in each simple form and what really happens behind
the scenes.
When we enter in some inputs and then click on some button to get started I'm going to first open up
the network request tab inside of my chrome console so open up my Chrome developer tools and then find
the Network tab right here.
Then I'll find my form once again I'm gonna enter in some text to all three inputs and then click on
sign up and I do so I can very clearly see that a request is being issued.
This request is going from the browser off to the server.
So in other words we know right away that whenever we have a form element and we click on some sign
up button or something like that Eddie request is being issued.
The important thing to understand is exactly what is being communicated.
So by default whenever you click a submit button or any button really inside of a form or whenever you
select an input and hit the enter key the browser is going to do something called an automatic submission
in an automatic submission.
Your browser is going to take a look at that form elements.
It's going to find all the different input elements inside of it.
The browser is going to attempt to collect all the information from each of those input inputs or input
elements that have a name property assigned to them at present are different inputs don't have name
properties assigned.
So right now our browser is not trying to collect any information whatsoever.
I'm gonna go back round to each of these three inputs and add in a Name property to each of them.
So for the first one I'm gonna add in a name of email then password and finally password confirmation.
All one word.
This time around I'll then save this.
I'm gonna go back over to the browser.
I'm gonna make sure I refresh the page to get the latest each e-mail that we just authored and I'll
enter in an email a password and a password confirmation and click on sign up as soon as I do so you'll
notice that now are your l has been updated.
So that is our browser taking a look at those three different input elements.
It takes a look at the Name property of each of them.
So email password and password confirmation and the value from each of them as well.
It informs all that information into something called a query string and then the browser makes a gift
type request.
So a request with a method of get to the same year L that is currently looking at.
So you'll notice that the request right here was automatically mean the URL was automatically updated.
I can see a question mark right there and then all the information out of the form is right after that
question mark.
So everything after the question mark is referred to as the query string so we could configure our Express
server to receive this information right here and take a look at the email password and password confirmation
properties and then use that information to create an account for this user by default when the servers
I mean when the browser takes this information and makes a request it is a get type request but we can
and very frequently do modify that behavior.
I'm gonna go back over to my browser.
I'm going to find me and my editor to find that form element.
I'm going to add on a method property to it and I'm going to give it a value of host like so this is
going to cause the default behavior of the browser to change slightly now rather than making a get type
request to our Express server it is going to instead make a post type request a post request is a type
of H CTP request that is commonly associated with creating a record of some kind.
This might be like creating a blog post or a comment where a new image upload or even a user account
as is the case for us.
So the default behavior of the browser is to make form submissions with a method of get we are overwriting
in this case by applying a method of post.
So let's now save this.
Go back over make sure we refresh enter in some fake information again and click on sign up.
And this time when we do I'm going to take special note to take a look at what happens inside of our
network request log it's going to click on sign up and I see an error message like this right here.
Your message is totally fine.
We're gonna ignore that for just a moment.
Instead I'm going to click on the request that was just issued when I do so I'll notice on the headers
tab at the request method is now made with a post.
So again a post method is associated with creating a record the reason that we're seeing an error message
here is because our Express server does not have a root handler associated with the type of requests
we just made.
Remember when we call app dot get right here with forward slash we are telling that router that is inside
of this app object.
We want to watch for any incoming request for a path of forward slash and a method of get.
If we ever received that we're going to run this callback function.
We don't have any type of configuration receiving any other type of request or any other request with
a different method or a different route our browser is now trying to make a method or request with a
method of post and a route of forward slash.
And so this error that we see right here is coming from our running express server.
It is complaining that we don't have any configuration to handle a request with this configuration we
could very easily fix that by going back over going underneath our apt I'd get statement and adding
in app dot post with a forward slash.
So as you would guess this is telling our router to watch for an incoming request with a path of forward
slash and a method of post if it sees that it's then going to run this callback function right here.
So inside of this callback function let's try pretending that a user signed up successfully for an account.
I'll do so by saying resident send account created like so I'll then say this go back over I'm going
to manually navigate back to local host three thousand once I do I see my form again so I'm going to
once again enter in some email password and password confirmation and click on sign up.
So this time around I then see account created.
That is because when we clicked on that submit button our browser took that form took all the information
inside of it made a post request to the current year L that we are visiting our server now has some
configuration to handle a request to this year L or this path to be more specific.
And with this method of post so our server then ran the appropriate callback function and from inside
there we called resort sent to send back the simple string account created obviously no account has
actually been created at this point in time we would have to actually add in some code inside this callback
function to create an account for the user.
We'll take care of that in just a little bit but right now I just want to have that kind of fake success
message in there.
OK.
So in this video big things that we focused on and doing it a kind of reiteration of this because this
is a very important topic that we're going to repeat or have to reuse quite a bit throughout this application.
We created a form element we added on a method of post to configure what the browser does whenever we
attempt to submit this form the browser then took all the different inputs it took all the information
out as different inputs and it knew what to call each piece of information because the name property
that we assigned to each input the browser then took all that information and made a post request to
the same route it was currently visiting our server then saw that incoming request for a post of forward
slash and then ran that callback function right there.
Last thing I want to mention very quickly when we made the formal submission with a method of get we
saw the form information inside the URL when we changed it out to post that information is no longer
placed inside the URL.
Instead it gets appended onto something called the request body.
So our HDTV request if it is a post request has a body property which can contain some amount of information
we can see the information that got sent from the browser to our server by once again opening up the
headers tab and clicking on the request was issued right here.
So this is the post request we issued if we scroll down to the bottom we'll see a section that says
form data so that's all the information that was contained inside the form that we submitted to our
back and server.
So I've got my email password in password confirmation right there so we definitely are sending some
information to our server but now the next logical step is understanding how we can actually access
that information inside the request handler that is handling that request because at some point time
inside this function we are actually going to have to take that form information specifically the email
parser and password confirmation and create an account for this user.
So let's figure out how to handle that step in the next video.