Now seeing a little bit of know J.S. and so now we're going to start to work on a project to get a better
idea of how to build applications with it.
The first project we're going to work on with node is going to be fairly simple and straightforward
and it's really focused on helping you get a handle on the Node J.S. standard library.
We'll talk about what that is.
Just a moment.
I first want wanna tell you exactly what we're going to be building.
All right so if you run a Linux based machine or a Mac based machine or even a Windows machine with
a Linux terminal emulator you might be familiar with the LS commands that we run at the terminal the
Ellis command can be used to print out the different files and folders inside of some directory.
So in this case I can run l s and see a couple different folders.
I could run l s on some other directory like my root directory and see all the files and folders inside
there as well.
So we can really use the Ellis command in two very basic ways.
We can call Ellis by itself with no arguments and that's going to print out all the files and folders
in the current directory or we can call Ellis with a path that can be a relative or an absolute path
they'll print out all the files and folders in that target directory.
So I want to use no G.S. to re implement this basic functionality around the Ellis command.
So we're going to make our own version of L S that we're going to build to run directly at our terminal
inside of any project or any directory on our machine and just print out all the files and folders inside
there.
So like I said pretty simple project what we're going to learn a lot about node along the way along
with a couple of different topics around async programming and some array helper methods and whatnot.
The first thing want to do is help give you an an idea of how we're going to actually read out files
and folders at all at this point.
We've only been taking a look at javascript inside the browser and in the browser we don't have any
access whatsoever to the user's hard drive but with node that all changes with no G S we can read out
files and folders inside of a directory very easily.
So here's how we're going to do it.
We're going to first take a look at the no GSM standard documentation so I can open up a new browser
tab and visit that link at the top.
You can see that I'm like get the documentation for version 13 1 0.
You might be looking at a very much newer version of the documentation if you are totally fine.
Turns out that no J.S. releases new versions quite frequently but there are usually very very few breaking
changes.
So if you're looking at a version of like 20 or something.
Really no issue whatsoever.
It is extremely unlikely that's going to have any issue with the code that we're going to write for
this project so on this page we can take a look at the left hand side.
These are all different libraries or modules inside of the node at JFK standard library we can use all
these different modules right here and they're all chock full of code in classes and functions and whatnot
that we can use to build out a node application pretty darn easily.
So we can use these modules to get access to things on a user's computer that we don't usually have
access to for our project.
We're going to be wanting to work with the file system on the user's machine.
So if we scroll down a little bit we're going to find a section called file system right here I click
on that.
We can then be taken to a big gigantic page like this really is a giant page with a ton of different
functions that can be used to work with the users file system.
So in other words we can use the functions and objects inside of here to read different files on the
user's hard drive create files edit files rename them and so on just about everything you can possibly
think of.
All right so let's pause right here.
We're going to come back in just a moment and I'm going to point out a couple of different methods that
are probably going to be really useful for us in building the application that we just discussed.