Last thing I want to do to replicate that little demo we were looking at over here is to just make sure
that we can show a bunch of different shapes at the same time and there's not really any magic to this.
And that's why I want to show you how to do it.
And a little demo when I see it.
There's no magic to it.
I mean essentially we're gonna do the same thing as what we did before.
We're just gonna create a bunch of different rectangles and add them into the world.
That's it I'm going to find where we're creating that one single lone rectangle by itself right now.
I'm gonna get a little comment right above it that says something like random shapes.
Again just to remind myself of what this code right here is about to do.
Then I'll set up a for loop around that statement.
They'll say for let I starting at zero I less than 20 plus plus and I'll throw that in there like so
it's let's save this.
This should create 20 rectangles all on the exact same spot with the same size.
So if I go back over and refresh we're gonna see very quickly that they kind of like spread out.
That's because matter J US wants to allow all these shapes to just contact each other on the edges.
When we create a bunch different shapes on the exact same point matter J S freaks out and tries to distribute
those all around the screen and that's what we end up seeing them all kind of stack up like so.
So a slightly better way to handle this would be to slightly randomize the starting positions of two
hundred and two hundred in order to randomize those starting positions.
We can multiply the starting position by the width and the height of the canvas overall and that should
give us some even distribution all around the screen to make sure that I multiply by the width and height
correctly.
I'm going to define the within the height up here at the top as constants.
They'll say width is a hundred and height is six hundred.
So now we're down here at options.
I can replace the numbers with just within height because the keys and the values are the same.
I can leave it just like that and those will be expanded to width is width and height is height you
might be curious why we're pulling out these separate variables right here.
Well it's because I essentially want to refer to the White height and width.
Later on down the file if we start to reproduce numbers like six hundred and eight hundred down here
on this line of code it might be hard later on to figure out exactly why we are using the numbers eight
hundred and six hundred and so by defining a constant.
At the very top that means that if we ever want to change these values we can change them in one location.
Now we'll make updates all throughout the file.
This is a technique that we're going to use quite a bit when we start working on a maze version of this
app.
In just a moment now we can use those two variables to do some random placement so for the position
on the x axis I'm going to say math at random times with and then for the position on the y axis we'll
do math at random times.
Right.
And I'll save just to get that all down to multi line like so okay so let's see now give us some random
distribution about the entire canvas.
Let's now save this.
Go back over refresh and there we go.
That's all a bit closer to the demo we saw over here where they all get kind of randomized.
Right now the last thing that we need to do is to just try to create some different kinds of shapes
instead of just squares.
So for that inside of our for loop we can add in a little if statement I'm going to create a random
number.
So again math not random.
Remember when we called Math dot random that's going to create a number between 0 and 1.
I'm gonna check to see if that is greater than zero point five if it's greater than zero point five.
Then I'm going to go ahead and create a rectangle otherwise I'm gonna create a different shape altogether
so if we don't create a rectangle and we have a value less than zero point five I'm going to instead
try to create a circle.
So I'll do another world.
Add I'm going to add a shape to the world.
And then as the second argument I'll put in bodies dot Circle the Circle method right here is very similar
nature to rectangle.
The first two arguments are going to be numbers that represent where we want to put the circle in the
world and we have to put in those two values as x y coordinates so we can use the same trick we used
right above.
So I'll say asked random times with and math at random times height then the third argument is a little
bit different.
The third argument is going to be the radius of the circle.
In this case I'll do about a slightly larger circle than the rectangles we're adding right now so I'll
do a radius of.
Well actually technically if you like about 35 or so that's the radius.
So the entire diameter or like the full width of the circle will be seventy five which will be just
a little bit larger than the rectangles we're adding in it so I'll save this as well refresh.
And there we go.
Now if we want to we can adjust the number of shapes we're adding in.
So instead of the 20 right there we could do like say 50.
Just make sure that you don't add in too many shapes because otherwise your browser is going to lock
up due to the processing power from trying to figure out what to do with all these shapes.
So I'd say that's pretty close to the demo we just saw.
Now you will notice that these the demo over here has those little lines.
The lines are meant to indicate the orientation of each shape.
We can easily add those in by just adding in another option or two we will worry about that just yet
but there is one other option.
I thought you might be curious about.
Right now we are operating the entire canvas in what is called wireframe mode in wireframe mode.
That means we just see the outline of each shape but if we want to we can go back up to where we create
our render.
Here it is right here into the options object we can put in wireframe is false so that means tried to
render a solid shape as opposed to just the outline and we do a wireframe a false who sees me I think
it's capital F..
Let's try that.
No I'm totally wrong wire frames.
That's what it is.
So I was going off of memory here lowercase f. pl. S..
That's better.
Okay.
So when you set wire frames to false.
We're gonna get solid shapes and the colors for them will be picked at random.
There we go.
Now you can even see that the bordering shapes or the bordering rectangles are solid as well firstly
I like the wireframe just a little bit more but when we eventually put the maze together I think you're
going to find that showing the maze with some solid shapes instead of wire frames just makes the maze
look a little bit more interesting lasting one dimension is that we can customize the color that is
being used if we go to where each shape is being created.
So let's say that for each circle maybe we want them all to be the color red.
We can find where we create the circle so that's the bodies start circle right here and then as the
last argument we can put in an options object and inside there we can add in a little render property.
So this is going to customize how this circle gets rendered onto the screen so inside of this new render
object we can add in Bill style and that can be any valid SS color so it can be like a normal color
like red.
It can be a hex value and so on.
I'll try out red really quickly so I'll save now all the circles are red where I can do say green and
now I've got a bunch of green circles.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for the demo.
We've seen basically believe it or not just about everything that you need to see to build out the maze.
There's only one or two additional topics that we need to be aware of when it comes to matter J.S. that
is to actually build the maze out and that's really just understanding how to control a single shape
using the keyboard instead of the mouse.
So we'll figure that out.
Honestly that's not the worst thing in the world at all.
It's actually rather easy to add in the keyboard controls.
So most of the stuff around the maze that we're going to be doing is just discussing the algorithm we're
going to use to calculate the shape of the maze.
All right.
Let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back the next video and start working on our maze code.