All right now we've got Cabral in there and he a really long discussion behind us about require statements.
Let's go back over the documentation and get a better idea of how to use this library.
Normally I would love to show you a diagram about how to use the library or whatnot.
But in this case capital has a really specific set of instructions on how to use it.
And so honestly it is easiest to just take a look at the documentation here.
So when we require an Cabral we're going to first chain on a couple of different methods to configure
the command line tool that we are trying to create.
The first thing we're going to do is chain on a method call of version the version method call right
here doesn't really do a whole lot.
It really just sets a flag that's going to print up later on for our users benefit specifically in the
screenshot.
Down here you'll see that it says Pizza dot GSM and 1 point 0 point.
That's really what calling version does.
So it's not really something that adds any behavior to the program.
It just helps tell our users who are using this help screen right here.
Exactly what is going on
after that.
We're going to chain on a couple of different method calls.
So the first one that we can chain on is command that is used only if we want to have some kind of sub
command inside of our command line tool.
So for example if our command line tool did many different things like maybe we could have it watch
a file and run it or maybe we can have it automatically delete a file whenever some other file changes
or something like that.
If those were two completely different tests we would wire those up as sub commands inside of our program.
And that is the purpose of this command statement right here.
It defines a sub command after that we can also cheat on dart argument calls not argument calls specify
an argument that a command is going to take.
We can specify them in one of two different ways we can either provide argument with a argument right
there of a string inside of some angle brackets if we do so that means that we require the deploy command
to be called with this argument called at if we tried to call this program without providing that argument.
After all will automatically display an error and say Hey sorry but you need to provide this command
person to this argument if we instead use square brackets that means that this argument is optional
and we don't have to provide it if we don't want to we can also chain on a dot option call which is
going to you to find some kind of option flag that can be passed along and just like the angle brackets
and square brackets right here angled brackets means you must provide this thing if you have square
brackets that means it is an optional option
only when we are all done specifying the different options and arguments and whatnot that our program
is going to have we chain on dot action dot action is essentially going to say OK once the user calls
our program and provides all these different commands and arguments we're going to run that function
right there we're going to receive the arguments that we're provided and the different options that
we're provided and then inside of here we're going to essentially have our actual implementation for
our program last thing to understand is that none of this stuff actually gets used or executed in any
way until we call frog or program not pass and pass in that array of arguments were provided to our
our actual CLIA program when it was started up by the user that's pretty much what is going on here.
So with all that mind let's go back over to our Ed right after our require statement.
I'm going to take my program while chain on a version called because this version doesn't really matter
that much as I just mentioned we'll just use a version of 0 0 1 and they're going to specify an argument
that I expect our program to be invoked with it's going to be an optional argument it's all put in square
brackets and I'm going to call the argument file name the documentation doesn't really say it in what
we're just looking at right here.
But the second argument right here is kind of documentation for our users.
So if a user ever tries to print out some help about what these different arguments and commands are
doing the user is going to see that second string right there.
So I can make sure I put in a second string to tell my users exactly what this argument is doing.
It's going to put in a string that says name of a file to execute
now in our case.
We don't really need any other arguments options some commands or anything like that just yet.
So we can then immediately call action passing a function to invoke and again this thing is going to
receive a first argument of ARGs and that's going to be an object that has all the different arguments
that were provided.
So right now we'll just do a console log of ARGs one thing you might be surprised about is the fact
that I said that the file name was going to be optional is remembered.
The entire point of our program is to run a file.
Right.
So how can we make the name of the file optional.
Well the thing that we're going to do here is say that if a user does not provide the name of a file
to run we're going to check and see if there is an index J.S. file in the directory that they're running
this tool from.
If there isn't indexed not just file then we will just run that by default.
Otherwise if there is not an index that j just file and there is no file name provided by the user then
we'll show an error message okay.
Then after we define our program remember we finally have to do program DOT pass and specify process
dot GV like so now before we test this I got to comment out everything else inside of your just so all
those extra console logs don't kind of muddy up the screen so I'm going to save this.
I'm gonna go back over my journal
and I will run watch it needs to and I do.
I see just a console log of an object.
The reason for that is that in that invocation we did not provide an argument for file name right here.
So usually that first argument is gonna be an object with all the different arguments provided we did
not provide one.
So file name was just empty or semi the args object was just empty but if we do watch it would say file
to run dot J.S. will then see a console log of an object that is file name and there's the argument
that we provided right there.
Now here's the real benefit in my opinion to using this capital stuff we can do right away watch it
Dash H that's going to print up a bunch of help that gets automatically generated by the capital tool
when I run capital dash H.
We're going to display the name of the program the version and then some information about how to actually
call this thing.
This means if a user wants to use our program they have to call watch it with some file name optionally
if they want to know what that file name is used for.
Well it's gonna be the name of a file to execute.
There are also some other global options that can be used here that get specified.
These are all added in by capital automatically.
This all looks pretty good.
So quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're gonna start to move all of our file watching code into that action
statement and then start to start up the user's program and actually get it running so quick pause.
I'll see you in just a minute.