All right now do we understand how the browser makes a form submission to our server.
We need to figure out how we can somehow access the information that is sent along with the request
on our server when we making a get type request for that form submission.
Accessing the information was very easy because all the information was stored inside the URL of the
request we're making.
But now our form is making a request with a method of post which means all the information is instead
being appended into the body of the request.
So we need to understand how to access this information from our server Believe it or not.
It's gonna be just a little bit complicated.
We're gonna end up looking at two different ways of getting access to this information on our server.
The first way is going to be kind of a behind the scenes look to understand what is really going on.
After that will then take a look at a second way that is more of how we handle receiving this information
on a real production application on a day to day basis to make sure it's really clear.
Our goal right now is to make sure we can add in some code to this request handler right here to take
the email password and password confirmation that was provided inside of this request object and actually
create a user account with it.
So all we're trying to do right now is get access to email password password confirmation
OK.
So now we understand that.
Let's take a look at a diagram.
Get a better sense of what is really going on behind the scenes.
All right.
Here we go.
So whenever we make a request from our browser to our server there is not just one single exchange or
packet of information that gets sent over.
In other words it's not just like one single box that is being sent from our browser to the server instead.
All right.
Request that we issue is broken up into several different little packets of information that are sent.
Bit by bit from the browser to the server in the initial exchange between the browser and the server
the browser sends over some H TTP header.
This header is essentially just the path that we are looking for along with the method of the request
and any relevant headers as well.
So in other words when the server first gets wind or notice that there is some incoming request it only
understands the path that the request is looking for and the method of the request as well at that point
time.
It has not yet received the entire request so it doesn't have any firm idea about what information is
being sent inside the body of the request namely it doesn't know about this form data right here now.
Unfortunately when the browser sends over that first little bit of information to our server our server
receives that request with the just the and method and it immediately runs the appropriate callback
method.
So in other words this function right here is going to be invoked before we have the full request in
our hands before we have access to the full thing so in other words.
The problem here or the challenge with getting access to the email password password confirmation inside
this function is that well we just don't have access to it yet.
We don't have the full story.
So we have to write out some code inside of here that essentially says hey wait up for just a second
let's wait for all that additional information to come in before we run any additional logic so back
on the browser after that initial little exchange or negotiation of communication the browser is then
going to take a look at all the data that is inside of that form is then going to take all that information
side the form and send it over to our server.
Bit by bit.
So like one little chunk of information and then wait for confirmation that the server received it then
the next little chunk and the next little chunk and so on until all the different little chunks of information
are sent to our server only at that point does the browser consider the request to be complete or at
least the initial sending of information to the server so we need to figure out how to write the code
that's going to take all these little chunks of information and essentially assemble them together bit
by bit.
So let's go back over to our request handler and write out the code that is going to do that tobacco
over here and going to remove the comment I just added and replace it with rect on data then I'll pass
in a callback function that's gonna receive an argument called data and inside there I'll do a console
log of that variable
all right.
So first off what's going on with the record on and the string of data.
Remember back inside the browser we had that ad event listener method that we can use to register a
callback whenever some event occurred.
The same thing is going on right here.
We could think of the Iraq object as being like an HMO element that is going to emit an event at some
point time.
The on method is just about identical to add event listener.
So we're saying that we want to run some callback function when some event occurs.
In this case the event that we're waiting for is called the Data event.
So the request object emits a data event any time that it receives some bit of data that data is then
passed in as the first argument to this callback function.
And as you'd guess right now we're just console argument OK.
So right away let's do a save of this go back over to our browser.
I'm going to navigate back to locals 3000 manually.
I'm going to put in some dummy information to my form and then click on sign up now Nothing changed
here which is to be expected.
Well let's go back over to our terminal which is where that console log should appear.
So I'll go to my terminal and here's the console log.
Right there.
You'll notice that the data object that we received is not some like plain information that is very
easy to understand.
Instead it comes in the form of something called a buffer a buffer is essentially an array in javascript
that contains some raw information.
So like Ra Ra.
In other words each of these little pairs of numbers right here are hex values and each of them represent
a single character inside of the response or the bit of data that we got back from our server or suite
that we got from our browser.
One thing you'll notice is that we only saw one console log even though I told you that the information
that gets communicated is going to come over chunk by chunk.
Well in reality each chunk is sent over little piece by piece but usually each chunk is going to be
of some minimum size.
In other words each chunk can accommodate some amount of information.
Right now we are sending over a very small amount of information from the browser to our server.
So the a very small amount that we are sending all fits inside of one little chunk.
Which is why we only see one data event.
It's only it's because we only receive one chunk of information if we were trying to send over much
more information like maybe the contents of an entire book many megabytes worth of text.
Then we would start to see this kind of chunking behavior instead so as you guess working with the bug
buffer is not super helpful.
Like we don't really need access to the raw information.
What we need is to take this information and convert it into well a plain string so that we can understand
exactly what is being communicated to do so we can go back over to our editor on the console log of
data so data right now is a buffer object.
Remember that is like an array of raw information to turn it into some plain information we can work
with.
We will call to string UTF 8 on it.
That means take all the information in the buffer turn it into a string that is encoded in the UTF 8
format so I'm then gonna save that and then going to go back over to my browser.
We're going to do the form submission again and see that console log a second time so I'll sign up again.
Go to my terminal and now I see the string representation of everything that was inside of the body.
So it's the same kind of query string looking thing that we saw inside the URL so now as you can imagine.
Well we have to pass this string right here to get the information out of it that we really care about.
We don't really have to write out the logic to pass this thing.
There are libraries out there to do this kind of passing logic for us.
But just as a quick exercise let's do it ourselves.
Okay.
So back inside of my browser I'm going to take that variable right there.
That information that's being communicated and we're going to essentially pass it bit by bit and add
all that information into an object to make it easier for us to work with so to get started going to
first cut data to string UTF 8 out and assign it to a variable they'll call past and then going to split
that thing because it is a string by the ampersand symbol it's now past is going to be an array of strings
where each string is going to be email equals something then password equals something then password
confirmation equals something so I'm going to take that array of strings I'm going to loop over it.
I'm going to take each of those something equals something split it into a kina value and then add them
both to an object.
Let's just write out the logic for it.
I think you'll understand what's going on I'm going to first create an object called form data.
This is going to be an object that's going to eventually contain all the information inside the body
the request or then use a for of loop to iterate over each pair or Sammy each little grouping of strings
inside the passed array.
So I'll say for let pair of asked then inside of your pair.
Once again is going to be equal to email equal string or password equals blah blah blah and so on.
So I'm going to split that based on the equals sign it's all say const key and value are pair dot split
on equals.
You'll notice I did some.
Yes 2015 restructuring right here.
So I know that when I call it paradox split I'm going to get back in array of two strings by putting
in the brackets right here.
It means take the first element out of that array and assign to the key variable.
Take the second element out of that a right.
And assign it to the a value variable.
Now I can use key and value to add that information to my form data object they'll say form data at
key equals value and finally after we iterate through all those different pairs I'll do a console log
of form data.
Now if this logic inside of here looks really confusing that is totally okay.
Remember what I'm showing you right now is just kind of a behind the scenes look we're eventually going
to use a library that is going to take care of all this stuff for us automatically.
All right.
So going to save this I'm going to once again go back over to my browser.
I'm going to go to locos 3000 entering some fake info and then hit sign up and finally go to my terminal
now once over here I can see all that information in a way more usable state no longer is it inside
of that confusing object let alone that confusing buffer thing.
Now it is inside of a plain javascript object that I can use to work with that information super easily.
So now if we want to know the e-mail password password confirmation that the user is trying to sign
up to our system with well we can just access each piece of information inside this object.
So as you can tell this would be a very ideal way to work with this information.
So like I said let's take a pause right here.
We're gonna come back the next video and rather than writing out all this stuff on our own we're going
to instead use a little library that's going to take care of all this form handling stuff for us automatically.