All right.
Our friends we've now discussed salting and hashing passwords.
So let's start to write out some code to implement this entire process.
The first big question that comes up is where are we going to put all this code.
Are we going to put it inside of this sign in request handler.
Are we going to put it inside of a sign up up here.
Well I think that the best place to put a lot of this logic is inside of our users repository inside
of repositories.
Users J.S. inside of here we have a method called create this method right here.
We could add in some additional code to automatically generate that salt append it onto the parser that
gets provided hash the results and then store that along with the user attributes we pass in.
In addition we could also add in an additional method to this class called something like compare passwords
or something like that.
And that method could be responsible for this entire process we just described of handling when a user
signs back in and we need to essentially take the password they just provided through on the random
salt hash it and then compare it against the original START stored one so all this hashing and salting
stuff we're gonna add all the logic to it or for it directly to users repository.
Now that we know where we're going to add this code now it becomes a question of well what code are
we going to write.
There's two big things I want to point out.
Inside the no GSR standard library that are going to help us implement this hashing and salting algorithm
or this entire process.
Let's take a look at the No GST in our library documentation once again and again at no Jazz dot org
slash API.
Once here I'm going to find the crypto section on the left hand side the inside of here.
There are two different functions we're going to use.
First take a look at a function that we're going to use to generate our salt.
Remember the salt is the random string of characters that is going to prevent a user from giving us
the password that is too common.
The function we're going to use to generate the salt is going to be simply the random bytes function
which we are used a little bit ago.
So we can use random bytes to essentially calculate a random series of characters.
So we're going to use this to generate our salt then to do the actual hashing process.
We're going to use another function inside the crypto library called s crypt so we can search for s
crypt.
There it is right there.
This has a really weird name for a function.
The word s crypt is named after a very specific password hashing algorithm scheme.
So this is really the name of a specific way to compute a hash we can take a look at some of the arguments.
I think a lot of them will make sense right away.
The first one is the password.
So this is going to be the plain text password that we are trying to turn into a hash that we can store
inside of our database or compare it to an existing password.
The second argument is going to be our salt then we've got the key link that's not super relevant or
important for what we're doing.
There's also an options object.
We're going to use the default values for all these options and then finally there's the callback function
after we call s scripts.
We're gonna put in our UN hash password and our salt.
Once this function has computed the hash it will then invoke our callback function.
So we're going to receive the salted and hash password or to be precise the hashed salt plus password
inside that callback.
So we will receive that callback.
It'll be called with what they call a derived key the drive key is really just the hash password.
We're then going to store that inside of our database along with our user OK.
So now we have a good idea of some the different functions we're going to use.
Well let's get to it.
Let's start to update our users repository they've already required in crypto at the very top.
I'm going to then go down to the create function down here so we're going to assume that this adders
object right here is going to essentially represent a user.
So we're going to assume that adders always has a object with an e mail property that is a string and
a password property that is a string as well that's what we are assuming that adders is so that in mind
we're now going to take that adders object we're going to generate a salt then throw the password that
was provided along with that salt into the s crypt function.
OK.
So right underneath the I.D. I'm going to first generate a salt.
So I'll say salt is going to be crypto dot random bytes I'll throw an eight.
Remember this is the number of bytes for every byte we create we get back to separate characters and
I'll call to string
that's going to give us a random series of numbers and letters for our salt we're then going to use
that salt plus the password that the user provided inside the actor's object to generate our hash password
so we can call inside of your s crypt with the adders password and the salt that was just provided we're
going to put in a key length of 64.
Again not super relevant about what that is all about right now.
We could add in our callback function the callback will be invoked with some air object and what is
called Inside the documentation derived key as really a buffer that has our hash password inside of
it.
Remember a buffer inside of no Jesus is like an array that has some raw data.
So rather than calling that argument derived key I'm just going to call it above.
Short for buffer and then inside of here I'll say hash equals buffer dot to string x.
Now that is our hash password.
We're going to want to take the hash password and store it along with the salt inside of our database.
But before we add that in I just want to point out that having to be constrained by a script with its
callback right here is just a little bit awkward because well we wanted to use that hash right there
to store it with our user.
But in order to do that we would have to essentially take all the rest the code we have inside of here
and paste it inside the callback I don't really want to use any callback based code.
So rather than using the default script function we're going to instead use that promise of fi function
from the U till module inside the no J standard library we're going to use that promise if I function
to take this callback based version of s script and instead give us a premise based version of it instead
we can safely use the async await syntax with so to turn this callback based version into a promise
based version we'll go up to the very top I'm going to require that you tell it's quick reminder here's
the you till library right here.
So utilities inside of here is the promise of I function so we can pass promise ify some function that
usually receives a callback and it's going to give us back a new version that function that returns
a promise and a function returns a promise we can use of the async await syntax at the top I'll say
s script equals you tell dot Rama's mystify crypto dot s script.
Now this is a version of that function that returns a promise.
Let's now go back to our create function and make use of that new version the years create I'm going
to remove the callback because there no longer is a callback because we promise to find this thing I'm
going to put a weight in front of it to say let's wait for that has to be generated and then I'll store
the output as hashed now we've got our salts and our hashed password
so now where we call records stop push rather than just throwing in the entire adders object which remember
has the email and the raw password we're going to instead a massage that object is to a little bit so
I'm going to delete adders I'm going to replace it with an object I'll say dot dot dot adders and then
after that I'll put in password is set of tactics and we're going to put in hashed that to string with
hex because remember it has right here is still that buffer maybe to make this code a bit more clear
rather than calling it hash.
We should really just call it love stroke to the buffer instead.
So let's do that we're going to take that buffer convert it to a string hex based string in this case
well then put in a period and then also store inside of our password field the salt that we generated
as well remember the entire goal that period right there is just to make it clear inside of this one
single field where our hash password starts and where the salt starts.
So later on when we need to compare users password we can just very easily splits on the existence of
that period and get back but the sultan hash password and the salt you're the thing you want to remind
you about around this dot dot dot syntax.
This means create a new object.
Take all the properties out of our atoms object and then overwrite those existing properties with this
new password.
So essentially saying replace the default or plaintext password that was provided inside of batters
so we're going to push that new record into records were then going to write all of our data to our
users not just on file.
And if there is one last little change we need to make down here.
We just returned the adders object so we understand exactly what idea we have.
But now our final object they're actually saving is that one right there.
So instead of calling records not push but that object in line.
I'm going to instead cut that assign it to a record variable I'll push in record and then finally now
down at the very bottom instead of returning outers which still has the original plaintext password
I will instead return record which instead has the hash insulted password most are going to delete that
comment at the top and there we go.
That's pretty much it.
Now I know this refactor has been a little bit painful but this is pretty much it.
OK.
So let's now do a quick test.
So I'm going to go back over to my browser.
I'm going to go to my sign up route.
I'm going to enter in a new email that I've never used before.
I'll do test five at test dot com.
I'll enter and password and password I'll attempt to sign up NSC account created.
Yes that's definitely good start.
It's now going to go into my users dot JS on file now inside of here.
I'll find the new users.
That was just created.
So here's test five at test dot com and I can see that the password is no longer a plain text password.
Instead I've got the salted and hash password right there I go over to the right sufficiently far I'll
see a dot and then I see the salt joined on at the very end so that's pretty much it they're now storing
users passwords in a way more secure manner.
So now we can take a quick pause when come back the next video.
The last thing we have to do is make sure that we implement the flow for handling a user who tries to
sign it to click pause and I'll see you in just a minute.