There's one last change we're going to make to our validation logic so if we take a look at our overall
sign up request handler right now we've now got a couple of different Middleware is wired up that are
going to handle validation of email password and password confirmation.
However if we also look inside of our request handler sets the callback function right here.
There are still two steps of validation that are occurring inside of here reverse checking to make sure
that a user does not exist with that email and they're checking to make sure the password is identical
to the password confirmation.
So in other words at this point in time we are handling validation in two different locations of our
code base.
This is generally a very bad approach because now it means that any time we want to see if something
went wrong with our validation attempt we have to take a look at two different sources of errors both
what is coming out of our middleware and what is coming out of these different if statements.
So wherever possible we always prefer to merge or centralize all of our validation logic together.
So we only have to do one single check to see if anything went wrong.
Let's figure out how we can take these very custom validation checks right here and somehow merge them
in to these different validators so we've already set up up here first one to point out something that's
probably pretty obvious to you.
If we take a look at the different validators so we have access to there's no function inside of here
that's something like check to see if email is in use.
There's also nothing inside of here that says like check to see if this property equals this other property
for the password confirmation.
So because of that we're going to have to put together something called a custom validator a custom
validator is essentially some custom function that we're going to add into these different validation
chains.
It's gonna run some custom validation logic that you and I put together and then if something is not
quite right with the check that we're doing we're gonna throw an error which express validator is going
to interpret as meaning something is wrong with say the email property or password or password confirmation
documentation page has a really good example of how to use these different custom validators.
So on the left hand side will find it features and then custom validators so if we scroll down just
a little bit lo and behold there is actually an exact example of what we're trying to do check to see
if an email is in use.
There's also an example of checking to see if a password confirmation matches a password.
So these are both examples of just about exactly what we need to do so in order to check to see if an
email is in use.
We're going to chain on a call to a function called Custom when we call custom.
We're going to provide a function that is going to be used to validate that particular property.
Our function is going to be called with the value that was provided by the user.
And then inside of that function it is up to us to figure out whether or not this is a valid input or
what if the input is valid then we don't have to return anything but if it's invalid we're going to
throw an error message.
And I know that that's not quite what you see inside of here.
They've got a promise rejection that's because they're using a very promise based approach right.
Here we are making use of async await in order to do something equivalent in our setup we have to throw
in air.
Let's go back over to our editor.
We're going to write out some somewhat similar logic to what you see right here and check to see if
an email is in use okay.
I'm going to find my check for email at the very end.
I'm going to chain on custom and then pass in a function.
This function is going to be called with the value that we are checking rather than calling it value
as the argument side of here.
I'm going gonna call it email because that's really what it is.
I'm also gonna mark this function has been async because I want to use async await syntax inside of
it.
Then inside of there we're gonna do exactly what we're doing currently inside of our callback function.
We're gonna check to see if there is an existing user and if there is.
That means that something just went wrong.
So I gonna take that little block of code right there.
I'm going to cut it and then paste it into the custom function
then instead of trying to return and call a red dot sent.
There is no red dot send or even a red variable inside of here.
So instead in order to indicate that to express validator that we just failed validation we're going
to throw a new error.
We're going to provide a string to the error and the string that we put inside of here is going to be
the message that eventually gets shown to a user.
So in this case I'll say something like email in use
okay.
That's pretty much it.
Let's now save this.
We're gonna go back over to our browser and test out our sign up flow again.
So I'm going to go back over I'm gonna go to my sign up about I'm going to enter in an email that has
already been used before to make sure that I enter a email that's been used.
I can always open up my users dot Jason on file and find an email inside of here that I know has been
used.
So going to use test three at test dot com they'll do test three at test dot com I'll enter whatever
passwords and then attempt to sign up I'll then go back over to my terminal and take a look at the era
that was thrown.
So here it is right here.
So I'm being told now that that e-mail is already in use OK.
So that's definitely good.
So we now know how to kind of take all these custom validation checks and centralize them with all of
our other validation logic.
So now we're going to have one source of ear information inside of all of our different request handlers
which once again makes error handling way easier.
We cannot repeat that same process for the other piece of custom validation we have which is to check
to see if a password in password confirmation are identical so for this I'm going to go and find where
we are doing some validation on the password confirmation.
I'm going to add in a custom call
that's going to receive a password confirmation on this case in order to validate the password confirmation.
We need to get another property or another value out of the incoming request.
We need to compare a password confirmation against the password.
Unfortunately this function right here is only called with the first argument of the value that we are
actually trying to validate.
But we do have a little trick or a little escape hatch if we go and take a look at the documentation
once again around checking to see if a password confirmation matches the password.
You'll see that this custom validation function takes a second argument or receives a second argument.
It is an object that contains the request object so we can d structure out that req object and then
manually inspect the body property and find the password inside there.
We can then use that to do a comparison against the password confirmation so we'll do that back inside
of this custom function.
I'm going to receive the second argument.
It is an object that contains the Rec object under the REC property.
So I'm going to d structure out rec just to be really clear if we were not using D structuring here
we would have something like Obi J short for object and I would say const Rec is object rec that is
100 percent equivalent to just doing the D structuring step like so so that inside of your will say
if password confirmation is not equal to rec body password then we need to fail validation and to fail
it will throw a new error and in a string it will just explain to the user why this validation just
failed so let's say passwords must match
Okay that should be it.
So let's save this and do a test of the password confirmation as well so I'll go back over go to sign
up I'll put in whatever email I'll put in two passwords that definitely don't match and then intend
to sign up so now if I check my terminal I'll see passwords must match very good okay.
So this is looking pretty good.
We have now centralize all of our validation logic into this middleware the set of middleware.
Last thing I'm going to do inside of here I'm going to make sure that I remove that little password
check right there right away.
You can tell just immediately that since we have removed all that validation logic at this request handler
the logic inside of here is so much easier to understand.
In particular if we remove some of these comments
it just gets a lot easier to really figure out what is going on.
Nonetheless we have to do is to make sure that if there are any errors that occurred we need to somehow
get those into our original form that we showed while the user was filling out the sign up form and
somehow show some validation messages inside there and explain to the user hey here's why this mission
just failed so we're not quite done yet.
The other thing that we need to take care of is if you take a look at our post request handler This
is a lot of code and a lot of extra lines to be placing inside of here.
And so we kind of nice if we figure out some way to kind of condense all this validation logic because
otherwise this attack JSF file is going to be incredibly hard to read and navigate over time especially
if we want to validate many different properties in an incoming request.
We still have a couple things to figure out.
Let's take care of that in the next video.