I'm still taking a look at the documentation for the file system module inside of no J.S. so inside
of here.
I want to take a look at a very specific function that's going to allow us to accomplish the app we're
trying to build which remember is to print out all the files and folders inside of some given directory
so in the FSA or file system documentation I'm going to do a search on the page or read
that we are looking for the FSA dot read dir which is short for read directory function it's going to
find that documentation and click it to this is a function that will allow us to read the contents of
a directory.
So we're going to be given back a array of strings and that array of strings is going to be all of the
different file names inside of a given folder.
So this is essentially exactly what we need to start up our project because like we said we're trying
to just really read the contents of a directory and print it out at the Council.
All right so let's start up a project.
We're going to create a new project folder create an index not just file inside there and then we will
tried to get access to this function and call it from within our code to get started.
I'll go back over to my terminal and back inside of a workspace directory of sorts inside of here.
I'm gonna make a new project folder called list.
The idea here is that we're going to be listing files and folders.
We can call it anything we want.
The name list is appropriate or at least good enough.
I'll then change into there and then start my code.
Ed once my editor is open I'll create an index.
Dot J.S. file.
All right.
So now we've got a place to get started.
We need to get access to the file system module inside of our project to do so.
We have to add in a required statement and add in the module from the node standard library that we
want to make use of.
So to get access to the file system module we will write out const F S equals require F S So why did
I write f s here.
Well it turns out that the filesystem module in node is abbreviated just about everywhere as simply
f s..
This is not the case with every module inside the node center library.
They are not all abbreviated so unfortunately as you start to get used to the different modules we have
access to you're going to have to take a look at some the different documentation to get a better sense
of exactly what we have to require when we're trying to look for a given module with most other modules
that we're going to use.
It's pretty straightforward to figure out exactly what we're going to require in.
So for example if we go back over to our documentation and take a look at the left where the path module
to get access to the path module we would require the word path as opposed to the abbreviation of it
which might be just like the letter P or something like I said.
Unfortunately you're going to have to get a little bit of experience reading the documentation to understand
how to get access to these different modules just understand that some of them are going to be kind
of abbreviated or whatnot or they might have some naming it is not a hundred percent expected.
Another good example of this is the child processes module.
So to get access to this module you might think you'd simply like the letter C P or something or even
just the word child process or child dash process or something like that.
We'll know it turns out that to get access to that wanted it as child underscore process.
So again you're gonna have to do a little research and just have kind of a good memory on how we get
access to these different modules.
So again to get access to the filesystem module we write out require FS and we assign it to a variable
f us.
Now this object right here or that variable is an object that has all the different pieces of functionality
that are stuffed into the file system module so on that object we can get access to every single function
that you see listed out inside of the file system documentation so everything inside of here we access
all of it through that F S object.
So as we mentioned the one that we really care about here is read Dir.
I'm going to get it back on screen.
Here it is right here.
So now we can call the F S dot read it dir function directly.
Let's take a quick pause.
So this video doesn't go on too long.
We'll come back the next section and start to learn how to use this function.