Now you've got a better little test harness to make use of right here.
Our goal is to be able to run for each dot test out J.S. with our TMI program and have the test in here
actually be executed and then report some results about it.
The most obvious thing we need to do right now is to make sure that the IT function inside of here is
somehow defined.
So remember whenever we make use of moka moka is going to run all of our different test files inside
of our project and it's going to magically make the IT function available inside of here for us.
It really does appear like it's magic because look inside this file nowhere inside this file did we
define the IT function.
So how do we magically make the IT function available inside of here.
Well it's actually kind of simple and straightforward back inside of runner Duchess right above the
require statement which is where that file is going to actually be executed.
We're going to define global dot.
It
Global is a very special keyword or a very special variable inside of no J.S..
It's very similar to the window variable inside the browser.
This is a variable that is available inside of every file and it's shared between every file as well
if we ever write out the name of some variable like so like just it inside of any given file of our
project node is going to first check to see if the variable was diff or that variable is defined anywhere
inside this file.
If it wasn't notable then automatically take a look at all the different properties that are attached
to the global variable.
If node can find this on that global variable it's going to reference that property so in other words
if we write out simply it right here node is going to resolve that to this function automatically and
this global variable really is global in scope.
So it is shared between all different files.
So long story short if we define this function right here right before we require this file when we
execute the file.
So the for each dot test file the actual it statement right here or this it will look up node is gonna
see that variable that's going to see that nowhere inside this file was it defined.
So it's then going to look at the global scope or the global object and that's going to find it function
located over there.
That's how Moka does it.
And that's exactly how we're going to do it as well.
OK.
So now inside us it statement I'm going to receive the description and a function that the IT function
is going to be called with.
So description and effect right here is going to be that description.
And that function so far right now inside of our IT function let's just do a real simple console log
description or DSC it's going to save this go back over to my terminal.
I'll run to me again and we'll see the description of our test should some and a right.
Awesome.
So that means that we can successfully kind of inject the IT function into the file that we are about
to require.
Now keep in mind that we want to have at least somewhat parity with moka moka has not only the IT function
it also has the B for each function as well.
So I would like to have a kind of kind of pseudo or mock implementation of before each.
Remember when we spoke about this project overall we said that we were going to write our own testing
framework that works in like 80 percent of cases.
It turns out that MCAS implementation of before each is like really really special.
And there's a lot of like interesting corner cases that it handles.
We're not going to really implement any of those corner cases.
We're going to simply make sure that if anyone ever calls before each inside of our testing framework
it's simply going to run a given function once before every et statement that's pretty much all we have
seen before each do with Moka but just you know Moka has like some really interesting things that it
does with before each as well.
Again we're not going to worry about that extra stuff where it can take care of the very basic implementation
so let's add some code inside of here that's going to kind of serve as RB for each I'm going to put
a before he try here and then to have like an actual legitimate usage of it I'm going to define a let
variable up here called numbers inside them for each I'll say numbers is 1 2 3 and then I'll delete
the numbers declaration inside the it statement.
So in other words our goal of before each is to just initialize the numbers array and make it make it
available for the statement that we're about to run
OK.
Now to really make sure that the before each is running before every it statements let's add in a second
it statement as well it's all do add second it's statement down here and I'll say it before each is
ran each time.
That's essentially our description we're literally writing a test about our testing framework right
here kind of better so then inside of here let's try to use the numbers array in some fashion it's all
just say like about asserts and we'll do a strict equal about numbers what length should be equal to
it.
Three.
Now to really test this thing out.
The idea here is that we're going to reinitiate size numbers for every single it statement.
So to really test this out inside of our IT statement right here after the asserts let's add in some
code to kind of destroy the numbers array.
Second to say numbers dot push re And how about we do that a couple of times now after this statement
runs we have now like destroyed or completely wrecked the numbers array.
If we then attempt to immediately run this it statement down here we're not going to get a numbers length
equal to three.
Instead it will be the one two three like we have right there plus four five six seven so if the before
each is going to actually run before each it statement we should have both test passing right now.
If it doesn't run before each the second test is going to fail because we have changed the numbers array
and it did not get reset between each test case.
Let's go back over to our runner dot j ust file and now we're going to have to implement global dot
before each so this thing is going to be given some function to make sure that we receive that function
and then eventually call it before every it statement that actually gets invoked I'm gonna create a
new array up here called before each is and I'm going to store a reference to that function that was
passed in inside
it's now inside of our IT statement we're going to fill out the actual implementation it's going to
take a look at all the different type of right there by the way and make sure that's global dots before
each.
There we go so inside of our it's implementation we're going to take a look at all the different before
each is that have been loaded up so I'll say before each is that for each and for each function that
we loaded up and saved a reference to we're gonna call each one and then only after that are we going
to call the it statements function that was passed in so we'll call f n like so OK so let's test this
now going gonna say the file and if we don't get any errors that means everything worked as expected
I'll flip back over run to me no errors that means everything worked so now we can kind of make sure
that everything is really working as expected by going back over to the test file and I'll try changing
Say how about on a strict equal right here let's change that from six up to seven I'll save that go
back over and now we see an error because we failed that assertion unclear uncommon that or change that
back to six and then in addition down here on the second test let's try changing the number assertion
from three to four makes sure that fails as well and yet that fails as well so that's kind of like the
beginnings of our testing framework we now have the ability to setup inside of our test file some before
each we can set up some it statements and our runner is going to take a look at all the different statements
it's going to invoke every before each that has been defined and then run the actual test function so
I note this stuff is like really crazy right now don't get me wrong like this is a pretty darn challenging
project but we have something that like really works kind of not that bad.
So far we just have to add in a couple of extra stuff and we're going to be in a really good spot.
So take a quick pause right here and continue in just a moment.