Well we now understand the basics of matter J.S..
So now we can start to think about how we're going to build this actual maze.
In this video I'm going to give you an overview of the algorithm that we're going to use to generate
the maze itself.
And we'll start to write out the code for it.
So let's talk about how we're going to generate the maze that we're going to go through the algorithm
that you see right here.
I'm going to first give you a verbal description and then we'll take a look at a series of diagrams
to help you understand how this actually builds a maze out.
The first thing we're going to do is create a grid of cells a cell essentially represents each space
that a user can visit.
If we go back to the original diagram over here right here this kind of rectangular space like right
there that is one cell and then right next to it we've got another cell.
And then right underneath that another cell another cell and so on.
So we're going to build out a 2D array or a two dimensional right to represent this grid of cells we're
then going to pick a random starting cell inside there and then starting at that cell we're going to
build a randomly ordered list of all of its neighbors for each neighbor that we find.
We're gonna say that if we've already kind of visited that cell so to speak we'll discuss what it exactly
means to visit a cell in just a moment.
We're going to remove it from the randomly ordered list then for each remaining neighbor.
We're going to move to that neighbor and we're going to remove the wall between those two cells and
then we're going to repeat that process for that new neighbor.
We're going to go back there and repeat this process over and over and over again.
Now I really don't expect you to understand this algorithm just from these kind of text steps right
here.
So instead let me show you a quick diagram and help you really understand what's going on here OK.
So this represents a starting grid.
This is going to be a 2D array that we're going to build out of some javascript code.
So we're going to pick a random starting cell inside of here.
We're then going to iterate it using the same steps that I just spoke about right here.
We're going to see how it eventually is going to build us a randomized Nate's.
Let me get a different color really quickly get so out of our grade right here.
We're going to first start off with a random cell.
So in this case I'm going to start off with a random cell of that one right there.
We're then going to take a look at all of the cells different neighbors.
So in this case I'm going to look above to the left to the right and below.
So the four possible neighbors I have are one two three and four it's on then going to pick one of these
neighbors at random to visit.
So maybe in this case I decide to go down.
So I would go down to this cell right here when I go down there.
I'm going to remove the wall between those two cells so I would delete this wall right here then at
this new cell I would now take a look at all of this one's new neighbors.
So there's a neighbor above a neighbor to left below and to the right.
Now in this case I have already been to or kind of visited or processed the neighbor above.
So in this case I would drop the neighbor above from my list of possible cells that I could visit so
then maybe in this case I would decide to go to the left.
So I'm going to visit to the left.
Go over here and then just like before I'll delete the wall right there.
And now this process essentially is going to repeat itself over and over again.
So right here I've got three possible moves in this case I'll decide to go up.
And again this is totally random I'll go up to right there.
I will remove the wall in between
I've now only got two possible moves.
So either up or to the left because I've already been below and to the right.
So now maybe I go.
How about to the left now I can go up or down and only a couple more steps here because there's one
kind of corner case I want to point out to you here really quickly now maybe I would decide to go up
now I'd go up here I've only got one possible direction now I'm going to imagine that I come over and
then maybe I come over again I come over again and now I've got a random decision to make once again
I can either go to the right over here or below right there.
So I'm going to say imagine that maybe you randomly I go down and then randomly I go down one more randomly
down I know kind of crazy odds to go down that many times in a row.
But let's just imagine for a second.
And now here's where we start to get to a really interesting situation.
Let's imagine I come over here and end up right here.
It's now in this scenario as I am right here.
I don't have any additional way to move but there are still unlimited squares all the way over here
on the right hand side that I still need to visit.
If I ever get to a point where I have no possible moves whatsoever then I would essentially backtrack.
So I would go back until I find a cell that does have a valid neighbor to move to.
To the first one as I backtrack.
That would have a valid move would be this one right here.
So backtrack from here all the way to this cell right here and then back at this cell.
I would once again say what are my valid neighbors in this case.
I can only possibly go to the right.
So I would move over that way and then repeat the process for all the rest of those squares.
Now as I drew out some of these steps here rather quickly I didn't remove the walls but just be clear
I still would be removing the walls all along the way.
So I would drop that one that one right there right there right there and so on all the way through.
This drawing is getting a little bit messy here and one other right there.
It's getting a bit messy here so I got to delete some of the red lines.
Now if I do so you're going to start to see how I actually do end up getting a real maze shape here
I'm going to delete all those lines I drew on
and you can really start to see the maze start to form out.
So if I imagine I kept on going through this maybe I went from this one here to the right and then up
and then like something like this you know if I trace that out and removed all the appropriate walls
I really would start to see the entire maze start to form
so drop the walls for each one that I cross over and there we go there's my entire maze.
That's the general idea.
Again we're going to build out the grid.
We're gonna pick a random cell look at the neighbors walk to each neighbor as soon as we do we're going
to drop the wall if we ever get to a point where there are no valid moves as we saw right there.
We're going to backtrack until we find a cell that there is a valid move at and we'll repeat the process
from that cell.
So this is how we're going to generate the mates it's going to make sure that we always end up with
one valid path to every single square inside of our grid.
So this is going to guarantee that if I have a starting position up here as we said that our app was
and I want to get to the ending position down here at the bottom right hand side there will always be
a valid route to get there.
So that's the idea.
That's how we're going to implement this as you can imagine some of the code for it is gonna be a little
bit challenging but at the end of the day as long as you remember back to this example right here it
will eventually make some sense.
One thing that I highly recommend that you do as we start to write out all this code is get out a sheet
of paper and try to sketch out a grid like this one right here.
I'm going to continue to do a lot of drawings to help you understand every step along the way but it's
really no substitute for you getting out a piece of paper on your own and kind of drawing out or diagramming
the maze creation process.
So now that we understand the general idea or the general strategy let's take a pause right here and
talk some more specifics in the next video.