In the last video we added in some code to make sure that we only call our search function after the
user stops pressing on their key inside that input for about one second or so.
This entire process right here is referred to as D bouncing in input.
So this is when we are going to wait or some amount of time to pass.
After this last event before we actually run some function there is actually many different scenarios
in which we might want to d bounce some event inside of a web application not just for text inputs.
There might be some other scenarios that we want to limit how often we call it an order for performance
reasons exactly like what we just did for our API because of that I think that it might be useful to
think of some way to refactor the code that we just wrote right here and make it more usable in nature
because like I just said it might turn out that we have to balance other things inside of our application
at some future point in time.
And I don't know about you but this code right here is kind of hard to read and hard to understand.
So it would be nice to make this more reusable and kind of hide the complexity or hide the implementation
of the actual DB bouncing logic.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
We're going to refactor this into some more reusable fashion so we don't have to think about these like
really complicated set time out and clear time out calls and whatnot.
Now before we start to write this code I want to show you a diagram to just help you understand how
this refactor is going to work because it is going to be slightly complicated.
So here's what we're going to do right now we are essentially trying to D balance the on input vector
the on input function.
We're saying that we don't want to receive any notifications of a change to that input after until after
some amount of time occurs.
So we kind of want to guard access to the en input function to make that happen.
We're going to create a new helper function called the D balance function.
This DB bounce function is going to be a little bit complicated for exactly one reason we're going to
pass a callback or a function into this D bounce function.
The thing that makes it complicated is that the DB bounce function itself is going to return a function
as well.
That's what is complicated in my opinion.
Maybe that's really easy to understand but I think it's kind of hard to grasp the very first time you
see it.
Now like I said we're gonna pass a function in to the DB function that is something that is probably
not going to be a big shock to you throughout this course.
We've seen several times already where we pass callback functions to other functions and we're already
doing it back over here.
We are passing a function into add event listener so that on input can be called at some point in the
future when the user input something into our text input so that part passing a function into another
function not that bad.
The only hard part to understand here is understanding that DB bounce is going to return a new function.
So this green box right here represents a new function.
It's like a wrapper of sorts that's going to restrict calls to the original on input.
So this on put input right here is the same function as that one.
So again this green box it just restricts access to on inputs.
It might be better to visualize this using a slightly different diagram from this diagram.
We saw the green box that represents kind of like a wrapper function of sorts that restricts access.
You can imagine that the green function this wrapper kind of has like a shield of sorts and it's going
to guard against repetitive instantaneous calls too on input.
So if we start to call on input very quickly several times in a row the shield is going to step in and
say Sorry you can't get through.
You have to wait some amount of time before I'm actually going to execute your call so we can imagine
that maybe one second passes and we end up like down here.
And at that point in time the shield is going to say okay you know what most recent call to on input
I'm going to actually let you through is one second did pass and you were the last person to call this.
So I'm going to let you through.
So again we can imagine the green function right here as being like that little shield that's going
to deflect all those other calls that's the idea.
So let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to refactor our code and build out this D bounce helper
function.