In this video we're going to start to figure out how we can handle these.
Add to Cart functionality inside of our app so the end goal here is to allow a user to say OK I want
these gloves right here.
Click on the Add To Cart button and then take some record of these gloves right here with this title
and that price and add it to a shopping cart.
We'll eventually then show user all the different products they've added to their shopping cart whenever
they go to that cart page.
We have a link to up here on the top right hand side.
So in this video we're going to start to figure out how we can essentially represent a shopping cart
inside of our application and how a user is going to interact with that shopping cart before we start
to think about our application in too much detail.
I first want to give you a quick demonstration of how Amazon.com handles a shopping cart.
So quick demonstration I'm going to open up a new incognito window inside my browser and then navigate
to Amazon.com once I get here.
You'll notice that I am not signed into amazon so I'm not authenticated or anything like that and then
going to scroll down I'm going to find some random product like how about these sunglasses right here.
I click on that product and then on the right hand side I'm going to click on Add To Cart.
So that's essentially the exact same kind of button that you and I want to implement.
So ideally we might just do whatever Amazon is doing right.
I mean can make sense.
So I got to click on that button and as soon as I do I get presented with a window that says OK fantastic.
You added those sunglasses to your shopping cart and then I can click on the cart button right here
and it will take me to a page that lists all the different items that I currently have inside my cart.
The really important thing to understand here the entire purpose of this demo.
I want you to understand that I have interacted with Amazon's product.
I have a shopping cart.
I have some items inside of my shopping cart.
But I am not logged in.
I have not signed in.
I'm not authenticated.
I don't have any kind of Amazon account right now or anything like that so in order to implement some
system like this some system like Amazon has where you can have a shopping cart without signing in or
anything like that there are really two big questions that we have to answer.
The two big questions we have to figure out is how do we somehow tie a shopping cart to a person who
is never going to be logged in.
So we want the user to go through our entire application like the entire shopping side experience without
ever having to create an account.
Remember the original idea behind all that authentication stuff.
We said Oh yeah.
The only point of authentication or logging into our application was to be able to get access to the
administration panel.
That was the only reason we put in any kind of authentication so you should not have to log into our
account in order to have a shopping cart.
So that's the big problem we need to figure out.
After that there is kind of a secondary problem.
So once we figure out how to kind of tie a shopping cart to a person who is using our Web site how can
we somehow figure out what different products are in that cart.
So again two problems and they're really the two kind of stages of the life cycle of a shopping cart.
How do we assign a person to a cart and then how do we assign a product to a cart.
That's a big thing we have to figure out.
So quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to start to discuss our solution to problem number one.