Hi there, and welcome to this Pluralsight course, Monitoring and
Event Response on AWS for DevOps Engineers.
My name is Mike Brown, and in this module,
we're going to be working with CloudWatch events and Amazon EventBridge.
We're going to begin this module by introducing
CloudWatch events and Amazon EventBridge.
We're going to discuss what we have in common and talk about how
Amazon EventBridge extends the capabilities of CloudWatch events for
managing event‑driven architectures in AWS.
We'll then discuss event structures in both Cloudwatch events and EventBridge,
and we're going to demonstrate events using both tools.
Finally,
we'll finish off this module by looking at how we can use
CloudWatch logs to monitor CloudWatch events.
So let's begin by introducing CloudWatch events and Amazon EventBridge.
Our customer Globomantics would like some advice on which AWS
service to use to automate certain actions.
For example, they would like to automate the deployment of new application code,
but they need a service to monitor their application repositories and
to trigger code pipeline when their code is updated.
They also need the ability to schedule a lambda function to run every 5 minutes,
and they require to be notified when Amazon GuardDuty records a new finding.
Ideally, if they can do this all in the same tool, then that will be preferred.
So, what we'd recommend?
Well, we'd advise Globomantics to use CloudWatch events or Amazon EventBridge.
Either of these tools can perform the actions that Globomantics requires.
So let's learn a bit more about these tools before performing a demonstration,
which will show Globomantics how to use these tools
to satisfy their requirements.
CloudWatch events have been around for a while,
and they essentially work in one of two ways.
First of all, they can be event‑driven,
so we can create a CloudWatch event that monitors for
some form of operational change in AWS.
We can then configure that event to inform a target to take action.
An example of this would be application code being changed in code commit or S3,
our CloudWatch event seeing that change,
and then triggering code pipeline to run.
We can also configure CloudWatch events to run a schedule.
These schedules self trigger,
either based on a cron expression or a rate expression.
Using cron expressions, we can be very specific about the minute,
hour, day, month, or year that we would like a particular event to run,
including repeating that event on a schedule.
With rate expressions, we create an event that runs when it is first created,
and then based on that input, periodically after that.
So with a rate expression,
we can create an event that runs when it's created and
then every 15 minutes after that.
These schedule events will be great for Globomantics and their lambda
function that they want to trigger based on a schedule.
So which of these would be used by Globomantics to notify them
when there's been a change in GuardDuty?
Well, that would be an event‑driven event.
An event‑driven event could see the change in GuardDuty,
trigger an action, then informs Globomantics about that change.
Amazon EventBridge builds on CloudWatch events.
It supports both event‑driven and scheduled events,
as well as allowing a greater level of integration with AWS services.
We can also more easily integrate our own applications,
as well as applications offered by third parties.
Amazon EventBridge also offers a real‑time stream,
delivering real‑time information from event sources to data targets.
When working with CloudWatch events, we monitor for events.
An event is a change in your AWS environment.
So, for example, if you create an EBS snapshot, that would be an event.
We can monitor that event and take action.
If like you delete the snapshot,
that also is an event that we can monitor for and take action against.
Almost every action that involves invoking API in AWS can
be registered as a CloudWatch event.
Our job, then, is to create rules in CloudWatch.
These rules match incoming events and routes them to a target.
Typically, a target is another AWS service,
but I want to react based on information from the event.
Targets then process the event and perform whatever
action the target was designed to do.
Now, Amazon EventBridge is very similar.
We have events, we have rules, and we have targets.
But again, EventBridge builds upon what CloudWatch events can do.
So EventBridge, for example, supports additional event buses.
An event bus forms integration between CloudWatch events,
or, in this case, Amazon EventBridge, and the source of those events.
With CloudWatch events, we have a single event bus, the default event bus.
With EventBridge, we have custom event buses available,
too, provided by third parties,
and event buses that allow us to integrate with your applications.
Today there is already a community of AWS partners out there
building event buses for EventBridge to integrate their
applications into our event system.
Here you have an example of event workflow using CloudWatch events.
It's quite a basic workflow with a single default event bus and
AWS services that can feed into that event bus.
We then create rules to monitor for certain events,
and when that event is seen, we pass that onto a target,
which typically is another AWS service.
Here we've got an event workflow, but this time with Amazon EventBridge.
Notice here the different event buses, partner event buses,
a default event bus, and customer event buses.
So AWS services still report into the default event bus,
but now you can build custom applications that could take advantage
of the default event bus or a custom event bus.
Notice as well the partner event buses allow an integration with
different software‑as‑a‑service applications.
The event buses interpret the events,
which again are then picked up by rules that we've created.
Once a rule picks up an event, it again sends that information to a target,
which triggers an AWS service.
The concept of events and event response in AWS is a very powerful thing.
And there's plenty of use cases for CloudWatch events and EventBridge.
So, for example, we can integrate AWS Config to CloudWatch events or EventBridge.
So if there's a configuration change to one of our resources,
we can all admit it saves us steps.
They either just inform us about that change,
or take remediation action, reverting the resource back to a previous state.
We can collect application metrics and use these to scale your
application's compute resources using events and EventBridge.
And in this final example,
we can see that we can use the details generated by an event to
place messages in Kinesis Firehose where those messages can be
transformed and processed and used by a wide variety of AWS services for analytics and reporting.