Now we have an understanding of what CloudWatch events are,
let's take a look at some CloudWatch event structures. In this
first example, our customer, Globomantics, needs to be informed
when an EBS snapshot is created.
So the first thing we need to do is create a rule.
This rule will be based on an event pattern as opposed to a schedule.
We would select EC2 as the service name when creating the rule, and
EBS snapshot notification for the event type.
We would then further filter the rule to monitor for createSnapshot events
as opposed to deleteSnapshot or editSnapshot events.
Once the rule is created, we should see the following JSON event pattern.
Here we can see the source is aws.ec2, detail‑type Snapshot
Notification, and the detail event, createSnapshot.
This is the event pattern that we're monitoring for.
You can create these patterns in any text editor and import them into
CloudWatch Events or EventBridge, or you can use the steps on the previous
slide to create the event rule for the console.
Next, we need to select a target, so that once createSnapshot has been seen,
Globomantics can be notified. So we select the target, and in
this example we're going to use SNS topic as that target. We
select the appropriate SNS topic. We then configure details for
the rules such as rule name.
So two steps for monitoring that snapshot event,
create a rule and select a target.
This is the JSON object we should see when that snapshot event occurs.
If you set up SNS, then you'll receive an email from SNS topic.
This is the detail you'll see inside your email.
Notice the detail‑type of EBS Snapshot Notification, the account ID that
generated this event, and the event was createSnapshot.
Next, Globomantics would like to run a lambda function every 5 minutes.
This time we choose Schedule as the event source when we create our event
rule. We select a fixed rate of 5 minutes as the interval, and then
select lambda function as the target.
We select the appropriate lambda function and finally finish off
this rule by configuring details such as rule name,
so just one step required for this scheduled event.
When you configure a scheduled event,
you get to choose between a rate expression, which,
as we stated previously,
will run when the initial rule is created, and then a fixed schedule
after that, and a cron expression for fine‑grained schedules not
supported by regular rate expressions.
Here's an example of creating a schedule‑expression using the AWS CLI,
aws events put‑rule ‑schedule‑expression, and then we have the rate and
the frequency of when the expressions have run, in this case every 5
minutes, and then we provide a rulename.
Now, this command is not complete.
Missing from this command is the actual target that
I want to run every 5 minutes.
Here's an example of a cron expression. These look more
complicated, and possibly they are,
but they do give us that finer‑grained level of control. Here, this cron
expression will run this rule at 12 o'clock every day.
We know this from the 12 in the second column and the
question mark in the fifth Column.
The question mark is a wild card, which in this position means
every day. When working with cron expressions,
we have six fields that we can work with,
starting from the left and working to the right, minutes,
hours, days‑of‑the‑month, month, day‑of‑the‑week, and year.
So now in the expression above we've got 12 in the hours
column, so 12 o'clock, and the wildcard question mark in
the day‑of‑the‑week column, which means every day.
So let's take a look at creating some events in CloudWatch Events and Amazon EventBridge.