EC2 instances generate lots of metrics that appear in CloudWatch,
but what about the applications that are running on those EC2 instances?
What about events that are registered by the operating system?
Well, we can cover that information too.
So in this section we're going to spend a few minutes talking about
how we can gather log files from EC2 instances,
and this conversation involves talking about the CloudWatch agent.
We can deploy the CloudWatch agent to EC2 instances or on‑premise servers.
Once deployed,
we can use it to gather metrics and logging information from the
operating systems and installed applications.
Whether we're running Linux or Windows,
there's a version of the CloudWatch agent that you can deploy.
And we can go back several generations of the Windows OS and the support
for multiple different types of Linux distribution.
The rough steps for deploying the CloudWatch agent include creating an IAM role.
If you're deploying the CloudWatch agent to an EC2 instance that
instance will need a role that's allowed to write metric and
logging information to CloudWatch.
Now we can't attach a role to an on‑premise server,
so if you're deploying the agent to an on‑premise server you
will also need to configure a credential file.
In that credential file you'll need the credentials that can write
metric and logging information to CloudWatch.
You then download the appropriate agent package
suitable for your operating system, but don't install it straightaway.
Instead, you need to modify or create the agent configuration file.
It's the agent configuration file that contains all
information about what you want to monitor on the EC2
machine or on those on‑premise servers.
The configuration file is a JSON document that you can create manually,
or there is a configuration file wizard that you can run through.
Once you have a configuration file configured you can then
install and start the agent on your servers.
This is a two‑step approach.
You install the agent first and then from a command prompt or in Windows from
PowerShell you start the agent by specifying the agent service and the
configuration file that we used to configure that service.
So, for EC2 instances, create that role that can write to CloudWatch.
For on‑premise servers,
create that credential profile locally. The credential profile will contain keys
for an IAM user that has the rights to write to CloudWatch.
Now the CloudWatch agent itself can be installed manually or you can deploy the
CloudWatch agent using Systems Manager or CloudFormation.
As mentioned a minute ago,
the CloudWatch configuration file is just a JSON document you
can create manually or by using a wizard.
The wizard will ask you a series of questions about your configuration and the
information that you want to gather and store in CloudWatch.
It then creates a JSON document for you,
and it's good practice then to store this JSON document in Parameter Store.
That way you've got a configuration file that's centrally stored that
other instances can then use instead of configuring a configuration file
manually each time you deploy a new EC2 instance.
So now we've got the CloudWatch agent deployed, we can gather all the
extra system‑level metrics from our EC2 instances that we just can't
get without the agent being deployed.
Add to that the ability to collect on‑premise metrics as well, we've
got ourselves a very powerful monitoring solution.
Don't forget, it's not just about the operating systems.
We can also create custom metrics that report information for our
installed applications and our installed services.
But possibly the most powerful feature is the ability to collect logs from both
EC2 instances and the on‑premise servers and use all that logging information
for our monitoring event response in CloudWatch.
Sending log data from your EC2 instances and your on‑premise machines has
lots of benefits starting off with the centralized storage of log files.
With all our log file information stored in one place it should make it
easier for us to secure those log files and work with them. Because we can
use a standard set of CloudWatch tools and APIs to access the log
information, and we're not having to learn individual tools for individual
apps, we should get quicker access to all this consolidated log information
as well.
Also,
by integrating with CloudWatch we can have indefinite log file retention. Now,
if you store log file information on the EC2 instances and those
instances fail or are replaced you lose access to the logs.
So by taking that log file information and storing it centrally in
CloudWatch we will have access to that log file information
regardless of the state of individual instances.
Also by collecting this log information from our EC2 instances
and storing it in CloudWatch we can access other CloudWatch
features such as CloudWatch alarms.
So now we've talked a bit about metrics and alarms and gathering
log information from EC2 instances, let's jump into a demonstration and have a look at some of this stuff.