We've had a look at some of the tools used in automated event
management, so now let's look at some specific scenarios around
automated event management and healing.
So our goal here, then,
is where possible, let the system heal itself and report the
results to you. In this first scenario,
then, we want to automate the deployment of new infrastructure if
there is a failure, and we've got a couple of possible solutions to
this scenario. Here you can see we've got an auto scale group, and
right now that auto scale group contains two instances, probably
deployed across multiple availability zones in the same region. Here,
if an instance fails,
then we'd expect the auto scale group itself to launch a replacement,
bringing us back the two instances and healing itself. At the same time, this
auto scale group can log an event to a log in an S3 bucket. We could then use
S3 events to start a reporting process that will cause a failure and inform
you that this event has occurred.
But what if the failure is more severe?
So same scenario here, we want to automate a response in the event of
failure, but this time let's say we lose all our instances.
Perhaps an AWS region has failed, or it could be that something's
gone horribly wrong with the applications deployed to those
instances, and that's caused a failure.
Either way, we're losing our auto scale group.
This infrastructure failure could be detected by CloudWatch event rule.
Once seen by the event rule, the event rule could trigger a step
function, and the first thing this step function does is trigger
a lambda function. The job of this lambda function is to deploy
our infrastructure.
It'll probably do this by working with CloudFormation to create a
CloudFormation stack that can deploy our replacement infrastructure
in a different region. Our step function could also instigate an SMS
step that sends you a text message so that you know about the
failure, and that the lambda function has successfully invoked the
CloudFormation stack.
So if it's a minor failure that can be resolved by the
auto scale group or a major failure which needs event
rule to trigger a step function, AWS has got us covered.
In the second scenario, some of our IAM access keys have been publicly exposed.
If detected, then, these access keys could be used to gain access to
your AWS account and cause all sorts of havoc.
One common place where we see IAM access keys all the time is GitHub, usually
embedded in some application code because the developer has forgotten to take
out the keys before making that code public.
Now it turns out that AWS routinely monitor public services
like GitHub looking for IAM access keys.
Once detected,
they can inform the relevant AWS account using an AWS Health event.
So what we need to do is configure a CloudWatch event that
will monitor for these AWS Health messages,
letting us know when our access keys have being exposed.
The CloudWatch event then will trigger a step function.
This step function will trigger a lambda function
to delete the relevant IAM keys.
It will also work with a second lambda function to
generate a report of recent key activity.
If these keys have been used,
then the information about that will appear in CloudTrail.
So the job of this second lambda function is to look for the CloudTrail
logs and build a key activity report based on the information found in
there. Our step function will also trigger a lambda function that informs
security that this event has occurred, and provides security with the key
activity report, so an example here of security event response and
automated healing.
How could your organization benefit from automated healing?
I guess a lot of the benefits will come down to quicker response times,
more consistent response to events, and freeing up your time to work on tasks
that add benefit to the business rather than responding to events that could
be easily automated. Whenever we talk about automation at AWS, we must include
a conversation about CloudFormation.
CloudFormation is our infrastructure's code tool in AWS that allows us to create
CloudFormation stacks that can do everything from deploying VPCs through to the
deployment and configuration of compute services.
If you're not familiar with CloudFormation,
then I would advise looking at one of the several
Pluralsight courses that covers CloudFormation.
Although there's lots of other infrastructure code tools out there,
because CloudFormation is fully integrated with AWS, it's a really good
starting off point for our infrastructure's code.
Also,
if you're in a developer‑led environment, consider
using tools like Elastic Beanstalk.
Beanstalk will automate almost everything for you, from the
deployment of EC2 instances through to their patching, and
deployment of your application code. As developers,
you just keep track of your application code, providing Beanstalk with new
versions of the code to roll out when necessary. Also,
consider containers.
If you're not using containers right now, then you probably will in the future.
Using containers for compute offers rapid deployment and rapid
scalability that we need in today's cloud world.
If we use the Elastic Kubernetes Service to host our containers,
then we can let Kubernetes manage the availability of our containers and
recovery of our containers in the event of a disaster.
Finally,
if we haven't already, start getting familiar with Systems Manager. Systems
Manager will give us operational insights and control of our compute
infrastructure that we don't get with any other tool inside AWS.
So now we've discussed a couple of event response scenarios with self‑healing, let's jump into a demonstration.