In this demonstration, we're going to be implementing CloudWatch Events.
We're going to be working with the AWS console.
And if you want to follow along with the demonstration,
you'll need your own AWS account.
Now we do encourage you to follow along with our demonstrations.
But you must be aware that whenever you deploy resources to AWS,
you might incur charges.
So if you do follow in this demonstration,
make sure you delete all the features you deploy once you
are finished them or you may incur costs.
I'm in the CloudWatch dashboard, and this time let's select Events.
One thing to note here is this information message.
CloudWatch Events is now Amazon EventBridge.
So we still have access to Amazon CloudWatch Events
through the CloudWatch console, but we also have the Amazon EventBridge console.
Now you may find that at some point in the future, the
EventBridge console will be visible through here or that
CloudWatch Events will be removed completely,
and you'll have to use the Amazon EventBridge console.
We'll be using both throughout this course.
For those of you thinking about the AWS DevOps exam,
make sure you consult the current example overview to see if the
exam has been updated with the new terminology.
So let's select Get started.
So here we're creating a new rule,
and the first thing to choose is an event source,
either event event pattern or schedule.
We'll leave event pattern selected and then choose a service name.
So I've selected EC2.
Now you can see the event pattern preview being built up
as we make changes to this new rule.
For event type, I've selected EBS Snapshot Notification.
And I don't want any notification, I want a specific event.
So if I select the specific event radio button, I'll then
for the drop‑down choose createSnapshot.
So I want this rule to be invoked when a new EBS snapshot is created.
Again, if I scroll down a little bit,
we can see now the full event pattern that's being created for us.
We can edit this directly by selecting Edit.
This also means that you can create event patterns outside of
CloudWatch in any text editor and paste them in.
I'm happy with this rule, but now I need to select the target.
So if I select Add target and for the drop‑down list,
we can see the list of targets that are possible for this rule,
including CodePipeline to trigger a software deployment,
Lambda functions to trigger a Lambda function based as rule,
and Step Functions.
Step Functions are one of our main workflow services inside AWS.
For this example, I'll leave SNS topic selected and then select a topic.
Now you can have multiple targets for each rule.
So if you need an additional target,
select Add target and choose the additional target.
If you're happy with the rule and targets, we can select Configure details.
This includes giving the rule a name and an optional description.
We could also untick the Enabled box to leave this rule created, but disabled.
I'm happy with my sentence here, so I can select Create rule.
It should only take a second to create the rule,
and you can see here the rule was successfully created.
We can search for the rule by typing its name in the filler box.
So in the future if I need to edit the rule, I can select it.
We can see the existing rule event pattern and its target.
Then from the actions, we can delete rule, disable rule, or edit rule.
So how would this looking EventBridge?
Let's take a look at that.
So from the Amazon EventBridge dashboard, we could say create rule.
We would give the rule a name and description.
We could then define a pattern, either event pattern or schedule.
So we select event pattern and then choose either a
pre‑defined pattern by service or a custom pattern.
If I choose pre‑defined pattern by service,
choose a service provider, so AWS, the service name,
EC2, and then the event type and the specific event.
So pretty much the same wizard that we saw through CloudWatch itself.
But because this is EventBridge,
we also have additional options for the event bus.
Our selection uses the default event bus.
And you may have noticed that from the Service provider section,
we could have selected Service partners.
If I select that now, then in the service name,
we get a list of partners who have integrated their services with EventBridge.
So Amazon EventBridge makes it easy to integrate with
Software as a Service providers.
Here we change back to our EC2 snapshot creation pattern.
If I scroll to the bottom of this wizard, we get select targets.
And it's the same target list that we saw from CloudWatch itself,
including Lambda, SNS, Step Functions.
And if we select SNS, for example, we get to choose our same topic.
Now I'm not going to complete this wizard.
But to complete it, we'd say Create, and that would put our rule into production.
Back in our CloudWatch dashboard, let's create another rule.
So if I say Create rule, this time we'll select Schedule.
So we want this rule to run every 5 minutes.
That would be a fixed rate.
And here you can see that's already selected.
If we want a more complex rule,
we select cron expression and then configure the expression.
With my schedule in place, I can select Add target.
This time I'll choose a Lambda function,
and then I can select the Lambda function that I want
to be triggered every 5 minutes.
If we're happy with the rule, we can select Configure details.
Again, we provide a name for the rule and an optional description.
If we're happy with that, we can select Create rule.
And our rule was successfully created.
So here we've created two basic rules using CloudWatch Events.
We'll be using CloudWatch Events throughout this course, creating more complex rules for our event response needs.