I think most of us will benefit from using cost allocation tags, but
tags can be used for so much more. So in this section,
let's have a look at working with tags for organization and security.
The first use case I want to discuss is using tags in AWS
Systems Manager to create resource groups.
Resource groups are used to identify sets of resources that are part
of the same project, that is being deployed by the same team, that
have the same lifecycle and security. And by grouping resources into
the same resource group, it makes it easier to manage and monitor
those resources,
as well as making it easier to run automation tasks against those resources,
particularly at scale. There are two ways to identify resources
that should belong to the same resource group. The first way is
to integrate with CloudFormation.
So when creating a resource group,
we can identify a CloudFormation stack, and all resources deployed to
that stack can be made part of the same resource group.
The second way is used tags to identify the set of resources
that should be part of the same resource group.
This means we could group together resources that have been deployed in a
myriad of different ways, and we don't have to rely on CloudFormation and
CloudFormation stacks to identify the resources for our resource groups. Now
that we have resource groups, we can work with them. We can collect inventory
from those grouped resources.
This will show us things like the operating systems deployed,
applications that are installed, the top applications that are
being used on those resources.
We can use these resource groups to target a specific command against all
resources in the resource group. We can define patch management and maintenance
strategies for the resource in our resource groups.
And we can identify common IT tasks that we need to run on a regular basis,
such as monitoring, alerting, and deployments, and target
that against the entire resource group.
So resource groups are a pretty powerful feature in AWS. But having
worked with lots of customers over the last few years, I also think
it's one of the features that is used least, possibly because
people don't understand the power that resource groups and Systems
Manager give us.
Another use case for tags is access control.
We can use tags for both resource‑based access control
and attribute‑based access control.
With attribute‑based access control, permissions are based on tags.
We attach tags to IAM principles, such as user and roles, and we
attach the same tags to AWS resources.
We then define policies that use the tag condition to grant
permissions to principles based on tags.
So if an IAM principle is given access to a tag called Project X,
they then can be immediately granted access to all
resources that have the Project X tag.
This can simplify your administration. Because as new resources come
online and they're given the appropriate tags,
your principles will automatically have access, instead of you
having to assign the access either during resource creation or
after the resource has been created.
We've got example of a policy here. We have the API
version and then the Statement section.
So here at the top of the Statement section,
we have an "Effect": "Allow" and an "Action".
So this first part of the statement, we're allowing access to the
rds:DescribeDBInstances action for all resources.
This should give the holder of this policy the ability to
describe, so read, all RDS instances.
The next part of the policy identifies additional
actions, again, Allow, this time rds:Reboot,
Start, and StopDBInstances. This also applies to all resources,
but take a look at the Condition section here.
This includes a tag condition.
So this effectively says that holders of this policy can reboot,
start, and stop DB instances as long as our DB instances are tagged with a
CostCenter tag of 0735 and a Project tag of DataAnalytics.
So we use the tags here to limit the list of RDS instances
that the holder of this policy can reboot,
start, and stop. Very clever stuff.
One of things we want to achieve with our tagging is consistency.
And one of the best ways we can do that is by implementing tag policies.
Tag policies define a set of rules on how tags can be used in AWS.
They allow us to standardize the use of tags in our AWS accounts.
We do this by identifying tags that are allowed to
be used in our AWS organizations,
including the tag keys and the allowed values that each tag key can have.
So instead of users free‑forming their tags,
we can say that each EC2 instance that's deployed must have
a tag of Department, and the department you choose must be
from this list So in short,
we can use tag policies to make sure that resources that are
deployed to AWS are tagged with the right key‑value pairs. Tag
policies are integrated with AWS organizations. So if you're not
using AWS organizations, then tag policies won't be available to you.
Once created,
a tag policy can be applied to the entire organization,
to a specific organizational unit in the organization, or
to individual AWS accounts.
This means that you can have different tagging policies for
production AWS accounts as opposed to accounts that are used
for development and testing.
The enforcement part of tag policies is optional,
but if you enable enforcement for a tag policy,
it will prevent noncompliance.
This includes preventing changes to tags, and also, it'll prevent deployment
of resources that don't have the correct tag supplied.
Now we've gone through a couple of use cases for tags, let's jump into the console and give it a go.