So now we've seen CloudWatch Events and Amazon EventBridge in action,
let's take a look at monitoring CloudWatch Events.
There are several tools we can use to monitor CloudWatch Events,
starting off with event metrics. So CloudWatch Events themselves
generate metrics that we can monitor. We can monitor these metrics
through the console by building a custom dashboard, or we can monitor
key metrics by using CloudWatch Alarms. We can also monitor CloudWatch
Events using CloudTrail events.
So as your team build CloudWatch Events, they're triggering APIs, on these
APIs are registered as CloudTrail events, so we can see who created the
CloudWatch Events and when, as well as they're monitoring ongoing change to
CloudWatch Events also through CloudTrail.
Finally, we've got CloudWatch Logs.
So as CloudWatch events are triggered,
we can also log that and then view the information in
CloudWatch Logs using tools like Log Insights.
There are several CloudWatch event metrics that are generated automatically.
These include failed invocation. This will be when
a CloudWatch rule is triggered, but it fails to invoke its target.
We also have invocations. So this will show you when
CloudWatch Events have been triggered.
We have matched events so you can see details of how many events of
matched CloudWatch event rules and triggered rules.
This will show us how many times a particular rule has been triggered.
So a wealth of information here about the actual ruling of CloudWatch
Events. These same metrics are also supported by EventBridge.
As already mentioned,
CloudTrail can monitor the API activity as registered in CloudTrail by
CloudWatch Events. And by interacting with Lambda functions, we can log
all the details of events to CloudWatch Logs.
In this module, you have learned the power of
CloudWatch Events and Amazon EventBridge.
We've discussed the structure CloudWatch Events and how
they are created using rules and targets.
You were also shown a demonstration working with
CloudWatch Events and Amazon EventBridge.
Finally, we went through some of the options for monitoring CloudWatch Events,
including CloudWatch Events metrics,
monitoring events with CloudTrail, and the ability to log
information from CloudWatch Events in CloudWatch Logs.
In our next module, we'll be working with tags in AWS. So join
me there, and we'll carry on our journey monitoring event
response on AWS for DevOps engineers. Thank you.