If you found yourself here, you're probably already
well aware of what the cloud is, at least at a high level.
As the concept of shared infrastructure matures,
it rapidly takes over common tasks that previously were handled by
on‑premise servers, or even personal computers.
A relatively new concept that has become widely adopted is leveraging the
power of the cloud for actually writing and debugging code.
With this new wave,
Amazon Web Services, Cloud9, is leading the way in regards
to adoption and cutting edge technology.
Integrated development environments,
commonly referred to simply as IDEs, are software applications that
provide tools for better enabling software development.
IDEs have been around for quite some time and can vary in regards to
the features and visual displays that they include.
Some popular IDEs right now include Visual Studio,
WebStorm, Xcode, Atom, and PyCharm, just to name a few. With most IDEs,
developers download and run the IDE software on their local machine.
They use the IDE to locally write, debug, and run code.
Cloud9 is a pioneer in the IDE world because it actually enables developers to
write the code, run, and debug all within their browser.
So what does this mean exactly?
Well, in short, you can access Cloud9 from a URL, and then from your web browser,
perform any functionality that an IDE would typically provide.
Straight from your browser, you could write, run, and debug code
with the suite of cutting edge features.
Let me say that one more time.
Cloud9 is a cloud‑based integrated development
environment, or IDE, that allows users to write, run, and debug code directly from their browser.