Since Cloud9 is entirely cloud‑based,
AWS has incorporated a concept called shared environments,
which allows multiple users to actively code and
collaborate in a single Cloud9 session online.
If you're familiar with Google Docs,
this is a similar concept, but for an integrated development
environment. Shared environments allow users to view and update the
same code in a single Cloud9 session and collaborate in real time
with built‑in chat functionality.
Paired programming,
which is a popular coding technique that involves two programmers
actively programming and debugging together,
is easily facilitated with Cloud9.
A good benefit here is that both developers do not need to be in the
same location or even have the same operating system,
since Cloud9 is entirely cloud‑based.
Shared environments are also beneficial when teaching
or providing live code reviews.
Teachers can allow students to view active coding sessions to provide real
time hands‑on experience with programming. And code reviews,
which are a concept where teams of developers actively review one another's
code, can also be facilitated easily with Cloud9 in this manner.
Lastly,
general group collaboration is a concept that shared environments can
facilitate, as you can have entire meetings of large groups of individuals
viewing the same code on their desktop in real time using a shared environment.
Using shared environments with Cloud9 is wicked easy.
So let's go ahead and take a look at how you can leverage
shared environments to collaborate in live coding sessions
with other programmers using Cloud9.
If we bring up our Cloud9 project from earlier,
we can see a Share button on the top right of the IDE.
Selecting this button, we can then control who has access to our Cloud9
environment. In the bottom of the popup screen, we can type users' IAM names
to invite them to collaborate in our environment.
There's a simple button toggle we can use to either give
the users read or read and write access.
I'm going to select the RW button to provide both read and write permissions to
our user from the last demo named Luka Doncic. We are then prompted with a
notification letting us know that the user we are adding has full access to our
environment. We will select OK and move on.
Great.
Now we have a confirmation that our user was
successfully added to the shared environment.
Now that our user is added,
we will see a popup that indicates when they have come online,
which means they're viewing the same Cloud9 IDE session as us.
If we select the Collaborate tab,
we can view the other users that are online within
this current Cloud9 environment.
The pane shows us the users in the current session and
also has built‑in chat functionality.
Since we have another user online, we can collaborate with them on the chat here.
Let's go ahead and send a message to ask them to extend our
application to add another sports team.
Now we can see that Luka, our shared environment IAM
user, is actively updating the code, and we can see his updates in real time.
This example shows how shared environments can be used to collaborate in
real time with other users remotely in the same cloud IDE.
It's often useful to leverage shared environments with video calls so
that you can collaborate with other developers on the same IDE as if you
were in person when you're both actually working remotely. It's more
common in the modern environment for software engineers to work remotely,
so leveraging tools like Cloud9 that can facilitate online real time
collaboration with IDEs is essential for providing cutting edge software
solutions and collaborating with coworkers to build resilient products.
We've covered a lot so far in our adventure with Cloud9. Let's
take a quick second to review and recap what we've learned thus
far. You've learned how to read,
write, and debug code using Cloud9, and an overview of some of the more
important features that can provide a better developer experience.
You learned how to provide users access to Cloud9 for team
environments using identity and access management with user groups
and IAM roles. Next, you learned how you can create an environment
setup that has environment variables in Cloud9 to have dynamic
runtime of Cloud9 applications.
And lastly,
we showed how using shared environments can allow you to use the
IDE collaboratively in real time using Cloud9.
Stay tuned.
Next,
we're going to cover how Cloud9 can integrate with other AWS
services and some of the advantages it has when developing applications within the AWS ecosystem.