In order to get a better understanding of how Cloud9 came into existence,
let's take a quick look at the evolution of cloud computing.
Back before companies like Amazon had shared cloud
services readily available for the public,
companies often had to host and maintain their own physical
infrastructure with their own on‑premise servers.
For engineers,
this meant that you would install an IDE directly on your local
machine that you used to write your code.
Then, you would push your code changes to a code repository that
was hosted on your company's local data center.
This data center often would also be used to run end hosts or
applications so that they could be accessed and used externally.
Obviously, this creates a lot of overhead for most companies,
since they actually have to run,
host, and maintain their own physical infrastructure.
So unless you're Google,
Amazon, or Microsoft, and your infrastructure is so
sophisticated that it could actually bring you revenue,
it's often a huge burden to have to host your own infrastructure.
So, as computing matured, on‑premise applications
often started to show common patterns.
Many applications leveraged common computing services and solutions,
such as databases, security procedures, object storage, user administration,
logging, and queues, just to name a few.
Since most companies have their own data centers,
they would be responsible for running,
hosting, and maintaining these types of services within
their own data center. Even if they leveraged open source
or purchased external solutions,
it added another layer of overhead on top of purchasing and
maintaining physical servers. Then, came in the cloud.
Companies such as Amazon decided to solve this problem by
providing cloud services that host, maintain, and run physical servers.
And on top of that, they also provided solutions for common application needs.
This concept of centralized infrastructure revolutionized the industry
and fueled the startup culture we often see today. By leveraging the
power of AWS, startup companies such as Airbnb and Lyft were able to
build world‑changing solutions without significant overhead, and now
they're household names.
In today's day and age, cloud computing is widely available,
so let's take a look about what modern application
development in the cloud looks like.
Engineers will often download the latest IDE on their local machine to write,
run, and debug their code. They leverage cloud services for common
architecture needs they have and to host and run their applications so
that they can be accessed across the world.
Software engineers often have very high‑powered personal computers so
they can write and run their code locally without any performance issues
that would result in loss of productivity.
Let's think about some cons of this setup. Foremost, having
high‑powered personal computers for every engineer in a large
organization can become quite expensive.
But what if the engineers actually needed to write
applications that require more processing power than even
the best personal computers can have?
Would it not make more sense to leverage the cloud,
since it's a centralized infrastructure with significantly more
resources than any individual could feasibly obtain.
If we mature our cloud setup a little bit more so that our code and IDE also
exists in the cloud, our computer then just becomes a conduit for us to
access the cloud where we actually do our writing,
developing, and debugging of our code, and our hosting of our applications.
Cloud9 is leading the way in cloud IDEs,
and we can easily access it via a browser through a URL. This means
that with a cheap Chromebook or an inexpensive laptop,
a developer could leverage the compute power of the cloud and
write and debug code with access to more processing power
than any personal computer has.
One of my favorite analogies for defining the cloud is the cloud
actually doesn't exist, it's just someone else's computer. Using this
rationale, you can have access to Amazon,
Microsoft, or Google's computer for an overall
cheaper price than buying your own. So since that's the case, why shouldn't we leverage it?