Now with this out of the way and prototypes, constructors and so on, you really learned a lot about objects,
all the key parts already have been covered.
Now it's about the finetuning and what you can do with object, how you can configure them and work with
them.
I want to have a look at how you can create and delete properties on objects, which can be done in a
more powerful way than you currently know it.
Here, I have an example object which has a cash property and a withdrawal function which basically
reduces the cash property by the amount passed to the function and then prints out the new amount,
so if I run this, we get that I withdrew that 1000 and therefore the new reserve is 11000. Now it would be great
to also have a deposit method
and I could create it by simply writing account deposit equals function,
whatever. I could do this but I also have another method of doing this, I can use the static built-in object
and call the defineProperty method.
With that, I pass as a first argument the object on which I want to define a new property, account and
then as a string, the name of the property I want to create,
deposit for example. The third argument then is the interesting part,
it's a Javascript object
and here I configure this property because until now, you might probably ask yourself 'why would you
choose
this way', it's much longer than by simply doing it with dot notation.
Well here, you can configure this property and there are some keys available which you can set, for example
the value key
and of course these keys are built-in and you can't enter any arbitrary names here but the value is available
and
here I can set the value of this property, like I could do it with dot notation still.
So I could set that a function should be the value of this property which takes an amount and all it
does is it increases cash by this amount.
So now if I call account deposit and I deposit 3000 and then I withdraw some money
right after that, I'm depositing 3000, then I'm getting 1000,
I would expect to see a new cash reserve of 14000.
Let's see what happens.
Yes, that's exactly the case,
so the deposit worked.
Still the question remains why would you do that,
it's a bit complicated task, right,
to do it like this? You cannot only configure the value, you get other keys as well. I'll demonstrate this
with another property, I'll name it name here and the value will not be a function, just the name of account, like
something like this.
Now of course I can log this account name to the console and if I run this, you'll see this name.
So far, so good.
Now I'll change the name to let's say ID000-3 and I'll print it out again.
Now that's pretty straightforward of course but you'll see what I want to get soon.
So what happens if I print this?
Somehow, this didn't get updated,
it's still the old name.
The reason is if we create a property with defineProperty, by default it's read-only,
so I have to pass another configuration here,
I can make it writable by setting writable to true.
Now if I run this code, you'll see the name changed and this should be the point where you understand where
the value of defineProperty lines.
It's useful if you want to create a property with a more detailed configuration,
you can't do this with the normal dot notation but here, you can use the default by not specifying anything
here which would make it read-only or you set it to be writable.
You also got other fields you can set, for example you can set it to be innumerable and this will come
in handy in the next few lectures where I talk about how you can loop through all the fields in an
object,
this basically will allow you to use switch this on and off if this should appear when looping through
but
I'll come back to that as I said.
You can also create getters and setters,
so I can create or set the get field here and set this equal to a function.
This function will be called whenever I try to access this name value here.
Then I can define what should happen when this gets called,
I could for example return
Hello.
Now for this to work, I'll get rid of the value because I can't set this together with get and now if I run
this code,
you'll see Hello there.
So I'm getting
Hello whenever I try to get the value of name.
I can also specify a setter which could do something but for this to be more useful, I'll go up to my
account up here and I'll add a property here too, _name where I will have a default
value let's say.
So this is a property on my object and I'm creating a new property, also named name but without the
prefix
and that's just the naming convention I'm using here,
both names are totally up to you. In the setter,
I'll then set this._name equal to name
and here in the getter, I'll return this._name, I'll
also sure that here I'm passing name
and here I should add a comma after this field.
So if I now click on run, you'll see we get default and then the new ID but we get this getter and setter
in between
and if I return Hello here again and I run this again, I see Hello all over the place.
So with getters and setters, you can control how values in your object are being set or fetched whenever
is something else from outside tries to access them.
This can be used to filter values for example,
so let's say I'm always returning this name but I'm not always setting it, I want to check if name equals
Max,
only in this case will I set the name.
This of course means if I run this now, it stays default because here where I tried to set the name, it's
not successful since this if check here is not successful whenever I'm not setting this name.
This however is important because this name here is what I retrieve when I try to access this name property,
so this
name property is kind of like a filter which bridges the outside of this object
and the inside, so which controls the access we have on this object.
That being said, what's always possible in Javascript is to simply print account_name.
If I run this, you'll always see I do get access to this and you will see this clearer if I print hello
in all the other cases, here
I'm still able to access
default.
Nonetheless, if you choose a set up where you provide getters and setters and in the end, you are the
person writing your source code,
you can make sure that you implement such filters and prevents certain values from being set and even
besides getters and setters, as you learned, this defineProperty allows you to set up and configure
your own properties for your objects
and again in the cheatsheet,
you'll learn more about this and you'll find links which explain you which configuration you may use
with the defineProperty method here.
Of course there's more than just get, set and writable.