With all that, I think you should have a solid understanding why objects are important, why they aren't
difficult at all, how you can create objects, how prototypes are important when it comes to inheritance
or kind of fallback places where certain methods or fields could be, how constructor functions make
it easy for you to create your own objects of pre-defined blueprints, how you can use different functions
or methods or things like this for/in loop here to work with your objects and how the this keyword
can be tricky but can be handled with bind or call or apply.
This has been a rather long module but objects are of course a key part of Javascript
and I'm very happy that we're now at the point that the basics as well as objects as well as arrays as
well as types and scopes are all set
and hopefully, you feel comfortable with those concepts,
if not as always check out the cheatsheets attached to the last lectures. There you'll find more descriptions
as well as links leading to resources which may allow you to get a bit deeper into the different concepts
explained here.
I'm looking forward to the next module where we will have a look at errors and how we can debug
them
before we dive deeper into functions and what we can do with them in Javascript. See you there. Bye.