Let's start with the window object,
so the overall holding container and remember that I've already said that the global scope is the window
object, so this global object is the window object in the browser and this is the case.
Therefore, you can log many things, like for example the width of the window, you can access it either
by using window.innerWidth
and the value you see here depends on if you click on output here, the size of this container,
so how big you make this container
here. Now it's 510 as you can also see here,
as this increases and decreases,
this is only here on JSBin but that's just the setup here.
Generally, this will be your whole window width here, not just something like that,
so if you create your own index.html file and import a script and run window.innerWidth,
you'll get the full width here.
You can also use this without the window object
since again, we're on the global scope here anyways
and the global object is the window,
therefore you might just use innerWidth like this.
So clear this, execute it and you see this is the same
and I'm just going to uncheck Auto-run JS to stop all these errors while I'm typing.
You also have outerWidth,
let's try this,
what will happen if I run JS now? And I'll hit clear first, so what'll
we see if I hit run?
Well now here, we got as outerWidth the full size as innerWidth is.
Now again, this is just because we're on JSBin here
but generally, the difference is in outerWidth is only what you see on your webpage, including the scrolling
side bar and outerWidth is all of that plus any borders your browser might have
and this is why in this case here in JSBin, we have this huge difference because innerWidth is
simply this tiny output
container here and outerWidth is the complete page. Normally
the difference is not that big but the difference are possible borders you might have
and so on.
You of course not only have width, you we also have innerHeight and outerHeight
and if I execute this, you also got the difference, including the borders and so on when using the outerHeight
or just the field itself
if using the or just the webpage itself using the innerHeight. Now what else could you use on the
window?
Well try it out, simply and I'll get rid of output for now,
hit run now and log the complete window,
so here you go.
These are all the available properties and methods and so on
you can use on the window object.
So quite a lot
and no worries, a lot of that won't be needed and this includes for example the complete DOM because
that is a property of the window object as well.
So the window object is a really complex object, giving you access to a lot of high level features here
and
for example as mentioned before, the setTimeout and setInterval are also methods available
on the window object here.
Another important or useful property you may access is the local storage which is a built-in storage
which will save certain values in your browser as long as the application is running here,
for example you can store something by using the setItem method on the storage, give this a name because
your save key-value pairs here. So
you have a key here, key1 for example
and then the value, let's say 1000
and I'm not logging this but I will log the following where I get the value, so I will log
localStorage.getItem and then the name of the key, key1 for example.
So what do you think we'll now see if I hit run? Well we get 1000,
this is how we can store some data to keep it in our running application and use it from different points
in our application because in whichever script file we call local storage,
we only have one local storage and this is why this is a great way to store values you want to use throughout
our application at different points of time.
We don't only have local storage,
we also have session storage and as you can see if I hit run, this works in the same way and the difference is
that local storage should persist whereas session storage will be deleted or emptied when the
user closes a tab or the browser. The window object also has, as mentioned before, this location property
and
if I hit run, you get the location, I'll comeback to that in separate lectures
but here, you have access to the location you're currently at
and of course very important too, it has access to the document, the DOM
and this will have its own lectures as well of course. Another very important thing or cool feature
is
you can run window.open and then just enter some address, let's say google.com and let's see
what happens if I hit run.
Well, a pop-up was blocked,
so this tries to open a pop-up with this new address which of course nowadays won't work too often but
you've got this possibility and you will see other methods of navigating in the location lecture.
So that's the window object
and as we saw, there are a lot more available properties and so on
but the goal is not really to go through them all,
the goal is to show you how you can work with it and what kind of properties and methods it stores and
you learned about the most important ones already.
If you want to learn more, definitely check out the cheatsheet as always and there, you'll find a link
to a full article on the window object which will allow you to dive deeper into that and find out if
it has that specific method you are looking for.
Also keep in mind, the global scope in which we are working here refers to the window object, so the global
object is the window object and therefore, you don't need to specify window dot anything, you
can directly use the dot anything without the dot because again, we're on that object already by default
.
So that's the window object.