So how do Javascript events work?
We have the general event interface and I'm on the page of this built-in object on the Mozilla
Developer Network which is generally a great resource for all kinds of Javascript related questions
.
So this is a general event
Javascript offers and then you have multiple specific events which kind of implement this top level
event and therefore all events in Javascript share certain properties and methods which you find
listed on these pages here and there are especially some specific properties and methods which
are important and to which I'll come back later.
So this is the event interface or the general event object and as I said, you have then specific events to
which you can listen. How can you listen or handle an event?