Now a common thing to use such loops for is to use them in conjunction with arrays. Remember, an array,
I'll just
create a variable here
looks like this with brackets and contains multiple values.
Now, since we have multiple values in one place, I think it's one of the first things you think about
that you could loop through this and use these values step-by-step or value for value.
You could do that by setting i back to zero and going back to incrementing, I'll also change this to being
smaller then something but the something,
well it could now be hardcoded 3 and I could then log array and access the index with
the variable i
which of course gets increased upon each round.
So now if I hit run, what will we see?
Well we see 1, 2, 3 because I now step-by-step access the value in the array
but that's not really the best way because I hardcoded the size of the array here.
If I change this to 5 because I expect the array to have five elements but it actually only has three, what
would I now get?
Well I get
undefined undefined because I'm accessing values which aren't there.
So that's not really good because rarely can I know how big an array is and even if I could know it because
I hardcoded it, I might change this later on
and then I would have to change the size of all places in my code where I hardcoded it. So a better way
is to use my array and access the length property on that array
because remember, an array is an object and it happens to have this length property built-in
and as this name implies, this gives me the length of the array.
So now I'm looping as long as i is smaller than the length of the array.
What do you think will happen if I now hit run? We get 1, 2, 3 again
because the length is of course three.
Notice that it is important to understand that since the first index of the array is zero, we have
to use the smaller sign then and not smaller or equal because in this case, we would loop until i takes
the value of three which actually tries to access the fourth element
and that is not the behavior we would like to have.
So this is how we would write it to loop through such an array.