Now let's have a look at subtraction
and of course, first the very basics, for subtraction,
we also got this syntax where we have a quick way of subtracting b from a,
so if I now print a,
what do you think we'll get? Well we'll get 11
because this is just a short way to write a equals a - b
and as you already saw before as well, we also get this -- syntax here to subtract one.
So that's all great but it's definitely interesting to see what happens if we subtract a minus b
and now we have two strings,
so for example split us and hear us,
what do you think? Do you think we'll get just split?
We get NaN.
Subtraction doesn't work like addition, Javascript can't figure out that much as it is able to do
with addition.
Addition is simple with strings, it just concatenates them. Here,
it would have to search for us in the first string and it's not doing that, therefore we simply get
not a number,
it's not able to do subtraction with strings.
What do you think we get
if I have 12 and then b being 1 but as a string?
Remember when you were adding this, we got a result of a string being 121 but a string again.
So what do you think we'll get now?
Well now we get 11.
So when subtracting, as I already said, Javascript is not able to construct new strings out of that,
therefore it falls back to the other way of subtraction it knows, using numbers and it tries
if it is able to cast this string into a number which is of course possible with 1 and therefore, it's
actually doing this calculation, even though the second argument, b, isn't a number.
Of course we can still also use true and null and NaN and undefined
but here, the behavior doesn't change compared to the addition case where we would get back NaN
if using undefined or NaN or where we would be able to use True or False as one
or zero or use null as zero,
so that all doesn't change. The important parts were the ones I just showed here when using strings with
numbers.