So in this app.js, I'll use strict mode since that certainly makes sense
and then I want to hook this button up to an event listener.
Now the thing is I could do this in this file but this file will get very long because I need to fetch
this button from the DOM, so get a reference to it. I'll also need to get references to the weather item
here which I later want to update and so on.
So I think it makes sense to have another script file where I initialize certain things, some kind
of init.js file and this file should basically load some elements from the code or get me all
the elements I need to work with throughout the application.
So here, I'll also use strict mode and then I'll create a variable search button for example
and I want to get this show weather button here.
Now how can I get it?
If we have a look at the index.html file, this is the button I want to get
and as you can see, it doesn't have any class or ID
but in this application, it's the only button on the whole page.
So therefore I can simply use my query selector on my document here, query selector and
select by tag,
so by button tag and this should give me my search button. Next, I want to get the city the user entered
.
If we have a look at the index.html,
we do have an ID on this input field,
we could also select by input field since it's the only one
but since an ID is given,
why not just simply retrieve it like this,
var searchCity equals document.querySelector and then #city to select by the ID, city here
.
Now with that, that's all I want to select for now but I'll add code to this file later.
Now currently if we have a look at the index.html, we're not using that file, right,
we're only importing app.js.
Well we need init.js too and we need to import it before app.js of course because in app.js,
I want to use all those things I initialize in init.js. So I'll add a script tag here too and I'll import
init.js here.
With that, I can go back to my app.js file and here, I can access the search button which
I initialize in the other Javascript file, so it will be available here
and add the event listener. I'll add a click event listener and I want to trigger a method or a function
called search weather.
Now we're getting a warning here that search button is not defined but we know that it will be available
since we set this up in init.js.
So here, I'll next create this function, searchWeather and I'm creating it after assigning this click listener
because if you remember this, it will be pulled up to the top of the file by Javascript.
So in search weather,
all I want to do now is I want to output this search city, so what the user entered into this input
field.
So I'll output search city and then the value property on this input element allows me to get the value
the user inserted,
so value is a property available on the input HTML element.
Now with that to actually see something, I'll open up my Chrome dev tools and clear my console here
and now I enter test and click on show weather and we see test.
So this all works, I'm able to fetch this button to hook up an event listener and also to successfully
output what the user entered here.
That's great and with that, we got the very basics, we're able to retrieve the city name the user enters.
Of course the next step is to somehow send the city name to a service which actually gives us the weather
and then use that weather we get back in whichever form we will get back to actually output it here
.
Let's do this step-by-step in the next lectures.