Now sometimes, you don't want a library like jQuery but you want to build a real single page application
which means everything is handled through Javascript,
the whole user experience is handled by Javascript.
This is very modern nowadays and there are quite some frameworks doing this for you,
one popular and brand new one is Angular 2 for example.
Now the difference to jQuery is that this doesn't simply offer some helper methods and functions
but it creates a complete environment in which you can work, you're writing your whole application
with this framework
and yes you still use normal Javascript, though with Angular 2 you use Typescript which is kind of a
superset to it but you may just also use Javascript but you're working in that environment the framework
gives you with all the commands and tools the framework gives you,
so it's a much more powerful thing than a library like jQuery which only adds certain parts. This framework
like Angular 2 or ReactJS,
frameworks like these give you a lot of power and you have to learn them of course, it's not just
like throwing them into your project and you're good to go but it's very modern nowadays to use such
frameworks,
so definitely consider checking out courses on for example Angular 2,
I do have a course on that if you're interested
for example, to learn more.