Recovered closures and if he's not want to close this module with some very important things about functions
or some nice Meffert and properties we can use with functions for this I will again just create a little
dummy function here which I would call a message and this will take a message as an input let's say
and and simply again
log it to Tikhon's.
Now of course if I hit run we won't see anything but if I pass dummy message into there and now it run
we see high of course so that shouldn't be too surprising.
However inside a function we also will have access to a certain variable if you want to call it like
this I can print out arguments not arguments.
Isn't the variable I created I didn't create it anywhere.
And what do you think I'll see if I now run
I get an object which basically like an array has key value pairs with just an index which is incrementing
and then be passed in argument so high here of course because I passed one argument.
Now what happens if I pass another argument even though this message here of course only takes one argument
as function only expects a message nothing else.
What do you think on that.
See if I hit run now I get both arguments because in javascript as explained earlier in this course
I'm not getting an error if I pass more arguments then expect that I'm caught.
I'm of course not using them here but I could use them.
And with the arguments very well here at the reval could use it because I could check if you have the
extra argument or I could in generally check how many arguments I got and then I could simply access
them like this for example to access the first argument and I would print 10.
So this gives me a way to at runtime during runtime determine how many arguments I have which arguments
these are and use them.
Now if I use this with two and try to access an argument I haven't passed into this function.
What do I think I'll get now and run.
Well I get undefined because I'm trying to access an argument which isn't there.
So this argument's variable here kind of has like an array even though it technically is an object here
where I can access my different arguments and use them.
And this again gives me a way to dynamically expand the functionality of my function and well consider
the number of arguments I got and even use them.
Of course I can also check how many arguments I got by accessing the length property.
So now I get to because I pull past two arguments here.
So let's see arguments property here are already arguments.
Variable if you want to call it like that.
What our useful helpers or things can you use with functions.
Well for example I can't get rid of this function call and instead I could print message Darnay.
What do you think we'll now see if I hit run message because this is the name of the function so I can
access the name of a function.
Now you might say Well that is a bit stupid right.
I have the name here where would I access that here.
Again you might have some kind of functions you are creating dynamically during runtime or anything
like that.
And then while this could be very useful to use it of course will also be useful if you have this case
.
So you create a new variable which you seiners message function.
And now what happens if I run this.
What do I see in the console still message.
So now I'm not referring to the name on the left of this name call or just name property but the real
function which is bound to this variable.
So this is why a name could be useful due to find out which function actually will get executed and
this might allow you to write more dynamic code for example.
I also have access to length.
Now what do you think we'll now see if I hit run
one.
And length refers to the number of arguments this function expects it expects.
Not the are a number of arguments it gets because well it does no what with how many arguments you will
call this function eventually but it doesn't know how many arguments it expects.
And if I add numbers here well what will we see now.
To of course because we are now expecting two arguments so this could also be very useful to again in
a dynamic context where you for example loop through an array of functions and for each function you
want to find out how many arguments you have to pass.
This is a great way to do it or to find out how many arguments this function expects.
Now here's something else.
Consider.
I'm well I'm taking this function here and I'm setting it equal to message very well that get rid of
the name here.
So this is the other way we can create functions if you remember this.
Now avoid printed name.
What do you think was now see.
Actually nothing because the name is looking for something here.
So by setting up a function like this we're basically binding an anonymous function.
This part here to a variable and an anonymous function doesn't have a name as well.
The name Anonymous implies therefore we're not able to print the name because the name is not the variable
name but the name of the function which isn't there so that's important to keep in mind that there is
a tiny difference between both ways of setting up a function.
If I had turned us back
and I print out this dot name inside the function at the end I simply execute message.
What do you think we'll will now see.
Well not a function name here I'm just referring to the name of this app here so to the global object
the window object name.
So this name does not work.
You can access the name outside of this function not inside though so that verst some tiny but yet important
additions about functions in Chava script and which built in helper's are properties you can use to
well enhance your functions or to write more dynamic code.
It's very important to be aware of all the tools Schulthess could offer you here.
Therefore this was a very important module to get you on the next level regarding function usage so
that you're now able to use closures to know what they are and what the advantages are that you are
able to use.
If he doesn't know what they are and what the advantages are and that you're able to use all the built
in helper is provided by java script