This course follows a special approach.
I believe that you learn the most
if I'm able to focus on one part of language at a time.
Now oftentimes, you see courses where you learn certain features but you want to implement them in a webpage
and therefore you need to write some other code which is not really connected to the topic you want
to focus on right now,
I think that's a problem because it deters you from really deeply diving into the topic at hand.
Therefore the format I chose for this course is the following;
we'll be using a webpage named jsbin.com.
So if you navigate over there in your browser, you'll see that it should look something like this
.
Now it might look a bit different if you open up for the first time, you might close this blue thing
you've got at the top when opening it for the first time and then make sure to only check Javascript
and console here so that only these two items are highlighted.
Now from time to time, I'll also use some HTML code and possibly the output
but what this page allows you to do basically is to write a simple Javascript HTML program and see it
run immediately,
therefore we don't have any problems with setting up our workspace or having to write redundant code
which isn't really the topic at hand.
That being said of course, I have a separate module about setting up a workflow and setting up a real
project because in, the end of course you won't be writing applications in this tool but it's great for
learning and that's why I'm using it. For the majority of the course, we won't even see the HTML
code,
we'll use Javascript and see what happens in the Javascript console which is a convenient way to output
values.
Now you might argue my programs won't output it to the console,
I need knowledge how to work with HTML code and you would be right
but that is why I have a complete module or two actually about interacting with the HTML document
but it's very important to understand all the other parts of the language first
and for that you won't need HTML
since it's only one part of the language and it's only about actually displaying it in the HTML
code but not the logic you write, the logic you write depends on functions objects and data types and
that can be perfectly output in the console like this.
So for example you will see me type something like assigning a variable and of course, I'll
come back to variables very soon
and then logging that variable to the console log
and if you then hit command enter here or click this run button, you'll see that it gets executed and
gets printed to the console on the right which is a very convenient way to see what actually happened
and what the result of a certain calculation might be.