Back to the object creation, here's another way to create a new object.
I'll get rid of person1 here and I'll get rid of the check
and also of this but I will still create another person but I can use the built-in object but now not
with the new keyword but instead the static method create.
This allows me to create a new object,
however I do have to pass something here and I will pass
null for now, I'll come back to it though.
I can still say anotherPerson.name equals Anna and I won't set the age
but of course I could do this too
and if I log out another person here, let's see what happens,
we got an object with the name, so object create.
Why do we have this, we already had another method we're not using so why would we need object create?
This
method actually makes sense to have, it's longer than the literal notation but it does have an advantage,
you'll
be able to grasp more once we reach the lectures on prototypes.
To talk a little bit about this right now without going into depth because I'll do that later,
prototypes are kind of Javascript's form of inheritance,
so basically prototypes allow you to have a prototype of an object and then creates create objects of
that prototype
and if that prototype has a certain function, all the objects based on that prototype would have that
function too.
So that is what a prototype is and each object you create,
also that object here for example has a prototype,
the default object prototype is Object.prototype.
That's a built-in object on its own which is the root prototype of all objects here.
So that's just a side information and I will come back to prototypes later.
With object create, you see me pass an argument which is null and this argument specifies which prototype
we want to set for the object we create.
As I just explained, the default is Object.prototype,
this object would have the prototype. This object will not because I am passing null and now the interesting
thing is I cannot only pass
null, I can pass any other object which I want to be the prototype for this object.
So if I pass person here, I can now try to log anotherPerson.age
and would you think that this works now? Let's see it. It works, we get 27 even though another person doesn't
have an age property but its prototype, person which we set here, does have it
and again if you're not 100% sure what this is all about, I'll get back to prototype soon
but object create is a useful way of creating new objects where you can control what the prototype
should be.
We'll also learn about yet another method of creating objects later where you can also control what
the prototype is
but this here is a very useful method if you need to set the prototype on your own.
If you don't need that, if you don't care, if you just need an object like that to work with, then the literal
notation is still absolutely fine.
So that have been very basics about object,
it's time to dive deeper into one key topic when we're talking about Javascript objects,
prototypes.