Before learning those more convenient ways, it's however important to understand how you can navigate between
elements in the DOM
and as I said for example you can chain children calls like this.
So if I log this again, console log
and I'm accessing the first child of this block here,
so body
and then the first child and then the first child of that accessed element, well the first child of
this body part is of course the unordered list and then the first child of the unordered list is this
list item.
So if I now print this to the console, you'll see indeed that what we now selected is a list item which
as a content has a link
by the way because it has this content of a link. You may not only access all your elements with
this array and then the index, if you for example want the first child,
you can use first child like this.
Now if I get rid of children, what do you think we'll see if I hit run?
Well you probably expected to get the unordered list here,
however instead we get something else and I'll tell you what we
got, we get the whitespace before the unordered list because this is the first child.
Now you might say, that's stupid,
I'm not interested in that, I want to get the first element here no matter if there is a whitespace
in front of it or not and you can select it with the first element child property here.
If I now hit run, you get the unordered list here as you can see,
so now you're selecting this. Of course you also have the last element child.
Now if I clear this, what do you expect we'll now get?
Well here, we get a script element which we can't see here but again, that's something JSBin entered
for us but of course normally, you would also get the unordered lists because it's the first and last child, there
are no other direct child to body, only the nested ones in unordered list
but when we're talking about the body here, we only got the unordered list here. We also can for
example select the first element child,
then the first element child to get the first list item and then the next element sibling.
What do you think we'll now get? We get a list item and to see which one we get,
I'll change text so that they don't all have the same text inside the links.
So if I run this again, you see we get Link2.
So we get the second list item here which makes sense since we're selecting the first element child
of our body, which is the unordered list,
then the first element child inside this unordered list which is this list item and then the next element
sibling of this which is of course this one, this is the next element sibling of this list item.
And this is how you can traverse inside the DOM, how you can move between different objects with
these
first element child next to element sibling and so on methods.
If I select the first element child and again, the first element child,
so if I select this item but now I'm not using the next element sibling but instead, the parent element,
if I now hit run, well I get the unordered list again because I'm selecting the first element child which
is on unordered list, then the first element child which is the list item and then the parent element again
and the parent element of this list item of course is the unordered list.
So I took a step into this and then one back out and again, this is how you can traverse here and with
this traversal, you should be able to select whichever element you need to select because you want
to change something.