Now as mentioned before, this way of doing it is a bit difficult or you have these very long statements
and you have to kind of go to your HTML code and count how many levels
you have to go deep into to get the correct element, so that's not really the most convenient
way of accessing your elements.
There are better ways.
Now I'll show you the mediocre way first, the way you did it a few years ago before going to the
most optimal one.
So a quicker way than this way here is to use some methods the document offers you, for example the get
elements by tag name method which allows you as a string to specify the tag name you want to get.
So if I now clear this and hit run,
what do you think I'll get?
Well again I get the very complex object but in the end, this will be an array of all the list items
here
and by the way, if you're not liking this way of displaying it in here, you may also open up your developer
tools and here you also get the same console logs
but here you've got the more structured like this
and here you can click into and see what got selected.
So if I clear this and run it again, you see we get an array of list items
by this
method here. We not only got elements by tag name, we also for example have elements by class name.
Now we're not using any classes but let's add some, so I'll add a class here, a CSS class
and I'll name it simple.
Now here, I can specify simple as the class name by which I want to get elements
and if I run this, you see I also get an array which in this case only contains one element with this list item
of class simple and then again, I can access all the properties of this element and so on, the style which
is its own object and so on
and maybe you want to work with this console here which is a bit more clear to see and it's easy to
see which properties your elements have and maybe set or used.
So you got these methods and you also can find elements by ID, by get elements with the get element, not
elements but just element, by ID
and the reason that it's not plural form is that ID should be unique right,
so you shouldn't get an array of elements, you should get only one,
therefore it's get element by ID.
You also have to get element by name, which is if you assign names to your elements and so on.
So these are nice little selectors to let you get the right element very quickly without having to write
these nested statements or chaining multiple property calls to get to the right document, instead here
you can easily find that
and this also has the advantage that if you change something in your HTML code and you add
one extra level to it, you'll still find it instantly if you search by class name
but if you were chaining your children; first child, first child, first child calls and then you add one
extra layer,
well then suddenly all of the statement is broken and you have to add one extra first child or
whatever is appropriate.