So with all the prototyping going on, let's go back to object create and I'll create a new object, I'll
name it Max and I'll create it with object create and I'll pass person as the prototype
I want to set for Max, I'll then log Max name.
Now what do you expect to happen if I hit run? We see Max, even though I didn't set the name on this Max
object,
it has person as a prototype and this prototype has this name field.
Now, another interesting question,
what happens if I call Max.greet, what will show up in the console?
Hello there.
Now that might be confusing,
we set the prototype to person and person doesn't have greet,
why does this still work?
Because of the prototype chain I was just showing. Javascript will work its way up,
it doesn't find greet on Max, so it looks in person. It doesn't find it here too,
so it looks in the prototype of person and the prototype of person is of course Object.prototype
and here it does find the greet method
and that shows the advantage of prototypes.
I can copy this and create another object,
Anna.
Now Anna should probably have her own name, so I'll set this to Anna
and if I now copy this here for Anna, what do you think we'll see in the console?
Hello there two times,
so Anna does have this greet function as well and that's the advantage of prototypes.
We can create multiple objects of a certain blueprint kind of, of a certain prototype and they all
have access to the methods of this prototype.
I could go in this a bit further.
Let's say I want to greet with my name and say Hello there, I am,
I skip out of the string here and then I access this.name.
Here is this this keyword again with which I was able to access properties of the object.
Now the prototype object probably doesn't have a name field,
so what do you think we'll see if I hit run? Max and Anna.
So this refers to the object on which we're calling this greet method, not to the prototype here
and that is an important behavior of this. It refers to the object on which you're calling this function
here,
this greet function and I'm calling it on Max and Anna and Max has a name and Anna has a name and therefore,
this name refers to the respective names and doesn't search for a name property in the prototype of
Anna or Max,
so not in the Object.prototype.
What will print
if I remove Anna's name here? I get Max because now Anna doesn't have her own name anymore
and again with the prototype chain, we start at the bottom with this,
we start at the Anna object, we don't find the name here,
so we go up one level to the prototype of Anna which is Max or person, excuse me, which is person and
here the name is Max, so therefore we're seeing Max two times here.
I know I'm really dive in deep into that but it's so important to understand how prototypes work and that
they're really easy to be honest,
you often read a lot of articles that make it look like prototypes are the most difficult thing in Javascript
but in the end, it's all about blueprints from which you can build different objects and which have the
advantage of providing you with functions or with properties you would not have access to in your object
here on its own
since it doesn't have a name here for example.
That's what prototypes are about in its core and that's key to understand at this point here.