So I was showing this mediocre way as I call it,
well there is a best way of course as well.
Javascript also has query selectors,
so now if I change this and I use a query selector instead, I still use the document object here
but then I use query selector and the query selector allows me to select by ID, by class name, by tag
name but all in one single method.
How does it work?
It uses CSS selectors for that.
Now if you're not familiar with CSS, CSS selectors basically are how you define, if writing style
sheets, which elements should receive a certain style and you could write a code that all h1 elements
are styled or only elements that have a certain class and the way these CSS selectors look like
are basically that
if you have something like h1 without anything else, just a string of h1 here, this would select
all h1 elements.
So let's add one here, let's add a h1 element which says header. If I now clear my console,
so
if I now execute this code by showing the console just enough that I can click run, like this,
you see we select a header with that query selector.
Now you can also select by class by adding a dot in front of it and then a class name, like simple
and
this is how you write it in CSS code as well.
So if I now hit run, we select this
li element. Notice that we don't get an array here and that is because I'm using query selector and this
will only give me the first element which matches this query. If we want to get the array,
so all the elements matching this query, you would have to use query selector all.
If I now hit run, you'll see that now it's an array of list items,
it only has one object but it could hold multiple ones.
So if I add this class to let's say another element and this is your anchor tag, no list item
and I hit run again,
you'll see both elements here.
But again, if only using query selector without the all, we only get the first one, the list item and
the second one is omitted,
so use whatever you need.
Now this is the class selector,
you may also use the hashtag selector to select by ID.
So if I now add an ID, for example to the header, ID equals easy, then I can select by ID easy here,
click run again and you see I get this header.
So this query selector is the fastest possible way to select elements by certain characteristics, be that
their tag name, their ID, their class name, you can also select by attribute or something else
and again to learn more about that,
check out how CSS selectors work or check out the document attached, the cheatsheet attached to this
module where you will find a link to the query selector and you're able to learn more
but generally that is how it works
and that is how you select elements with it.
Now of course with the elements selected, you may still use style, background color and set it equal to
red for example and I'll
get out of my console log, hit run and in order to see it I'll show the output as well, close
this so that it's a bit more easy to see and again, hit run, it's getting red here.
So this still works,
that is what the selector is there for, to work with it but it makes it easier,
you don't have these chained calls
instead it's very simple
and of course as I said, you can use multiple ways to select your elements here.