So we saw how to get elements, how to change them
but sometimes we also want to create or destroy elements, so let's have a look at this.
I create a new element by creating a new variable here
and let's say we want to create a paragraph, so I'll just name it p here.
Then I can use document.createElement and then as an argument, the tag name p, capital p here
since we're creating a paragraph. With that, we already created the element, it's not being added to the DOM
right now but it's there, it's an HTML element,
therefore I can also access the text content and set it to a new paragraph.
I can also style it, so I could set the font size to let's say 6 or 17 pixels here since I mistyped
.
So we have the element and we can prove that it's there by logging it to the console.
So if I close my output for a second and open the console instead and if I hit run,
you see this is the paragraph element here, new paragraph, tag name p
so it's there,
however let's add it to the output.
We have to decide where we want to add it and let's say to make this a bit more difficult,
we want to add it after this link here.
Well as a first step, let's select the element where we want to insert it after, so this link.
I'll save this in a new variable and then I'll just use a query selector here to get this link here
.
It's the first anchor tag, therefore I can use query selector and choose a as a tag name to select
this one.
I then want to insert this newly created paragraph after this link
and I can use this anchor tag
I just selected which already sits in a DOM and
then the append child method and I want to append this paragraph.
So let's see what happens if I now hit run, well a new paragraph gets added but it looks like it's
part of this link
so let's have a look at these in the Chrome dev tools. Here under elements,
if we increase this a bit, you see it's part of the anchor tag and not really appended after it
and
that is because the append child will add it to the current element,
so inside of it,
so it appended it after the text, inside of this anchor tag.
However we wanted it to add it
after this link, not inside of it.
Now since append child simply takes the element and adds it inside of the element but at the end of
all the child elements,
we can simply select the list items of the anchor
and if we now hit run, a new paragraph is actually inserted after the link.
So it's important to understand, append child with append it and it's not that difficult to understand
if you look at the name as a child but at the end of all the other children. What if we wanted to append
this paragraph in the list item
but before the link? To do this, we have the insertBefore method here.
Now with insertBefore however, if I run it, that doesn't really work because we're not really specifying
before which item we want to insert it, right? We're just telling
OK in the list item, insert the paragraph before, before what? So we also need to get the element before we want
to insert it,
so the anchor. Now I could use a query selector to get the first anchor or since
I know it is the first child of my list item,
I can just use first element child here and then just insert it before this anchor tag which I selected
here.
So if I now run this, you see the paragraph gets actually added before the link.
So this is how you can add your elements in different places in your document with the append child
and insertBefore method and by selecting the elements where you want to select it to define the position
where it should get entered.
And of course create element is an important method to actually create a new element
and don't forget, once you executed this method, the element is there,
it's stored in this variable here and therefore you can access all the properties this object or
this element would have if it were already in the DOM as well
even though it hasn't been attached to the DOM yet and then use append child and insertBefore to
actually insert it.
So that has been how you insert an element, but how do you delete one?