Let's take a moment and look at the Pluralsight LIVE conference site to get
an idea of some of the concepts that we'll be coding up.
This was the agenda for the 2019 Pluralsight LIVE
conference held in Salt Lake City.
Towards the top, there is a general overview of the agenda with the schedule.
And as you scroll down, it takes us to the Breakout sessions.
These sessions are essentially what we'll be creating.
We'll have some data structures and endpoints around
sessions and speakers for a conference.
An example of a session would be LESSONS LEARNED
BUILDING A GLOBAL TECHNOLOGY ORGANIZATION.
Sessions obviously have speakers or presenters associated with it,
and in this case, you can see that there are two presenters,
Shawn Malhotra and Thomson Reuters.
If you expand the session title, you can also see a summary of the session.
The topic in the description will be also something
that we'll include in our application.
There are a lot of other things like session tags and the session
schedules which we won't be building simply due to time,
but that will give you something to work on on your own.
The more practice you have building and working with Spring Boot and Spring,
the better you'll get.
So now that we have a basic general idea of what we'll be building, let's go ahead and get started.