The good news with Spring Boot is that it provides a lot of ways
to override and customize your application.
In fact, there is more than a dozen ways to set a property value for your app.
The bad news is there is an order of precedence that Spring and
Spring Boot uses to properly set your values.
If you're not careful,
you can have a property set incorrectly if you aren't aware of this.
First off, there are two basic places that you can put your configuration.
You can use something external to the app like command-line parameters,
environment variables, or JNDI stores,
or you can use something internal to your application like servlet parameters,
property files, and Java configuration.
Keep in mind that your internal configuration tools
can also point to external sources.
Since there are a variety of ways that you can set up your configuration,
you should be aware of how Spring Boot handles reading and setting them.
Here is the basic order excluding test configuration setup.
The main rule of thumb is external property sources override
internal property sources with the exception of servlet config
and servlet context parameters.
Those take precedence over JNDI, system properties, and environment variables.
So here is my advice and a side note on how you should think about properties.
You should pick one internal source, like property files,
to set up your application defaults and then pick one
external source to provide overrides.
This keeps configuration in one of two places,
allows for sensible defaults,
and then gives you the ability to use external sources for sensitive data,
like credentials and passwords.
I'm going to follow my advice in this course and use OS
environment variables as the external source and application
property files for the internal source.
Coming up next,
we'll start working with the basic application property files as our main internal source for configuration.