Getting processes in place to be able to handle your app in
multiple environments is something most teams will end up doing
over the life of any serious project.
At some point, you might ask,
how can I work with an app in development locally then
deploy to a nightly test server, staging,
and finally, into production.
Spring Boot uses a combination of Spring profiles and
profile-specific application property files to accomplish this.
Simply add any profile suffix to the application part of the file name,
and Spring Boot will use those properties instead of the
default application.properties file.
To specify the profile,
you have to use a spring.profile .active -D parameter on
your app startup with the profile name to activate
whatever profile you want to run.
In this case, the dev profile would be activated,
and Spring Boot will look for an application-
dev.properties file on the class path, which would be in src,
main, resources of our project.
Let's go ahead and set up a new profile configuration.
I'm back in IntelliJ,
and I'm going to go ahead and create a production-specific property file.
So under src, main, resources, I'm going to create a new file.
Since this is for prod, I'll call it application- prod.properties.
For production,
we probably want to trim down the logging to just errors or warnings.
We can add some properties to the file that will do just that.
You can adjust the logging level on your application to
anything in the org package to just print out WARN or error
messages by using a property like this.
I'm going to make sure my application-prod properties file is saved.
And really quickly, if I open the Run section,
you'll notice we have a lot of log statements when the
server starts out that are INFO, or WARN,
or other scopes in the log file.
The logging level that we just set says we only want to
see WARN particular log statements,
and so we want to remove this INFO for production.
So we can test that our by setting the profile on the run configuration,
so we'll go ahead and reopen the Run,
Edit Configurations section of IntelliJ again.
This time, we want to utilize the VM options,
so I'm going to select in here, and I'm going to add the following -D parameter,
spring.profiles .active, and it equals prod.
And note,
prod has to match the suffix that we've given our property application file.
Go ahead and apply that and close this.
Then we can go back to the Run tab and rerun the server and see if our log
files are reduced because now we're in production mode.
Okay, so the application has started, but you might be asking,
why am I still seeing INFO messages?
I should only be seeing WARN messages.
Well if you remember,
we only set WARN messages on any code that begins in the org package,
so these codes over here begin in com.
It's not going to take effect.
But overall,
you'll notice that the log output is substantially
smaller using the prod profile.
Since we're still in development mode with this application,
we'll go ahead and remove that from the run configuration,
just in case we do run into errors later,
we can see them. Coming up next, we have even more configuration options with Spring Boot.