Spring Boot has been a game changer for the Java platform.
Before Spring Boot came around,
it wasn't uncommon for a developer to spend a few days
wiring an MVC framework to a persistence framework and
getting that talking to a database.
Did you catch that?
Days to get the app propped up before any real coding can take place.
Spring Boot takes an opinionated view on how a Spring app should be constructed.
By doing so,
you can now stand up a fully-wired application from controller
to database in just a matter of seconds.
Spring Boot prefers Spring frameworks, like Spring MVC and Spring Data,
which is one way it makes it opinionated,
but this also serves another purpose.
Spring Boot makes building applications very quick,
quick like Ruby on Rails, and Django, and Python quick.
Finally,
Spring Boot got away from container dependence and really
wants applications to be standalone Java apps.
This makes a lot of sense for cloud deployments.
Instead of deploying a WAR file to a Tomcat container,
for example,
Spring Boot embeds Tomcat inside of the app and produces a self-contained JAR
file that can be run on its own using the Java command.
As fun as it might be to talk about how awesome Spring Boot is,
I know that you're really here to code and get your hands dirty with Spring Boot, so let's go ahead and get started.