If you weren't aware, I18N stands for internationalization.
It literally means there's 18 characters before the beginning I
and the trailing N of the word internationalization. To this
point in our course, we haven't been internationalizing our pages
to accept other languages.
Everything has just been hardcoded. This same code
internationalized that we have here,
where we've got firstName and lastName and the Save Changes text
just hardcoded in English would look like this.
Notice that we have removed any of those references to just plain English
language in here and are now grabbing them from a resource bundle.
FirstName, lastName, and the Save Changes text are all pulled from that bundle.
Even notice that the case with the Submit button is changing the value of that
actual button and not just the label on the page. To do this,
though, we need to introduce a new concept,
and that is interceptors.
Interceptors are used to allow us to intercept calls to our
server and perform special tasks on a call.
Common uses for interceptors are logging.
We can change the log level on an application without having to redeploy it. Not
useful to end users but very useful for debugging a specific problem in an
environment without having to restart the application.
Another common use is security.
When we want to intercept each call or direct them to a page,
make them log in and then redirect them back to that page that they were
trying to access, it's a very common use of an interceptor.
Security is outside the scope of this course,
but there is a separate course that is focusing on the use of Spring Security
in your applications here on Pluralsight. As we mentioned earlier, I18N
internationalization of sites and catching their request to change locales is
a very common use of interceptors. And, lastly,
performance monitoring. Similar to logging, this is not
something we're going to display to the end users,
but we may want to intercept each call to perform
some metric gathering on a request. Let's add internationalization support to our application now.