You'll often hear people talk about applications in
terms of a tiered architecture, or an n‑tier architecture,
or layers.
We try to build our applications in tiers more now in enterprise languages,
and there are great reasons to do so.
A few of these are separation of concerns.
This just means that each layer is only concerned
with the task that it's assigned to.
So our presentation layer is only going to have presentation type things in it,
and our business logic is going to be contained in a layer,
and data access is going to also be contained in its own separate layer.
Now there's another term called reusable layers,
and that sounds very similar to separation of concerns,
and in some ways it is, but its focus is different.
If I have business logic in my presentation tier,
I can't easily change my presentation tier or expose a web service,
for example, without recreating some of that logic.
If I have extracted it into its appropriate tier,
then I'm not duplicating that logic.
So if you ever notice yourself copying and pasting code in your application,
it's probably not in the correct tier or it's not
architected in the correct tier or way.
Now, that's a little bit of a difference between the
separation of concerns and the reusable layer.
Separation of concerns is not about reuse.
It's just about having things in the right layer,
so I can re‑architect them later.
Where reusable layers means that I have a purpose and
a point that I'm trying to drive.
I can expose the same data in multiple ways without having to worry about it,
or I can replace my presentation tier without having
to re‑architect my application.
Another term is maintenance, or refactoring,
that might be a better way to put it.
The ability to change things without having those
things ripple through all of our code.
So if I have Hibernate in my application,
and I have to change something in my UI based off the
change I made in Hibernate, no, I'm not talking about a business need,
but more of a I want to change how a table is structured or something like
that, I'm not separating those into the right tiers correctly.
If this is done correctly,
we can change our code and not have to retest everything,
but rather just the pieces that we changed.
This leads into a much larger discussion about unit testing,
but that's outside the focus of this course.
Talking about those layers of our Spring MVC application, and this is
important because of how we annotate our components,
which we're going to talk about here in just a second, we first have a data
model that we would be accessing using something like Hibernate,
or JPA, Spring JDBC.
This layer represents the data or model of our application.
Next we have a controller that interprets the user's requests and
selects the appropriate view based off of what we've requested or what
information we got back from our data model.
And then we have our view.
For our class, we're going to be using the JSPs,
and we'll also look at Thymeleaf, as well as exposing
some things through web services.
Now, one thing that's often misunderstood by people is that Spring
MVC has nothing to do with regards to our database,
but it has a model associated with it.
So is the model talking about our database or the model talking about what
our framework is going to represent to just our JSP page?
It's actually the latter.
It's referring to what we're going to represent in our JSP page,
or our Thymeleaf page, or our web service.
We always have to get that information from somewhere.
So that's where our various components come in and what we're going to talk about next.