In our first demo, we configured an InternalResourceViewResolver,
and didn't even realize it.
We've used that in all of our controllers since then.
We simply return a string,
and that is what's used by the ViewResolver to find the JSP page named
and in the location specified with our resolver.
We can also return a view object that wraps a string
that is the view name as well.
Our controller can build a model if necessary and return that to our
ViewResolver with data that is needed in the view.
We can also have multiple ViewResolvers,
as well as multiple view types in our application.
Let's look closer at that ViewResolver we've been using and
not really realizing that we had created it.
As we saw earlier in our controllers,
I'm going to open up our RegistrationController, we're just returning a
string of a name. On line 22 here we have return registration,
and that's referring to our registration JSP.
You may or may not recall that we configured two lines inside of our
application.properties, the spring.mvc.view.prefix and the
spring.mvc.view.suffix, and this tells it where those files are
located and what extension to look for.
So really it's taking that name that we have in our
RegistrationController and pre‑appending the prefix and
appending the suffix to that file to serve it back to our UI,
so that's how it knows where to find this.
Now how did it know how to do that?
Well, in our ConferenceApplication configuration,
we have this @SpringBootApplication, and we extend
that SpringBootServletInitializer, and this configures it for us.
But let's show you how to override that.
Let's create a new class, and to do so we're going to put it
alongside the ConferenceApplication. We're going to
right‑click and say New Java Class.
We're going to call this ConferenceConfig.
You can honestly name it anything you want,
it doesn't matter. And we're going to define a couple of things inside of here.
First of all, we're going to designate this as a Configuration class,
so we're going to annotate that with the @Configuration annotation. Then
inside of here we want to create a Bean. We're going to create @Bean, and
this Bean we're going to make a public ViewResolver, and this will just
return an instance of viewResolver. It can be named anything we want. Inside
of here, we're going to create an InternalResourceViewResolver, and this
bean is nothing more than what's already being defined for us in that
application.properties.
So I'm going to show you the same code side by side
here before we comment it out.
I want to say bean.setPrefix, and we want to add in here
WEB‑INF/jsp/, and then we want bean.setSuffix. We want to add
quotes inside of there and say .jsp as well.
Then we want to set the order, and this just tells it if we have
multiple ViewResolvers, which one we want to fire in which order, and
whichever one is first successful is what it will return. And then we
want to return the bean at the end.
Save this.
This is all of the configuration that's done for us
behind the scenes with that ConferenceApplication
annotation being SpringBootApplication.
So this main class that would launch our application if we had it
self‑contained, it still gets read off the class path,
and the SpringBootApplication has a component scanner in there that
tells it to go look for any other class labeled as a configuration, and
inside those configurations load up the beans.
Now, these two lines, line 14 and 15, are the exact same
lines inside of our application.properties.
So I can now comment out line 1 and line 2, and save that, and you'll
see that line 14 and 15 will take place of that.
I'm going to restart my server, and now we can test that our
ViewResolver is doing what it should be.
I'm going to click on that registration link, and it
did, it served those pages up for us.
So looking back at our editor again,
line 14 and 15, and really this whole method of 12 through 17, sets up
the ViewResolver that's already preconfigured for us.
And now we can override things and do various changes to this
that aren't really exposed through those properties like we
have in the application.properties.
We started using that to begin with, we can convert it over to this.
We are going to add other ViewResolvers inside that config as we do
more things to our code. So we'll leave this here, and it's a good base for what we want to move forward with.