The bean validator reference implementation is actually an instance of
hibernate‑validator. To configure it for spring, we just need to add it to
our class path and begin validating objects.
It doesn't matter if you are using Hibernate the ORM tool, the
validator is actually just the reference implementation and
has nothing to do with databases.
Let's add the hibernate‑validator dependency to our project. We want
to open up our POM file, and I'm going to put that below our Tomcat
starter, but above our starter test,
and I'm just going to add that code in there.
We want to have a group ID of org.hibernate.validator, an
artifact ID of hibernate‑validator, and a version of 6.1.1.Final.
When you first add this in here and save it,
it is going to take it a minute to download.
So if you get a red error for a minute,
realize it just has to resolve that dependency and
download it to your local repository.
Once you've saved that, though, just as we've done with other dependencies,
you should be able to look in your external libraries and look for
org‑hibernator, and specifically the hibernate‑validator,
and you can see that it's downloaded there.
We've got it in our window pane on the left,
and it's specifically version 6.1.1.Final. Let's go back and see how we start using this now.