Our previous example displayed static pages as a fully
self‑contained Spring Boot application, and that works very well,
and it works fine if you want to just go ahead and use RESTful services too.
But deploying JSP pages,
which a lot of you may be watching this course to migrate
and existing application or maintain an existing
application and have to use JSP pages, they actually still work great,
but Spring Boot self‑contained JARs don't do well with them.
In fact,
Spring will caution you in their documentation to not
deploy your application as a fully self‑contained JAR and
as a Spring Boot application.
So let's go ahead now and look at converting that to a packaged
WAR and deploying that on a Tomcat server.
To get an instance of Tomcat for us to use for our project,
I'm going to go ahead and open up a browser and navigate to tomcat.apache.org,
and then we can go down to the Download section on the left here.
And if you're not sure which version you want to use,
there is a link that you can navigate to and read
about all the different versions.
But for Java 11 and what we're doing, we want to use Tomcat 9.
So I'm going to click on that, and scroll down a little bit,
and click the Core zip version, and it will download for me.
And let's expand that ZIP file.
I like to do that in my DevTools directory, and here's my downloaded ZIP file.
As I mentioned,
I like to have all of my tools under a DevTools directory
where I've got multiple versions of Maven,
and Tomcat, and those types of things,
any of the things I'm messing around with on projects,
I like to put underneath here.
You can see I expanded our apache‑tomcat‑9.0.30 version here.
And we'll want to remember where this path is because we
have to configure this inside of IntelliJ.
We have to tell it the home path to this Apache Tomcat instance.
So remember where that path is.
Let's open up our IDE and get that all configured.
To begin with, we want to stop that server if yours is still running.
So our self‑contained server, I'm going to go ahead and click Stop on it.
Then I want to open up our settings and preferences,
so I want to go to File and Preferences.
I'm on a Mac, so mine's underneath the IntelliJ application name.
Yours may be under Windows Preferences if you're on a Windows machine.
I want to go to Build, Execution, Deployment,
Application Servers,
and you'll notice that we don't have anything configured here yet.
So I'm going to click the plus sign and say that I
want to choose a Tomcat server,
and this is where it's asking for that home
directory like we spoke about earlier.
So I want to navigate to that folder structure,
which mine was under DevTools, and I had Apache Tomcat 9.0,
and click Open.
So you see where I had mine into that Tools directory,
apache‑tomcat‑9.0.30, and it also put that as the base directory,
which is correct.
That's what we wanted that to have.
Those two should mirror each other.
There are cases where they don't, not in this course though.
For what we're doing, this is how we want it to look.
I'm going to choose OK, and it has all of that environment set up,
and select OK again.
Now, we need to change our project to be packaged as a WAR.
So if we open up our pom.xml file, right now,
there isn't a package type associated in here.
So there's a lot of stuff going on in this Maven POM filer.
There's the parent, there's the group, and artifact,
and version ID, and our name of our project,
our Java version, and then dependencies that were added inside of here,
but we don't see any packaging type inheritance,
and it's because it's defaulting to what the parents says that we are.
We want to go underneath version here,
and you see it on line 13 in my application,
and choose package, and the packaging type is a war now,
and we'll save this.
And you can see that Maven,
I've purposely left it turned off on mine to show you,
is asking if we want to import these changes,
and I want to choose Yes, and you can enable it to auto import it as well.
I want to have it import these changes,
and now it's changed the project type of the structure of what we had.
Before, it was packaged up as a self‑executable JAR,
and now it's a WAR, so it should be available to our Tomcat server to deploy.
We need to make one other change to our POM file.
I'm going to scroll down,
and I've already copied and pasted in the code because I didn't want
to have to have you watch me just type it all in.
I'm going to add a dependency, and I've just commented mine out here.
I'm going to uncomment it.
Below the org.springframework.boot, artifactId of spring‑boot‑starter‑web,
and above the spring‑boot‑starter‑test, you see on line 29 through 33,
I've got this spring‑boot‑starter‑tomcat plugin in here,
and this is to remove the dependencies on the internal packaged
application and convert this over to where we now have our own
standalone Tomcat‑enabled WAR,
and so we have a WAR that will work for Tomcat with all
of its dependencies all packaged up.
Let's save this, and now we can go edit our runtime configuration.
Click on Add Configurations up in your toolbar up here,
and you'll see we currently don't have a configuration for Tomcat.
We added the server, but we haven't created a configuration,
so let's click the plus sign, scroll down,
and select Tomcat Server and local.
If you don't see this,
you probably skipped the step earlier where we added
that server in when we downloaded it.
So let's choose Local and open this up.
To start with, I want to select the correct JRE.
So make sure if you have multiple JREs installed, you choose the right one.
This is the one that I want.
For deployments, choose the Deployments tab and click the plus sign,
choose artifact, and choose the conference:war.
Click OK.
I want to change the Application context to just /conference,
and let's switch back over to our server,
make sure everything looks good here, and it is.
The URL is localhost:8080/conference,
though it should be the same from our deployment in our server,
and click OK.
There's one other small change we need to make.
I'm going to exit full screen mode here.
Static resources aren't served from src,
main, resources, static in standard web applications.
They're usually out of a src, main, web app directory.
So if I right‑click and say New, Directory,
and choose webapp, now, notice, I started that off of src,
main, so src, main, and enter in the new directory web app,
and hit Enter, I now have a directory to start
hosting up static resources out of.
And to begin with,
I'm just going to copy and paste that index.html that we had under resources,
static and paste that into of the webapp directory.
Click OK.
Now we have everything ready and configured to run our application.
If your configuration says Tomcat 9.0.30,
like mine does or whatever version you downloaded,
go ahead and click the plus sign next to it,
and it should start up your server for you.
And you'll see the build status in the lower‑right‑hand corner,
and then your server pop up.
And once its loads,
it's automatically configured to bring up your
application and launch that Index page.
So it did it faster than I could even walk you through it,
and you'll notice our application pulled up,
and it's now localhost:8080/conference.
Before, we were just at root.
Tomcat, by default, does it by the name of your WAR file.
So our application is now localhost:8080/conference.
There's ways to change that.
You can go put the final build artifact name in there, but this is great.
This gets us developing and gets us doing everything we want to do,
and our app is now up.
We did a bunch of stuff there.
Let's walk through that real quick.
We started off by opening up our POM file and changing the
packaging type to war and then adding this dependency for
the spring‑boots‑starter‑tomcat.
We also downloaded a Tomcat instance and added a
configuration for it. We see our configurations here.
I changed the URL to be /conference, and in the deployment,
I changed the Application context to be conference.
We need to make sure those two line up.
Back on our Server tab,
if you hate that it launches a browser every time it starts up,
you can uncheck this Open browser After launch checkbox right here in
the center of the application configuration section,
and that can become a little bit annoying after a while.
I like it because it gets me up and running and
lets me see what I want to faster.
But if you do hate that, you can go ahead and disable that there.
Then we went ahead and created a src, main,
webapp directory,
and copied over that index.html you can see on the left‑hand pane there,
and launched our application, which pulled up our index.html page.
So quite a few steps, Tomcat downloaded and expanded,
installed, configured the runtime configuration,
and then switched it over to a WAR and added a plugin for it,
not that bad when you break down the steps. It just maybe seems like a lot if you're not used to all of that.