The Post/Redirect/Get pattern, or PRG,
is a technique used to help eliminate form resubmission.
The user's POST to the controller does whatever intended action was requested,
but before returning the view back to the user,
it does an internal redirect and issues a GET back to
itself to display the page to the user.
This makes sure that all the variables of state have been cleared,
so a back button then resubmitted is disabled or stopped.
Let's implement this in our app now.
We've already done all of the work that we need to for us to
implement the Post/Redirect/Get pattern because we've set up our
GetMapping and our PostMapping separate.
A lot of examples out there show these being combined.
All we actually needed to do is go to line 22 now and
put in redirect: and save that,
and this will tell the ViewResolver to go ahead and do a
complete redirect and a GET back to registration, and it will
clear that form out for us. Now, yes, you can still back up,
but it will be a new,
completely separate POST. It won't be reposting the same information,
if that makes sense. So let's save this, start or restart our server
depending on what state you left yours in.
And now we can go to our registration link, and inside of here,
if I put in my information and click Add Registration,
notice that it has submitted it and returned us back here and cleared it out.
So we've done the whole GET, and then a Post/Redirect/Get back to
ourselves, and it's cleared this form out. And that just helps us
have that information in a safer state to not resubmit or overwrite the existing page that's there.