Views are resolved in Spring MVC by the controller building a
model that it passes to a view resolver,
which then will determine the correct view that we want to display and
choose the appropriate view based off of that request. And there are
various view resolvers that are provided by Spring.
You can create your own custom view resolver,
since they just extend the ViewResolver interface.
Some of these resolvers are used for templating
tools like Thymeleaf or FreeMarker.
It just configures where it should be looking for those templates and then
executes the bindings and writes the output. The ResourceBundleViewResolver
is used for internationalization purposes,
and it's used for things like templated layouts. In
a later example in this course,
we're going to look at XML content negotiating and how to
respond with JSON responses versus HTML or JSP responses, and we'll walk through one of those examples.