This is Carol and welcome back to the course in Tablo.
And Congratulations on completing the first section of the course and more importantly and making this
step into the second section.
I'm super excited that you're here and I hope you are as enthusiastic as I am about the material that
we have ahead of us in this section we have a real business problem a real challenge ahead of us and
let's have a look at what it is.
So here's a document that specifies a challenge.
Let's have a look.
It's end of financial year and that means it's means it's time for annual bonuses.
The store which we're looking at the store operates in three regions and only the top performing employee
in each region qualifies for a bonus.
Find out which three employees are eligible to get a bonus to get bonuses for this year.
Employees are measured on the total number a total value of sales and the daughter.
As we discussed is located at this link.
So here's the Web site and you can download the data here so just a quick word of caution if you're
using just a normal windows.
Get this first file.
If you are using a Mac get the second file and if for some reason for whatever reason you will experience
problems with either of these three files then just go ahead and download the third file and proceed
as we did in the previous section with an Excel data source.
But do let me know and I will definitely do everything I can to help you out to make sure you're able
to work as few files as well because they are quite common.
So save link as.
And so to my Tablo of course folder save the file.
So what is the file.
It's basically a text file but it's data separated by commas.
And that's what's called a comma separated values file.
That's what CSC stands for.
So let's open that up and have a look.
OK.
So this file contains once again transactions and played by region.
It's got the rep name so the person who conducted that transaction what he sold.
So this stationery shop and office supplies shop so they sell pens binders desks sometimes.
And the number of units that were sold and the unit price.
So this is a much smaller file only 44 rows including the header so it is a very basic sample file.
And but it's good it's good to start with this because it will help us understand exactly how tablet
works and moreover if you do have anything that you're curious about you can always come back into the
file and have a look for yourself and even just filter out that information that you're looking at in
Tablo and just compare.
So it's a very good very small very good file to start exploring Tablo with.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
So in this section we've got quite a lot of ahead of us.
We're going to be looking at some things like creating all calculated fields we'll be working colors
we'll be adding labels will be formatting our chart exporting our work sheets and all of the basics.
We're going to cover them in this section and that will create a great foundation for us going forward.
So we'll get started in the next tutorial and I look forward to them until next time happy analyzing.