Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo and in the previous sections of this course we created
the dashboard.
It's all ready to go.
Fired up.
Let's have a look at it and analyze how the different regions.
What's happening in the different regions of the U.K. for this.
So to get into it right away this is our customer base line.
Let's have a look at it.
We know that most of our customers are in England.
Then second place is Scotland Wales and Northern Ireland.
Now if you look at the breakdown by balance you'll see that it's dropping off gradually as first slowly
and then quite quickly and that is something that you would expect that the lower the balance band the
more customers you will have in that band.
So zero to 10000 10000 to 20 20 to 30000 all have about 15 percent of our customers which in total constitute
45 percent of our customers sit under thirty thousand dollars.
Next the distribution by age is also quite interesting.
Here you can see that most of our customers are in their 30s so early 30s and late 30s.
And together that's 40 percent.
So if I change this to age group by 10 years you'll see that 40 percent of our customers are in their
30s to in their 30s basically.
And now if we go back here you can see the gender breakdown some a bit more males and females but not
that much of a difference because most of white collar only half and then a quarter each for blue collar
and other.
All right so now let's look at the regions and see how when we click on the regions they deviate from
the baseline because that is ultimately what we want to report how each region is different to the overall
average.
So if we click on the United Kingdom you can see the distribution by balas doesn't change that much.
Gender changes a little bit but also not that much so 5 percent change distribution by age changes so
here in our overall representation on our baseline you can see that this is a right skewed distribution
meaning that the this is the mean of this it looks like a normal distribution which is which is a natural.
So here you can see that the machine is sitting at somewhere about 35 years old and then is going along
right side tail.
So that means that it is a right skewed distribution whereas when you clicked on England the distribution
is no longer right skewed.
What that is telling us is that the customers that are in their later age groups they are not predominantly
they're not in England they're somewhere else.
And now what we want to look at is the job because.
So here you can see white collar 50 percent in England it's actually 70 percent so much more white collar
workers in England and perhaps that has something to do with London.
The economic hub of Europe being in this region and therefore perhaps a lot of the finance workers or
workers in the finance industry decide to bank before bank.
So they might find attractive and that's something you want to convey to the executives that when they
are advertising or working with customers in England perhaps it's a good idea to take as Jew care or
special care of the white collar workers and see how you can tailor the services to their needs in this
specific region.
So that's what we're going to be focusing on in our storyline that England is predominately white coworkers.
Next we'll move on to Scotland once again who will unclick the map so we have the baseline and now we
can on Scotland we can begin to compare.
You can see that the balance distribution changes a bit but not too much.
There's some anomalies but the rest of the charts change quite a lot.
So gender breakdown goes from 54 percent male all the way to 72 percent male white collar workers completely
disappear or there's a little bit of them here and mostly blue collar workers and other and also the
demographic age demographic is completely different.
So now our customers are in their late 40s early 50s which is a very very interesting.
So what this is telling us is that if you're going to service this region or when you are servicing
this region creating promotions and different campaigns for this region you have to aim for a much older
demographic predominately male and more in the blue color space so if I click on blue color here you'll
see that 95 percent of the blue collar workers in this region are all male and if I click on other you'll
see that there's a different picture here.
More female So if you are going to aim for blue collar workers you want to expand the net or the bank
customer base in Scotland in the blue collar worker space then you should be targeting males in their
late 40s early 50s on the other hand if you want to target other kind of professions then you should
still take into consideration that there is a large female representation in even in this region where
overall there is predominately male representation.
So that's what we'll be focusing on in Scotland and our story line.
Let's move on to Wales What can we see in Wales.
Well the first thing that jumped into my attention is the balance so if you look at the overall distribution
of balances it gradually falls off in Wales.
It's staggering for a bit.
We can dig into this further by grouping these balance balances not into ten thousand dollar groups
or but into $15000 groups and here you can see a different picture.
So for the overall base you can see it's still gradually falling off in these baluns groups.
For Wales it's actually first going up then it's staying above the original level of about 18 percent
and then it's dropping off.
So what that is telling us is that in Wales there is an abnormally large representation of average or
not average.
Normally large representation of mid size balances societ balances from zero from zero to $45000.
It is above average.
It's not consistent with the overall baseline.
And so that's something we want to report.
The other elements here they're not as significant Well there is quite a bit of a gender split a different
gender split a job classification changes a bit decision by age but probably what is the most interesting
part is this distribution by balance.
And finally we move on to Northern Ireland.
Here you can see another completely different demographic again once again.
So I'm going to go back to balance group ten thousands.
And this is quite consistent with the baseline a bit of anomalies but has to do with the low sample
size.
But what we can see here is 74 percent are female and mostly this demographic is a younger demographic
so mostly these people are in their 20s late 20s early 30s as opposed to the baseline very early 30s
to late 30s.
So they're a bit younger and they're predominantly female.
Seventy four percent which is completely opposite to a baseline where their customers are predominantly
male.
And here the main job classification is other work.
And if you click on that you will see that they're predominately female.
So that is how to analyze a segmentation dashboard.
You can definitely look at additional insights and Drilon further so you can go here and then you could
try to analyze what's going on with the specific workers and derive more insights from this data and
that's different that you should say something you should do.
But for the storyline that is sufficient for us.
Those are like conversational topics something to get the storyline going and you'll see how this all
comes together in a storyline.
And also you can see now what's called the segmentation dashboard because it allows us to seek a mentor
a customer base and understand how to service them better.
I'll give you an example let's say you have your bank comes up with an insurance offering or some kind
of new product that involves insurance Well if your bank wants to market the insurance offering to your
existing customers then you would approach it differently in different regions.
For instance in Scotland you know that your customers just by looking at this picture right away you
know that your customers are in their late early or late 40s and early 50s are predominantly male and
mostly blue collar workers.
So you just keep that thought in mind for a second.
Now let's go to Northern Ireland.
Here you can see a completely different picture.
You can see that they're predominately female in their early 30s late 20s early 30s so even if you're
marketing the same product you might want to position it differently.
So in Northern Ireland you might say that this insurance will allow you to you know take care of life
changing events.
For example purchasing homes or getting married or having children and so on because that's important
to take care of these events that are changing your life and so on.
And in Scotland these people have already had all of those events.
Most of these people so you would position it differently would say this insurance is important because
it will help you protect the people you love it will help you look after your families.
And we know you're you're in a high risk profession and you're doing a lot of manual labor so it is
important to have this insurance so that you are covered and the people that you love your are protected.
And so that way that is how businesses benefit from these type of segmentation dashboards because they
not only are able to sell their products are able to sell their products much more in a much more tailored
fashion much more making the offering more relevant to the people they're targeting and there's nothing
bad about it's actually a good thing that you're delivering a good customer experience.
You're showing your customers that you know who they are you know what what they care about and what
is important to them and that is very important in today's world where we have lots and lots of data
which you can use and you can analyze and you should businesses should take advantage of this that this
data to make the customer experience as great as possible.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.