Hello and welcome back to the course on tumblr in today's tutorial We'll look at how to connect to PTF
documents from within Tablo.
I know the previous lectures were a lot of talking but today we actually get to doing.
And I'm super excited about this topic because now we are able to connect to PDA documents and this
has been personally one of my challenges in the past.
Who gets provided a PDA of document and also to analyze it.
All right but let's jump into Tablo and have a look at how this works.
Now you'll notice the PTF file connection other than normal connection options.
So we'll collect that and we will use our N.Y.C. Paul crime stats PTF fall.
Now immediately you'll notice something different as when we are connected to our previous falls it
provides.
It opens up with a page picture.
Now this page because allows us to specify which single pages we want to use or a range of pages.
And in our case we will be using all but this is super handy if you remember the example we had of when
a table was on a specific table.
Then we can specify that over there.
It's also very important to note that we may be working with page numbers in.
And I'll just open up our PDA fall is that Tablo uses the absolute page number reference.
And that's what you'll find here in your PDA reader.
Do be careful when using the page number on the sheet as that might differ from the actual absolute
number of friends over there.
Because sometimes in reports you will find that the first few pages are just an introduction or some
images and the actual report only starts on later pages.
So do be careful and only focus on that.
This will save you a lot of time and problems going forward.
Trust me.
But back to Tablo So we will just be selecting all of the pages because all of our data is located on
all pages and immediately you'll see that Tablo has interpreted the PDA fall and created a whole number
of different tables.
But let's unpack that quickly.
We can see that we've got each page one or two different tables and we'll have a closer look but that's
just to indicate that Tablo has interpreted the data on the table or the data on the page rather in
two different possible formats.
Let's take page one table 1 and have a look what that looks like.
And as you can see this looks familiar to what we had with Excel files earlier the way some of the data
is not properly orating it's also iterating some of the information and therefore quite a bit messy
at the moment.
But just like we clean our Excel files we are able to use the data interpreter to clean the PTF document
or allow Tablo apply some logic to see if it can clean this fall for us so let's use that let's stick
the used data interpreter and as magic and as we've seen this for Excel falls Tablo is able to identify
it correctly and put the right names into the right columns with the right correct data.
Now what you'll see we've got all the parks running down we've got 14 records and this does look complete
but let's look at what is in table 2 then.
So if we go to table we have a look at Table 2 and still using the data interpreter.
You will see that we have much less records so tableaus only Intifadas nonrecourse to be ready and we
know for a fact when we look at our actual PTF fall.
There's more than nine lines.
They are actually 49 so you can count them by the way but Tablo has been saying all these things saying
that in this method number two it's needed to find nine lines so that different it does not look correct
and we won't be using the second interpretation that's at back.
The first one.
And we're always using the interpreter.
It's good to check your data quality or you can trace your data it's complete.
So let's click on the Revera results just to make sure there aren't any funnies that happened to him.
Tablo was in was interpreting this.
Now we've worked with us before so we'll skip that first part but what we can see is that tableaus correctly
identified the hidden in red and all of the lines correctly and you'll see there's nothing at the bottom
so it's connected to all the lines.
And as I mentioned to you they are basically 49 different lines in our data.
Perfect.
So we know that is complete and correct.
But obviously we don't only want the first page we want all of the remaining pages as well.
So to do that we'll just hold down the control button and click on the first table only of each page.
So ignoring page 2 because we know that the first method of importing the data is correct.
And what you might want to do in the dead interpreter is also just to confirm that I have actually already
checked that.
And that is complete.
But yes we want to add these different tables from these pages.
So how do we do that.
We don't want to join them so if we drag them straight into our area over there it would join them.
We actually just want to open them or rather a union name.
So how you do that is once it's all selected you just drag it over into this pain and you hold it close
to the page one level one that's already there.
You'll see it opens up a and drop area for us an area to basically track the tables to union and make
sure that it turns orange so that it is actually dropping it in there and not next to it.
So once you drop it in sublevel do a few calculations and it will actually add the number of records
you can see we've got a thousand.
We can just make it a bit more make the limit a bit more by just adding a few zeros.
And now we end up with 1155 rows so we think that this is all of the records.
But we will check that what has happened is that Tablo has added an A for one field and that might seem
strange because we know we didn't we didn't have that in the first page in first table.
But if we scroll down and have a look we can see that this is simply the POK name way in some cases
it didn't incorrectly or it didn't correctly identify that.
So we can fix that quite simply we just click on bauk it hole hold while holding control down click
on F1 and from the dropdown select may merge mismatched fields.
It would then throw the NOS away and populate them with the correct value.
That was actually used.
So you can see if we scroll through not all of the parks have names and if one has disappeared and was
merged in there I am actually just going to change this.
I just want to call it back and then clean up the fall a little bit because we don't want some of these
fields for instance sized We can hide.
We don't want any of these fields because we only work with a total so we can just hide them as well.
And I don't care about the table name.
And let's give this a proper name let's call this incidence.
As the number of incidents reported.
So end up with three fields nicely cleaned file.
However we did see that we've got a 1155 records.
And as we don't have a record count let me just get to that for once again if the fact that we don't
have the number of records in our fall but we do know we've got a total loss so we can consign back
to the total line.
So back to to our Tablo we could just open up a sheet and simply drag in the incidents into our area
over there and we can see that now at least 218 which does not seem correct at all.
So if you go back to our data source we know that Tablo might interpret this total line actually also
as a record.
So let's see if it has done that right at the bottom you can see Tablo has seen that as a normal record.
And we know that is not a balk that's just a total.
So we can add a datasource filter to remove that.
So we can just click add by the filters add another one and go box.
So we want to basically full to the total line of the line with the total in Pawk.
So we will just basically say we will look for the total we will select that and say excuse.
This is just if we do refresh our data with new information that we add a new box being added that we
don't include total or we don't specify specific box but we just exclude any totals from there.
So we can hit OK it's OK once again we can see a number of rows obviously changed one place.
And now if we go into our sheet you'll see that we've got 109 records which is or rather 109 incidence
which is correct as we know from our PTF.
So as you can see a bit of cleanup is required and a bit of quality checks also when working with pedia
files but actually quite an easy way to connect to the false.
And this is for me.
Excellent then two purposes of sum up.
It's important to note that each belief document that you'll work with will have different clean up
procedures.
They might be additional steps required or even less steps.
It's all about how the data is interpreted by tabla.
Also important to note that tableau will have issues importing hierarchies and hater's subtotals multiple
rows of content that should be interpreted as one or any color and shading on your PDAF document can
affect how Tablo interpret the data.
So do be careful with that in the next Tauriel we'll be looking at another fall top which we are able
to connect to in Tablo now with a new Tablo connector.
Also a very exciting one in my opinion in any case.
But we will have a look at the file type and how we can best make use of them in Tablo.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.