Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today we're talking about a new and exciting feature in Table 9 which is called the Dahdah interpreter.
And as we discussed previously we already know that machine and human format for Dadda is a bit different.
So let's go ahead and have a look at how tablet can help us overcome these challenges that occur when
we're trying to import human like data into software like Tablo.
So first of all we're going to need our browser and in our browser we're going to go to supersize dot
com slash Tablo scroll down to the bottom here at the bottom you can see a file which is called personal
vehicle sales global.
Let's go ahead and download that now right.
Saving that file.
That's good.
And now I'm going to open the folder.
There it is.
So where is our file personal vehicle sales.
Lol we'll just drag out into Excel and there we go.
So this is what our file looks like.
It's a report showing how the sales of vehicles personal vehicles have been growing or changing through
the past couple of years.
And so having years that we have here 10 years and you can see here these numbers represent the total
number of vehicles sold so these dollars these are actual numbers so for instance in all a strange thousand
fourteen there was about 330000 personal vehicles that were sold.
And as you can see the format of the spreadsheet is very much oriented as humans and say humans I'm
not a robot.
It's very much oriented at us humans.
So here are the great great ones.
You can see these are approximate numbers or estimated figures here.
There's like a legend a little bit of a legend up there and right away you can see like there's a header
as we discussed there's this top row scrolls along top five rows scroll along.
That's because it's easy for us to navigate that way.
What else.
So here we've got some totals for instance Europe or let's have a look at this one now.
So the North American Free Trade Agreement that's Canada Mexico the United States so you can see these
totals which will obviously jump into our data and we don't want that than just America.
The totals for the whole of America including nafs and Central and South America.
And then there's like empty rows all over the place.
What else do we have here.
That's they can be a problem here.
All the countries total often immaterial and some comments we hear of stars.
You'll also notice it took me it took me a while actually to figure this to see this one is that there's
hidden columns in here and you often forget about those if we hide You'll see that there's actually
three hidden columns here and that can also interfere with our daughter import when we do start doing
it.
So this is quite a challenging file as you can see for a machine to comprehend.
Let's go ahead and see how Tablo is going to handle it.
So I'm just going to close the file for now.
I don't actually I'll keep it open because we might need to have a look at it.
So I'm going to open up Tablo Tablo.
And here we've got a lot of beautiful spreadsheets or tabs and worksheets that we've been working on
so we can go to connect to your file Excel.
Here we've got the file personal vehicle sales global.
Open it up and right away we've got this previa at the bottom so that zoomin all that we can see here
that everything is completely mixed up.
So instead of the call them names are like random or one of two or three and then this one has a name
that has some random names and some empty columns estimated figures.
Remember that piece of coal called a legend that we had before.
I had him there we've got the region's countries which are actually years or so regions countries in
this call them in years and here as part of a dot and so completely messed up daughter it shouldn't
be like that.
So what are we going to look at now.
Is it is a Tablo daughter interpret it what it does is it allows tabbouleh to help you kind of understand
what's going on and done all kind of like it allows Tablo to be smart about what it can see in the data.
So here you can see a common saying that Tablo daughter interpretor might be able to help.
So why don't we go ahead and click turn on for that feature.
And so what happens now is the data is changed.
Now we've got two regions countries as the name of this column which kind of sounds about right.
Names of these columns include both the year which is right.
So if we go back to our data so here you'll see that the names of the columns are actually years but
also include a number which is not correct.
And then we've got some numbers it still has the totals which are which is not good but already a bit
better.
So let's try to understand what happened here.
What are we going to click on this button here.
Review results and then once we click it and new spreadsheet is going to be open for us.
So this spreadsheet pops up basically what it's showing us is it's got some descriptions here but the
main tab that you want to look at is the second tab and it's it's a description of what Tablo saw.
So we're going to zoom in a little bit I'm going to make this a bit wider so.
Oh that's a bit too wide I guess.
So what tablas telling us here is it's telling us what exactly.
So in the data.
So tablas saying all right these red ones so I can completely ignore these white collar white cells
then these red cells as you can see here.
Tablo saying that's ahead or I will look at that as if it's a hitter.
And that's why in our data in our preview of our data we can see a combined date and the number because
Tablo said.
OK so that's ahead or that's ahead.
I'll just combine the two combined combined combined combined.
And so that's how it created the header and then it's got these green cells which is considered to be
Datto which is clearly correct to some extent some of these do have to be omitted because they're total's
and then as you can see it ignore the common at the end of this with this Asterix.
So that's a good start.
So we now know Tablo can do a bit of work for us.
Let's help tabel out a little bit as well.
So I'm going to close that because we don't need that.
Now we're going to close this as well we'll redo that in a second.
So what are we going to do now is we going to adjust this file so it can actually work if it's so it
can do all the work for us.
But it can do definitely can do quite a lot of it.
So what we're going to do to start off with is we obviously need to delete these totals because they're
just remaining in our data and they're not being removed which is not good.
But before we delete them as soon as we delete the totals.
As you can imagine we will lose information on.
So if I delete these roles like this we lost information on which region this was.
So this is Europe.
This is Europe new members we want to keep that information.
So we're going to add a column on the left here.
So I basically Press Control shift plus or we can just right click and insert.
So what am I going to do is I'm going to copy the region name here.
Got a copy it says is just an example of how to quickly fix up your daughter before importing it into
Tablo in Africa.
And then we don't need that.
So next we're going to do is we need to obviously copy down remember we talked about this so we need
to copy down the name of the region for these empty cells as well so you can just double click and copy
until the next one.
Or you can drag an old copy.
This is very basic Excel stuff.
I like to do what I like to do is I like to select all myself that I need to copy including the top
one.
And then if you press control g on your keyboard and you go to then you click special and you go to.
OK.
And now you click enter this and then instead of pressing enter your press control enter then I'll do
the whole job for you.
So as you can see Europe Europe Europe new members Russia after and so on.
So now we have to do is control copy this and then I'll basically copy paste values.
And now we don't have the formula that is perfect and what that means is now we've got these copied
now we can get rid of these totals so we're going to control minus these.
So I'm basically deleting these rows with the totals.
So be careful here because there's some empty ones here.
South America there's another to go destroy everything.
All right.
So that's all deleted.
Now we only have our countries and the region that they're from and of course the data over here.
And that's pretty much it.
You just have to obviously give this one a name.
So it's cold regions.
And he'll just leave countries.
All right so that's our file.
We fixed it up.
Doesn't even matter that we've got this empty row here.
Tatel take care of the rest so let's go ahead and save that that's saved.
Now open up Tablo as well.
And we're going to go to excel personal vehicle sales global.
There we go.
And once again problems so tabloids can see these empty empty columns it doesn't have all the names
turn on Dot interpreter and voila.
Much better right away.
So this empty columns still here because I think this is like a value in one of the one of the rows
so we're just going to click it and click hide and perfect.
So now we can see the region the country the sales of the number of vehicles sold in that specific year
one second OK.
So that's good.
Now what we want to do is we want to review results just have a look at what tablet did exactly.
There it is.
So if you go to to the second tab you'll see that this is the header for tabbouleh which is correct.
Then from here onwards it's the daughter Rose.
So the first thing I was a bit concerned about is did it pick up this empty row as a row of data.
But in reality if we count the rows here there's 144.
Now if we go back to Tablo it will tell us that there's 144 rolls here so it basically picked it up
as a daughter.
But because it was empty it completely ignored.
And so that's how the data interpreted tablet works it can definitely save you some time and because
it cuts out these headers for you I ignore those blank rows and so on.
It doesn't do all the work but at the same time it can help you can Nudgee in the right direction if
you import daughter you check what that interpreter looked at and saw and then and then you corrected
a little bit and then you send it send it back into Tablo again then Tablo can really help you out and
do the remaining groundwork for you so you can import the data into title in the next tutorial we will
look at.
Another cool element of importing data and that will be pivoting data.
So that will be fun and I'll look forward you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.