Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today we'll start on the demographical segmentation of our member base on the rest of the bank.
So what do we mean by that.
Well we want to see some visuals representing the gender of the members or the customers of the bank
the different types of professions they're in.
Different age groups and so on.
So let's get started with that first thing we're going to do is we're going to change the name of this
worksheet to map.
And then now we're going to create a new worksheet and let's all forget to constantly save our progress
by pressing Kontrol S..
So here we're going to just create a very simple visualization which is going to be a pie chart.
So let's take a gender and drag it into Tablo and number of records which we now know how to use do
I get into trouble as well as you can see now we have female and male and tells us exactly how many
of each gender they are in total in the bank and now we're going to change this to a pie chart.
Probably not the best way to change a pie chart let's try this way.
So there we go.
If you use a show me functionality you get this pretty cheap pie chart.
Now you can make it a bit bigger if you like maybe change the size.
Now what we're after is some labels here because we can see what's going on.
Wolf first of all probably change the colors will change male to blue and female to pink.
So they're intuitive.
And now we want some overseas some numbers in here and what are we going to do is take this some of
a number of records and all this just take number of records from the measures and will drag them into
label and what we can see here is the total number of males and females that were bank with our bank.
We can change the format here just to see this little bit better and keep it consistent with this part
of the future dashboard.
So if this worksheet we read everything is 12 and bold so little change out here.
But for a pie chart you know you are probably interested in the total number of people males and females
you want the percentages.
So how do we get percentages.
And this is where we start working with table calculations.
It's a very powerful feature in Tablo and this is the first time we're introducing it.
So it's going to be very helpful going forward for us to add a table calculation.
So basically tell us what is this number what percentage is this number of the total of what we see
here.
You can you just need to do one simple step.
You click on.
In this case the table self-ish is going to be added to this field so we want to replace this field
with the table calculation.
So click on this dropdown here and so I'll probably move it a bit.
So yeah we have more space.
So click on the dropdown here and select quick table calculation and here from the quick table calculation
select percent of total and you select that these numbers have been replaced and you see this little
triangle up here on the actual measure so on the right there's this triangle it's indicating to you
that there is a table calculation being performed here.
And if you go here you can see quick table calculation.
It's telling you which one has been selected and it is percent of total as we selected it.
So now we want to format this again so we'll go to format and we'll change it from numbers to percentage
and no decimal points.
And there you go.
So now we sort of seeing the total number of males and the total number of fields was females we can
see what percentage the makeup of the total or of the segmentation that we've selected will in this
case the segmentation that selected is the whole population of the bank.
And that's why we can see that it's 54 and 46 percent.
And you will see what I mean by selective segmentation when we move on to creating the dashboard.
It will become more clear how by selecting different segments of our bank these percentages will actually
change.
So that is how you perform table calculations.
This is the most simple one.
It is called percentage of total you'll be using it quite a lot.
It's very handy to quickly change from absolute numbers to relative percentages.
And they are more table calculations and we will explore them further on down the track.
So that's all for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then I'll be analyzing.