Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today we're looking at filter's important lecture today.
But before we get to it I want to talk to you for a favor.
So I know we're not finished over the course yet but I would really appreciate if you could leave a
review for this course.
We're we've done a few modules so far and if you like the materials please go ahead and click the button
at the top of the course which looks like this and just choose the number of stars that you think the
course deserves and leave a review if you like if you don't want to write it you think just choose the
number of stars and click submit.
The reason I'm asking now is because a lot of students don't finish the course to the end for whatever
reason.
And I definitely hope it's not.
You're not going to be that student.
I hope you get to the end but at the same time I would really appreciate a review because it helps me
understand whether you like the course or not.
And also it helps other students who are considering taking this course undecided whether it's worth
their while.
So I would be very happy if you could do that for me today.
And now let's get back to the show.
So we're talking about filter's today.
We've got this area chart that we created last time which if you ask me looks pretty amazing already.
We're just going to add a bit of formatting to it at the end of the lecture.
But how can we add a filter.
So what's information is missing currently on this chart.
The information that's missing is gender.
We've got the age groups and we've got the unemployment rate split by months but we can't see gender
here.
So one way to add gender is by putting gender into a filter.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
So to do that you have to take gender or the variable that you want to add as a filter and put it into
the filter shelf.
And it's as simple as that.
There we go.
So now you've got this filter menu pop up and you can specify the kind of settings or set up your filter.
So here we go into select food.
We are allowing this filter to work by selecting from a list and there's only two values men and women
custom value lists.
I don't normally use that you could add like your own types of values use all.
So normally you stick with this select from list and this is for like dimensions.
We'll see.
We'll look at a filter for measures in a second so wild card usually I don't use any of these these
are more advanced kind of things that you use in very specific cases so we won't stop on them right
now because if you really need them you can understand them.
But to be honest with you I very rarely.
I don't think I've ever used the wildcards in my filters.
That's when you have huge lists that you're filtering from.
So we'll just stick with general and for now we'll just select all and the other thing that you need
to know here is you can select exclude and what that will do is it will allow you to filter what you
don't want to see.
So if you had like 10 values then you could click exclude and not allow you to cancel out a few rallies.
But right now we're just going to select what we do want to see.
So we'll click.
All will click OK.
And now you can see the chart and change because we selected both genders but now we have gender is
a filter.
And so if I want to change the filter I click filter and say I want to see the chart only for me and
then I click OK.
Then you can see the chart change because now it's only unplumbed for men and the access is much the
top value or the Maximillian X is much smaller because there is less unemployed people because we're
only looking at a subset.
Now for one to change it for women you check that and check that you could apply the Chara's changing
in the back there.
So that's all great but that is quite tedious Don't you find like you have to click the filter every
time and then change it and then close it again.
So that's when Tablo there is a solution there's a quick filter and we're going to learn that right
now as well.
So in order to bring up a quick filter you need to right click on the filter and select Schalkwyk filter
and just click that and you will see this quick filter pop up over here so it's quite far away.
How about I just put it there.
So I'll put it there for now.
But usually you keep them on the left.
I'll put it there just for our convenience so I can zoom in a bit.
And so here if I uncheck men you can see the chart is changing right away.
And check women Chartists changing so I can take all of them are the child disappears.
Very handy thing to have this quick filter because it helps you quickly analyze your data.
You can change it to type of quick filter you want to see and you can look you can see these different
types or it can be a drop down single slide.
So what we're going to do is we're going to actually put this one back here and now I'll bring up a
quick filter.
So actually what I'll do is I'll make my table a workbook smaller so we can zoom in like that.
There we go.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to add a filter for H because there's a lot more value
as we have an age and will be a bit handy.
So let's just do that.
Well put Asian to filter will select often I'll apply and will also create a quick filter for age.
There we go so that's a quick filter for age.
And now you can see how we can customize this filter.
So first of all we can uncheck certain values and as you can see they will disappear from the chart.
So this is not the best thing to have for this chart because we do want all groups of ages in unemployment
in this chart but we're just looking at it like this for now because it's a good example.
So you see we can uncheck the values we don't want to see and the chart changes right away dynamically
right in front of us.
So then we can just select separate ones.
But once again there's that option to highlight.
So you wouldn't need to do that ever if you have this highlighting option and then next what we're going
to do is we're going to look at the types of filters you can have so say you can have a single value
list if you only want to see one at a time.
Then you can just do these radio boxes.
And also you have this option also with filters you have the option to remove this all values so I can
check and then there's no old values so you have to select an option from the list.
But in our case we actually need the whole the whole year.
So how about we can also have like a single value dropdown.
So it's like a radio box but it's a drop it's a bit more convenient.
What else you can do like multiple values drop down so you can check that.
So it just kind of makes compact you can do a wildcard match where you type in 20 to 24.
Let's see that pick up the value that you're looking for.
So there's a lot of different options for filters and the more for convenience.
So that's that's pretty much that's I'm just going to get rid of this one because we don't need age
as a filter.
The other one I wanted to show you is we'll probably have a look more at measures as filters in the
next section because it will be more relevant there.
So we'll definitely have we'll definitely look at that in a bit more detail.
But just so that you know you can add filters and they are very easy to use so in this case if somebody
wants to analyze only men or women he can select from here so actually I mean is going to change this
to single value from list.
And that makes more sense so you either looking at everybody looking and just men or just women and
the chart adjusts dynamically and you can just look at exactly what you want to see.
So as promised we're just going to quickly fix up the formatting here so we'll just go format and make
it like a 12 and be unemployed and then we'll take a format here as well.
Make it a 12 and a B and make this a bit bigger.
So there you go.
There's a chart it's ready for export.
If you really want you can add some text it here just to replace this label that's missing.
But otherwise I think it looks probably quite good.
And yeah.
So that's all for the section.
Hope you enjoyed creating this chart.
We learned quite a lot of new things and make sure to do the quiz because that will help you solidify
your knowledge and to finish off.
I just wanted to remind you I would really appreciate if you could leave a review that would mean so
much to me.
Thanks a lot for watching and I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
Until next I'm happy analyzing.