Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today's going to be a very quick tutorial.
We're just going to create one more charge for our segmentation dashboard and this chart will be a trauma.
This tree map will be working with the job classification variable in our data.
So let's go ahead and create a new tab.
We will call this tab job classification.
And now we will start creating our team.
So let's take a job classification drag it into our workspace and let's take a number of records and
drag it into workspace.
Now if we use the Show Me functionality we can select tree map from here and once we do that you can
see a tree map has appeared.
It is funny how it's called the tree map.
I know it's it's actually boxes.
There's no trees here.
But nevertheless it's a tree map.
So what we want to do now is get rid of this color that's been determined by the total number of records
in each box.
And instead of that will take jobless classification hold control and drag it into color.
So that's our trauma.
Let's just make it look good now to start off with we're right click some way here and we'll click Format
change just to bowl to 12.
And bold.
And now I also would like to change the colors that go into colors and change them up a bit.
So blue color can stay blue either.
Let's make other green and white collarless make it gray.
We can really make it white because our background is white but let's make it gray.
So there's our tree map.
And now we'll just save all those worksheets.
And that's pretty much it.
That's how you create trim up there.
Pretty easy to create.
What else you could do you could drag this into labels as well.
If you wanted to but we're not going to do that at this stage so we're done with all of all worksheets
which is great in the next tutorial we will finally start creating our superpowerful dashboard.
I look forward to seeing you then.
And until next I'm happy analyzing.