Hello, and welcome to my course on Performing Continuous Integration
with AWS Codebuild. First, a little bit about me.
My name is Joshua Edwards. I'm the Vice President of Engineering at a
blockchain and cryptocurrency‑focused business. I have previously been a
head of DevOps, and I have used Codebuild on a day‑to‑day basis.
Throughout my career, I've worked in the GovCloud space, a start‑up space,
and also for tier 1 consultancies.
This has allowed me to deliver fully automated and
secure environments inside of AWS.
If you like my course or you have any questions,
please feel free to reach out to me on Twitter.
My username is @JoshuaGEdwards.
Okay, let's jump right in.
This course is going to be focused on Amazon Web Services Codebuild.
We're going to look at planning a build,
creating a build, managing build artifacts, the security
aspects, and finally, monitoring builds.
Sounds exciting, right?
Let's get started.
Okay, so let's delve into what AWS Codebuild is.
So let's take a look at an overview of the service and some of the
prerequisites required to use in this service.
Codebuild is a managed service from AWS that allows you to run
custom build commands and scripts from other sources.
So let's take a look at some of the components.
You can build all sorts of things such as code, packages,
executables, scripts, and config files that all gets stored in
an S3 bucket after the build process. You can even use
Codebuild to run a packer script to create an AMI. You're going
to see more about this later.
You can use code sources such as S3 bucket,
GitHub, CodeCommit, and even BitBucket.
CodeBuild makes it so easy to build artifacts,
and it fits perfectly into your automation lifecycle, and
integrates nicely into CodePipeline and CodeDeploy.
It handles all of the complexities of building your application and
can build it exactly how you want it to be built.
It makes builds a safe and seamless process for your users
and your developers. AWS CodeBuild is aimed at AWS
developers, AWS DevOps engineers, AWS architects, and also system administrators.
But this does not mean that it's solely exclusive to the people in those jobs.
CodeBuild is for anyone who wants to use it, so I recommend
programmers, engineers, and anyone else who wants to know more
just to have a go and have a look.
It's a fantastic service to use in your development lifecycle.
AWS CodeBuild uses Docker containers to run build scripts and commands.
You can use custom containers that contain any OS that you want,
or you can use the AWS Linux one.
The AWS Linux one has runtimes that you can specify to build most
of the common programming languages available.
We'll see more about this later.
Okay,
let's take a look at some of the CodeBuild security features that are in
place that are going to keep your information secure.
Codebuild is in the boundaries of the AWS shared responsibility model,
which means that you know AWS has your utmost security desires at
heart and will allow you to manage your data securely.
It supports encryption at rest.
So when your build, cache, and logs are created,
you know they are encrypted and secure. CodeBuild uses TLS
connections for all of its endpoints, so you know that all
information in transit is encrypted.
All of the CodeBuild actions are monitored through AWS CloudTrail.
This means you can see how all of the actions happened and who did them,
as CloudTrail logs all of the API calls. For incident management, you can
use AWS CloudWatch events to detect and react to changes in the CodeBuild
state such as if a build happened, you can create an alert to notify you.
AWS CodeBuild has been audited and vetted by third‑party auditors
such a SOC, PCI, FedRAMP, HIPPA, and many more, so you know that
you're getting a highly secure service to use.
First off, to start using AWS CodeBuild,
we're going to need to make sure your user has some access
and permissions set up to allow the right access levels to
use the services required.
And we're also going to need to make sure that the AWS CodeBuild
service also has the correct amount of permissions to work. In this
demo, I'm going to show you how to allow and restrict access to
CodeBuild in IAM. Also, I'm going to show you how to create service
roles for some of the use cases of CodeBuild we'll be creating in the
following modules. Okay,
so I'm going to create a group and give it the
admin CodeBuild policy. Here it is,
and then we're just going to add that to the group,
but let's just hang on a second.
There are two other CodeBuild policies available, CodeBuildDeveloperAccess
and also CodeBuildReadOnlyAccess. Now dependent on what level of access
you want to give to the user, you would pick either one of these. And in
the next step, we're going to have a look at what some of the access
permissions the CodeBuild admin access policy has. Let's just create that
group, and with that policy attached, and then let's have a look at what
it can do.
So as you can see here,
the policy we have attached actually has a lot more actions and
access permissions available than just for CodeBuild.
We can see sorts of access permissions for logs, for ECR, EC2, CloudWatch, and
all sorts, S3. So that's going to be perfect for us to allow us to perform the
next few modules that we're going to be doing. Okay, to use CodeBuild, it's
going to need to have a service role.
We're going to create two service roles for both of our
use cases in the following modules.
We're going to create a generic CodeBuild service role,
and then we're going to create one that has more expanded access and
permissions to allow Packer to then create an EC2 AMI.
So let's go ahead and create the first service role.
We're going to select AWS service,
and we're going to scroll down and select CodeBuild. Next, let's jump over to
Permissions. We're then going to create our own custom policy.
We're going to select the JSON tab, and then in here you're going to paste in
the ServiceRoleCodeBuild JSON from the course document files.
And as you can see in here, we're going to give CodeBuild access to
everything that it needs to perform properly.
So let's review that policy.
We're going to give it a name, and then hit Create policy,
and then let's jump back over to our role, and then let's see if
it's in here, CodeBuild, there it is, and we'll select that, and
Next: Tags, and then Next: Review,
and then we'll give it a name. So, in here, we're probably
going to want to call it a ServiceRole,
and we'll call it CodeBuild, and then we'll hit Create role. Perfect.
Next, let's create the second role.
Same thing again, AWS service, select CodeBuild, Next:
Permissions, and then create our own policy.
And then we'll select the JSON tab again, and then we'll replace this with
the ServiceRoleCodeBuildPacker JSON. We'll give it a name.
Let's copy that, make it a bit easier to find it,
create the policy,
and then let's jump back over to the role, let's hit Refresh so it
has more of the new updated policy in there,
and then we'll find our policy, and then we'll then attach that to our new
role. And then we'll give it a name. Perfect. Create that role.
Now in here, we should be able to see our new roles.
There we are, ServiceRoleCodeBuild and then ServiceRoleCodeBuildPacker.
Here's a quick list of the AWS managed policies that can be
used for the IAM CodeBuild permissions.
We covered them in the previous demo,
but I thought I'd delve into it a little bit more here. We
use the AWS CodeBuild admin access, and that provides full
access to the CodeBuild,
including administrator access and permissions to build project.
We then have the other two we mentioned, which were the developer access and
the read‑only access. Developer access only allows access to specific build
projects and administration, and the read‑only allows you to just view and
take a look at CodeBuild and the project.
If you had a keen eye,
you would've also seen the S3 access too. In this section, we're going to
cover monitoring AWS CodeDeploy actions and events.
These are important to keep your environment secure like we talked about
earlier, and we can show how to order events if needed.
Okay, so in the next walk through,
we're going to take a look at the API call logs in CloudTrail for CodeBuild.
Let's jump right in.
Okay, so here I am on the CloudTrail dashboard.
Let's go over to Event history.
In here, we can see all of the event history in the CloudTrail log.
So if we select Event source and then we then select our CodeBuild
service, we can then see a list of all of the different actions and
events that happened in CodeBuild.
Let's open one of these up to have a look.
We can see what region it was.
We can see the event name and source.
We can see the time, and we can even see the IP address
where it originated from of the user.
It's that simple and that easy to monitor CodeBuild through
CloudTrail logs. Okay, first module finished.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
And we're well on our way to becoming CodeBuild pros.
Let's have a quick recap of what we just covered.
We covered what CodeBuild is in an introduction,
we had an overview of the service, we had a look at managing the permissions, and then also monitoring CodeBuild actions.