The final part of this course will conclude with
creating an EC2 AMI using Packer, which is being run by a CodeBuild build.
Let's jump right in and get to it.
First,
we need to make sure you have the right prerequisites required
to create an EC2 AMI with AWS Codebuild.
There's only one thing we need to have,
and it's already set up for this module as we set it
up previously in an earlier module, and that's the service role.
Awesome.
So we already have everything set up and in place.
Let's take a look at how to plan our build for AWS CodeBuild.
For our next build, we need to set up an S3 bucket on a CodeBuild project,
which will then create an EC2 AMI using Packer.
So now we understand the core components of this next build.
Let's take a look at creating it.
In this demo, we're going to cover the following.
We're going to be creating a build, we're going to set up the S3 buckets,
were going to have a look at the source code, we're going to run that build,
and then we're going to have a look at managing the AMI artifacts.
Let's create our S3 bucket.
Remember to give it a unique name, location London, and create the bucket. Cool.
Now,
let's find it, and let's go into it, and then we're going
to create two folders, same as last time, one called
Source and one called Artifacts.
So let's add that Artifacts one too, save that, on the in Source,
we're going to upload our ZIP file of our source code and then
upload that. Cool. Then let's head over to the CodeBuild dashboard,
and then let's create a build project.
We'll give it a name, PAcker‑ CodeBuild, and we don't need to give a
description, and then select our Source as S3, similar to how we did it
in the previous module, and then we'll give it an S3 object key of
Source/Archive.zip. It doesn't need to have a source version, and we're
going to select the Managed image from Ubuntu, it's going to have the
Standard runtime,
and then we're going to select 4.0. We're going to
select an existing service role.
We're going to pick the one that we created in a previous
module that has the elevated EC2 permissions.
It's going to use the buildspec file in the archive.zip,
and then it's going to produce a build.log for us, so let's store
that in our S3 bucket, and then we're going to give it a path as well
of artifact/build.log. We're not going to package that up, and we'll
have CloudWatch logs enabled.
So let's create the build project now. So that's now
created. Let's start our build.
Let's scroll down to Phase details, and we can watch
CodeBuild running through our build spec file.
This might take a few minutes,
so let's leave that to run until we hit Build phase, and then we can have
a look at CodeBuild, spin it up an EC2 instance for us, fire a packet, and
then creating the EC2 AMI for us. That's now into the BUILD phase. So
let's jump over to the EC2 dashboard,
and there it is, spinning up our EC2 server,
and it's going to run in our install scripts, it's going to copy
over our Go binary, and then it's going to create the image for
us. So let's jump back over to CodeBuild. That looks like our
CodeBuild build has succeeded.
Let's jump back over to EC2, and then let's have a
look at the images that it created.
There we are. There's our latest image, and we can see that's
just been created for us, and the tags that we set in packet 2
are Go‑AMI and it's our Go Web Server.
How cool is that? Super simple, super easy, and CodeBuild, it just takes the headache away.