In our next module, we're going to learn how to set up and run CodeBuild locally.
So without further ado,
let's dive into the local CodeBuild environment and talk
about what is needed to perform this task.
First,
we need to make sure you have the right prerequisites
set up to use CodeBuild locally, so let's take a look at what they are.
There are two things you're going to need to have ready and
set up before using CodeBuild locally.
You're going to need to have the CodeBuild.sh script.
We're going to download that.
And then we're also going to need the CodeBuild local container,
so we'll download that container from the repository,
and then we'll build that too.
So let's go ahead and get these set up locally now.
So in this next demo,
I'm going to show you where to download the CodeBuild.sh script from,
and I'm also going to show you where to download the
CodeBuild container and then build it.
This will then form the base layer for our builds locally,
So let's go ahead and jump right in and get this set up.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to clone the repo from
AWS with all of the AWS CodeBuild Docker images in it.
So I'm just going to jump over to our Visual Studio Code,
and we can have a look what's in this repo here.
So you can see that we have a local_build,
ubuntu, and we are going to use this Ubuntu standard image,
and we're going to use the latest 4.01.
And this is a Docker file that we are going to build,
and then this container will then run our CodeBuild builds locally.
So let's jump back over to Bash.
Let's cd into our new repo.
We are then going to cd into the ubuntu folder,
and then we're going to go into the standard folder,
and then we're also going to go into the 4.0,
which is the latest build.
So let's go ahead and build our container now.
We're going to build the 4.0 version.
Now, this built really quick for me,
but it might take a little bit longer for you as
I've already built it previously.
Now that's finished building, we just need one more container,
so let's go ahead and pull that one down.
We're going to need the codebuild‑local container.
Cool.
Looks like I already have that one.
You might see the container pulling down from the repo.
So now we have the codebuild‑local container.
Let's go back to our working directory, so let's go back a few where we‑‑‑ Yeah,
let's pull the CodeBuild.sh script, which is one of our requirements.
There it is.
And then let's make it an executable.
We just need to run the chmod command, and that should do it for us.
Perfect.
So that's it.
That's all we need to run our local CodeBuild builds on our local environment.
So now we have the script and containers locally,
let's take a look at how to use them.
In this demo, we're going to cover the following.
We're going to actually run a local CodeBuild build
that creates a Go binary for us.
So in our local dev working environment,
we're going to need to create a folder called Artifacts.
So let's create that now,
and then the next one we're going to need is our simple Go app.
Now, you'll be able to find this in the course modules,
so I'm just going to pop that in here.
And then inside this SimpleGoApp is just a really simple web server
and then also the buildspec file for CodeBuild.
So in the CodeBuild buildspec file, you have to select the version at the top.
So we can just use the latest 0.2 version.
And then in the phases, we just need one phase,
and it's just the build phase, and it's going to run a command that says,
build started on this date, and then it's going to build our Go binary.
It's then going to output an artifact called simplegoapp
into our artifacts folder over here.
So let's go ahead and do this now.
So let's jump over to the command line.
As you can see from this command here,
we're going to run the CodeBuild.sh script,
and it's going to need some variables passed in,
and let's walk through them now.
So the dash ‑i, this one,
is the container that we built before with a 4.0 version,
and then we're going to tell it where to store the artifact of
the build with ‑a in the artifacts folder.
And then the final one is the ‑s, which is the source repository for the code.
So let's go ahead and run that now.
As you can see, it spins up the container,
and it's starting to run our build for us.
You can see from the output here in the Bash window that it ran through the
different phases that we required, it ran the build phase,
and it ran the build command, and you can see all the output from that,
and then exported the artifact for us over here.
So let's jump over to Visual Studio Code,
and you can see that that build container created an artifact.zip for us.
So let's have a look what's in there.
We're going to unzip it,
and then here you can see our simplegoapp executable that was created
from our CodeBuild build local build environment.
How easy was that?
Whew!
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Let's have a quick recap at what we just covered.
We had a look at the local CodeBuild build,
we had to look at the prerequisites required,
we had a look at setting up the local build environment,
and we had to go running a local build. So let's carry on and move on to our next module.