A lot of this is Curole from for ex-beau dot com.
And welcome to the 19th tutorial and algorithmic trading for beginners.
And in this tutorial we're going to be talking about one more transactional related function a function
call for which allows us to modify orders which already exist in the market and this function is called
order modified.
So with no further ado let's proceed to mid-to editor and start looking at how all of this works within
the code.
So we're going to take tural 18 and we're going to build upon the existing code so we'll save this as
tural 19.
It will change a number up here and there we go so we compile that it all works all compiles and I'll
just quickly recap on what we already have.
We accept external variables from the trader.
We use these variables to calculate Stop-Loss and take profit levels.
We use the stop loss and take profit levels to send an order to the market.
Currently we are working with your dollar and then we have a failsafe mechanism in place so if there
were any errors when sending the order then will the trader will be notified.
Otherwise we know that the number of the order is stored in the ticket variable and this ticket variable
is used to further down the track in the program.
So this part is executed.
If there were no errors when sending the order we tell the trader that the order was sent successfully
and then this bit over here his bid is related to closing orders so I'll just put a comment here.
Osing the order and here we practiced closing the order and we told the trader that the order being
closed is going to be closed.
We used the order close function in combination of the ticket number to actually close that order and
once again we had a failsafe.
I would have a fail safe mechanism here telling us if everything went all right or not.
So we're not.
What are we going to do is we're going to replace it.
The closing of the order.
We're modifying the order and that is going to just save us time basically and allow us to practice
modifying the order instead of closing it.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'll just comment this out for now.
And then we'll just create a very similar bit to that but we'll modify the warrants that will say more
Maundy buying order and
let's just start coding it right away.
So alert we want to tell the trader that we are modifying
the order
then we will be using that order modified function.
So let's highlight this function and go into its help or and call for reference and just have a look
at it and how it works.
So the order modified function it all just transfer this
in Q4 so it's in a bigger font.
So that's how it looks.
The order modified function has takes several variables which are ticket price subclause take profit
expression and color and returns a boolean.
So it's similar to both the order send function and order close function.
It's similar to the order close function in the sense that it returns a boolean.
So we already know and we can check this and confirm this with reference that boolean means that if
the function succeeds it returns true.
Either way the trans folds.
So in that sense it's very similar to the order close function.
And it is similar to the order center function in the way that it requires.
You can posse's Stop-Loss and take profit parameter to it which allows you to control those two levels
associated with the order you're modifying.
And also you can change the price but that is something separate that is for the changing price only
relates to pending orders and that's something we're not going to be looking at for now.
We'll we'll look at that in the more advanced course of them kill for.
But at this stage we don't need to worry about the price and the ticket number is the number basically
and ticket number of the ticket office of the order that you'd like to modify.
And these two last parameters the expiration also relates to pending orders which we won't be worrying
about for now.
And the color we basically know we're about the color.
I just use the default settings.
So that's that let's create order and modify function.
So we have the ticket.
We know that we have that variable double price because we're not modifying impending order we will
just put zero full price because order is very open so we can change the price stop loss and take profit.
So this is the main probably the main reasons why you would want to power in order to adjust the Stop-Loss
though or the take profit level.
So that's what we'll do we'll.
We will adjust the stop loss and take profit level and set them for example to 20 pips or we'll actually
set them to double of what the trader has asked for.
So we'll take we'll take the bid price for this.
So this is a stop loss for so for the stop loss will take the bid price and we'll track it two times
of Stop-Loss and then multiply it by point.
So this is if this is 10 then this is 20 and this is 20 pips so 0.00 to zero.
And then we subtract 20 picks from the bid price and we'll do a similar thing for a profit.
It will be plus two times take profit Times point and we have to put a zero for daytime exploration
because it is a required parameter.
But in this case he'll be ignored.
Semi-colon our same thing as previously will have a bool arrests variable just to create a failsafe
mechanism.
We can actually just copy this from here put it in and if resits falls then we want to say Alert area
not closing or about modifying or
and otherwise order modified successfully and so we'll do one more sneaky thing here we will add a delay
and that what that will do is actually before after opening the order so after all this happens but
before all of this happens we want to maybe wait for one second so that we have a chance to actually
look at the chart and see what what has happened and then we'll modify the order so it's not necessary
but it's something.
It's good to know.
So the delay is given by the sleep function and sleep tells the program to stop working for a certain
amount of milliseconds.
So in this case we want to stop working for let's make it two thousand milli seconds which is a delay
of two seconds.
I'm pretty sure this can come in handy in some of your programs down the track as well.
So we'll compile that no errors or warnings and then go to the terminal and see how this works.
So if you go to scripts take total 19 drag it onto the chart inputs as you can see 10 and 10.
Sorry.
So that's what happens when there has been an error.
And luckily our failsafe mechanism has picked that up.
So in this case the error was that expert advisers and scripts Well basically all algorithmic trading
systems are switched off.
So we have to switch it on up here.
And the way I know it I just in this case I just remembered that they were off.
But from that message we can't really tell what the error was.
And that's something we won't go into that amount of detail in this course but if you'd like to learn
more about that and I encourage you to have a look at the more advanced course on for.
So now just drag a tutorial 19 over the chart.
So 10 and 10 will click OK.
So there you go or is opened and now order has been modified.
I hope I hope you saw that.
Let's let's quickly go back and change the delay four to five seconds for example compile that.
OK.
Total 19.
So I'll just close this order so it's not in no way
Toral 19 drag.
So let's say let's take profit 20 and then it should be changed to 40.
All right.
So there it is the order has been opened now in a few seconds.
It will be modified.
They go as you can see the tape profit and the Stop-Loss have doubled and that's exactly what we were
looking for.
So that's that that's how you modify orders in Q4.
And I hope that this tutorial was useful.
Have a play around with that and maybe create your own rules for modifying orders and to what levels
you want to modify.
Maybe it might be worth adding extra external parameters just to for the new stop loss and take profit
and just to basically train up your skills a little bit more.
As always you can find the source code of this Tauriel on w w w dot for export dot com.
I hope to see you on the next tutorial.
Until then coding.