Flow this is Carol from for example dot com.
And welcome back to the beginners course on algorithmic trading in em kill for and today we're going
to discuss what is in fact kill for now in the previous tutorial we successfully installed metal trader
for which is a trading platform developed by a quote software and medical software is a company which
was founded around 2001 and they primarily focus on facilitating online trading in the trade or for
package.
You got the Met a trader trading terminal which you can see here on the left and you also got the Mitta
editor development environment which we briefly launched in the previous tutorial.
So these two programs they are separate programs but they work closely together.
They met a trader for the trading terminal you can trade you can conduct transactions and see prices
and carry out different types of analysis manually.
And also you have some indicators and scripts which are prepackaged with the terminal and you can use
these to facilitate analysis.
On the other hand the Mitta editor is a programming development environment.
Or you could call it a software development environment.
It is a C-based.
So in the original language that was put into the core of programming language in Mitta editor is c
but because it's a modified language it's called em kill for.
And that stands for Medek quotes language version 4.
And this language allows you to create programs that falser in logic and at the same time they are able
to conduct transactions on the market through the metal trade or for trading terminal and hence that
green arrow between the two because their work really close together.
So we'll just replace these with the relevant icons the meditator like is on the left and the old editor
icons on the right.
They have a new one since build 600 I think came out.
It looks like a little yellow book but I can find one at this stage in good resolution.
So the Mirror editor allows you to create three different types of programs or software.
And those are expert advisers.
That's the one on the left the boot the guy in the blue hat indicators on the middle and scripts the
one on the right.
So in short the scripts allow you to execute one of the actions on the X market like maybe close an
order or open a certain type of order or just a stop loss or perform like that one of analysis indicators
are well the name speaks for themselves for itself.
They can tell you they do some sort of analysis and they draw something on the chart or give you some
some information and it continuously updates as new information comes in to turn them on.
And finally the expert advises the one on the left and the guy in the blue hat.
They allow you to create algorithmic trading systems that will work continuously and they're not one
off.
They just keep working as new information comes into the trading terminal.
So let's have a look at how the metal trader for trading terminal and Middx editor worked together on
the foreign exchange midair trader for once you have access to a broker.
Your broker provides you faxes to banks and other financial institutions.
And altogether this bill still states your access to the foreign exchange which in Medicare for looks
something like this.
The Editor On the other hand allows you to enhance your training by adding expert advisors indicators
and scripts to your trading systems.
This in turn allows you to generate lots of money by automating the whole extent or part of your analysis.
And this is actually called algorithmic trading when you substitute part of the decision making process
that you perform manually with a piece of software which can either be an indicator script or an expert
device.
In this beginner's course we will be focusing on learning and developing basic scripts and expert advisers
won't be looking at indicators as yet because this is this is a beginner's course and we want to just
learn the basics of algorithmic trading.
But we will successfully develop some scripts which do analysis some scripts which perform actions and
also will work on creating I'll own fully functional standalone expert adviser which will be able to
trade in our Instead of us.
And so that's that's all for this Tauriel I hope to see you in the next one.
And until then happy coding.