(techno music)
(typewriter keys being struck)
[Instructor] All right, so to end off this section
I'm just gonna have you practise
inserting and deleting notes
from a binary search tree.
And we're just gonna go through this using slides,
because that's what you really have to understand.
We've already coded insert and delete
and get and getting the minimum value
and getting the maximum value and traversing the tree.
I thought it would be good just to practise
inserting and deleting values.
And so we're gonna start with this tree
and what I suggest you do is just make a copy of this
using pen and paper, and then we're gonna practise
inserting and deleting nodes.
So, we're gonna go through a series of insertions
and then we'll go through a series of deletions.
So the first thing I wanna do
is have you insert node 28 into this tree.
So, we have the value 28 and we want to insert it
into this binary search tree.
And so, go ahead and do that.
And pencil in, and I say pencil
'cuz you're gonna be deleting nodes later,
so, use pen or pencil, whatever's gonna work best for you.
Go ahead and pencil in node 28
where it should belong in this tree.
So pause the video now and do that.
Restart the video when you've inserted node 28.
Okay, I hope you've inserted the node.
So we come in and 28 is greater than 25
so we're gonna go to the right.
28 is greater than 27, so we're gonna go to the right.
28 is less than 30, so we're gonna go to the left.
And 28 is less than 29, so we're gonna go to the left.
And so 28 should go here.
And so, this is what our tree looks like
after we've inserted node 28.
Remember, for a binary search tree we go to the left,
if the value is smaller than the node we're checking.
And we go to the right if the value is larger
than the node we're checking.
All right, so we're gonna keep 28 in our tree,
and now I want you to insert the value 16.
So pause the video and give that a try.
Okay, I hope you were able to do that one.
So we're gonna come in.
16 is less than 25 so we're going to go to the left.
16 is less than 20, so we're going to go to the left.
16 is greater than 15 so we're gonna go to the right.
And 16 is less than 17, so we're going to go to the left.
And so 16 should be inserted as 17's left child.
And so, that's where 16 belongs.
All right, so 16's still in our tree,
except I forgot to colour it white.
So pretend that's white now.
And we're gonna insert now the value 23.
So pause the video and give that a try.
All right, so we come in.
23 is less than 25, so we go to the left.
23 is greater than 20 so we go to the right.
And 23 is greater than 22 so we go to right.
And so, we're going to insert 23 as the right child of 22.
And so, there we go.
All right, so let's do 14.
Pause the video and insert the value 14 into the tree.
All right, so we're gonna come in.
14 is less than 25, so we go to the left.
14 is less than 20, so we go to the left.
14 is less than 15, so we go to the left.
So we're gonna insert 14 here.
And that shouldn't be a surprise,
because 14 is the lowest value.
So it's the minimum value, and as we know,
to find the minimum value in a binary search tree,
you start at the root
and you just keep travelling along the left edges
until you hit a node that doesn't have a left child.
And so, it shouldn't be a surprise that 14,
being the minimum value,
is gonna be inserted as the left child of 15.
And so, there we go, 14 has been inserted.
Okay, so our tree's pretty crowded now.
So it's time to delete some nodes.
So, I want you to delete the node with the value 28.
Pause the video and give that a try.
Okay, well 28 is a leaf node.
That's the easiest case.
We just need to knock it off.
So basically, we just gnawl out 29's left child.
And so, there we go.
28 is gone and our tree, otherwise, stays the same.
So now, let's delete the value 22.
What will the tree look like after 22 has been deleted.
Give that a try.
Okay, well 22 only has one child.
So when we're deleting a node with one child
that child basically just replaces the deleted node.
So it's gonna become the new right child.
23 will become the new right child of 20.
And so, this is what the tree is going to look like
after we've deleted 22.
All right, so now I want you to delete 15
and I want you to look down the right subtree
for the replacement value.
So, delete 15 and find the replacement value
in the right subtree.
Pause the video and give that a try.
Okay, so this time 15 has two children.
And so, we need to find a replacement value
and, we can do that by looking to the left
or the right, but as I said, always be consistent.
If you're writing a delete method
always go to the left or always go to the right.
So, we're going to go to the right.
And so, because we're looking at the right subtree,
we want to find the smallest value in the right subtree.
And we want to do that because
then when we move that value up in place of 15,
we know that everything remaining behind
will still be greater than whatever's here,
'cuz we're taking the smallest value.
And so we know that that characteristic
of a binary search tree will be preserved.
And so we're gonna start at 15.
We're gonna move to the root of it's right subtree,
and then we basically want to find
the minimum value in the right subtree.
And so we're gonna travel down the left edges
until we hit a node that doesn't have a left child.
And in this case, it's not gonna take us very long,
'cause that would be 16.
And so we're going to, replace the value of 15 with 16,
and then of course, we need to delete this node.
And so, that's what the tree is gonna look like
after the deletion.
15 is gone, the node 16 here is gone,
and the value of where 15 used to be is now 16.
Okay, so now I want you to delete 27,
and once again, I want you to look for the replacement
in the right subtree.
So give that a try.
Okay, so we're gonna look for the replacement node
in the right subtree.
So we're gonna start at 27, the node we want to delete.
We're gonna move to the right subtree
and then, we want to find the minimum value
in the right subtree,
and that, of course, means travelling down the left edges,
until we hit a node that doesn't have a child
and we're gonna hit that node very quickly.
It's node 29, and so we're gonna move 29
up to where 27 is and delete it from here.
And so, this is what our tree will look like.
Okay, so I've added some new nodes into the tree.
And I want you to delete 40,
and as usual, look down the right subtree.
And so, pause the video and delete 40.
All right, so we're gonna look down the right subtree.
So we're gonna start at 40
and we're gonna move to the root
and then we want to find the minimum value
and we do that by travelling down the left edges.
But, 46 doesn't have any left edges,
so this is our minimum value in the right subtree.
And so, we want to replace 40 with 46
and in this case, we can see that 46 has a right child.
And since it's the minimum value
it can only have a right child
and it's perfectly safe to just drag this entire subtree up.
And so, 46 is gonna come up here
and it's subtree ia going to come along for the ride.
And so, after the deletion,
we'll have 46, 66, 60 and 62 and, so basically,
we've just taken this entire subtree
and replaced 30's right child with this subtee
and the new left child of 46 will be 34.
And so, this is what our new tree looks like.
And, it's still a binary tree.
Everything to the left is smaller than 30.
Everything to the right is larger than 30.
And, everything to the left of 46 is smaller than 46
and everything to the right is larger.
And so, that's it for practising insertions and deletions.
If you understand how to do those,
then you understand binary search trees.
I'll see you in the next section.