(light music)
(keyboard clicking)
All right, so in a few videos
we're going to start looking at sort algorithms,
and it would be really helpful for us to be
able to compare the performance of one algorithm
against another algorithm.
So you might think that one way we could do that
is to implement one algorithm and then put a line of code
that records the start time and then run the implementation
and then have a line of code that records the end time
and we can subtract the start time from the end time
and we get the running time of the implementation
of that algorithm.
And then we do the same for another algorithm
and we just compare the two.
Sounds great in theory but unfortunately
that's not a good way to do it because of hardware.
Hardware is going to influence the running time
of these algorithms.
I mean, think about it.
If we were to run an implementation on a desktop computer
that was built in 2017 and compare that
to the running time of the exact same implementation
on a desktop computer that was built 20 years ago
and perhaps is an old Pentium computer,
or we'll even go further than that and run
the implementation on a Commodore 64 or something like that,
obviously the implementations are going to run slower
on the older hardware.
And if we were to run an implementation on a super computer,
it's going to run really, really fast even though
it might be a really inefficient algorithm.
So we need a more objective measure
than just the straight running time.
And so what we do is we look at the number of steps
that it takes to execute an algorithm.
And we call this the time complexity.
There are two types of complexity:
there's time complexity which is the number
of steps involved to run an algorithm;
and then there is memory complexity which is the amount
of memory it takes to run an algorithm.
Now these days, because memory is so cheap,
memory complexity isn't such an issue.
So these days we mainly concern ourselves
with time complexity.
So we're interested in how many steps does it take
to run an algorithm?
Now when we're doing we like to look at the worst case.
Looking at the best case doesn't help us because
you're rarely gonna have the best case.
Now we could take the average case
but that's not gonna tell us the absolute
worst time complexity.
So if we wanna know what the upper bound is,
like what is the absolute worst that we can expect
from this algorithm, it's much more helpful
to look at the worst case.
So it's helpful to compare the worst case scenario
for one algorithm against the worst case scenario
for the other algorithm.
And so that's how we do it.
So let's look at the algorithm
that I have up on this screen.
We've already looked at an algorithm for making tea
so now we're going to look at one little step.
And we have an algorithm for adding sugar to tea.
So in this algorithm step one is to get the bowl
containing the sugar.
Step two is to get a spoon.
So we're assuming we have loose sugar here.
Step three is to scoop out sugar using the spoon,
and step four is to pour the sugar
from the spoon into the tea.
And of course if you want more than one teaspoon
then you have to repeat steps three and four
until you've added the desired amount of sugar.
Now we can see from this that the number of steps
that it's going to take to add sugar to your tea
is going to depend on how many sugars you want.
If you only want one sugar,
then this algorithm will run taking four steps.
But if you want two sugars,
it's going to take six steps because
you're going to have to repeat steps three and four.
So let's have a look at what happens
for the number of sugars.
So if you have one sugar, you just need to do four steps.
If you have two sugars, you're gonna need six steps.
If you want three sugars in your tea
you're gonna need eight steps because you're gonna
have to repeat steps three and four three times.
And if you want four sugars in your tea,
I'm sure most of us would have bailed by now,
but I do have a friend that I say takes
tea with her sugar rather than the other way around.
So she might actually make it down to row four.
If you want four sugars in your tea,
then you're gonna have to repeat
steps three and four four times.
And so you're going to take 10 steps
to put sugar in your tea.
So as we can see the number of steps
or the time complexity of our sugar algorithm
depends on how many sugars someone wants in their tea.
If they only want one sugar,
it just takes them four steps.
But if they want four sugars, it's gonna take them 10 steps.
So the time complexity gives us an idea
of how an algorithm will perform as the number of items
it has to deal with grows so as we can see
as the number of sugars this algorithm has to add
to tea increases, the number of steps required increases.
Another way of saying this is it tells us
how well an algorithm will scale.
So how well will it do when it has to deal
with 100 items, versus 1,00 items, versus a million items?
And we'll see that some algorithm will scale really well
and others not so well.
The more items there are,
the more algorithm's performance will degrade.
Now the big O notation is a way of expressing
the complexity related to the number of items
that an algorithm has to deal with.
And it's written as a capital O
followed by an expression in parenthesis.
So let's work out the big O value for our sugar algorithm.
So it's conventional to designate the number of items by N.
So in our case the number of desired sugars will equal N.
And as we can see from our table
and from our algorithm back here,
the number of steps is going to be two times N plus two.
And the reason for that is you have to repeat
steps three and four for the number of sugars you have,
so that's the two N.
And then the plus two is steps one and two.
Now as we've seen when N grows the number of steps grows.
Now notice that the two,
this is gonna be hard for me to say,
but the two two's in the two N plus two,
they remain constant.
They don't change as the number of sugars changes.
And because of that we don't consider them
when we're coming up with the big O value.
It's N that's influencing the number of steps.
And so in this case we say that the time complexity
for this algorithm is O of N.
And because the time complexity for this algorithm
increases in a linear fashion,
we consider this to be linear time complexity.
So a time complexity of O of N is linear time complexity.
And if we go back to our table,
we'll see that we go four, six, eight, 10
and of course we're gonna keep going, 12, 14, 16, 18.
That's a linear progression, it's a linear sequence.
And so the time complexity of our adding sugars
to tea algorithm is O of N.
So these are the big O values
we're going to mainly see in this course.
You have O of one which is constant time complexity,
O of log N which logarithmic time complexity,
and that's log to the base two not log to the base 10.
So it's log to the base two N.
O of N which is linear time complexity.
And then we have O of N log N
which is N times log to the base two N,
and that's N log star N time complexity.
And we have O of N squared
which is quadratic time complexity.
You'll see that when we look at sort algorithms,
the first few we look at will actually be quadratic.
And the order in the table is in best to worst.
So if you can use a constant time algorithm
that's way better than a quadratic time algorithm.
Now as I said, you heard me say O of one and O of N,
that's how you say it.
O of and then the value that's in brackets.
Now when I was taught about big O notation,
for some reason the person teaching the information
instead said O to the one, O to the N.
And so that was drilled into my head
and it's a hard habit to break.
The big O notation, it's the sort of thing
that you don't have to say most of the time
you're reading it or you're writing it.
So the correct way of saying it is O of one, O of N,
O of log N, et cetera.
But I am going to slip up occasionally
and say O to the because that's what was
drilled into my head when I learned this material.
And so if you hear me say that,
if you hear me say O to the one,
O to the N squared, et cetera,
just convert that to O of in your mind.
Chances are you're never gonna actually have
to say this ever.
In my entire career I never once had to say O of whatever.
In fact in my entire career we never once discussed
big O notation.
I'm sure that depending on what type of
application you're working on,
that might be different for you.
But in my career big O notation was sort of a non-issue.
It was never something that we needed to worry about.
And so if you're talking to somebody
and they ask you about big O notation
or big O values say O of.
And if you hear me say O to the in this course,
just convert that to O of.
So now let's go over to Wikipedia
so we can actually see the big O values
plotted on a graph so we can get a visual idea
of the differences between the different big O values.
So I'm here at Wikipedia and you'll find this image
in the Wikipedia article about big O notation
and I've also included a link directly to this image
in the Resources section.
This image was created by user Cmglee.
And so this is a graph of some of the big O values,
and this represents how an algorithm would degrade.
Along the X axis we have the input size,
so the number of items;
and along the Y axis we have the number of steps.
So you can see for a constant algorithm,
O of one which is in this violet colour,
as the number of items increases
the number of steps remains the same.
This is just a straight horizontal line.
So here's the number of steps.
And this line isn't climbing at all
as the number of items increases.
So that's the best case.
If you can get a constant algorithm,
that's pretty much the best you can do.
The next best thing is logarithmic.
And notice that it's log to the base two.
And we're gonna see some algorithms
that have this time complexity.
This is in a dark blue.
And as we can see it kind of starts off climbing.
So as the number of items increases,
the number of steps goes up.
But then it levels off and it's pretty much
almost constant time.
If you can achieve log
to the base two N time complexity, that's great.
We're not gonna see any with,
I think that's square root, the square root of N,
but we are going to see some linear algorithms.
We've already discussed linear time.
And so here's the graph, this is in green.
So if you have 10 items you're gonna take 10 steps,
20 items, 20 steps.
It doesn't have to be an exact match like this.
It's more pattern of growth.
So if the pattern of growth is linear,
it's a linear sequence, then the graph
is gonna look like this.
And this is what it looked like for our
adding sugar to tea algorithm.
We didn't start at zero steps.
If you want no sugars, obviously there's zero steps,
but our algorithm is for adding sugar to your tea,
so that assumes that there's going to be sugar added.
And so the minimum number of steps for one sugar is four.
So we'd actually start at four
but then we go six, eight, 10, et cetera.
And so it's a linear progression.
Now this orange line is N log to the base two N.
So here we're multiplying log to the base two N
by the number of items.
And we're gonna see some algorithms
that have this time complexity.
This is worse than linear because as you can see
the number of steps required climbs much more sharply.
And then of course worse than that is quadratic
and we're gonna start out looking at sort algorithms
that actually have a time complexity of quadratic time.
And this is an even sharper climb.
This is the red dashed line.
And so if you have 10 items it's gonna take 100 steps
because that's gonna be 10 squared.
And so if you have a quadratic algorithm,
this quickly degrades.
1,000 items is already a million steps.
So keep this graph in mind as we look
at the different algorithms.
The absolute best is constant time.
If you can't get that, you want logarithmic time,
log to the base two N.
Linear time is still pretty good
once you start getting up into N log N and N squared.
You can see that the number of steps required
rises sharply as the number of items increases.
In conclusion, this is what you have to remember really,
a big O notation gives us a way of comparing
the time complexity of different algorithms
in an objective manner, in a hardware-independent manner.
Okay, so that's it for now for the big O notation.
We'll revisit this as we go through the course.
So I'll see you in the next vide.