(bright music)
(whooshing)
(clickety clack clack click)
Alright, so, the first challenge for this section
is gonna be pretty easy.
Gonna be a warm up challenge.
What I want you to do is modify the merge sort algorithm
so that it sorts the integers in descending order.
Now, I want you to sort the usual example array
that we used for most of the sort algorithms
and in the resources section there's a start project
that basically contains what we did
in the merge sort implementation video.
So, it has the array and then the call to merge sort
and then it has the merge sort code
except the merge sort code that we implemented
sorts the integers in ascending order.
So, I want you to modify the implementation
so that it sorts the integers in descending order.
I strongly encourage you to actually do these challenges.
Even if you struggle and you don't figure it out,
you're going to be a lot farther ahead by trying
than you will be if you just click the next video button
and watch the solution.
So, give it a try and I'll see you in the solution video.