(cheerful electronic music)
(typing)
Alright, so in this video
we're gonna take a look at the Binary Search Algorithm.
Binary Search is pretty much the standard search algorithm.
But and there's a huge but, and this is really important,
it requires that the data that it's searching be sorted.
And so, you can only use the Binary Search Algorithm
on data that has been sorted.
And so, if you wanna use it to search an array
and the array has not been sorted
then you're gonna have to sort this, the array first
then you can use any of the sort algorithms
that we've looked at to sort the array.
And then you run the Binary Search on the sorted array.
And that goes for any data structure,
I mean, if you wanna use Binary Search on a link list
then you have to sort the values in that link list first.
Now, if you know your application is going
to be using Binary Search to do a lot of searches
then what you might consider doing is
inserting items into whatever data structure you're using,
so that they're always in sorted order.
So rather than sorting the array or whatever you're using
every single time you wanna run a binary search,
if you know you're going to be running a lot of searches
then it might be better to just always make sure
that the values in the data structure are always sorted,
then you can do that when you insert values.
Okay, so what is Binary Search?
Well, the way it works and we'll use an array as an example
is that it chooses the element in the middle of the array,
and it compares it against the search value.
Now, if the element in the middle of the array equals
the search value we're done, right?
Because we found the value we're looking for.
Now, if it doesn't equal the search value then we have more
work to do.
So if the element is greater than the search value
then we're gonna search the left half of the array,
and the reason for that is that the values are sorted
and so let's say the middle of the array is at index five.
And so we compare the search value against the elemented
index five,
well if that element is greater than the search value
then we know that the value we're searching for has to be in
indexes zero to four.
Because the data is sorted and so if the value at index five
is greater than the value we're searching for that means
that the values from indexes six up to the end of the array
are gonna be greater than the one we're looking for.
So, we need to search the left half of the array
that's where all the values that are less than the middle
element are located.
On the other hand, if the middle element
is less than the value that we're looking for
then we wanna search the right half of the array
because if the elemented array index five is less
than the value we're looking for that means
all the elements from position zero to four again,
also gonna be less because the array is sorted
and so we know that the value
we're looking for has to be at in index six
or later on in the array.
And so, what we do is we compare the element against
the middle value and then depending
what we find if the values are equal, we're done,
if they're not, we're then going to just focus on
the left part of the array or the right part of the array.
And then we rinse and repeat, we do the same thing.
So, if we're gonna focus on the left part of the array,
we take the middle element in that left part of the array,
and we compare it against the search value
if the element in the middle of the left array is greater
then we're gonna look at the left part of the left array
and if it's less than we're gonna look at the right part
of the left array.
And we keep doing this, dividing each partition up
until we're gonna end up ultimately
either hitting our search value
or we'll end up in the end with getting down
to a one element partition,
and that partition is gonna equal our search value.
So, with each step we're dividing the array in half.
It's very similar to what we were doing with merge-sort.
So at each set we're partitioning the array in half,
until the middle element of the partition we're searching
equals the value we were looking for.
And so, because there's a rinse and repeat step,
we can write Binary Search recursively.
So let's look at our familiar array
and it's sorted because remember,
you can only use Binary Search on sorted data,
so the array has been sorted.
Maybe we used merge-sort, maybe we used quick-sort,
maybe we used insertion-sort, doesn't matter,
we've sorted the array.
And let's say we wanna define the value one.
So our start index will be zero
and our end index will be seven for the entire array.
The end index will always be one greater
than the last valid index,
and we get the midpoint by dividing start plus end by two,
and so our midpoint, our middle element,
is going to be located at position three.
And then we compare one against seven,
and seven is greater than one,
and so we know that our search value must be located
in this area because the array is sorted, right?
So, if our search value is less than the value here,
it's not gonna be located up here
because this array is sorted and so we know
that all of the values from four to the end of the array
are equal to or greater than this guy.
If we compare one against the value at three,
and the value was greater we know that one must be located
in front of the middle element.
And so, we're now gonna look at the left half of the array.
So our start will be zero and our end
will equal the midpoint from here,
and so our end will be three,
rememeber the end is always one greater
than the partition we wanna look at
so we're basically saying we're now gonna search
elements zero to two and we get the new midpoint
by adding start to end and dividing by two,
and so that's three over two,
so our new midpoint is one,
which is here, minus 15.
And so we're gonna compare one against minus 15.
Now minus 15 is less than one,
and so we know now that the value we're looking for must
be in this partition, not in the entire array
but in this partition, the value we're looking for
must be in the right half of this partition.
And so, we're gonna search the right half
and so, our start in this case is gonna be midpoint plus one
so our midpoint before was one and so we're gonna add
one to that so our start will be index two,
our end remains at index three,
and our midpoint is two plus three,
which is five over two, which is two.
Basically, because our start is two and our end is three,
we have a partition at one, so it's not surprising
that array two equals the value we're looking for.
And we have found our value.
Now in this example, we did as many steps as we would've
done for Linear search but if we were looking for a value
up here it would've been a lot quicker.
Because we would've come in and we would've looked at here,
and said oh we're looking for 35, okay,
well we're just gonna look here now.
And so we skip all of this traversing
of the front part of the array.
And so, that's binary search.
It basically starts out by dividing the array
down the middle and then it always
looks at the middle element
and then depending on what the comparison result is
less than, greater than or equal to,
we've either finished or we're then only gonna focus on
the left side or the right side,
and then we run some repeat.
So middle element, and then only left side,
right side, etcetera.
So as I said at some point,
if you don't find the search value early on,
at some point, eventually you're gonna get down
to just one element in the partition and in fact
that's what happened in the example wwe just went through.
We can implement this recursively and the time complexity
is O(logn) because we just keep dividing the array in half,
and remember that will be O to the log base two n.
Okay, so that's how Binary Search works.
Let's go ahead and implement it.
I'll see you in the next video.