So at the end of the last video
we learned that the way we're resizing the array
won't work for a wrapped queue.
That when we resize the array for a wrapped queue,
we have to reset the queue,
and bring all of the elements
back to the front of the array.
So we're going to wanna copy the elements from,
if we look at this comment here,
we're gonna copy the elements
from the front to the end of the array.
So we'll copy Mike and Bill
into positions zero and one in the new resized array,
and then we're gonna copy from the beginning of the array
to the last element in the queue.
So Mike and Bill will be followed with Jane and John,
and then the back will be the next available position
in the new array.
So let's modify the code in here.
So the first thing we're gonna do
is save off the current size,
because we're gonna need it later.
So I'm gonna say int num items equals size.
Because we're gonna have to use that later
after we've resized the array,
and we're gonna use this to set the back pointer.
So, creating the new employee array, nothing new there.
We're gonna double the length,
and we're also going to, at the end of everything,
assign newArray to queue,
but we're gonna change what we're doing here.
So, the first thing we wanna do
is copy the elements from the front to the end of the array.
So I'll say System.arraycopy,
and we wanna copy from the queue.
We wanna start at front,
because what we wanna be doing
is copying starting at Mike.
We're gonna copy into newArray, into position zero,
because in the new array we're gonna be copying
the front of the queue back to position zero.
And we want to copy queue.length minus front items.
So, if we take a look here, Mike is at front,
and the length of the queue is five.
So, we're gonna copy five minus three,
because front is three, which equals two items.
And that's how many items we have here.
And so this array copy is gonna take Mike and Bill,
and copy them into the front of the new array.
So, that's resetting the queue to the front.
And then, the second part of this is,
we have to copy Jane and John behind Mike and Bill.
So we're gonna say System.arraycopy.
We're gonna copy from the queue again,
but this time we're gonna start at position zero,
at the front of the array.
We're gonna copy into the new array,
but we don't wanna copy into position zero.
We're gonna copy into queue.length minus front.
Now, these two calculations are the same.
We saw here that we figured out we had two items,
and so we've copied those two items into the new array,
and so we wanna start copying
at position the number of items,
because that position will be two.
If we have two items from the front of the queue
to the end of the array in the original queue,
then we'll have copied those two items into zero and one.
If we have three items, they'll have been copied
into zero, one, two, et cetera.
And then, how many items do we wanna copy?
Well, back items, right?
Because the queue is wrapped at the front,
back points to the first available position.
Back basically always equals the number of items
that have been wrapped to the front.
And that's our two array copies.
So, the array copies are taking this, and producing this.
So, they're unwrapping the queue,
and resetting the front of the queue to zero.
So, we have two things left to do.
After we've assigned the new array to queue,
we need to set the front and the back field.
So the front will now be zero,
and the back will be the number of items.
We can't just call size here,
because back is still set to the old back.
So, you know, we've set front to zero,
and back would still be sitting at two.
So, our back position is no longer valid.
And that's why we had to save off the size here
and use it to assign back.
So, when we come out of this code,
front and back are now valid, they've been updated,
and this queue would now look like this.
So, if the queue has been wrapped, it's been reset.
Now, if the queue has not been wrapped,
and we're resizing it, this still works,
but we'll be doing a redundant copy here.
So, it's an unnecessary copy,
and if we wanted to we could check for that.
We could put an if here, and try to figure out
if the queue has been wrapped or not.
But I'm just gonna leave it here,
because when you're using a circular queue,
unless you're only ever adding stuff,
and you add a whole tonne of stuff before you remove it,
most of the time the queue's gonna wrap at some point.
Okay, so, now that we've properly resized our queue,
and we've updated this code, that's the updated add method.
So, let's take a look at the remove method.
This isn't as complicated.
The add method is actually the method
that's probably the most difficult to understand.
Remove, we don't have to make that many changes.
We're still going to throw an exception
if the queue is empty.
We're still going to return the employee at queue front,
and we're still gonna clean up queue front.
We're still going to reset the queue,
if the size is zero.
So, if we've pulled off the only employee in the queue,
it's safe for us to just set front and back
back to zero.
But, now we have to worry about wrapping front.
Because if we go back to this situation here,
let's say we pull off Mike.
And so, front gets incremented to four,
and then we pull off Bill.
Well, at this point, we want front to wrap around
to zero, to Jane.
And so, we have to check for that case.
And so, we're gonna have an else here, and we're gonna say,
if there are still items on the queue,
then if front equals queue.length,
and that should be a double equals there.
That's why the compiler's squawking at me.
Then, we wanna wrap front to the beginning.
Now remember, when we're doing this test,
we already incremented front.
So, if we pulled Mike off, we'll increment front to four.
And then we pull Bill off, we'll increment front to five,
and then we're gonna do this test.
And we're gonna say,
is front equal to the length of the queue?
Yes, it is, in this case,
because the length of the queue is five.
And so, we're gonna wrap front back to zero.
If front was less than the length of the queue,
then that means there's more space beyond here.
So, it's safe to have front sitting here,
it's not going to be an index out of bounds exception.
And that's it, that's it for remove.
Told you it would be easier, a lot more easier than add.
Add is actually, as I said,
the method that's probably gonna be the most difficult
to understand, and required the most changes.
We don't have to change the peek method at all.
We're still gonna throw an exception
if the queue is empty.
Otherwise we just want to return the employee
at the front of the queue.
Now, our size method is gonna have to change,
because subtracting back from front won't work anymore.
It's possible that front will be larger than back.
And, if that's the case,
we'll end up with a negative number.
And so we're gonna have to test here
whether the queue has wrapped.
And the way that we can do that,
is we can say if front is less than or equal to back,
then we know the queue hasn't wrapped,
because back is still greater than front.
And so front is more towards the front of the array
than back is.
So we don't have the situation where we have
front towards the back of the array,
and back towards the front of the array.
And so, if front is less than or equal to back,
the queue has not wrapped.
And so in that case,
we can just do what we were doing before.
So I'll just copy that, and put it in here.
If that's not the case,
then we need to return back minus front,
plus queue.length.
So, what's that doing here?
Well, let's take a look at our two situations
back up here.
So, if the queue hasn't wrapped,
so if the queue hasn't wrapped, we have this situation,
and then we can just say four minus zero equals four.
We have four items on the queue.
But if the queue has wrapped, in this case front is three,
and back is two, and the length of the queue is five.
We're gonna still say back minus front.
So, that's gonna be two minus three,
that gives us minus one.
And then we're gonna add the length of the queue,
which is five, and that'll give us four.
And indeed, we have four elements on the queue.
So, that's how this calculation will work.
By adding the length of the queue,
we can adjust the negative number
to the actual number of items on the queue.
And that's all we have to do for the size method,
nothing too complicated.
Now, the last method we have to change is our printQueue,
because, obviously, printing the queue
from front to back now isn't going to work,
because back could be less than front.
And so, we're gonna do something similar
to what we did for size.
We're gonna check whether front
is less than or equal to back, because if that's the case,
the queue is not wrapped.
And so, if that's the case,
we'll just do what we were doing before.
If the queue has wrapped,
then we'll print the queue in two pieces.
First, we'll print this piece.
So, we'll print from front to the end of the queue,
and then we'll print this piece.
So, we'll print from the beginning of the queue to back.
And so, I'm gonna copy this here,
and plunk it into our printQueue method.
So, if front is less than or equal to back,
and if it is, we're gonna do what we were doing before,
because the queue hasn't wrapped.
Otherwise, we're gonna say for int i equals front,
i less than queue.length, i plus plus,
and we'll just print whatever is at position i.
So, I'll just copy and paste this line in here.
So, this code here will print
whatever's at the front of the queue
to the end of the array.
And then after we've done that,
you wanna say for int i equals zero, i less than back,
i plus plus, and we'll print what's at queue[i].
And so, this code will be printing Jane and John.
And that's it, we have now updated our array queue class
so that it's a circular queue.
I think probably the add
is the most difficult one to understand,
so if you're kinda struggling with the code,
go through these cases with pen and paper.
I think it'll make the code clearer.
Okay, so now that we've updated to a circular queue,
let's go back to the main method,
and we have this adding two employees,
and then removing, adding, removing, adding.
Now, we saw with the non-circular queue
that when we came to add Jane Jones, we resize the array.
We hit the break point that was resizing the array,
because we'd already added five employees,
and so, when we came in to add the sixth employee,
the back pointer was equal to queue.length,
and so we resized the array.
But this time, we're gonna check
for queue.length minus one.
So, this should never happen now,
because we're checking the size.
And the size is never going to be greater than two, right?
Because we only ever have two employees on the array.
And so I'm gonna put a break point in here.
And so, if we hit this, we're trying to resize the array.
And I just wanna make sure all the other code
is commented out.
And so, this time, we do not expect
the array to be resized.
We don't expect this break point to be hit.
So, let me run the debugger, and sure enough,
the break point was not hit.
We finished the process.
We have Bill and Jane on the queue,
which is what we expect.
And we did not try to resize the array.
And so, we've improved our implementation,
because with the previous implementation,
80% of the array was empty.
We came in and we were resizing it.
All right, let's go back to our main method,
and I'm going to comment out this code,
and let's run the code that we ran
to test our non-circular implementation.
So, the first thing we'll do is add five employees.
And then print the queue.
So, let's run.
And we have our five employees
in the order they were added.
Now, if I were to put a break point here,
which I've already done,
if I run this in the debugger,
we expect the array to be resized.
Because remember that now we're checking the size
against queue.length minus one.
And so, when we've added Jane, John, Mary, and Mike,
we'll have four employees on the queue.
When we come in to add Bill,
four will equal queue.length minus one,
and then we have to resize.
And we went through why we have to do that.
We have to do it at that point because
we can't wrap back to zero,
because zero is occupied by Jane.
And so, if you've forgotten that,
maybe you watched the last video a while ago,
go back and watch the last video
if you're unsure as to why we're resizing
when we only have four employees on the queue.
So, we are resizing when we still have
an empty space in the array,
but it's a lot better than resizing
when 80% of the array is empty.
With this implementation,
we'll only ever resize when we only have one space left.
So let me run the debugger now.
And, as we expected, we're resizing the array.
And we can see that the queue.length is five,
and back is four.
Queue.length is five, and if I look at where we are
in the main method, sure enough,
we're coming in and we're trying to add Bill.
And so that's all working as we expected.
I'll just tell the debugger to finish the run,
and then I'm gonna shut this down.
All right, so let's remove two employees,
and then we'll print the queue again.
I'll comment out this printQueue, and do this one.
And so we expect to see Mary, Mike, and Bill
remaining on the queue.
And sure enough, there's Mary, Mike, and Bill.
Okay, so let's peek at Mary, I think that's what we did,
in the other video.
So I'll just uncomment this System.out.println peek.
Let's run.
And, this is the print out from this printQueue,
and then we peek at Mary,
so that's all still working great.
Okay, so I'm gonna comment these out,
and then we're gonna remove
the remaining three employees on the queue.
And, I'm gonna uncomment this printQueue down here,
because we wanna see that there's nothing on the queue.
So, let's run, and we don't expect to see anything printed.
That's good, and nothing nasty happened.
We didn't get any exceptions.
So now let's try removing the sixth employee.
Let's see what happens there.
We should get a no such element exception now.
And we do, at line 43,
so everything's working as we're expecting.
Let's comment that out,
and now let's add Mike onto the queue.
And, that'll just show that when we took
the last employee off the queue,
our front and back was set correctly.
So let's go ahead, and there's Mike on our queue.
So, our circular queue implementation is working.
So now that we know that our implementation is working,
lemme just uncomment, rather, comment all this code again,
and let me uncomment the first code we ran,
because this is the case
where we're actually gonna wrap the queue.
We don't actually wrap the queue here,
because we're adding five employees in a row,
and so we end up resizing the queue,
rather than wrapping it.
As we saw when we ran the debugger.
But let's what happens when we wrap the queue, here.
And I think we're gonna wrap it,
I'm not actually sure where.
So, let's put two break points in here,
and then I'm gonna remove this break point.
And, we'll run in the debugger, and we'll see where we wrap.
I would expect it to wrap on one of these employees,
probably Jane, but let's run.
At this point, we've added Jane and John,
and then we've removed Jane, we added Mary,
we removed John, we've added Mike.
We step into this method,
so I'm going to step into it.
So, now we're in our add method,
so we can take a look at what our queue looks like.
So here's our queue.
And you'll see that we only
have one employee on the queue at this point.
Because back here, we've added Jane and John,
we removed Jane, we added Mary, we removed John,
we've added Mike, we remove Mary.
So by the time we're at the call now
where we're adding Bill,
and at this point only Mike is on the queue.
So we shouldn't resize,
so I'm going to step over that line,
and if we were going to resize,
it would have stepped into here.
And so all we do here is assign the employee
into the back of the queue.
And, if I go ahead and keep going through the code,
line by line, we'll test whether back
is less than queue.length minus one.
At this point, back is four,
and queue.length minus one is four,
and so this test should fail.
And so at this point we're gonna wrap the queue.
So, let's look at our queue before we do that.
The first three elements are empty,
and then at position three we have Mike.
And at position four we have Bill.
So, what we're gonna do at this point,
because we have empty room at the front of the array,
is we're gonna wrap back to zero.
And so, we're doing that because back,
which is four, is not less than queue.length minus one,
which is also four.
And so if I step over this,
we should see back reset to zero.
And we do.
And so we have just wrapped the queue.
I mean, the elements in the queue aren't wrapped yet,
because there's nothing at zero,
but we'll take a look at what happens when we add Jane.
So, I'm gonna just hit run here.
All right, so we finished the call to adding Bill,
and then we remove Mike.
And now we're going to add Jane.
So, let's do the same thing we did before.
Let's step into our add method.
We don't expect to resize,
because we've wrapped the queue.
We've only got one employee, Bill, on the queue.
So, there's no need for us to resize the queue.
So let's keep going.
We're going to assign Jane into queue[back],
and back is zero, because we wrapped the queue.
So after we've done this, if you look at our queue now,
we'll see that we have employees at position zero,
that's Jane, and at position four, which is Bill.
And we'll see that the front of the queue is four,
because Bill's at the front of the queue.
And the back of the queue is currently zero,
because we haven't incremented it.
So now we're gonna do that test again,
is back less than queue.length minus one?
Well, yes, it is, because back is zero,
and so this time, we're just gonna increment back.
And there we go.
And so, when we leave this method,
front is four, back is one.
That's the next available position in the queue.
And we have Bill at position four,
and Jane at position zero.
So, we have wrapped our queue.
And because we're wrapping the queue,
we never come in here and resize the queue.
So because we're doing those alternate
adding, removing, adding, removing,
our array never gets full.
I'll just run the debugger now, to completion.
Okay, so that's the circular queue.
It's definitely an improvement
over a queue that does not wrap.
And that's all for implementing queues.
In the next video, we're going to take a look
at what's available in the JDK for queues.
So, I'll see ya there.