(upbeat music)
All right so in the last couple of videos
we looked at singly linked lists.
And now we're going to look at a double linked list,
or a doubly linked list.
With a doubly linked list we have nodes.
We have a head, we have a tail,
and each node in the list points to the next item
in the list and to the previous item in the list.
And so this time we have two reference fields,
this would be the next field,
and this would be the previous field.
And as you can see, for the first item in the list
the previous field will point to null
and the last item in the list,
the next field, will point to null.
Just like it does with singly linked lists.
And so as I said, this time we have references
to the head and the tail.
So in this list, Jane would be the head node
and Mike would be the tail node.
And so we can traverse the list from front to back.
From front to tail.
Or from tail to head.
And this time if we want to insert or remove a node
from the end of the list we can do it in constant time
because we have a pointer, or a reference,
to the tail of the list.
And so the advantage of using a doubly linked list
is you can work with the node at the front of the list
or the node at the end of the list in constant time.
But if you want to work with nodes in the middle of the list
you're gonna have the same problem
that a singly linked list had.
You're gonna have to traverse
from the head or from the tail,
find the node you wanna work with,
and in the worst case, that could be a linear operation.
So let's look at inserting and deleting nodes
into a doubly linked list.
So we have a little more work to do now
because we have two references that we have to manage,
the next and the previous.
And so if we wanted to insert Bill at the head
we'd start out the same way that we did
for inserting a node in a singly linked list.
We're gonna create a new node
for the new information.
And now we need to set Bill's next and previous fields.
So his next field is going to be whatever
is currently being pointed to by head.
So this is the same as when we did singly linked lists.
And his previous field is going to point to
whatever Jane's previous field is,
because if, if we're inserting Bill in front of Jane,
which is what we're doing, then Jane's previous field
is now going to become Bill.
And Bill's previous field will become whatever
Jane was pointing to.
Now if we're always inserting at the head,
that would mean that Bill's previous field
is going to point to null.
And now we have to fix Jane's previous field
because Bill is being inserted in front of her.
And so we want her previous field to now point to Bill.
And then we're going to assign the head field to Bill
because Bill becomes the new node
that's at the front of the list.
And so essentially when we insert a node
it's all about setting the references of the node
we're inserting and also updating the previous field
of the current head node.
And so after we've done all of that
this is what the list will look like.
So we didn't have to change Jane's next field
because when we're inserting in front of the list
what comes after Jane isn't going to change.
We had to update the previous field
because the previous field would have been pointing to null
but now it's going to point to the new node.
Because this previous field used to point here.
We're dropping a node in front of it.
And so we need to update the previous field.
And so we need to update Bill's previous field
to point to whatever Jane's previous field was pointing to.
And then on the final step we just set the head to Bill.
We go through the same steps if we were to insert
Bill somewhere else.
In that case we'd have more references to update.
But we'd go through a bunch of similar steps.
We basically would have to set Bill's previous and next
and then we'd have to update the next field
on the node in front and the previous field
of the node that comes after the one we inserted.
But as I said, when you're working with linked lists
you mainly wanna be focusing on working with
items that are at the front of the list,
or in the case of doubly linked lists
at the tail of the list.
If you start playing around with items in the middle
you're gonna lose the advantage of a linked list,
which is that inserting and deleting items from the front,
and in the case of a doubly linked list from the end,
you can do that in constant time.
Once you start playing with other nodes
you're getting up into potentially linear time.
Okay, so that's inserting a node at the head.
So let's go back to pour original list
just to remind ourselves of what it looked like.
So we're back to before we inserted Bill.
Now we're going to insert at the tail.
So once again, if we want to insert Bill at the tail
we'll create a new node called Bill.
And we want to assign the tail's next field
to Bill's next field.
Because if we go back to the previous slide,
if we're gonna drop Bill in here,
then whatever this guy is currently pointing to is next,
we're gonna want Bill to point to as next.
And so we're gonna assign the current tail's next field
to Bill's next field.
We're going to assign whatever, the current tail
to Bill's previous field because Mike is currently the tail.
And so if we put Bill in here we're gonna want
Bill's previous field to point to Mike.
So we want to point the previous field
to the current tail.
And then we're gonna assign, want to assign the tail's
next field to Bill.
And so Mike is the current tail.
And after the insertion, his next field,
we want him to point to Bill.
And finally we're gonna assign the tail to Bill.
And we can do that in constant time complexity.
It doesn't matter how many items are in the list.
You're gonna go through the same number of steps
to insert a new item at the tail.
And so after the insertion this is the situation we'll have.
So Mike's next field has been updated to Bill.
Bill's previous field has been set to Mike.
And his next field has been set to null.
Which is what Mike's next field used to be.
And the tail has now been set to Bill.
So let's say we want to delete from the head of the list.
So we wanna delete Jane.
Well let's look first at what we'd have to do.
Well we're gonna assign Jane to a remove node.
And then we wanna assign John's previous field
to whatever Jane's previous field is pointing at
because we're removing her.
So we wanna take that reference and go here.
And then we just need to move the head reference to John.
And that effectively moves, removes Jane from the list.
So we're gonna assign Jane to remove node.
We're gonna assign John's previous field
to Jane's previous field.
We're gonna assign head to whatever is at Jane's next field.
Because Jane's next field is pointing to John
so we're gonna assign John to head.
And then we're gonna return, remove node from the method.
And if we wanted to we could clean up Jane's next field
by setting it to null.
We don't have to but we could.
And once again, that'll be constant time complexity.
And so once we've gone through that, Jane will be gone.
And John will be the new head of the list.
So let's put Jane back in.
And let's look at removing the tail instead.
So this time we're gonna remove Bill.
And so how would we do that?
Well we're gonna wanna take Mike's next field
and point it to null.
And we're gonna wanna move the tail to Mike's.
So the tail will be moved
to the current tail's previous node.
And so we'll assign Bill to remove node.
We'll assign Mike's next field to Bill's next field.
We'll assign the tail to Bill's previous field,
which is Mike.
And then we'll return remove node from the method.
And once again we can do this in constant time.
It doesn't matter how many items are in the list.
If we wanna delete an item from the tail
we can do it using the same number of steps.
And so after the deletion, we'll have this situation
where Mike is now the tail.
And Bill is gone.
So in general to insert a node A
between nodes B and C, we want to plop A
between B and C.
And we're gonna assign A's next field to B's next field
because B's next field will be pointing to C.
And we're gonna put A between them.
So we want A's next field to point to C.
We're gonna assign A's previous field to C's previous field
because C's previous field will be B.
And we want A, we're gonna drop A in between them,
so we're gonna want A's previous field to be B.
And then we assign B's next field to A.
And C's previous field to A.
Now to do those four steps is constant time but,
unless we're doing this
at the beginning or the end of the list
we have to find nodes B and C first.
And we're gonna have to traverse the list to do that.
And so, the worst case for this is actually linear time.
O to the n.
Now to remove a node A from between B and C,
so this time we have nodes B followed by A followed by C,
we assign A to remove node.
We want C's previous field to now point to B
because we're removing A.
So we'll assign C's previous field to A's previous field.
Because A's previous field is pointing to B.
We want B's next field to point to C.
So we'll assign B's next field with whatever A's next field
is pointing at because A's next field
is currently pointing to C because it's in between them.
And then we just return A from the method.
Once again, these steps are constant time.
But, we have to find A first in the list.
So unless A is at the head or the tail,
we're gonna have to find it.
And so this, the worst case for this
would actually be linear time.
And that's it for looking at how doubly linked lists work.
Once again we're gonna do a simple implementation
of a doubly linked list.
We're gonna update our singly linked list implementation
to turn it into a doubly linked list.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'll see you in the next video.