Hello everyone and welcome to the control flow lecture for Skala programming in this lecture.
We're just going to be discussing if else and then else if statements.
Let's go ahead and jump to the Adam Ed. to get started.
All right.
Here I am at the Adam editor.
I've gone ahead and paste it and the commented code for the notes that go along.
This lecture just to show the overall format of if LCF and L statements and Skala if you're coming in
from a programming language such as Java or Python you're probably already familiar with this sort of
concept.
So maybe you can just review the notes.
If this lecturer goes a little slower than you'd prefer.
Well let's go ahead and review.
We'll say if have some sort of boolean statement in print CS and then curly brackets and some code you
want to run.
If this boolean is true then you can have LCF statements stacked on top of that.
Again a check for a boolean do something.
If none of these Blands ends up being true we finally have or L statements curly brackets no princes
check since it's the L statement.
And then we do something.
If none of the other booleans were true and as a quick note some Java developer sometimes like to put
in semi-colons in these blocks of code.
But developers typically omit those.
Let's go ahead and go ahead and clear this out and get started with just some simple examples so we
can work through north to run these examples I'm going to go ahead and click.
Plus here to open up a new terminal and I will start my Sparke shell.
That way we can load this Skull's script once we're ready let's go ahead and start with an if statement.
So I will say if and we'll start at the very basics.
So putting in true here that is that it's a lower case t Klear brackets.
And then we'll go ahead and say Prince Allen and we'll go in and say I will print if true and then notice
here we have a blue dot which means this file hasn't been saved.
It's going to do.
Control Yes.
You can do commands if you're on a Mac you actually save this and now in order to load this file we
just do Colan load and then go ahead and type in Scala programming the Scala enter and then we noticed
a result here says I will print if true which is exactly what we're looking for.
Let's go ahead and expand on this topic.
Maybe you're not going to put in a boolean here but you may do some sort of comparison operations such
as CheckFree quality.
If three is equal to three.
Go ahead and save that.
Let's change this to say three is equal to three.
And then we all go and run that code again.
I'm just sitting up on my arrow key to run that same line.
And it looks like that works as well.
Let's go ahead and show one final example of just an if statement using a value going to go ahead and
create a value x equal to a hello.
And then I will say instead of three is equal to three here we'll go ahead and check if X ends with
and noticed that be capitalized check ends with 0.
And then this print line statement is going to be a little different.
Well go ahead and say the value of x ands with 0.
Go ahead and save that.
And then we will run it.
And here we see the output X is the string that's equal to hello that comes from line 1 and we say that
the value X does in fact and with an 0.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and expand this to an if else statement.
So if this isn't true and we still want something to execute we'll go ahead and add an L statement.
So I will say else and here I can say Prince L-N and we'll say the value of x does not end with 0 save
that.
And if we just run this again we would expect the same output as last time.
But let's go ahead and change this.
X value is something like z z z.
Save it and then run this again.
And now notice that this statement ends up occurring and you should also note there's no print here
on the statement because there's no Boolean check.
That's if nothing else happened to be true.
And finally let's go ahead and expand this idea to if else if and else statements.
So for instance let's go ahead and I'm going to clear this just so he can start over we'll say vow of
person is equal to George.
So we have some person named George and I'm going to I'm going to check this person.
So I will say if person put that in parentheses if person is equal to for instance Sammy going to go
ahead and say print line welcome Sammy.
And then I'll say else if and this is going to be another blank check we'll say if this person is equal
to George we will go ahead and say Grant's line come George.
And then finally else if neither of those conditions are true they'll just say print line.
What is your name.
Let me make sure I spell that right.
What is your name questionmark.
Go ahead and save that and run it to make sure we have everything correct.
It looks like we said Welcome George.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and change the names.
We will say Sammy here save it and run it.
We should say welcome Sammy.
And then fine let's go ahead and put in a name that is not here.
We'll say Jose check this runs and it looks like strings cause I say what is your name.
Perfect.
And then finally I want to discuss logical operators so we discuss comparison operators such as equals
equals a lot of times you're going to actually want to check for multiple conditions maybe person is
Samie or person is equal to George or persons equal to Samie and persons equal to something else cetera.
So those are logical operators those and or and then not let me go ahead and review them with you right
now.
So we'll start off with the ANS and hopefully that you can read that contrasts.
And there in the comments but.
And.
And Skoll it is these two and symbols so I can say something like.
Let's go in and print the result prints.
Ellen so I will check if one is equal to two and if two is equal to two.
So think about this for a second.
What we expect to prints here we need both of these statements to be true in order for this to print
out true as a result.
So we have is 1 equal to 2.
That's false and is equal to two.
Well that's true.
So we expect this entire statement to be false.
Let's go ahead and run it.
It looks like we get false out.
So that makes sense so this is the ANS logical operator.
Let's go ahead and say this is on equal to 1 and the reason I'm just showing prints line is so we actually
see something in the output here.
Let's go in and run this again and here we get.
True.
So that's the and operator.
Let's go ahead and show the OR operator which is just going to be the pipe symbol.
So I can say print's Ellen will go ahead and check if one is equal to 2 or and this is the double pipes
here.
Two is equal to two and then we'll go and save that.
Let's go ahead and run it.
See what we get.
So we get true from this first line and then in this line we get true because one of these does happen
to be true.
So either or needs to be true and then fine let's go ahead and show you knots which is basically you
want this to not be true.
So I'm actually going to comment these lines out just to make it more clear what's going on.
And then I will say Prince L.N. and I'm going to start with.
Printing is one equal to one.
So in that case we would expect that to be true.
So I want the not operator to occur.
I just go ahead and I put an exclamation mark in front of the entire statement.
So if we go ahead and run this again we see false.
So we do not want this result here.
So is it not true etc..
That's going to be false.
In that case basically a way of checking for inequality if you want it to.
All right so that's basically it for logical operators and the if.
Else if n l statements.
Hopefully this was pretty straightforward.
And again you could have just read the notes if you're already familiar with these topics.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.