Welcome to the machine learning section of the course in this introduction section we're going to be
discussing a general overview of what machine learning is in this lecture.
Then in the next lecture we'll discuss machine learning and its specifics of spark and then we will
show you how to install Intel Ejay ID which is a full ID which may be helpful to you when conducting
Sparke with machine learning in this course.
We're going to be focusing on overall machine learning ideas and concepts not on specific algorithms
for each machine learning concept.
We will show you an example algorithm that you can easily switch out for the other algorithms available
in Spark's machine learning library.
Otherwise known as e-mail it.
The reason for this is because SPARC setup is actually tedious for M-L tasks due to the way that it's
distributed.
So you won't learn much by continually repeating the same mundane tasks for a different learning algorithm.
Instead SPARC makes it very easy for you to switch the algorithms with its pipeline object which we'll
be discussing in the next lecture.
Keep that in mind as you continue out through this machine learning section of the course.
For each specific machine learning algorithm that we do discuss we will have a brief theory discussion
for more information and background the machine learning algorithms.
I highly recommend the textbook introduction to statistical learning this book which is commonly referred
to as I SLR is a fundamental textbook for machine learning.
It's also available for free.
You can check out the resource link for more info.
Now let's get an overview of machine learning in general.
Let's discuss what is a machine learning machine learning is a method of data analysis that automates
analytical model building using algorithms that iterative Lee learn from data.
Machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly programs where to
look you may be wondering what is machine learning used for.
It's used in a lot of fields such as fraud detection real time ads on Web pages calculating new pricing
models financial modeling email spam filtering text sentiment analysis customer segmentation recommendation
engines and so much more.
And we're going to be exploring a lot of these cases with the machine learning portfolio projects presented
throughout this course.
Let's talk about the machine learning process in general.
First you need to acquire data so your data is going to have a lot of features based off whatever you're
trying to study.
Then you'll probably have to clean your data to get it into a nice format and you can use your panderers
skills in order to do that then you're going to split your data into test data and training data.
You will train your machine learning model on your training data and then you will test your model on
the test data which the model hasn't seen before.
And then you can iterate through this process try to tune your model to best fit both the training data
and then test well on the test data.
Then once it's ready you can deploy your model.
Let's talk about what is machine learning and a little more detail.
There are three main types of machine learning algorithms supervised learning algorithms unsupervised
learning algorithms and reinforcement learning.
Let's briefly describe each type before diving in a little more detail.
Supervised learning is when you have labelled data and are trying to predict a label based off of known
features unsupervised learning is when you have unlabeled data and are trying to group maybe together
similar data points based off of other features or doing some other unsupervised Machine Learning tests
which we'll get into later on.
And then finally the reinforcement learning algorithm tries to learn to perform an action based off
of previous experience.
Let's discuss supervised learning in a little more detail.
Again supervised learning algorithms are trained using labeled examples such as an input or the desired
output is known.
For example maybe have a piece of equipment that has data points labeled either for failed or are for
runs the learning algorithm receives a set of inputs along with the corresponding correct outputs and
then the algorithm learns by comparing its actual output with correct outputs to find errors.
It then modifies the model accordingly.
Through methods like classification regression prediction and gradient boosting supervised learning
uses patterns the values of the label on additional unlabeled data meaning train your model unlabeled
data and then later on you will feed your model unlabeled data and see if it can correctly predict the
label value.
Supervised learning is commonly used in applications where historical data predicts likely future events.
For example it can anticipate when credit card transactions are likely to be fraudulent or which insurance
customer is likely to file a claim or can even attempt to predict the price of a house based off of
different features for houses for which we have historical price data unsupervised learning is used
against data that has no historical labels.
The system is not told the right answer.
The algorithm must figure out what is being shown and the goal here is to explore the data and find
some sort of structure within that data or can also find the main attributes that separate customer
segments from each other.
Popular techniques include self organizing maps nearest neighbor mapping Kamins clustering and singular
value decomposition these algorithms are also used to segment text topics recommend items and identify
data outliers.
This will make a lot more sense when we actually perform unsupervised learning with Python.
For now we'll just leave it at that and know that it has unlabeled data reinforcement learning is often
used for robotics gaming and navigation with reinforcement learning the algorithm discovers through
trial and error which actions yield the greatest rewards this type of learning has three primary components.
The agent which is the learner or the decision maker the environment everything the agent interacts
with and then the actions what the agent can actually do or perform the objective is for the agent to
choose actions that maximize the expected reward over a given amount of time the agents will reach the
goal much faster by following a good policy.
So the goal in reinforcement learning is to learn the best policy.
All right so that's it for this lecture.
Coming up next is a discussion of machine learning specifics when using Sparke.
After that we'll show you how to install the Intel Ejay idea or idea interface.
Thanks everyone and I will see at the next lecture.