Hello everyone and welcome to the model evaluation section of the Course model evaluation is a fundamental
topic of understanding your model's performance and the machine learning in general.
If you want a more in-depth look at this topic go ahead and review chapter two of an introduction to
statistical learning in this section of the course we're going to be discussing the following topics
we'll review train splits and talk about holdout datasets.
Then we'll review parameter Gritz and talk about how we can actually use Scullin spark for model evaluation
then we'll have a brief discussion of the bias variance trade off and then we'll explore some documentation
examples and also code out through some Skala and spark examples.
Let's begin by talking about train splits which you've previously mentioned when discussing machine
learning in general bullets for the concept you will always train the machine learning algorithm on
some data but afterwards you're usually going to want some measure of how well it performed some sort
of performance metric and each made machine learning task or idea has different metrics for evaluation.
Let's show examples of just a few of them for regression tasks.
You have metrics such as R-squared values for Explain variance or other metrics such as the root mean
squared error for classification tasks.
Through your confusion matrix you usually get metrics such as precision accuracy or recall.
And then for clustering tasks you have things such as within sum of squares error.
These are definitely not all the metrics but just a few examples of them.
Well you could get these measurements or metrics using the same data.
You trained your model on that's usually not a good idea.
Your model has already seen this training data.
Meaning it's not a good choice for evaluating your model's performance.
What you really want to do is get these sort of metrics off test data which your model has not seen
yet.
And this is the main idea known as train test split you split your data into two sets your training
set and you're testing set.
You fit your model to the training set and evaluate it using the data hasn't seen before the test set
in expansion of this idea is the hold up dataset.
And this is separate from the training and test sets.
Basically in this process use the training data to fit your model and then you use the test set to evaluate
and adjust your model.
So now you have not just training and test sets of data but you have three sets of data.
The training set the test set and the holdout set and you can use that test set over and over again.
So you train on the training data fit your model use the test set to evaluate and then adjust back to
your original model and the training data to fix parameters or play around your model and see how you
can improve it.
Then before you deploy your model you check it against the holdout data set to get some final metrics
on performance.
And once you've tested it on the whole dataset there's no going back.
That's your final measure of how well your model perform or how well you expect your model to perform
right before you deploy your model onto some new data.
Now let's talk about parameter grids as I just mentioned usually needs some sort of parameters to adjust
in your machine learning algorithms.
And as we've already seen we can have optional parameters in machine learning algorithms of skull and
Sparke however many times it's difficult to know what are good values for these parameters.
And there's no right or wrong answer.
It really depends on your particular dataset.
So a lot of times people want to know what's a good value for parameter x or parameter y in this specific
machine learning algorithm and there's no real good answer in those situations.
However SPARC makes it possible to set up a grid of parameters to train across.
That way you can create multiple models train them across the grid and SPARC will report back which
model perform the best based off of some sort of evaluation metric or some performance metric.
Now let's talk about spark and Skala in a general sense for model evaluation Sparke makes all of these
processes generally easy with the use of three object types.
It has evaluators Parama grid builders and train validation split objects and later on this section
of the course we're going to have coded out examples where we're going to be exploring how to use these
object types to implement the ideas we just discussed an important aspect to understanding all of this
is the bhai's various tradeoff we won't directly explored spark and Skala because it pertains more to
theory than data engineering.
However with that being said let's take the time now to at least understand the concept so we can have
full context for this section of the course.
The bias variance tradeoff is the point where we are just adding noise by adding model complexity or
flexibility.
The training error goes down as it has to but the test error will start to go up.
The model after the bias tradeoff begins to overfit Let's go ahead and discuss this topic by imagining
a dartboard.
So it measures the center of this target or dartboard is a model that perfectly predicts the correct
values as we move away from the bullseye.
Our predictions will get worse and worse and we're going to go ahead and make a quadrant of low variance
versus high variance and high bias versus low bias.
So we can get an understanding of what the bias in variance terms mean generally imagine we can repeat
our entire model building process to get a number of separate hits on the target each represents an
individual realization of our model.
Given the chance variability in the training data we gather sometimes we will get a good distribution
of training data.
So we predict very well and we are close to the bull's eye.
While sometimes our training data might full of outliers or nonstandard values resulting in poor predictions
and these different realizations result in a scatter of hits on the target what were aiming for is something
for low bias and low variance.
But realistically you'll have to do is tradeoff variance or bias.
And here we can see in the quadrant of the target a low variance low bias model will predict correct
values on the bullseye a low bias high variance model will predict values around the bullseye.
But with a high degree of variance versus a high bias low variance model in that lower quadrant will
have a higher bias to a certain location but low variance.
All your models predictions are in a certain area and in the worst high variance high bias means you
just all over the place basically a common temptation for beginners is to continually add complexity
to a model until it fits the training set very well.
And let's go ahead and begin to understand this in a machine learning algorithm to learn about linear
regression.
What you may want to do is let's say you're given a set of red training data.
Now you're testing data your training data you might have a simple model such as the blue line and you
get a certain error on your training data and you the site as a beginner hey maybe I should just make
the model more and more complex or flexible so that it hits all those training points.
However if you're hitting all those training points you're going to your model is going to fail to predict
for new test points which is why we do that train test split doing that can cause a model to overfit
to your training data.
And like I mention cause large errors on new data such as the tests that we're going to do is take a
look at an example model on how we can see overfitting occur from an air standpoint using test data.
We'll use a black curve with some noise points off of it to represent the true shape the data follows.
All right.
We have three images here.
The first one is the X versus the Y.
And here we have model flexibility as different linear fits a linear fit a quadratic fit or a spline
fit with each one getting more complex.
So the simplest is just a linear fit more complicated that is quadratic.
And then you can have a spline fit and you'll notice that the black curve is the truth that the model
actually follows.
So all the points are just noise around the actual black curve which is the truth.
In order to evaluate your models and compare the complexities to each other well you'll have to do is
plot out the complexity or flexibility of the model.
For instance the polynomial level of a regression fit versus the error metric such as mean square error.
And you can see here in that middle plot that's exactly what we've done and we've plotted out for the
training data versus the test data.
You'll notice all the way to the left.
We have a simple model that yellow linear model for this model.
We have a high error on both the test data and the training data as we begin to get more complicated
with the quadratic model in blue.
We begin to lower the error for the test data and the training data as we get even more complex however
we begin to lower the lower the error for the training data significantly.
But as a result you begin to have raised the error on the test data.
The new data show you want to find the point that's going to balance out the bias and the variance in
this particular case that's going to be closer to the quadratic fit that Bluepoint.
So you want to balance out the bias and variance of your model to the point where your test data and
training data have reached some sort of minimum and grouping together.
This is the classic plot to show this as a general stance where you have low versus high model complexity
on the x axis and some sort of prediction error on the y axis.
And as you moved to the left you get a higher bias but lower variance.
And as you move to the right to a higher complexity model you get a lower bias but high variance.
And what you want to do is pick a point where you're comfortable with the bias tradeoff.
If you go to the left of it you'll start to under fit to the data.
And if you go to the right of it you'll start to overfit the data meaning you're hitting all those points
in your training data and new data is cutting a larger error because of that.
All right let's continue by going through some examples and exploring the documentation.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.