Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on the skull and Sparke Mac OS installation.
Make sure you check out the resource link for this lecture.
That's what we're going to be walking through in this lecture.
It contains fully written instructions on how to install everything that includes Java.
Scala Sparke it's dependencies and this lecture will explain these steps.
Walk you through that resource link and then we will show you how to install the Adam text editor which
will be using later on in the course and how to run a simple Skala script.
Let's get started by going to that resource link.
I'm going to jump to that link now.
OK here I am at the research link.
It's just a blog post and I will make sure this blog post is updated in case any changes happen.
As far as the installation process goes but everything here should be basically up to today already
in order to install Skala and Apache's SPARC.
There's a lot of dependencies we need to install and usually this is actually really difficult on Mac
OS systems but a system or program called homebrew makes your life a lot easier.
So what you will do is go to this Web site which is going to be brewed S H and it will tell you how
to install homebrew.
It's basically just go to your terminal and in case you don't know how to use your terminal use click
command space spacebar type in terminal and paste will copy and paste this into your terminal.
And this single line will basically install homebrew for you.
Once you've installed homebrew that's the first step you're going to maybe install X code select.
So in order to install a Java Scala and Spark's to the command line which will be doing you will probably
need to install X code select.
If you haven't done so already for some other programming language that's actually quite easy you just
go to your terminal and type X code that select space dash dash install and you can just copy and paste
these commands from the resource link to your terminal.
You may get a prompt that looks something like this asking you to install command line developer tools.
Go ahead and click install on that link once you have that setup.
It's time to use homebrewed to install Java Skala is dependent on Java.
As we've previously discussed the easiest way to install Java again is just use homebrew.
So once you've installed the homebrew at your command line you just type in Brue task install Java and
it will automatically install a job for you.
It may prompt you for your password.
So make sure you have that ready.
Once you have Java installed you can install Skala again.
Really easy to just say Brue install Skala and type them into your terminal.
It should automatically install sculped for you then you just use homebrewed to install Apache Sparke.
Again very easy.
You say Brue install Apache dash Sparc and they will automatically download and install Apache Sparc
and that may take some time.
These are not very small files or kind of large.
So depending on your internet connection that Dalat installation process may take some time.
Once that's ready to go you should be able to use SPARC shell at your terminal command line.
What's really nice about homebrew is it will automatically add all these commands to your path or to
your source file that bash RC file.
That way you can call SPARC shell from anywhere once you type in SPARC shell you should see a flood
of text and warnings but eventually see something like this that says welcome to spark.
And then you'll have a Skala input there and you can confirm that it's working by typing in something
like this.
Let's go ahead and jump to the terminal and show you how that works.
At the end of this resource link there's also a common issue homebrews should automatically take care
of adding things to your path in bash but in case you need to copy this or you want to add the python
Bash as well.
You can just copy and paste these two lines into your terminal.
That should take care of it all right.
Let's jump to the terminal and show you how the sparks shell should actually look I'm going to say terminal.
So here I am at my terminal.
You should be able to just say SPARC shell.
After installing everything this should work.
And you will see some warnings there.
Don't worry about those later on the course.
We will show you how to adjust the warning level.
SPARC is kind of notorious for showing you a warning for every single little thing but we'll show you
later on how to actually add a line to your script to only get output for severe errors or warnings.
You should see something like this.
And then finally see the sparks shell.
And just to make sure everything's working can say Prince L-N open parentheses and then type in something
like.
Hello world McCarry using double quotes here.
Enter And there is.
Hello world.
And that is your Sparke shell running Skala and in this case I'm running version two point eleven.
Make sure that the spark version you are using is 2.00 or higher in order to use everything that we
do in this course to quit this SPARC shell.
All you have to do is say colon Q And then hit enter.
That will bring you back to your home directory.
Now let's go ahead and show you how to install the Adam text editor.
We won't be using the text editor immediately.
We will use it later on in the course of learning about data frames and then later on after that we'll
jump to and tell you J ID or other ID options and then after that I'll show you how to use notebooks.
But for now since we're already installing things let's show you how to install the Adam text editor
and what plugins you need to add the Adam text editor.
Once you're at this Web site you will be at the Web site for atom.
I know this is a really useful text editor.
We won't use it at first but we will gradually evolve to doing full Skala scripts in our Adam text editor.
If you don't have it already just click on this download for Mac and it will automatically download
the DMG file that you'll need for installing this text editor.
It's one of my favorite text editors.
Again as I've mentioned before you're free to use whatever idea you want.
If you want to jump straight into Intelli J ideally or something like Scala ID for Eclipse.
Those are all viable options.
Feel free to choose what feels right to you.
But if you're just starting out like this course assumes you are we will gradually introduce more and
more ideas and text editors as we go along.
So just download for Mac.
I've already downloaded this so I will jump to the Adam text editor.
I'll open it up and I will show you two plug ins that you need to install to make sure everything works
correctly with Scala.
I'm going to jump to the Adam text editor now.
All right here is what Adam text editor looks like.
A lot of times the first time you open it you should see some sort of welcome message but what we want
to do is show you how to install plugins which is one of the best features of ADOM in my opinion.
Just come here to Adam go to preferences and you should see something that looks like this.
Under settings what you want to do is click here on install and here you can install packages or plug
ins to actually enhance the text editor.
There's two main plugins we need to do.
As far as installation type in Skala and enter into install packages and what we want you to do is install
language Dasch Scala.
All you have to do is click on the Install button.
I already have it installed so I don't need to do that.
But this is your first time using it.
They'll be a little blue Insall button.
Go ahead and click on that.
When you have this language Skala installed the next thing I need to install is a terminal package.
So just come here.
Type in terminal enter to search and there are a lot of terminal packages for Adam.
They're all pretty good but my favorite is this platform you.
Dash ID dash terminal.
So I would recommend just installing that one.
Some of these other terminals sometimes are buggy between operating systems.
I've found that platform Real ID the terminal works across pretty much all the operating systems I've
been to Windows and Mac.
Which is why I recommend to install this platform ID terminal.
Once you have those two installed you should be ready to go as far as running a scarlet script.
So let's show you how to do that.
You can go ahead and say file new file.
In this case I already have an untitled one here.
I will do a simple print Ellen and say my first Skala script close print CS note that right now we're
not getting any syntax highlighting what you need to do is come down here to the bottom right it plain
text and then type in Scala and you can see the syntax highlighting.
And now we will also save this so I will say file save as
it's going to say this to my desktop.
I will say my first script scholar and I will save that file.
And then in order to actually open up a terminal inside of Adam what you can do is just click here on
this plus sign.
And this plus sign should show up once you've installed that terminal.
Here I am at my desktop so I will call Sparke shell enter later on as the course progresses we will
show you how to use things such as Spark's submit or even SPARC notebooks up in the cloud.
Right now we want to keep things simple.
So we will keep with SPARC shell once everything's loaded up.
Let me jump to that now.
You should see something that looks like this welcome to spark and then to load a scholar a script you
just say call and load and then type in the name of your skulls script.
This case it's my first script Scala hit enter and you'll see my first script whatever this output was.
All right.
That's really all there is to it.
Just follow the directions in the resource link.
I can't really walk you through the directions here on this computer because a lot of the stuff is already
installed so it may look a little buggy and I don't want to confuse you but everything that you need
to type is basically already in that resource link.
So just open it up.
Follow through.
Make sure the instructions are followed in the correct order.
And if you have any questions feel free to post the Kewaunee forums I'm here to help out.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.