Hello everyone and welcome to the windows setup section of the Course.
As I mentioned the section is just for Windows users so go ahead and move past this section if you're
not using Windows.
Also make sure to check out the resource links for written guides and download files throughout the
lectures in this section of the course.
Coming up next we're going to go ahead and start off with installing Skala and Sparc and making sure
you have everything set up as far as the languages and programs on your computer.
Then after that lecture we're going to go ahead and discuss development environments or ideas for Skala
and Sparke.
OK.
So let's go ahead and get started with installing everything onto your computer.
I'll see you at the next lecture.