Hello everyone and welcome to the data frame project exercise solutions lecture and this lecture.
We're going to code through the solutions for your data frame project.
Let's go ahead and jump to the text editor to get started.
OK.
Here I am at the text editor for the data frame project.
Go ahead and check out the different project underscore solution that scul a script.
If you ever want to reference what I'm typing out here that basically we're going to go along and just
explain the code.
All of these various answers for the tasks.
OK let's go ahead and get started.
First thing we want to do is start a simple Spark's session.
So in order to do that you're going to have to say import or Apache SPARC that sequel that SPARC session.
And then we want to go ahead and create a value for Sparc just as we've done in all the sparks session
Ensberg data frame lecture's will start Sparke session and say builder get or create.
And as I mentioned before there's a lot more options you can add to this such as giving her app a name
or specifying how many cores you want to use.
But for right now we'll keep it simple just add the builder and get or create.
And then finally we're going to load the Netflix stock CAC file.
So to do that a creative value.
F say spark that read and I'm going to set some options here as we've done in the past.
I'm going to set the hetter to true and then I'm going to also set the option of in first schema it
be true.
And then finally going to say that CXXVI and you could also say format if you wanted to.
Well let's go out and then call the Netflix underscore or 2011 underscore 2016.
And if you look here the extension is not see that we see that in as well.
Okay.
So there you have it.
And as a quick note sometimes depending on where you save this you may get an error if you ever have
a Mac computer and you have spaces in the name of certain files.
You may get an error when opening a CAC file so if you got the error make sure there's no spaces in
the file path to the actual CSP file.
All right.
Going to go ahead and save that.
And now let's ask what are the column names.
So hopefully remember that you can just say f doc columns are going to say this and let's go ahead and
run this.
This is the data frame project's going to say data frame underscore project Skala.
I'm going to run load all that up and then for the rest of the solutions lecture I'm actually going
to type straight into the terminal.
So here I can see my first result is date open high low close volume and then adjust it close.
So these are my columns and then I'm going to go ahead and just go straight into the terminal to answer
the rest of those questions because I already have data framed here so I can go ahead and just reference
it so I can say something like that show you enter in I'll see the top 20 rows.
So we're going to go ahead and just use this given that DFA has already defined that we don't continuously
run the script over and over again.
So we want to know is what does the schema look like.
Hopefully remember that you can just say death print schema and here in the terminal you can actually
use tab to help autocomplete some of this.
So there's the schema looks like we have the date is the time stamp.
Everything else is either a double and then the volume is an integer which makes sense because you can't
trade half of a stock.
Next we want to print out the first five columns.
Hopefully you remember that you can just say head for any number of the first columns you want to see
and we can see that head there and we see an array of the axle Rose returned to us.
Next we wanted to use describe to learn about the data frame.
That's basically the answer right there you can just say ZF describe and this will report back the statistical
information if you just say that the scribe you may not see it.
So you need to say is that describe that show.
And this will actually report back the max min standard deviation mean and count for the various columns
in your data frame.
And if you have some issues here with the actual formatting you can either print one line at a time
or even try expanding your terminal to try to get the formatting to show a little nicer.
All right.
Let's go ahead and create a new data frame of a column called HIV ratio that is the ratio of the high
price versus the volume of stock traded for that day.
OK.
So whenever you see create a new data frame with a new column you should be thinking the with column
command going to say thou Ze'ev to.
We're creating a new data frame Beldi 2 and we're going to say DMF with column and then I want the column
to be called HIV ratio.
So we pass in the new column name first and then as the second argument we pass in the actual calculations
we want to do we grab the columns in this case I want the ratio of high versus price so that's going
to be high column divided by the volume column.
So that's a ratio
and then make sure you have the balance parentheses.
Let's go ahead and run that.
Here is DFI 2.
And if we go ahead and just check the two columns we should see now that we have this A V ratio.
And let's go ahead and just check out the head to make sure everything looks OK and there's the ratio.
Okay perfect.
So you notice that it may be a very small number and that makes sense because you may have a lot of
stock or volume trades that day as the price gets higher and the high price is limited to about three
digits but you can have thousands and thousands of stock transactions.
Also if you wanted to you could have reversed this to be DSF volume divided by DFI depending which way
you want to actually read that ratio.
OK moving on to the next question let's go ahead and clear this one to ask what day had the peak high
in price.
Well one very easy way to do this is just order by the high price.
So I'll say if the order by make sure that's a lowercase order by high
and then I'm going to say D E S C for descending and then I'm going to go ahead and just show and I
can pass on a number here to show to see how many Rosemount return.
And I just want the first row.
OK.
And here we get the high price or the high date.
So that happened in 2015 of June 13th or excuse me July 13th.
OK.
So that was the peak high.
That was the day that it happened.
Let's go ahead and get the mean of the close column.
So for the mean of the close column all you have to do is remember the aggregate function lecture where
we say DFT selects passen the aggregate function.
This case its mean pass in the column you want to get the Mino's sum this case it's close.
And let's go ahead and show that result.
So there it is the mean of the close column or the average is about $230.
Let's go ahead and find the max and min of the volume column.
So we'll say DFA but selects and it's going to be very similar will pass and Max for volume and then
we'll go ahead and show that.
So that's the max volume Let's go ahead and just click up and then show them in
run that.
And there we have the men so you can see that there's a pretty drastic difference between the max and
the men.
And what's fun to do is actually grab the dates of where these max or min values happen and then explore
using Google if anything interesting happened in that stock's history.
In this case you can go ahead and check out the maximum volume traded and see if there was like a good
quarter for Netflix or what actually happened during that day of the men or max values of volume trading.
All right.
Moving along there is a quick note here that for the Scullin Spark's syntax you need to import something.
So the thing you had to import or go ahead and write here is Sparke dot implicit stuff underscore this
is if you want to use the Skala or Spark's syntax for these filter commands.
Or you could have also then the spark siecle syntax in which case you didn't actually need to import
this going to go ahead and just copy that line and imported here.
So say import sparked the implicit
underscore and we'll go ahead and import that.
That way we can use these Skala spark syntax for filtering.
OK first question was how many days was the close lower than 600 dollars.
Well that's easy I can just say DMF philtre dollar sign close column less than 600.
And then I can use an aggregate function to actually count how many days this occurred.
This case is going to be counted.
That was a little tricky for this problem.
Try to remember that aggregate function.
But here we can see that 1218 days the price was lower than $600.
And if you wanted to using Sparke sequel you could have just said close less than 600 as a string.
And then the call don't counts on that.
Now we're giving you the same answer.
So use whatever you prefer.
We won't assume any simple knowledge although it's very likely that if you're this far into the course
you probably have some database experience.
Kate.
Coming up next what percentage of the time was the high.
Greater than $500.
So it's a bit of a tricky question it's asking not just how much or how many values you get that the
high or is greater than 500.
It wants to know what percentage of the time was the high greater than $500.
And that's in reference to the actual entire data frame.
So we're going to do is say DMF and I'm going to type this out here in the script and then copy and
paste it so we can see a little bit of the syntax highlighting.
I want to say DFT filter where my column is greater than 500.
I'm going to count that.
I remember that returns an integer long integer and then one I'm going to go ahead and do it.
This is the percentage of the time.
So I want to divide that by the total number of rows in the data frame.
So let's go ahead and break this down.
We're not quite finished yet but I just want to explain what we have so far.
The question is asking what percentage of the time was the high greater than $500.
So the way to answer this is to grab the total number of times using count and filter that the price
of the high was greater than $500.
Then divide it by the total number of rows in that data frame.
So if you interpreted this question a little differently and came up with a different solution that's
OK too.
But let's go ahead and understand what we have to do next.
So we want a percentage.
Meaning we're eventually going to have to multiply this by 100
end just doing this is actually going to give us the answer quite yet.
So I'm going to show you why.
Go ahead and copy this
and then I will go ahead and paste.
Let's run this.
Make sure would have any errors.
OK.
You notice this gets long is equal to zero.
So if you're were doing a division and you notice something goes straight to zero that's because you're
probably doing classic divisions that have true division since these are both integers and they're both
long integers.
We need to get one of them to be a double to actually get the true value.
In this case I want to just multiply the top number by one point zero in order to convert it to a double.
And then that should fix the actual problem.
So let's go ahead and copy this paste it and then run it.
Now I can see the actual percentage of the time.
So around 5 percent of the time the high price is greater than $500.
This is probably one of the trickier questions in this project assignment.
So go ahead and take the time to really understand what's going on the solutions here.
Again the question is a little tricky especially if you interpret it differently.
We're basically asking out of the entire dataset.
What percent of the time was that high price greater than $500.
So we grabbed the total count of the high price being great and the $500 divided by the count of all
the rows in the data frame.
Multiply it by 100 to get a percentage.
And if you get that zero error the trick was to convert one of these to a simple double.
OK.
Now we want to know what is the Pearson correlation between high and volume.
Now we've actually shown this before in an exercise of using the correlation function but you just say
DFP selects c o r r and then passen the column names as just straight strings.
In this case I want to say core of volume and let's go in and show the results.
So high volume T.F. select.
And there's a correlation there's basically no correlation either negative or positive between the high
price and the volume column which kind of makes sense given their unit difference.
OK.
Now finally we want to know what is the max height per year.
This is going to be a multiverse that process so let's go ahead and write this out in the scripts will
save Val year death and the first thing I want to do is actually create a year column.
So I will say with column
year I'm going to capitalize this and then I'm going to use that time stamp function or that date function
year and pass the actual date column and then make sure my princes are balanced there.
And then using that year if I'm going to go ahead and select the year and the high column then group
by the year and then call the max off of that and then you can technically do this all in one giant
step.
But this is a little nicer as far as being able to read it.
So I'm going to create a new frame called The Year Maxxis and it's going to be year DMF.
I'm going to select that year column and then I'm going to selects the high column and then I'm going
to say Group By then I will say year
and then call the max office OK and then let's go ahead and just select what we want to show.
In this case go ahead and save this will comment out some of these earlier commands looks like everything
else is good.
Come out this command for the columns.
And let's actually just run this whole script to make sure it's all working.
So we'll load that data frame up again.
Well let's go ahead and clear the console and say load data frame underscore project Skala run that.
OK so it looks like you're the year Max has worked so far.
So we haven't actually shown any thing as far as the results yet.
But let's go and are you done.
I want to show what is the max high per year.
So we want to say a new year column using the time stamp function say Dhia with column year year the
F set that equal to year the F and then off of you.
I'm going to just select the columns I'm concerned about.
I'm only concerned about the year column in the high column that a group that by year and asked for
the max and since that's year Maxi's I can always just say year Maxi's And let's go ahead and say this
your Maxie's that selects
year.
Remember I have to add in the aggregate function so max of high.
And then I'm going to just say show
and there it is there are at the max high prices per year.
So you can see the high price of 2011 2016 2012 et cetera.
And if you actually want to order this what you can do is just do something like this.
You could if you wanted to you could this all in one step.
So it might be nicer to say something like that of results is equal to this.
And let's go ahead and not show it and then I'm going to say results dot order by and I will order it
by the year
and let's actually show that results Okay.
And there it is ordered by the year so we can see how the max price per year has changed so 120 133
389 49 716.
And then we got a drop to 129 in 2016 and if you're wondering why that it dropped so much.
Well this is most likely due to something like a stock split.
Finally the very last question we wanted to answer was What does the average close for each calendar
month.
This is going to be really similar.
So let's go ahead and break it down.
I'm going to go ahead and separate out this into multiple steps by saying that all month.
It's going to be death with column and then we can say month and then call the Month function off the
date column and then I don't want every single column I just want the month and the close columns now.
So let's go ahead and say thou month.
Avi G-S is equal to month that selects and then I'm going to say month.
Let's go to make sure that's capitalized and then I'm going to also ask for the close call that I'm
going to group by the month column and ask for the means and I want the average And then finally let's
go ahead and show that.
So I will say month EVGA Yes.
Select the columns I want right now it has the high low close volumes etc..
Let's go ahead and just grabbed that month column and then also the year average of the close column
and then we'll show that.
Regarding comments out these two lines here save this and let's go ahead and run the script.
So we will load data from their score project about Skala and see the results.
Okay.
And there it is.
Here are the results so for the calendar month we get the average close price.
Now right now this is again not sorted.
So if you wanted to you could again use ORDER BY.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to go ahead and say that ORDER BY WHEN TO ORDER BY THE MONTH.
Now last time we did this in a separate step but it's also okay to just do it all in one step.
Go ahead and run that again and he can see it's been ordered by the month.
So you can compare the average close price for a calendar month.
Now keep in mind this is the trend across all the years in the data set.
So this is for January of all the years in the Netflix data set.
In this case those years we go ahead and look at that dataset name it goes from 2011 to 2016 and you
can see here that this is going to represent the average closing price for every January 2011 to 2016.
So all the days for all those years sorted or grouped by the month.
All right.
So hopefully this was a fun challenging exercise for you.
Some of these questions are way trickier than others especially these last two.
What is Max high per year.
What is average close for each calendar month.
Those are probably some of the much trickier questions.
And then the other tricky question was this what percentage of the time was height greater than 500.
Those three questions are much harder than the rest of them but hopefully had a good stab at it and
had fun while you're doing the exercise.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums and I'll be happy to help you out.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.