Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to spark data frames.
We finally reached this section of the course where we're not going to be dealing with Skala by itself
but we'll also be working with SPARK and capability is the spark specifically data frame's in the second
or the course we're going to discussing what is a spark data frame we're going to talk about that in
this lecture and then later on we'll talk about how to use smart data frames and how to program with
data frames discussing things such as aggregate or grouped by operations how to index or select columns
from a data frame or even how to deal with time stamp information and much more.
Then at the end of this section will have some data frame exercises dealing of some financial data to
test your understanding so Sparke data frames are now the standard way of dealing with data.
For Skala and Sparke as well as other languages such as are in Sparc or Piscean spark spark is moving
away from the traditional D syntax that it used to use in favor of the simpler to understand data framed
syntax.
And if you've worked in other programming languages that use data frames such as Python's pandas library
or just the our language you probably already have a good familiarity of what a data frame is going
to look like.
If you haven't you can basically think of a data frame as kind of this large Excel spreadsheet where
it has rows and then columns spark data frames are also now going to be the standard way of using Spark's
machine learning capabilities with the Lib library or machine learning library.
In fact if you actually go visit the documentation for Spark's machine learning capabilities you'll
notice that there's two sections.
One for the outdated RTD version and then one for the newer SPARC data frame version.
So all upcoming developments will occur for Sparc data frames.
Now that we've reached SPARC 2.0 dispersed data frame and general documentation is actually still pretty
new and can be sparse.
So let's go ahead and get a brief tour of that documentation to teach you how to best utilize it.
Go ahead and go to spark that Apache org and explore the documentation there.
So I'm going to go out and jump to my browser right now.
So you have find that documentation and discuss how to best utilize it.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to my browser now.
OK so here we are at Sparks that Apache the org or let's go ahead and show you where you can find the
documentation for Sparke data frames.
Just come over here to the documentation tab and you should see the latest release documentation.
Go ahead and click on it.
And then here and there programming guides go ahead and scroll down to you see data frames data sets
and sequel.
Click on that and you should see the spark sequel data frames and data sets guides.
This is just a general overview guide and if you actually click here in the time you'll get an overview
explanation of how sequel data sets and data frames all relate to each other.
That basically sparked sequel is a spark module that allows you to use sequel like syntax or exact sequel
syntax so you queery structured data and then when you do that sort of query you can get a data set
back a dataset is a distributed collection of data and then a data frame is a data set organized into
named columns data frames is the main data type but we're going to be working with here.
But go ahead and on your own time read about this overview here to totally understand how data sets
relate to data frames and how secure can be use to actually query a data frame or data set.
Later on we'll actually show you how you can use sequel syntax for clearing a data frame.
Now we won't focus on that particular aspect because that assumes you have sequel knowledge.
Instead we'll actually show you how to do most of this stuff just through basic Skala if you keep scrolling
down here you'll see stuff like basic getting started documentation and then creating data frames.
Now here under the creating data frames you have a very simple example of reading H.A. some file showing
that.
And then you'll see something that says the columns of data frame with some rows of data and then if
you come down here you'll see three basic operations.
Print schema select the column select on the increment one column by a certain value do a little bit
of filtering and then do it by and you'll notice that's actually it really for the documentation as
far as basic programming guides everything else is just topics on other things such as data sets or
interpreting these etc..
But as far as working to spark data frame as a programming guide this is really all there is at the
moment.
Now you can come down here to the bottom of this.
If you go here you'll have data from operations.
So if you scroll down here at the bottom you'll see that there's a complete API documentation.
That's what I really want you to know.
And there's a link in the resource section to this API documentation directly.
Go ahead and click on that.
OK so this is the full API documentation page for data sets and remember data frames are just data sets
organized into columns of column names.
So they're very similar but here you can scroll down see a lot more code examples of actually create
in work with these data frames or data sets and then more importantly as you come and scroll down you'll
see all the various actions and transformations that are available to you on this data frame object.
So this is really important to know and visit this page if you're looking for a specific action or transformation
you want to perform on a specific dataset or data frame.
Now keep in mind we're going to be going over a lot of these transformations and actions especially
the most common or useful ones.
Things such as order by or filtering etc..
And in case you're looking for something specific.
So is a day to come here to the API page and see if you can find that yourself and you can also just
search the API documentation here.
Now keep in mind a lot of this stuff is still new and if it's really new you'll see something like experimental
attached to it which means it's still experimental There may be some bugs in it.
So if you're working with production code.
Keep that in mind as far as how stable you need your environment to be and your code to be all right.
So go ahead and explore the documentation not just this API documentation but also the previous page
in order to learn a little bit more about the very basics of data frames and data sets.
Coming up next we're going to give you an actual programming overview of how to create a spark session
how to create a data frame and how to work for data frame.
All right I hope you're excited for this section of the Course.
This is going to be some of the latest and greatest for Skala and Sparke.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.