Hello everyone and welcome to the documentation example lecture for the principal component analysis
section of the course in this lecture we will briefly walk you through the is official example of how
to implement PCa with Scalia Scotland spark.
Let's jump to that Scala script now.
All right.
Here I am at the Adam text editor and I have opened up the documentation example.
All the scripts for this section of the Course can be found under the machine learning instructions
folder under the PCA folder.
And in this case I've opened up these PCA underscore doc underscore example dot Skala script lets you
simply walk through this documentation an example of how to actually create a principal component analysis.
The main thing you'll notice here is that you started Spark's session but more importantly you have
to import from M-L dot feature PCA PCA is technically in Scala and SPARC thought of as a feature processing
out for them.
It's not really thought of as a unsupervised machine learning algorithm that is not to say that principal
component analysis is not an unsupervised machine learning algorithm it just letting you know that don't
expect to find it under M-L dog clustering or something.
PCa is found of the features section of Spark's machine learning library but principal component analysis
is an unsupervised task meaning we only expect to see features not a label when working with PCa and
the other thing we want to import is from M-L Butland alledged vectors.
Then we start a spark session here we're calling it PCa example.
We create some data documentation instead of using some lib SVM format just creates some simple data
right here.
Notice that it's just some array of vectors.
And here we can see that it's 2 0 3 4 5.
So right now we actually have what are essentially five features for each of these vectors.
And we're going to end up doing is saying sparks create data frame with some operations to transform
this array of vectors to a data frame and the frame just has a single column.
This single column is just called features which makes sense just as we saw in the Kamins clustering
lectures.
We just have a single column of that array of features when dealing with unsupervised machine learning
algorithms.
This case we're dealing with PCa to actually implement PCA It's quite simple.
Basically treat this just as you would some vector assembler object or a string indexer or other objects
that you find under the if I scroll up here and that feature section of Spark's machine learning capabilities.
So all you have to do is say Vau PCA is equal to a new PC object.
You set the input column to be that features column so the output column.
You can call it whatever you want but we usually just want to call it something simple like PCA features
those principal components.
And then you have this important set K value.
So the set K don't mix this up with K means all this is saying is how many Princeville principal components
do you want.
There's no real correct answer here as far as what value you should choose.
It's the value that you want to reduce the number of features too.
So for example here we're dealing with five features.
And here we're going to reduce it to three principal components.
And as I mentioned in the theory lecture it's pretty hard to interpret these components directly but
basically you can think of these principal components as just combinations of all the features.
Again there's no real right answer of how to choose this k value.
It really depends on your data your situation and what you're trying to achieve by how much do you actually
want to reduce the number of features you have.
Then in this case we're going to put everything in once that by saying that fit to the data frame.
So he's saying new PCA set the input column set the output column so that the number of principal components
you want and then fit this to the data frame and then you can just transform and check out the results.
You say Val PCA death is equal to that PCA object that transform on that data frame.
So note that there's basically two steps here.
You have to create this PCA object fit it to the data fring and then to actually get the result transform
that data frame and then you can just select that column PCA features that you just created.
And you can show that off.
Let's run this whole script and see if it works you will say load PCA doc.
The example that Skala enter and let it run.
Up everything.
Let me expand this so we can actually see this results so noticed now we have this PC features column
and if we take a look at our original data frame number it's called the death.
I will say DFI show and we can also say if or actually we have all three rows here so we can see that
we have more than three principal components in these features.
If I say the result does show we have this PC features in effect call the first row of that by saying
results head.
We notice that we just have three principal components.
Here's the first one.
Here's the second one.
And there's the third one.
So we successfully reduce the number of features this has two just three principal components where
each principal component is essentially representative of a combination of features.
So that's really all there is two principal components analysis.
You just basically treat this as you would for some vector assembler or some string indexer or really
any other sort of feature object you would get from this and Malkoff feature light.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Kewney forums.
But coming up next we're going to go over what you can expect to do in your PC project exercise.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.