Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on arrays in Scala arrays are mutable unlike the list which
is immutable and the way Skala is designed you're usually going to be using lists much more often than
you'll be using arrays.
You can go ahead and check out the resource link for more information.
As far as what's going on under the hood for performance differences between a list versus an array
that it's far worse when you're programming a scholar at the basic level that we're doing right now.
They're going to feel so similar.
You may not actually notice a difference between an array and the list.
So we're going to do this lecture as quickly show how to create an array but most likely throughout
the course as far as this section we're going to be using lists rather than arrays.
Let's go ahead and jump to the spark shell and go to the Scala interpreter.
OK here I am at my Scala interpreter.
You can create an array just by saying Val or var pany Fionna value a variable the name of the array.
I'm going to go ahead and call it our for array and then use the keyword array just like you would a
list and then pass in the elements you want.
And Scalzo report back.
They have an array containing whatever the data type is.
In this case integers so it can do something similar again just by saying re-assigning that to an array
for instance strings such as ABC
and now Ill reports back you have an array of strings.
And just like a list can also hold multiple data types so you can say array 1 to point to maybe a boolean
in there and you'll see array.
Any Val.
Now from this standpoint arrays look extremely similar to a list like I mentioned go ahead and check
out that resource link as far as more detailed explanations of what's going on underneath the hood and
the connections to Java based language.
As far as the differences between an array and a list what I really want to let you know about though
in regards to arrays is the use of the range function.
So this range function is going to allow us to generate an array containing a sequence of increasing
integers in a given range.
So there's various ways of calling it you can say either array dot range.
And then you'll input a starting integer and the ending index so 0 to 10 is going to give you from 0
to integer 9 because indexing starts at zero and you can actually specify a step size as well as a third
argument here so you can say zero up to and not including 10 and go in step sizes of two.
And that gives you a bunch of even numbers so zero plus two two plus two is four etc..
And you can call it off of the array but a lot of times what you will end up doing is just calling range.
But notice that I'm using a capital R here and this is going to like to do the exact same thing it's
calling it from Skala dot collection the immutable dot range instead of just saying returning an array.
So that's really the difference here between these two.
One is the actual array being returned.
And another one this capital our range is this actual Skala collection that range object being returned
to you.
So that's a difference between using the array that range versus the capital our range.
Now if you're just using this sort of thing in a for loop which will go over later the capital our range
should be totally fine.
OK.
So that's really all you need to know as far as the basics of array.
Like I mentioned that throughout this course and throughout Scala in a general sense you're probably
going to be using lists much more often than an actual array type object.
All right.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.