Hello everyone and welcome back to the regression spark section of the course.
And in this lecture we're going to go ahead and walk you through the example that's used in the documentation.
So let's go ahead and explore the documentation.
We'll take a brief walk through the actual regression example and take a look at that Web site.
Now a version of this documentation example is available to you as the Linn Reg doc example that Skoll
a script that's already in your regression folder.
So you don't need actually go looking around in your downloaded smart folder for the official documentation
example.
I already have a simplified version of it for you in that Russian folder.
So let's go ahead and quickly jump to the documentation Web site.
Check it out and then we'll open up that Skala script and walk you through it.
I'm going to jump to that Web site now.
All right.
So here we are at the documentation under the machine learning library guy.
You'll see that you have two guides the Arkadi based guide and the main guide the main guide is the
one that uses the data frames and it's the newer guide.
So let's go ahead and use that.
We will click on classification regression and if you scroll down you'll see we have regression something
to note here is that SPARC machine learning library has a lot of options for different regression algorithms.
And what's really nice is that once you learn how to use the most basic one which is linear regression
you can basically switch out any algorithm for linear regression.
That means if you want to use a gradient lose to try regression a random forced regression a decision
tree regression.
You just need to easily swap out the models and then set your new parameters.
If you click a linear regression you'll be taken scrolled down to the linear regression section and
you'll see how the Escala example code.
This is the code we're going to be walking you through in just a little bit.
If you want the full example code just go to wherever you installed Sparke.
There should be an examples folder and you have to keep going down to the RC main Skala org Apache Sparke
examples M-L And then finally you'll see that Skala script Linaria rational for net example because
this is such a long file path and really annoying to find.
I went ahead and set that line Reg doc example that Skoll a script already in your regression folder
that comes with the download for this course so you don't have to go around searching for it.
OK let's jump to the Adam text editor and walk you through everything that's in this code and explain
how with just this knowledge you can implement a regression algorithm really simply using Spark's new
data for a machine learning library.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to the Adam text editor now.
All right here I am Adam text editor.
I've gone ahead and opened up the Scala script for the documentation example.
You can open this up in whatever Id prefer.
Now let's walk through line by line.
What's happening here.
You'll notice the first thing you have to do is make imports.
Here we have the regression import.
We're going to import every Russian and then we have to import the spark.
Session.
We've gone ahead and put everything here under a single function.
You'll notice that if you actually read the official documentation examples they're using things such
as packages and objects.
We're going to learn about those later on when we actually need to package this nicely.
When you're first starting off learning everything it's nice to have everything just under a single
function instead of a single object or to actually not even have a function and just do this line by
line because when you open up the spark shell you can actually pick and play with these objects and
learn more from them.
If you have everything in a nice package even though it looks really nice it's hard to dissect what's
actually going on inside instead of the sparks shell.
So will teach you how to do all that later on when we actually want to work with large distributed datasets.
Right now to optimize our learning we're going to do all this simpler fashion.
First thing we have to do is go ahead and start a spark session.
Then you need the file path to your data.
In this case reason the documentation's example data which is sample any Russians data that ticks T.
It's actually in a lib SBM format so you need to say spark the read format lib SVM.
If you open up this text file you'll notice that it's not exactly a CACP file.
This L this lib SVM format is a little different than the point that it has the label in the first column
and then the features number out.
So it's not exactly a c file so keep that in mind.
It's a bit of a quirky file format that suit and more for a machine learning but we will show you later
on how to actually deal with machine learning with CSP files and other data types.
Once you have that path and keep in mind you may need to have the full file path here.
We're working with the text file that's actually in the same Russian folder so we don't need to specify
the full file path but in case you do remember that you may need to start with file colon and then three
forward slashes and on Windows computers and sometimes on Mac computers there can be no spaces in your
file name.
So keep that in mind.
Now we have that training data in this simple example.
We are going to be getting metrics off of the data we trained on.
Later on we'll show you how to do a full train test validation split.
For now we're keeping things simple.
Then we create a new linear regression object and this is basically the main step you're going to go
ahead and create a value or a variable name say new linear regression and then you can set a bunch of
parameters for this actual linear regression later on in the model evaluation section of the course.
We're actually going to show you how to build a parameter grid so you don't have to guess and check
manually different parameters.
You can set a grid of parameters and test those automatically and these parameters that you set you're
going to learn more about them when you learn more about statistical analysis behind these actual algorithms
what parameters that you mathematically want to set.
You can set them here.
So for instance this linear regression is actually using an elastic net so you can set that parameter
itself.
And as you learn more about statistics and the mathematical algorithms you can go ahead and play around
these parameters more or you can just build a parameter grid and test those out automatically then you
fit the model.
In this case we're fitting into the training data.
And that's basically it.
After that you can call coefficients and the intercept off of this model and you can call a summary
off the model and the summary has information such as the residuals the root mean square error R-squared
error etc..
Now we went ahead and stopped that spark session.
And if you go to the left here we just call this main function.
Let's go and run this.
I'll open up a terminal make sure I'm in the regression folder and then I will start a spark shell later
I will talk about putting this all into a package and saying Sparke submit.
Right now we want to learn and kind of play around with this so we're just using Spark's show.
OK let's load this up.
We'll say load when Reg doc example not Skala enter.
And then the output.
All right so that finished running.
Keep in mind you may receive some warnings but as long as you don't receive a full error that stops
the operation that should be totally fine.
And here we can see that we have the root mean square error.
The R-squared value in this case it's very poor.
That has to do with the data and the way we set it up with the parameters.
But don't worry about that later I'll show you how to edit that and set up parameters correctly so you
get a much better value.
Here you can see the residuals.
That's the difference between the predicted value and the actual label value.
And you can see the history number of iterations coefficients in the intercept and then you'll may see
some warnings as you explore further up.
But as long as you don't get Eyres that's totally fine.
All right.
That's the basics of the documentation example.
I encourage you to read through this and actually check out the other examples for other regression
algorithms in the documentation.
Coming up next we're actually going to comb through and walk you through an entire example of using
linear regression.
So you can get a feel for it step by step on how to actually do this sort of operation on your own data.
Thanks everyone and I will see at the next lecture.