Hello everyone and welcome to the school and Sparke overview lecture and this lecture will give an overview
of the scholar programming language then we will discuss the general big data ecosystem and afterwards
we'll show how Petchey spark fits into all of this.
This is going to be just a non-technical overview lecture.
Just to give you some context of how all the topics we learn in this course actually fit in with each
other.
Scala is a general purpose programming language and it was designed by Mark know their ske in the early
2000s.
EPA.
Fell a technical university in Switzerland and it was designed to overcome criticism of Java's shortcomings.
Source code is intended to be compiled to Java bytecode to run on a Java virtual machine.
So when we install Skala will also need to install Java Java libraries may be used directly in Scala
which is nice.
That way if you have understanding of Java and Java libraries you can leverage that knowledge in Scala
unlike Java.
Scala has many features of functional programming.
A large reason skald the man has dramatically risen in recent years is because of Apache's SPARC which
is written in Scala.
So let's go ahead and discuss what spark is in the context of Big Data.
We'll begin with a general explanation of what big data is and related technologies.
So for this big data Overview section of this lecture we're going to go ahead and give an explanation
of Hadoop map reduce and sparrer.
We'll talk about local versus distributed systems.
We'll give an overview of the Hadoop ecosystem and then an overview of SPARC itself.
Let's talk about big data in general.
There's data that can fit on a local computer and that's usually in the scale of 0 to 32 gigabytes depending
on how much ram your computer has.
So this is just data that can actually fit onto your RAM.
But what do you do if you have larger data sets which are bigger than what you can actually hold in
memory on RAM.
Well you can try using a sequel database to move storage onto a hard drive instead of a ram or onto
a cloud database using sequel.
Or you can use a distributed system that distributes the data to multiple machines or computers and
this discussion of a local system versus a distributed system comes into play.
You're usually using a local system for just that home using a single computer with a distributed system
you can actually have a master computer controlling more course.
So instead of actually thinking of these as computers you should actually think of this distributed
system as controlling servers which in combination of each other can actually leverage the power of
smaller computers to have more cores than just a single local computer.
So a local process will use the computation resources of a single machine in a distributed process has
access to the computational resources across a number of machines connected through some sort of network
after a certain point.
It's a lot easier to scale out to many lower CPM machines that try to scale up to a single machine with
a high CPQ distributed machines also have the advantage of easily scaling.
You can just add more machines and they also include things such as fault tolerance.
So if one machine fails the whole network can still go on unlike your local computer where if it goes
down that's it you're out.
So let's go ahead and discuss the typical format of a distributed architecture that uses Hadoop and
then we'll discuss how we can use distributed computing with SPARC Hadoop is a way to distribute very
large files across multiple machines and it uses what's known as the Hadoop distributed file system
or HFS DFS allows a user to work with large data sets and HFS also duplicates blocks of data for fault
tolerance.
It also then uses map reduce and map Redus allows computations on that data.
So let's go ahead and look at a simple example of what distributed storage looks like.
This is just a general overview of what a Hadoop distributed file system may look like.
You'll have a name node with some C-p in RAM and then you'll have your data nodes which contain your
data in a distributed format.
So DFS will use blocks of data for the size of 128 megabytes by default.
And each of these blocks is replicated three times and then those replications are distributed in a
way across those distributed servers or computers in order to support fault tolerance.
So if one of these servers goes down you'll also have copies or replications of that data.
Smaller blocks provide more paralyzation during processing and multiple copies of a block prevent loss
of data due to some sort of failure of a node map reduce is a way of splitting computation tasks to
a distributed set of files such as HFS and it consists of a job tracker and multiple task trackers.
The job tracker is going to send code to run on the task trackers and then the task tracker will allocate
CPQ and memory for the tasks and monitor the tasks on these worker nodes so that we cover it can be
thought of into distinct parts.
You're using HFS that Hadoop distributed file system to distribute large data sets and you're using
that produce to distribute computational tasks to distributed data set.
So you have the storage and formatting versus the actual distribution of the computational task.
So next let's go ahead and learn about the latest technology in the space known as SPARK what we cover
in this course spark improves on the concepts of using distribution.
So this lecture is going to now be an abstract overview of spark spark versus map reduce spark already
does and then spark data frame's so Sparke is one of the latest technologies being used to quickly and
easily handle big data.
And it's an open source project hosted on Apache.
It was first released in February 2013 and has exploded in popularity due to its ease of use and its
speed.
It was created at the amp lab at UC Berkeley in California.
You can think of Sparke as a flexible alternative to map reuse and spark can use data stored in a variety
of formats.
Cassandra AWOS S3 HD effects and much more so map redos requires files to be stored in the FS while
SPARC does not.
It can use those multiple file formats Sparke can also perform operations up to 100 times faster than
map reduce.
And this is its main selling point.
Its speed overmastered does.
So now we want to know how does it actually achieve this huge speed increase will map reduce writes
most of its data to disk after each map and reduce operation spark however keeps most of the data in
memory after each transformation and spark can spill over to disk if the memory is filled.
So the simplified the difference a little bit.
You can basically think of SPARC as keeping all its operations in memory as much as it can versus map
reduce having to write the disk after each mapping reduce operation.
So as you may imagine SPARC can do these operations much faster since it's keeping everything in memory
at the core of SPARC.
Is the idea of a resilient distributed dataset.
Or are you going to be hearing that term a lot when you have discussions about SPARC resilient distributed
datasets or are does have four main features.
It's a distributed collection of data.
It's fault tolerant.
It has parallel operations that are partitioned and it has the ability to use many data sources.
So what does this actually look like in a general sense.
Well it's actually going to look pretty familiar.
Based on what we discussed about Hadoop Smet produce but already these are slightly different.
You have a driver program which has a spark context or a spark session.
Then you have a cluster manager which is going to manage the different worker nodes that are executing
the tasks that are being held in memory.
So what does this actually look like in a more physical sense.
We'll usually have what are known as Master nodes and then these slave nodes or these worker nodes.
The master controls how the data is partitioned across these worker nodes and then it takes advantage
of data locality while keeping track of all the stream data computation.
All these worker machines if a certain machine is unavailable then the data on that machine just gets
reconstructed on another available machine and that allows for this fault tolerance and the distribution
of the data set allowing it to be resilient distributed datasets or Arti these are Didi's are immutable
lazily evaluated and then cashable and there's two types of art to the operations.
There's transformations and actions and this is a critical point to truly understanding.
These transformations are basically just a recipe to follow you give instructions as a recipe to your
actual RTT that set of data that's distributed across these worker nodes.
Then once you actually want to perform an action you call some sort of action operation that will perform
what the transformations say to do and then return something back.
The reason for this split of operations transformations vs actions is because if you're working of spark
it means you're working with a very large dataset.
So you want to make sure that every time you adjust a transformation you're not actually recomputing
everything across your entire cluster.
It's only when you call that action that the transformations actually get computed and that's why it's
called lazily evaluated.
It's lazily waiting for you to actually call the action.
Now when discussing Spark's syntax you're going to see RTD vs data frame Syntec show up especially as
you start to browse the documentation with the release of SPARC 2.0.
SPARC is moving towards a data frame based syntax.
But keep in mind that the way files are being distributed physically across the cluster can actually
still be thought of as the DS.
It's just the actual typed out syntax that is changing and we're going to discuss this a lot further
detail when we actually learn more about Sparc and how to actually type out Sparke commands in Scala.
But in this course we're going to be focusing on the future of SPARC which is this data frame based
syntax.
But don't let that confuse you.
As if already these are suddenly disappearing from your physical cluster management.
It's just a cleaner syntax for working with data so I know we've covered a lot.
And don't worry if you didn't memorize all these details a lot of this will be covered again as we learn
more about how to actually code in Scala and utilize all these ideas.
This is just a basic high level overview for you to understand the context of everything you're about
to learn in this course.
OK thanks everyone.
I'm super excited to get off the course and I'll see you at the next lecture.