Hello everyone and welcome to the walk through example lecture where we walk you through how to perform
logistic regression for the classification section for machine learning with SPARK.
We're going to walk through a more complicated classification example using the classic Titanic data
set from Kaggle.
This basically is a data set that contains passenger information for passengers on the Titanic.
And we want to try to classify or predict what passengers survived the Titanic and what passengers didn't
survive the actual crash of the Titanic.
You can check this all out at Kaggle dot com.
And just google searching for the Titanic data set there if you want more of a background on that actual
data set.
We will go ahead and walk through an example on how to actually deal with this more complicated and
actual real data.
Let's get started by jumping to the Adam text editor.
OK.
Here I am at the text editor.
If you go to your classification folder you should see an example script called log Reggy example Scala.
And this is basically a simplified version of a more complicated logistic regression script.
And the reason for that is because I'm not going to use an object layout due to objects not allowing
us to really play around the data inside the spark shell.
I'm going to just put it in line by line.
The imports the value statements the functions everything we're going to be doing.
OK I'm going to leave this for you to reference and I'm going to start a new file here called log Reg
X Skala and actually walk through line by line type all this out and explain along the way.
So you can always just reference everything I'm doing here and then log examples call a script.
I've created a new one called log Reg export Skala.
First thing I want to do is some of our imports import stuff along the way.
As I've mentioned many times before I usually want to do all your imports at the top of a script but
for now just for learning purposes I'm going to just put them all as we need them.
So we want org got a patch that sparked the M-L the classification.
And this is where we choose a specific algorithm.
In this case I want logistic regression and then up next I want to import or Apache that spark that
sequel spark session and there's an optional script here you can type in.
This is just the logger.
So I'm going to just copy and paste this from that script.
And this basically allows us to not see a whole bunch of warnings.
All right.
First thing I want to do is actually create the spark session.
Keeping things simple right now.
We'll just say Val spark is equal to spark session builder.
And then we will get or create that spark session then that's quite a few times during the spark data
frame lecturers not doing anything fancy right now by saying how many cores you are or what we want
the app to be named.
Keeping things simple so we can focus on the logistic regression aspects.
Up next we want to use Sparke to read in the actual Titanic CACP file.
If you look at your classification folder you should notice that there is a way expand this out a bit
Titanic that see every file.
If you open that up you'll notice that there is a passenger ID column you survived the column indicating
zero.
If they did not survive.
What if they did survive the passenger class.
So passengers were on three separate class and the Titanic first second or third class the name of that
passenger which isn't actually going to be super super useful for us at this point in time.
The sex of that passenger male or female the age of the passengers some number age.
Sid espie that's the number of siblings and spouses they had on board this par S.H..
That's a number of parents are children.
They also had on board the ticket.
So they have some sort of ticket number the fare that they paid for that ticket.
The cabin number that they were in and then embarked and embarked you'll notice is also just a letter
string where it's S or C or q which designate what actual town they embarked on OK.
You'll notice that we have some categorical data that we want to deal with.
We haven't actually delved categorical data before so we'll explore how to do that in this lecture.
Now let's print out the schema of this data frame.
Well first let's actually grab this and create a data frame from the Titanic cxxviii file so say valid
data spark.
We're going to do that before read option.
I want that header to be true.
Just pressing the strings here and then the other option I want is to infer schema I will also say
and then I'm going to say format c s v.
We know at c a c file and then just say load Titanic the CSP OK.
And you can use parentheses to split this up into multiple lines if you want.
It's not really good style to have everything in one long line but sometimes it's easier for you to
understand what's going on.
If you can see everything builds off of each other totally up to you how you want to approach this.
OK moving along now it's actually print that schema so we can get an idea of what it actually looks
like.
We're going to save this blog Wrex open up a terminal here already have a terminal that's running Skala
let's make sure it's actually working.
And I'm going to load log.
Reg XT sculler enter.
We should see it load up that data and there we have the schema.
So again here the calls we have passed already survived the class name and you notice that we have some
of these as strings and things such as the name of the passenger aren't going to be especially useful
for us right now.
For instance a machine learning algorithm isn't going to be able to detect more accurately whether someone
survives if their name is Charlie or if their name is John.
Well you can do is something called feature engineering.
We try to engineer new features off a feature column.
If you go back to the file Titanic TSB you'll notice that under the name column scroll to the left some
of these people have titles such as Mr. MS. Mrs. M..
And later on he keeps rolling down and see things such as Dr again Master etc..
Now that's a feature that may or may not be useful and it's something you may want to explore.
We'll keep things simple right now and we'll just drop the name column.
But there are certain columns we don't want to drop.
There are still strings such as the sex column or even the embarked column.
These are categorical data columns that we're going to have to deal with so we'll have to focus on how
to actually do that.
OK.
Let's go ahead and display the data instead of typing this all out I'm going to just copy and paste
the display data.
We've done this before many times.
It's basically just a way of printing out an example row and going to copy this and paste this into
my file.
Save this.
And I will press up on this key and run the script again and this will print out an example row for
us.
OK so we have cut Cabane no embarked s fer $7 me five cents.
Some sort of ticket number 0 parents were children on board.
One sibling or spouse the age the sex is male and this guy's name is Mr Owen Harris.
He was in third class did not survive.
Sorry.
Now that we understand what the data more or less looks like we want to be in setting up a data frame
for machine learning.
The first step in doing this is to grab the actual data.
We want to use.
I'm going to create a value called log Reg data all and they all set equal to data that selects an I'm
going to select my label column.
Remember we're trying to predict how someone survived or not.
So I will say select data survived and I'll set this as lower case label number how important it is
to actually have the label and feature orientation for data transfer machine learning.
And I'm going to use open print CS here and a close parentheses here so I can actually start writing
this on multiple lines.
OK.
Next up we want to actually grab the columns we want.
I'm going to end up using the past year class column the sex column the age column the sibling and spouse
parent child column the Fair column and the barked column the other columns.
I don't want to use in order to kind of quickly type this all out a simple trick you can do if you're
using no objects and spark shell in the way I'm doing it say data columns enter and you can be into
just copy and paste some of these.
So I once not passenger ID we really don't survive want P.E. class name sex age parent child ticket.
And then the fair and the embarked and I'm going to delete some of these that actually don't want in
a little bit.
So let's highlight this right click copy and then right click paste.
This should save you some time when you're trying to actually grab features.
Remember these need to have the sort of dollar notation.
So I'm going to set this all up I want peak class I want name enter here I do want the sex of the individual
age aunt's sibling spouse put this back up here.
How many parent child they have.
I don't want a ticket that's not going to be very useful to me because it's just some sort of information
that I don't understand.
Maybe later for future engineering maybe useful Cabane we can just ignore that for now and then embarked.
We will also have that what city they embark on.
OK.
So those are all the columns.
Let's close up these princes.
Make sure they match
and check that they match so survived sear labels their data's selecting their looks like I have one
too many parentheses going to delete that.
OK.
Now that should all work.
I'm going to save this and run it just to make sure that all worked out.
Let's load it up and make sure we have log rig data all OK.
We have our data frame.
Next thing I want to do is actually drop missing values in this case.
We have a few We want to drop and I can do this just by saying log Reg data is going to be able to log
data all day and a drop.
Keep in mind at this point in time this is technically still experimental but it's been around since
Sparke around one point three or 1.6 I want to say.
So it should work just fine.
Now there's a few things we need to deal with before Spahr can actually accept this data.
And this is one of the main focus of the lecture is how to actually deal with these categorical columns.
And we're going to use vector assemblers and vectors.
I want to take a quick tour of the documentation and then in the next lecture we'll actually show you
how to build out these vector assemblers and vectors.
I'm going to save the script as I have it.
Now jump to the documentation.
Explore some of these vector assemblers and vectors with you.
And then we will in the next lecture actually implement this and want to open up my browser and jump
to spark that Apache the org.
All right here Amyt sparked that Apache the org go to documentation.
Latest release programming guides machine learning and then hit here under extracting transforming and
selecting features.
This is where we can actually see all the tools that SPARC has for us for extracting transforming and
selecting features and one of the transformations we have to do is dealing with categorical columns.
We've already seen how to work with vector assemblers and vectors.
But now we need to work with string data that's things such as the gender which was male or female or
the city of embarkation which was s q or C and if you scroll down here you will see that there is a
string indexer.
And basically what the string Incs index or does it encodes a string column of labels to a column of
label in the.
And there's actually an example of how this kind of works here.
You can say the category and then if you have some idea zero it's in Category A B and C you can kind
of think of these as strings of male female or strings of those cities that the passengers were getting
on the ship at.
Then you can use string index to create some sort of category index to convert that to a numerical value.
OK.
And then eventually you can drop the category column because your machine learning algorithm isn't going
to understand how to actually take a letter but it will understand how to take a number.
Now that's one way of doing this but you can actually expand on this by then converting this category
index into what's known as one hot encoding.
And there's real quick.
An example of how to use string indexer which is pretty nice you can refer to this in the documentation
for more details on that API.
But the next one I want to show you that we're going to use in the next lecture is if you scroll back
up here.
One hot encoder and if you're familiar with dummy variables maybe from some of my other courses or just
machine learning or using excel in general you know about 100 coding already because it's pretty similar
to a dummy variable.
Basically what one encoding does is it maps a column of label indices.
Basically the result of the string indexer to a column of binary vectors with at most a single one value.
This encoding allows algorithms which expect continuous features.
In our case logistic regression to use categorical features and that's basically we're going to be doing.
And you can see here that this is exactly the steps we are going to follow.
We'll start with a string indexer that will take in this category ABC etc..
Set some sort of output for it and then fit that data frame then we will transform that data frame and
after that we will use one hot encoder to convert that into columns of binary vectors zeros or ones.
So you'll end up having a column called a with zero or one values.
Was this passenger coming from City 0 for false 1 for true.
Then you'll have another column B which if they show up in a as true B and C will be false etc..
Ok so I encourage you to actually read the docs if you want more details on that API or you can actually
just click here.
One Hutten coding this links straight to the Wikipedia article on what hot if it's a little confusing
for you.
Keep in mind one hot sometimes refers to digital circuits so don't let this sort of stuff confuse you
here.
Basically just think of it as creating what's known as a dummy variables and we'll explain that a little
more than we actually see the output of this one Hotton decoder.
It's not so complicated.
You're just converting string columns into columns of binary zero or one true for that particular string
value.
OK so that's enough of me talking.
Let's move on and actually implement all of this.
I will see you at the next lecture where we will jump right back into the code and actually implement
string indexers in one hot encoders.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.