Hello everyone and welcome to the installing Skala and Sparke lecture for Windows.
Go ahead and skip this lecture if you're not using a Windows computer.
If you are make sure to follow each step exactly as shown in this video lecture there's quite a few
steps in order to make sure everything works properly.
So make sure you have enough time set aside in order to fully watch this video and follow along.
Also make sure to use the referenced link in the resource for this lecture for written instructions
for this video.
Let's go ahead and get started by opening up our browser.
All right here I am at my browser at Google.
The first thing we need to do is actually install a JDK which is known as a Java development kit you
can either just google search for Java development.
Kids enter and the first link should be the one we're looking for.
Or you can just go ahead and click the direct link in the resource lecture.
All right you'll go ahead and scroll down a little bit until you find the correct package here.
Well go ahead and accept the license agreements and then I'm using a 64 bit computer.
If you're using a relatively modern Windows machine 64 bit should be fine for you.
So go ahead and just click here and install will download that XP file.
Ok this is about a 200 megabyte file so give it some time to download.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to the finished download.
All right so now that that has finished downloading the next thing we need is Apache SPARC itself.
You can go ahead and go to spark the Apache dot org or just google search Apache Sparke should take
you to this page and you're going to want to go ahead and click the download.
And then we want to download Sparc and we want to make sure that we get a pre-built for Hadoop SPARC
version.
I'm going to go ahead and use the latest release which is 2.0 0.1 at this time of filming.
Go ahead and use anything that's above 2.0 any version of that should be fine.
But make sure that you have pre-built for Hadoop 2.7 and later then we're going to go ahead and say
direct download and you'll go ahead and click here to download Sparke.
It should be a TGV file which is basically a compressed file format and I've already downloaded it.
It's actually here already.
Again it's a pretty large file so it may take some time for you to download it.
Once we have that let's go ahead and go to those files locations and they'll probably be under Downloads
so you can click here and say show and folder and we see here that we have Sparc and the Java development
kit.
Let's go ahead and install the Java development kit.
I'm going to go ahead and double click that
and then will say next go ahead and choose all the defaults.
Click next and let it run.
And make sure I remember where this was actually saved to the default.
It should just be saved to under your C-drive drive and I'll show you how to find that later on.
Well let's go ahead and jump to this thinnish installation.
OK.
Eventually it's going to ask you about the destination folder.
Go ahead and choose this default one but remember where it is.
So I have under-sea program files Java and then this Gerry file.
So make sure you write that down somewhere or just remember where it is and then go ahead and click
next and then it will continue to install Java and I'm going to go ahead and jump to this completed
installation OK.
It looks like it finished installing I'm going to go ahead and close this.
All right.
The next thing we need to do is actually extract the contents of this TGT file.
Go ahead and write click it and then you're going to want to open it with some sort of unzip program.
In this case I'm going to use 7 dashes zip or 7 zip as my program and other program you may want to
use is when rar w i n r r.
There are some links in the resource.
In case you don't have a program but let's go ahead and just extract here.
So as I mentioned go ahead and check out the resource for this lecture.
In case you need to download one of these sort of files as a quick note for some extraction programs
you may just get a tar file.
If you end up getting a tar file.
Go ahead and Right-Click it and then using your program extract it a second time.
So go ahead and extract that again.
And eventually it should give you a folder that looks like this.
This SPARC 2.0 been Hadoop 2.7 So this is what we're looking for here.
Have the downloads right now.
Go ahead and either use the resource links or use when rar or 7 zip or some program like that in order
to extract the contents of this TGT file if it gives you a tar file instead of this direct folder.
Go ahead and just extract that again and then it should give you the folder of the contents.
All right the next thing you want to do is go ahead and move this SPARC folder to a different location.
That way our programs can find Sparke later on we're going to go ahead and do it under our C-Drive OAC
right click and say new folder and we're going to name this folder.
SPARC all right now that you have this spark folder created we want to go ahead and copy the contents
of that spark download.
So go back to your downloads double click on this Sparke folder and then go in and copy all of this
or cut it and go to that spark folder and paste it all there.
All right there it is.
And that's exactly how we want everything.
So let's go ahead and move onto the next step.
The next thing we need to do is again under your C-drive right click Create a new folder and this folder
is going to be called when you tildes all lowercase.
And in that folder I want you to go ahead and create a new folder and call it Ben and inside this bin
folder we're going to go ahead and place the when you tills start X-Sea file which is downloaded as
a resource.
This is basically going to allow us to work with Hadoop and windows together.
So go ahead and go back to your Downloads folder and as a resource link go ahead and check it out.
But we're going to download this when you Tilse file.
Go ahead and cut it out and paste it back to when you tildes been and then pasted in here.
All right.
So now that's set up we're going to go ahead and continue on with the rest of the setup.
The next step we have to do is actually add user variables and paths to those user variables in order
for Windows to know where to actually find everything that we just downloaded installed.
So go ahead and go to your Windows menu and find your control panel by just saying control panel.
Click on that.
OK so here we have the control panel.
Go ahead and click on system and security then click on system and then we have advanced system settings.
Over here on the left go ahead and click on that and then I'm going to move this over a little bit so
you can see it clearly.
OK.
And then what we would need to do is go ahead and click here on environment variables.
And then we need to add some new environment variables.
So go ahead and click new here.
And this variable name the first one is going to be in all caps Sparke underscore home.
We can go ahead and then type in C call and slash Sparke because that's where we saved spark.
Go ahead and click OK.
And we want to create another one so click new again and this user variables are going to be in all
caps.
Java underscore home.
And this is going to be where we say that JDK in this case we can go ahead and find it.
So if you want you can type in the whole file path if you remember it but you can also just browse through
directory for it go ahead and click on browse directory.
And then go ahead and click this piece see the C-Drive and then we're going to go ahead and look for
under program files Java.
So Program Files.
Scroll down to you see Java right here and then select that JDK folder.
OK.
So basically it's going to be C. Program Files Java and then that JDK folder that we installed earlier
go ahead and click OK.
That's your Java home.
And then finally we need to set the Hadoop home so click new this variable name is going to be in all
caps a dupe underscore home and then Hadoop is actually going to be that when you Tilse full or remade
so you can again browse directory for it.
But if you're falling long it's actually just under C so c when you tills and then click OK.
All right the next thing we have to do is edit our path variable.
So you should already see something here that says path.
Go ahead and select it and click at it most likely if you've done other courses or download other things
or have a bunch of environment variables here or paths under this path User variable go ahead and select
new.
And here we're going to add the spark home path.
So it's going to be percent sign.
SPARC home.
All caps here.
Percent sign.
And then backslash been enter for OK.
Now we're going to add one more and it going to be for the Java home.
So percent sign Java underscore home per cent sign backslash been and then OK.
And there we have it let's go ahead and hit OK and hit OK again an exit out of the control panel.
All right.
Now it's time to make sure that everything actually worked.
Go ahead and open up your command prompt.
You can actually just type in CMD D in it's a search for your command prompt.
Go ahead and click on it.
You should get something that looks like this and then we're going to go ahead and change the directory
to the spark folder.
So go ahead and type in CD for change directory and then say See Colan backslash Sparke hit enter and
now we're located at that spark the rectory and you can actually type in d i r for Windows users in
order to see all the folders here.
So let's go ahead and clear this screen by typing C L S And We have a clear screen or in Sparke.
We'll go ahead and get started by just typing in Sparke dash shell enter.
And you should see a little bit of Spark's default log for Jey profile.
We'll talk about that later but it should start up with the spark shell OK.
There we have it.
Welcome to spark.
Let's go ahead and type in our first line of skulker.
Just our Hello world line will say Prince l n for Prince line open parentheses.
And then with double quotes.
Say hello world.
Close quote.
Hit enter.
Then you should see Hello world pop up.
OK so that's it for this installation lecture.
Later on we'll talk about possible ideas and text editors in order to build out programs that are more
than just a single line of scarlet code.
If you have any questions.
Make sure to check out the resource link or post the Q&amp;A forum member.
There's a lot of steps here and you have to follow them exactly in order to make sure everything worked
out OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.