Hello everyone and welcome to the Skala and spark development environments lecture in this lecture.
We're going to be showing you various options for development environments.
However before we get started I want you to know that you should feel free to choose whatever environment
you personally prefer.
Let's go ahead and discuss our approach to maximize learning in this course.
For this course we're actually going to start off just by using the REPL or read evaluate print's loop
interpreter.
Then we're going to go ahead and move on to using a basic text editor with some Skala plugins and that
text editor will be Adam then we're finally going to move on to a fool idea.
Again you don't have to follow these steps but these particular pathways from going to the interpreter
to a text editor to a fool ideally should maximize your learning process.
But if you want you can also just start with the Fool ID.
Let's go ahead and get started by jumping to our browser showing you the options and then walking you
through how to download our first text editor Adam OK here I am at the browser.
The first idea I want to discuss is the Scala ideally for Eclipse.
Now if you've programmed in Java or maybe some other languages you're already familiar with Eclipse
Scala.
Id eat basically allows you to have a Scala ID with Eclipse and you can go ahead and check out this
Web site.
It says Skala that idea or has lots of features and documentations.
It's definitely a full blown I.T. with features editing debugging highlighting etc. and it's something
she definitely check out.
If you're interested in using a more professional Skala ID is probably the most popular Skala ID on
the market and it's free.
The next idea I want to talk about is Intel A-J idea from Jet brains or idea.
And this is a Java idea but it's actually more than just Java.
You can scroll down and check out the various languages it supports.
But again this is a full ID development environment.
It's going to look a lot like pi charm if you're familiar that for Python that it has what you would
expect code completion frameworks specific assistance things to help you debug intelligence built in.
And like I mentioned it supports Skala.
This is the idea we're going to be using later on this course so you can go ahead and scroll down and
download the community edition.
You can do this now or wait till we actually approach this later on this course.
It's quite a large download so we'll just leave it at that for now.
Later on we're going to come back to this and actually show you how to use this for larger programs
and tasks.
For now we're going to go ahead and move on to text editors.
This is the link for sublime text you can find the sublime text dot com sublime text is just a text
editor for code markup and prose and it works for a variety of languages and basically state text editor.
It's not a full blown idea in the sense that it has debugging capabilities but it does support things
such as syntax highlighting.
It's a very famous text editor is probably one of the most popular out there.
So if you program in something before you may even already have sublime text the text editor we're going
to be using for this course however is Adam.
Adam is from the developers at hub.
It's also a text editor but it has some really nice plug ins for Skala which we're going to be using.
So Adam is the text editor will be using throughout this course before we jump to an idea.
I'm going to go ahead and click download here in order to begin the Adam download.
It's a little lighter than Skala.
Ian Intelli J.
ITA.
So it's about ninety one point five megabytes will take maybe a few minutes to download.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to the finished download.
All right.
So the Dalat has completed.
Let's go ahead and open up that executable file.
Ok when you click that you should see Adam beginning to install and it's going to launch.
Once it's done I'm going to go ahead and jump forward to the finished installation process.
OK.
This is what Adam looks like.
Once it's done installing it's text editor will go ahead and make this full screen here so he can explore
it a little bit.
We're going to go ahead and check out the welcome guide.
What I want you to go ahead and do is click here on install a package you can later checkout.
Choosing a theme for coloring customized in the styling such as font etc..
Well let's go ahead and say install a package and we're going to import.
Scuse me.
Open installer.
And then here under install packages I want you to search for Scala and try to search it's going to
search packages for Skala and you should see here language dash Scala Skala language support.
Adam you'll go ahead and click here to install that.
And basically the really cool aspect of Adam is that it's open source and there's also a lot of support
in community around this specific text editor.
So a lot of people create really cool packages and plug ins for this text editor for various languages.
Now it already has most languages at least the common ones built in as far as syntax highlighting.
But you can go ahead and check out under here install under settings to check various packages that
maybe aren't default installed into Adam.
OK.
So once we have that installed we're basically ready to go.
You can just click file new file and then let's go ahead and say Say Prince l an double quotes.
Hello world.
The book quotes there and I'm going to go ahead and come down here where it says plain text.
Click on that and then start typing Skala to make sure this is actually a scholar file and you should
see now that the syntax highlighting has changed for print line.
Now we can see the hello world is a string and it's going to give us just enough help so that we don't
feel overwhelmed by a fool either.
We're also not totally lost if a blank text editor which is a really nice balance.
At this stage of our learning so we're going to go ahead and save this we'll save file save as and you
can save this basically wherever you want.
Let's go ahead and make a new folder and save it under Sparke.
So good to see Dr good to spark here and I'm going to make a new folder click new folder and call it
my programs open up this folder here and then I want to call this my underscore first program and then
hit save.
OK.
Now let's actually show you how to run this program code.
This my first program I'll go ahead and go to your command prompt again you can just search for it by
typing a command prompt you should see this pop up and then you're going to CD to that folder where
it was saved.
In this case it's my programs so we can see the two or change the directory to see Colin back slash
spark and then we'll go back to see the my programs and I just did tab to autocomplete there.
And now under my programs I'm going to go ahead and start my Sparc shell enter.
This may take a little bit of time to load up but basically once you have spark shell I will show you
how to load up that file you just made.
OK so here's the spark shell.
We can see that the Skala are EPL is ready and loaded.
So let's go ahead and load this program file not to do that.
You just do.
Colin load and then type in my first program.
So remember this has to match exactly as you saved it.
So we're going to say Colin Lote's space my underscore first underscore program is going to load up
my first program and then it prints out Hello world.
Great.
Let's go ahead and confirm that this is actually working by editing our first program file.
So we'll go ahead and change this print line to something that says maybe new line.
So we'll say new line.
We'll go ahead and save that control.
S come back to the command prompt.
And then type in again colon load my first underscore program enter.
Now we can see that it outputs new line.
All right.
Great.
So let's go ahead and quickly review what we discussed in this lecture in this lecture we showed you
various ideal options.
And then we showed you a few text editor options.
We showed you how to install Adam as a text editor how to download the Scala plug in for Adam and then
how to actually run your very first program of Scala code.
Coming up next as we deal with the very basics of Scala Roxi just going to go and input right at the
interpreter Scala code.
Later on we'll move on to actually using the text editor that we've set up here for now as we continue
on through the very basics.
We're just going to actually put stuff straight into the interpreter.
OK thanks everyone.
Do you have any questions feel free to post them to the Kewney forums.
I'll see you at the next lecture.