Hello everyone and welcome to the solutions lecture for the project.
Exercise for the principle component analysis section of the course.
Let's go and get started.
All right.
Here I am.
This is the PCA project exercise thought Skala script and if you want a written reference for everything
going to be coding out you can check it out here and there.
Project exercise underscore solutions that Skala.
Now you start off of the data set description you can read through that.
Let's scroll down until we actually get to the tasks section.
Scroll down.
And here we see Project exercise tasks.
Now the first thing we had to do was import spark and create a spurt session.
That's really easy we've been doing it very often.
By this point in the course we'll say import or Apache that spark that sequel and then call a spark
session and then actually build a spark.
Sessions will save Val Sparke is equal to spark session builder.
We can call the app name whatever we want.
Or you even have to put an app name or call it PCa.
This part doesn't really matter but we just want to make sure we get or create that spark session.
Then we want to use SPARC to read in the cancer underscore data file the check out the cancer underscore
data file.
It's also located here under the PCA folder and just by looking at this we can actually tell it's comma
separated variable.
So that means we should use the C S V as a file format for this.
We can say valid data is equal to spark read.
The option will Hetter to be true because we just saw the file there was a header there and then we
also want to infer the schema that we make sure we get the right schema types so that we're actually
dealing with numerical information instead of string information.
And then I want to say that format is CXXVI and I will ask to load in that file.
And in this case the file is just called Cancer underscore data and there is no extension this case.
I don't want to print the scheme of the data it will say data print schema.
You actually don't have the close princes if you don't want to there but let's slow this up and see
if it works.
Well say load PCA project underscore exercise Skala or you would just run the actual solutions scul
script depending on what you were using.
But here we can see that we have our output on the printed schema.
You can see the mean radius mean texture I mean perimeter mean area etc. and if you scroll the way down
here we see that we have these call names will actually visit that interest a little bit but that's
the actual column names that are left for you you have to type them all out.
Up next.
Let's go ahead and just comment that out so we don't deal with it but we want to import PCA Victor Sembler
and standard scaler from M-L that feature.
So say imports or that Patchi that sparked the M-L the feature and then I'm going to be doing multiples.
I just put this in curly brackets PCa and then call standard scaler and then call vector assembler and
then I want to import vectors from m-L.
Lynn alge so that should be imports or Apache.
That sparked e-mail.
Ouch.
And then just call vectors I don't want to use the vector assembler to convert the input columns to
the cancer data to a single output column of an array called features.
I've done this many times before where we have to basically coalesce all those column features into
a single column with the array of features.
Then we set the input columns from which we are supposed to be the values that we want to call this
new object assembler.
And since there are so many columns I left this line for you this array of the column names which means
all you have to do is this.
We can say Val assembler is equal to a new vector assembler.
Set the input calls to the call names.
The array of column names and then just set the output call to features hopefully that made your life
a little easier.
And then we want to use the assembler to transform our data frame to a single column called features
which means I'll create some value called output and call assembler.
Transform transform that data we have.
And we will just select the actual feature column or features column I should say.
And often it's a good idea to normalize each feature to have a unit standard deviation and or zero mean
when using PCA.
And this is essentially a priest step.
So hopefully you're able to figure out how to do this based off the documentation.
The documentation has a really nice example of how to use this standard scaler It's really similar to
use in the PCA.
But let me walk you through it and in case you were able to figure it out.
Going to create a value called scaler and set that equal to a new standard scalar object.
I'm going to put this all in parentheses so I can write this on multiple lines.
Then let me start a new line here.
Tab.
And then I'm going to set the input columns to be the features column we just created and then I want
to set the output call to be my scaled version of these features.
In this case I'm just going to call it scaled features.
That's what the example in documentation does.
And then I want to say set with SDD meaning set with the standard deviation or pass in the boolean true
for that and set with mean we can go ahead and say whoops false.
And the way you would get these values is just by following the the standard scalar documentation example
exactly.
But basically here you're just choosing the option.
Are you scaling with integrity relation or if the mean true or false etc..
You can check out the documentation example under Mehldau features.
Basically the exact same location of the PCA documentation example.
Now we want to compute summary statistics by actually fitting that standard scalar and we do as you
say create some new value.
This case I will say Val staler model is equal to scalar fit output WIPs.
There it is.
And we want to normalize each feature to some unit standard deviations so you'd transform off of this
scalar model object create your scaled data which means I will say so now scaled data is equal to that
scalar model I just built or just created scalar model.
There it is and then I will say transform my outputs so I fit to the output and then I transform it.
And there's basically those two steps here.
So a normal model instead of a feature usually just fit it and then do something with it.
But in this case we want to fit and transform.
OK.
Now it's time to actually use PCN principal component analysis to reduce the features to some sort of
principal component.
And we want to create a new PC object they'll take in the scale features and output those PCA features
using four principal components and then fit the scale data basically following along with the example
from documentation.
I will say new PCa and then say set the input calls or the input column to be those scaled features
that I just made.
And then I want to set the output column to something like PCA features.
So all I'm doing is I'm taking the features I just scaled and I'm going to basically apply principal
component analysis.
And as I mentioned the last lecture we have this set came at trick and that's how many principal components
you want in this case I asked you to put in four.
And as I mentioned since principal components are difficult to interpret There's no set correct value
for what how many principal components you should choose really depends on what you're trying to achieve
here.
How much do you want to coalesce your data.
And then we want to save fit to the actual scaled data that we just created.
And once your PCa has been it's created and transformed the scale data and call this new data frame
PCA ADF which means I just create that value PCA ZF is equal to that PCA object they just made.
And I'm going to call transform on the scale data.
So again it's another fit transform do.
And then we want to show the new PCA features.
So I'll create some value called results and say PCA DMF and I will select those features just as we
did in the documentation example.
So PCA features and I will say results show but kinda close.
Prince is there and if we also want to use head confirm that the output column array of PC features
only has four principal components I can say results the head of one.
So let me say this.
Let's run it and expand this a little bit so we can see it.
Now I'm going to press up here.
Load up project exercise and make sure everything worked out and I don't have any errors there.
So if we take a look at this I do believe I got one error and here we can see the air.
So just a little quick debugging tip you come up here and see the air dial the input calls is not a
member of standard scalar that makes sense should be just a simple input call not calls plural.
So if I scroll up here to where we have that standard scalar let's fix that to the input call because
it only expects a 1 column feature.
So let's say that run this again and make sure we don't get that same error as we run it a second time.
OK and that's what we expect.
So they can see the output here.
These are our principal component features and we scroll down here and we can confirm that there's only
four principal components based off of what we did.
And that's really all there was to it to this piece of exercise.
Again the PC is pretty simple to do once you have an understanding of how to actually use meld melded
feature objects you set the input call to the features do some sort of transformation of the output
comm fit transform etc..
Do you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But definitely check out the documentation too because they have great examples of how to use each feature
object.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.