Hello everyone and welcome to the data free operations lecture in this lecture we're going to continue
our discussion of data from operations will show you how to do operations such as filtering data from
a data frame based on certain conditions.
Let's go ahead and jump toward sex ed. to get started.
OK here I am at the text editor the skull a script for this lecture is data frame underscore operations
that Skala and we're going to go ahead and start a simple Spark's session grab that same CACP felt that
we've been working with this group 2006 2008 file and then we're going to show you how to do some basic
operations based off of filtering data and let us discuss how to use Spark's sequel as well Scullin
notation to filter and do some operations on that data frame and then we'll show you later on the very
basics of some more complicated operations that we're going to be going over when we talk about grouped
by aggregate functions.
But let's go ahead and start a new script and go ahead and start the spark shell.
I already created the script DFA that skull from the last lecture and I have these three lines of code
just starting that sparked session creating the spark value either get or create that and then reading
we have the options that CFE Citigroup.
Let's go ahead and print the schema one more time so we can actually remember what this looks like one
to say Dia.
The print schema save that.
And then let's go ahead and run this.
Open this terminal a little more clear that and then say load the Skala and it's a quick note usually
don't want to call your skull script the same name as a value or a variable inside of your script.
I'm just doing this because it's really short.
So is isn't going to be typing this.
I want to keep it simple.
OK.
So again the CSP file itself in our data frame has a date the time stamp and then an open high low close
price.
And then the volume of stock that was traded that day.
Let's go ahead and discuss how we can actually filter out data based off of some condition.
So a lot of times you don't want all this data.
You only want data that meets a certain criteria.
So there's two ways or two main ways of filtering out data and one way is to use Sparke sequel syntax
and the other the other way is just easy Skala syntax in order to use that Skala syntax with the dollar
sign notation you're going to need to import Sparke implicit dot underscore and that will allow us to
use the dollar sign Skoll annotation by default.
You can go ahead and use the sequel notation without importing everything.
Now we don't assume that you understand or have any sequel experience.
While it's very likely that you do if you're already this far into discourse and are interested in Sparc
and Skala I'm not going to assume that you have that siecle experience.
So we're going to mainly stick with these Scullin notation although if you do have sequel experience
you'll probably be a big fan of Sparke sequel.
So just keep it in mind.
I'll show you both examples but later on in the course we're going to stick with the scal annotation.
Let's go ahead and show you an example of grabbing all the rows where a column meets a certain condition
in order to do this.
You go ahead and call your data frame object and then call the filter method off of it.
And the skull annotation looks like this.
You put a dollar sign and then the name of the column you want.
For instance the close column and then you go ahead and put in whatever comparison operator you want
to grab some sort of condition.
So for example let's say I want to filter out the data frame where the close column was greater than
$480.
So I can say we're close greater than 80 and then I'm going to go ahead and show that.
So sometimes you would set this as a new value or new data frame.
But since we're just working the Wycliffe's the terminal right now and I want to see these results to
understand how they work I'm just going to go ahead and say that show at the end of this let's go ahead
and run this again.
And here I can see the top 20 rows where the close price here happens to be greater than $480.
Great.
So we can also use equal notation.
Let me go in and show you what that looks like it's going to feel really familiar if you already know
sequel.
But basically in sequel when you have the where statement and then some sort of condition that where
condition is what you're going to pass here.
So for instance if this was a sequel I would say where close.
Greater than 480 and that should give us the exact same result.
If I run the script again and there it is there are the top 20 rows where the closing price is greater
than $480.
OK.
So let's go ahead and discuss how we can do multiple filters.
So you don't always want to just filter by one column.
You want to filter by multiple columns in the skull annotation.
This is really easy.
You just use the and ampersands or the or pipe operators.
So for instance if I want to go ahead and maybe check where the close price was less than 40.
So for instance I want to say close ups less than 480 and then I use Scalia's and operator which is
2 percent so EON's dollar sign Hi is let's say let's go ahead I'll say less than 40 I can go ahead and
show this animal control as to save this and then I'm going to go ahead and enter there to run this.
And here I can see the results.
So you notice that close lesson of 480 and high is less than 40.
OK so that's how you can use multiple conditions there and you can use the pipe operator to do the or
this is the scal annotation.
Let me go and issue the spark siecle notation.
So I'm going to go and just comment this out.
So we don't lose it.
I will say if that filter and again if your experience of sequel you can go ahead and just say close
less than 480 and it's equal you're going to say.
And and usually capitalize it you don't have to.
But by sequel conventions usually capitalized those key words.
And then you can say something like high also less than 480.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And let's actually show this result as well.
Let's make sure this runs and you see here that this also works.
So again these are all based off of Sparke sequel objects in those.
Or that Apache.
So the data Freman data sets and spark sessions all fall under Sparke sequel which is why we're able
to use this sort of sequel syntax with these data frames.
Now again it's up to you what you want to use here.
I'm a fan of sequel and it's makes sense to me so a lot of times my own personal work of using this
sequel iteration but this course does not assume that knowledge but we know that we showed you how to
actually program a scholar.
So we're going to be using the sort of Skoll notation but when it's appropriate I'll show you the alternative
sequence notations in case you're interested.
OK let's go ahead and show you a couple more actions that you can perform on a different.
Right now the main action that we've been showing so the filter's the transformation and shows the action.
But this main action of show basically just shows the results and a lot of times you actually don't
want to see the results you want to maybe save it as something else or maybe count the results etc..
What we can do is instead of showing these results I can use the action collect in order to collect
these results into a scholar object.
And because I'm actually collecting these results into a skull object I'm going to go ahead and save
them as some sort of new or new variables so I will save them all.
Let's go ahead and say S.H. underscore low or something whatever you want to actually do this let's
go in and save that and then I'm going to clear that terminal and run again.
And I should see now instead of actually seeing the results as a data frame I can actually see I've
collected these results as an array.
So now this array contains these row objects where the rows are the rows where this condition happened
to be true.
And this is the way that you can grab the sort of result back and then perform all your Skala operation
knowledge on it.
So then once you have this array you can do whatever you want that you could do if a normal array in
Scotland you can run a for loop through it print out every row.
Scam it for certain objects or certain elements etc..
But the stock collect action is the way that you transform data frames into arrays.
Now keep in mind this array the objects inside of it are still rows.
You can index them just like you would with a normal skull array OK.
Couple more closing points I want to discuss is a rather common method or action here excuse me.
Instead of collect It's actually just do count.
Now we're going to discuss aggregate functions a lot more in detail and we actually get to that by an
aggregation lecture.
But let's go and just show you an example of this.
So instead of actually grabbing the results and saving them as an array let's say only wanted to know
how many results are how many rows or returns I can use the dot count to actually get that result back.
So if I go in and save this clear my terminal and run it I will see at the very end some sort of number.
So in this case S.H. low is 397 in this P-word long just in the case.
This is a long integer.
And if you're unfamiliar of that don't worry about it too much.
It just has to do with the way computers and machines store integers in memory.
But this is just a basic integer 397.
So I know I got 397 results back for my S.H. low.
So that's the counts action.
So again we can think of this as some sort of transformation on this data frame and then some sort of
action on this data frame so we can separate out in our mind that we can stack transformations on top
of each other and they're lazily evaluated so they don't actually occur until you actually perform the
action on them.
OK.
Couple more little tidbits I want to close off with here is if you're trying to filter for equality.
So for instance the filter and you want to figure out where Hy's equal to a specific number.
If you end up saying something like for instance high equals equals what's going to say four eighty
four point four Xerox.
I know that's true and I'll say show you'll get an error at this point in time if you actually run this
so using spark 2.0 point one this returns an error and you'll say something like cannot be applied to
boolean.
What you end up having to do to fix this using Skala notation is to use triple equal signs and then
go ahead and save that.
And then you'll get the results you want.
So if you go ahead and run that you'll notice that now you get the Roback where high happened to be
exactly equal to four hundred eighty four dollars and 40 cents.
This is kind of a weird quirk right now.
Spark data frame's hopefully in future versions.
The double sign or double equal sign notation actually works like you would expect it to.
But for now keep that in mind that you're going to have to use those triple equal signs with the scarlet
notation.
Well you can do instead.
Also if you're familiar with sequel is say equal to and in this case it was forty four point four zero.
Let's go ahead and run that show it.
And you'll notice that this also works exactly the same as you would expect.
So for me if you're familiar a sequel you don't have to worry about that kind of sort of weird quirk.
It'll just work like you expect it to work.
All right.
Now later on in another lecture we're going to learn about aggregate functions in a group by.
But I want to go ahead and show you the various operations and functions that you can perform with Scala
on a data frame an example is correlation.
So let's say you wanted to actually get the Pearson correlation between two columns.
You can say diea that selects and then you're going to passen a built in function.
So in this case the built in function is c o r r for correlation and this is the Pearson correlation
which is going to tell us how correlated are two columns.
And then you can just pass in a.
No need to do any special formatting or a dollar sign in this function.
You pass them in strings high low and then you can go ahead and say that show or collect whatever action
you want to perform.
You can say DFA that select and perform functions on your actual columns and then say that show.
Let's go ahead and see this.
And we should expect after the filter statement a number there and there it is.
It's the correlation between the high column and the low column.
And here we get an extremely high correlation it's almost perfectly correlated.
And that actually makes a lot of sense because that means within a certain day the high price and low
price are roughly going up and down together which makes sense because you don't get such drastic differences
on a day.
So for a relatively stable stock so it makes a lot of sense that for almost all stocks you'll have high
correlation between the high and low column.
If you want to go ahead and check out all the functions that are available to you in all the operations
you can click here on data frame underscore operations at Skala the notes for this lecture.
Scroll down and you should see various examples everything and we just discussed if you keep scrolling
down you'll see here operations and useful functions and commented out.
But go ahead and take this.
Is this your l.
And this takes you straight to the documentation of the latest API.
Go ahead and copy this.
Let's copy this and then I'm going to put this in my browsers are going to go ahead and jump to my browser
and here you are at the URL and you can see that there's objects functions and these are all the functions
available for a data frame and you should note that some of these will have an experimental tag on them
so if you scroll down eventually see some stuff this is experimental so keep that in mind.
If you're working in a production environment you don't want to use experimental stuff on things that
are really important and can't break.
But other than that you have a ton a ton of functions and operations here and we're going to be discussing
a lot of these as we continue on through this section of the course.
But I just wanted to let you know that you can basically use all these functions just like I should
that simple correlational on.
So let's say for some reason you wanted to get the inverse cosign or the arc cosign of a particular
column.
Well you come here to the math functions section.
Check out see that they have a S.O.S for cosign.
See the description here computes the cosign inverse of the given column the return angle etc..
Some information about that but more importantly it says how it expects to actually get the input and
just like the functions that you've developed.
So here the function is called a S.O.S.
And it expects a column name as a string.
So if we actually check out the correlation function that we used earlier I went ahead and searched
for here.
It's c o r r.
And here we can see that there's the Pearson correlation.
So this actually works two ways.
One way is just say C or R and pass in the column name one is a string column name two as a string or
what you can actually do is pass in the column itself.
So I remember from one of the previous lectures we show that one way of just calling a column is say
DSF.
And then in parentheses pass in the column name that returns the actual column object.
So this particular function works on both the string or the actual column however you want to pass it
and you can check out the various operations and functions that are available to you.
So we don't have enough time to go through all of these because there are so many.
Hopefully you can see how useful some of these are.
And for certain of these says Date Time functions we actually have whole lectures devoted to exploring
these sections a little more.
But what I would encourage you to do is kind of play around these check them out.
There's a ton of math functions.
Miscellaneous functions non area functions you can check out string functions.
So if you ever have a lot of string data you want to compute things such as the length of the string
or lowercase the string uppercase etc..
Regular Expressions it's all available to hear it's built in and it's ready to go.
So hopefully now you're really starting to see how powerful the data frame structure in Scala is for
you and how a lot of the work has already been put into pre-built functions and you can check out the
link in the documentation.
It's right here and there SPARC that Apache that org and it's in your notes.
OK thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.