Hello everyone and welcome to the project exercise overview lecture for the clustering of Sparke section
of the course and this lecture will have a brief overview of what you can expect for the project.
Exercise.
Let's jump to the script and get started.
All right.
Here I am.
I've opened up the Kamins underscore project underscore exercise thought Skala script and basically
we're going to be doing is trying to cluster clients of a wholesale distributor based off of the sales
of some sort of product categories and this data source actually comes from you see Irvine's machine
learning data set repository.
And there's a link here.
I'm going to copy and paste this into my browser and show you a little bit about it.
All right.
So if you go to that link it will take you here to use the eyes machine learning repository and UC Irvine
has a great repository of real data sets that you can access for free and play around with in order
to test machine learning algorithms.
And in this case we're going to be looking at a Portuguese data set on wholesale customer data.
And basically what this data set refers to is a wholesale distributor and it includes annual spending
on specific product categories and what you'll try to do is cluster them into specific regions.
So based off of spending information such as fresh milk grocery frozen delicatessen detergents cetera.
So how much the annual spending on fresh milk for particular regions you'll try to cluster them and
in this case we actually have three regions.
We have this one or Port-Au and then other regions so 316 77 and 47 for a total of 440.
And what you'll try to do is based off of these attributes.
See if you can cluster them into three specific regions.
Now keep in mind in this case you actually already have the label.
So you would technically already know the answer in order to treat this as an unsupervised learning
problem.
We're just going to be dealing with these first seven attributes.
Fresh milk grocery frozen delicatessen channel.
Cetera.
You can check out the actual download for the data set by clicking here on data folder.
And here's a CSP file and it should also be included under your clustering folder.
Now one more thing to know if you want to explore more about the machine learning repository you can
just click here to view all the data sets.
And here you can actually browse through based off default task data types area a number of instances
how all the data set is number of attributes etc..
So I encourage you to play around for a lot of these datasets.
They're really great to work with and gain some real experience working with real data.
Now let's jump back to the script and here we are back at the script and basically what you're going
to be doing it's just like the other project exercises you're going to complete the tasks below that
are commented out here.
So you're going to import a spark session create your clustering algorithm load the wholesale customer
data etc..
And in this case the following columns are going to be used for training.
You're just going to be using fresh milk grocery frozen detergents paper and delicatessen.
You actually use data channel or region data because that's essentially almost a label.
So you're just using based off of the sales of these various groups or products can you actually predict
what region they come from.
Then you're going to import vector assembler and vectors etc. create that features column create a Kamins
model and eventually just cluster the algorithm and show the result very close to what we did in the
actual example so you can refer to the example if you need a little bit of guidance.
And if you can't figure something out you can always refer to the solution script or to the solutions
video coming up next.
All right I hope you guys enjoy the project.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.