Hello everyone and welcome to the data framed group by an aggregate functions lecture this lecture.
We're going to show you how to use group by way of a data frame as well as actually perform aggregate
functions after a GROUP BY statement on your data frame.
Let's go ahead and jump to our text editor to get started.
All right so here I am at the text editor the Skala a script that goes along with this lecture.
Isn't there a spark.
Data frame's folder and it's called by underscore and underscore A-G for aggregate methods or functions.
And you can check it out here we're basically going to be showing you how to use some basic group by
functionality meaning to actually group rows by a column and then performing some sort of every function
on it.
We'll show you that and then we'll also show you how to actually perform some other aggregate functions
using the select statement with some other function names there and then we also show you briefly how
did the use ORDER BY NOW something to note here is we're going to be using the sales that CSC file that's
also located in the spark data frames.
So go ahead and just copy these import lines in the DFA setup line that we have everything set up the
same way I do.
I went ahead and created a new Skala script called L.E..
For a lecture that Skala and I copied the first three code lines so starting a spark session importing
that and then I'm going to go ahead and read the sales that see s feed data.
Let me go ahead and print the schema and show you what this data frame looks like so we understand we're
actually working with here.
Now go ahead and say DFI print schema and then see just say DFT.
Sure because this is a relatively small sales file.
Or C every file we should be able to see it.
Let's go ahead and load Elly's see that Skala and run that.
And as you can see already started my Sparc shell.
OK expanding this terminal to see the output.
You can see that we have a company is a string a person as a string and then sales as an integer.
And here we have company.
So we have Google Microsoft and Facebook.
We have a particular person that works at that company and then their sales number for that quarter
or a year.
So we're going to want to do is group by certain columns and then perform an aggregate function on the
remaining numerical columns.
So for instance let's say we wanted to group by the company column so grouped together everyone from
Google everyone from Microsoft and own from maybe for Facebook.
So we can do is say DMF dot and then you're going to say group capital B Y group by and then you put
the column name.
No dollar sign just a string of the column name for instance company let's go ahead and save that.
And if we don't ask for anything on top of that group by you won't get anything out
what spark will report back to you is that you have a sequel and what's known as a relational grouped
data set.
So that's what it calls this group by object a relational grouped data set.
Once you have that group dataset where we can go ahead and do is call aggregate functions off of it.
Now there's many functions you can use but some of the most common ones are things such as find the
mean and we can go ahead and add show to this command so that we actually see it as an output.
So if I run this again I mean and that show will go ahead and run this.
And what SPARC will do is it will take any numerical columns it will go ahead and take the mean or average.
And note how it actually changes the column name.
Here it says AEG.
Sales.
And now we can see the mean sales across the company.
And later on you can add options if you don't want to see this long of a floating point number but you
can also do things such as count.
So if we wanted to actually count the number of instances we can say group buy in off that group project
called accounts so we have three employees from Google to Facebook and three at Microsoft and the other
ones that are really common to use are things such as Macs that are going to go ahead and just copy
this.
We can see all of them at once.
Men is another really common one.
And then some.
All right so all we're going to be doing is reporting back the max values and the minimum values as
well as the sum of all these sales values are these numerical columns when you group the data by the
company call.
So let's go ahead and save that and run it and we'll see three little reports back.
Here we have the Mac sales.
So whoever had the Mac sale at google it was 340 whoever had the Mac sale at Facebook it was 8 7 the
600 at Microsoft et cetera they can see the minimum sales amount and then we can see the total sum of
sales because if Facebook had the total sum of the sales to be the largest.
All right.
So we can go ahead and show you a couple of more aggregate functions.
If you go to the actual lecture notes there's a link here.
So if you scroll to the left and then go down you will see a link to the aggregate functions page in
the documentation.
And here you can see a bunch of examples instead of just typing all of these out.
I'm going to go ahead and copy these.
And these are aggregate functions that you call off a column.
And unlike a group by your just calling aggregate function off a particular column not by a group by
statement.
So what that means is for instance let's say I wanted to get the sum of all the sales not grouped by
company then I would say something like this DFA that selects and here I would put in my aggregate function.
So you can see here their standard deviation.
But in my case I could say something like this if that selects the aggregate function I want SU M for
some the column I want to perform it on such as the sales column and then in this case I can either
collect it to return it back as an array or if I just want to show it in the terminal.
I can say that show let's go ahead and run this.
I'm going to comment some of these out so you don't get a whole lot of output but we can see the basic
pattern.
We're doing an aggregate function DFA that selects the aggregate method or a function and then that
show or collect the painting what kind of action you want to perform on this transformation.
So I'm going to go ahead and run this code.
And we should see quite a few little data frames pop up as a result.
Okay great.
So here we're working of a numerical column can see things such as the sum of distinct sales count of
distinct sales some of total sales which in this case are going to be the same.
The variance if you want the standard deviation of the sample and you can even collect sets.
So as I mentioned there's a link here which has the link to all the aggregate functions that you can
use and going to go ahead and copy this and show you the aggregate function.
So we've actually already explored the functions page a little bit.
Let's go ahead and touch a little more detail on the aggregate functions you're going to go ahead and
jump to this.
You are LMI browser now.
OK.
Here I am at that functions page and you'll notice that the very first group of functions are these
aggregate functions.
And basically when you're using an error function without that group by statement all it means is that
you're aggregating an entire column all the rows in that column into a single output.
Now that output could be a single array of multiple values but the basic idea is that you're going to
aggregate all those rows of information into a single result.
So for something that's really obvious such as average you just take the average of all the values in
that group and you can see the format that the aggregate function expects its input in either expects
the column name as a string for using the select statement or you can just pasand the column itself
so something like DPF open parentheses and then passen sales but hopefully you can see here that you
have a lot of options for aggregate functions things such as counting distinct checking what is first.
So the first value in a column grouping columns kurtosis a lot of statistical information here Max means
men skewness stereo deviation and much more of the sum of the stink that cetera variance.
So you can go ahead and check this out.
A lot of these sort of terms will feel familiar if you're already familiar forking of sequel things
such as first or count distinct.
There's a very sequel like concept but hopefully you can see here the power of referencing these area
functions in case you ever want to get more information from a particular column.
But that's basically all there is to it.
When you're dealing with either a group by statement or an aggregate function Let's go ahead and jump
back to the text editor.
All right.
Here I am back.
So just to briefly review what we covered you can either say DFA group by and then cause some sort of
aggregate method off of this.
And basically what this does for you is it performs the aggregate method in chunks based off of what
you grouped by.
So in this case grouping by the company performs the aggregate method in the chunks of the company.
But if you don't want to use it group by statement instead you can just not worry about a distinction
by another column and performant aggregate function off every single row in that column.
So that's the difference between group buy versus just putting the arrogant function by itself.
Now finally let's go ahead and show you how to order by with sparks and spark data frames.
If you want to order your results actually quite easy you just say ADF dot order by so our lips order
by capital B there and then you just input the colony on to order by.
So for example I'm going to order by the sales and say Dot show and I will show the original data frame
when we read it and so say DMF that show that we can see the order.
So if I go ahead and clear this and run that scripts going to go ahead and expand the terminal so you
can see the results.
So the original See S We had everything already an order of the company.
So Google Microsoft Facebook but we can actually order by a particular column such as sales here and
now it goes from lowest to highest sales if you want the sales to be in descending order here we can
see that they are in ascending order.
You can just use some Skoll annotation for that.
Well you end up doing.
And it's a little funky but you can say dollar sign.
And then the string of the column name that you say dot D E C for descending.
Let's go ahead and save that and then we should see the results but in a descending order now based
off the sales column for go ahead and run this we can see now we had the descending column of sales.
All right.
That's really all there is to it as far as using group by or aggregate functions.
I definitely recommend you check out that link in the lecture notes just to see all the options that
are available to you for aggregate functions.
OK.
Hopefully you enjoy this lecture.
It's going to be a really useful method when you're dealing with large data sets to group them by a
particular column and then get some more information or just perform aggregate functions on a particular
column without the group by statement.
Thanks everyone and I'll see if the next lecture.