Hello everyone and welcome to the walk through example lecture in the regression where sparks section
of this course in this lecture we're going to walk you through an example of that actually implement
Linaria Gresham line by line.
Let's jump to our text editor to get started.
All right.
Here I am at the text editor I've opened up the Lin Regg walk through that Scala script.
This is the script we are going to be walking you through will set up everything and explain line by
line what's actually happening here.
The text data will be working with is this USA housing data.
This contains various columns such as average area income average area housing age number of rooms.
Number of average bedrooms the population address of the house.
And finally this price column is what we will try to predict with a regression model based off of all
these other features.
What does the actual price of the house.
Let me start a new script and start coding this out.
I will send you file.
You will call this LR Scala and let's begin.
First thing we want to do is import or Apache that spark that sequel and say spark session that's going
to allow us to actually build or get or create that spark session and then we also need to import Apache
the spark M-L regression and we will be using linear regression and later on if you want.
You can use different regression models and one less import.
I will do a peer is say or that Apache log for J underscore.
Import everything there and that will say logger get logger person org here.
And then we will set level 2 level dot error in all caps and that's just going to allow us to see a
little bit less as far as the reporting back of the warnings.
Now let's start a simple Sparke session.
We'll say vowel Sparke Sparke session builder and then gets or creates.
Keeping it simple right now not even giving an app name.
And notice I'm not even putting all of this into a function because I want us to really play around
with this to understand that.
Now the next step is to actually prepare the training and test data something to know is the way that
these machine learning algorithms take in data is in a very specific format.
It's essentially just a data frame of two columns with the first column being the label column and then
the second column being a column consisting of arrays of all the feature values and we will show you
how to actually do that with your data.
So I will say valid data is equal to spark that read this option.
And I will set the header to be true and it can pass and strength's here should be fine.
Now that option in first schema to also be true that what we actually get the data types we expect
and then say format's we expect they see as we form it.
And then finally we want to actually passen where the file is located.
In this case the file is actually located in the same regression folder that we're in.
So I can just say load USA underscore housing CXXVI and you'll have to check the pending on the file
whether or not to pass and that extension.
All right.
So we have our data loaded up.
Let's go ahead and just print the schema we'll say print schema save this and now let's run this mixture
everything works.
So to run this I will load all our thoughts Skala and then hit enter.
All right we've imported everything and we can see now the printed schema we have average area income
the housing age average number of rooms average number of bedrooms.
The area's population the price of the house to double and then the address something we are going to
want to do is to make sure that our formatting is correct.
So we will have to make all these new airco columns B in a single features column with an array of each
of those values.
Ill probably have to drop off address since we dont know how to actually use text data just to see an
example of what the data looks like.
Let's walk through how to actually print out each row of data.
So we will print out an example row instead of printing up scheme.
If you say data head and then say one saving that and then loading this up again.
You'll notice that you get an example here and what we can do is actually loop through the columns of
the data.
I will go in and just copy that for loop script so we don't spend a bunch of time walking it here.
All we can say if we scroll up here this little for loop is going to just nicely print out a row in
all the values for it.
So we'll save this you know what we're doing here is just grabbing columns.
Grab that first row in the column and then just print out that column and then that first row value.
This is just a nice way of displaying an example of everything that's in the data frame.
As far as what a typical Roe would look like so we can see an address typically looks like this.
The price for this particular house is this area population for this house is this average number of
bedrooms in the area of the house has four bedrooms etc. rooms and this is just a nicer way of presenting
that data than the head that we saw earlier which is kind of ugly but it's up to you whether or not
you want to use that.
This is just a little example script for you.
Copy and paste.
In case you ever want it now more importantly we need actually discuss how to set up a data frame for
machine learning.
As I mentioned it needs to be in a very specific format.
It needs to be in the format of a data frame.
It looks like this.
Labels or label is one column.
And then features is another column where features is just an array of values.
So let's use vector assembler in order to actually create this.
Now I will need to import this.
Usually you would do this all at the top of the script but I'm separating out my imports to the relevant
sections.
That way when you review this it's easier for you to understand.
So we need to say that Apache that sparked the M-L feature dot and then say vector assembler and one
other thing I want to do is say or at Apache that spark that m-L.
Lynn Owch an import vector's.
All right first thing we need to do is actually grab the label column.
Now the label we are trying to predict is the price of the house.
So let's go ahead and rename the price column to label column for naming convention and also only want
to grab the numerical columns from the data.
So here's a quick trick.
In order to do this rumor that since we're using everything not an object we can actually call in SPARC
shell data columns.
And get back the columns themselves which is going to be nice when we actually need to type these out.
So I will say Val DSF is equal to data.
Select and then I will select the price column as label
and then everything that's numerical.
So I want the average area income average house age average number of rooms average number of bedrooms.
Area population.
I don't need the price because that's already here label and I don't want the address because we can't
use this text radio for a linear regression model.
We will copy that pasted in and then we will just edit it.
Let's make sure it's actually lines up correctly.
And I will wrap this in parentheses so I can use this under multiple lines.
So let's start making some lines here.
Won't say tab and then I just need a raptus in dollar sign quotes.
So let's do that.
For all of these column values so you'll know as you're working more and more with Sparke data frames
it's actually pretty tedious to make sure everything's in the correct format.
As you'll notice that I'm doing here this isn't exactly very fun but the main advantage is that once
you have everything set up it's going to be instantly parallelizable across a distributed set of data.
And the reason I have these outside princes is just to wrap everything in multiple lines.
If I don't do that I need to have everything in a long single line which isn't really good practice.
So we will go onto the next step.
So I've selected my data.
Let me save this.
Run this and make sure it all worked.
So let's load L.R. that Skala run this.
And here we see DFAC So if I say DMF print schema then you can use.
You can just use tab autocomplete there.
You'll notice now I have label and then my numerical columns.
That's the data frame we are going to be working with.
Now now I need to use an assembler and that's the vector assembler what the assembler does.
It will convert the input values to a single vector which is necessary because a vector or an array
is what the machine learning algorithm needs to actually read to train the model.
So we will set the input columns from which we are supposed to read the values and then set the name
of the column or the vector will be stored.
So we will say Val is assembler.
Wups is equal to new.
And here's where we will call vector assembler.
So create a new vector assembler object and then you will set input columns end here you pass in an
array of the input columns you expect to receive.
In this case I expect to receive all my feature columns.
So you don't include label here and in that case I can actually just copy these from the slide here
so I can copy this paste it in.
And this actually just except strings.
If you read the documentation it will tell you it just needs the street names which means you don't
actually need these dollar sign notations for Skala.
And I'll put this all in one line even though that's a little bit about practice.
But just to make it maybe a little more recognizable as far as what we're doing.
So I'm saying vector Sembler set the input columns.
I'm sending an array of all the feature columns as my input columns here.
And the last thing I want to do is actually set the output column and in this case the output column
should be called just features.
So let me put this at the very end.
Here so I will say that sets out put call and just in lowercase features and then I will put a closing
parentheses here to actually split this up into multiple lines.
Now that we have everything written out and then I will put the closing Quincy's there.
And then let's format everything a little nicer.
And then put that in one more line and there we have it.
All right so what's actually happening here.
I'm creating a new vector assembly assembler object set my input columns what goes in there.
Well it's an array of all the string column names.
And then I need a set output columns to just features what this actually does is it takes in all those
columns in your data frame puts them into an array of a single column called features.
Now let's go ahead and say Val output is equal to assembler that transform transform that data frame.
And then I will selects the label column and the features column.
Let's run this.
Make sure it all works.
And then we will explain why we're just selecting labels and features helps load L.R. Scala
expand this a little bit and see what we have.
All right.
So we went ahead and imported vector Sembler got vectors there.
We created this data frame which is just a numerical information with the label.
Then we said assembler is this vector assembler and this output here if I check out what the output
actually looks like.
So I say output show notice here that the format is label which in this case is the price and trying
to predict and features and features is an array.
So all the features that I have are now under a single column as an array of features.
And this is the formatting we need to actually work with the machine learning library in SPARC.
Now if I happen to have not said select here so we will comment that out let me show you what happens
if I just say assembler that transformed the f.
In fact since we are dealing with everything I can actually just copy and paste this into spark shell
and this should work
OK.
So notice what we have here.
We actually keep in all the remaining columns and just add a features column at the end which is why
we need to select only label and features.
So if I say come at this out save this run this again.
Whoops.
LR load that Skala expand my terminal until this shows and then I say output that show that will happens
here.
I get all the old columns.
So not only do I have label and then all my old columns and features I need to just have label and features
which is why we use that select statement.
So vector assembler creates that new column.
But that doesn't mean it gets rid of all these old columns which is a reminder to you to remember after
you do the assembler transform that old data you need to select only the columns you need in that case
its label and features.
All right.
So we have that ready to go.
Now it's time for the fun part which is actually creating our linear regression model object training
and fitting it and then seeing the summary.
I'm going to go ahead and stop the video here.
We'll quickly review what we've done and in part two will go ahead and create the model and finish off
with this lecture that as a reminder what have we done so far.
Well we imported the spark session imported the linear regression model we haven't used that yet.
The These two lines just to see less errors or less warnings I should say went ahead and created the
spark session read in the see every file which was true inferring the schema.
And then this is probably the most important part of what we've done so far this vector assembler and
setting up the data as we need it.
And this label and features array.
You select the data.
In this case you want to make sure that whatever you're trying to predict that label is called label
as a column name then you grab all the numerical columns in this case.
Later on we're going to explore how to deal with categorical columns.
String information but right now we're dealing with simplified data where everything's just numerical.
Once you've done that you go ahead and say create a new vector assembler set the input columns as an
array and then set the output columns as features.
And you just passen your features as an array.
Then you say assembler transform this data frame that you have here that old data and you only want
to select that label column and this newly created features column.
Then you have everything set up for your machine learning model which we're about to cover in the next
lecture.
Have any questions.
Go ahead and review the notes or feel free to post to the Kewney forums.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.