Hello everyone and welcome to the overview lecture for the skull a programming assessment test for the
assessment test of this section of the course you're going to be given some problem statements and you'll
have to write some code in the form of a function in order to solve the problems.
Let me go ahead and just walk through the general problem statements now.
All right.
Here I am with the assessment test.
So basically we are going to have to be doing is creating functions to solve these following questions.
It's not a huge assessment tests or just five questions.
The first one wants you to write a function that takes an integer and returns a boolean indicating whether
or not the integer was even.
And I also want you to see if you can write this in one line.
That's not necessary but see if you can figure out how to do that as a little bonus.
You may want to refer to the notes on the function section in order to do that.
Then the next one is to check for evens in a list.
So building off of that last question I want you to write a function that returns true if there is an
even number inside of a list.
Otherwise return false.
Then the next question is known as lucky number seven.
We'll go ahead and taken a list of integers and calculate.
There are some however sevens are lucky.
And so they should be counted twice.
Meaning their value is actually 14 for the sum.
And you can assume that the list that's passed into the function is an empty next question.
Can you balance given a non empty list of integers.
Return true if there is a place to split the list so that the sum of the numbers on one side is equal
to the sum of the numbers on the other side.
So for example given a list of 1 5 3 3 you were to return true because you can actually split that list
right in the middle where one plus five is equal to six and three plus three is also equal to six.
As another example a list of 7 3 4 would also return true because you could split that list at seven
and then three and four added together is also equal to 7.
So just the idea is there somewhere in that list where you can actually split it and have the sum of
both sides equal to each other.
And remember you just need to return the boolean not that split index points and then finally just a
quick question here the palindrome check where if you're given a string return a boolean indicating
whether or not that it is a palindrome which just means it spelled forward and backwards the same.
And you can try exploring various methods to help you out here.
OK.
Good luck on this assessment test.
It shouldn't be too hard but it should be a little bit of a tick up in that challenge versus some of
the other assessment tests you've had in the past.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture where we will coach through the solutions.