Hello everyone and welcome to the solutions lecture for the project.
Exercise for the classification for machine learning of Sparke section of the course.
Let's jump straight to the project exercise to get started.
All right.
Here I am at the project Skala scripts.
Let's scroll down and get started.
I want to complete the comment to tasks below.
Just scroll to left a little more.
First thing we need to do is import a spark session and logistic regression.
Let's start off of that.
Hopefully by now you're beginning to memorize some of these common import commands so you'll say import
or that Apache that spark M-L classification.
Logistic Regression.
And then I want to say import or Apache that sparked that sequel spark session then optional.
We can use the following code that will be available to you but Scheck's just from the solutions.
If you want to have this error reporting totally optional up to you next you want to create a spark
session will save Val spark is equal to spark session and then we want to say builder and then get or
create.
Then you want to use Sparke to read in the advertising see file so this advertising see as we file if
you open it should look something like this to see if we file.
So let's use Sparke don't read that option.
It will save Velle data is equal to spark read option and you notice that when I look at the CC file
it has a header to it.
So I will say header true as one of my options and then as another option I'm also going to ask to infer
the schema since I have mixed data types in my CSP file.
I will say for schema to be true.
And then I want to save formats is CSFB and then I want to say load and passen advertising C is free.
This should actually be lower case a then I want to print the scheme of the data frame so will say data.
Print schema is often H me save this and run it just to make sure everything's working so far.
I've already started a spark cell so will say load and then log Reg project Skala and hit enter OK.
Perfec we have the schema printed out.
I can expand that to explore it.
We have the daily time spent on that site.
The age area income daily Internet usage ad topic city male country.
A time stamp call on which will work with later and then clicked on ADD yes or no.
Next we want to actually display that data.
Lots of ways to do this.
You can use a for loop as shown on the solutions or really easy ways to say they are ahead hit enter
and you will get printed out a row of the data frame.
Now keep in mind if you're putting this all into an object you won't be able to play around of stuff
as we do here in Sparke shell.
Which is why we don't use the object notation yet.
Then we want to set up the data frame for machine learning.
There's a couple of things we need to do here.
We need to rename the clicked on add column to label.
We want to ground the following columns.
Are listed here for us and then we want to create a new column called Our from the time stamp containing
the hour of the click and to keep in mind that we don't actually need to do all of this in this exact
order.
You just need to come out with the same result at the end.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
By starting off creating this our column.
So create a new column called our.
I'll say all time data is equal to data with column and hopefully a member from the previous lectures
and spark data frame dates and time stamps.
You can just say our and then passen the column itself.
In this case it's called time stamp.
Capital-T
and then off of that I'm going to say Velle log.
Reg data is equal to this time data and I want to select the clicked on ADD clicked on add a column
as label and the next the other things I want to selects are all the columns.
So in this case to put this on multiple lines I'm going to reprint sees an open print cease here so
I can type on multiple lines here.
So I will also close this off print sees may do a tab here and now.
Let's start off by putting in the actual columns who want I want.
And they're actually all listed here and the directions daily time spent on site h cetera.
So daily time spent on sites that I want h.
Let's make sure that's in double quotes.
Then I also want the area income.
And then I also want the daily
Internet usage.
And then finally I want our column we just created.
I also want that mail column indicating whether or not this person was a male and we can actually just
close this off right here.
So I will take this print seas close it put it right here we can actually put this on the next line
and close that office just for formatting purposes.
So we've done so far we selected clicked on ADD as label and then daily time spent on site age area
income daily Internet usage our and then mail.
Let me make sure everything's right.
One thing to note is that here in the directions it says Select time stamp.
But what it wants you to do.
Select time stamp and then convert that into a column called our.
Make sure you don't have that time stamp column here on your final logistic regression data.
Otherwise you may get an error because time stamped information is not going to be compatible with the
logistic regression algorithm.
Instead we want just our which is going to end up being a digit from somewhere 0.24 OK.
So next we want to import vector assembler in vectors.
So I will say imports or Patchi sparked the of feature and then I want vector assembler.
Next they will say import or Apache.
That sparked the animal.
Ouch.
And I will import vector's we save this.
Next we want to create a new vector a similar object called the Sembler for the feature columns as the
input set and the output columns to be called the features just like we've done multiple times before
we need to make sure that our data frame is in the correct format.
So I will say this Velle assembler is equal to open and close.
Prince is here to work on multiple lines O.S. new vector assembler code parentheses and then it will
say Dot set in put calls to.
And this is going to contain an array and it's just an array of all the columns we just typed out.
So let me go ahead and just grab them here and then it will deletes the actual dollar signs so grab
that going to us right click copy.
Scroll down.
Right click paste.
So that's my array of columns.
Let me make sure to delete these dollar signs because we just want them as strings.
And then make sure my princes are balanced here.
OK.
So those are my input columns.
And then finally I want to set my output call ups Peetie call and that's just going to be called features
as always.
All lowercase.
Let me save that and let me run this to make sure all my princes are balanced.
I'm doing a lot of stuff on multiple lines.
Running that looks like we're good to go.
Perfect.
And I can actually just close that princes off here.
So so far we have our vector assembler ready to go next we want to use random split to create a train
to split 30.
So I will say that all array training test is equal to log Regg data dot random splits.
And then we pass in an array.
We want training to be 0.7 and the test to be 0.3.
Basically the way this works is this point seven lines up with the first item in the story which is
training the 0.3 lines up with the second item in that area which is test.
And if you want you can also add a seed to this.
I had a seat in just so if you're following along you can make sure your results match up to mine.
Common see is just one two three four five.
How will you get the same random split that I do.
Next we want to set up the pipeline and this is going to make our life a lot easier using pipelines
instead of just putting everything onto an actual model.
I will say import or puckey the spark the M-L the pipeline and then I will create a new pipeline with
the stages assembler and L R but whoops I forgot I skipped the step.
I want to create a new logistic regression object called L-R.
Let me cut this and paste it here.
Now I want to create an eulogistic Russian soci.
Well L-R is new logistic regression close parentheses.
Then I can create a pipeline well pipeline.
This is going to be a simpler pipeline than what we used in the example walkthrough lecture of course
just a pipeline with essentially just two stages here.
The stages are passes an array and the stage is just an assembler and then the logistic regression model
itself that we want to fit the pipeline into the training.
So we'll say well model is equal to Pipeline.
Fit as in training.
And then we want to get the results on the test set with transform.
So I will say that all results equals modeled transform test save this we will run this make sure we
don't need to debug any mistakes but we should see everything clear out and then we will be able to
actually call the results and see what they look like and this may take a little bit of time depending
on how fast the computer is as far as running everything.
If you run this on a cluster it would be much much faster.
All right ends up it was actually already done it just needed to expand this command prompt here.
All right we have our actual results if we say results that show actually that print schema
we can see we have a prediction and a probability and also a what's known as a prediction.
And then the label it's the integer.
Now we can evaluate how well our results did for this right now we're going to use this semi outdated
multiclass metrics.
Again make sure you check the lectures surrounding this one in case there's an extra notes and check
the Q&amp;A forums.
I will make sure to post there if anything's changed but we'll just say import orgullo Apache that spark
M-L lib evaluation evaluation.
And they will say multiclass metrics and I earlier noted that the newer machine learning is sometimes
just called M-L and the older oddity is called Emsellem.
The reason for that is this because ardy the stuff you imported from sparked the M-L lib you were stuff
you import it from SPARC that came out.
So keep that in mind if you ever hear someone say Sparke MLS that a spark at Bell lib.
Next I want to say well I will just call this prediction and all labels as we've done in previous lectures
will say results selects and then you'll select the prediction column and we'll select the label column
and I need to convert this to an R D D.
You can reference lecture notes for this but you just say double double and then RTD lowercase.
They want to instantiate a new multiclass metrics object so I will say yvel metrics is equal to New
multiclass metrics.
And then pasand those predictions and labels.
Next I want to actually print out that confusion matrix.
I will simply just say Prince L.N. confusion matrix and then I will say Prince Elen actually off the
metric subject.
Grab the confusion matrix.
Capital M their matrix.
OK save all that and let's make sure this thing actually works.
Hopefully it runs with no errors.
It's funny Dr. Sembler pipelined classification is looking good.
Got a results and there is a confusion matrix and I spell confusion wrong.
But other than that no errors.
OK perfect.
If you evaluate this model looks like that pretty good.
It only mislabelled 8 points makes sense because the state is actually pretty well separated.
Let me quickly review everything we did here.
This should have been a pretty straightforward assignment especially if you went through the walk through
example earlier in the section of the course.
But as a quick final run through let me just tell you everything we did.
We got our data imported logistic regression and SPARC session set the error reporting created a spark
session.
You Spark's read in the advertising file printed the schema splayed some of the data using head.
We grab the time stamp and set it to be our cause we can't use just time stamp information.
So a little bit of feature engineering here then grabbed the actual features we wanted.
Make sure that the clicked on ADD was set as label.
Then after that we need to import vector Sembler and vectors to actually put all these feature columns
to an array called features actually set up vector assembler.
Split the data into a training and test set.
Then we imported the pipeline create a new logistic regression object actually set the pipeline if it
stages fit to the training data then transform the test data and then violate the results.
Using this kind of older multiclass metrics All right.
That is for the solutions here.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Kewney forums.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.