Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the walk through example for regression with Sparke.
Let's jump right back in where we left off last time and jumped to the editor for a script.
All right.
Here I am at the script right where we left off last time.
Let's quickly review what we did last time we went ahead and imported sparks session in linear regression
set the level of the warning to just error.
That way we saw less output.
Then we created a separate session.
We went ahead and read in our CXXVI data and since the formatting was C S V We need to go ahead and
make sure that everything's in the correct format.
That means our data frame for the machine learning algorithm needs to have only two columns in it.
One column is the label column which is just the actual label you're trying to predict.
And then the next one is the features column that's going to be an array of all the features in order
to do that.
We essentially did three steps here.
We said our original data grab that price column which is what we're trying to predict.
Rename it the label column and grab all the other columns that I want to treat as features.
In our case since we haven't learned how to do all of categorical data we will later on we're just grabbing
numerical values then we needed to use vector assembler to select all those input columns as an array
and then set an output column as a single column called features.
After that we went ahead and said assembler transformed that data frame that we selected earlier.
And since this vector assembler object creates a new column with this array of all the features we just
want to grab those two columns so we say select label and then features.
Now it's time to actually move on and create the linear regression model object.
Train it and explore the results.
To create a linear regression model object you just to save Val.
LR is equal to new and then linear regression.
Close parentheses.
Now there's a lot more stuff you can add onto this such as different parameters.
We will explore that later on in the model evaluation section.
Keeping things simple will just create a base linear regression.
The next thing we need to do is actually fit our model to our training data.
So I will say well our model is equal to L-R that fit.
And in this case I'm going to fit to the output.
And as I mentioned in the model evaluation section will go over how to actually do a train test split.
Right now we're doing what you usually should not do which is not split up your data and then train
and get results from an entire singular dataset training and test splits are coming up.
But we're keeping things as simple as possible to not jump to a higher level too fast once we've fitted
our model to the actual data I can say Val training summary equal to L-R model summary and off of that
summary object that training summary I can call the residuals and the residuals are the difference between
our predictive value and the actual true value.
So I'll say training that some rethought residuals and we can show that it should just be a data Frane
Let's save this.
Make sure everything ran correctly and then explore the output of the model summary I will load L.R.
that score and then expand this terminal so we can see everything.
All right here's the output we requested in this case we just wanted to show the residuals.
And this is the residual for each label and each predicted value.
Now we can actually explore a lot more information off of the training summary.
Remember the training summary was just the model after it's been fit you call summary off of it.
So I will say training summary and as I noted earlier what's nice about doing this all outside of an
object is that in Sparke shell I can just say dot and then hit tab here and I will see all the methods
or attributes available off this summary object.
In this case I can ask for a lot of information such as what were my predictions if I want the predictions
themselves.
I can just say that predictions and it returns this data frame.
I actually want to see if I can say that show or if I want to collect that as something I can say that
collect.
But keep in mind this sort of action can be dangerous if it's a extremely large dataset.
So I'll say just not show up because it only shows the top 20 rows and what happens when you say that
show Ill say the label column the features column and then show the actual predicted value and the residual
is just a difference between this label and this prediction.
If you want some more statistical information about how the summary actually went you can call.
Go ahead and say that tab again here called the R-squared value which is just how much variances explained
in our model.
In our case we got about 91 percent or nine point nine one R-squared value.
It's not so bad but remember we are taking that value off the same data we train those.
So later on we'll need to check how to actually split up the data into a training set and a testing
set.
But keeping things simple right now.
Hopefully you can see just how powerful the training summary is.
Then we can call training summary and call stuff like the root mean square in our lips tab autocomplete
that and it will report back the root mean squared error.
Or you can even just get the means Square if you want it to.
So there's a lot of stuff here that you can explore and rat information off of.
But that's basically all there is to it.
As far as actually training your model the most difficult part when you are creating a machine learning
algorithm in Scala and in Sparke is your data set up.
And there's a really common saying in data science and data engineering in general that 90 percent of
your time is manipulating the data getting in the right format.
Cleaning that data data manging as it's called and then 10 percent of your time is actually just setting
up the algorithm.
So unless you're some sort of machine learning algorithm expert where you are actually creating your
own machine learning algorithms most of the time is going to be set up on these more tedious tasks of
cleaning up your data making sure everything's in the correct format.
So we will focus much more on that aspect of machine learning due to the fact that it's a little more
tedious when you're working with Scala and SPARC.
But the advantage comes into play when you're dealing with a large distributed data set.
You essentially need to change your code.
It's going to automatically scale to as large of a data set you want it will show how to do that later
on on systems such as data breaks data Brick's excuse me or Amazon Web Services.
All right go ahead and check out the rest of the walk through that Scala script.
If you scroll down I show the print summarization.
Things such as the number of iterations the history main square squared the residuals etc..
If you have any questions on what we just did here feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture Uller where we will be going over your project
for this section of the course.