Hello everyone and welcome to the missing data lecture in this lecture.
We're going to discuss various ways you can use spark data frames to actually deal with data that is
missing from your data set.
Let's go ahead and jump to the text editor to get started.
All right.
Here I am at the text editor.
I've created the new Skala script files called Elly's see for lecture and the Scala a script that goes
along with this lecture is the missing data that Skala And you're also going to read this contains no
but see the file you take a look at this contains no you'll notice that say CACP file that it's actually
missing some information.
So only this last row is complete where you have an employee ID a name and then a particular sales number
or sales figure.
Go ahead and copy these first three lines of code.
Or we started Sparke session get create and set up our import of this CSC file.
Again it's the contains no CACP file.
All right let's go ahead and discuss missing data.
Before we do that I'm going to just show you what happens when we actually print the schema of this
particular data frame.
And what happens when we show the schema member it's missing some data in it.
So let's go ahead and load really see that Skala here.
Run it and then I'm going to expand this to show you.
OK.
So as I mentioned and as we saw contains nulled out CAC is actually missing some data.
And what happens is SPARC is actually going to show that by inputting and you L-L for NULL.
So we can see here that we have all the employee ID information but we only have two names and two numbers
and we have a particular employee ID with neither name nor a sales number.
And basically we have three options when we deal with no values.
Either you can just keep them in and maybe only a certain percentage of no values exist.
So maybe you're OK with missing one or the other.
In this case names or sales but you're not ok with missing both of these information points.
So that's option 1.
Just keep them and maybe limit them to a certain percentage.
The other option is to just drop them completely.
So maybe you just drop anywhere where you don't have an employee name or drop any rows where you don't
have the sales data.
And then the third option which is really common when you're done of machine learning is to actually
try to fill them in with some other value.
And I want you to know there is no perfectly correct answer here.
There is no correct answer where you'll have to drop them or have to fill them in.
It's basically up to you as either the data engineer or a data scientist or whoever you're talking with
on the particular project and what your particular data set looks like.
So again there's no correct answer you're going to have to adjust the way you think about the problem
to the actual data that you have.
Let's go ahead and get started by showing you how you can drop values.
Now if we take a look at this idea if there is a thought and a method and then there's methods we can
call off of this if you want to explore these methods you can actually see them in the terminal.
So after running this in this terminal and the Skoll determined can say DMF any dots and then TEB and
you'll see that you have drop fill and replace.
Now at this point in time these are still technically experimental but they should be off experimental
in the next update release of SPARC.
So keep that in mind.
But from my experience they do work well.
Okay.
So the very first option is to drop our data if we want to drop any rows with any amount of any values.
We just say DFA any that drop and then I'm going to say that show to actually see the state of frame
as an output and I'm going to show the original data frame just so we can see the difference here.
So let's go ahead and load L.E. see that Skala and we can see the original data frame and then what
happens when we say that drop.
So in this original data frame we can see that we have the null values and when we say any drop it will
drop any rows to have any null values for any columns.
Now you can actually pasan a number arguments into this any draw and you can draw any rows that have
less than a minimum number of non null values and that's going to be an integer that you put in there.
So for example if we go ahead and put two go ahead and save that and run this again.
And let's compare the results we have now.
So here we can see that we have the original data frame in by inputting the value to we go in and scroll
down here into any that drop.
All right so how does this actually work with this and a that drop the two as the argument.
Remember this is going to drop any rows that have less than the minimum number of non null values.
So less than that integer amount which in this case we're looking for any row that has less than 2 non-null
values.
So unfortunately we can see here that employee number two had two non or 2 no values and we want to
drop any rows that have less than the minimum number amount of non-null values.
In this case we're left with any rows that has at least one or more non-null values.
This is sometimes a little tricky to understand because it's kind of warding it backwards it's almost
like a double negative when you're thinking about nulls.
So go ahead and check out the missing data that Skala in case you need written out for you.
So if you scroll down here you'll see here that there's drop any rows to have less than a minimum number
of non-null values.
So a couple of tricky points for beginners sometimes is this use of kind of a double negative.
Dropping any rows with the non-null values and the other confusion points sometimes it's that this is
a less than not a less than or equal to.
So keep that in mind if you're still a little confused by this what I would recommend doing is actually
open up this contains no doubt see a c file maybe add in some more columns and more empty value slots
so you can truly understand what's going on here.
Again sometimes some beaners have issues with this as far as understanding it but it's pretty straightforward
once you are able to get that click in your mind where it says drop any rows they have less than a minimum
number of the double negative non null values.
OK.
So that's basically it for dropping rows.
Either you drop any rows of any amount of null or any values or you actually specify a threshold number
where you drop any rows that have less than the minimum number of non-null values.
All right.
Now that we discussed how to drop any values either drop any rows that have any null values or drop
rows if a certain amount of non-null values that meet some sort of minimum threshold.
We can do is discuss how to actually fill in no values.
Sometimes you have a particular singular value some sort of based value that you actually want to fill
in.
Let me go ahead and show you how you can do that.
And there's some really interesting behavior as far as inferring schema.
So we're going to go to say DFA N.A. Phil and I'm just going to pass any number one hundred and then
I'm going to go ahead and show this and we'll see some interesting behavior.
Go ahead and just to remind you show you what this data frame looks like.
Our data from right now has a string column of ID's a string column of names and a double column of
sales numbers here.
Now I'm going to say fill 100.
Let's see what happens when I run this code.
So I go ahead and whips load see that Skala will see something interesting happen.
OK.
And this is what's interesting and a lot of languages that deal with data frames won't actually do this.
What Sparke is able to do is based off we go ahead and scroll down here based on the data type of what
you put in for fill.
It will look for all the columns that match that data type and fill it in.
In this case we put in a 100 which has a numerical value or a number and it went ahead and looked at
the columns and said OK look at the data types and tell me what columns have a data type that is a number
that's going to be either a integer or that will and then it says OK Will the sales column has that
sort of data type and it goes ahead and fills in 100 only for the missing values in that sales column
and then it goes ahead and leaves name as null values.
Let's go ahead and see what happens when we fill in a string here.
So I'm going to fill in missing name save this and run this.
Now think for a second what you expect and how this is going to infer the schema for the fill job.
We go ahead and run this.
Notice we get back these results.
So now instead of filling in the sales which was a double type it's going to fill in any missing values
that were the same data type here in Phil..
In this case that is the name column.
Keep in mind that if we had other columns that had strings in them that were also missing it would also
put in missing name into those columns.
So a lot of times you're going to want to be more specific and specify what columns you actually want
to fill in.
You usually won't just use a fill command like this unless you have a pretty small data set.
As far as columns concern.
So if you have a few columns and you only expect to fill in one column you could use that thought fill
with no specification as far as what column you want to pass.
But in this case let's go ahead and specify what column we want to do.
So I'm going to specify that I want to fill in the name column.
So I'm going to say specific as my string and you can name the string whatever you want.
So let's go ahead just to make that clear.
We'll say new name though don't confuse anybody.
And the second argument you passen is an array of the column names you want in this case.
I just want to fill in the name column.
Go ahead and save that I'll clear the terminal and let's run this again.
OK.
And now we can see that we basically got the same result.
But in this case instead of just specifying to fill any columns with missing values of the same data
type I was able to specify that I want to specifically fill in only the column that has this name column
or this name column name.
Let me go ahead and show you the same thing for the sales column.
So for instance let's go ahead and say 200 dollars and instead of saying array name I'm going to say
arraying sales.
Save this and run it in now I can see I only filled in sales because I specified it not that it actually
inferred the data type here.
Let me go ahead and clear this terminal and before we finish off this lecture I just want to do a simple
exercise which is going to be filling in the sales with the average sales data.
So how do we actually get that average sale data.
Well he could use an aggregate function but I'll show you a very simple method to do this in two steps.
Usually you want to do this in one single step but you could say something like this.
DFI thought describe and remember the scribe shows you that statistical information often numerical
columns.
If IDF taught the scribe sales I can see that my mean or average sale is 400 point five.
So then I would say fill four hundred point five to the sales column save that heaps and load my lecture
Skala and I've gone ahead and then filled in my sales data with that average and if I wanted to I could
also copy this.
And let's go ahead and fill in the name data as well and see what happens.
So if I say something like missing name and specify that I want the name column here let's see what
happens when I do that.
You'll notice that I end up getting two results here one with the sales filled in but the name missing
and the other with the name filled in.
But the sale still missing.
If I wanted to actually affect both of these columns what I could end up doing is setting a value here.
What's in my script for Val DFI to equal to that data frame and take off show and then I could say here
DFI to that N.A. that Phil. Let's go in and run this and see how it works.
And at the very end they see now that I have both my name column filled in and my sales column filled
in.
All right.
Great.
Go ahead and check out the Skala script for this lecture.
And keep in mind these are still technically experimental at these times but they've been around since
1.3.
So they should work pretty well.
I've never had an issue with them at all.
Okay thanks everyone.
Make sure you go ahead and kind of reclean look for this missing data.
That's called a script in case you want to see any more comments or any more code.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.