Hello everyone and welcome to solutions for the Skala programming assessment test.
Let's go ahead and walk through solutions to the questions on the assessment test.
Want to go ahead and jump to the text Ed. now.
All right.
Here I am at the Ed. Let's go ahead and start the first question which just to check first single even
basically had to write a function that takes in an integer and returns a boolean indicating whether
or not it is even.
And there was another hint see if you can write this in one line.
Let's go ahead and just see if we can write the function first.
We'll go ahead and say DCF and we'll call this method or function check.
Even now we're going to go ahead and accept an integer.
So we'll say numb colon.
And then the data type we expect back is an integer and we're going to be returning a if we check back
here.
We want to see it boolean returned.
So we're going to say boolean and then put in equals curly brackets and begin.
So I check there's an even here or you can do is just actually a return numb.
And check for equality with zero.
So let's go ahead and check that out and make sure it actually works.
So I'll say check even pass any number here.
Let's go ahead and put a number we know that is even such as four.
And then we'll run it again check.
Even passing a number three.
Let's go ahead and then say Prince lion.
So we actually print the results of those calls and filing in the same print line over here OK.
Save that and let's get ready to run it.
So say load Skala underscore program that's guala or whatever you happen to be naming your skull a script.
Run this.
And we should see true false so that makes sense.
Great.
So if you did some Googling or searching around you would have realized as far as making this into a
single line.
There's also notes on how to do this in the notes for the previous lecture on functions.
But you can check out that you actually can write this in a single line if you remove this return and
remove this boolean equals curly brackets statement and the colon and just right equals Scala actually
allows you to write this in one line in this format.
So if I save this and run it again you'll see that we actually get the same results.
Now we won't really be using this too often in the section of the course but I do want to be aware that
it is possible.
OK let's go ahead and move on to question number two.
Question number two is to check for evens in a list.
We wanted to write a function that returns true if there isn't even number inside of a list.
Otherwise return false.
Let's go ahead and check out how we can tackle this problem.
We'll start with DPF and we'll go ahead and check we'll call this check list.
And we're going to pass in a list we'll call this list numbers and then we expect it to be illest bracket
of integers.
So make sure you remember that when you're passing in some sort of collection object you also specify
what is going to be inside of that collection.
And then we expect a boolean back because we want to say whether or not there are even numbers in this.
And then we're just going to do a for loop for those numbers.
So we'll say for an in that numbers list we're going to go to perform an operation will say if an maade
2 is equal to zero just like we did last time we'll go ahead and return true.
Otherwise we'll end up doing it after that for loop if we never return true.
And we know there are no even numbers in there.
So we'll go ahead and return false.
I'll save that and then I'm going to make two lists I'll say Val even sample is equal to list.
One two three four five.
And then I know there's an even there so it's going to make an odd sample list where there are no even
numbers list and we'll say 1 3 5 7 and then we're going to call that function two times we'll say Prince
Elyn that check even our checklist.
Well person that even sample and then we'll say Prince Ellen checklist and then pass in that odd sample.
Say that and let's go ahead and run this again.
OK so it looks like we it true that there is a result of an even number and even sample and in the odd
we get false so it looks like it's working out again very similar to the last question.
But we have to make sure that we did it properly for illest and use the for loop as well.
And if control flow check.
OK let's go ahead and clear this and move on to the third question.
Third question was called lucky number seven.
We wanted to taken a list of integers and calculate their sum.
However sevens are lucky and they should be counted twice.
Meaning their value is actually 14 for the sum.
And you can assume that the list isn't empty when you receive it.
Let's go ahead and tackle this problem.
A clear that we're going to go ahead and say f and we'll call our new function lucky.
We're going to accept numbers as an argument.
And this is going to be a list of integers as stated in the problem statement.
Remember we want an actual sum back which means going to be an integer.
So let's go ahead and define a variable called output.
So our basic strategy will be to go through every number in this list see what it is if it is a 7 we'll
add 14 to the output.
If it's not a 7 then we'll just add that number I'm going to make a variable called output here inside
of the function equal to zero.
And then we're going to say for and numbs you go ahead and say if and has it quality with seven we're
going to take the output and set it equal to output plus 14 because it was a seven it counts for twice
otherwise.
Or else the output is just going to be the output plus that normal number which was in this case and
here.
So we'll have it be.
And then finally after this for loop is done we're going to go ahead and return that output.
So let's go ahead and save that and set it up for us to run.
Let's make a value call that numbers all set it equal to a list let's say 1 2 3 7 and then we're going
to go ahead and say Prince Elon and I will in and in Lucky Numbers.
OK.
So let's before we actually run this calculate what this should be.
So looks like we have 1 7 in here that should be 14 plus 7 is going to be 17 plus to 19 and then plus
one is 20.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure it all worked out.
And to run that Scala program that scul the script and it looks like we get 20 out.
So that's good for us.
And there's a little bit of a weird typo here as far as what the term is showing says Alex it's kind
of overwriting the Skala.
We go ahead and expand this.
Maybe we can get rid of that weird error there OK.
There it is 20.
So let's go ahead and continue on.
You can always just reference the solutions as well.
If you're confused on any of this but hopefully make sense so far let's clear this and move on to the
next question which is a little trickier.
So this one is called Can you balance.
And this one's a little more complicated but we want to be given a not empty list of integers return
true if there is a place to split the list so that the sum of the numbers on one side is equal to the
sum of the numbers on the other side.
So for example that 1 2 5 3 3 can be split right in the middle.
Or another example 734 can be split right after that 7 there is actually lots of ways you can solve
this problem but we'll try to go through the most simplistic way of solving it.
So I can say half and call this balance check and I expect to get a list then and this list is going
to be a list of integers.
So specify that type and I'm going to return a boolean back because I just want to know true or false.
Is it possible to split this into logic.
I'm going to use is have the first half and the second half as I iterate through this list.
So to make two variables I'll say VAR of first half and I'll set it equal to zero initially and then
VAR of second half and set that equal to zero initially and then the second half.
I'm actually then going to reassign to my list that sum.
So we're basically starting with the second half being the entire list and the first half being zero.
We haven't moved our cursor from the left hand side throughout the list and then we're going to do is
actually begin to move and compare that cursor.
So I will say for I in this case in the range from zero to the length of that list and we can figure
out the name for that list just by using that length method we saw earlier in the course and I'm going
to take my first half and say the first half plus my list at that index location and maybe we can use
parentheses to grab that.
And then the second half is going to be equal to the second half minus the value at that location.
So basically what we're doing is we go along as we add an element to the first half and take it away
from the second half.
Some are just going through this list moving along from left to right and exchanging those elements
and then at any time in this for loop if the first half is equal to the second half but we'll go ahead
and do is return true because that means there is some point in the list where we can actually make
that split.
And if you wanted to know what point it was at that list you could have just returned.
That's the actual index that's occurring at.
But in this case we just want to turn the boolean if that never happens in this for loop which matches
up with this curly bracket.
You can kind of see Adam is telling us what this little blue line.
Then I'll go ahead and do is return false in this case.
All right let's go ahead and test it to make a few values.
We'll call now.
Balance list or balanced is equal to list.
We'll go ahead and say One two three four and then 10 and then we'll say Wow another ballast list.
So Bellis to list and we'll say 2 3 3 2.
So we know both of these lists should be returned TRUE.
Finally let's get an unbalanced list there.
So say unbalanced equals list 10 20 and then some very large number will go in and put 70.
So the first should be true.
And then the last one should be not true.
So let's go ahead and then run this we'll say Prince Ellen and we're going to run print in three times
with the actual function balance checks all say balance check and going to copy and paste this here
three times.
One two three.
And then just actually pass the lists themselves so the first one is balanced.
The second one is this balas two.
And then finally unbalanced.
So let's save this and break down.
Real quick what we're doing.
We're going to go ahead and accept the list of integers and return a boolean.
We set two variables inside of this first half is equal to zero.
Second half is equal to zero.
And then we can reassign second half to my list that sum if you want.
You could have just done this and once that line three and five it's not actually necessary to separate
out like this but this just looks a little clear in my perspective.
And then we can go ahead and say for every index from range zero to the length of the list.
Go ahead and add that particular element at the end of the list the first half which remembers zero
and then subtract that from the total sum of the second half.
And then if at any point that some of the first half is equal to the sum of the second half will turn
true if that never occurs.
For this for loop we go ahead and return false.
Now we're going to test it out on three lists that we know two are the first two are balanced and the
last one is unbalanced.
So let's go ahead and run this OK it looks like we got the results we expected.
True true and false.
Great.
Now finally we have one last question which is quite a bit simpler.
It's just a palindrome check.
Now we want to be given a string return a boolean indicating whether or not it is a palindrome spelled
the same forwards and backwards.
Try exploring methods to help you.
So hopefully you were able to remember how to explore methods and you can do this just treating your
terminal by saying something like Val s t is equal to the string will go in and say hello and you can
say s t dot and hit tab here and you'll get a bunch of attributes or methods available to you on this.
And one of them hopefully you're able to see or with the power of Google you're able to find out that
it is reverse.
So if I do as t r at tab again we know that one of them will actually allow us to reverse the order
of this.
So a palindrome since it's going to be the same backwards or forwards.
We can actually do this really simple if that tool we'll call this palindrome.
Check taken a string s t make sure we qualify that it is a string and then we're going to go in and
say boolean is equal to since a boolean is what we want to return.
And we're just going to return this logical statement is the string as t equal to s t reverse.
So what reverse we're going to do.
Just to clarify if we actually call it here make clear this as t da reverse enter.
We get the reverse of the string so if it's a palindrome the reverse should be equal to the string itself.
So we can then just say Prince L.N. Let's go ahead and do a palindrome check on a string that we know
is a palindrome.
Such as a B C C B.
And we'll do one more on a string.
Now we know it's not a palindrome palindrome.
There we go.
And then we'll go in and put it just hello.
Since we know it's not a palindrome.
So we expect true and then false.
So let's go ahead and run this.
So there it is true and then false.
Ok that's it for the programming section.
And that's actually it for these scolloped programming section.
Hopefully it felt pretty straightforward.
We didn't cover the vast expanse of the skull.
Language in a general sense but we just focused on what we needed to know in order to work with Sparke.
After this we're actually going to shift our mindset not so much from Skala but working a spark spark
data frames and sparks machine learning libraries.
So the skills you learned here is exactly what we need to move on to the next section.
We don't need to waste too much time.
As far as the deep dives and the Skala because we don't actually need them or working with SPARC and
Skala.
So let's go ahead and move on to the next section of the course.
Thanks everyone.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Q&amp;A forums.