Hello everyone and welcome to your data frame project exercises overview lecture in this lecture we're
going to just be discussing him briefly walking you through the final project or the exercises for this
section of the course.
Let's go ahead and jump to the data frame underscore project that Skala script which is in the spark
data frames folder and walk through the project.
So the key here I am at the data frame underscore project that Skala script file.
And basically what you're going to be doing is using some stock data and specifically it's going to
be Netflix's stock data from 2011 to 2016.
It's in the form of a CAC file and it's actually stored already downloaded for you in the spark data
frames folder and what you're going to go ahead and do is answering completely common to tasks below.
And this will consist of your project and we should have done some variation of form of all these tasks
as you go along.
So if you ever need a reference or a computer on anything go ahead and revisit the previous lectures.
We're going to start off with the basics such as asking what the column names are how to print the schema.
Check out the head and then later on we'll go more and more advanced such as how many days was a close
lowered to 600 dollars.
What percentage of the time was the high greater than $500.
What's the max high per year.
So if you're confused on that you can check out the date and time stamp lectures etc..
So go ahead and just answer all these questions.
Best of luck on the project.
And coming up next is going to be the solutions walkthrough for this project.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.