Hi guys and welcome to this very first practical section on tens of Flo 2.0.
This is in this section that we will get introduced to censor flow 2.0.
But before as you see we're just going to have a quick refresh on tons of floor one just so that we
can see the main difference and the main added value of 10th floor 2.0 with respect to tens of floor
one.
So right now what we have in front of us is a Jupiter notebook environment on Google collaboratively.
This is super practical you'll get many notebooks in this course where you will have basically all the
tents flow sin taxes that are used in general for several purposes whether it is to work with constants
and variables or to build neural networks or even to build convolution rule and recurrent neural networks.
So you'll have several notebooks and this first notebook that we have right now contains the general
features and the general tools of tensor flow 2.0 with of course a little recap on tensor flow one.
So you're going to see we're going to learn everything about the constants how to define a constant
how to get the values of a constant.
Same for the variables how to define a variable how to get the values of a variable how to change a
specific value in a variable will see all the different operations we have with dancers like in addition
multiplication how to use them by functions on since flow dancers and how to do a dot product between
two dancers and then we'll even study how to work with strings with Dancer flow.
So that's one notebook.
And the approach we're going to take in this course is going to be quite different from our previous
courses because I'm not going to type in front of you all the different tense flow commands that we
have in each notebook.
And the reason for this is that I wanted to make this new course much more interactive than before.
In fact after each notebook that we're going to see in this course you're gonna have a series of practical
activities you know little exercises which will check your knowledge and skills on each notebook.
So the way this is going to go is that I'm going to explain each notebook in each of the cells step
by step until the end after which you will get a series of exercises on the same notebook.
Explain me just before and actually these little exercises are a new feature of Udemy.
You know now you can make some video lectures but you can also make some coding exercises.
So this is going to be quite new.
The approach basically is in three phases.
First we see the notebook together.
I'm going to explain each of the sales and I'm going to explain all the different concepts and techniques
and tools of tense flow 2.0.
Then second phase you'll get a series of exercises.
And finally third phase you'll get the solution.
So let's do this let's start with this first notebook just to get us introduced to tens of Luke 2.0
with the general features and then we'll move onto some more advanced features of tensor flow which
are of course you know to build artificial new one that works convolution on the one that works.
Record new networks and actually much much more you're going to have a very broad course on tensor flow
2.0 covering basically all its techniques.
So let's do this let's first get the basics of tensor flow and as we said I just want to do this little
quick tour on 10th floor one for us because I want you to understand the main new features of tentacle
2.0 with respect to tens of flow one.
So first of all the first cell here just installs denser flow one you know you install it with the pip
command preceded by an exclamation mark then you just click the play button here but by the way you
won't have to execute any of the cells even though you could you know if you want to execute them again
you can but what's good about a Jupiter notebook environment is that you can keep the output of each
cell and that's what I did for each of the notebook you were gonna have all the outputs that I executed
myself.
So this is the output of running this and indeed you install a series of dependencies after which you
install tensor flow GP you and that intensive low one.
Then of course after installing it you have to import it.
And that's what this next cell is doing.
And then if you want you can get the version I give you the syntax for that.
And indeed we're using tensor flow one point thirteen point one.
No worries we'll soon get to 10th floor 2.0 then let's see what we have.
So as you can see intensively one quick refresh that I want to do is only on constants and variables
because this is where we have a big difference.
Intensive load 2.0 and you can already suspect what this big difference is going to be.
It's actually about how to get the values of a constant and a variable.
So we'll get to that right now.
First how to define a constant.
Well that's really easy.
You do this thanks to the constant function which you take from tensor flow you know that's the shortcut
TAF we gave the of floor library.
So this constant function takes as input a tensor because usually you know when you create a constant
or variable intense flow it is a tensor.
You know most of its sense of flow variables and constants you create or tensor is because the whole
point of working with sense of flow is to use its advanced sensors because they have a lot of properties
and lot of tools that actually allow you to build for example advanced deep learning or aim or all such
as artificial neural networks or you networks.
So whenever you're going to create a sense of low constant or tense of a variable it will usually be
a tensor.
So that's why I called here the tensor flow constant tensor.
And so inside this constant function you're going to input Well the shape and the values of your tensor.
So here we have a double square brackets meaning it's a 2D tensor composed of two rows and two columns.
Okay.
So then after you define your tensor flow constant well you can call it but you won't get the values
actually you will just get the shape of it.
And indeed it's a two by two tensor and you will get the type of values inside.
And indeed they are integers but then.
And that's where we get to the main difference between sense for one intensive flow two if you want
to accept the values of your tensor you know twenty three for thirty two fifty one well you have this
method called a vowel you know the AVAiL method which you call from your tensor flow constant which
we call tensor but in order to call this a well function you know to get the values of this tensor Well
you have to initialize what we call a sense of flow session that was intensive low one whenever you
want to access the values of a constant and you will see that it will be the same for a tenth of the
variable Well you have to initialize a session first and that's why right now we haven't initialized
any session yet.
And therefore when we call the event method to get the values of this tensor Well we get value error
and it even explains why we get such an error this is because no default session is registered.
Right.
So you have to register a session you have to initialize a session and actually initialize all the variables
that are going to be in this session in order to access the values constant or variable.
And so now.
Well let's see in the next section how to get the values of a constant by therefore initializing a session.
And that's why in the next section here in order to get the values of the constant the same constants
we introduced before while the first thing we do is we initialize a session and to do so well we introduce
a new variable that I chose to call session which is created as an instance of the session class the
session class which is a class by tensor flow so that initialize is your session.
But then as I told you you also need to initialize all the variables inside your session and you do
this with the run method to which input to the global variables initialized that's an initialized of
all the global variables in your session then you're going to connect your tensor to the initialize
session with the run method again and that will return a new variable which we called tensor value because
now indeed when we call tensor value well we're able to get the values inside this constant tensor right
this time since we have our registered session well we can access the values of the constant tensor.
All right.
So again I'm showing you this because you're going to see that it will be different with tensor flow
2.0 and actually a lot of people were so happy about this.
You're going to see that indeed with tens of Look 2.0 it is much easier to access the values of a constant
and a variable.
So speaking a variable Well now let's get a quick refresh on the variables intensive floor one how to
define first it turns a flow variable.
Well this time you're not gonna use a function here you're going to use a class which is the variable
class called from the tenth floor library of course.
Therefore your variable is actually an instance of that variable class but same inside this variable
class you're going to input the shape of your tensor with of course its values right.
Once again when defining intensity variable it's usually a tensor.
That's why I chose as an example to create a sense of variable then it's the same when you call your
variable this way without doing anything else.
Well you will only get the shape which is a two by two tensor with integers inside.
Okay.
But you don't get any values and same again if a session is not initialized.
Well you can access the values of the variable indeed you know you accept the values of your variable
with the Val method which you call from your variable tensor but then you get this value error because
indeed no default session is registered.
All right.
So same in order to get the values of a variable while you first have to initialize a session would
you do the same way by creating a session object as an instance of the session class by tense of flow.
Then you initialize all the variables from the session with the run method that takes his input.
The initialize the tip that global variables initialized and then actually for a variable you can just
directly call the Val method from it.
Because remember the difference with the constant is that you know your variable is an object you know
an instance of the variable class in the variable class has directly this evolved method that allows
you to access the values of the variable but only if the session is registered and that's why in the
event method you know as opposed to what we did here in the event method you have to input that session.
Here we did input any session so we had a value error but now we registered a session we input it in
the event method and there we go.
We get the values all right so that's it for potential flow 1.
Now we're not going to hear ever again about tensor floor 1.
We can move on to 10th flow 2.0 and you're going to see the main difference around the basics of tensor
flow which is of course how to get the values of a variable.
So let's do this in the next material you know to really begin a new sense of flow 2.0 journey from
the next materials.
And keep in mind how we got value so far and you will understand in the next story or how we will now
do things differently with sense of flow 2.0.