Hello and welcome to this new editorial.
And now we begin our tenser flow 2.0 journey.
All right.
So remember intensive floor one in order to assess the values of a variable or a constant.
Well we had to initialize a session and assess the values of the tensor through the session.
And now you're going to see that things are going to be different with tangible 2.0.
There is a much easier way to access the values in a tensor.
All right.
So first before we execute any sense of low 2.0 COMMAND Well we have to of course install it and we
install it the same way with the pip command preceded by an exclamation mark.
And so there you go you have the tenth floor 2.0 0 point 0 version with the GP you so that you can gain
even more performance.
All right.
So once you execute this sale you get this download all the dependencies that you need to install tens
of.
They're all here.
So everything comes in a package.
Then of course you import it.
And we also import number because you're going to see that the way we accessed the values is also by
using by.
Right.
It's like 10th flow 2.0 made some new name by based feature we're going to see that in a second.
And then of course to check the 24 for version that you're using you can just run this and indeed we're
using tens of low 2.0 porno and now.
Well let's see.
Let's study the constants and variable incentive 2.0.
Right we have the whole structure here.
You can if you want to have a look at it first.
This is a structure right now we're being in with the constants so first of all how to define a constant
well with exactly the same way as we did with tensor flow one you know we take the sensible library
from which we call the constant function and inside you just enter the shape of your tensor.
So here this is a two by two tensor with their values inside two rows two columns.
All right.
We called this new tensor tensor flow 20 as it tends to flow 2.0.
And then when you call it well there you go.
Now you have directly the values wasn't that so simple.
Right.
Before we only had this tier of the tensor and the idea and the shape you know two rows two columns
and the type of the values inside your tensor.
But now we get also the array you know with two rows and two columns and with the exact same values
as the one you entered here.
All right so that's a main new feature that is making your life a bit easier and that is a big change
in tensor flow 2.0 and then.
Well if you just want the shape you know if you just want the dimensions of your tensor well you can
just call the shape attribute from your tensor constant right and you will get tensor shape two rows
two columns.
OK.
So now in this next section you're going to see another way to get the values of a constant and actually
this will get you only the values that we see here and not this information above as you see you will
get directly the array.
And the trick to do that.
I just added it so that you know it as well to get the values straight from a tensor flow constant with
non pi.
That's why we important than pi and without the need of a session you just enter this you know your
constant tensor and then you just add non pi with some parenthesis and you will get directly to values.
Right.
So pretty practical too.
And mostly we're not needing any session right.
We won't bother opening new sessions now which was something we always did with tens of floor one each
time you know you are starting to build a new sense of flow program and especially a new neural network
or a new neural machine or whatever.
You always had to open a session and here as you can see we don't need it anymore.
And again.
So these are the main differences intensive flow 2.0 around the base acceptance of flow but we're going
to see that there are going to be more differences when building neural networks.
And by the way we will see if we use any session right then you have to know that you can also convert
an umpire right back to a sense of flow tensor as well.
And to illustrate this well here I introduced a new non pi array which I called non pi tensor and which
is the following num pi array.
Know this is the shortcut that we get known pi and P and this is the array function by Nan by 2 which
again you input the same you know the format with the double square brackets therefore giving you two
rows and two columns and then inside the values exactly the same.
Only this is and then by array and basically you can convert this name by Ray to tensor flow tensor
the following way by just calling your tensor flow library TAF.
And from which again you just take your constant function to which can put the number tensor.
Right.
So into this constant function you only have two input you know the double square it's in your values
you can directly enter a non pirate.
And this will give you exactly the same meaning attentive look tensor but created from them by all rights
and then when you call it again.
Well you get this you know first some general information you know the fact that it is a tensor.
The idea is that just nine and fire the shape of your tensor two rows two columns the type of the values
inside your tensor which are integers and again the array with all the values.
All right.
So now it's much easier to play with constant tense of low constants.
And so there you go that's one of the new features of tension flow 2.0.
And now let's move on to the variables.
All right.
So for the variables.
Well first of all let's see how we define a variable and actually that's exactly the same.
You take your tensor flow library T F from what you call the variable class inside which will put the
shape with the double square brackets and the values inside.
And then when you want to get the values well you have two options either you just call UTF two variable
which as opposed to before won't only give you these informations but also the array with the values.
Right.
And then the second way to get the values of your variable of your tensor variable is to do the same.
You take your t f two variables that are tensor variable which we've just created and from which you
call the non pi function that was associated with tons of flow 2.0 in which directly gives you this
time only the array and also the type.
All right.
So much easier.
And now I'm just giving you an extra tool which you might use sometimes in your project and which is
something you do on a variable only of course because a constant cannot be changed its value.
So this is about changing a specific value in the variable like for example let's say you want to change
this cell here you know this value here in the first row and the third column.
Well to do so what you're going to do is take your variable get the first row which has index 0 and
get the third column which has index 2 and then you just add that and assign 100 sine this method of
the variable class which is exactly used to change any value you want inside your variable.
Right.
And therefore when we execute this well we get this with again the new information of your tensor and
inside the values and indeed three which was the cell before the first row and third column was replaced
by one hundred.
Right.
So good thing to know but once again you don't have to remember it.
We were giving you all the notebooks and and you know you can just keep them close to you on your computer
whenever you're working on a project so that you know you can quickly get access to a series of practical
functions to use with tons of load 2.0.
All right.
And then once again if we call the T F2 variable again we just get the same thing because indeed the
assign replaces the cell you wanted to replace in that you have two variable.
So it's not like a new one is created.
Indeed the value was replacing in UTF 2 variable which we created before.
All right.
So now you clearly know the difference between tensor flow and intense flow two in terms of constants
and variables.
And now we're going to finish this section with the last story all where we will study how to do some
operations with tensor is it's actually not too different from 10 to 1 but I'm giving you some useful
tools and techniques that you can use with sense of flow 2.0 so that you can have a sense of flow 2.0
toolkit of the main things you can do with it still around the basics right.
Then we'll of course study neural networks and I'll give you much more tools related to artificial neural
networks.
So I'll see you in this next material to study all these operations with sensors.
And until then enjoy tons of low.