And welcome back guys.
So far we cover the high level overview of the tens of flow serving.
And in this video we'll talk about its architecture obviously.
You don't have to know these things or to know them in great detail.
If you want only to put the modelling production you can do that in just a few lines of code.
But if you want to create more complex infrastructures around your models or to handle some errors this
knowledge will come in handy.
In the previous video we started the client side architecture.
Since then the client side did not change at all.
Still we have an application from whom a user uploads an image for the post to request to our server
by the server side was much simpler on the server side.
We had a model that takes an image from the request and sends a prediction back to the client.
Now let's take a few minutes to explain what is the role of tens of serving on the server our server
is now split up into two different parts the file system and the tens of low serving on the file system
we have free models saved it could be the same model but three different versions of it or we could
have a totally different models and let's say that we have an app where we want to serve a different
model based on geo location to our user or we want to test the model one on one set of users and the
rest should be served by a model to that's where the tensor flow comes into play the tensor flow has
many moving parts and we won't cover them all in this tutorial just three of them let's start from the
left in the desert floor serving because we are serving the model a model is called a server all because
of that we have a path called solvable handler it is a module of the tens of flows serving infrastructure
that handles a model for us the middle path here is called version MANAGER We can either have multiple
models for different tasks or various versions of the same model we as a deep learning engineers our
job is to improve the current model constantly or to come up with newer and newer architectures and
that's how we end up having multiple versions of the same model or even multiple models to make sure
that our newest version of the model works better than the current one in production we need to test
it well testing the latest version of the model we don't want to expose it to all the users but one
subset that is that subset for us let's say on the users from Serbia are going to experience latest
version and we can specify that to a version manager and the manager will handle that for us and then
we have a model loader it is the closest part of the tells a flow serving stack to the filesystem it
takes a message from the version manager what model to load based on that message the model loader will
reach for the file system load the model and provide it back to a version manager the version manager
will inform the cerebral handler that the model is a loaded and ready to be served.
And finally the prediction based on the uploaded image is sent to the user and that's pretty much it.
We won't go into more detail than this.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll
see you in the next tutorial.