Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this section we are going to build our image classification API using tens of low serving.
The question you may have right now is what is the difference between our previous solution using flask
and this one using tens of low serving.
And that is a great question the previous solution worked great but it wasn't scalable that much if
you end up having 1 million users or 1 million requests per day that solution wouldn't be able to handle
that.
On the other side we have tens of low serving which is built with that in mind.
It was built to handle millions or even billions of requests per day.
All Google products from Google Translate to Google Maps are built on top of it.
And if Google can use it.
So can we.
If scalability is not your only concern.
There are other great stuff that are handled in terms of low serving.
For example if you want to train or experiment with multiple models or versions of the same model this
library handles that for us in the background.
So we don't have to stop the whole application to handle that.
Everything is handled in the real time and users won't even notice a thing.
Now let's start our project by setting up our environment to use you instead of CPO go to edit notebook
settings and for hardware accelerator select you the next thing to do is to install all dependencies
for the project in the first cell.
You may notice this long line that I've just pasted there.
I want explain it in great detail but in a nutshell it will set a path where our virtual machine can
find all dependencies for the tens of flow serving you can find this line in the resources of this section
copied from the resources to a free cell and executed the next thing to do is to update linux packages
if you use Linux before you already know how to do this.
And after that it's time to install tens of low model server exclamation mark up get update then this
and sign up to get install there's a flow model server.
The first part will update all packages and after that is done we will install tens of flow model server.
It's time to install tell the flow one point thirteen.
I know you may wonder why do we use this version after all this is a course for tens of floor 2.0.
Well at this point tens offload 2.0 doesn't have a great support for the tens of low serving because
of that we will use this one point thirteen version instead.
But no worries.
The code that we are going to write will be executable later down the road in the tens of 2.0 as well.
When they upgrade it tends a flow serving.
LIBRARY SO JUST RIGHT.
Exclamation mark pip install.
There's a flow that Jeep you equals equals to one point thirteen point one.
And the last thing to do is to install a library called requests.
It is most likely that we have it already.
But to make sure let's try to install it right.
Exclamation mark pip install requests and that's it.
If you have any questions or comments please buzz them in the comments section otherwise I'll see in
the next tutorial.