Hi guys welcome to this editorial.
We've just built our convolution all new network from start to finish with tons flow 2.0.
So now it is time to train it.
We are already loaded and pre processed the data set.
So everything is ready to be connected together.
And speaking of connections well the first thing we have to do is of course compile the moral meaning
to connect it to an optimizer and a loss.
The optimizer is the tool that will performs to Cassie gradient descent to date the weights in order
to reduce the loss and the loss is indeed the error between the predictions of the model you know which
objects it predicts the images to be and the real values that are of course in the training set.
You know why train.
Right.
Because when we're training we have the real values which we are comparing to the predictions to incur
the loss and back propagated into the new network in order to finally update the weights with the Cassie
gradient descent.
And once again we're gonna use an Adam optimizer it is one of the best stochastic greenness and optimizer.
So this is the one I recommend by default.
And as for the less well we're going to use the same one as before the sports category called Cross
entropy.
Right.
In fact this is the exact same way to compile then with our artificial new network.
Remember we used an Adam optimizer as poor scanner equal crossings would be less and poor as categorical
accuracy metrics which is the same metrics we use here for a convolution or new network.
And that's because the application is more or less the same.
You know we're doing image classification on more than two glasses so it's not binary classification.
It's multi class classification.
And that's why we had to use here sports categorical accuracy.
And for those you who want more details on this sparse categorical accuracy.
Well I provided some extra source here where you can find some extra explanations.
But what's most important to remember is that this is the metrics you should use when doing multi class
classification.
You know when predicting more than two classes and so there you go.
This is exactly the same as before you call the compile method from your model and you will put the
less the optimizer and the metrics.
And this is the exact same set of inputs as are artificial neural network.
All right.
So now that we connected our moral to an optimizer loss in a matrix.
Well the next step is naturally to train it.
Training the model so to train the model it's once again exactly the same as the artificial neural network
we're gonna use the fit method.
Remember where you input your input images contained in exchange.
The real answer is you know the real classes of the images and extreme in white train and the number
of bugs meaning the number of times you want to feed the whole training set into the neural network
and update each time the weights.
And we chose five epochs for a and then and now for a CNN it's exactly the same five books.
And once again feel free to choose a batch size if you want to do mini batch learning it's usually recommended
but you know remember that you had the exercise then which will have you explore some more techniques
in order to improve the results.
And one of them is by including a batch size.
So let's do this.
Let's train the model by executing this well what do we get we get are five epics with for each the
loss and the accuracy.
So here it's interesting because remember before we got some pretty good results at the very first epic
but now the problem is much more complex.
Now the relationships between the different convolution or layers inside our CNN are much more complex
than inside just some fully connected layers in the end.
So that's why in the first book we get a low accuracy but what's interesting to see is that it quickly
improves you know the accuracy almost doubles at the second book.
Right we go from 28 percent to 44 percent and then it improves once again pretty well 51 percent 56
percent and 60 percent.
So it's pretty obvious of how you can improve the results.
Right.
I'm sure you're thinking right now that one solution of improvement is to try with more epochs.
Of course if you try with more epics you should get a higher accuracy.
So this will be part of the exercises and then you know you have many more options to improve the results.
You can change the architecture you can at drop out you can add more tools you'll actually get to experience
on this in the practical activities and remember that okay we improved the accuracy over these five
books and even if we got a final 60 percent accuracy which is quite decent.
Well don't forget that.
This is not what we're looking for.
Ultimately what we're looking for ultimately is to get a high accuracy on the evaluation set you know
because the evaluation set contains the new observations meaning new images on which our model wasn't
trained.
And so that's exactly the last part of this notebook.
Evaluating the morale and you evaluate it exactly the same way as before by calling the Evaluate method
from your moral object which takes as input.
The test set composed of all the input images of the test in excess and they're real classes in white
test.
And by executing this this will get you the accuracy and also the loss on the test set.
That's why we introduce these two variables here because this evaluate method actually returns the loss
and the accuracy but it also outputs them this way.
You know by running the model on these 10000 observations and we get the final accuracy of 59 percent
we could have feared that we would get lower accuracy than here because actually our model didn't have
much time to train first of all and second of all no drop out was applied but still we get a good accuracy
here but there is still much much room for improvement so I want you to try improving this will guide
you on how to do this through the exercises.
But of course if you think of other extra solutions which largely improves the accuracy.
Well feel free to share your solutions and your results we'll be happy to see them once again.
This will help the other students in this course and that will make the course even greater.
So there you go.
And then we have the final print.
You know when you only want the accuracy and not the loss you know loss is not really the way to evaluate
the performance of your morals so you just want the accuracy.
Well here is the final prints with indeed the same test accuracy.
All right.
So congratulations.
Now you know how to build a convolution or new one that work intensive low 2.0.
Now it's time for you to practice.
It's time for you to really improve this test accuracy even if it is quite decent but I left some room
for improvement on purpose for you to succeed on improving this.
And once again share your results share your solutions communicate and then you will generate ideas
between each other and will probably improve your skills even greater.
So good luck on the exercises.
I'll see you in the next section for third kind of new network which will be a recurrent neural network
for which the application will be much different.
It will be an MLP application.
I'll let you find out about this in the next section.