Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In the previous video we downloaded the dataset extracted and created paths to each part of the dataset
and in the next couple of years we are going to be building the model for the project.
The goal of this video is to load a pre train network called Mobile natively to any pre train network
that we decide to use for our project is nothing more but a very big convolution of neural network with
fancy weight.
And since you have worked with CNN before you know that if CNN expect fixed size inputs pre train models
expect the same thing.
So let's defined AMG shape and set it to 128 128 free.
This is going to be the shape of all images in our dataset now that we know that information.
Let's use it to load our mobile laterally to create a variable called Bayes model and set it to T dot
care US DOT applications.
Here you could see various models pre trained ones that we can choose from.
But in this case we are going to choose model letter V to it is pretty small and pretty fast.
The problem with this model is that it doesn't have a dog string so we don't know which arguments if
any it expects.
You could easily google it and find which arguments to provide in this course we are going to mention
just a few most important ones.
The first one is input shape.
Set it to our AMG shape that we have defined the next argument is include top.
It is boolean argument so it could be true or false.
As we learned that the intuition part of this section these networks are trained on image genetic data
set for example.
So its top players including the output layer are designed explicitly for the image and enter data set.
We wondered that top part to be specific for the task that we are trying to solve.
And that's why we are going to create our custom head so you can send this variable to false and the
last argument is weight.
It accepts the name of a data set that the network was trained on.
In our case less right image imagine it execute the cell and now it will download the model and loaded
in our environment.
The last thing that we have for this lesson is to check what the architecture of this network is.
Right.
Model dot summary.
And as you can see these networks are huge.
This one has more than 100 layers inside of it.
Now that we have our pre train and model load it's time to define our custom head for our task if you
have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I'll assume the next tutorial.