Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in this video.
We are going to define our distributed strategy in the first video of the section we find and talked
about distributed strategies in general.
For example there were a mirror strategy multi worker strategy and typical strategy.
All of them sounds very complicated because you need to incorporate multiple computers servers or multiple
dispute.
But in this video.
Trust me you're going to get very very excited because all of that is only one line of code one line
of code to distribute any modelling production to multiple abuse or multiple servers let's do that by
defining our mirror strategy for our model.
We will start by defining a variable called distribute.
It is going to be equal to the to distribute.
Now we need to specify which strategy we want to use in our case.
We are going to try mirror strategy after you are done with that.
Execute the cell and that's it.
In just one line of code we defined a mirror strategy.
We are going to use that to distribute any model in production.
It's very exciting times when we are allowed and able to in on this single line of code to distribute
any model across multiple or any number of disputes in the next video.
We are going to distribute our model using this strategy.
Stay tuned for that.
And in the meantime if you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section otherwise
I'll send the next tutorial.