Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
And finally we're on to the fun stuff.
We're onto deep learning.
All right so let's have a look.
Previously we spoke about kill learning and what it's all about.
And we learned about the age and the environment and how the agent will look at the state here or she
is in take an action get a reward enter into a new state and based on that feedback loop they will continue
taking actions and they'll learn from that.
Understand what are the better actions to take.
And so we looked at this basic example of a maze.
We understood that as the agent explores the environment and understands what the values of the states
are.
Then we moved on from dealing with the values of the states to dealing with the values of the actions
or the Q values and then based on that we understood how plans in an answer caustic environments work
and how policies work in the casting environments and this is an example of policy.
So that's a quick recap of everything we discussed in the basic learning.
And now let's have a look at how this can be taken to the next level through deep learning through adding
deep learning.
OK so this is our environment and what we're going to do now is we're going to add instead of just doing
basic calculations in this matrix that we have which is pretty simple.
What are we going to do is we're going to add two axes which add an x and y axis or we'll call them
X1 and X2 just to make things even more general.
And here we've got two will number the columns one two three four.
You'll hear world number at the rows 1 2 3.
And so now every single state can be described by a pair of two values x1 and x2.
So any one of these squares in which the agent can possibly be in can be described by x1 x2 So for instance
right now he's in the square with X1 equal to 1 and x 2 equal to 2 and therefore that's in the same
that same way we can escape any square meaning we can describe any state.
Then of course this is a very simplified version of an environment of describing states but nevertheless
it works in this case and that means that now we can feed this these states into a neural network.
And by the way here I would just like to mention that at the end of the course of good annexes we've
got an X number one and an X and but two in order to proceed successfully.
This section is highly advisable that you check out an X number one which is on artificial new neural
network so you understand how they work so that we can.
We don't have to delve into that here and we can just use the benefits of the knowledge of how artificial
neural networks work.
And so we feed in this information on the state into a neural network and then it will process this
information so x1 x2 depending on the structure of the neural network good might have multiple hidden
layers and so on.
So that's something that you you'll figure out in their practical tutorials but at the end we will structure
in such a way that it spits out four values and these four values are actually going to be our cue values.
So the values which dictate which action we need to take and further down in this tutorial we'll see
exactly how these key values are used to decide which action is taken.
But the main point here is that we no longer look at just this maze from a cube learning perspective.
We're now taking the states of the maze and we're feeding them into a deep neural network in order to
get these key values.
And at the end of the day we're still going to come up with an action we're still going to understand
how what action we need to take and we'll discuss all this in more detail.
But the question right now is why why are we doing all of this why we complete why we're making things
so much more complicated when that initial approach of Q learning was working already well the reason
for that is the Q learning was working in this very simplistic environment and we're continuing to deal
for now with this very simplistic environment in order to better understand the concepts.
But at the same time that simple Q learning will no longer work in more complex environments and we're
talking about for instance the self-driving cars we shall be creating or playing Doom when the artificial
intelligence is playing Doom or other Atari games like breakout or even self-driving cars and more advanced
reinforcement learning things such as like robots walking around and performing actions in all those
cases basic learning is insufficient is not strong is not powerful enough to be able to master those
challenges and just like we've seen in the deep learning course if you've been in our discipline course
or if you've done the annexed sections and X number one and angst do you will where you know that deep
learning is by far superior to any type of machine learning let alone simple Q learning and that's why
we're leveraging the power of deep learning here so we're feeding in the information about the environment
as a vector of values so in this case just to values into a deep neural network and then we're using
that to perform the actions that we want to decide which actions are agents going to take.
So that's kind of like a high level overview of why we're doing this.
Now let's have a look at it a bit more detail.
What happens to the concepts of kill learning when we transfer when we make this transformation from.
Or transition from simple learning into deep Hillary.
So as you saw in the previous intuition tutorials we had a slide like this which is the foundation of
temporal difference learning.
This is the formula for temporal difference.
And basically so let's go through it.
So basically we had an agent who was in this state over here which is indicated the blue arrow and we
were understanding how Temporal Difference works for this Q value of for instance going up.
And so what we saw here was before this is in the simple coloring not the Depew learning this in the
simple Hillary what we saw was before the agent had a certain and create value that he had learned about
this action of going up.
And so then he decides to take deception to go up and right after he takes his action he gets a reward
for taking this action in this state.
And that is that reward plus now he can evaluate the value of the current state he is in which is the
maximum of all of the new Q values of all of the Q values of the new actions he can take a prime in
the new state as prime and read multiplied by the decay factor of gamma.
So that is essentially the Q The new Q value or kind of like the the empirical Q value that he has just
received for taking that action.
And ideally these two two should be the same so that actually the Q value that he had in his memory
about this action in this state should equate to the actual reward plus the gamma times the value of
the state that he ended up in and therefore that's how we calculate that Temporal Difference we take
what he got after minus what he got what he had in mind what he was expecting you'd subtract one from
the other that's a Temporal Difference and then you use your learning rate alpha to adjust your Q value
your your new Q value by the Temporal Difference but with a coefficient of alpha so that is the essence
of the simple Q learning.
Now let's have a look at how it changes in deep color.
And so we're still going to work with the slide but we're going to just see exactly what's happening.
So in a deep Q learning the neural network will predict for roles as we saw in the previously.
And as we'll see for a donor's tutorial the neural network will predict for values or it might predict
more values if there's more possible actions in a given state.
But in this case we know we know that there's only four actions upright left down.
And so the neural network will predict four of these values.
So there will be no in in a deep learning situation is important.
Understand there is no before or after.
And this is how we we'll get to know this a bit better.
So the neural network will predict four of these values and it will compare not to what will happen
after.
But the neural network will compared to this exact value but it was this value which was calculated
in the previous step.
So in the previous time when the agent was in this exact square.
So let's say I don't know.
Some time ago the agent was again was in this exact square as well and it calculated this value previously.
So in the previous time long time ago the agent calculated this value.
Then the agents stored this value for the future.
And now the future has come.
So now he's in the square again and now he's got these Q values which is predicted and one of them is
for the for going up.
So now what he's going to do is going to compare the predicted value of Q to this value which he had
recorded from the previous.
And we'll understand exactly why this is important right now so just important understand here is there's
no before and after.
In this specific square this specific time we're taking the cue value that he's predicted using the
neural network this time and we're comparing it to this value which he had from the previous time from
the previous time he was in this square assessing all of the situation and likely the previous time
he actually performed this action.
So there we go.
Now let's have a look at how this all works out in the neural network and why why is it like I know
it sounds a bit complicated right now but we'll break it down into simple terms right.
Just in a second.
So this on your own network we're sitting in the states of the environment into the neural network is
going through the hidden layers then it's coming out with these outputs Q1 Q2 Q3 Q4 in that specific
state.
These are the Q values that the neural network is predicting for the possible actions.
Those are the key values.
So then we're comparing to target and these targets is exactly so if we go back here.
This is the target.
So this is the value that was predicted and then but also we know that we have a target from the last
time we were in the square.
We have a target for this same action which is up for instance.
So here we've got a target and we're going to compare so we compare Q1 versus that target.
We're comparing Q2 versus that target.
The target we had from previously Q3 versus the target Q4 versus the target.
And so this is the part where the neural network or the agent is now learning through deep learning
how to better go through.
And the key point here is that we're still applying Q learning but the concepts in set in simple killer
and you learn through temporal differences which are pretty straight forward which we've already discussed
and we know quite well by now but at the same time in deep learning how do neural networks learn while
neural networks learn through adjusting their weight.
So we have to adapt the concepts of reinforced the concepts of simple kill learning to the way neural
networks actually work and that is through updating their weights.
And so this is what we're trying to figure out here how do we adapt that concept of Temporal Difference
to a neural network so that we can leverage the full power of neural networks.
So far we've gotten this.
So we enter our environment state here as a vector goes through a neural network we get predictions
of Q values and then from the previous time the agent was in that state we have these Q target to target
one two three and four for each of these respective actions.
And so now we're up to Okay let's compare each one with each one.
And from here it's it becomes pretty straightforward if you're up to speed with neural networks.
Once again that's on a and.
Number one we're going to calculate a loss which is l here and we're going to be a huge target this
one minus Q minus this one.
We're going to square that so the square difference of the of each one of these and we're going to sum
them so we can take the sum of the squared differences of these Q values and their targets and we're
going to send them up and that's going to be a loss.
And so ideally just as we had into in the temporal difference learning so if we go back for a second.
Remember we said ideally we want this to be equal to this.
So we want the temporal difference to be zero.
So that's that means basically the agent is predicting exactly correctly what you know the Q values
that the agent is predicting are exactly or that he has a memory are exactly descriptive of the environment
and therefore the agent can navigate navigate the environ pretty well right there's no surprises there's
no there's no.
So as long as this temporal difference is a highly positive or highly negative then we've got some surprises.
But if the temporal difference is zero then he knows environment so well that he can predict what's
going on and he can and therefore his policy is going to be very good and he's going to be able to navigate.
So here.
Same thing.
So we want this loss to be as close to zero suppose as small as possible and that's why now we're going
to this is the part where we are going to leverage the real true power of neural networks so we could
take this loss we're going to use back propagation or stochastic gradient descent to take this loss
and pass it through the network pass it back or back propagate it through a network and through stochastic
gradient descent date the weights of these synopses in the network so that next time we go through this
network the way it's already a bit better descriptive of the environment.
And that's exactly hard work.
So here you have if we go back this is calculated losses calculate and it gets per prove propagated
for the network the weights are updated then the next time we get here.
This happens again and we get here and this happens again and so on and so and it keeps happening and
that's how this agent learns or basically now it's the neural network which is the brain of the agent
is learning is becoming more and more descriptive of the environment and therefore the agent is able
to navigate the environment when we say descriptive environment basically means that when we put in
the states of the environment that the agent is in we are more likely to get closer and closer to the
actual cue values.
And that happens because the key values that we want to find the right action.
And that happens because these new targets are actually empirically derived so he every.
How does he find these new targets.
That's because that's actually there.
So he actually observes.
Okay.
So once I do take this step what's the reward I get.
And then what's the value of this state.
So same thing as we saw previously in Q learning in the simple Q learning intuition so he learns this
through trial and error and then he constructs his network or updates the way it serves his network
in such a way that the predicted Q values are close and close up proximity to the target.
Q values so very similar to the concept we discussed here in the simple Temporal Difference learning
of the simple Q learning algorithm.
So there we go.
That's that's how the agent learns.
So we're up to here.
That's the learning part.