Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this video we are finally starting with a stage five of this project this stage is all about saving
the model and converting it to tens of low light version of it.
So we are going to take everything that we learned so far.
Train the model and save it to tens of low light version and the first step is to save the model itself.
So let's do that.
In this video before we say the model let's define a model name.
So define a variable called Model Name equals two and you can set whatever name you want.
It is only important to have H5 ext so in my case I'm going to name it fashion underscore mobile underscore
model dot age 5 the age 5 is extension of carers save the model.
That's it for our name now that we have the name of a model.
The next thing that we have to do is to save it.
To do that we are going to call dear adult carers not models that save model.
This function takes two arguments a trained model and model name execute a cell.
And now we have our model saved.
It is very easy to do.
And this is how you save models for other applications as well if we go to files of this project we
can find a new file called Fashion mobile model that age 5 which is our model itself and that's it for
now.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.