Hello everyone and welcome to despite a tutorial in the previous with you.
We have started our flask API on the board.
And in this video we are going to use the postman to send the request and make predictions over the
Internet just for the track.
I opened uploads folder to see all objects that we are trying to predict.
If you haven't used the postman before this is the interface.
I know there are a lot of moving parts but in our case we are going to use just a few of them.
For example this line right here is just a line where you can enter an address where you want to send
a request.
Here you can specify what type of the request you want to send in the blue send button.
It's pretty much self-explanatory and the response window is here to visualize all data that we received
from the server okay.
If we take a look at the address line you can see that we already have some address there.
The first part is just a local host IP.
In the second part is the port that we specified in the plastic application please note if you specify
another port for your flask application specified here instead of this one now about the request we
want to send a request to classify image function that we've wrote in our flask API backend.
And if you remember it only takes the post to request go to this part of the interface and select the
post request.
Now it's time to specify the full path to which we want to send the request this address right.
Here is the root address for the API and it always stays the same.
The second part of the address is one that changes and the one that we need to specify right now.
So after the port in the address right API slash V1 and here we need to specify a name of an image let's
use these free dot PMG as the first test subject right.
Free dot BMG before we send our first request just a side note to remember if we had the full functional
web application this part would be automatic for the user.
OK.
Now are you ready to send the first request to our custom made API and click Send button.
And we get amazing results for this image.
We recognize the correct it was trousers on it this proves that we have successfully build a fully functional
API that has an accuracy of over 98 percent on unseen data.
Let's test this API on other images that we selected before we end the tutorial.
Let's go with Image 4 and click send.
As you can see amazing correct results.
Again.
Now let's go with the image 1.
And again our results are correct.
This time we predicted pool over class and finally let us go with image 0.
It should be a boot and again we have correct results.
Congratulations for creating your own custom made flask API that harnesses the power of deep learning
in the backend.
I'm really excited that we sold this project in this course together and for now if you have any questions
or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.