Hi friends, welcome to AWS automation with moto three of Python and lambda functions.
Let me provide the object two of this course before starting it.
The objective of this course is to cover the core concepts of
moto three and lambda C. Most of the cases in real time,
moto three works along with the lambda.
That's the reason we included both moto three and lambda into one single course.
And this course is designed to understand
Bhutto three and lambda concepts with realtime scenarios.
We divided this course into two parts to get more clarity
on moto three and lambda part one,
it is about how to write and execute Python Bhutto three scapes on our local server.
You were local server maybe.
Anyways, PO2 is about how to write and
execute Python boater escapes in lambda with the different triggering methods.
And finally, by the end of this course,
you will get the knowledge to apply
different concepts of Bhutto three and lambda four different AWS services.
Thank you.