Friends here our concept is how to implement Python Bhutto three escapes using
client object C. We know that we can implement
python both risk using either client or resource object.
And client object is available for each and every service of your AWS.
So here we are going to show you help
to use client object in your Python moto three skips.
Let me open my diagonal.
So here I am working from Windows Terminal,
but same steps you can also follow on your Linux terminal.
Let me open this script.
First. Let me import Bhutto three.
Now, see if you want to enter into any of your AWS service.
You have to enter into that service from AWS management console.
So first I'm going to create AWS management console.
Of course, you can also go with the default session,
but I'm going to create customer attrition.
So AWS management console session or object equals
to simply Bhutto 3.Now session, session.
Now in your hand you how you were AWS management console.
So I created this epidermis management console with my root credentials.
Of course, you can also go with your Butler IAM credential.
But I want to work with the different services using this Python script.
That's why I'm using Profile Name as root.
I mean, I'm working with the root credentials.
Now you how your AWS management console in your hand.
Suppose I want to walk with IAM EC2 and S3.
Then I how to create your IAM EC2 and S3 consoles in your script.
So let me create my IAM console.
And here we are working with the client.
That's why I'm going to create I am console using client equals two.
So I am console using client object equals to simply from your AWS management console,
use client method, the opposite service name.
So I wanted to work with IAM,
then provide us some region name.
If in case if you don't provide any region name,
it will consider from your config file default region name it will select.
Now, I want to work with EC2 and S3 also.
So you have to create your AC3 EC2,
and then yes, three console objects using client.
So just to modify the names in C2.
So instead of IAM,
so this is now easy to console object.
This is S3 console object.
Now in our hand,
how I am console object,
EC2, Console object, then S3, console opposite.
Then what is your requirement?
Suppose I want to display all my IAM users,
all EC2 instances, and then all buckets.
Then how you can implement your logic from here.
As of now you are on,
I am console absurd or on EC2 Console object or S3 console object.
Let me take list all IAM users using client object.
That's it.
I don't know what is the next step of how to do then how you can implement.
I am on IAM console,
but how I can list using your Python scripts.
So first open a web browser.
I bought O3 documentation.
Then open your first a link moto three related documentation.
Then goto here, available services.
Then what is your required every service I am,
then go to down somewhere you will find I am.
I am.
So using client object we how to implement then select the client.
Right-click open new link client object.
So we already created this client object.
This is like your IAM console using claimed,
we already created these steps.
So those are the steps inputting Bhutto three,
creating AWS management console,
then I am console client.
Now this is equals to client here
because official documentation is with respect to default session.
That's why I don't get confused.
These two steps already we've done in terms of three steps.
First step, second step, three step.
Now we have this asic client for IAM.
Then if you see immediately in the next line,
there are these are available methods.
Then what is your requirement?
I want to list all my aim users.
First of all, just to go with each and every option,
just read them somewhere,
you will find your required option here.
Definitely, there is no doubt in that definitely you were option will be available here.
So our option as of no list IAM users, right?
See that somewhere listed group,
groups and list roles and L2 users.
Just click on that list users and it lists users is taking some arguments as of no,
don't worry about arguments.
We will discuss about it right now.
See simply, you are,
I am console client object dot L2 users,
and it is taking some arguments.
Don't worry about arguments.
Let me show you the output for that.
So directly I am printing.
You can take, yeah,
let me show you that first IAM console,
client dot, what is the operation?
Simply L2 users, that's a list to users. That's it.
Now this will do some output directly.
You can print it out, or you can store that output into a variable.
So I am taking that as a response.
So you know, documents you how response you can take any variable.
There is no restriction for this.
Then let me printed that response.
So directly you can print or you can store,
you are outputting via variable called response and you can print that.
So let me save this.
Python held on client object dot p way and see the output.
You are getting some output that is in terms of dictionary, right?
Not only for the IAM service,
for each and every service,
only the first-level operation is not operation.
I mean, let me show you that from your IAM console client object,
you are doing some dot operation only.
This is upset on this object you are having first-level operation, has dot operation.
After that, definitely you will get your output as a in terms of Dictionary.
What we are getting here, victory.
Even you don't need to print and to see these response
in official document itself will have a output also.
So to list a user support,
this is the syntax.
If you go down, you're also having response, response syntax.
You're going to get your response in this way.
See that? So in this output you are having,
this is a dictionary, right?
Mixture remains key and its value key value representation.
Key-value paper presentation, right?
So I don't want,
suppose these undesired self, No,
I need only uses information.
Then just take your output instead of getting response
directly just in terms of use key as users and see the output.
Now from this entire output, from this entire dictionary,
I want these users value.
That's why I'm taking this as my key so that I will get this as my value right.
Now, see that, see the output users.
Now this user sees it does list, list.
In this list, if you observe, again,
the first value is one dictionary up to this,
this is one big, sorry, second one is second dictionary.
Anyway, you how in this list two values.
Now from each value I need only username.
So from list, I wanted to separate,
foster these first two value,
then second value, then you have to use loops for loop.
Now let me take for low.
So instead of printing that Italy, this response,
what I'm doing is from that response I'm taking for loop.
For each item.
In response, you can take any variable, right?
I mean here each item you nothing but any variable.
Then simply print it, we're each item.
That's it.
Let me save it and run it and see the output.
Here. I forgot to close with one square brace,
bracket,
o, extra parenthesis.
That fine. Now see the output.
You are getting each item separately.
Now each item is a dictionary.
Whatever the, each item you are printing, that is a dictionary.
See that?
This each item you are printing,
this each item is a dictionary,
but from these each item,
I need only username.
Then use one more key.
See that instead of directly printing you are each item then print.
Here with respect to C0, that is the dictionary,
each item is a dictionary, then I need only user name from the dictionary.
That's a, that's where
you're getting your all am users which are there in your AWS account. That's it.
This is the simple help to use for your IAM.
Just to list a users.
We have lot of operations, okay,
we'll go with our different different operations while going forward.
That's fine.
Now, let me open.
So you guys saw instead of opening my script from terminal,
what I will do is I am using one of the,
ideally of your Python called Sublime Text.
You can go with any your favorite tau.
Ideally, I'm going with Sublime Text.
You can go with the atom or by chomp.
Spider can go with anyone.
So our script is held pawn.
This one.
Now let me comment this.
Now next step we suppose I want to display all my EC2 instances IDs,
list all EC2 instances IDs.
Then already you have in your hand you are EC2 Console using client object.
You how your EC2 client,
but how we can list all EC2 instances.
Again, open your official documentation, moto three documentation.
Go to available services,
then go to your required service called EC2.
Under EC2, don't look with the remaining operations, okay.
As of now we are working at client only just click on plain.
Now import border three client equals to bow to the nullcline for EC2,
we already done these two steps in terms of three input moto three,
your AWS management console session from the delta-V created EC2 Console.
Now, this client is exactly equals to our EC2 Console plank.
That's fine.
Now, see that below.
These are the available methods for your client object of EC2.
First, go with just to read them all options.
But as of now, directly I'm going with I need instances, right?
Describe instances option will be here somewhere.
But if you go with each and every option so that he
can understand what is the purpose of each and every one.
You had to go with at least once.
Now, I mean describe instances,
describe images, but we want to work with the describe instances.
Describe instances method is there C in your client operations,
the first lowest dot operation.
Of course, this method is also taking some arguments,
but as of now, I don't want to explain about them.
I want to go with without any arguments, fine.
Now, directly you can print the word reason it,
EC2, Console, client object dot describe instances.
Or you can store this into a variable called any variable you can take.
But here suppose I am taking response equals two.
Then just let me bring to
them and see the output.
So I'm running this Python script from my terminal C,
the output, you're getting information.
But if you observed that ending with curly brace,
starting with curly brace means this either dictionary.
So only first-level operation is dot operation.
After that, immediately you are going to get you a response in terms of dictionaries.
That is, in the client.
I mean, if you use client operations,
you are going to get dictionary as the output by performing one dot operation.
Fine.
But in this output what we need,
we need our instance IDs,
but where they are.
Right, see that incase if you are getting confusion
here from by seeing this output C in the official documentation itself.
This response is there.
I mean, this output is also there somewhere just to go down somewhere,
they are giving in detail about your response, your output.
So you have a dictionary, reservations, groups, instances.
Now, these instances, or they're under this reservations.
So that's why what I'm doing is I'm taking first
the key so that I'm going to get all this is the list.
One more thing. First, let me take reservations.
So in this output I am taking reservations.
So response reservations, No,
let me rerun your Python script.
C, the output. You are getting a list.
In that list, again,
you have a dictionary, different types.
I mean, number of dysarthric tells you how because on my us-east1-d. uh,
how three instances, that's why you're going to get three dictionaries.
First, let me take list.
So that is a list, right? That's why I'm taking for loop.
This manual observationally is required for your client.
For each item in let me print the work each item.
Just for our understanding purpose,
I am printing dots,
hyphens so that you are going to get only 13.
Where is it?
Yeah, from here. If you observe,
this is for first,
second, and then third, right? Find.
Now in this output, what I need.
I need from each item, I need instances.
Let me print from each item.
Only instances.
Be clear on this.
Now let me rerun and see the output.
You are getting again. Three outputs.
Fine.
But after printing your each item instances,
that is also your dictionary seed,
sorry, that is a list.
You see that there is a list for each item.
Instances output you are getting as a list.
Now in this list,
right, there is a dictionary again.
Now let me do one thing that is a list.
That's why I just, I'm taking for loop on this.
For each instance, I'm taking suppose in.
Let me print each instance and see the output.
You are getting some output,
right there, getting some output.
But what I need from this output,
you're going to get output as a dictionary.
But I need image ids are not immediately instance ID.
Then what I'm doing is simply I'm taking here instance ID as the key.
Now see the output. You are getting.
You are incense IDs, three instance Hardy's.
Let me show you. On my console,
I have three instances.
So this is the way how to use
your client observed to work with your required operation using client.
I mean, for your service.
Two running instances, one-stop for instance,
just after the instance ID. Double 6F.
Yes, double 67. Then 3-5 year four.
3-5 year four.
That's right. That's right.
So guys, now you just try with S3.
Create some buckets in your account and try to
print your bucket names using client object.
But it's simple.
Again, just to go with your documentation somewhere,
you will find your S3 available services in S3 Just to go with client.
Yeah, here somewhere.
S3 Just to go with client, open that client.
So these two steps already we done.
So import border three,
create database management console session object than S3 console.
So this S3 console CLI is exactly equals to client object in your page.
Then go With all your options.
Somewhere. You will find option called list of buckets.
Just use that and get it your output and manipulate based on
dictionary keys and values so that you will get all you were buckets using client object.
Let's say.
Okay, thank you.