Prince, here we're implementing a simple Python Bhutto three slave to get AWS account ID.
So this concept is useful whenever if you are working with multiple AWS account.
So you are analysts or quantity can be get by using SDS service.
Let me open my sublime text.
So I have taken a simple Python script name has get AWS or controlling dot p y.
Let me import Buddha 3 first.
Then after that, first let me create your epidermis management console.
So simply AWS management console.
So I'm going to create a realist management console with root access.
So equals two.
Bhutto three, got Shizhen session,
then just providing your profile name,
whatever you configure on your host.
Then let me create your STS object, your STS console.
So how we can create.
We know that for some of the services we have a resource as well as
client let me such in our official documentation for sts.
So B23 documentation.
So available services go here, STS, SDS.
If you observe here for sts you have only client option, you don't how resource.
Then let me click on that and open it.
And here they are creating default session.
Of course we created our customization.
So from that we need to create our SDS concerns.
So simply SDS console using client equals to
your AWS management console dot client than service name equals to SDS.
Then if you want to provide region name, that's it.
Now in your hand you how STS console using client opposite.
Then how we can get AWS account ID c.
We know that in our client object,
we how all operations as one set.
Just to go and start somewhere.
So here as of now directly I'm going with your required option.
So that is get color identity.
If you open this option in this option output,
you will get your account ID.
This is user ID, and this is a container.
If you are working with some IAM user,
you will get you IAM user ID. Let me show you this.
Get color identity. So simply,
directly, Let me take response equals two.
You are STS client object dot your operation get color identity.
Then let me print your response on C, the output.
What happened? Moto three. What I did.
Yeah, sorry, I see that you're getting some output.
It is in terms of dictionary.
In this dictionary, if you observe some very HUB, our cone,
this account is nothing but your account ID and user ID.
This is user ID.
If you observe here both user id and account ID both
are same because this is root account.
We created our, our AWS management console using the root. Let me do one thing.
I'm going to come in this.
So now let me create your AWS management console with particular IAM user.
Instead of this root,
I'm creating my enemies management console using a let say,
easy to IAM user,
easy to download per user equals to simply Bhutto 3.What Session.get.
Such an then just provide your profile name.
So I have one of the profile called EC2 developer.
Then from this just a creative or SDS console.
So here instead of root,
let me take, so from this AWS management console.
Now let me take these two lines. Now see the output.
So now user id is different, account is different.
So our counties, your root account ID.
Now in the same script,
we know that we can create any number of AWS management console by
using different am users profiles or with no,
let me run and see the output.
First output.
This output is using the word root account credentials,
and this account is using Institute dollar per IAM user.
C in the both the cases are same, account ID is same.
The only thing is you are running the first output using root credentials.
So that's why user IDs route.
But second output is from easy to dollar per.
So for that, your user ID,
not only you already are also having Jaron, right?
See that?
And you are username here.
And even if you have the rehear route, that's it.
So now from you can go with
either root account credentials or with its particular IAM user.
And by using this operation on your console,
you are going to get your account ID.
So directly I can take here,
these are cone, either hear or see.
In your dictionary you can use to get your output.
Square brackets you were key. That is one way.
Or instead of square brackets,
you are also having one more option operation on your dictionary
that is not good, then you are key.
So you now see the output.
Let's say.
So by using this simple logic,
you can able to get your AWS account ID.
Let's say. Okay, thank you for watching this video.