Friends here we are implementing some simple Python Bourdieu three scapes on EC2 service.
First, let me open my EC2 Console.
So I'm entering into EC2 Console from AWS management console.
And if you have done in newer left aside or having different types of options,
you can see instances, instance pipes, amazed.
What are the available volumes with your account on your particular region.
Then snapshots, security groups, elastic IPs, keypads.
So and having lots of options for each and every option,
you can implement your Python bow to three scripts.
So let me open my sublime text editor first.
I'm going to import Bhutto 3 first.
Then let me create my AWS management console using,
by using profile called root or anywhere how one more profiled called Easy to developer.
That is configured with easily to dollar per IAM user.
So I want to work with the institute than I can
take that easy to dollar per profile also.
Now let me take Bhutto three Session.get fashion than profile name.
C, I want to walk with EC2 service.
So you have to take the IAM user profile name,
which is having access to access your EC2 services.
So I have a institute dollar per profile.
These are how access to you or easy to services.
Fine.
Now let me create my AWS EC2 Console.
C to create your EC2 Console,
we are having both client and resource options.
Let me open your official documentation and let me create,
let me click on your EC2 Console.
And for easy too, we how client and also your resource.
So here I'm implementing Python boat O3 scripts using client.
You just try to implement for same concept using resource object.
Directly.
I'm going to attach the script for service resource object,
but I'm implementing here using client.
So let me create my client TO AWS EC2 service client.
So EC2 Console using client object.
So simply your analysts management console,
client then service name equals to e, C2.
Then select your region.
So for ec2 region name is important.
So I want to work with suppose US West One.
So now in your hand you how you are easy to console,
then what are the scripts you want to implement?
So the very first clip, what I want to implement 0s,
I want to list the available instances in
my vest US West One instances IDs into state and when it was launched.
So I need that. So let me open Sublime Text first.
Let me go to your documents also.
And see we know that in our client,
you are having all options under one set.
So if you go down somewhere,
you how your option.
So you have to look all these options at least once so that you can
remember what is the operation with what option.
So some very hard describe instances.
Describe emails. Are there describe instances just to open that.
So they say describe instances.
So you could take some arguments as of now.
Again, I'm not touching about this.
Arguments will discuss in detail about
these arguments while discussing about collections concept.
That's fine. Now let me take response equals to simply you're easy to console.
Dot u1 operation that is described EC2 instances, describe instances simply.
Now let me print the result of first, see the output.
So we already know that same response with an example.
It is there, here itself in your document itself.
So this is the response if you want to see your output in this format.
So you actually, if you observe here,
the response is there with continuation lines.
Now I want to see in this format then Python three,
you have a module called P print.
So I'm going to import from P print, import pre-print.
Now instead of print, simply if you print,
now see the output, you will get some clarity and output now.
So whenever if you want to see the output detail,
clearly just use pre-print.
So under reservations, some very how instance's first let me take reservations.
So directly I am taking response equals to describe instances.
Then there I am taking reservations.
Now let me print. So initially you need
to execute step-by-step so that you'll get some idea from the output.
Now this is a list.
So that means the response is a list.
Now I am taking here for loop for each item.
In a response.
Let me print each item and see the output.
So you are going to get dictionaries, right?
So up to this disease, one dictionary,
entitling is only one data center because under my us,
only one instance, I hope.
Yeah, only one instance will see that.
Now this entire thing is a dictionary.
So some very hard instances here.
So now let me take
here from this response instances, now observe the output.
Now these instances, he's also a list,
even though you have only one instance information, but that is a list.
That's why you have to take here once again, you our for loop.
For each in stance info.
Non-nuclear. Take this lengthy variable,
you can take your simple variable name.
Now I'm printing, you will each instance info, see the output.
So if you want to get clearly your output just to print.
Now see the output.
What I need. I need my instance ID.
I need my guess image ID if you want,
you can take instance ID is the instance type, is there.
What is the key yield for that?
What is the lunchtime?
So let me print at least what is the image ID
used to launch this EC2 instance and then Instance ID.
So very simple, just simply print.
So let me take first image id.
See I'm printing the image ID used to launch this instance keys.
So here I want to pray that slash n.
Now, the instance ID E is.
Then I want to print out what is the lunchtime for that?
Of course, you can also print your instance tie EPA key name,
lunchtime, whatever the option you want you can print,
I'm printing some of the options.
Then the instance, launch time
e. So here I want to print my lunch time of this EC2 instance dot format.
So simply take your each instance NFO.
Now instead of taking this Lindsey wherever now I'm making it as short,
simply each I'm taking.
So each.
So first I want to print each of,
let me copy directly these key.
Then next, each instance ID.
Then each launch time.
Now see the output would happen.
Unexpected end of file.
That's it.
Now see the output. You are getting your required output.
Let, let me remove these people because I need normal print.
You're getting your information image ID launch ID, ease.
And lunchtime is just,
I want to use a lunchtime as suppose I want to print only date,
then you can format this because this is DATETIME format in your AWS,
whatever the output you are going to get using Python script,
that is datetime object.
So directly you can apply string format time.
So simply percentage.
Percentage is month, then percent, percentile date.
Now let me run and see the output.
See that you are getting only you would date.
So this is very simple Python script just to work with your EC2 instance Service.
Now, let me do one more thing.
Let me work with volumes.
So now let me come at this.
Now. I want to work with one, yeah, one more thing.
Let me select different region.
Suppose I, how ease US East one in that house from different instances.
Say the output C.
So just to differentiate each and every output.
So print.
Instead of here, I will do one thing.
Just for differentiation purpose.
Oh, let me run and see the output.
That's it.
So at having three instances in my US East One,
you're going to get the information for these three instances.
You just try to print the instance ID and also instances state,
some very hokey called state so that you will
get what is the current state of your EC2 instance?
You just try with that. That's fine.
Now, let me comment this score.
Suppose as of now we worked with the EC2 service, EC2 instance.
Now let me work with volumes.
So we have three instances.
That's why Definitely you how tuple three volumes.
Now, let me click on volumes C. All are under ec2 service only.
So already we have our EC2 Console in your hand.
The only thing from EC2 Console,
how we can get our institute incenses First, let me work on US.
West one and C, two list1 volumes.
Definitely somewhere you how option?
Just to go and such volumes is there.
Just click on that and open it.
Similarly, this is also option like describe volumes.
So let me copy it.
So describe volumes also taking some arguments as if not don't worry about them.
Now simply, I am taking response equals to
our EC2 Console using client object dot,
you would describe volumes.
Then let me print.
So I am using p print just to see the output.
Clearly.
See output, you are going to get clearly.
And indeed, suppose what do you need volumes.
Now if you have done the output in this dictionary,
there is a key called volumes.
Take this key here itself.
Now see the output.
This is at least see that attending you how square bracket,
that means this is a list,
whether you have one volume or two volumes or three volumes,
that is always a list.
That's why now Andy's response,
what I'm doing is I'm taking for loop for each item in response.
So if you don't want to write two lines directly,
you can copy this score and Berkeley pasted here itself.
You can guess if you don't want, write two lines.
That is your wish.
Then suppose, let me p print each item.
First, I need to observe the output.
See each item output you are getting for each,
easy to install the volume,
you're getting some information in terms of a dictionary.
Then see that your volume id is there.
What is the volume type? Is that even you can also see availability joan,
Even that information you can also see for your EC2 instance also.
Then what is the for each instance it is attached.
See that intense ideas is there.
Right?
What is the creation time when it was created?
Now let me print that.
So now what I am doing these so here guys,
directly you are getting,
you are listing the first-level itself.
So I am printing for in,
let's say the volume id.
So here I want to print them volume ID.
Then. What is the biopsies,
their sizes, their AGB by default,
this is in terms of GB, right?
What is the state it is in use?
What is available to join when it was created,
is it encrypted? No.
Right.
So that information is available here.
Yeah. We held three right here because you are working with the US East one nanomolar.
Let me print that. Then.
Intensity.
Then what is the state?
Is it used in user state R-naught,
volume IT volume type.
Let me print at least creation availability, Joan.
So here I want to print availability June.
Then if you want to print what is the volume type?
Then I'm printing volume,
I see nothing is there.
You can observe each and everything in this output,
because this is claimed to definitely each and every option is there in the output.
If it is a resource, there is a doubt.
May be a may or may not.
How your output, your required the option in your output volume type.
So here I want to print.
So now let me take dot format.
Then let me print here each item in this item first you are printing volume ID.
So let me take volume ID.
Then. What you want after that?
Availability Jones.
So each item then availability,
Joan, C, whatever the options you want,
you just printed them. That's it.
So this concept is useful just to create
some discovery script or inventory skipped for your required service.
Not only for EC2, even for S3 also,
this concept is useful just to implement your discovery scripts.
Then last option, you are printing volume type.
So here volume type is there.
And that's it. Let me save it and run it.
See the output. That's it.
Just get clarity for each and every volume.
Just I am writing this.
That's fine.
So same way you just try to work with
your remaining options which are there in your EC2 Console.
If you have some VPC, yes,
you can work with that if you have some load balancers, auto-scaling.
So whatever the options you want,
You all options you can get from your EC2 Console.
40 were easy to related services.
That's it. Ok.
Thank you.