Friends here we are discussing about moto three collections concept of resource opposite.
See collections concept is slightly different in your client object.
We will discuss about it in later videos and go to
three collections are useful to collect group of resources information.
And here I'm explaining about this concept by taking an example called EC2 service.
But you can apply the same concept for any of your AWS service.
Now, let me open my sublime text editor.
Suppose I want to explain this concept with EC2 service.
So let me create EC2 Console.
So for that first time creating AWS management console equals to moto three
dot Session.get session profile name.
You can take any profile.
Then let me create EC2 Console using
a resource object because we are working with collections concept of resource.
Then AWS management console dot resource,
then provide your service name equals to EC2
than region name, US East one.
Suppose.
Now let me open our AWS management console once.
C, this is easy to console,
then what our group of resources see in your AWS EC2 Console,
you can work with instances or instance types
or let me go with images or volumes or snapshots or security groups,
all these things or group of resources.
Now collectively, to collect all these group of resources,
you have to use collections concept.
Now let me open your boat O3, official documentation.
And let me navigate into You are easy to surveys.
So available services.
Go to EC2 and select your service resource open that.
We know that in our resource object,
we have three set of operations.
Set one set to unset,
three set three are related to collections.
And see here, what are the group of services you
can collect by using resource collections on your EC2 Console.
See, you can get or you can collect all these group of resources.
Suppose if you want to work with images or instances or
volumes are subnet snapshot, just click on that.
Suppose I want to collect instances.
Then click on that instances.
Now, first let me create your instances collection object c.
Simply medically, I'm printing from your EC2 Console resource object.
I'm creating instances collection object.
Now, just run it and see the output.
This is an object.
See the list of operations on this.
So that you are getting some output.
So in that you have these many sub methods on the world.
Collection of disease collection object.
On this object you can apply all these sub methods.
And as of now just try to concentrate on all filter and limit.
We'll discuss about remaining options in our next session, next video.
Fine.
Now let me make a note on this.
So on instances collection object,
we are discussing a boat all limit then filter.
So first let me go with all and limit.
Simply you have to do operation called Not all.
Not all.
Even this operations you can find in your console.
I mean, in your document itself,
see instances of objects.
It is having all create tags, right? Filter.
So all options are available here also,
but you can easily get from your command line itself.
Now let me save it and run it sees output.
Again, you are getting an object,
but this is an iterator.
So simply all means you're going to collect
all your EC2 instances from your particular region of your in-situ.
Now, for each in, simply print each.
Anyway, this dot all is going to collect all your EC2 instances.
That's why you're going to get three instances because on
my AWS EC2 Console under your US East one,
I have three instances. That's why it is collecting.
That's fine.
So you're never, if you want to collect all your EC2 instances,
you are using option sub,
sub method called all.
But I want to limit,
I want to get only assume that you are having
some a 100 EC2 instances in particular region.
I want to get top ten,
I mean order, order.
So first ten I want to get,
then you can use simply limit.
Limit. I want to get ten.
Of course I have only three.
That's just I have taken too,
limited too. And now see the output.
Anyway, this option is not useful very much in your real time.
No problem, but you have an option.
That's fine.
Now the important operation submitted on our collection object is always filter.
First, let me apply a filter and see the output.
You are getting all your EC2 instances.
It's like exactly equals to all.
But using this filter submit on your collection object you how lot of
advantages let me show you by opening you are documentation.
See that this is a filter.
So now funder is taking some arguments.
So as of now I am not touching about the remaining arguments.
I'm touching with only filters.
And be clear, these filters is an argument for your dot filter method.
And this filters is a list,
and this list consist of weekly or a dictionary.
And you can write here any number of dictionary CR,
each dictionary is like one filter.
So just for your understanding purpose,
I am making a simple syntax.
So.
Field tests equals to list.
And in this list you can apply any number of feeders.
Now let me create my first filter.
So fritter one, you can take any variable name here.
I am taking simply f one.
So what is the purpose to create filters first,
see in my console,
EC2 Console, or how three instances out of which two instance or stop,
then I want to display only running instances.
I wanted display only running.
I want to collect the information about running instances.
I don't want to collect the information about stopping stances,
then you need to flatter you are instances for that.
You have to use this filter.
For that you have to use u sub resource submitted
called filter for that you have to apply argument called filters.
And that filter is a list.
In this filter, you can apply any number of filters.
First, let me create one filter, F1.
And what are the filters you are going to apply in the list,
that is L, that is the dictionary.
See that?
This is a dictionary. And this dictionary consists
of standard key called name and key called values.
And name is a string.
You can provide your required name here.
And the values based on this name,
you have to provide a value here.
Now, I am taking this entire thing as a filter one.
So one is a dictionary.
So in that he has standard key called name and how to provide the name here.
We'll provide it comma values.
Neither standard keys in your filters.
Then values or list of values.
Again, don't get confused.
Just follow this syntax here so that it will be easy to apply
filters for your collections filter method.
Now, my requirement is I want to list the running instances.
Then what is the name I can provide here?
And what is the value I can provide here? Just go down.
C, sum.
These all are name values.
Whatever the name is there, right?
You have to provide some string here.
So you can select any one of this string from here, already there. How?
So as of now what we need instead to state name.
So just such somewhere, yeah,
here we have instance state name.
Let me take it, copy and paste it here.
Then values.
So what are the instances State named,
you need a running,
instances are pending or running and pending are running and terminated.
So all values are there directly here itself.
Now, I'm taking a run mean.
Now let me take my value as running.
Not only one value, you can provide any number of values inside of your values list.
As of now first, let me apply the same phone and see the output.
How many instances you are getting.
You are going to get only one instance that is six f,
c, six f is currently running.
Now assume that anywhere EC2 Console you how running instances to operating centers,
some pending state instances,
some terminated, but I want to display running and stopped.
Then c here it is, L,
We have one more value stock would copy it.
And your wireless itself,
you can apply running values,
sorry, earning comma, stop.
That's no, let me save it.
And now you're going to get three instances.
That's now my requirement is this is one filter.
I want to get the instances which are running and which are p2 dot micro instance type.
Then you have to take one more filter and take name as instance pipe,
and apply your required value there.
So let me take one more filter here.
Likewise, you can create any number of filters.
So anyway, while creating your filter, first of all,
just follow this syntax name you have to provide here, comma values.
Values is a list.
Take This is the syntax.
Now name, what is your name?
So my requirement is I need to filter the running and
stopper instances which are under T2 dot micro instance type.
So to get you are running and stopped.
This is the filter. And to filter you are p2 dot micro.
You had to take name as instance pipe.
And here you have to provide T2 dot micro.
Please don't get confused somewhere.
I'm taking double quotations somewhere.
I'm taking a single condition.
You can take any. Today's No problem. Now save it.
F2, apply here.
Comma F2, you're fun comma F2.
Now you are filtering based on your F1 and F2 filters.
So what is a fun to get running and stopped?
What is F2 to get T2 dot Micro now intersection part you are going to get.
Now see the output, right?
So this is the very,
very important concept to collect your group of resources.
So filters or filter method is very,
very important on your collection object.
K will discuss about your remaining operations on collections in the next session.
Okay, thank you.