Friends here we are implementing Python Botox to delete unused and untagged EBS volumes.
Let me open my sublime text.
And here we are implementing this script using a resource as well as client objects.
So first let me import Bhutto three,
and let me create my console.
I mean AWS management console object equals two,
moto three dot, dot,
dot session then just provide you a profile name.
So here I am taking EC2 dollar per IAM profile name,
then see if you want to work with the volumes.
Volumes are there under your EC2 Console.
That's why let me create EC2 Console.
So I'm creating EC2 Console for resource object first,
then AWS management console,
then resource, then service name.
So we want to work with EC2 service because volumes or present in insitu console,
then select your required region.
So I want to work under the region name called US East one.
So whatever the region you just take that. Now.
So before going to delete your unused untagged EBS volumes First,
let me collect all EBS volumes.
So to collect your all EBS volumes,
you had to use collection object.
Let me open the word photo documentation and let me enter into available services,
then select your EC2.
And here we are implementing using resource.
Then let me open resource documentation.
And here go to last.
Because third set in thoughts that we have collections.
See that volumes is they're open that and there is a method called all or filter, right?
Or limit or pays size, whatever it may be.
Now, let me take all first.
Simply, I'm taking for
each volume in your EC2 Console a resource object dot volumes,
collection object dot all I want to see all.
Then print you are each volume.
And on this object,
Johann number of operations.
So if you want to see you can do here DAR off,
you are each volume or in your documentation itself,
you can see that C under EC2,
if you go down somewhere, you how volume.
So this is the object which is creating for each and every volume object.
Now on that, see that there is ID.
These all are the operations.
Again here also three sets.
So I want to print ID and what is the state?
Then?
Let me print your each volume id comma,
each volume dot state.
And after the output c,
we are getting four volumes.
And out of four volumes,
three volumes are available and one volume is in use.
That means these three are unused volumes.
Fine.
Now let me open my Database Management Console and go to volumes.
See that how many volumes are there?
Yes, four volumes are there out of which one is in use
remaining all are available unused volumes.
Now.
As of now because of all you are going to get all the volumes.
But I need to get only available volumes.
I don't want to get in use volumes only unused volumes I need to get then apply filter.
Dot filter method apply here filters.
So filter c goes to list.
Let me take some filter for EBS unused.
I'm taking that as a filter name.
Then how to create this filter c,
We know that for each filter you have a standard syntax, that is a dictionary.
In the dictionary, how two keys name, clue, right?
What, what is the name here?
Then values.
And these values is a list.
So first, if you follow this syntax,
then it is very easy to create your fetus.
Now go to your documentation.
Here, filters are there.
So filters, you can apply filters.
Then what is the name you can provide here as of now,
what is your requirement based on state?
You need that then such here somewhere.
See that status.
Status is the name for your filter.
If the status is available,
then I want to display that c just right here.
Status, then year values just take available.
I want to get only unused volumes means available volumes.
Now save it and run it and see that.
Now you're going to get only available volumes.
That's fine.
But along with available volumes,
so I need to get my untagged volumes.
See, suppose if you search here, if you observe here.
Let me such all the volumes.
C4, second volume.
Here we have a tag called do not delete it.
That means even though it is available unused,
I don't want to delete it because all it tanks are there.
Now.
You need to identify the volumes which are available and which are untagged.
So now as of now you are getting all are available volumes,
but one of the volume is having tags,
but you need to separate that in a ticket only untagged volumes,
then how you can write or we can modify your logic.
And there is no filter to get
volumes or any EC2 instances are snapshots which are not having tags.
If you have a tag that you can identify by using filters, if you don't,
how tasks, then there is no filter to identify that.
Then what I will do is see that along with the word.
There is one more option on each and every volume.
Come here and see that tags.
So I'm running, I'm dot packs I'm using.
Now see the output.
C for foster volume.
There are no tags for second volume, there are some tags.
Third volume there are no tags.
Now what I will do is here I will take some if condition if each volume bags.
If, if if each volume tags means if tags are there,
then this will become true.
If there are no tags, this will become failed.
So not each volume tags.
If there are no tags,
then I want to display them.
Now see the output. Now you are able to get
the volumes I available volumes and which are not having any tags.
So untagged unused volumes, you are able to get it.
Now our next step is you need to delete that.
So how we can delete it.
See that anywhere individually,
on each and every volume,
you have an option called Where is it?
Delete?
See that operation?
Simply volume dot delete.
That's it. Now, let me do one thing.
Print.
Deleting unused and untagged volumes.
That's it.
Not to delete it. What is the syntax?
Simply, you are each volume object dot delete.
If you want to capture the response, you can capture it.
But I'm not capturing as of now.
That's it. So once it is done, your loop,
then finally I can say deleted,
all unused untagged volumes.
That's a no, let me save it and run it and see the output.
Now go to your console.
And after that previously how 1234 volumes
and out of which one is in use and one is having tag.
So remaining two are not having tags on therein.
Available state means unused,
so those two has to delete.
See there has been deleted.
So these are simple way to delete your unused untagged volumes.
And we implemented this using resource.
You can also implement this by using the word client object as well.
Now let me create your client object.
So now I created analyst management console.
Now I'm creating client object.
Then.
First of all, let me try to display all you are volumes which are there in your console.
I mean, anywhere.
So before that, let me create two volumes.
And volumes are there available?
Unused volumes.
Fine.
Now I want to implement same logic using client object.
Now how we can display all 0s were available volumes using client first.
Let me open your documentation.
See everything is there in the document.
The only thing you had to such it open inclined plane to documentation.
Now, if you go with these all options somewhere,
you will you are volumes.
So describe volumes, is there somewhere?
Let me find it.
Describe volumes.
See that?
Described volumes.
So first let me take only describe volumes.
Then after that we will apply our feta.
So simply print your EC2 Console client object dot or describe volumes.
And for this, you're also having your response.
What is the output you are going to get?
Go down and see that.
So under volumes, so I'm going to take that key.
Now let me try to print the result as of now.
Yes, you are getting your volumes and that is a list C that there is a list.
Now, I will take for loop on this.
For each item in.
Now let me print each item and see the output first.
So this is each item.
So in this each eye down,
very easy word ID.
Where is your volume ID?
So this is the volume ID.
That means if we take a key called volume ID, you're going to get.
So along with that, suppose I need bags also.
Now see that tags,
there is a tags option here for this instance.
Now here there is no tag for this tags are there you are getting tax option.
Now here, there is no tags.
Then how you can identify,
see that let me take these tags here.
So each item,
let me run a consider output key error,
bags key's not there in that.
Then I'm doing one thing. See there.
If not bags, you are each item,
then I want to print them.
Then what is the meaning for that you're trying to print?
So there isn't.
For three volumes, you are not having tags.
Right now.
See 12343 volumes.
You are not having tags.
See that?
This one, and this one,
you don't have tags.
And this one you don't have tags.
But for last one your tags,
but we need to delete only unused,
But this isn't news right?
Then how you can identify this?
Let me print simply,
you are each item once again.
And let me break it just I want to see for first.
And in this, if you have just some weight state is there, then what is the state?
If steady available, then I want to delete that.
That's why IF NOT bags in E tie down from your each item.
If state is equals to. Let me copy.
If steadies equals two available.
Then remove this.
Now see the output what you are going to get.
123. So this is having tags, right?
B7. What is the ID for this?
Why we are getting for this B7.
Let me print it once again.
Sorry, I have taken spelling mistake TAG. Yes.
It's my back.
Now let me remove this.
Now see that you are getting only two volumes,
E to L and B to see that be tune no tags and it isn't available.
E2e, no tags and it is available.
Now we need to delete these two.
Now in our hand we how your volume IDs,
but how we can delete it using client object.
Just go to your client page and see somebody how delete volumes.
Just to go through all options,
one so that you will get it you are required options somewhere.
Delete volume. So here we can delete one-by-one volume,
volume mighty how to provide.
So client.read, delete volume,
then volume ID equals to your volume ID.
So after getting your volume,
so I'm printing, deleting.
That's it. Oh, let me delete it.
Simply easy to console client object dot delete your volume.
Then what is the volume ID?
So from this you are getting your volume writing.
That's it.
Now after completion of this,
you can print deleted,
all unused and an volumes that say,
no, let me save it and run it over the output.
So deleting, deleting these two,
go to here and then refresh it.
Now, see that two volumes has been deleted.
So as there is a simple way to implement your Python Bhutto transcripts using
a resource as well as client to delete your unused untagged volumes. Okay. Thank you.