Friends here we are implementing simple Python, Bhutto,
three squared, four EC2 instance Discord is great.
I mean, after running or Python bottled three scraped,
I want to get a CSV file which consists of your EC2 instances information.
Let me open my pre-defined template format for my inventory script.
C that suppose after running Python script,
it has to fill this data.
So I need to get some serial number.
How many instances you are having.
Then Instance ID, instance type.
What is our teacher for that? What is the lunchtime?
I mean, when it was launched,
then what is a private API for that?
Likewise, you can take any number of parameters.
Just for example, I have taken few of them.
Now, I want to implement this Python Buddha.
The risk of using resource,
you just try with the client.
Now.
So let me take my steps.
So already how some steps here?
So I want to implement a discovery script.
I mean Finally I want,
I want to export my data into csv file.
That's why I'm putting CSV.
Now from your resource object,
you know how to display your all instances.
See for each instance in your EC2 Console resource object dot instances, not all.
Then simply printing over each first appear at the output.
See that I have this many number of instances.
Let me open my, yeah, one more thing.
I will take some county here.
So after displaying just I want to increase my count. Now, draw the output.
So suppose six instances are there,
but some of them already, already terminated instances.
Let me show you that only two instance are up and running.
Fine.
Now, our requirement is we need to
get some information of each and every instance like this.
Now, if you observe each and everything is one instance object.
Now if you open your official documentation, let me open that.
Go to your particular service,
ec2 service and the selective work.
Yeah. Ec2 service.
See after displaying your each, every,
each and every instance from
this collection of all instances you are getting some object.
This is like one instance object.
Now, on your instance of that,
what are the available operations?
You can see with the help of D-I-R of each operation.
Or else, if you observe here,
there is a instance operation.
This is nothing but your instance object.
Now on this object you have this many number of operations.
You can go here and you can search your required operation on each and every instance.
Now as off, now whatever I want,
I already have a output for that.
So let me take this Nazi,
nor let me save it and run it and observe the output.
Forget some of the incentives or I mean,
10 million instances gone.
Yeah, now we have one time metered instances until running instances, but no problem.
Now for tabulated in Kansas,
you don't have any IP, that's why you're getting None.
See that instance object then
your ID type architecture when it was a launch and what is the IBM does.
Likewise, you can take any number of parameters
which you need for your distorted purpose.
Now I want to export this data into csv file then.
So let me show you.
I want to create this inventory with this name.
Then. I want to create a CSE writer object.
Whether it'll, I'm giving steps.
These are from your Python, basic Python scripting.
Now I need, these are the parameters in my CSV file.
Now I want to export the data into csv.
Then finally I need to close my opened object.
That's now let me save it and run it.
Now let me go to my location where I see that this is the inventory info.
Let me open it and see the output.
So automatically you created CSV file report,
which consists of your required parameters,
not only CSV file, you can create XL seats if you have some XLR DSL,
WT modules on your host,
I mean with your Python.
So as often I don't have them because they are not the default models, right?
So I used simply CSV module,
but it is a better way to use CSV module to create your report.
So you just try with client absurd to get all these informations.
So suppose if I want to get volume ID,
let you open your documentation.
For instance. You don't have any option to get volume ID.
That's why he just go with the client.
Object to get your volume mighty.
See, my requirement is here I need to add one more parameter.
Suppose volume ID I need what is the volume attach you for this.
But as of now using resource object,
you are not able to get the volume IID from these options.
There is no option to get volume IT from your resource instance object.
That's why he just tried to walk with client.
Not sweet inclined you how Definitely you allow each and every option.
That's okay.
Thank you.