Friends here we're implementing simple Python Bluetooth rescale to list all snapshots.
C, you can get your snapshot from your AWS account under your ec2 service,
just to open your ec2 service.
And there, if you go with Elastic Block Store,
there is an option called snapshots.
And he had a house to two snapshots under my US West One.
Now let me try to get this information using Python Bhutto three skip.
So let me open my editor.
So simply import your boater three.
So I have already taken script name as least all snapshot PY there.
Let me create AWS management console.
I'm creating custom fission, simply Bhutto 3.Now,
Session.get session than just providing your profile name,
whatever the profiles you configured on your host, just take them.
So now let me create my EC2 Console either by using the source or climb through.
So here I'm implementing with the help of resource you just try with client.
I will show you the steps we just try with that. So resource.
Then what is the service name if you too,
because snapshots are available under EC2 Console,
then what is the region name?
So I don't want to go with the default region because now my region is US West One.
So let me take it. Now you how your EC2 Console in your hand.
The next step is you need to implement the logic to list all your snapshots.
What do your documentation.
But agreed documentation, select your service.
So under available services,
go and set up your EC2.
Then we are implementing as of now using resource object,
opening your resource object.
You know, under resource object you have three set of operations.
And in the last operation you hope collections.
So I need to collect all my snapshots.
So there is option called snapshots. Click on that.
And there is option called all.
By using that you can get your all snapshots.
See that EC2 dot snapshots dot all.
So here you see two is nothing but our object EC2 Console upset.
So simply paste it and modify that EC2 instead of EC2,
we have taken EC2 Console resource.
But these are the collection of snapshots.
So just take one by one out from the iterator using for loop.
So for each snap in this,
let me bring to your snap up the output.
It will take some time because it is going to get lots of snapshots,
even though if you have only two snaps in your account.
So first let me show you the output of that.
We'll discuss why we are getting a lot of snapshots from this script.
So you have to wait for at least 30 seconds.
Just wait and see.
It is going to display not off snap shots.
That's why he's taking some time.
See that?
How many snapshots you are getting.
Right?
Now you're getting that many number of snapshots.
Because if you observe on your console there is
a filter option here won't buy me or public slab federal private snapshots.
So what are the snapshots you need owned by you or someone else?
Private or public.
Right? So now, instead of using all method on your collections,
go with a filter so that he can figure your required a snapshot.
Suppose if I want to filter based on size, based on availability,
Joan, based on availability,
based on status, then you have to sell it to these filters argument.
But as of now, I need based on a cone,
I need my worn snapshots.
Then there is a one more argument called Warner IDs.
So here, this one or ideas,
he's a list of a list.
That means you can provide here.
You are required.
Aws account ID is so that it is going to
fetch you a snapshot from that particular accounts.
Now, in case if you want to provide only your AWS account ID directly can poverty.
But we're also, we also
implemented a script to get your head unless account ID, let me get that.
C.
Simply, we are creating STS.
From STS, we are getting our AWS account ID.
So these are the steps, right?
So previously we implemented this.
Just from that I am taking let me modify it.
So whether you're reasoning is used to
one or two or three or account radius, same, right?
So now simply, this is the word,
this is Herodotus account ID.
Now just I'm providing that are let me take this India variable.
My wound ID equals two.
So you can probably hear a number of fewer AWS account IDs.
That's, you know, let me save it and run it and see the output.
What happened in values syntax.
Oh, snapshots, dot filter instead of that filter and how to apply this.
Now, see the output.
What you are going to get. You're going to get only you are two snapshots.
Right?
So that is the concept here to list your all snapshots which are
available in your particular region using your Python script.
And here we implemented this script using resource concept.
You can also implement using client object.
Let me show you the steps so that they can implement by your own.
Just go to your documentation.
Just open client object.
Under inclined you how Anyway,
underlined you how all options are?
I mean, all operations as a one side.
Just to go from top-down somebody how describes snapshots here?
Describe snapshots.
Just click on that that syntax.
You are client object, whatever you created
your EC2 Console using client object dot describe snapshots.
Then here, just apply inward owner ID.
That's it, so that you will get the output incomes of victory.
You just manipulate the output from that.
Let's say.
Okay, thank you for watching this video.