Friends here we are implementing python both risks to list only snapshots based on size.
Now let me open my AWS snapshots,
which are under US, West One.
So here I have three snapshots if you observe foster two or in LGB,
and last one is ten GBs snapshot.
Now my requirement is I want to implement Python Bluetooth or escape to
list AGB snapshots or to get ten GB snapshots are 30 GB snapshots.
First of all, from our previous video, I'm copying the slip.
So the purpose of that script,
just to list all your snapshots under your Butler region.
So USUS to one.
Yes, we are getting three snapshots,
but now I need to filter.
I wanted to get only ten GB snapshots.
I wanted to get only AGB snapshots.
Then how we can do it?
C, Let me open official documentation.
As of now, we are taken core from resource object.
So under-resource, if you go down here somewhere, he how snapshots.
So under snapshots you how submitters,
calls all and filter in feeder already we used wound ID arguments.
Now if you observe there is one more argument called filters.
Now let me take this concept.
Let me add it.
Comma arguments equals two.
So here I need to apply a filter based on size.
Now let me create that feeder value first.
So filter size.
So you know, the standard filter is a dictionary which consists of name,
key, and then values t.
Now here, what is the name you can take?
C just to go here in official documentation itself.
If you observe there is volume size.
Now, let me copy this, just apply here.
So based on, suppose I wanted to get based on AGB.
So you had to write eight that has a string by default that is a GB.
Now let me save it.
And let me run it and see the output.
You are getting two snapshots AT 484.
If you observe here.
Let me expand it.
844 or an eight GB.
Now I want to get ten GB snapshots.
That's it.
So only one snapshot.
How with the ten GB that snapshot I am fetching using our Python Bordeaux three, skip.
That's it.
Okay, thank you.