Friends here our concept is executing Python Botox escapes using IAM roles.
See till this moment,
we use programmatic access keys to
execute your Python Bluetooth is keeps on your AWS account.
Now.
You can also exclude or Python Bhutto that escapes using IAM roles.
And why using IAM roles,
just use default session.
That's it.
Now let me open my EC2 instance.
So here already I have a simple script just to list your EC2 instances and its state.
Now let me run this first.
And here we are working with programmatic access keys.
So I already configured programmatic access keys fall profile called root.
And I used that programmatic access keys to create
your enemies management console or session object.
And from that we created EC2 Console using resource object.
Then I'm printing the instance ID and it's the state.
Now what I will do is I am removing dot AWS directory.
That means I am removing configure credentials or profiles from my host.
Now.
Now let me run your script once again.
Now see the output profile not form.
Whatever the profile we use in our Python Buddha three scape profile is
not configured on our host because we entirely removed our edX dot AWS directory.
There are no preference on our host now.
Now, my requirement is I don't want to exclude with programmatic access keys.
That's why I removed or database directory.
Now I want to execute this script using rolls.
That means I have to assign one IAM role for my EC2 instance.
So that from the EC2 instance I can run my Python Bhutto three escaped on.
I can get the result.
Now first let me open my AWS management console.
And here just let me go to IAM and create one IAM rule first.
Now, simply go to IAM,
then click on roles and create role.
So AWS service role I am creating.
And that to whatever the role I am going to create that I want to assign to
my EC2 instance because I want to run
my Python Bluetooth risk of SMI EC2 instance or from my localhost.
That's why I just select easy to then next permissions.
So what are the axis you want to provide for your IAM rule?
We want to provide entire administration access.
Or you want to work with only EC2 instances using this I am rule,
or you want to work with only S3 service using this I am rule.
Now as of now I want to work with only EC2 instances using these IAM role.
Then select your existing rule.
Or you can also create a new policy and you can attach that to your IAM rule.
Now, EC2, full access,
I want to do this IAM rule.
That means whatever service you attached with this role from that service,
you can work with your EC2 instances.
No, I'm not providing any tags if you want,
you can provide then simply provide a role_name.
Both O3 execution for EC2 services.
You can take any rule.
Now let me create a hole.
Role has been created.
So your roll is let
me such 123123 execution for EC2 services.
Now go, do You are easy to console and select any one of you or
EC2 instance from where you want to run you and Python Bhutto that escapes.
Now as of now I have only one instance in this region.
Let me select this instance and go to actions,
and go to instance Settings and go to attach and replace,
attach or replace IAM role.
And here I am.
Bowl is therefore that.
Just click on that and such for your role, whatever you created.
That's it.
Now applied close.
Now, you attach an IAM role to your EC2 instance.
By using that IAM role,
you can able to work with your EC2 instances with
full privileges only for your EC2 instances.
Now go to your EC2 instance.
So where we have our Python Bhutto that escapes.
And for this instance we attach IAM role.
Now, you don't need any profile name here.
See whenever if you're working with IAM roles directly use default session means.
Now let me open our script and modify it.
Comment these two lines.
So whenever if you are using profiles,
then we are creating AWS management console session object.
From that we are creating our required service console.
But whenever if you attach IAM rule to your EC2 instance,
directly create your EC2 Console,
maybe client or resource just by using default session,
that is nothing but what a_3 dot either resource or claimed.
Not say, oh, let me save it and run it.
Now you are going to get to your reserve.
Now your Python boat with recipes executing.
So this is a simple way to execute our Python Bottura escapes using IAM roles.
So while going forward,
we'll also execute our Python,
both racecars from lambda with the help of IBM bolts.
So that is the general practice in your realtime.
So whenever if you're executing your Python boaters risks from lambda through lambda,
then we are using maximum cases we are using I am holds only.
Okay, thank you for watching this video.