Friends here our concept is simple Bhutto, three exception handling.
So you basically have two types of errors in your Python scripting.
The first one is syntax errors,
and the second one is runtime errors.
First, let me go with syntax errors.
Suppose I am trying to import a module called says No,
let me save it and run it and observe the output.
You are getting a syntax error.
So why you are getting the syntax error?
Because you are not following the exact syntax to import your module called sys import.
So here instead of P, I have taken x.
Now let me take it as a t.
And one more thing. Whenever if you get any syntax error,
then there is no any special mechanism to handle it.
How to rectify it manually.
We are rectified that. Now let me save it and done it.
Now it's fine.
Now let me try to take one more example.
Suppose I am trying to print a string called Hello
using printf function and let me run it and observe the output.
Again, you're getting syntax error.
So why you are getting this syntax error?
Print, if you want to print any string using printf function,
you have to write your string inside of quotations.
But I have taken only starting quotation.
I forgot to close into quotations,
then rectify it manually.
Run it. Now it's fine.
So this is about the worst syntax errors.
Now let me go with the word runtime errors.
Suppose I am trying to import module called B23.
See that syntax where it is perfect.
No, I'm running C, the output.
You are getting an error called module Not Found error.
It is not a syntax error.
It is a runtime error.
While running, your Python interpreter
identified that voter three is not installed on your python.
That's why it is showing that no module named Bhutto three.
Actually I uninstalled Bhutto three.
That's why you are unable to,
your python is unable to find that module.
You are getting an exception while running.
You're getting another while running.
Now, whenever if you get any errors,
exceptions while running, you can handle them with the help of a block called Pi.
And except now let me take it C, not only here,
whenever if you are trying to import any module which is not a default model,
then try to use you what pi index_set to block.
So I'm using try.
I'm trying to input o to three.
And here I am writing except exception as E. Then let me print your E.
What is the error you are going to get c That no module named Bhutto three.
So it is very simple way just to handle lever exceptions.
See, while implementing your Python scripts or Python Bhutto transcripts.
If there is any possibility to get
any exception there he just tried to use try and except block.
That's it.
Now, while going forward,
always tried to use try and except the blog while
importing your boater three or any third party modules.
Now let me install first your Bhutto three.
It has been installed.
Now let me enter into your Python terminal.
I'm inputting Bhutto three here.
And let me show you the list of available operations are classes on your Buddha three,
same thing you can get from your official documentation as well.
And in this, if you observe somebody how exceptions Class C,
that there is some exceptions.
Now, let me show you the list of available exceptions from your Bhutto three.
So these are the list of available exceptions from your Bhutto three.
Then what is the use of these exceptions?
Very simple.
In case if you are very good at your exception handling concept from your Python,
then you can go with the exception.
Otherwise use simple tie and accept to block.
See here, I'm using that.
Suppose while importing your module.
While importing a module,
let's say try import B23.
Suppose if moto three is not there,
then there is an exception name for that.
See that?
Suppose I am trying to import XYZ,
just loginData expertise like boat u3.
If that boat u3 modelling is not there,
you are getting an exception called module not found an exception.
That exception directly can paste here,
except in case if you get any exception called modal naught phone directly,
you can display your one description.
See that voter three is not installed.
So please install B23 and try again.
So other than these exceptions in case if you get any exceptions,
then in that case,
that exception falls under this line, under this block.
That's it. So if you're getting confusion with this line, just forget about this.
Just use simple accession block called tri-accept.
Fine.
And one more thing. Suppose if you are using Botox remodeling
your entire Python script and you are not having utopian your host,
then, then there is no use to use Bhutto three newer code.
That's why I want to stop my Python script.
Then whenever, if you get any exceptions there,
just write sys dot exit, stop us.
I don't want to execute the next lines.
So that is a best practice.
That's it. So same way you how
these many number of exceptions in your boat of the suppose
if you are not able to find your exception in this list,
you can also enter into Bordeaux core because both 2-3 is built on
the top of Bordeaux core.
That's why here you have Bordeaux core exceptions.
Also. See that these are the exceptions from your Bhutto core.
Now, instead of using moto three exceptions,
you can also use Bhutto core extractions directly.
See whenever Bordeaux trees installed by default,
Bhutto core module is available with your host.
Now, let me show you one more example.
Suppose I am creating my AWS management console using, let's say.
Aws management console are session object, that is your wish.
Moto three dot, dot Shen.
Then I'm taking Profile Name as let say some dope profile.
Let me save it and done it and observe the output.
These not error because syntax right is perfect.
But if you observe portico dot exceptions,
profile not phone, DO profile actually I don't how dope profile on my configured list.
That's why you are getting this exception.
Then if you are able to predict sees generally we
can assume that if del profile is not formed,
then are the time definitely Bhutto coordinate expressions on
profile NOT_FOUND exception will occur.
That's why what I'm doing is try.
Just try with this line and then just I am writing one exception.
In case if this exception occurred,
then I can say that pre DO profile is not configured on your work,
not AWS credentials file.
So use other profile or please configure DO profile, that's it.
So this is the advantage with exceptions.
If you are able to predict your exception then by using this except your exception,
you can write your wound message.
You are wound description, you can print that.
Say, now after that,
I don't want to exclude HIV profile is not there.
How can I get access with my AWS or cone?
That's why I'm stopping my Python script.
So instead of taking exit one,
let me take here exit three, different than our exit.
That's it. You can take any error code that is your mission.
So other than this, suppose Bordeaux.co.uk self-funded profile not phone up than this.
If you get an exception, then that exception,
I want to fall in this block,
then just write that's now save it underneath.
What happened.
Yeah, Bordeaux core is not defined,
so we need to import that Bhutto core.
So once voter three is there,
by default, protocol is also that.
See that DO profile is not configured on
your database credentials file use other profile or please configure DO profile.
Now let me take S3 dollar per.
So just replace wherever there is there that S3 profile in terms
of replacing this Just to take in terms of variables so that it is very easy.
Automatically you can change your profile names.
That's fine.
Now let me save it and now it's perfectly fine if you get any exception,
that related block will execute and it will stop.
So as of now everything is fine because as they fall upon prophase,
they're now using this AWS management console session,
which is created by a $3 per, i want to work with.
I am actually S3 dollar per profile is from S3 dollar per IAM user.
And that I am user is having a policy and that policy will allow to work with S3 buckets.
But I'm trying to work with IAM.
Let me see what will happen.
So i am console using resource object.
Then from your console,
edit list management consultation object.
Then just use a resource.
Then provide your service name.
I want to work with IAM.
Then for each user in I am console dot uses not all,
just I want to display all users.
See the output. What it is giving.
Again, it is giving an exception.
If you observe simply these access denied.
And if you observe this is Bhutto code erotics,
sexual dot client run.
So simply you are getting access denied because the IAM profile,
which is having a policy to access S3 buckets,
but we are trying to work with IAM.
So that's why you can also create tri-accept
block while creating your required service console are well,
getting your required information.
See that what I'm doing is trying to do creative work.
Required a service object,
then pi to work on that in case if you get any exception,
except exception as just I am trying to print that E.
This is the simple way just to handle you are exceptions.
So let me take here some exception as fine and observe the output.
Now, simply are giving this information instead of dark.
See that what I'm doing is x in case if you no exception, right?
So from Bordeaux core dot exceptions,
dot client Iran, then you are,
you can simply in print in this way.
So this is a client error exception up the output.
If you get anything other than client error,
then it will exclude this exception blog.
And one more thing, whatever the error you are getting here,
exception you are getting that also you can store
in a variable and you can print it that variable on.
So now let me try to print that.
And what about the area you are getting here under the house on list of operations here.
See that? So it is,
it will be very helpful after that.
So there is a response on that note.
Let me try to print it on response
for what our the error you captured under there is a option called response.
That is a dictionary.
And in this dictionary there is a heirarchy.
In that era, there is a court that is access denied.
So that's why what I am doing is from this response I'm taking,
which is very useful for your real time error.
In that error, I have a key called code.
Let me save it and run it and observe the output access denied.
So now what I can do is I can take one if condition here.
If you are exceptions, dot response.data dot.
I mean, in terms of fatigue et al and code,
if it is equals to access denied.
So you may get a different error here,
error code, if it is access denied than I can say print,
your profile is not authorized to use,
is not having access to
walk with IAM user.
Let's say l.
L simply I'm printing that entire code,
whatever the code you are going to get,
you make it to some different code asthma.
So simply I'm printing back.
Then I'm stopping simply sys dot exit some error code.
Let's say here phi and here let say six. Save it and run it.
That's your profile is not having access to work with our users.
Now let me take it off S3 dollar per I'm taking
suppose route and replace wherever I say developer is there.
And Annette and observe the output.
Now it's working perfectly.
So in this way you can handle your exceptions for your boat to three.
So just simply using with the try and except to block.
So while implementing different types of skips,
you'll get different types of exceptions.
Based on that, you can add that exceptions to
your code so that you will make perfect code.
That's okay.
Thank you.