Friends here we're implementing simple Python B23 escapes to get
IAM user details and to get all I am users details.
Let me open my editor.
So simply I'm importing Bhutto three here.
Then let me create my AWS management console session.
So instead of taking AWS management console from here onwards,
I am taking simply that has a session.
So session equals two motor 3.What
Session.get session and just provide your profile name.
So our profile name I am taking as a rude because
root profile is having access to work with IAM users in my case.
So in case if you have any other profile which is having access to work with IM uses,
just take that profile name.
So now let me create IAM console using resource object.
So you can also go with client object.
I'm going with the resource.
So simply session dot resource,
just providing a service name.
So I want to work with IAM, that's it.
So anyway, I want to work with the default region.
Anyway, region is not concern for your IAM.
Now.
So we have I am console resource object.
Then what is your next step?
So first thing, just I want to get details off one,
any, any, any IAM user.
So that is your wish.
If you want to read your IAM user,
you can read it by using your input command and the input syntax.
Let me open my documentation.
So I'm opening IBM,
so as of now I'm working with the resource object.
That's why I'm opening resource object.
In resource object we know we have three set of operations.
So first set, second,
certain thoughts or if you have done in third steady how user just open that.
So user, you can create any IAM user object if you know your username.
Now let me open and create particular IAM user object equals two,
that it Lake and create my user object.
So simply from your IAM user,
IAM console resource observed dot simply how to use user,
then provide your username.
Suppose I how S3 dollar per IAM user.
That's it. Then on this object,
what are the available operations?
C, return type I am user.
Click on that and see that.
So anywhere I am user,
these all are available operations.
Suppose as of now I want to see what is the username anyway,
that, that's what we are giving already.
Then I want to see, suppose if there are any tags are what is the user ID,
what is the year and when it was created?
Or simply, you can simply print a DAR IAM user object so that it will list
all your available operations on you were created
IAM user object so that you can see your access key wherever it is,
having login profile or not, right?
So let me give at least some of the details so
that you can work with the remaining operations.
So simply I'm printing IAM user object dot.
I'm taking simply.
User name, then IAM, user object dot.
So I want to see what is the user ID then I am user dot.
What is the EIA or an IAM user object dot.
Then I want to see suppose when it was created.
So created date.
Let me save it and run it and observe the output.
C, S3 dollar per.
This is the ID for that my I am user, ER,
and it was created and so,
and so date, so I want to format that date then import datetime module.
So it is already datetime module.
Then I'm in datetime object,
just use dot string format time than simply use,
I mean, year, month and day,
save it and done it.
Let's say it was created on this date.
That's it.
So here we worked with 11 IAM user.
My incase, if you want to work with multiple I am users,
I mean, on All I am users,
then you have to take your for loop then for each user.
Because before that, let me show you what do your documentation.
Here you how user,
if you observe here your users.
Users.
Now, simply whatever the console I am
console resource we have on that you can perform dot users.
Then after that you how not all collections meters or their right for
each user in simply printing for each user and observe the output.
This each user is an object.
That object is exactly equals to one IAM user
object c that if you observe giving list off am users,
each IAM user 0s one user object.
We already worked with one IAM user.
So if I take this,
so instead of h, I'm paying simply here because I
don't want to modify that variable name in each and every place.
Simply I am taking here IAM user.
Then. So here also I am taking that as I am user,
save it and run it and observe the output.
Okay, I am user object.
We are taken there after the output.
First I am user object.
For that, from that object, required information.
Second IAM user object from that required information.
So in this way you can get your user's information.
One user if you want to work with one IAM user, just to go here.
If you want to work with all am users go with here.
And here we can also apply limit or filters.
See that filters are there.
So you can also apply your filters based on your requirement that say, Okay, thank you.