Hyphens.
In this video, we're going to implement
one simple Python script and which is used to generate random password.
So simply random password generator using Python.
So there's this script while going forward will use while creating IAM users.
Okay, now let me open my editor.
Let me create one Python file.
So I want to create a python file, random password generator.
That's it.
Okay.
See here, I need a module called random.
So from this I am going to import all,
but actually I need only choice.
So what is the choice you will see in this video?
That's fine. Now guys here,
first you have to decide.
Suppose you are going to implement one skip
through which you are going to generate a password,
then what is the length of your password, right?
So I need the password length, light.
Suppose let say eight characters I need.
Then what are the valid characters you need in your password?
So let, let's say valid characters.
Simply cause for password,
no need to take this lengthy variable names.
Just I am giving for your clarity.
Right?
And just assume that these are my characters which I want to take in my password, right?
So for that, what I am doing is I'm going to take first sum valid characters,
which I how to include in my password.
That's fine.
Now before going to implement your actual script, just assume that.
So observe that I am going to print choice of u are valid characters for password.
So guys, if I run this script very first-time C, what is the output?
You are going to get? C, some parentheses right?
Now I am going to read them this.
Now see the output. Yeah, it's there right in India.
C, C output or the output I am going to read on.
Each time you are going to get some different characters
in output side means tries is simply
a method from your random module which will
select from your string randomly anyone of the character.
Right? Now based on this concept,
first of all, I need eight characters in my password, right?
Though that's why first-time taking password equals to sum a list.
So guys, you can implement this in different ways.
I'm going bit first, very simple one.
For each car, right?
I mean password character in range of So this many times I want to repeat it right?
So simply first-time printing, print,
choice of your valid characters for password.
First observe the output.
See you are getting this.
Let us write. Now I am going to read on this. Now you are getting some different.
Let us, once again, I am re-running.
You're going to get some different letters.
That means randomly you are generating some eight letters,
but password means it has to there in one single string, right?
That's why what I am doing is,
instead of printing my password,
I'm going to append these letters for our a list
called password. That's it.
Right?
Now first let me print directly what is your password now,
in your hand, software running your for loop eight times.
I mean, often repeating your for loop with
eight iterative iterations you are having now in
your password list eight characters. Now see the output.
Now I'm going to read on this and you'll get definitely different password,
random you are going to select, right?
But password means, again,
it should be one single string,
not a list of values.
You know, in your list you have a method operation called join.
So using join method,
see there getting us a one string now,
and this is your password.
If I rerun this similar,
definitely some different password, yes.
Okay. So guys, now this is the simple way to generate your password.
So final password is nothing but or simply let me take random password.
You can take any variable I'm taking simply in this way.
Now you can print that.
So random passes is our variable guys,
user-defined variable.
That's a radon.
Radon. That's it.
Ok. Now,
observe here, instead of this lengthy aligns,
you can also use some shortcut.
Just let me comment first of this code.
For a for loop, you have a shortcut based on that c. Let me write
a random password equals to simply join us if you are able to understand this,
you just to follow this otherwise previous score,
the score is also valid one.
Now I'm going to denote the single line dies off your valid characters, right?
For each cat in a range of you are length of password.
That's a offer that just stride forward,
print your password so that he can see random password.
Let me open your output.
Clearly, you see that.
So now I'm generating your password here,
any one single line with single line, right?
So actually you are going to get list of values one by one from your for loop,
but I'm adding them as one single string.
So antilog asic, I mean this for loop and joined a logic,
I heard another single line.
If you are able to understand this line, just follow this.
Otherwise you can also follow this one.
Both will do the same result.
The only thing is here you are reducing your number of lines.
Okay? So this is the simple way to generate your random password.
And guys, we will use this concept while creating IAM users in your AWS.
So you, while creating your IMU lets,
you can also assign some password,
a random password or custom password.
So I want to assign random password for each different IAM user.
So at the time I will use this logic.
Okay?
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.