Hi friends. Here we are going to create an IAM user
with console login access with moto three of your python, right?
Simply you're creating one IAM user with console login access, right?
You know, you can provide to is access for your IAM user, right?
One is using programmatic access and one mode is using console access, right?
Okay, case C, before going to create an IAM user,
you should have some idea, right?
So that is like first thing,
whatever the IAM user name you want to create,
that user name you should have in your hand.
Then second, they want to provide programmatic access or console access or both.
So based on that, you have to create your IAM user with moto three.
Then finally, what is the policy you want to attach with your IAM user?
All these things you should have in your hand before go into create your IAM user, right?
C, Let me go ahead and write our Python B23 script.
But before going to write each Tao some clarity, I will explain that.
So create an IAM user with
console login access dot pi.
Let me write it up in Python.
Then let me import Bordeaux three.
Then first, I am going to create a session.
You know that how to create a session, right?
Simply your boater 3.Now Session.get expression profile underscore name.
Using this profile, I wanted to create a new user.
That's fine. Then create IAM object that you can create using resource or client.
But what is the object you can choose to achieve your required task?
Our task is created an IAM user with
console Eigen axis just to go to your official documentation first.
Right, that is moto three documentation. Gaze here.
Just observe your required operations are there with your resource or not,
or you are a square operations are there with your client or not?
Right.
Let me go with first I am I am right where it is.
Yeah. First I'm going to open
resource because always first I will prefer resource if incase,
if any option is not available in resource for your required operation,
then I will go with client.
And now if you observe here,
you are having create user base.
Before going into that,
let me go with your manual steps.
If you want to add a user, IAM user,
how you can do it, add user, right?
You're providing some name.
Let me take some x, y, z.
Then here you are assigning programmatic access keys or
AWS management console access. Right?
So if you want to both the heart to enable both, right?
Or if you want to only console axis,
you are to enable this and that to here.
Auto-generated password or custom password, that password.
And after that user must create
a new password on next assignment that is reset yes or no,
right, likewise, so that means offer giving your name.
You should able to create access keys or you should able to provide login access, right?
And you should able to provide password.
These all options are available with your resource or mark.
Since there is no availability with the resource,
because there is only create user,
there is no option called create access keys here.
The whole year. Create access keys, no.
Or do you have ligand profile option here? No.
Right. That's why I'm not going to select resource now because resource, you know,
in resource sometimes you may have a well a required option
or sometimes you may not have been inclined you how each and every option.
Now I am going to work with client for your IEP.
That is, first we need to create user, right?
So there is an option called CREATE_USER.
Let me open that. Create user is there.
After this, what you want,
you need to attach your policies are the unit to provide
access keys or management console like an axis, right?
So here if you observe here, create login profiling.
This is just to provide login access.
Right? Then one more thing,
attached policy, unless there is a one more option called create access keys.
But as of now you are going to create a user with comes with like an access.
We are not going to provide programmatic access keys.
That's why I don't want to create access keys.
I need to select this.
But I mean, I, I kinda option called attach policy, right?
See here, attached user policy.
Now you have three options which are available with your client. Right?
Now. Let me go and implement your Python Bordeaux that
escaped using IAM client a method, right?
So I am object I'm going to create using client
is nothing but simply you are Session.get client.
Let me write surveys underscore name equals two IAM.
And then after that, let me provide a region name has some us is
to one. That's fine.
Right?
See this, this is simply you are a session and I am Clint.
Ok.
Now, there is, I am going to write this program,
the state with the help of functions because a later
descript you can apply to create multiple IAM users.
As of now, you are going to take only one IAM user.
So I'm going to do an assignment like create multiple IAM users,
write that phi c. I'm going to create.
If underscore underscore name,
it is a better practice always to start your code.
In this way. So this is your Python basics guys.
So I am going to call main function.
Now, I'm going to create a function called main.
So under main, very first function I am going to create,
or simply I am client equals to this.
I'm going to get as a function,
get IAM client object.
Right now I am going to add these two lines under your function call.
You get IM client object,
profile underscore name equals two.
Okay?
By default, I am giving us,
if you want to work with the different profiles,
you can modify the script.
Right now I'm going to copy and paste it.
Right?
So now after this,
I need to return the object called IM.
Client. Got that.
I need, right?
Let me delete these two lines.
Fine.
Now in your hand you how IM client object.
So after that actually I need to create a IAM user.
So there's Before going to create your IAM user,
let me define some variables,
but gaze, while writing in the real-time script.
Note don't fix your variables here.
Instead of this, just create one CSV file there, just right.
Required I am username,
right? Or policy, right?
Whether you need console access our mode.
But here, as of now, for simplicity purpose,
I'm going to write IAM user name.
Let me write something called some.
Go with Python.
So if gmail.com,
So with this, I wanted to create an I am user.
Right?
So after that, let me take my I need password also.
Right off of these creation of user,
I need to set a login profile further.
I ate password, so password equals two.
You get random password.
So I want to define one more function to get my password, get random password.
So guys, we have one of the scraper to get password here.
Latter-day I'm going to copy and paste it.
Let me already we implement their gaze.
Just go through this once to get random password,
that to be the length of eight characters.
If you want to change the length of your password with any number, you can change it.
Right? So then now I am going to take it in your random password, length of password.
I'm going to fix it as eight.
If you want to change it,
you can write your logic in such a way that
Your length of password can be changed.
Right? Then after that,
what I need valid characters for my password.
I am going to directly take a characters that it lean shop that you can also use
some string module and you can create these valid characters for your password.
But for anyway, for simplicity,
but most directly I am taking this.
Then nightly I'm using random password.
Check. Now I am going to written thus that password.
So eventually this bird-like enlighten it, right?
I don't want right number of lines, then it's better.
That's it. Now you have a password in your hand.
Then what you need policy year and I mean,
if you whatever the attached whatever policy you want to attach for you or IAM user,
then what is the ER and for that,
so I am taking policy AR in equals to let me copy it from your AWS account.
So I guess you have already predefined policies.
I'm going to take that in case if you create your own policy,
you can also create in that way.
Right? I'm going to take an existing policy, Erin.
So policies, let me take full administration access policy, RN.
So you heard earlier policy OR and here let me copy that.
Otherwise, you can modify your policy around me,
create that and you can assign that to your abuser.
Now what else we need?
We how am User,
password further and policy RN.
That's fine. Now let me create an IAM user first.
Right? So I'm going to create an IAM user for that.
I'm going to define a function or monitor of that.
We have a function that if you write,
this is create user.
Right?
Now let me, let me create your user base here.
To create your user,
I am going to take that Italy B23 method,
that is create user.
And anyway already we how IN username and I am client, right?
I'm going to get it. I am going to take that one directly.
Okay, now see here,
I am client dot create user.
So guys here I'm going to take username as what is the username,
your technology, how your username here,
let me take this has my user name.
That's a simple thing I created.
Now, if I execute this script,
know because of that you will get that I am user name, right?
So after creation of your user,
what is your next step?
Actually, you need to create a login profile means you have to provide console access.
So to provide login profile already how a method,
once again, that is simply create login profile, username, password.
Right?
C, I am taking,
I am client ID dot create login profiling.
So for lying profile, what do you have to provide?
Username equals two.
So already we how your user name in this variable.
Let me copy and paste it.
Then what else you need for this method?
Password, right?
We have a random password already.
Password equals password, right?
Then after that password reset required.
So I don't want to reset it.
Let me I mean, why logging?
I don't want to reset.
I want you this possible only just I am using POP false if you make
it as a true while logging your user,
password, reset it, that's it.
So after that you have one more thing,
guys, you need to attach your policy, right?
So simply attach policy.
So username policy, Aaron, Very simple, light,
IAM, client, attached policy.
So simply how to provide username.
Ok, how did you, how username here?
Let me copy it and paste it.
Username.
Then policy here,
and I already told my policy are in,
into this policy or n. Let me write it.
That's it.
All right. So now to login, right?
To login you need you what?
Iam user name and password.
So password is there in this variable just I want to print this password.
Print IAM, user name,
whatever you created and password for that.
So they senior realtime don't display engine of that.
He just tried to store this information into some CSV
file so that you can share that with a particular IAM user.
Dot format, your IAM underscore user and a sport name,
then pos, what I have taken this variable.
So just I am printing because I need to login, right?
That's it. Ok. Fine.
Now let me save it and run it.
So if any exceptions occur,
then we'll try to handle them.
Now I'm going to run the script, just see the output,
right within this password your new IAM user has been created, right? See that?
Let me go ahead and refresh my userspace.
Yes, do with Python it up gmail.com user has been created,
right? With administration axis.
Right. Now, let me log in into
direct. Verify it, right.
So what is the password we have assigned for that? Oh, sorry.
Light
management console.
Everything is finite. Okay.
Okay.
I am username.
So already we have our AM username.
Then what is the password?
Yes, already we have that signing.
Right? Nuts. It are able to
login id how full administration access you can do whatever you want, right?
Let me go here.
Otherwise, I will go with the services, IAM,
whatever the action you want to do now you can do
because you are given administration access.
Let's say guys, right?
You're able to login now with the Euro created profile.
Now if I rerun this program just after the what is happening,
entity already exists, means already same.
I am usury existing.
That's why you are unable to create our entity.
Right now. How you can handle this? Nothing is that.
See. Now before going to create your IAM,
my axis, I am user.
Just try with, try and accept and handle with an error. Try.
Fce, excerpt,
exception as e.
Right? Nowadays, you know,
already we have seen while getting user details,
we handle this exception handling in a simple way in this, using this right.
That is, if E dot or response of error,
then code equals two.
So whatever you are getting now,
now we're getting right.
Like already, you are entities existing, right?
So that is entity already exists.
So if it is already exists,
then I don't want to run this.
Then simply print already
IAM user width is exist.
So that is, whereas I am user, I am username.
Then after that, I went to simply exit from the script.
So sys dot exit.
Suppose I am giving this, right.
Else. Suppose if we get any unknown error,
just tried to rectify that.
So based on that errors,
you can handle any number of errors.
So as of now, suppose this is my error.
I'm going to handle these otherwise, please,
of verifying the following error and retry.
So what is the other you're going to handle it,
you are going to get into your E logic.
Then again, I want to exit because we got this error.
You are not able to create your user.
So I don't want a 100 million script.
That's it.
So let me import my sys module as well. That's it.
Now let me save this, right?
I'm going to run your user, see what is happening.
That's a great IAM user.
Already a user with the do with python that humor easily exist.
That's a okay.
So there's, there's a simple way to create an IAM user with login access,
edit list management console, access.
The same way you can try if you want to create
an IAM user width programmatic access keys, right?
Or if you want to get an IAM user with
both programmatic access keys as well as console access.
Right? You can do that.
In next video, we will see how to create an IAM user with programmatic access keys.
And after that, we will see how to create an IAM user.
Both the axis, I mean programmatic access as well as your console axis.
Okay?
Okay. Yes. Thank you for watching this video.