We are going to discuss about your AWS lambda or lambda function.
Anyway, that is simply introduction to your AWS Lambda.
Okay, let me start that.
So AWS Lambda or AWS Lambda function.
So guys from official documentation,
the meaningful or edit this lambda is this one.
So as I've no, I don't want to go with that.
If you want, you can go through that, right?
So before coming to your database lambda,
i want to say something from my local server.
Let's say just assume that.
So this is my Windows Server.
So in case if you are using your local server has
some my ways or some Linux, whatever it may be.
So this is my Windows Server.
This is my simple, my local server.
So here I installed one of the application called PyCharm.
Just assume that this is my pie chart.
Of course, you know, what is the pie chart when she's like a one editor, right?
So to write and execute your code.
Ok.
So now just assume that you were AWS Lambda is
also one of the editor and which is used to write your code and execute your code.
And along with that,
it is having some extra features.
That's it.
Now you can simply remember a diverse lambda is nothing but it is one type of editor.
So you know, what is the use of editor?
We will write some code or some texts. What old?
Maybe you can write something through your editor and you can save your file, right?
So you can write your code and also you can execute your code through your NLS lambda.
Along with that, you are having some extra features.
So now we will see what are you an extra features right?
Now. First thing, it is simply, you know,
like an editor with some extra features.
That's it. So it's supposed it supports to run different languages like Python,
go lang, java, NodeJs, she shop something.
Right?
So now you have to understand that Ada was lambda is not only supporting for Python,
it is supporting for different languages to write and
execute through your AWS Lambda function or L of this lambda.
Right?
So C Our, let say suppose we have taken previously pi chump and
I install pi jam on my local server called the windows. The same way.
Lambda is also one of the editor, basically.
So it should run somewhere, right?
So where it is running.
So usually you're not going to install anywhere.
It is one of the service from your AWS.
So directly you are picking that and you're using that.
So somewhere it is running on one,
on top of one operating system.
That operating system is Amazon Linux.
Amazon Linux server.
So now you are not maintaining the Amazon Linux server to run
your AWS Lambda application that
phi we are calling AWS Lambda is a serverless computing platform.
Sorrow or less basically does have its needs server,
but you are not maintaining that server.
It is a serverless, that's it, right?
Anyway, you are using your AIDL is lambda two, right?
Your core and to execute your code.
And you know that now that AdaBoost lambda is running on top of Amazon Linux server.
So from that Lennox or were in case if you want to store
some temporary values or files while running your edibles lambda,
then you can directly include if path called root term inside of you or lambda function.
I mean, when writing your code,
you can store some files temporally under root term directly.
You can access that path.
You have access for that.
Okay, That's fine.
So now you have to understand that simply.
There is one Amazon server, Amazon Linux server.
It is maintained by your Amazon.
You are not maintaining this. On the top of that.
They installed one application called lambda a1 plus lambda.
Right?
Now you are using that Ada was lambda survey
simply to write your code and to execute your code.
Right?
So I told that this is like one of your editor like VA,
MR. PyCharm Sublime, right?
But along with that it is also having some extra features.
So to know that let me go with this thing and
requirements for analysts lambda function, right?
So the first thing, enemies lambda function has a few requirements.
That is, the first requirement you need to satisfy is to provide a handler.
What is this handler? In case if you no good with,
I mean, any one of the language right,
while writing your core, sometimes you'll include handless.
Now, this handler is nothing but one of the function.
While writing your inverse lambda core,
I mean the code which you are going to write inside of
your analysts lambda function, right?
These handler is the entry point for the lambda.
That means whatever the code you are going to write know innuendos lambda function,
basically AWS Lambda, start the execution from this Lambda handler function.
I will show that from where it is going to start, right?
And this AdaBoost lambda function accepts JSON formatted input.
And we do this same JSON format as output.
But of course you can also written some string typeof output.
Right? That's fine.
Then second requirement is that you
will need to specify the runtime environment for the lambda.
Nothing is that.
Suppose I want to write
some analysts automation code using Python and just write your Python code.
You don't worry about the weather,
the Python software installed or not already these that you can see
that anywhere lambda service, right?
Then third one is, the final requirement,
is a trigger. What is a trigger?
C, you are going to write some code inside of your AWS Lambda function.
And in case if you want to run it manually, yes,
you can trigger manually or you can run by as I mean, simply, you can run.
But, but things are nothing but taken.
Assume that as a trigger,
you are running your code. That's a
Right?
Or you can configure your AWS Lambda function such
that it will execute automatically when something happens.
Suppose you are going to upload some data into your S3,
some object into your S3.
So one event is occurring.
Based on that event,
you can configure your AD plus lambda functions
such that they are lambda will automatically execute,
will automatically trigger whenever something uploaded into your S3.
Right?
See guys, you have a,
suppose let me take PyCharm,
you have a pie chart editor.
So to run your code, what you are doing manually,
you are running same way.
Manually, you can trigger your code,
or you can do some settings such
that automatically your Lambda code will execute when something happens.
So you had to write that when something
happens requirement you have to write for your end of this lambda.
So while going forward,
you can see how you can trigger
your idlis lambda function automatically based on your requirement.
Right? Fine.
Now we are saying that we are going to write
some automation code in your Oedipus Lambda function.
And we are going to execute that with your end of this lambda.
That's okay.
But we know that whenever,
if we want to execute some code against your AWS or cone,
we have to provide either credentials or IAM rule.
Right?
So for your inverse lambda,
you are going to write your code.
You're going to implement your Python Bhutto three scripts, suppose.
So while implementing your Python Bhutto three script,
you have to provide your credentials for your editors lambda function.
Or you can create an IAM role
and attach that role to your edit was lambda function such that it will run your core.
Okay, so guys, now assume that I am going to write some Python script. How about 2-3?
Skip on my local server while writing our Python goto, the risk of two,
we are going to provide credentials in the form of access keys,
or we will configure access keys on local server with some logical profile names.
And we are giving that profile name while implementing our code.
We have seen this procedure till this moment.
And of course we have seen by creating one of
the IAM role and we attach it that I am bold to one of the EC2 instance.
From there, we ran our code.
We have seen this also right.
Now, the same procedure you can do from your AWS Lambda function also while running,
you are edible is Bhutto three scripts.
Right?
Suppose, let me open my AWS or cone, right?
Just to go and such here in services,
you can see under compute,
you have a lambda function.
I mean, lambdas are we just click on that.
So as of now,
I'm not sure where omega,
i don't have any lambda functions in my account.
Now just to create a function,
creating a function is nothing but you are going to
create your NLS lambda function or code.
Right? Just click on that.
So here if you select this one,
very first option, you are going to write each and every step.
You can select this, you know,
it's like already predefined formats,
quotes, or then you can edit and you can use that for your requirement.
And now also you can browse our wireless app repository.
So for time being, I am going to work with the very first option from scratch.
I want to implement my code C while writing our code even on our local server,
what we are doing, we are giving first some Python script name, right?
Let's say demo Python lambda function.
He had just assumed that you are code name is demo Python lambda function.
So you're going to write lambda in terms of Python program, right?
But you have to set up your runtime.
So see already these type of languages are already supported by
your AWS Lambda directly how to choose
your required language while implementing your core.
I'm going to implement my code in terms of Python and data in Python,
you can select any one of the wash. And here,
so I'm going to select for timing to dot seven.
Now just create a function, right?
First observed the guide will take some time to create
your function once it is done, right?
Just give me a second.
Still. It has been created.
Now observe that don't go with any options as of now.
We will go with step-by-step, just come down.
See, now this is,
there is a some editor here already.
Some initial function is there,
or handler is there, right?
So you can go, you can edit your code here.
If you observe a year handler,
lambda function dot Lambda handler.
So this Lambda handler is there somewhere here.
So whenever if you run your code in
your lambda automatically the execution starts from here.
I mean the function execution start function will start from this function.
If you observe they are giving default output or written value as in terms of JSON.
So as of now, I'm not going to use that, just delete them.
Of course I am as of now,
I don't want this JSON as well, right?
Let me write simply one Python, Bhutto,
three scraped to list out all your EC2 instances which are under one region.
So you know you need both O3,
you don't worry about your voter three already bought O3 is there with
your lambda function directly import that boat A3, right?
So guys, suppose while writing our aid of place moto three scripts on our local server,
what we are doing first,
we are creating a session, right?
Let me create that session.
Session dot, sorry, moto three dots session dot, session guys here.
You know, for while creating your customization,
you can provide your credentials
or you can also provide your profile names on your local server.
But yeah, you don't have any option to provide
your profile names instead of that directly.
How to provide your credentials?
Of course, providing credentials directly inside of your script is not a good practice.
But just for our understanding purpose,
I'm going to provide AWS access key ID equals two.
I will get it from my account.
Then AWS secret.
Access key is you have to grow it directly.
You are keys here, right?
Let me open my credentials Pysch let me click on this, my security credentials.
Just go to that and tried to collect your access keys.
Now I am going to create new access case.
Right? So this is my access key ID.
Just provide directly here and take your secret access key.
That's right.
Now, what I'm doing is I'm going to create my EC2 Console using resource method.
For your ec2.
If we want to write surveys underscore name equals two, is retune them.
Regina's coordinate.
Sega is how we are writing the code on your local server.
The semi are going to write a only thing is you
are going to start your code from dysfunction. That's a.
Then here, let me write,
giving US East One.
Of course you can also write your code and you're gonna exclude from here,
but the thing is only Lambda handler will handle the Logs.
That's why you have to write the core under your Lambda handler.
Now see, I'm trying to list out my instances from this easy to console.
Instances dot all.
Let me print each instance and its id.
Right?
Just save it. Okay, nowadays,
if you want to run this manually, right?
I mean, you can run by your cells the score.
You have to test it.
So once if you enter test,
it is asking configured testing event.
So even as of now,
just assume that it is a one JSON which is having
key-value pair representation to run your code.
N equal, which is there in your LLS lambda E,
hard to provide at least DMI went, right,
let me take some sample event. That's it.
Sorry.
I have to say too, that just come down and you
create whether there is a use or not, that's a secondary.
First of all, it's needs one event.
That's it.
So we created that. Now let me test it.
Right.
See, it is showing something called invalidate a syntax error in model lambda a function.
Let me check it. What is the syntax error?
Ok, for each instance IA,
we misread in here.
In for loop.
Now save it.
And tenth street.
Of course, you can also see your logo and a bill of this here,
I'll see here 3D saying that task time route after three seconds.
So by default, if you create any lambda function,
the execution time which is assigned for your lambda function is three seconds.
But within three seconds you are not able to execute your core.
Then you can change your time just by coming down here.
Now I am going to use suppose three minutes,
three seconds for my core.
Save it.
Right. Now, test it.
Pays. You are having a lot of options yet.
I'll go with step-by-step. Now see the output.
You are able to get your instance IDs,
but able to get your instance IDs, right?
That's fine.
Now what I'm doing is
I will as I've no don't bother a bowtie well-written. We'll see that later.
Nuts. Okay.
Now if you come down,
you're having different types of options and environment variables.
You know, on your operating system you are having some a neutron into variables.
So if you want to use your annual unmanned variables inside of
your Python moto three are simply
a Python script you're going to use waste module from there,
you're going to use res.end neuron in your Python scripts.
The same way you can provide some variables here.
Let say suppose interrupt providing my,
because see, suppose if I want to work with the access keys, my access keys,
maybe sometimes if I create new access keys they will change or that I'm,
I don't want to enter into my Python script and I don't want to change it here.
Instead of that, you can pass externally AWS access key,
that value we can provide here something, whatever the value.
Then secret access key
began provide something here.
And you can access these values using your way is.na neuron meant method.
Ok?
So for timing, I'm not going to use it well going
forward where it is required there, I will use that.
If you want to provide some tags,
you can provide tax 40.
Well, edible is lambda, right?
So if you want, write some description again, byte.
See here, use an existing role, is there,
say as of now how you're running your Python both rescued by providing
your credentials of your account, right?
So you are providing your credentials for your account.
Instead of that, you know,
we can also run our Python Bhutto that escaped using IAM roles.
So if I don't want to provide credentials,
now let me direct my credentials.
I want to run my Python boatload risk based on IAM role.
Now I am not giving any credentials here,
but I want to run my Python Bordeaux Transcript by assigning some role.
As of now, just assign some simple rule that is not having any permissions to work with.
We are edible soko demo that is you don't worry about that.
Okay. That's okay.
You can also assign you are VPC in case if you want.
Okay.
That's fine. As of now.
No, let me go with your AWS account.
Okay.
Now let me delete my recently created case c. I'm going with rules.
Let me create my role first.
So I'm going to create a role.
The purpose of my role is I want to execute code from my analyst lambda.
So I need to create a role for my AWS Lambda function.
Just simply click on Create role and select. Lambda rule.
Allows lambda functions to call NLS services on your behalf.
So if you create some roll here, right?
If you create some roll here,
and if you assign these royalty or
lambda function now you are adding plus lambda function.
We'll get the access to work with your LLS services on your behalf.
I'll just next to permissions.
So what are the access you want to provide for your NLS lambda using this role,
I want to use simply suppose only to walk with EC2 instances, right?
Ec2, full access only for EC2.
Next, tags review, right,
role_name I'm taking for
my lambda EC2 to work with the sort of just I am taking some name.
If you want to add some description,
you can ride here, create a road.
Right now your role has been created.
That is, for my lambda,
easy to just go to your Lambda function,
come down and see here you are having use an existing role and tried
to such hear role,
role. Where is our role?
Let me refresh it
and now go down.
So this is our previous score.
Okay.
So if you want, I will,
I don't want to, because you are credentials or you can take it no problem.
By delta, right? Yeah, see here,
use an existing role.
Now, click on here and select here.
So now you are always appearing.
You're just select this role and save it.
Okay, now come here in case if you are using your role,
you should not use these two lines.
Okay, directly create your EC2 Console.
So guys, we have seen in our course known here.
I mean not here.
Yeah, I am rose to executing Python Bordeaux three scripts.
So in case if you assign,
you are a IAM role for EC2 instance,
how could we have seen now,
same way if I assign my role to your EDL is lambda functions are already assigned here.
Role.
Then how can I create my UC to console directly how to create using default session.
So that session we will get the credentials using your role.
You don't bother about that.
Simply moto three dot resource.
You were EC2.
Under US East one region.
Save it.
Now I am going to run the code just up there, the output.
I am running.
C, the output execution details.
You got your instance cities.
Okay?
No, let me do one more thing.
So as of no, you're Rollies having access to work with your EC2 instances.
But my requirement is let me create.
I'm going to come into this code.
Let me comment this.
Now I'm going to create S3 console using your resource object.
That is here we how to use default is to shun,
you don't need to create a session ECOSOC border, they don't sessions something.
Whenever if you assign role for your editor is lambda function or some
S3 or some you're EC2 instance
there in case if you're writing moto three scraped directly,
you have to take a session.
Defaults Russian default section is nothing but directly creating your required console.
Creation of your session will take care about by your boater three from the rule.
Now I want to work with this three, right?
So I want to walk under this region.
Now let me do one thing.
I want to list out all my buckets which are there in your S3 under US East one.
See if you observe clearly, right.
You are Rollies having access to work with the Institute.
But now I'm creating lists out your buckets.
Now let me run this and see the output what you are having,
you are getting some exceptions.
Let me show that C.
Just go down and see the complete client error.
An error occurred while I'm calling the list bucket operation access denied because
your role is not having to access your S3 buckets.
Let me go and attach some new policy for your role.
This is the roll. This role we assigned for our intellect lambda function.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to do one more policy as of no,
your policy is Amazon EC2 full access.
Now I am going to attach one more policy for my this.
So let me take S3 policy.
I'm assigning now for my role to policies.
One is to work with EC2 and one more is to work with S3, right?
Let me open your C and C. How many policies or lead to policies, lauren?
Now, let me retest it.
See now you are able to get your buckets because we have changed the role policies.
So I attached policies.
One is to work with EC2 and one more is to work with this three.
Okay?
So guys, simply you have to remember that while going forward,
not only here, even in your real time,
you're not going to work with your credentials using, I mean,
from your kiddos lambda function always you'll
assign some role for your EDL is lambda function.
And from the role,
you're going to create your default session.
From the default session we are going to implement your Python boat O3 script.
So make sure, you know,
whenever if you're trying to write your code on your Oedipus lambda,
you How to Create directly.
You are default session.
From that you have to create your required console in this way.
Okay?
Okay guys, thank you for watching this video.