Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to see how to automate
the start and stop EC2 instances for your test.
And you don't mend on AWS using lambda function.
So there's just agenda. You're having some tests,
annual event and there suppose you are having some 30 to 40 servers.
Now your requirement is,
I'm in, on those servers,
you are using these 30 servers for suppose
some testing purpose and assume that you are not testing dream suppose, right.
And you need instances are up and running only for certain hours.
All working hours.
Just say.
So. You're working Hobbes working hours are,
suppose some morning eight AM to yearning 5pm.
So only during this time, right?
You want to you need your EC2 instances are up and running.
So out of these interval unit to stop them manually,
if you want to stop, you have to select
your test servers and then you have to start it out. You want to stop.
You can stop it manually on your UI mode.
But it is a time taking process and daily how to do this action.
But I don't want to do this the action daily.
Suppose, if I want to start,
I don't want to start daily.
I want to stop I don't want to stop dialing manually.
Then I want to automate this 30 servers instances start and stop action.
Right?
Then how you can do this?
Okay?
So I guess we're going to do
this action using automation
with the help of your Python moto three and lambda functions.
Ok, so now our assumption is every day I want to start my EC2 instances at 08:00 AM,
that to Monday to Friday only in weekdays working days,
then I want to stop EC2 instances are suppose 5pm,
again, this also Monday to Friday only.
Right? Fine.
So this is to implement this automation script through your lambda.
You have to follow some steps.
Ok, when he first step is create a rule for lambda function.
So y is in our previous video, right?
While going through introduction to your Lambda function,
we came to know that in lambda we can write both O3 in two ways.
One is using with your programmatic access keys,
and one more is using a role.
I mean, whatever the code you are having on your lambda,
if you want to run that,
you should have some access on your required services.
So for that, you can provide your programmatic access keys,
or you can also assign some role two or lambda,
such that lambda will perform the action on your required services based on your role.
Right?
So in your real time,
instead of providing programmatic access keys,
we use generally roles for
lambda function to execute your code which is there on your lambda.
Right?
So that's why a first I'm going to create it all.
So it's already if you have some role, just use it.
I mean, you need a lambda function to execute on your EC2 instances, right?
So that's why in case if you have any role which is
having a policy to work with your EC2 instances, you can use that.
Just assume that I don't have any rule.
Now let me work on my console. I'm going to
Okay, I will go with the IAM right there first, I'll create one role.
The purpose of that Rollies.
If this role is assigned to your lambda,
your lambda will get an access to work with your EC2 instances.
So in that way, how to create a maypole just to go on and go to your IAM.
Then there select roles and create a new role.
Actually how already holding on,
but I want to use new one.
So what is our intention?
We want to assign this role to you or lambda.
So just click on this allo lambda function to call AWS services on your behalf.
Look on that next to permission.
So what are the permissions you want to go for this role while working with your lambda.
So I want to give you an access to walk with only EC2 instances.
Okay? So EC2, full Amazon, EC2, full access.
Even if you want to modify that,
you can use your own policy.
I mean, with the help of policies and rhetoric on gender and we can attach that,
but I'm using existing policy.
Then.
If you want, you can take this lambda role.
Is it to full access?
That has given unroll lemma.
I am giving lambda role to
work with EC2 instances.
Not say I'm creating a role.
Now in my hand, I have a role.
Using this role, I can write some code in lambda and I can
execute that without having any credentials, programmatic access keys.
For that I have created a role, right?
Then second thing into lambda function using moto three, right?
So based before going to write you a lambda function,
actually we are going to work with
some EC2 instances which are there for the word test environment, right?
So let me go and see my EC2 Console,
which instances are running?
Just loginData Uriel demo having some 13 stanzas.
As of now I'm having only two, right?
So how can I identify which instances under
test environment and which instances under different environment.
So, you know, you have a tag concept.
Now let me create for my required instances,
tagged him as any run when t equals two.
Let's create one more tag.
So I'm taking a new dawn meant as some test, test and environmental.
Then let me create tag for second instance also.
Now these two instances are there under my test. Any RON mentor.
Ok, fine.
Now we have to write a lambda function using moto three.
Suppose to start our star Posada is first I will go and
write a script to start your EC2 instances.
Same way you can proceed with the word stop EC2 instances.
Okay, now let me open my lambda.
So before that, once again,
let me clearly take my ENV.
These two are my dad's, right.
Let me open this hazard is,
and I want to open a new console.
And I want to enter into my lambda surveys.
So here I am going to I del lambda function.
So the purpose of lambda function,
suppose we are going to start some EC2 instances which are there on a test environment.
So he's here to start,
you have the right one lambda function to stop,
you have to write one more Lambda function.
I'm going to write in that way.
Let me create a new lambda function, create function.
So I want to write the core from scratch.
Let me select this option and knew the name as autostart test.
You can give it any name, EC2 instances, the rate eight.
That's in my requirement.
Now, let's take python rationales.
You are required to Russian I'm taking two 0.7c then create a function.
So after creation of your function,
right, you have to write your code on how to execute your code.
To execute your code, you should have some privileges.
So that privileges for your lambda function you are going to get from the role.
That's why offer creation of your Lambda function.
Let me go down and see here somewhere you are having a Rules option,
execute role, use an existing role.
So just know we created some role, right?
What is that role? Lambda role to work with EC2 instances. Save it.
Okay, so if you want write some description, you can write it.
So I want to take suppose execution time as five minutes,
okay, fine, when some three seconds, that's your wish.
Let me save that also.
Now, come to your editor.
Okay.
Now you need your boat o3.
So import moto three, right?
So I'm adding go to implement.
So guys here, while writing generally or Python Bhutto three scraped,
you are creating your own session or customization.
Medea, you no need to create your session,
Custom session or your own session because we assign a role to your lambda automatically,
you are moto three will create a required session from the role.
You don't bother about that.
So that's why directly create your required console.
So I'm going to create my UCT console in terms of,
let's say suppose using resource, we can go with anyone.
But I'm going with this one.
Moto three dot.
Let's take a resource.
So service name, EC2.
And I wanted to work under region name as US East one.
Right? Fine.
First I want to collect
all my EC2 instances which are there under develops or a test environment.
So for that, right,
for each instance in your EC2 Console using the source object dot instances, dot.
If I take all, you will get all instances without having any, without checking.
Which instance is related with the environment.
So for that you have to use a filter.
Right? Then feeder offer that filters equals three.
How to write a list of filter?
So now I want to create a my filter that is test to filter destiny Ron meant filter,
I am taking, this is my,
I mean meson, my requirement I am selecting suitable variable names.
And you know, filter syntax is a dictionary which consists of by
default name as one key and the value size.
One more key. And this is the standard syntax for your filter while creating.
And here, based on tags you are filtering right?
Tag colon. So what is your required key?
Env? Let's provide that e and v here.
Then values. Now let me take values or test and Iran meant, right.
That's it.
Now for time being,
let me directly print who just instance IDs.
Okay, let me save this.
And guess, after saving your code,
you how to test it. Suppose.
So, by default it needs at least one dummy event.
So let me take sample event.
You don't bother about this as of now.
We will work out with this while going forward.
Now let me test it.
It's executing other that yeah,
it has been executed.
Let's go and see the details here.
C, you're able to fetch your instance IDs,
which are related with the word test a neuron.
When suppose I am taking,
I am going to modify this value or an environment.
I suppose this is broad and Iran meant.
Okay.
Now see that if I read on the core previously or getting to insurance studies,
if I read and you will get only one instance ID.
Let me check it.
Did they say oh, this?
Yes.
Yeah. Let me save this.
Yeah. Radon.
See the output here.
So you are tags or test ENV,
fine, would end up lay the feeders.
So, so that's why you are getting all the values.
So you have to apply. No, let me save it and rerun it.
Now I am running that.
So it's minus take Identify the filter here.
So we have to apply a filter here in this portion, right?
Okay, hi, ran that. Now go and see the output.
You are getting only one instance ID now.
That means based on your requirement,
you are able to separate your instances from your required environment.
Now let me modify this to tag to now test.
Because I want to work with at least two servers so that you will get idea.
Now, as of now you are having only one instance ID because previously
one of the your instance environment was dealt nowadays, test.
Now I'm going to rerun,
but see the output, what you are going to get it.
Now we are getting two instance IDs.
So my intention is first of all,
you are able to separate
your test instance IDs or test EC2 instances from your all instances.
Yes, we got that.
Right.
Okay, sir, to stop your EC2 instances,
we already explained different ways, right?
You can go through our previous easy to parts, right?
We have different parts to work with. Easy to write.
Let me go with select two hour.
Where is it we are working with now these scores, right?
Yeah, fine.
So under curriculum, so you directly,
you can get your course doodles c here.
To stop your EC2 instances,
write multiple instances on single instances we,
we follow different procedures.
I mean, we have different ways.
So radically simple way.
I'm going to use it here.
Stop or start.
Okay?
No, I'm doing you are each manually first,
I'm checking whether it is going to work Cournot, start.
Right, save it.
Currently either in turn,
status is top predators.
First, I will check it manually where it is working or not.
Still it's working here, it's down.
Let me go and refresh here and see the output.
Now that in pending status means after sometime the hunted they will come to,
you are running status.
Ok.
So now just to wait and I want to stop them and I want to come back here.
Meanwhile, what we will do is say, okay,
so now in our hand we have a core to stop.
You are EC2 instances based on your required enviornment.
Next, finally, you have to schedule a job.
So as of no,
we are running JavaScript manually if you want to start your EC2 instances,
but automatically our Python moto three in your lambda,
whatever it is there that should trigger,
that should run automatically at 08:00 AM,
two from Monday to Friday.
So in that way, you have to schedule your job.
Okay. Not to schedule your job, right.
Just observe that. Go to your services and go to your CloudWatch.
So guys here also you can trigger your job.
Okay, you how your cloud watch here.
But this is the easiest way and better way.
Always. O, I will choose this one.
I mean, I will prefer this one just I will go to
CloudWatch and I will create a rule here such that
my lambda function will trigger or run whenever that particular time occurs.
So after entering into a Cloud was just to go to rules.
Okay.
So yeah, they are running now.
I want to stop them.
Stopping.
That's fine.
So guys, now we are,
whatever the lambda function we are having in our hand,
that lambda function we are going to schedule like, you know,
on your Unix-like systems you have a cron jobs candlelight symbol.
So I want to trigger this script.
I wonder run this script.
I want to exclude the script at particular time.
So for that you hard to schedule the job so far
that just go to your CloudWatch and rules, create your rule.
Okay, so guys here, two types of rules are there.
One is event, a patrimony schedule as are not just go with schedule.
So in in a while we'll go and work with even the pat on aswell schedule.
Right?
And again in schedule also,
you want to run the software every five minutes or after some five hours,
orange and of that,
just to use some cron job expression such that it will automatically trigger your job,
automatically run your job.
So here you have to form something such that it has to work.
Okay?
Now how you can form this, i mean,
you had to write some expression such that it has to form.
I mean, it has to represent eight AM from Monday to Friday.
So if you don't know, just click on this here, learn more.
It may lead to your official documentation.
It should of that will also having some yeah.
Let me take this. I will do this.
So we have first scheduled expression for rules.
What are the rules here and having?
So for cron job expression,
you are trying to work with con job.
So in cron job, if observed here, how many fields are there?
123456, then what is the meaning of each and every field?
See first, if we listen minute, second hovers,
then day of the month,
month, day of week, okay, year.
Ok.
So now every year,
suppose that for you just to make it as a star at last,
then here question mark, is there no.
So I will write cron jobs operatory first.
So I want to write some pattern here,
expression here such that it has to represent every Monday to Friday, 08:00 AM.
So you're having suppose there 123456 fields.
Let's take 123456.
Ok. Now, foster families minute.
So I want to start exactly at 08:00 AM.
Then secondly is Howard eight.
Okay.
Then what about third field?
You are having a day of the month.
So I want to start every day, suppose.
Okay.
Day of the month, okay,
I'm writing suppose star,
then month, every month,
I want to do that.
Then day of the week.
Suppose if you have during a Sunday to Saturday,
but I want Monday to Friday, right?
So if you want to write Monday to Friday,
how you can write it, you can write here already, is there no.
So simply can copy this one also. Monday to Friday.
Then. Sorry. Last one is what is the having ear right.
Every year I want to run it.
Fine.
Now guys, in case if you are getting convenient just to
go through this so that you can get how you can use that.
Ok.
Fine. Now this is the expression to start the worker code at Monday to Friday.
Monday to Friday, and Monday to Friday everyday, eight AM.
Okay, so now this is the expression I required forum,
our job, just copy and paste it.
So now it is going to represent here Monday.
Suppose next, when it will occur means Monday as of now,
what is the time now suppose, I'm sorry,
this is in IST,
abilities in USD, right?
No wrong.
So as per USD will run on 13th May eighth AM GMT, right?
So this is the interval this is going to represent.
So after writing your expression here,
you can also understand from the below triggers values.
So it is going to do next or ten triggers,
I mean, but when it will run this code,
so for the 3D giving next ten intervals, that's fine.
Okay.
So, but now I can't wait up to tomorrow, 08:00 AM, right?
So what I am doing is the HIPAA expression.
So instead of that, just I am giving after one-meter how-to start my code.
So as of now it instances are installed status, right?
If you wait for one minute automatically,
you are instances will come up.
So there's often writing your pattern here,
schedule, it just added target here for
which lambda function you are going to assign this chron job.
See that?
Autostart test, EC2 instances eight AM.
Ok.
So as of now I don't bother about this.
You just use default values.
Ok, we are not giving any input.
Okay?
Just keep this as this.
While going for I will discuss each and everything.
Just configure details.
Name.
So for rule also, you have to give some name. That's it.
Let me take autostart,
EC2, test incense, test instances rule.
That's it.
If you want try some description you can write.
Start enabled just to create a rule.
Rule has been created.
Okay, now, I wonder what the, what is the rule?
So if you go with your rule,
right, fix a rate of one minute.
Offer one minute automatically you are instances will trigger.
Just wait. Offer one minute.
Okay. It will take one minute time mater
one-meter automatically it will, they will trigger.
But while applying our exert concept,
you have to write your cron job in this way and you have to save it.
So after checking this,
yeah, see now they are automatically coming up.
Because you've given a pattern as one might offer one minute to try to start.
Right?
So this is the way how you can do.
But in your real time, right?
As per our example,
you should not go and start this out or every one minute initiative
that we have to follow this pattern,
you just save this pattern and we can execute this vector.
Ok, now this easy. What pattern?
Now if you have done here conjugate expression, it is there.
Now based on this intervals automatically my instances
will start at every Monday to Friday,
every day, 80 AM.
That's it.
So it's just a four.
You are understanding what we did for our cases.
First, we need a role for your lambda.
So why we are using this role means to get access of your AWS required service.
So in our case, EC2 through moto three.
So after creation of role just to create
a lambda function that is based on lambda function call.
So it is based on your requirement.
So at the same time, don't forget to assign previously created roll.
Okay, then offer that scheduler job in terms of your con job expression.
So how do you learn about your cron job?
It is they're officially in our official documentation
of your AWS directly can understand by going through this.
Ok. Now guys, you implemented only 40 watts start.
Then what about stop wearing your lambda function.
So same core, Exactly. Okay.
Even you don't end up this return because you are not getting money.
If you write something, you can return it.
Actually, you know, any of this here, in this case,
simply I am writing such as something.
So same cone, nothing is it guys,
you just try to implement for stop button 05:00 PM.
Okay?
Just ideas, stop, that's a stop.
And same core are near expression is instead of a to just write nine.
It is morning, right? So 17 told plus 717 so that it will represent for you or pm.
Okay.
Okay, so here's the way how you can automate
your jobs to cron job while working with your lambda function.
Okay?
So if you have any confusion or just posted a message so that I will respond for that.
Okay.
Okay, guys, thank you for watching this video.