Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to see how to automate snapshots
of EBS volumes using AWS Lambda and CloudWatch.
Right? So singly automated EBS snapshots using AWS Lambda and CloudWatch.
So whatever the code you are going to use in AWS lambda,
that is moto three of Python, right?
So you know, lambda is also going to support for other languages as well, right?
Like Node.js, JavaScript, go lang, Right?
But here we are using moto three of your Python, right?
Fine.
So the is to implement this grip just i'm going with some steps.
Very first step is first,
I will write a small code to list all EBS volumes based on our requirement.
Suppose yes are generally how
some 50 to 60 of some 50 EBS volumes in your AECOM in one particular region.
And one more thing is this script is going to work with only for one reason.
And in next video, I will make a script such that it has to work for all the regions.
Okay?
That's fine. Now assume that you have 50 volumes in region, right?
And in the summer or our product volumes on somewhat non-profit, right?
But I want to take backup for suppose only for product, right?
So based on this condition,
first of all, I need to get all EBS volumes IDs.
Once. If I get all EBS volumes IDs in my hand,
then I can extend this logic to create snapshots, right?
First, let me go and open a simple script to
list all your EBS volumes based on your requirement.
Now, our requirement is First let me open my icon.
See, you know, EBS volumes or they're under your ec2 service.
Right. So we are under EC2.
Let me go with the volumes. Right.
See observe here.
Let me login.
Now. See here
we have two volumes, right?
And if you observe that tag values for these two key as broad and value as backup.
So whatever the EBS volume which is having
key as broad and value as backup those volumes.
For them, I want to take a snapshot, right?
And we have only to unfold those to you how CHI has broadened value as backup.
Right?
And if you have the snapshots as of now,
I don't have any snapshots, right?
First, let me go and write a simple moto three scripts to list out all your EBS volumes.
Then we will apply a filter based on tax, right?
I will show the simple script. Okay?
So automate EBS, snapshot PY.
Let me write my Python shebang line and then import photo three.
Then I'm also importing pre-print module.
So instead of using simple print,
paper and diffuse preprint for dictionaries,
it will display output in Eclair format.
That's it, right, fine.
The first thing you are going to work with volumes.
Volumes are there under ec2 service.
That means you have to create first EC2 object.
And to create your EC2 object,
you are having two methods to objects.
You are having resource object as well as client object.
You can go with any one of that.
So here I'm going to work with client object.
Of course, same option is there even if your resource as well.
Right?
And anyway, you are running the score from your local host, right?
So finally, I will copy and paste this coding lambda,
and I will show you how to automate based on your required time.
Right? That's fine.
Now, so you are running this board as of no, from localhost.
That's why I always try to create a session first.
So this session is nothing but your moto three dot.
So shen dot session.
How to provide some profile name.
See we are using from starting the profile landmass route.
If you want to use any other profile just to
configure your credentials on your local host.
By running database configure, hyphen,
hyphen profile man provided the profile name,
whatever the proper limb you want,
un-pause the credential so that that profile name will have access to
work based on your IAM policies.
That's fine.
Now, I have a session in my hand.
Right now let me create my easy to console
object that I am going to use using client object, right?
So simply session the client.
So what about the service you need?
I need EC2.
That's why I'm going to take service name as EC2 when I want to work
with a region name that is USBs 21.
That's fine.
Right now the thing is using your EC2 client object.
I need to get all my required volume IDs first.
Because for them only entity could take a snapshot.
So whatever the volumes ids,
you're going to get for that unit to take snapshot.
That's why force I'm trying to collect my required volumes IDs.
Let me go and open your official documentation for your moto three.
On let me select your service as EC2.
Go with available services, right.
So under that ec2.
And anyway, anyhow here, under EC2,
you how both are resource as well as client object,
C, client as well as resource object.
Right?
This is a resource and this is quaint.
Now I'm going to work with client.
Just click on that client, right?
And if you observe somewhere you how option coral.
Your client, you know,
all operations are one-step operations or describe volumes or they're somewhere.
Describe volumes, right?
Just take client.write volumes.
So based on freedom affinity filter,
you can apply a freighter as off null initially.
I'm not going to apply a filter directly.
I want to list all the volumes which are available in mind, but color, region.
And one more thing here,
they're using client dot describe volumes.
But the client means in our case EC2 dot Klein Because we are creating
a client object from a session, right? That's fine.
Now let me print directly.
I want to use P print,
print your EC2 underscore,
client dot describe volumes.
That check. Ok, let me run and see the output.
Let me provide a excretion permissions for this.
Now I'm going to run it.
We print what syntax?
We print needs parenthesis.
It's like a python three statement.
See that you're going to get your output nuclear format.
And if you observe the output, right,
this is response later and the status is
200 success our query has been executed successfully.
Now under volumes, right?
See that this is a list of values and new consists of,
this is for one is volume ID and this is for one more volume IT anyway,
as of now you have only two volumes as well.
You are getting only two volumes.
You've held some number of volumes.
You will get all the volumes here.
Right.
Let me open you are I don't want to get response data.
I need that at low volumes.
That's why I'm picking a key called That's it.
From your described volumes.
I am getting the information for this only volumes
that's certainly key called volumes right?
Now let me run and see the output now.
Now you are getting your output only four volumes.
And that too is a list.
A list.
A list consist of two dictionaries because you have two volumes.
Right?
Now. First of all, I want to separate these
one-by-one volume information by using for loop.
That's why c I am taking for each volume in this.
Let me print here also just use P print so that the output will be clear. That's it.
Now let me run this and see the output.
I need to collect one-by-one.
Yes, no, you are getting this as one value and this has one value.
But in this what you need volume ID.
That's why what I am doing is I don't want to print the entire informations.
Nbi need volume ID.
So you can use either get or like square brackets you were key name.
Anyone be fine. Let me save it and run it and see the output. What you are going to get.
Oh, I have taken dot that is for not get.
That's fine. Yes. We are getting two volumes IDs.
Right.
But the thing is yeah,
you are collecting your volume IDs,
but I want to store all volume IDs into one variable.
And I'm going to take one list for two story.
We're all volumes.
So list of volume it is equals to.
Now instead of printing each time,
what I'm doing is I'm going to append this so
that I can use this list of volume ids while taking snapshots.
That's it. Softer completion of for loop,
I'm going to print the list of volume ID saw. Right?
That's it.
Now let me save it and run it and see the output.
Yes, you're able to get to volume might is right?
But as of now we are collecting
all the volume IDs which are there in your particular region,
but based on requirement in anti collected, suppose,
let's say or for one of the volume ID I'm going to change tags into,
instead of fraud, I am going to continue to assert some dope, right?
But if I run this script,
it is going to collect again all volume IDs.
But I need only prod volume might is, right?
That's what you need to apply a filter here.
Let me create a filter first.
So my filter is like, you know,
filter for backup, prod backup,
Let me take broad backup.
So this is like dictionary format and it is consist of name as a fixed r1 as one key.
And you had to provide some name here and values.
As a fixed key again,
it consists of some list of values Now based on tag and that two key as proud.
And for that key,
what are the values you are going to take backup.
So based on this backup, right?
If I have a backup and if I have a product here,
then only I want to get the volume might is right.
So back-up or sometimes even write capital B.
Anyone of that, it may consist of either this one or this one.
Right?
Now, you created a filter called filter for prod backup.
Now that filter you how to apply while describing your volumes.
If you observe here,
describe volumes, you have a freighter option here, right?
So this is nothing but we created filter for broad backup.
This is one variable outtake and now just try to apply
your filters equals two list of filters you can apply.
As of now we have only one filter that is fritter, broad backup.
Now let me run and see the output.
Now we are going to get only one volume ID because only for
this Yao Qi as broad and value as backup CF, right?
Just to see if that is first one.
See for this only how?
Now? So just assume that I have.
This also like products because I need to take at least two volumes to work.
Now I changed for both volumes or how a key as broad and volume values as backup.
That's why you're going to get to volume ID's.
That's fine. So there is whatever the code we write.
So you're using client object whenever you are using client opposite,
if you go with the stride forward in this format,
I'm Describe your volumes, right?
It is going to fetch because this is a query, right?
It is going to get only MAC, so 50 results.
So if you have suppose volume arrays which are there more than 50 in
your particular region than the straight forward way is not correct.
While implementing your core with client object that to only four queries this query,
no, you are going to get number of volume IDs query.
So at that time, right?
If you have less than 50 volumes,
this is perfectly work, right?
Less than 50 volume IDs in your particular region,
this will work perfectly.
But if you have more than 50 results,
50 volume IDs in your Butler region, the core,
whatever you are running that you may not fix all that may not fetch
all you were volume IDs at that time you had to use pollinators, right?
Just come back.
See here we have paginated.
So guys, resonators are only applicable for your client object, right?
So you already we have discussed in detail with your resonators in your records, right.
Let me open that also once.
So let me open this and I will show you that.
So about resonators.
So if you are able to apply biogenetics For any one of those surveys,
then that is common for all the services.
Just come down somewhere we discuss in a boat.
Past senators.
Yeah. Fascinate us off moto three.
Okay. Just remember this is just to go through
this before proceeding with this script, right?
Then come back and I can understand how to use past senators, right?
So for time being, what I am doing is I'm going to comment your code fast,
whatever the core we are having.
But anyway, filter I need just simply these two lines of code. I am going to come in.
Then first I'm going to create a paginated creation of
pies net is nothing but what is your required operation?
Your first year selecting year past senators,
then you are entering into this page.
So what is your required operation?
Describe volumes, right. Just up there.
Yes, I'm very how volumes.
So whatever the query you with your normal object,
same query will be there even in your past Senator under your clients.
So describe volumes, right?
See such you how to create a resonator in this fate?
Just copy and paste it.
Resonator, right.
In our case, client is nothing but easy to underscore.
Client. We're not taking as a client,
we are taking another EC2 client, right?
So from this passage to paginate,
right, let me select a resonator.
Resonate the mean, get page by page.
And here you don't want to get all the alumina is.
That's why again, just apply your filters.
Simply copy and paste here,
whatever we have already,
we help us here. Right?
That's it.
Now let me print this object and see the output.
So as of now your list of volumes are empty.
So you are getting paginated 0.5x net as the object.
So based on volumes you will get number of pages.
So whatever the object you create dead, right?
This paginated consists of number of pages,
but it depends on number of volumes which are having in your account.
That's why you just tried to collect page by page.
So that's why I'm going to take four loop for this pass senator,
for each page in this let me printed that page.
I'm going to use P print.
So if you have, suppose more than 50 volume IDs
with this broad as a key and value as a backup,
then you will get two pages.
If you have more than a 100,
you'll get three bridges, right?
So up to less than or equal to a 100,
you'll get two pages,
but we have only two,
or you might is right further,
this code will work.
And anyway, this code is work for all.
If you have any number of volume mighty smite, let me pre-print.
We're each page.
So each fish, just observe the output. Right?
You're getting your volumes,
but I need only volumes, right?
So here's while applying your packet headers,
right, you are going to get one more extra loop.
Right?
You have to get first page by page.
Now you are having in your inner hand one-page.
So from that page,
I'm collecting like this volumes.
Right now, see the output.
I have taken a key called volumes. Now see the output.
They are getting List of volumes, right?
I think is there whenever, if you include pass monitors you need in it include
one more extra loop to iterate page by page.
That's why c here for H volume in this each page of volume IDs, right?
Then simply, I don't want to print holiday have a logic.
So in a previous video we have seen in previous logic,
whatever the logic you have, same logic.
List of volume IDs,
dot append each volume.
That's it. Now let me save it and run it.
That's it. You're able to get your volume IDs.
So base as of no,
in my Argonne to how only two volume Murray's,
that's why even normal stride forward,
whatever the code how to describe your option,
that core will also work.
But whenever if you are more than 50 results for your requirement,
then you may not get all your 50 volume IDs
using your straightforward method of your client object.
That's why you had to create the Appassionata paginated will_paginate page by page.
And each base consists of 50 volume ID's.
That's why I'm going to collect all of pages and from the dollar volume.
That's it.
Right now I will use this score.
That's fine.
Right now in your hand you how your list of volume IDs.
Now I want to take a snapshot further.
Just go into a client, right?
So how to take a snapshot?
So somebody how Create Snapshot option,
you just go through that, right?
Let me open that first. Create.
Create.
If you go with all the options so that you can come
to know what is the required option, right?
I have a creates snapshot here.
Client.print snapshot.
It's requires some descriptions on volume ID,
some tags, specifications, right.
And he had dried on whether you want to
run before proceeding with actual runoff martin, Right?
So I I don't want to use this.
Let me open my script.
So guys, I want to take one by one volume IID from this unfolded.
I need to apply this because it's taking only one volume ID, right?
See, first I will take your for loop for H.
Volume ID in your list of volume might ease.
And just I am writing some print statement
taking slump of whatever the volume ID you are having currently.
Not format each volume ID, right?
So first I am going to run it without writing your logic,
just check it, how it is going to work.
See taking snap off this volume and taking snap up this volume.
But to take that snap,
you need to include a logic, right?
So how I am going to include that logic is nothing but just
observe that they are quaint dot creates snapshot, right?
But in our case,
the client is nothing but easy to underscore client
because we are creating client as easy to underscore client, right?
Create snapshot.
And it is going to take some options, right?
So description.
So I want to write description, yes.
So as of now we are running this code from local host.
But later finally, we are going to schedule these through cron job.
I mean, like a cron job using your lambda and CloudWatch.
That's why taking snap
with lambda and CloudWatch, that's it, right?
That is one parameter we want to provide this Create Snapshot.
Then second thing is volume ID.
So you're taking your volumes IDs.
With your four loop, right?
So that's why what I am going to take is your volume IDs,
they're already anywhere this variable.
So for each iteration you are going to work with
one volume by means for each iteration you are
going to take a snapshot of one volume, then tag specifications.
So if you want to include, you can include it.
But yes, I want to include it.
I will tell you what is the reason here,
even if you can skip this part,
no bomb and hear resource pipe.
Yeah, anyway, does a dictionary,
let me open that. Provide that dictionary.
Then.
The resource type, what you are going to take,
you're going to take a snap, right?
That's why you have to provide resource type as snap.
Or getting confusion.
Here you will see somewhere you are resource type snap.
Just go to last, right.
Snap, right, let me just come back.
Snapshot.
Right? You're going to take a snapshot that's where it says type is Snapshot.
That's fine.
Then you need to provide some tags if you want.
If you want, right?
Yes. I want to provide it tags.
That's why.
Yes, I'm going to do that.
Tags like, you know,
key as suppose
I am taking key.
So what is my key means?
Delete on because see the allele or taking snapshots, right?
So if you keep on tick,
you are going to increase number of volumes.
I mean, snapshot for your volumes.
So I had to take snapshot today and this snapshot I want to delete after 90 days.
That's why after 90 days to identify my snapshot, right?
Just I am giving here delete on as a key.
But you can follow any tax.
But I'm taking for my continence This next value.
So what is the value you want to provide, right?
So after 90 days I wanted delegate.
So guys, whether it is a number or string,
you have to provide as a string only tags are always strings.
So now, see everyday I will run some one more script and through
which I will find out the snapshot which are A's within 90 days.
And if it is having a tag as Delete on 90, then I will delete it.
So there's these tags are for other purpose,
smart for this strip, right?
So I want write one more step through which I won't delete the snapshot
which are aged within 90 days or more than 90 days.
So for that I am giving it tags as this one.
But for time being, if you want to provide any,
any type of tag, you can provide it.
Right now close with the work.
So this is for tags.
Then tag specification close with dictionary format.
Then you How? A list.
Then you have parenthesis. That's it.
Now you close, right?
Now. Let me run the code.
And before going to run just to go to your account and go to snaps.
As often you don't have any snaps, right?
That one by me.
Not for all right. Not for our republic snaps. Let me run this.
Yeah.
See. Let me refresh it.
So one computer one is pending.
So of course you have taken your snapshot honest, you skipped,
came out, but still you are taking a snapshot.
Snapshot is not completed.
So whatever the core you implemented, that is perfect.
But the problem is with your queries exiting without completion of your snapshot, right?
It's still in pending, right?
Anyway, you can take some time and it will complete it. Right.
But my requirement is until the snap is completed,
your skipped should not exit the skip as to wait, right?
For that, how you can include your logic.
Right? So if you're going to get confused for further court, you can skip.
But the good practices always,
whenever if you are creating something,
include waiters, That is a good practice.
Right?
So let me open in your or your client's sorry,
your wages are there only for your client,
but you can apply that CLI waiters even for
your resource also know ballroom that may open waiters.
So you have very does know these waiters sore for actually client.
Right?
You can apply this waders even for your resource also.
So in next article,
I will directly write a code by using your resources are the same procedure.
I will give you a quote, right?
You can go through that so that you can understand, yes,
I am going to apply wages for that anyway.
So what is the requirement? I need?
Snap is completed, right?
Just to go snap shot completed. Just observe here.
First you have to create a waiter using your client, that straightforward syntax.
Then simply you have to include waiter dot weight.
But here you don't want to filters.
You need just to provide you are
snapshot IDs so that it will wait up to that snapshot is completed.
Let me go with that.
And before going to with this waiters,
see guys, these waiters includes a either filters.
I mean, you can provide either filters and even one or IDs or snapshot IDs.
But in our case you, anyway,
you are taking snapshots from this, right?
So this is just simply are taken one syntax, right?
So from this you can also capture the response, right?
Let me, So what,
what is the use of taking a response from here means?
See my waiter needs some snapshot IDs.
So if a province snapshot IDs,
your waiter will wait up to.
Sf snapshot is computed for this snapshot ID's.
That's why now it's time to story were response simply I am taking a response, right?
So often accompanies no fewer each and every.
I mean, after taking,
not completion, often running creates snapshot, right?
Simply I'm printing, let me print
so that you can see where you are going to get your snap ID.
So I'm printing response. All right.
Let me check for indentation.
123412345
See as of now,
you how to snap shots.
Right? Now I am going to run your code once again.
Right? See, observe the output taking snap off this.
And if you observe the output,
some very how snapshot ID.
Right?
Now, that's why what I am doing is I need to collect Actually that snaps.
That's why print your response
dot get or you can use square brackets,
then you can write your key.
I'm in. This way is also ok,
right, or dot github is also working.
Now let me rerun anyway.
We are going to get for now, right?
That's fine. Now from this we have taken snap ID.
Yeah, fine.
Now I am going to run once again.
I'll see the output. You're able to collect your snap IDs.
Right? Now I'm going to store this snap IDs into.
Now you have six just after that, right?
That's fine.
Now before going to start,
our for loop could take snap for one-by-one.
I'm taking snaps.
Snap ID is equals to some list, empty list.
And simply anyway, I'm displaying, but instead of displaying,
what I will do is snap ID's.
That's it.
Right after completion of your for loop just I'm printing the snap IDs or snap IDs.
So still you are not including your waiters.
So just now you collected your snapshot IDs for
which the volumes for which you are going to take a snapshot.
Now in your handy how snapshot IDs?
Right?
That's fine. No, you need to include a waiter.
So to include your waiter,
first thing you have to create a waiter,
right? Where is it?
Yeah, simply waiter equals two.
It's very simple guys.
You no need to worry about this much. It's very simple.
So snap shot completed because
after completion of your snapshot to exit from your script.
So client, EC2 underscore client is our object.
Let's say now you created a waiter.
Now you have to apply that waiter to apply that waiter,
you, How do you simply wait up, not wait.
Right?
Then you can go with either filters, right?
Or you were Warner IDs or snapshot IDs.
So snapshot id say list of snapshot.
It IS already we stored our snaps.
Right? In a variable costs are in a dictionary called Stamp IDs, right?
This is a list on the right.
But inside that list string and us naturally,
ID is a list to sorry, string only.
That's it.
Now after this you can write,
write successfully completed snaps
for the volumes of.
So anyway, how some variable volume might is right,
let me take it where you are amending your volume IDs.
List of volume IDs, right?
That's it.
So now if I run our script,
no, it won't exit immediately.
See previously whenever if you are running yours could be is going to exit immediately,
but it won't exit immediately.
So first let me do one thing.
I'm going to delete all the volumes,
so one by me, sorry,
snapshot won't buy me.
Fine. Now if I run this script, right,
see, okay, somewhere, list of duties not callable snapshot tidies.
What happened on second snapshot IS diaper list object is not callable,
easier to client.connect Vedas.
And this is the core part,
didn't eight line number, right?
This is OK. Snap, snap.
Snap shot, right is dot,
dot get snapshot ID.
List object is not callable.
So taking this is a dictionary, right?
Dictionary in that one of the keys snapshot ID.
Okay, let me try once again.
Is the syntax problem here.
Oh, sorry, I didn't do append operation that my mistake.
So I need to append one by one snapshot ID, right?
Ok.
Snapshot dot append.
That's fine.
Right now let me save it and done it.
So before that, yeah, we are run right?
Let me delete these two.
Even though if you keep no problem,
just I want to delete it.
Now I'm going to run, see the output.
So these thus snapshot ids you're taking right now if you observe here,
yes, you are going to get those two snapshot,
but it is still in pending status.
That's why you're CPS waiting.
Once it is completed,
then your stimulus will come out, right?
So that is called a waiter concept to right inside of your scripts.
So there you have to use waiters whenever if you're creating something.
So if you want to wait until the required action is completed at that time,
you can include your writers inside of your skipped, right?
You can use wages for any creation, right?
The, remember that waiters and clients or their Servetus and passionate is,
are there with your client.
And anyway, pollinators are applicable only for your client, but waiters.
You can create waiter from client and you can apply that for
even resource object also, right?
Still it is taking your completed.
Now your script will come out.
Oh man, successfully comparators.
Now for the volume at least off volume IDs attributed
string object has no attribute list of volume iris.
Ok, or script is working but somewhere.
Line number 46. Oh man,
I forgot to write dot format.
Actually script is working perfectly correct.
Okay, we'll check it once again.
So I forgot to mention that format.
That's it. Ok.
Now observe that your script is waiting.
Now if we refresh it.
So it is waiting for this snapshot.
Once it is done than you are, you come out.
Otherwise you just wait here.
Once if you are skipping is computed,
then go and see in your console so that your snapshots are completed, right?
So for that only we are including betas, right?
So there is, as of now,
what are the core we are working, right?
That is, we are running on your local host.
Now our next step is we want to keep this code in lambda
and I want to schedule a job such that everyday morning,
six AM, or evenings, 6pm, right?
Whatever it may be based on your required time,
it has to take a snapshot automatically.
Yes.
Or skip has been executed successfully just to go out and refresh it now completed.
Right?
So just I am deleting.
I don't want to give the snapshots. Right?
So this is the code.
And remember that this code we are working with
only 41 region using the score we are working with only 41 region, right?
In next video, I will implement this code for multiple reasons.
And one more thing, we are implementing these code using client object, right?
So I will give a code using a resource object for the same purpose, okay?
I will do it as an article I will include in our course so that you can go through that.
So maybe I will include somewhere where we are rocking it snaps right.
Yeah, so I will include some barrier or your script, you just go through that.
Ok, fine.
Now let me copy this entire core.
Now I want to run this core automatically with a scheduled intervals.
So you can do even as a con job on your local host like you know, you can schedule,
see this clip I want to run suppose for every ten hours or for every two hours,
or every day, morning sometime or app in a day,
particular time you can scheduled even using your conjure up from your Linux box.
But to schedule, right, you need a cron job.
And again, you need a local host to run your script.
But anyway, I mean finally you need to maintain some server to run your jobs.
But I don't want to do that because already AWS is
providing a lambda through which you can schedule your jobs.
That's why what I'm doing is,
so let me open lambdas service.
Right?
So here I am going to schedule my job.
That means automatically, it will take a snapshot based on required intervals or time.
So just click on Create Function.
So guys, this is your lambda, right?
So already we have seen some intellection part in our course.
Now we are going to directly create function.
So I want to build from scratch.
So simply write automate snaps for EBS volumes.
That's it.
So I want to implement it with this code with Python low,
I'm going to set Python 2.What amen.
You can select different languages case, right?
Two dot seven, then you can assign your role here.
But after creation of function, I will assign my role.
See whenever if you are running your code through lambda.
Again, lambda also need some credentials to work your work with your core,
but that credentials you can provide with programmatic access keys.
The way how you are working on your local host.
Or we can assign some role,
such that from the rule,
the lambda will get credentials, right?
C just to go down allocation of your lambda.
There is option called execution role.
Use an existing role.
I already created a role.
If you want to create a new row, just select this,
right than a house somewhere.
My role like Keno from lambda is U2.
I think lambda whole to work with, yeah,
I think for this argument,
full access for this role. I selected this role.
Just save it and see generally by default is given three seconds of execution time.
So within three seconds,
if you are not able to complete your lambda cold will get fail.
That's why I'm going to do suppose ten minutes before ten minutes,
if it is complicated, okay,
your script will exit No Barolo, save.
So if you're under select your network,
right, different parameters we can provide.
And also if you want to provide some tags for your lambda, you can do it.
And any random variables as of now I am not going to use,
we can use in, while going forward.
Aidan variables are nothing but,
you know, on your Linux bugs,
suppose if I run some ENV command,
you're getting some variables,
right? So these variables.
You can write a here and you can access inside of your B23 script.
I mean here, right?
That's fine. Now let me write first to code.
So guys, this is the Lambda handlers
from where you are automatically your core will executing your lambda, right?
So while writing your code here and while importing your boater three,
you need to think about
whether both of these existing on not already adolescents
maintaining in there lambda moto three module.
You don't bother about that.
The only thing you just copy your core and pasted.
Otherwise, stride forward, you can write your code here also.
Now already we have our code.
Let me copy it even in order to write been python, right?
Just import anyway that print statements,
we are not going to see it.
Yes, we can see it in log.
Let me copy and paste my code.
Now provide this is already we imported and we hear a pre-print also not required.
And but if you want, you can keep it.
Now here guys, you don't need to create a session object.
Actually, you are creating your session from localhost whenever if you provide,
if you configure the profile names, right?
But whenever if you assign your role or that time,
don't take session instead of directly take default session.
Nothing but Bhutto three only.
Don't worry, we'll take care if you assign IAM role.
So boater, they dot client.write, right?
So if you assign a role in order to create a session customization,
if you don't assign any of you are crossing,
passing some credentials, then you have to take
either Profile Name or directly access keys, right?
So now I assigned already a role for my lambda.
That's why I am creating directly with the default session.
Right now wherever you how let me modify our,
I mean, let me adjust this.
So there's here you are using ec2 client, your local host,
but here simply use,
yeah, that is easier to client only, sorry.
So we are not creating a session, right?
Only in this case a remaining parties, everything is same.
So by this you are collecting all your list of volumes.
Now you are going to create snapshot.
Now let me rearrange Hyman poverty notations correctly here also.
And we have not returning anything here.
Just write return num.
Okay, let me save it.
Okay?
First I'm going to test it where it is going to work or not as of now, right.
We don't have any volumes are snapshots. I deleted them.
Let me check it.
So guys, basically lambda is a event driven action, right?
So that's why before going to test,
even though if you are not using any events,
you have to provide some test event,
whether you are going to use that or whether you are getting another secondary story.
But by default you how to grow it at least test
event whether you are using are not secondary,
but you have to provide that.
Say, okay, let me check it.
If you have any errors,
it will throw so that we can rectify that.
If we don't, how errors, then ok,
it will work. Okay, it's running.
Right?
So let me go and see here.
Yes, it's taking, so it is waiting your lambda because you include your waiters.
But in lambda, even if you don't include weight has no problem.
But it's a good practice to include waiters if you don't want to just remove this.
So if you include waitress No,
you're going to consume your lambda execution time also.
So that is a somewhat drawback.
But if you're running from local host, right?
You can include your waiters here also for perfect, suppose, if,
if you are going to depend on these snapshots in your code itself, right?
Offer sometime, then you have to include your waiters.
But here just we are taking a snapshot on.
We're not taking From Snapshot Any other thing.
That's why no need to include waiters here.
But assume that after creation of your waiter, Sorry,
snapshots, you are going to take a snapshot into different, I mean,
if you're going to take a copy of that snapshot into
different region at the time before completion of your snapshot,
you cannot take a copy of that snapshot into different cross region.
R.
The timing out include waiters.
Ganymede has been completed, just completed.
Our Skip is perfectly working.
Right? Now.
As of now what you are doing,
even though if you have a coding your lambda manually,
you are running your lambda so that it is taking a snapshot,
but I don't want to run it manually.
I want to schedule the job.
So based on my required diameter has to take automatically the snapshot.
That is our requirement, right?
That's why what I am doing is see guys here you how different types of triggers.
If you go here you have a CloudWatch Events.
So in CloudWatch event,
just click on that and click on the configuration required. Just come down.
See configured trigger.
So just create a new rule.
I'm going to create rule name is automatic.
So here don't provide any space.
Sorry, automatic EBS.
Then Rule Description, you can take anything.
So I'm going to take automatically take a snap for PBS, lets say.
Now here you have two types of rules ways.
Either it is even pattern or schedule expression, even patterns, I think.
But if something happens based on that,
if you want to exclude your lambda,
you have to select event pattern.
But as of now you are going to schedule like a con job scores,
can't jobs could you'll expression, sorry.
If you want to schedule like a cron job,
you have to sell it always scheduled expiration.
Now, again, in this Yasu types of format, read using rate.
Using Khan.
So cronies exactly or cron job, right?
But red is nothing but see if you have some fixed intervals.
I want to run the script for every two minutes,
five minutes, one hour, two hours, right?
So that it will work.
If you take rate, suppose, let's say I'm taking the rate of
suppose sort two minutes. Right?
So for every two means it will take
automatically snapshots just for your testing purpose.
Now I'm selecting faster rate.
Okay, so in official document you how clear explanation for this?
I will show you that. Just wait.
Save it. Done after two minutes, right?
So you just wait two minutes.
So I'm going to mute.
Once it is done,
then I will enable them.
Then I will explain that yet wait, what do mates?
Right now you've got some old snapshot for given volume IDs.
Again, after two means automatically when you get to most snapshots.
So if you want to run any job for every two minutes,
right, like that, then you have to select a rate expression.
So let me open your official documentation itself.
Aw