Hi friends.
In this video, we are going to discuss about resonators for
S3 c already in our course somewhere we have a overall view of resonators,
pollinators of moto three, right?
So remember that pi resonators or applicable for your client object,
not for your resource object.
So why we are going with past senators?
So guys, whenever if you're acquiring
some information with your boat u3 from your AWS or cone,
right at that time, resonators or helpful.
So in what way they are helping us write C that just imagine that in your AWS or county,
how suppose sum is three buckets.
So max, we can create a 100 buckets, right?
So now if I want to list all my bucket using either client or resource anyway,
you don't have any problem with resource object. Problem if client.
So if I tried to list all my buckets from
this edible is silicone using client object, right?
So you are acquiring information,
you are making some EPA cause to get your information,
to get the result for your query.
Right?
You are making some API call with your enemies account using your Bhutto three.
Now this API call will get mags result of either 50 or a 100, right?
Most of the cases, it is going to give you the result of either 50 results or a 100,
except your S3 objects or three objects,
you will get 1000 objects per request.
And whenever if you're querying with your enablers or co-own,
related with your S3 buckets.
So this API call,
we do max a 100 buckets information for one query.
Now anyway, you can create maximum a 100 buckets from your AWS account.
That's why if you want to list all lever buckets using your client,
again, you don't have any problem with the word buckets were using client object.
Now your problem is yes, three objects.
Your problem is with S3 objects.
Let's say you how one S3 bucket in your cone, an agenda.
You how suppose more than 1000 objects inside of that S3 bucket.
Note to list1 objects,
you're making some APA call that APA col will get maximum of 1000 objects.
Whenever if you are working with S3 objects,
you will get 1000 results.
But if held more than 1000 objects,
the remaining objects information you cannot get with your normal procedure at that time.
You had to create a pages.
So suppose if you have, let's say,
sum to a 100 objects are there in your account.
Then if you use resonators automatically your paginated,
we create two pages.
And in first place you will get
1000 objects information and less than 2 thousand you have.
That's why remaining 200 objects you will get from second page.
Let's say suppose you have some 303 thousand
plus 3 thousand plus objects in your S3 bucket.
Right?
So automatically you are passionate or we create
four pages because prepares you are getting 1000 objects.
So if you have 3 thousand plus the remaining objects,
you have to get from fourth page.
So automatically you are both u3 passenger will create four pages.
Now you how to read one-by-one page.
And from this you have to read one-by-one object.
Right?
So now you need to use resonator to get you or S3 buckets information.
Because by default, your client API call will get all your S3 buckets.
The reason is you can create maximum of
a 100 buckets in your AWS account at the same time,
the AWS, so at the same time,
the Bordeaux three APA call using client will also get maximum a 100.
And that's why you no need to use resonators for your S3 buckets.
But you, how do you use buzz monitors for your S3 objects, right?
So guys, make sure that whenever,
if you are working with fewer buckets,
you don't need to create resonators.
But whenever if you are working with objects of a bucket,
then how to you how to use past knitters?
Let me go and write one simple skip just to list out all your objects.
List objects dot p, y.
So guys, you were intensities from particular bucket,
you how to get all your objects,
right? Let me write my core.
So as you know, you have to import moto three,
then you have to create custom session.
That is nothing but you are moto three dot session, session.
Then profile name equals to underscore root.
Right?
Then you can go and get
your objects information bright By creating either client object or resource object.
First I'm going to work with a resource.
Okay, then let me create YES, three for R3.
So S3 using resource object,
that is nothing but from your customization, dot a resource.
Then service name.
Our service name is yes, three.
Then let me provide some region name.
Anyway.
Your S3 is not specific to any region much just providing a region name, that's it.
Now in your hand you how S3 resource object, right?
But you want to get your all objects of particular bucket.
Let's say suppose my required bucket is bucket name,
I'm taking my required bucket.
Let's say in my home.
He's it.
Let me check it.
No, not this. Let me open one more bucket.
This one.
Now if you observe in this grill,
no, given not all this.
So what is my bucket actually?
Let me open this.
Yeah. See I how here almost although your guys here observed count,
how many objects I'm having, my account.
I mean, any particular bucket that is do it Python April.
So here, how many objects I'm having just to go through that 900,
even more than 900.
Let me open that. First after all the bucket,
sorry, objects in a particular IO, almost 1101.
Objects in Mike do with Python, April bucket.
Let me do one thing.
First time taking my bucket name here.
So the ice actually you are having your objects inside of your bucket.
That way first you have to create your bucket object.
So let me create my bucket object.
Right, is nothing but from your resource,
S3 dot simply bucket.
So if you're any doubts,
let me open official documentation.
It's very simple.
Moto three documentation.
Then just to go and select the word available service as is three.
So on this, I'm going to select S3 as my surveys.
Let me open that first.
So as of now you are going to work with
the resource object because for S3 you how resource as well, right?
So let me open this.
Now in the resource object, right?
If you go and see here,
there is a bucket object.
So what is the use of bucket means if you open that the existing bucket,
if you want to work with the existing bucket,
using your boat to three,
you have to create a bucket object first that is nothing but simply
your bucket equals to see your resource,
then dot bucket, bucket,
then whatever the name you are having.
So our name, you can provide directly inside the quote eight conditions like this.
Or because already we stored our bucket in this variable.
Let me say this,
do that. That's a, okay.
Now this, you have created your bucket object.
Now inside your bucket object,
you, how multiple objects?
You are keys, right?
If you go down
somewhere,
let me go.
And so you see buckets, right?
So yeah, how collections?
So your bucket object dot buckets,
your bucket object dot buckets, dot all.
We'll do all your objects. Let me do one thing.
Print your bucket object.
In that bucket object we how objects,
like if you remember while working with EC2,
you are creating first EC2 Console.
On that you are being dot instance,
dot all do get all your instances the same
way whenever if you are working with S3 buckets to get
your S3 buckets first you are creating S3 console dot buckets dot all the same.
But now you created your particular S3 object or butler S3 bucket console.
Now in this yellow number of objects,
so that for a dot objects,
dot all is the operation.
Now if I run this,
just see dot Woodward, you're going to get it.
You are getting some object inside this yellow number of objects.
I mean, your bucket objects,
not to get one-by-one.
You know, you have for loop for each object in this.
So I want to count how many objects you,
how in this butler bucket.
So print, count each object.
Let me save this and run this and see the output.
What you are going to get. A lot of objects in this cedar.
Oh man, I forgot to increment my cone.
Then only you can able to see how many objects are there here.
Now let me run it and see the output.
Just wait and see 1116 objects I'm having in my bucket.
Right now. I want to display only name,
bucket, sorry, object name.
Then there is a dot operation called key,
then simply your object dot key.
Let me save this and run this and just see the output what you are going to get it now.
Yes, you are getting all your objects inside of your bucket,
whatever the bucket you are having.
Likewise, for any bucket if you want to get these other simple steps.
So first create your bucket object from that dot objects dot all.
It can also apply some filters also, we will see it later.
But as of now, my indigenous,
I wanted to get just I won't list
all the objects which are available in one particular bucket.
And here we are using S3 resource object.
But now I want to use suppose as three client object.
So as of now, observe that how
many let me come and how many of this are there in a particular bucket?
So how many double 106 objects you how in a Portland bucket.
So this we implemented with the help of resource object,
but now I want to implement with client object.
So simply client equals nothing but you are session dot client.
Just copy and paste this anywhere. This is same, no.
So if you are unable to understand what is this S3 Klein turned S3 resource upset, right?
That very initial steps in our course we have given in detail why we
need to create S3 object or AC to object, right?
You just to go through introduction part. That's fine.
Now.
So there is nothing is there what we are doing as of now,
we created S3 console first.
See if you want to work with the objects first you out to enter into S3 console.
Now with the help of this week later S3 console.
But we want to work with particular bucket, right?
So in your resource you created your bucket object.
But whereas in S3, how you can get your objects of a particular bucket. Nothing is there.
You don't need to think much about it.
You just go and open your official documentation.
Just enter into S3 service,
then open your client object for your S3 and see the documentation.
What you have here.
Right.
So you've seen inclined badly we how each and every operation,
whatever the client object nucleated on that directly how you're all operations.
So, so somewhere if you go down,
you how list objects operation.
So in this you can provide different parameters.
As of now I want to get all the,
all the objects in a particular bucket, C, nothing is there.
Your S3 client dot list objects,
then you took away your bucket name as a string.
Right?
See that? Now, what I am doing is let me that
it'll print from your S3 client dot your operation.
Then you have to provide your bucket name here.
So here you have to provide syntax as bucket.
It goes to bucket name anyway, our bucket.
Yeah, I want write this as a very first because I want to work with this bucket.
So I want to use this variable.
Of course you can write anywhere no column.
Now in short, providing us it directly, you are data.
I'm providing us a variable name.
That's it. Right?
Let me run this and see the output.
So from this bucket you are listing all your objects.
So this is using client democratic guys.
Don't get confused easily,
just try to practice with anyone of them Method.
So now you are getting some data here.
But what do we need exactly?
We need only Keys.
Just come here.
So anyway, whenever if you are having
some operation in the document itself, we have some response.
Also see the response what you are getting for your operation list objects.
So you are getting as a dictionary inside that you have contents.
So content inside that you have key.
That means now you have to take this as a key from
your entire output instead of getting all output now,
I am going to take eight as in this way.
Right now, just see that what you are going to get.
Just to give me time.
Yes, you're getting something.
But in this data also what we need,
we need only key, right?
When you'd only key.
So that is there directly right?
Key as is your dictionary key.
Now what you have to do,
first of all, you how multiple things inside of this.
That's why just take four loop to get one by one.
For each object.
In your S3 client list objects simply print the word count comma County.
Just for our understanding how many objects you are able to get.
Initially, let me take count as one.
Then I am printing my count,
then I'm going to count equals count plus 1.
First order, the output one's just right.
It will take some time because it has to connect with your yes.
See you are getting some information and a man snow,
you're getting 1000 objects only buddy,
how around treble 16 object,
but you are getting only 1000 objects.
Anyway. I want to display only.
Key name, right?
So let me take as a key because if you have done in output He Hao Qi,
Qi as a key and its value as your required object.
Right?
Now let me save this and run it and see the output.
So this, whenever if you're working with a client, right?
So your client object,
something wanted, I reward tidied man.
Oh, I have taken square brackets are going to get a 100.
Take either square brackets or parenthesis.
Yeah, no, it's ok. You will get it now.
Yes, you are getting 1000 objects only,
but you how tricky 16 objects in your Butler bucket.
But you are not able to fetch them because whenever if you use client, client,
client object to list all your objects from,
from a particular bucket.
So you're both really make API call to your AWS.
And it will get maximum of 1000 objects only from a particular bucket.
But more than that,
that we want you all to do is before going to get your objects information,
first, you had to create a resonator.
So paginated will automatically create some number of pages based on your objects.
So suppose you've got 1000 plus objects,
then your paginated repeat two pages.
And in one page you will get 1000 of
this information and the remaining objects you will get in second page.
So nothing is there guys again is very simple.
You don't need to think much Hubbard.
It simply just click on resonators and remember
that fascinate us or they're only for your client.
Right? See that if you observe here paginated,
these are the possible resonators you, if you want to take it.
Now, as of now I want to go and see list object as y.
Just I'm selecting this paginated St.Petersburg dot list objects.
Simple thing, just create a passenger first in this way.
Her dad syntax.
The only thing is whenever you are more than 1000 objects, right?
You have to create a resonator.
Let me create my paginated first.
So I will keep this code as it is. I will do one thing.
So before that, this is your client object.
Let me take it my client on your tasks.
And guys here, client didn't documentation,
but in our case, our client is S3 underscore Planck.
So just know you created a resonator.
Now from fascinated you have to pass in it.
That means you have to get pages, right?
So that's why if you observe here,
here itself we have paginated at paginate,
then provide your bucket name.
So remaining operations, I mean,
parameters are also there,
but we'll discuss them later.
So it's very simple.
If you look like your list objects operation only.
So I think our bucket is bucket name.
So now from resonator,
you are creating simply pages.
So this operation will create automatically the number of pages, right?
C, Let me do one thing.
Print this information.
You'll see the output, what you are going to get it in intentional where MAN?
Maybe here. Yes.
Yes, although the output, so in this yao to paginate us, Simon two pages.
So how I am saying to two pages,
because I know how many objects are there in my account.
But if you don't know, don't know, need to worry.
So from this, from this objects,
you will get number of pages based on how many objects are there in,
in, in your Butler bucket.
But you don't need to worry about how many ways are there, right?
So if you want to count it,
let me do one thing.
So how many are there?
So for that, right?
For each page in this.
So simply I'm printing, suppose print page.
I don't want to print your each page information simply I'm printing some message.
So now you'll get to 2z times this page information
because in the CR two pages based on that,
these measures will repeat two times because you are using for loop, right?
So how many values are there based on that?
So you're getting two pages.
But in each case you how your information about your particular i mean,
in each base you have information for you what objects.
Right now that's why what you have to do is in each page,
like this operation only,
let me do it one thing.
For each object.
In each page.
Just simply print the word.
Each object.
Then let me print the count also so that they can understand.
So let me initiate some initialized sum count value one.
And after this, let me increase my count equals count plus one.
Right?
Fine.
Now let me run this and see the output.
What you are going to get it. Something wrong.
Yeah, it's my indentation above of Allah.
So first let me get output and I will explain once again, output, you are core.
Yeah, see in each page,
right, you how your keys like this.
So but you need only contents, right?
If you remember, while working with your year in 16th line,
while you are taking contents.
So contents, the response,
see the output or response.
So the response in contents you how your key information.
That's why here, let stake our contents.
Now let me run this.
Just see the output. Yes, no,
you're getting, you're all objects.
But in this information you need only key. Then do one thing.
Schottky.
Now let me run this.
So guys first up there, the output, then I will explain.
Now, you are getting only one object,
objects from your bucket.
So if you use normal list upsets,
if you how less than 1000 objects,
then it will be, it will work.
But if you don't know how many objects are there, then
If you want to get completely all your,
all your objects, then you have to create a resonator.
So let me go with some simple explanation about these paths render.
So guess fascial creating some object for paginated.
Then from this passage later you are calling paginate.
Paginate operation will go and work with your AWS or cone,
weighs down the objects which you are having in your account.
Based on that, it will calculate how many objects are there.
Then if you have more than 1000 and less than 2 thousand, automatically this resonator,
because of this operation,
pass metadata, resonate because of this operation.
In place of this,
you will get two pages,
page one and page two.
In our case, page one,
page two, if you have some 200 thousand,
greater than 2 thousand and less than 3 thousand,
then you will get three pages.
And you now you got three bridges.
So now you had to take one by one PE separately.
And on this page you have to work, right?
So for using for loop from 23rd line, right,
from this three pages,
I'm taking first one page and I'm working on that page.
So what King on one page is exactly like your list objects operation.
Right?
So for each object in your foster page,
so in your page,
the information that we get based on contents key,
if you see here in your documentation,
right, you how something like called contents here.
So under continue how key information this is for one key,
if you have more than that,
you will get this type of victories.
Likewise, right?
That's why I'm taking foster key, sorry, first page.
So on that page I am displaying the information.
So once if you're complete,
this for loop is completed,
you are getting all the objects from foster page.
Then you are not this main for loop.
We'll go and take next to page and
you're repeating same operation so that you are able to
get all your objects inside of your Butler bucket.
Okay, so guys, remember that C before going to use resonators,
you can also come here and you can check it for what operation you,
how fascinated so that you can decide whether you need to use fascinate us or not.
Suppose I am working on S3.
I don't know whether I how to use past data
inclined for Professor Butler operation or not.
All right, anyway, no need to use any passenger for resource.
Just click on paginated and open to
your page directly you can see the operations for which you have paginated.
Let me see. Only for this operations you have paths and
it is you don't have any passenger to walk with your S3.
That means I'm in buckets.
That means you don't need to use Pasadena four buckets.
Whatever the operations you are here.
For them only you how to use resonators.
That's it.
So even suppose if I want to work with, suppose,
let's say IAM user.
Suppose I am taking an example, right?
I am.
Let me open that page.
I am right. See here paginate is,
are there just taken that resonators?
So for which operation you can use paginated,
that information will be there here.
You don't need to think about it.
See some getToken operation it is.
So for this list e,
by seeing them, right, you can understand that.
So Paul Butler operation whether I need to use passengers or not,
by using client object.
Right?
So this is the way how you can use capacitors while working with your objects.
Specifically while running queries yard
use buzz monitors query said nothing but like list all the objects.
So you're going to use and query for your analysts are co-owned using
moto three and you're getting information from there, right?
Only in that case you have to use past senators.
Suppose if I want to create a bucket, don't use positive.
You have to remember this point,
passing eaters or helpful only while running queries.
That means whenever if you're getting,
whenever if you're trying to get some information about existing thing,
then at that time you have to think about pollinators.
And before going to use past data just to go and work
anywhere official documentation and select by Senator.
And another just see all the operations which are available.
So if any operation which you're performing,
if that operation is present in the buzz monitor,
then you have to use past data for that Butler operation.
And finally, remember that no need of pass senator for resource object.
And one more thing, resource is not available for each and every service of your AWS.
It is restricted.
I'm not a security is as of now,
it is available only for some of the services.
Anyway, for S3, you how resource and client, right?
If you remember these things,
then you can easily write your Python both rescued 41, S3.
So already we know about resource client.
And anyway, under collections we have seen all
we have to use filters while going forward.
We use fetus, right?
So anyway, these filters are also helpful whenever if you are running query a query,
instead of getting all,
if you want to get based on some specific parameter,
based on some delimiter are the time you had to use filters in your S3.
Just now we have seen pollinators.
So while going forward,
we'll go with this one and waiters and meta,
meta of course nothing is there already we have given if
you started your core with resource and if any operation is not present,
then without creating client dogs that you can enter
into client object with the help of meta object.
That say, okay, okay,
I thank you for watching this video.