Prints here we are going to write one lambda function for our simple requirement.
Our requirement is automatically assigned
secondary IP of mustard to slavery when mustard Downs,
I mean simply this is like a failover solution.
C agenda, it guides you how to EC2 instances in your AWS network, right?
And assume that these two EC2 instance as same application is running.
And this EC2 instance,
I'm assuming has a master and this I'm assuming as a slew.
And there is a one secondary IP for your master,
for your internal routing purpose.
And there is one external user.
And you know, user is able to access your application from your master server as of now.
But anyway, external user don't know that I'm in your client don't know that
from which application from each salary obligation is running, right?
So this secondary IP information ICANN figure somewhere in route, right?
Fine.
Let's assume that after some time you are master,
somebody's going to down or maybe in any state out of them running status,
then that server is fail to run your application.
Then external user, right,
is not able to access your application.
But I don't want to get this situation for your client or user, external user.
Right?
Then I'm the dumb. What do I need to monitor this?
And manually, I need to route your requests to
your slaves are worked by simply removing secondary IP or
an assigning your secondary IP from your master and assigning to your slew
so that your end user will able to access your obligation without any disagreements.
What is my intention is in case if your application is running on
one server and assume that secondary server is like a backup server.
If something goes wrong with your muscles are worth,
then automatically I need to route your request to your secondary server.
So this is easily possible by assigning
simply 0 second RIP to E1 slaves or work from your master.
So to do this process,
what we are doing, we are removing,
we are assigning secondary API from your Master and we're assigning that to your sleep.
Right? So this thing has to done automatically.
So this thing we can implement with your lambda function, right?
Fine.
Let me open my AWS console first.
So guess as off node there are two servers are running.
Let me take this as a master and let me take this as
a slew of primary and secondary server.
Now what I'm doing here as of now,
just I'm going to assign one secondary IP,
secondary private IP for my master server.
Let me assign something like 170 to 8063.
So we assign it, right.
Fine.
Now close it. Just check it here.
If you refresh this.
Now secondary server, right?
Let me for your primary server is configured with your secondary private IP address.
Let me check cross ticket.
Yeah, 63, right, fine.
Now that's what we are assigning here.
So what is our requirement is increased by any chance,
if your muscle goes down automatically,
this IP has to go and assigned to your slow.
So this thing I want to do automatically, right?
So first I am going to write a code in your endeavors lambda.
Then I will explain that how it is going to work
whenever if you're easy to instance status is changing.
Nothing is there. Let me open my lambda first.
So I'm going to create a lambda function here,
creating a lambda function from scratch.
So our requirement is auto,
assign secondary IP to slave.
When Master goes down, something like that.
Okay, fine.
So we are going to write Python code.
I'm selecting Python three dot seven, asthma interpret depth.
Then you know that gaze.
To run your Lambda code,
you need some execution rule or credentials.
So now I'm going to use execution mode,
which is your real time scenario, right?
D in real time,
most of the cases we will run out lambda functions through execution rule, right?
Let me use an existing rule.
See guys from our previous videos, right?
We have somewhere our execution role as mailer to lambda.
So the same rule I'm assigning now to your lambda to execute your core.
Fine. Now by default the no execution by means three seconds.
I want to change it to some,
let's come down and change it to suppose some five minutes.
No problem. Yeah, tenure can,
if you want to write remaining parameters so you can write it.
Now this is your domain Lambda code.
You need to write your code here.
That's fine.
So as of now, you are going to implement Bordeaux three core.
So that means you need to input Bordeaux three.
Don't worry about that.
By default, Bordeaux trees there with your lambda, just try to import that.
Nowadays.
Let me import your, let me write your code one-by-one.
Let me take muster ID first.
Then I will also write slave ID. Let me get them.
You are Muslim slave IDs from u,
r. So this is muster ID.
So same way, let me get my slave ideas.
Well, so why I need this means because we own,
we want to work with these two instances only. That's why I'm taking them.
Fine.
And then one more thing. What is your secondary IP?
Secondary IP, right?
Let me take that as well.
So this is your secondary IP.
I will take one variable, coral,
secondary IP, wherein I have written here. Yeah.
So let me write that code here first.
So now you're in your hand you how your required variables.
All right, fine.
So there is whenever if you want to work with your AWS services using goto
three you can work in two is using resource as well as client.
Right now.
First, I'm going to take a resource object first.
So to take you a resource of that nothing is that simply, that's it.
Then they suppose if you run this lambda core,
what it has to do, it has to check for your master status.
If it is running, it should not do anything.
If it is not running,
then you need to do some modifications.
So before going to get the information about
your master or your secondary server or your slaves or were.
First of all, you need to get the object of
your EC2 because you are not going to work with multiple,
you're going to work with only one EC2 instance,
one is master and one more is slew.
Now you have to create your objects.
Let me create my primary EC2 instance or you were
muster EC2 instance objects simply from your resource object,
there is an operation called instance for that if you provide your incense ID,
now it is going to create a object.
Now in this audio and averting,
avoid your muster instance information.
Now what do I need to check the status?
So what I am doing is if this status is running,
then I don't want do anything.
Sprint.
Master is up and running.
No need of any modifications.
Else.
If muscle is not running,
then only we need to assign your secondary IP from master to slim.
Now see that.
And now I'm going to create secondaries server object as well, PSI created.
Then let me get my primary server and secondary server network interface information.
Why we need means we are working with your private IP address, right?
So before going to work with your private IP address, first of all,
you should know what is your network and profess information for it was EC2 instance.
Then from the earth, let me yeah, symbol,
let me create 40 watts secondary server also.
Guys, to understand this,
you just run DAR operation on
your primary EC2 instance object and then secondary EC2 instance object.
You will see somewhere operation called network instance information.
Da or operational, you know, help, help, right?
Fine.
So already we have done that in our previous videos.
That's why I am directly writing.
Then let me get for a master and slave network interface ID.
So this is for your secondary server arm slaves are aware interface ID.
Now you have both the things in your hand.
So already we have secondary IP as well.
Now guys, if, for instance,
I mean mastery is running, you don't need to do anything.
If it is not running,
then we are finding your primary server and secondary server network interface ID because
to assign you a secondary IPR on Arsenio secondary IP for your Butler EC2 instance,
first of all, you should know network interface ID.
With Delft network interface ID, you can do that.
Otherwise you can't do it. That's why I got first in
network interface ID for both the servers.
Why we are getting for bodhisattvas means.
From mastered a way to assign your secondary IP,
then that IP we assign it to slip, right?
Fine.
So guys, to assign an unassigned,
there are no direct operations with your resource object.
That's why I'm going to create a client object.
Yes, in the same folder you can use client as well as resource.
Now what I'm being simply,
I'm going to assign an assigned primary server, secondary IP.
Then offer this by this very simple chord, okay?
Now I'm going to assign it to 4y secondary server.
See how I'm assigning based on network interface ID,
even anyone official documentation directly.
You can see this detail information, right?
Fine. We know how to see official documentation as well, right?
Fine.
Now finally, just to return none. Now check.
See for time being just for testing purpose manually,
I'm running this code but you should not done manually automatically, it has to trigger.
So we need to configure that.
I will show you that before that,
let me test it by running.
So I'm creating a test event.
You can provide an interest even as of now and see the output.
Still it is running or yeah.
Now we need to run, right? Yeah. District.
Yes. Up there the output mastery is up and running. Known enough.
Any modifications?
See what I'm doing is I'm going to stop this.
Whenever you stop this.
I mean, generally in real time in case if
something goes wrong with your master and then if it goes down,
then automatically it has to run.
But has no adult as of now we did not that setup manually.
I'm stopping and I'm going to run you work.
Before running your lambda CT,
just check it with the master.
You have a secondary IPS off node.
Now if I run your lambda core,
right, now, just come back with your console and refresh shade.
Now there is no secondary IP with your muster.
It has been moved to your slave weakened check it now by selecting
your slew the object, right?
Fine.
So what I am doing is this thing has to done
automatically whenever if you are EC2 instance master EC2 instance goes down.
So I'm going to do that setup.
Before going to do that setup,
let me reset my settings.
Now I'm going to assign with your master, your secondary IP.
Where is your master? Bed? Right?
1 second.
Let me crosscheck it. Yeah, fine.
This is my master.
Let me assign secondary IP.
And this IP I will update somewhere in
your router and load-balanced or somewhere if you want.
Okay?
So this is not completely real-time requirement from NPN,
but this is the part of your real-time requirement, right?
And let me run you are instance state as well.
Just to wait for some time, it will run.
That's fine.
Just human some time.
Yeah, now it is up and running.
C, actually our requirement is in case if your muscle goes down automatically,
we need to figure out lambda cor.
Well, we can do it simply by creating your CloudWatch Events.
Event is nothing but a data it is going to generate because of some action.
Now whenever if we use u to instance state is changing,
your master EC2 instance rate is changing at that time automatically with genetic data,
that data I want to use to trigger your lambda core.
Nothing is there. Just select your endless CloudWatch,
then go to events,
then gets started, then event pattern,
nothing but if you generate any event,
any data, that data is going to trigger the word quote.
So as of now you are going to work with easy to data, right?
If EC2 instance is going to genetic data,
that data we're going to use to trigger your lambda.
But what is your requirement?
At what time you want to generate the event
whenever EC2 instance steady state is changing,
any state, any medieval Cody,
how taken care whenever,
if your instance that is not running,
then only you are running all instances on only one particular instance,
only master we need to concentrate.
That's why now so let me select master, instance ID.
Copy here.
That's it.
Man art, add target.
So what is the use of add target means?
Suppose if you are easy to instantiate a changing,
this automatically will trigger that.
I mean, it is automatically generating a data.
That data has to trigger something that is nothing but your target.
So I'm selecting our target as.
So what is our lambda code here?
Auto assign, Right?
Let me select our TO assign.
I mean, you know how some Muslim to slave.
Is this one? Yeah.
To slave when Master goes down, yes, fine.
That's now configured data.
Just provide some name.
Ottawa sign I'm giving, right.
Changing secondary IP to write,
chaining, secondary private IP to slip.
That said, if you want write anything,
you can write it enabled, right?
If you want to enable later,
you can disable this as I've known,
but I want to enable creativity. That's done.
Now these first observe that now your setup is there.
Whenever if your mastery is goes down are the time you are also
having a setup to assign your secondary IP to your slave.
As of now, everything is fine, right?
And your secondary IP is also there with the one master just absorbing blow.
Now just I'm doing something called I'm going to change
the your EC2 mustard status to stop.
Whenever if you do this automatically because of your lambda, you are secondary.
Ib will go now signed to see,
now it has this disappear here.
Now there is no secondary before your master.
But if you select your slay,
you see that it has been assigned to you as slave.
Now what you are doing if master goes down at that time,
muscles generating some data,
that data we are simply using to trigger your database lambda function core.
In that code, what we, how we are assigning secondary IP of
your master to slow when muster status is not running.
That's it.
So simply we done that court case in case if you want to use this code in your real time,
what you ought to do is three values you need to remember.
I mean, you need to change three values.
One thing is you are master instance ID,
slave instance ID, and then secondary IP.
What is the secondary we are using to run your master or your sleep?
That's it. The men unquote is sin.
And one more thing, as AV node directly,
I have written your instance ID and your secondary IB inside of your code.
Instead of that, you can also pass you master ID,
slave ID secondary I plaza environment variables so that you can use this code
for anyone just by simply passing your environment details here.
Right?
So as of now I'm doing this one later in next video, right?
We will use that concept,
how to use environment variables for your lambda function.
Right?
Okay, yes. Thank you for watching this video.