Friends here our concept is how to install Python three,
0.8x and Buto three on Linux server.
So here we are installing Python three dots m dot four on Amazon Linux server.
Same steps you can follow on our HCl and sent to a server as well.
Now let me launch a new Amazon Linux server.
So just go to lunch and select anyone of the Amazon Linux.
I'm launching this Amazon Linux server with very basic steps. Just lunch it.
Just wait for some time to get the status as up and running.
And one important point is by default,
you will get one other,
Python Watson Anwar, any Unix or Linux like operating systems.
And don't disturb the existing Python version because
you were operating system depends on that default python.
That's why dont disturb that existing Python.
Then how you can install your required Python on what?
Unix or Linux like servers. It's very simple.
I will show the steps.
No, let me connect with the server.
Now, just check it. Is there any Python or not?
Yes, there is a Python.
Let me check with the Python.
I found, I found watch when there is no Python three.
Let me check with Python three dot seven iPhone, iPhone version.
There is no Python three or seven has been now willing to
install our required Python three dots have 1.4c.
So first switching to route.
Now go to a browser just such like
install Python on Rachel seven.
So just opened the very first link.
So I will provide this link on the goal of this video.
Now, I'm sorry, here,
before installing your Python,
you how to install some dependencies.
So just copy and paste the link.
Then you can go to any location and just I'm going with this location.
So here, just download you are Python 3.1a, 1.4c.
So once it is, don't know debt we just extracted.
It has been extracted.
Now. Go to that.
Extracted Python three dots or 1.4c and then configured with enable optimizations.
So let me copy next step.
Make old install.
See, we are also having make install command,
but if you use that,
there may be a chance to disturb the existing Python Watson,
but if you use may call installed,
it will install alternate Python version.
So it will take some time, you have to wait for that.
So once it is done,
then we will see you are Python three version and p3 Washington.
I'm pausing the video.
Once it is done, then I will show you what it is about two completely installation steps.
So it has been installed, you are required Python and also,
let me remove this node.
Fine. Now, go to see first, let me check it.
Python hyphen, hyphen version.
So we default to dot, dot 16.
We are not disturbing that. No, let me check it.
Python 3.What seven hyphen hyphen Washington.
We installed, but you are unable to get the watchman.
See by default, you are,
Python is installed under user local bin.
Just go to there and list.
So just now we installed this Python 3.1a and you are PIP3.
Right now let me run the industry dot slash python three 0.7. hyphen, hyphen version.
Yes, you are having then dot slash.
Let me check with 3.What seven hyphen, hyphen Washington.
Yes, we have. Now to get easily,
you are Python three and Python pip three,
just I'm creating a soft links under slash bin location.
So just create softening Eleni for less.
Let me take complete path user local bin.
In this we how? Python three dot seven.
So that's I'm going to create a soft drink as Python three.
I am renaming it as Python three is simply.
Now just check with Python three, hyphen, hyphen version.
You are able to get it, you are required Python version.
The same way.
Let me create soft link for P53 as well.
So PIP3, 0.7c, I'm creating under been Location slash bin location.
Now check it. Pip3, hyphen, hyphen Washington.
Let's say. Fine. Now let me enter into Python three terminal.
Say simply if you type Python on your Unix-like systems,
you will enter into your default Python version.
But I need my Python three.
You then type Python three, then enter.
Now here try to import the Buddha three.
Yeah, three is not there because we know that boat or there is
not the default model for your Python, we need to install it.
Now let me install it.
P53. Use p53 if you use simply,
it will install your boat O3 in Python to dot-dot-dot 16, I mean,
in the default Python of your waves,
but we need to install moto three under Python three,
That's why use p53, p63.
Install Bhutto three.
Just I am giving hyphen y for confirmation.
Sorry. I found ways for young, right?
So his P3 just run,
p53, are installed voter three, it has been instrument.
Let me enter into Python three.
Then here tried to import b2,
a3 so that we can verify. Yes, It Is there.
No. Let me show you one more thing.
Let me enter into Python two.
And if I tried to import here moto three,
there is no border that is because we install moto three for Python three.
This is the simple way to install your required Python on your Linux servers.
Thank you.