Friends here we are discussing about moto three concepts.
The core concepts of Bhutto three or like session,
resource, client, meta, collections, waiters, and paginated.
So if you want to work perfectly with your bot 2-3 to work with
your elements RV says you have to know all these concepts for time being.
We are working with the session and resource and declined.
Let me go with the first concept of your Bhutto three, that is session.
So simply, it is an AWS management console in our TMS.
So in our previous video,
we will discuss these concepts to work with particular AWS service.
First, you had to get aid and his management console.
Then you ought to enter into your, I am concerned.
Now to create your adolescent management console,
we are following this syntax.
So this is nothing but a session.
We got your AWS management console session using router cone.
It can also create your database management console with particular IAM account.
That is nothing but a session.
You can take this variable name as session
or your database management console itself. No problem.
C.
And you are creating the session,
your analysts management console by providing
some profile name which is configured on your host.
So while configuring profile names on our host,
we are passing credentials programmatic access keys.
That means you are session stores configuration information.
And using this session,
we can create either resource or client objects or services.
And moto three creates a default session for us when needed.
As of now, I am not touching about default session.
We'll discuss it later.
See, let me do one thing.
Suppose I want to create a session.
I want to create a Dulles management console
using root profile name or using some easy to develop her.
See, we created, we configure different profile names right?
Now, let me create AWS management console for root account.
Yes, simply Bhutto 3.What session North session.
Then there's simply providing a profile name.
Suppose I am providing group profile.
You can also create your AWS management console using your Butler IAM profiles.
Suppose Bhutto three dot session,
session profile name equals two.
Suppose we have easy to dollar per asthma.
So likewise, you can create any number of sessions in
your one Python Bhutto transcript that is based on requirement.
We can create a number of sessions.
Okay, for timing, I'm commenting this.
We have only root session route.
With root, we created AWS management console.
That's it.
Then the next concept is the resource and declined.
C.
These two either resource our client objects,
or useful to create particular AWS service console.
Like I am console are easy to console are SNS console or DynamoDB console or RDS console.
Whatever the console you want to create,
you have to use either resource or client.
From US session object,
session I was getting nothing but you are AWS management console object from this.
Suppose I want to create, I am console.
And you can create this IAM console by using either resource or client.
Now to differentiate that I'm taking I-I am console using
a resource object equals to your AWS management console session using root,
not resource, you can provide your resource name here.
You can also write some option here called service underscore name equals two.
I am, even if you skip that, no problem.
And you can also provide here region name.
In case if you don't provide any region aim here,
it will select the default region which is there in the config file under dot AWS.
Say for this particular profile,
whatever the default region is there in your conflict,
both profile config file that
default agent it will select if you want to work with some other region name,
you can provide your region name.
Suppose I want to work with us east to and therefore I am,
you don't have any I mean,
there is no need to take any region him here, right.
You can go with the default region name.
But for any other services,
right, you have to sell at region name.
That's it.
And same IAM console,
you can also create using client object.
So same syntax.
The only thing is instead of a resource,
you have to select the hard to type client.
That's it.
So you are having two types of options to create your particular AWS man,
you particular AWS service console.
Then which one is better?
So before going into that,
let me show you one thing.
Let me enter into my Python terminal.
I'm creating, I'm inputting Bhutto three.
And I am creating my session AWS management console session with the root.
And first let me show you what are the available options on this.
You know, in Python we how BAR OR method to list out operations available on an object.
C first thing in this,
you have different types of options.
As of now I want to show you only something,
some options, few options.
So u one is client.
So from this, you can create a client object or you can create resource object.
But now here my requirement is different.
Let me take this operation.
So I am printing AWS management console
or session with root dot, get available resources.
C, the output.
So resource object operation is available only for these services.
But do you know any AWS you are having a lot of services for remaining services,
you don't have resource option.
Now, by default for all services of AWS,
client is available, but resources are available only for these services.
Right now you have a confusion,
at least for these services,
which option we have to use,
either resource or client.
It can go with anyone of that.
But there is a small difference.
That is, the foster point is resources high-level object.
And it is available for some of these available services.
These are the some of the AWS services and climb these low-level service access.
What is this difference?
Very simple.
Inclined, the output is in terms of a dictionary.
In each and every stage.
If it is dictionary,
you have to do more work while implementing your Python Bhutto press kits.
But in resource it is an object.
You can do some dot operations using resource operation for your particular AWS service.
And in resource, there is no guarantee that each and
every operation of your particular service is available.
But in client, each and every operation,
whatever it is there on your AWS console.
Say suppose if you go with I am console,
you are having here lot of operations.
All these operations are definitely available with your client.
But in resource, that guarantee is not there.
If it is not there,
we can enter into client from resource with the help of
meta concept of your boat to three,
we have metal concept right here.
Using that metta, you can enter into client from resource.
But as of now, don't get confused. Forget about that.
Right now, let me show you with an example.
How much work is there with your client and how much work is there with resource?
Let me implement simple script.
So now we owe you or AWS management console session.
And the how I am concerned with respect to resource object.
Anyhow, I am console with respect to client object.
First time implementing a.
I'm listing I am users with resource object.
So for resource already how an object I am client connect,
I am consoled with respect to resource.
See that for each user in
your IAM console resource dot users dot all.
Then simply print each user.name.
That's it.
Let me copy it.
Open my simple difference.
With a resource and client dot PY two list1.
Paul, I am users.
Let me save it first.
And I'm running this for C, the output.
So you are getting, you are to IAM users
now to get the same output through client object.
How we can implement.
So for that first I'm entering into my Python terminal.
So there I am importing Bhutto 3 first.
Then I am creating your AWS management console session.
Then I'm creating IAM console using client object.
Now see the output step-by-step.
So first if I try to print I am console client object C,
the output. You are getting.
Object, or sorry.
Now in this object you how to perform an operation called L2 users.
See that, don't worry about the all these operations, okay,
we have a session to get help on each and every step on Bhutto three,
we'll discuss that in the next video.
See, this is a dictionary.
In this dictionary, user sees them.
Now let me do one more thing.
Let me take a user's key.
Now see the output.
You are getting a list, right?
If you're getting a list means you can take for loop for each in IAM console up to this.
And printed output, see the reserve, print each.
You are getting part the username, user id.
Of course you are getting inform indifferent informations for your each IAM user.
But I need only username,
but means you have to take dictionary again,
dot user name, Laozi, the output C.
Now, what we are doing there is the first step we are doing.
Let me implement the code here.
Listing IAM users with client object plaint operation.
Okay?
So all users that it taken right here,
for each in, in this,
you are taking users, right?
Then, see that you are printing.
So it is simply username dot c. You are taking i am console resource dot us.org dot
operations because this resource is like an object operations.
But here you are doing first of all, dot list users,
that is one level object operation then offer that you are
taking some key because this output is a dictionary.
And again, this is not a final output.
So that's why again, you are taking you each,
then you are selecting username.
That's it.
But he had simple operation,
dot, dot, dot, right?
So this is the only difference.
Now let me go to your Python script.
Let me open just
for our differentiation purpose I'm taking.
And then that's it.
Now let me run this output.
You are getting same output.
But the thing is,
you are using onetime client on one time and resource.
That's it.
So while implementing these code,
you have a Help also will discuss that help in the next video.
Okay, thank you.