Hello again you wonderful God people.
And welcome to a food fight which is going to be a 3D action game based around the joy of throwing food
at robots.
They don't hit you with food which is something they think we can.
All right OK.
I want to make a 3D action game.
I didn't really want to use guns so were using food.
I'm really looking forward to this game as a lot of suffering to delve into here.
So let's take a look at our essential experience when I think about the word food fight.
I'm seeing it a fast frantic and cheerful game about throwing food while avoiding being hit by more
food.
Right.
And the key words here are fast frantic cheerful throwing and avoiding.
So if we put those together we get this.
There's one more thing I'm going to bring in though and that's character customization.
Now this isn't technically part of the sensual experience unless we make a special effort for it.
But we do want to be thinking about this right at the beginning.
Character customization is a lot like multi player in that it's a lot easier to put in if you're designing
the game from scratch with an in mind than it is to add in later.
If we design the entire game and then cybernaut character customization to come in we're going to have
our work cut out for us.
And from that beginning you can see that I've got this kind of game right.
We've got very cheerful wording lots of bright colours we're using lots of low poly high contrast or
high colour or Hillary and I describe these colours but they're fun.
We've got current customization with two possible characters in here.
Right.
With male and female and we show you how you can do that and find the appearance you want bring them
into the game.
And we've got these fun little robots that are throwing random food at people and we're dealing with
collisions for furniture food have already died.
And that's fantastic.
And that's it.
It's a lot of fun.
There's a lot of cool things going to be doing here and some great God techniques including blending
animations character customization.
I'm really looking forward to that section.
So let's dive right into it.