Hello again, you incredible got two people in this video, WRC, a brand new section, and we are about
to move from Tudi to the world of 3D because God can do both.
And I quite enjoyed working in 3D.
I'm looking forward to this.
And we can be making a game called Cube Dude kick about now before any further.
Let me show you my prototype of Cubitt.
You kicked me out some just stop here.
And this is a local to play off multiple local to play game, local multiplayer game so I can use WSI
data on this character.
Cazares with this one.
And it's just a very simple physics based game with some fun effects and.
There we go.
Lots of fun things happening.
So let's begin with designing what the game is going to be.
And as always, I want to welcome the game's essential experience.
Now, when I'm thinking of this game, I'm thinking the cube did kick about is a fast, fun and playful
local blame.
Noko multiplayer game to play is trying compete to score the most goals.
I don't usually like reading slides out like that.
But what are the key words here?
Well, fast, fun, playful local multiplayer and compete.
Now one of these words isn't that useful for what?
Fun to think about fun.
It is not great feedback.
If I say you make your game more fun, you don't actually need to do is remove fun from the equation.
And what we're left with is will design a game that is fast, playful, local multiplayer and is a competition.
So with that done, let's get to the next video and start creating our first 3D game together.