Hello again, you wonderful go to people.
And welcome to this new section, Food Fight, which is gonna be our more advanced 3D game.
In this video, we're going to plan food fight.
I must show you a quick example of the kind of thing we can make by the intersection.
That's from the previous version of this course.
So there will be some changes happening to talk about our sint experience.
Let's start with our essential experience whenever making a game, as you know by now.
That's wrong to start with.
So I'm thinking that I want a fast, frantic game about throwing food.
What about while avoiding being hit by more food?
Primarily, I wanted to make something with the kind of feel of a third person shooter.
But I don't really feel like I'm in a shooting.
People in the head with guns kind of a place.
I'm kind of over that whole gameplay mechanic.
So what are keywords here?
Well, we have fast, frantic, cheerful, throwing food and avoiding being hit.
Which gives us this little shot here.
I also want to add in some some basic character customization players.
We will pick between two different measures, two different characters, and select a color scheme top
to and select color scheme to really make it theirs.
So let me show you the kind of thing what to make.
So just jump in here.
I'm going to begin.
I'm going to pick Frey and let's not pick a random color scheme that will jump in.
And here we are in food fight.
We have these lovely little robots trying to kill me, shooting food at me.
And I have to hit the robots three times each to get rid of them, which is surprisingly hard to do.
That's being hit myself.
I have one life left and I'm down.
So quite difficult.
I did manage to hit one, but you can see here we've got a lot of cheerfulness happening.
I demand a rematch.
We'll try it one more time.
This is what we're making.
So take a look at what you see on the screen.
We have these fun flying, almost shooting gallery pedestrian's going on here.
We have these very simple robots throwing randomise 3-D food at us.
We have this piece of furniture that fly around the room and quite a fun little 3-D space.
So looking forward to getting started.
And I'll see you in the next video.