Hi Folks you can hear and welcome in this section.
We're going to start actually making a game.
We restored got oh we've got the right version.
We're ready to go.
So what kind of game are we making and why in this section we're going to be making a word game now.
At first glance this may not seem like a big deal but bear with me because we feel that this is essential
to get into your grasp as soon as possible.
I know that getting something into your grasp isn't an expression but let's pretend it is in order to
make really good games and understand an engine.
It's critical that you understand key concepts early right.
So we're going to really focus on jeanie's script at the end of the section.
Ben we'll focus on C sharp and make a game that doesn't focus on things like graphics and level design
and collision and movement and all the other things like let's just make a game focussing on how the
engine works.
So how we're going to do that.
The game going to be make is called lunar eclipse and it's based on the game Mad Libs.
We're not calling our game ad libs because that is a copy written name that I'm not violating intellectual
property but it's going to be based on similar ideas.
If you're not familiar with Mad Libs it works like this.
There's a party and two of us are playing at any given time one of us has a story written here and you
can't read it so here is my story.
And on my story I have blanks that you have to fill in.
You're not allowed to see the story.
I'm going to ask you to fill the Mets it's say things like Can I have a name.
Can I have a feeling.
Can I have a place.
And we'll write them in and then I'll read the story that you've just written.
Our game is going to do that.
So before we go any further think about that and ask yourself how do I want the player to feel if you
followed the boardgame course you'll know that I'm a big fan of the concept of the essential experience
to me that's the most important thing in a game right.
How does the player feel and what do I do to make that happen.
So that's my task.
I would like you to think if we're going to have a word game based on Mad Libs called lynley Lips.
What's the essential experience I want to have.
Now there isn't a wrong answer here except I didn't think about it so.
Pause the video.
Come up with how you'd like the players to feel.
And when you come back I'll share mine.
All right.
Time to dig out the trusty white board so I'm calling it looney lips because I think it's a fun name
for about tall tales for a while but lonely lips is a better name and I'm going for a very simple experience.
I'm going for a goofy party right.
I want players to feel like this is silly and frivolous and anything can happen and it's fun.
In fact I'm going to give linae lips a little unofficial logo.
You don't have to have a copy of my logo.
Here's someone sticking their tongue out looking slightly grumpier than I meant.
But that's the feeling I'm going for.
I want a goofy party game something where a bunch of people are going to get together and just make
each other laugh.
That's some going for I'd love to hear your ideas if you came with something different maybe you're
coming up something a bit more sinister or something a bit more gritty.
That's great.
Love to hear them.
Now let's look at the requirements for the game.
What do we need to make happen for this scheme to work.
Well our game requirements are based on the fact that this is a word game.
So the first thing we need to do is get words from the player and these words have to have a prompt.
So I have to ask you for a noun or a verb.
Or if you prefer someone's name a thing a place an action.
Right.
I need to ask you for something and take that input.
I then need to have a story that I can plug those words into.
I want this to be an expandable game I want these stories to be easy to add to so you might start with
two or three and then write more and more and again should just be able to just take those and expand
without them to do anything more.
So that's what we're going to be making at the end of it you're going to have something looks a bit
like this.
And I'm really excited to see how your game turns out.
What kind of stories you come up with and to show you how much fun this energy can be.
So without further ado let's get started in the next video.