Hello you.
Gloria's wonderful and lovely God.
Happy for all of you at the same time Yanni.
And I just thought it'd be a nice idea at it where you probably know who I am.
You've heard my voice quite a lot because you did it.
You made it through the course.
I just thought it might be nice to wrap up by talking about all the things we've looked at so far.
By the time you reach the end of this course by it's I mean watching this we have gone on quite a journey
we started off very very simply with learning.
Right we're talking about variables.
Dictionaries are raise very basic concepts of what's a signal What's a function and then very quickly
we start improving.
Right we had happy days quite simple little platform Gameboy we add in things like lives college collision
masks and layers tile maps and then ice Meister's where we can start doing things like very basic line
of sight.
Lot cogeneration object oriented programming onto 3D with Cube did kick about playing with physics and
rigid bodies and static bodies and all the other fun things we can do three particles and then finally
into a food fight.
I really enjoyed this process and I hope you did too.
And I'd love to see not only what you've been making throughout this course but what you make next.
Please do stay in touch.
Share what you do.
Discord in our Facebook group on our community pages.
We'd love to keep in touch and what you do.
I hope you've enjoyed the God.
And you know I hope you continue to enjoy the kind of engine that you use it for professional games
hobby games indeed games education presentations whatever else you decide to do with it.
Finally on behalf of all here game dev thank you so much for joining us on the journey and excellent
work.
I have seen you in the previous videos and I hope to see you in another one.