Learning to code by making games is a great idea.
Some game engines get in your way and some languages are a little bit hard to grasp at first.
We've got the solution to that for you.
My name is Ben tristam founder of game live TV with over 400000 happy game development students and
I've teamed up with I'm an old friend of Ben's.
We've known each other for decades.
I have a master's in science education and I'm passionate about teaching game design.
Ben and I have discovered the God game engine an open source free versatile streamlined firm and easy
to use engine that can make amazing 2D and 3D games.
And we think that you should join us on this journey to learn this amazing game engine.
Ben who is this for.
Well if you're a complete beginner in coding or you're a complete beginner in game engines or both then
this course is ideal for you we're going to be teaching you game development and coding in a python
like language from scratch.
And how are we going to pull that off.
We'll pull that off by learning to code.
By making games godo is really fun and it doesn't get in your way and it shows you all the information
you need at that time and only at that time and g.d. Script the language I'll be teaching it in is based
on Python.
The world's most popular programming language which is incredibly fluid and very easy to use.
So this is not our first rodeo.
We've taught hundreds of thousands of people how to do this.
Just check out the reviews of the course.
The students are already taking it so.
Precisely how we're going to do this.
What are the first three games.
The first three games start with Luni lips fun simple word game to teach you the basics of coding and
how to use the engine.
We're going to move on to our very personable and charming platform game 2D platform game lots of fun
very colourful.
Great way to figure out how the engine plugs together.
Then tense top down stealth game.
Lots of sneaking around with lights and shadows and very advanced techniques and from They'll move on
to 3D.
Awesome and for the shop developers amongst you I'll be converting all of these projects to see shop
for you as well.
So this is going to be an awesome journey.
Please join Yahn and eye on this course right now.