Welcome back.
Marvellous God.
People in this video will make the background awesome.
We're going to look at parallax backgrounds which are really fun and easy doing god.
By the end of this video you're going to have self repeating textures that move at different rates so
that our background is not only awesome it makes us feel like we're going really fast before we go any
further let's have a quick refresher on what parallax means parallax.
That phenomena where objects seemed to be in different positions based on our viewing angles.
Imagine you are travelling you're in a car or a train.
You're in the passenger window you can look up the side you go through the countryside and what you
can see is our whole bunch of green in the background.
We can see lots of trees right.
That would be a nice dark green here they are.
In the foreground there are some bushes.
The Bushes are going past so fast they're a blur.
The trees are hardly moving.
This is parallax parallaxes really useful and some key concepts to bear in mind.
First the close of play is the faster it moves.
So the background layers should move very slowly in the foreground as you move very quickly.
Secondly the faster player moves the faster the player will feel like they're going again.
If the foreground barely moves along we're going to feel like we're tiny in hardly moving but if it's
zipping past we going to feel like we're riding the wind in God so we're going to control the speed
of a parallax layer through scale.
As a theory let's look at this in practice.
You'll notice I've drawn in a few more platforms in here with my tile map I just went in here and drew
some in.
That's mostly just so I can play around.
I was just thinking was a bit small.
I wanted some more height to my level.
Great.
So when do they open the camera scene.
And if you can't remember how to open a scene just remember this little film clack board thing whatever
it's called and within carroty I'm going to create a new child.
Note that child note is going to be a parallax background.
You need a parallax background before you put any parallax layers in parallax backgrounds.
If we take a look at the the inheritance inherit from canvas layers to canvas those are really useful
because they don't inherit position information which means if I need something to always be in a certain
position on screen it doesn't matter what the parent node thinks is happening.
It'll always be in that position on screen.
Well would making a background.
So it always wants to be in that place within our palicki background were going to create a parallax
layer.
And we need the Panix to be displaying something so let's make a sprite.
OK.
What Sprite are we going to make.
Well that's good too.
Graphics into G effects and in the background.
The very first thing I would do is b.g. lay out one that's going to go into textures cover things I
want to do the first things I'm going to offset and switch off centreing centreing is on it's going
to find the.
It's going to find the transform the position of the Sprite and at the 0 0 it's going to centre it.
I don't want to centre some sound off and now it's going to start at 0 0 and extend down right.
The next thing I need to do is go into the parallax layer an open motion.
Now if I press play right now.
In fact I can show you if I press play right now what I have is a rather fetching blue square in the
background that stubbornly stops.
Well that's not really the effect I'm looking for.
I want this to repeat itself and way we would do that is with this mirroring her mouseover you'll see
if the axis is set to zero it will not mirror.
Otherwise it's going to mirror every time we get to a certain pixel count.
So what I need is the size of this image.
Right click on it over here and the file manager do schadt show in file manager not shower and file
manager don't Sharon the fund manager is unhygienic.
Right click on it properties and other details.
There it is 2048 by 2048.
I realize that's going be different on Linux and Mac.
I apologize for that.
I'm pretty sure that you can find that but if you can't.
This image is 2048.
By 2040 it right.
So I want to mirror on the x axis by 2048.
I'm not just going to mirror on the X axis for this one because this is my pure background because if
I do then I suddenly have this transparent grey in the background so that's mirror on the Y as well.
And now we have is Infinite's blue plane.
We don't have a parallax background yet but let's face it it's already much better than that strange
grey colour.
Now one the do is of duplicate this parallax layer and then change the textures that for right click
on it.
I can see the shortcut is for that.
And Windows as control.
The sun's going to control deep three times why three times I have three more layers on each Sprite.
I'm just going to.
Also.
Well it looks like.
Remember.
Put it in texture.
Don't put it in a normal map.
Very nice.
Okay.
So if I go in here now I now have a much better looking background texture.
Couple of things will notice one I'm way too high on the map to all the layers are moving at the same
speed.
Well that's not ideal.
It looks better but it's not parallax.
It's an improvement.
But what I want is for these things to move at different speeds.
That's where that parallax effect is going to come from.
And remember that that speed is controlled in scales on each parallax layer.
The closer it is the faster it is higher number as far as leave the front layer is one and the next
layer.
Two point eight.
And on behind that point six there's no point in doing anything to this layer because when look at the
Sprite.
It's just a blue background.
It's not going to change.
Well first off there's something very odd happening up here.
Right.
But will now see that the various layers are moving at different speeds.
Awesome.
Why are we getting that would affect.
There's a couple reasons.
The first is I shouldn't be mirroring anything except for the background.
Right.
This blue line here you know just to make this easy.
It's ruining this background.
So now an easel a background that's one referring to palicki lair therefore is mirroring on the y axis.
That means it's repeating on the vertical.
I don't want that to happen that's what it is.
Let's put that to zero and do the same for Panix Lear three and two.
Secondly they're all kind of low down.
If I press play again.
You see that that actually start until get way down here.
So let's move them all up by I don't know what sounds good.
Let's go crazy.
So palace to let you do negative 1000 on the y axis because negative is up.
And I'm sure I do that to all of them.
I'm using offset by the way.
That just means okay here's the location of the node.
Now just nudge it in this direction so I am using offset negative y 1000.
That means nudge this up by a thousand.
UPS 1000 not 100.
Now I said all of them.
I dont mean background.
Theres no detail there so wont look any different.
Okay much better and was a bit much wasn't it.
So let's tweak that down too.
I don't know 750 750 sounds like a good number.
Negative 750.
Whoops I didn't actually do it.
And again over here.
Making sure the actually click where you mean to click.
Me with my mad mouse skills today.
And I promise I will never say the words mad mouth skills ever again.
Awesome.
So here we go.
And we are now moving and haven't moved vertically you'll see that this blue line here is moving faster.
We are gesturing a little aren't we.
Let's go to project settings and fix that project settings quality.
Pixel snap on.
And what to see and actually work a little better.
Yeah I have that weird juddering I was having just now.
Still not great.
We can fix the femora a little later.
But there we go.
We are moving now when we get down to here there's going to be a problem.
Now part of the reason that's happening when I get down here and I fall off the edge is because these
textures are moving quite fast repeating quite fast.
If I go and I change the Y scale to one on all the letters.
They're not going to get that huge movement every time I jump which I quite like.
And I'm also not going to see that big changing colour right there which make mcfall stratification.
I can't remember that weird thing a funny thing can do is on parallax background under scroll.
Let's take a ignore camera and see what happens.
You see this hard line over here as I move towards it.
Things pop into existence.
Why are they doing that.
Well with ignore camera switched off.
What it's doing is looking at the camera zoom in and applying that to the size of the texture which
means the size of the textures now wrong.
So we need to check it's on.
That means we can change the Zune to our heart's content and this will always look good.
Final thing I want to do is right click on this and do save brushless seeing what that's going to do
is take all of these child notes and move them to their own scene and turn this into an instance as
opposed to just part of camera today camera Judy uses the camera.
It's not really the same thing as Parallax background so right click on to save Brusher scene and call
it pollacks background.
And now the camera is a camera which instances in the parallax background that can move that and do
what I want with it.
And we now have a rather fancy looking background in our shiny shiny level.
I do feel like I should tweak some of these platforms because I keep falling and having to reshoot these
things.
But look we now have parallax.
Now we can change the speed of these tweets a little bit.
So let's say into character Deep Impact background.
You're not now going to scale up one you're going to scale at one point five not 15.
That's crazy talk.
Let's see how that works.
And you just zoomed past.
That's actually a fun little high.
But I want to call it one point twenty five.
There we go.
Parallax there behind it is going to be one and the one behind that is going to be point five actually
not just to the from one as one point five one point five one point five.
This is going to feel like we're just flying along like this and go.
There it is.
That's actually a little bit fast for me.
But tweet these values so that they feel good to you.
And that brings us to the end of the video in this video.
We've created a parallax background node and started using parallax layers on our parikh's background
to get that thing in there.
Now remember you can put anything on there you could just put little puffs of blue or even particle
effects and have really cool things.
Great work.
We now have a great looking background and our game is to look really completes a fantastic job not
seeing the next video.