Hello again you wonderful God people in this video we're going to start building our level playing with
walls windows doorways doors all that good stuff.
And I want to talk to you a little bit of our feature called grid map.
This is a node we haven't seen yet and I'm at about why it's awesome but why are we not going to use
it for this game to grid map or not to grid map.
Well let's begin with what's a grid map.
And I think the easiest thing to do is to show you.
So what it would do is a make a new scene.
I'm going to my models into architecture.
Let's turn snapping on to make this easier it's going to bring in a wall.
So here is a I need a parent that that's like a spatial node not gonna save the scene because not keeping
it here is a wall that's rename it wall.
And let's make it awesome by giving it a convex static body mass.
So it is now a static body with a parent of a mesh.
So it's a solid wall.
And let's make this more interesting by making a doorway to some drag a doorway and call it doorway.
Do do do.
And I mean give this one a tremendous try convex.
No it actually blocks the door which is not what I want to undo that and try mesh.
Awesome.
OK.
Now you remember to deal and we made tile maps and how amazing tarmac's were.
Well God has something called a grid map so I can convert this to a meshel library.
Just saving the roof fall for now because I don't think keeping this big test meshel up and when I go
back into my scene I can create a new node.
And this note is called a grid map grid map is a 3D tile map.
So if I bring in this mesh library I've just made I now have some 3D tiles.
Now this is a little different from 2D because we have to worry about axes and positioning all the rest.
But if I press Q and E I can move this grid up and down so I can change where this exists.
I can also rotate on various axes so if I want to rotate on the y axis looking straight down this green
on the gizmo I can press yes some eye wall can rotate.
And this is a really great way to build a level I mean look at this.
We can just you know looks good here and here and you know spot a doorway and you can live right here.
And so far this is truly awesome.
However we need the right tool for the right job this get out of the grid for now.
So yes while at the moment this is awesome I can go into the game and realize that everything is twice
the size I need it to be and I can fix that.
I mean I can get through the door.
I can't hit a wall.
Look we've got this weird thing happening here.
That's not the only problem we have.
We also have an issue if I want to do a corner on the other way and show why.
And I got here anx keep placing grits.
Boop.
If I continue the wall over this way this wall is going to vanish.
Why is this wall vanishing.
Well we need to understand how tile maps and Grid Maps work and what's happening is we have a single
node a single map and God is saying at this position x is 5 y is minus two whatever it might be.
We're placing tile no this time but one zero one time or one with this rotation.
If I look at the pieces look at the origin the origin is in the corner right.
This is true of most of Kennie's assets currently.
So it have to go into a blender and convert the origin to be in the centre which is doable.
We can absolutely do that.
And there's tools like.
And it's called batch AFB x something like that f the X exporter which allows us to convert these things
as a single batch and then we can export them into godda not as x f x files but that's a different story.
However even if we do that we have another problem and that's why michail if I duplicate the doorway
and you press controlled me and I rotate it right.
These are not squares of a place this manually.
They'll be fine.
But if I was placing them on the corner on the origin rather it would place here.
And that's going to cause some serious issues.
Right now the origin is here so it's kind of lining up but not really a line up that way.
But it won't line up this way.
It is trying to do that.
And the reason is Grid Maps really need squares right.
The x and z should really be the same size.
It doesn't work great for rectangles.
It works better for squares.
Obviously I'm working in 3D.
I don't mean rectangles and squares I mean cubes and cuboid.
But hopefully you understand I'm saying let's put this as a slide.
If we're making architecture 3-d we can absolutely use Grid Maps.
And if you're working on a tile based level where you've got at least two of your three axes the same
size.
These are awesome.
But we do still have the option of placing things manually.
It's not quite as simple and versatile as a grid map but it can give us much cleaner results.
In our case we will not be using Grid Maps.
They're not great for walls that aren't so blocks we have thin walls.
If we did want to grid map we need the origin to be centred at least on the x and z axis it doesn't
matter too much of is not centred on the Y on the up or down.
Access but we do want it on the left you right back we forward one.
And yes I realize I've done I'll be dalley left you right back you forward.
But only so grown up I can be in in one sitting.
And also ideally our message should be square right so great for floor tiles or if you're doing a city
block something like that they're fantastic or if you're doing something like a bunch of furniture or
it doesn't really matter that the corners are going to be great.
You want a sort of eclectic thing.
So I'm not keeping this seat.
So don't say that and I'm going to delete my grid map and if I try and delete this file now it's going
to complain oh no it's being used by template.
It's not.
But I haven't saved my template so let's save template and delete it.
OK.
Now this desk is the wrong size and reassured scale this down to what he thinks zero point seventy five.
Maybe let's see what that looks like.
Zero point seventy five and press play.
Nope.
I've also scaled the collision option should never do that.
That's probably a point five.
I just want to idea of how to scale the fetcher compare to the person because the assets were made by
different people.
I'm expecting the scales to be little different as your point.
I was a little small but we can play that later.
For now I'm going to leave the desk because I want to make level one and this is the template Not every
level is going to have a desk in it.
Maybe I don't know.
So let's make a new scene new inherited scene and going inherit from level template and right now.
If I save up a template that desk all vanish or some rename install level 1.
Alright.
Save a little libs a sailor one.
There we go.
See you back to level template.
And I want a new container and just a new node.
I've got furniture and every level I also have a empty node which I put up here called walls.
What's in that is going to be different for every level.
But for now here's a wall slip now.
I quite like the idea of every element having its own scene.
Some have a wall scene and all the rest.
Let's go to models and you see what mean models architecture.
Door scene.
Dunno why it's called doorway panelling Wall Wall doorway and all the rest of it.
Let's start with a window and slag on there and it looks like I have to scale these by zero point five.
Do this before anything else happened so let's skip out right now zero point five zero point five point
five.
Are you the right heights.
Maybe you know what I need a little above zero as a result don't I.
Let's see.
Yeah that's a good size.
OK.
So let's get the wall to where we think it lives it lives.
Their zero point one.
That kind of makes sense right.
Zero point to.
And I'm gonna call this a windowsill because we have two windows were a window and a window so let's
give that a simple collision and mash create convex static body.
You now have a static body great.
You are a fixed wall.
If I run this scene just the scene and I have a wall that I can run into.
I can't see through because I haven't see the thing transparent.
That's fine.
I feel like my mouse sensitivity could be a little better but great.
One would do is right click on it and do save branch as seen.
I'm going to go into my scenes create a new following here right click on here.
Do you follow what I call this architecture architectural fantastic window sill done.
And now this is a scene right so this is going to be usable in all future seems.
Back to my walls.
Let's bring it all up and look.
Now my wall is way too big.
That's fine.
Because I can go into here really at all and do the same thing.
So transform zero point five like five point five and translation on the y axis.
You're actually in the right place that's fantastic.
And if I put my snapping back on I should be able to make these line up perfectly.
I can't because the snapping is taking place where I placed it so that's fine let's figure out the zit
you are going to live on is 0 0 just for now.
I move you to zeroes as well.
And now I can move along the grid.
That turns out my grid is the wrong size for the asset.
I can fix that in a second but there's my wall.
Let's see the same thing for door and you know I might just speed this up.
Okay they're all in and they're all safe so I want to do and select all of them holding shift and clicking
on all of them.
You move into the exact same place.
Translation 0 0 0.
Fantastic.
Now let's translate them on wine by zero point two.
So up to the floor.
Great.
And I'm wishing I separate them because I'm snapping.
It's a little bit easier now.
The grade is not actually an ideal size for this so I will be turning the grid off in a bit but for
now let's just look at our assets.
That's awesome.
So I run this scene just seeing like a live one.
We now have the beginning of a level.
Can I fit through this doorway.
I can.
That's perfect just the right size.
I've got this nice wood panelling in front and actually decal and I can decide which side I want the
inside of the house to peel the inside of the building or whatever of love's going to be so let's make
a simple level because these are all scenes I feel pretty good about duplicating them.
And you'll notice this floor is absolutely colossal.
We don't have to use the full thing the way I want the levels to work is I want the player to be on
one side the non player characters on the other end in the middle and have bystanders who are going
to get in the way.
Are going to block shots so I'm actually going to cut this off and take my wall.
LH move it over here.
I'm going to just rotate this by 90 degrees I'm snapping so it's going to work quite well.
Do you get that.
We're not actually snapping correctly.
Why.
Well that's going to transform.
Got to configure snap.
We are currently snapping by units of one meter.
These walls are not one meter across there one point something that's changed to zero point five and
see if that's better.
And yes it is OK.
And just double check I take this double wide door.
Want a rotated by 90 degrees.
A United degrees.
Yes you are moving over here and look at the fact that it's looking pretty awesome.
So now I'm just going to start duplicating these a bit more so let's put you here and I feel like a
couple more so duplicate.
Duplicate and I've got the snap on and I'm just using these arrows and looking very cool.
I think when you think a little bit more apsey A little bit more depth.
So now with a whole shift from wall to wall five we duplicate that.
And it's starting to come together as an okay.
I do want some windows.
So let's put a few winners in fact that might be a little too much depth.
Yes a little bit too much at some of the elite.
You don't need you.
And now let's take a window window sill.
Window sill wedge the boop boop do windowsill directly you know your eye here.
It's at the top.
Good.
Don't mind me just having a moment delete you by delete you know rotate you.
Goodness me any more coffee this morning.
By 180 degrees.
For some reason my brain is simply not working right now but that's fine.
Movie to here.
Great.
So here's my challenge for you.
I'd like you to continue what we've been doing and just make it simple level.
And don't worry about decorating it just define the boundary.
Figure out which side of the wall you want.
How many windows you want.
What's going to look like an attempt to put doorways for Bison's come through pause the video you'll
do you'll ever.
And when you come back I'll show you what I've made.
And welcome back.
Okay so here's my level and you're not sure show it you running as.
Get in here.
It's nice and long.
It kind of reminds me of a tennis court.
To be honest which is really the fee I'm going for.
Now we do have an issue right now where the camera will go through the wall but that's okay.
I don't mind that I can work around that later.
Just nice and simple.
I've got a door here for the buy sell to come through and I will be putting in a collision wall so that
the player won't be able to cross this line and.
I will also be in the back of the plane never goes far enough back to clip through this wall so kind
of claustrophobic kind of tight.
What I'm looking for.
I have the option of making this wider and because of the way we've set this up.
Level 2 doesn't have to look anything like this.
Which brings us to the end of this video in this video.
We've looked at a couple of major things.
The first is what's a grid map.
Is it the right choice for this game.
The second is how do we make a simple level.
So don't forget to share the levels you've made.
I'm dying to see how your game is progressing and excellent work.
I'll see you in the next video.