Hello again you phenomenal go to people in this video.
Let's add some guards.
Make a brand new NPC and play with inheritance.
So before we do that let's talk about what's going to happen with these gods.
I'm going to instance a character.
So we've got the character seem willing to make a new instance of that.
We're going to extend the play detections script we finished on the camera going to change the sprite
and add a torch.
So it's pretty simple.
Before we go into that though we have currently been building this template level.
But this is not a template if this is the template level every level starts like this.
So what I'm to do is I'm going to delete the cameras from here because otherwise they can never be moved
and leave this note here for cameras while we're at it let's add in a new node which is a simple node
there it is.
And I'm gonna call this gods.
So every level must have a tile map a player a camera 2D canvas modulate the thing changes how dark
the level is.
And a place to put cameras in gods.
We can instance them in separately.
We can also start removing all of it.
So let's move the plaque.
Yeah we're going to the player W to get into move mode.
We could just press this button here and drag the player into this top left corner and now he'll take
my Tom up and make a little box of the player.
Pick the right one your wall and I'm going to select with Control B do a nice big marquee selection
get the Tom up and erase the selection.
I will do the same thing here.
So go to select and erase.
So if you want to know how to do fills in the races that's how you do it.
You can also do fills that back to paint tile but that's not good.
So say that.
Now I want to make a new scene that inheritance when you've seen new inherited scene and I'm inheriting
from the template right open based seat.
So I don't have to type it in using to open that and here's my new one.
I know it's the new one because as unsafe.
So let's save that safe scene as it's in levels and I'll call this level 1.
Now you'll see everything is great out right.
These are the things that I cannot change but I can go to the tile map and start making changes like
this.
So we have lots of new things.
So very quickly I want to make a very simple little level I will put a couple of rooms in this can all
be tweaked later.
But just something that works maybe a little corridor down there.
Zoom out a bit.
You know what that like that will there.
And let's go to bucket fill and do some floors and some floors and you don't want be bucket filled in
oil your paint tile.
How about some more offices put some over here it's too small but we're due to do that all and be a
nice big corner office here
keeping square for now.
So I look at and maybe a little I don't know.
Server room thing down here old maybe that's a different office.
I haven't built this out.
I can work with that later.
Let's put some more painted tiles in whoops bucket tiles that painted tile those two.
And now let's connect these rooms.
So let's put a floor in here.
No.
Go back to pink tile.
I did it controls the or controls it there.
I think that's going to look pretty good.
You know what.
Let's do that.
Put the wall back right here.
So there are two doors in here one out here that's a little I don't know what that is.
You know what let's make a little broom cupboard Yeah.
And that's looking pretty good.
So there's my level one.
I'm going to rename that template level to level one.
And let's say that's safe.
I also wanna make this my default levels now so back to Project settings.
Got to run and find Level 1 Now when I run the game.
It will run from this brand new level that we've just made.
OK good.
Nice and simple but I can tweak it later but it's good enough analysis close that window and put in
a couple new cameras just to show that we cancel instance and a camera
make sure I'm in move mode.
There's only one camera over here.
A duplicate that camera and get to rotate.
I could just type that in.
Can I
now.
I should have typed that I'm because look at this arm right here.
Should've been a factor of 90 degrees.
Not a factor.
A MULTIPLE OF NICE degrees but it isn't.
That is 90 degrees because the cameras don't start looking straight on.
So it's put you right here and camera one can be right here and one more camera.
You think more camera.
Yeah I'm feeling one more camera.
I'm thinking a camera in this room.
It's kind of up here and then rotate to you by a runway 90 degrees.
There it is.
Great.
More cameras.
Okay so I'm going to check that runs or I'll check if it works well.
I have a camera here.
Chemicals Seaney.
I can run past it myself.
Tense I can maybe make it through this don't make it through the door.
Nobody can see me behind here you can't see me and into the room a little bit scary but they're gone.
All that's done now we have a level we can stop letting some guards into.
So let's make a god.
So Peter the process unless a simple new inherited scene we've just done that.
Go back up a level the characters go into Templar character and there is in him my Sprite and I want
to find the correct scene.
So let's go to graphics and to PSG I've got him on a soldier and drag the soldier in here.
You'll notice the soldier is slightly wider than the man red.
So his occlusion isn't quite cutting the front the body's not too big an issue.
But if you don't like it go to offset and we'll just move him back by couple of pixels left two pixels.
That's about gets a negative 2 on the X looks about right.
I have decided that every god and I'm going to rename it God is going to have a torch.
I'm an instance in a torch
and I need to save this on a save to empty seas and call it God but we have an issue.
If you look at this script you can either open it or go to the inspector for a script.
It's the template current template character isn't what we want.
We don't inherit from template character someone remove that script to a new one.
It's gonna be in this scene and it's going to inherit from player detection.
Create that.
And that should work fine.
Let's find out.
Going to go into Level 1 and I'm going to add a brand new God.
So this instance in a god and just move my god of this and move over here and rotate.
Now you'll notice there's a torch.
But look what it's lighting.
Not a problem.
Going to God's and just make sure that the torch is outside of the exclusion mask.
This inclusion polygon right here will stop any light.
I will put it in his right hand just outside his body.
Save that back to level one.
And he has a torch.
Let's put another guard in as well.
Right now they're not going to move in on or do anything.
They're just guards.
So a couple that got here and a guard over here so e each rotate W to move or you can use these handy
dandy.
And that looks pretty good.
Now the next two videos we can start moving them.
But first let's see how it works in game and my camera can see me and this guard can see me if I'm in
the torch but only if I'm in a torch.
The same is true here.
If I get my center on the torch which is weird.
Oh.
OK.
So normally I would edit this out but this is such a silly mistake.
The detection beam isn't actually in the torch when I move the torch his right hand.
That was the wrong thing to do.
Let's move the transform here and on the why put that back to zero and instead I'm going to move the
torch beam out here and keep it on zero.
Why.
Because the detection script I mean let's take a look at it in the script.
Play detection is actually running from the origin of the character.
Right.
So if I look here where the character is this part here this node this kind of antibody not the sprite
not the torch.
That's where the line is being drawn.
So if I say that first play we should no longer have it to the right side of the guard is less sensitive.
So can see me can't see me see me can't see me.
Great and safety feature here.
Awesome.
So that's looking much better.
So now we have a couple of guards who admittedly don't do anything.
Just look at you and shine a red light.
And we have lots of cameras in the next couple of videos we can start moving them around.
Well that feels like a good place to end the video in this video we've made a new inherited scene and
we have hired some guards play some guards around your sound level one.
We're gonna redesign the level a couple of times as we add to this game.
But it's a good starting location.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.