Welcome back you glorious God nutters or God or people if you don't feel like being a god.
Not in this video.
We're going to continue play detection.
Let's make this really awesome by using a line of sight as well as field of view.
Just to clarify the difference the field of view is the angle that the character can see.
So the NPC has a field of view.
Now this line of sight can be blocked and then it is not related to field of view.
We can use line of sight in any direction and just say both field of view and line of sight have to
be true.
To set this up there's a few things we need to do.
We are going to have to set up line of sight functionality.
We're also going to have to say if something is in the way I can't see you.
And let's put in some concept of maximum detection range.
If you're too far away if you're outside the beam of light I still can't see.
Then we need to check if a player is in the line of sight and return True or false.
The immediate way to do this is by using something called a Ray cast.
We've seen Ray cast before in Hobby days right when we had this cloud Here's a cloud who for some reason
is green.
He had an invisible rate hoodie and when the bunny crossed it lightning was small.
Now we could do something similar here.
A very grumpy Guard and the grumpy Guard is going is going to have a great deal.
The problem is that rated he faces in one direction now.
Yes we could surround him with I don't know three hundred sixty of them.
We could do one of each direction one that's really cumbersome too.
That's a lot of bloat.
Sorry what happens.
The player is far away.
Managed to sneak out between these two lights.
It's just a lot that can go wrong here.
So instead of that we are going to do this.
We're going to have a much happier Guard and what he's going to do.
Is generate a line to where ever the player is.
So that line is going to draw itself from the guard to the player and then go do is check is.
I can see.
True.
Are you in line of sight.
If your line of sight.
That's true.
If something is blocking you.
That's false.
So how do we do that.
To do that we are reliant on a brand new function.
Get well to day and it's got access to something called direct space state.
Get well too deep is kind of an abstract class.
Everything that relates to the current two dimensional environment.
Sound physics everything and it has access to direct space which is specifically the physics we going
to be using this because this allows us to check collision without putting objects in first.
So it's kind of sneaky.
Let's show you how that works and can see why it's awesome.
Here we are back an engine and let's get in to uploaded to script on the go into the security camera
scene and open the script.
All right.
We're gonna have to make a new function so let's make ourselves a little bit more room down here.
Here we go and play a function.
Claire is in the line of sight.
So what do we need to do.
Well we need you very well.
Are variable's going to called space.
I got this very well name from kids can code his tutorial first put me on to this idea as a solution.
Really good series of tutorials on YouTube which if you want to go further into this I do recommend
variable space.
What is space is can be get world to deep dot.
Direct.
Spaced out.
Now let's make a variable for region of the good name for this at the best I can come up with right
now is line of sight obstacle.
The thing that's going block the view Obs dunckel area that looks wrong for some reason but that's right.
OK so what's this going to be.
Well going to use a new space variable.
And we're going to use intersect Ray.
What's an intersect right.
Well let's go into to the helpful direct space.
Some hoehler control and pressing it and you'll see well tuti has these members and one of them is physics
2D directional spaced it has quite a lot of stuff isn't it.
Let's click on that.
We have these public methods and one of them is an intercept Ray.
So it's just from a point to a point excluding stofan an array on this coalitional there.
So where's it going from global.
Position.
It's going from itself.
Where's it going to.
It's going to the player's global position.
Nice and easy.
What's it going to exclude if we look at the camera.
It's going to draw this Ray this line to the player from 0 0 and I don't want it interfering with um
collision box.
So best thing to do.
Exclude yourself just makes things much simpler.
What I mean exclude and exclude myself and this has to be an array.
And what collision moscona use.
He look at your camera and go down to the collision.
Mask over that collision mask.
So whatever this value is that's what you're using.
Here's a problem.
Look it's black.
It can't see the player.
Not only can it not see the player is not going to see wars.
Now we did this so that the player could walk through the cameras.
Let's do this a slightly different way.
Let's go to the player and change all of its collisions stuff to just itself so it only interacts with
itself.
Now the onus to interact with players is on everyone else.
Now lets go back to the security camera.
It's a security camera.
No change there and it can interact with players and walls.
If it can't interact with walls walls won't block line of sight so we have to put that in there.
But now we're back to the same problem right.
If I run this scene.
The player can't walk through a security camera.
Well we can fix that.
Let's go into the security camera scene and go to the collision shaped hoodie and disable it.
Now the collision layers and masks are still set.
But check this out.
I can walk through the camera.
If l'eau s obstacle dot Collider Collider comes from kinematic what it eudi it's built in is the player
return true.
Else.
Return false.
And lead colon the end else.
And then let's plug that in.
So if play is an f v tolerance and a player is in line of sight and that should be everything let's
find out.
Okay.
I could be seen.
I can't be seen.
I mean I can't be seen I be seen I can't be seen hahaha.
This is exciting and I'm going to go over here.
I'm not actually checking anything.
I just feel good about this.
Look we have a working line of sight but what we also have is infinite range.
Right so we can be seen by the camera out of range.
So let's put in the concept of a maximum action range.
So here we go.
So new constant Max detection range.
And that's going to be.
Well the image is six forty I believe and we've scaled it down by two.
So 320 we can change that is not right.
Now we need to set this up.
So what we need to do is find out what's the distance to the play and that should really be here in
line of sight.
Let's make a brand new variable variable listens to player.
Was this going to be.
Well I'm a draw.
Um.
Figure out the distance from the player to the NPC so.
Player.
Global Position not distance to very any function was it listen to me.
Global position.
And now let's go.
Variable
player in range.
What's that going to be.
It's going to be distance to player is smaller than than max detection range and that's gonna return
a True or false which I can use right here.
If one of the observable Collider So let us can say true or false and player in range which I have spelt
very weirdly.
Return true retard false.
One thing I've noticed a slight obstacle collider that's going to be true anyway so let's go eagles.
Eagles player and the players in range.
That should work fine okay.
Anything else we need to do in here.
This is looking pretty good.
Let's test it.
Okay.
You can't see me.
You can see me and if I hide here you can't see me.
I'm out of range.
Awesome in this video.
We've looked at how to use world to 2D and direct space data to check collisions and a time line of
sight.
We've also use collision masks and disabled the actual collision bit which is going to be really handy
later I'll give you a quick head.
If we change the place collision mask we can make them undetectable and that means we can disguise the
player.
So we put that functionality in later in the game.
Meanwhile great progress and excellent work.
I must see on the next video.