Hello again, you terrific go to people in this video.
We've already got a game that works, is fully functional, but now going to start making it awesome.
This is about enhancing the player experience with design decisions, not necessarily gameplay decisions.
I think the game place.
But how do I want the player to feel when they look at the game, when they hear the game and when stuff
happens?
Like what kind of feedback wanna give them?
And in this video, what kind of setting in.
So let's jump right into it.
And I'm going to quickly take a look at some of the assets are included.
So if you look over models, we've got a few things first.
We've got this advert.
Open that.
And this is a very simple little.
Much right now, right now.
This isn't coloring.
Let's take a look at the MASH real quick and open that we've got a single surface.
So what we could do is bringing offices.
I got a logo here and I think I might have two to do a Gotto advert albedo.
So what I might do is change this material.
When we go to the albino and just drag this in.
And at the moment, it's very hard to see, that's probably because it's so much like, let's tell them
it's all the way down.
There we go.
And there's some stuff we can play with here.
Now, what we could do is go to.
It's not quite the right place if I go to every detail here.
I probably movie X, not the Z.
Up.
Out there.
That's what you want it weirdly.
It's not scaled correctly.
So let's change the scale with little experimentation.
That's probably the best it's going to look.
I'm so quickly look what I just did that went through materials which just closed.
I've got scale on the X has point sixty five.
And the offset is twenty five.
Now ordinarily the sets would be built with these in mind.
Right.
But we haven't done what we've got is a simple mesh that like he's made and I'm putting a texture on
top of it to make it work.
It's not usually matte.
It's just making it work.
So maybe it only uses maybe two.
But if you do want to use this, which is going to take this mesh, we don't care about the rest.
So in this case, I am going to.
Right.
Click on this as a safe branch of seen.
And I feel like this is part of the level and a subfolder called Dekel.
So put that in.
OK.
So there's one thing we can look at.
Let's see what other assets we have.
Real quick models because we got an advert we've got keep doing the goals, you know, about them.
Leave the particles for now and set us a toys.
This lovely bear.
This one is from our good friend, Mark.
Hello, Jelly and Lessel Jeleva.
We've got these beautiful blocks.
I mean, they might not be beautiful is a single block made using a can block texture and you could
make as many of these you like, you could even spout simple words.
And we've got this lovely wagon, lovely wagon.
Now, this lovely wagon has multiple measures as part of it.
So you'd have to find a way of exporting all these, probably by doing the simple save as.
So you've seen as models, toys, wagons, bandwagon.
Great.
And from here, you could change it.
Right.
We also don't need the animation player in that.
The advantage to this, you can make different materials for each of these.
So what you do is go into Matu, go into the mesh itself, sorry.
And this material here would be a new spatial material.
And then I could make this.
I could make this a nice red wagon, for example, like metallic or whatever, and just play around
with that.
We've also got a few textures that we could use.
So I'm going to close these without saving them, as you might say.
OK, and let's take a look.
Texas.
I've got this floor, which I better put a plane here and I've got this hip's the background of the
backwell and a picture I could put on.
So there's a few things we could do.
I'm going to show you how to build a floor.
And then I'm going to let you loose and see what you create.
OK, so really make it your own.
One more thing you can do before I go any further is you could add in a mesh inserts, you could build
a mesh instance from scratch.
And over here, this is what kind of mesh?
Let's say I want a cube.
And move it to a place where I like it to turn little door properly with move and then I click on it.
I can change the sides on the X, Y and Z.
You don't even have to change scale.
You could say that this is, I don't know, 20 on the X and or 60 on the X and use it as a skirting
board, which I might do.
So what we gonna be doing is just just be making a simple mesh.
We don't care about physics bodies.
We're not making any effort to interact to the world.
It's just a mesh that exists with the texture.
So let's start off by making a brand new blank note, taking my computer off caps lock and I'm going
to call this scenery or Dekel.
Let's keep it consistent.
Dekel.
Within that, I don't make a brand new mission since.
And this is gonna be a plane.
Now, we already have a plane that made the pitch with, but this doesn't have to have any kind of static
body with it.
So let's call this off for.
And I'm going to move this down.
Transform.
Translation.
Why negative.
Point two.
So just below on this.
Make it big.
So what's a good size for this?
You know what?
Let's go crazy.
It's a 100 by 100.
OK.
That's one hundred.
One hundred and clearly quite ugly to look at.
So let's give it a new material.
So new special.
What, you're not shy.
Go.
And I'm going to use this floor texture.
I got a dozen crashes that took ages.
Ready?
We have a world that makes a little more sense.
We have some blood spots there, but let's just see the difference that makes walking.
See that now we are moving in space.
Still, maybe the camera's beautiful position because now culturally a lot in the back.
But that's looking good.
So here's what I'd like to do.
I'd like you to add background details of your version of Kutty Kick about using assets that build more
in blender.
Find more on on other sites and bring them in.
Really customize this and make it your own.
So pulls a video.
And when you come back, I'll show you what I've made.
And welcome back, folks.
OK.
So as you can see, I've gone and built some things first.
I'm going to quickly look at it through the camera previews here, looking wild.
I'm actually pretty happy with that.
Now, tweak the lighting in the shadows, change the angles.
But I cheat to talk you through each of these assets I've placed in and the kinds of decisions I've
made and the techniques I've used.
So first, the flow I've seen that is just a single plane with a single texture.
This all needs to be the back wall is the same deal.
Now, I've made this a different size.
I don't really need it to clip onto the floor.
Right.
So I've made it bigger than we need and I've kept it roughly proportional to the Texan.
Looks pretty good.
The skirting board is a single cube as a measure instance, and just putting out a nice flat red material
on it.
It does come through the back of the wall a bit.
But it gives a bit more dimensionality to the game.
OK, so this painting, this painting is exact, the same deal is this picture, PMG, that I drew.
And it's on a mission sense and I've put it at an angle because I want it to feel a little bit less.
So it was the bottom of symmetrical, right?
I'm a little bit of chaos.
I want to feel very playful.
The advert we looked at to sort of put it here, it works really well.
The bear, I just placed it here.
I actually think I might make the bear bit bigger.
So his only do I click on a bear transform and I only need to move the bear.
Now, if I look at the scene, instances open that you'll see this is a spatial with four measures.
I've got rid of everything else by changing the scale here.
It's a three times bigger.
It changes all the children of it.
So now the cubes can keep Doo's can look a lot smaller and everything's in in the same kind of proportion.
How do we make sure from doing that?
That I do too.
Don't go through the floor and I might just check how that looks through my camera just to make sure
that I'm not shadows a bit much, isn't it?
Maybe maybe three is too big.
How do you feel about.
Yeah, that's pretty good.
Now he's come out of preview to move the bed back down.
About that.
OK.
So I did the same process with the wagon.
What I've done here is I've created a simple material that is open the scene.
So I exported or saved as rather this specialist.
That's just keeping the spatial.
It's a nice, easy way of moving everything at once.
This hand wagon here, I just added the material.
It's a simple I'll be the texture and I've just turned the roughness down.
So it gives it nice.
Not quite reflexion, but nice flat feeling, very plastiki the wheels.
I've done a very similar thing here.
I've given more metallic and tan the roughness down.
Just a great texture.
It looks like a Plastiki fake metal, which is what I'm going for.
And I've applied them material to all of these just by taking this, copying it and pasting it to the
others.
Which means if I go into any of these and change them.
It'll change all instances of that material.
It's all one material.
What else we have in these building blocks?
I have three building blocks and I'm just place them and rotates them so they smell love.
I mean, I might even tweak these.
I'm fine with that.
Let's see how this plays.
That's the really important thing.
So again.
Team error messages got D.A. files open it on holiday with them, and suddenly this game feels very
different.
I have noticed that the characters are floating slightly above the ground.
So you wrote my collision that I fixed up.
But look at that.
That feels much more polished right now.
Have a space.
Now, if we wanted to, we could make this a lot more complex by having, like, little figures here,
maybe animate them fireworks that come up, whatever you want.
But by placing these scenic elements that fit with the game right there, the same kind of color palette.
They're all very playful.
They do the right kind of scale.
It really gives us a reinforced player experience.
It really makes the thing feel a lot more fun.
Might even with this painting Dell'Abate, let's move the painting down.
I'm also in a close these days because it's confusing everything.
Close, close, close.
Great.
So I'm going to move that painting.
Painting.
All right.
They are.
Let's just move you.
It's like one quick thing about the potential to say the transform.
On the Z access, the back was forced.
I have this negative nine point nine, seven, five, not ten.
If I put it as nothing negative, ten will be the same place as the wall.
And you'll get this.
This is a pretty common error in a lot of games where you've got two different objects in exactly the
same place with different textures.
And what's happening is the game engine doesn't know which one to render.
So it's just taking a guess and it's guessing inconsistently.
So to fix that, you just want to have them.
JERMEY Negative nine point nine seven five.
You just want to have a tiny, tiny difference in where they are.
Right.
So the nominators at which point is very clear to the engine.
This is in front of that.
So render it accordingly.
And that feels pretty good.
So in this video, he in this video, we've enhanced the player experience with background details.
We'll just add a bunch of measures with no collisions.
They don't do anything.
They just look better.
But we've added a bunch of awesome so great stuff.
And I'll see you in the next video.