Hello again you marvellous God people.
And this just occurred to me I don't think I've called you Marvellous not before but I have now.
So marvellous God.
People in this video we make some bystanders.
Let me show you what I'm thinking for these bystanders our bystanders are not animated.
I'm using assets like attorneys that have known animation rigged to them that no rigging to them.
They can't move.
They're effectively statues.
They're going to be randomly selected from a pool we're going make a bunch of bystanders and then God
is going to pick them to do that.
We're just gonna use foul grabber that's one of the reasons why we made it.
And they're going to be sporn on a semi random basis.
We can tell God oh pick a random integer from one to another number and we'll change that number as
we need to and spawn another bystander when that takes over.
There are obstacles right.
They're not characters they don't have to inherit from a current class at all.
They're just there to get in the way and make the game play a little more interesting.
You don't always have a clear shot.
OK.
First thing to do is make a bystander scene and to do that let's go take a look in the model's folder
and in the bystanders subfolder subdirectories whatever you call it you'll see a bunch of mesh some
females Some are called male.
One is called Woman.
I'm not sure why this one is different.
I was going to be doing this one actually.
And these were all supposed to be in the background of a game right so you can imagine if you're doing
I don't know let's say a racing game you know very fast and there a bunch of figures that go past in
a blur.
It doesn't matter fenham move.
But here we are to do things a little bit differently.
First thing to do is check the scale.
So I'm going to minimize that drag this in this chulalongkorn.
That's fine.
It's twice the size it needs to be more or less take that off snap and you just move that close.
And yes she's twice the size so does the check I've got those numbers right.
That's scaled down by zero point five.
All three axes.
And that's yeah that's about right isn't it.
So we know that our bystanders are going to have to be half the size they're gonna come in that are
let's make a new scene and make a new template for beisner and all to save in the scenes folder.
That's good live right here.
Now I want my bystanders to react to the projectile.
I want them floating off into the distance.
I'm going to make a rigid body as my basner and I'm going to call this bystander template just so I
don't accidentally use this in the game.
And let's make a new folder Wally.
Here's a new follicle bystanders and a save the bystander template in this folder but put the individual
bystanders here so that the file can just grab everything in the subfolder gets by so the template is
going to need a mesh instance and a collision body.
Let's put those two notes in real quick.
Have to do collision shape.
Awesome.
Okay let's put it on mesh.
So back to models to bystanders It doesn't matter which one I pick for now because when I switch them
out anyway.
But there they are.
I'm going to scale the meche instance down not the rigid body and not the collisions are just the motion
sets.
So you are zero point five on all three axes.
Awesome.
Fine let's put a collision shape in an inch.
He's a stat a capsule shape which is going to have to be rotated by 90 degrees on the X I believe.
And I'm thinking as been moved up by that looks like about a meter that's moving up by a metre.
So up on the y axis and then it needs to be scaled down not scaled.
You don't scale we need to change the actual extant.
I should know that by now is there a point five.
Well looking good.
That is pretty much perfect now.
There is a little bit of gap in places but honestly this game isn't that precision right.
There's not going to be any head shots in here.
It's not like we can shoot the Fullerton and have a certain effect happening it's just here is the shape
of the body and they can all share the same collision.
So great you cannot save that in my scenes folder as by stand by standard template.
Which brings me to the challenge.
Another early challenge.
I like these early challenges for this section because I feel like you guys have progressed quite fast
as we first out on a journey so let's see how comfortable you are with this.
Ignore the little slide thing down here it's not important.
I want you to make more Wice that let's create at least two more.
I'm going to be creating all of them.
But if he just will read a couple to see how it feels.
That's the minimum you should be using and remember.
Put all of your bystanders in their own fault.
I'll put them all in.
Do do do this.
Bystanders fold everything and he'll get used so Pausa Lydia give that a shot and when you're habu's
your results or you're sick of it and you want see how I do it.
Come back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
Hi.
So one of the DO is it a new inherited scene and going to inherit from by set a template.
And now I'm going to go into my model scene.
Where did you go.
Doo doo doo.
Normal scene models falder into bystanders.
And I'm just going to start reading them so I'm going to rename this running female running.
And that's nice.
Any of those words a female running go and I'm going to save this under US scenes.
Bystanders female running great.
I'll show you one more.
So let's once again inherit new inherited scene.
It's important I'm inheriting a scene again right.
I'm not saving him or running as a new thing.
I'm not duplicating it.
All of these are going to inherit from the same scene.
So then all I need to do is change by set a template and anything i change in here will propagate down.
So let's do that real quick.
I'm going to drag my feet are standing measure here rename this wanted female stand
and I'm going to keep my naming conventions the same so it's nice that he's It's your doing and just
save That's save into Bystanders and What to keep doing that for all of them and I could just speed
up the video while I do it.
But you know what.
You've seen me do this recently with food so I'm just going to cut forward.
And welcome back.
Okay so I now have all of these new scenes of ormet that I've made all in here.
That's terrible grammar.
I'm looking at Save mail walking in my basic bystanders scene folder.
Language is difficult today.
Let's just check the on here one two three four five six different seats.
Awesome.
I don't need all these others I'm just going to close all of these.
Now there's a few more things we're going to have in our bystander but I'm going to change the default
by set a template and it's going to propagate everything except what we've explicitly told is different
which in each of these is just what is the mesh.
Everything else is identical.
And while also the name but that's an important.
So any changes I make will be to buy set a template.
For example I want an audio stream play a 3d.
I want this because I want a sound effect to play when they're hit by projector.
Well don't worry about that in a moment.
I'm just going to leave that node in there for now.
But first let's make a sport.
I want an object that spawns these things and fires them as if they were bullets.
Right.
So I want a simple she sees a spatial the simplest 3-d node.
It has 3D position and she's going to fight objects.
I'm going to give it a ammash Just so I can see it in the level right.
This bit isn't it isn't vital but it's helpful.
And I'm going to use a simple She's the cute mash seems kind of huge.
Not that it matters too much but let's scale that down so size zero point five zero point five bizer
point five that's your size.
Awesome.
So here is our sponsor.
Which I shall name Spooner because it's us Borna.
I will say that in scenes.
Done.
Now I need a couple more things here.
The first thing I need is an idea of where Ford is right I want to spawn the bystanders outside of an
eye.
I want to use a position 3D.
We've already use one of these and I'm going to do the exact same thing when they call this forward.
Just like you did before and I'm gonna make sure that this is on the z axis right.
This is vital.
Don't just pick the direction that you think is forward.
Actually use the one that's inside got.
So I want Z forward one meter that looks good.
Great.
So there's my forward one more thing I need.
I need a timer note.
Let's give that a timer.
And that I think should be everything we need except for a script.
OK script time let's create a script inside the RIP's folder because reasons called spawn are dodgy.
Awesome.
Okay I can save this.
And before I go any further I can actually put one in the level so this level will need some filling
out no in a while and it's a little room here in a room to the other side.
But for now let's just put a sponsor in here to make a new simple note.
Might call this spawn so I can keep them all separate.
And let's.
Instance in a Spawn's So your scenes and your spawn are and you live say over here.
How's that.
That looks pretty good.
OK.
I need to know which way forward is don't I.
Let's put edits children on and see where Ford is you see now that forward is going to fire my pieces
that way.
I don't want that and fire too into the room putting snap on and rotating this bent like not the forward
of the whole thing silly rotating by 90 degrees you are rotated and you are not.
Awesome.
A switch off at Shelter affinia.
Now this will move and be edited for the rest.
This is just the check basic functionality.
What I want is a system where it's going to fire bystanders who are going to walk through the middle.
Once we get later in the game and put no visible collision walls the player can't cross this line.
We'll put some furniture and things is going to yeah our whole level.
But for now let's keep nice and simple.
And keep my sensible.
I'm going back into Scripps.
First thing I need to do is I'm going to have a couple of variables and a bystander speed which is how
fast bystanders go.
I'm about 10 for now.
We can tweak that as needed.
The other thing I need is a maximum wait time.
The max amount of time you can wait before firing the next best and say 5 seconds from now and let's
go into the spawning season so that all the alter completes work nice and easily.
One more thing I do need and this is not an export variable is the actual list of bystanders.
This is going to be a dictionary.
Why a dictionary.
Because many used file grabber and that's typeset file grabber up.
First you need to do is fill thatcherites right so and we use to treat the moment you are brought into
the scene.
Don't worry about anything else in a scene just when you're brought in you need to fill this entry.
Bystanders equals file.
Grab a dot.
Get files and then I need a string that points to the right folder which is this one copy path and pace
that it great so that should be good to go.
I also need to set the randomise were going to be using random information specifically random numbers.
We need to generate a random seed we need to do this once but we do need to do.
I guess I have this timer here.
I want this wait time to be changed depending on this value and this is going to happen multiple times
not just once when add a new function called Set a timer and let's make sure we're actually calling
it in a month.
We get to the scene so we're going to do set time as a function highlight what is set time and do well.
It's going to go timer dot wait time.
Equals.
And now I need a road number.
It's going to be a random integer modulated by maximum wait time.
Now key thing to remember if I look at random integer some kind of hold control in documentation you'll
notice were actually counting from zero right so we counted from position 0 and this many spaces.
So we're not actually counting between 1 and 5 seconds were counting 0 to force.
Let's add that in.
So now it's going to be a random integer modulated by that and add 1.
If my max wait time is 5 the lowest number you can have is one and the highest you can have it's five.
That's what I'm looking for.
What do we need to do from here we actually start the timer.
And timer got start into the timer.
Let's make this a one shot.
So it's something to keep repeating.
And let's actually connect it to the script.
So node signal.
So when I connect my time out to the spawn a script and there it is.
Was it going to do it's going to spawn which does not have a spot spawn.
Let's give it then spawn spawn bystander.
Great and we're going to go straight back in to set time right so we just got to loops this forever.
All that's left now is to make spot buy stamps.
Let's do that function spawn bystander and this is going to be very similar to this flight function.
Going to use actually almost identical code but I'm not going to copy paste it and then write it out
variable bystander.
This is not the same as bystanders and I do need to be careful here because it's the kind of mistake
I like to make.
But what is variable by Santa when we need to load in a bystander and we alone it's something from the
bystanders.
Dictionaries are bystanders and this is a dictionary so we need to tell it.
Which one were loading it so it's going to be called by key.
So let's pick a random key so random integer I am going to modulate that by the by standers dictionary
size.
So what I'm telling it is go to this bystander's variable dictionary right.
Find out how large it is.
Count how many things are in it and then pick a random integer.
Now I don't need to add one here.
Why.
Because if I look at my file I got a script.
The first key is zero not one.
So you don't have that off by one error that we would do if we're using the timer.
In other words if there are five things in this bystander The keys are not 1 2 3 4 5 they're 0 1 2 3
4.
So this will work.
However before I get too excited.
We do need to load this in as an instance.
So let's going to destruction from those we have from here which go instance so bystander is a random
entry of the bystanders dictionary loaded as an instance.
I get reports.
Now let's add that as a child.
So add child.
Bystander.
Now let's move the bystander to the top level.
Technically speaking this isn't necessary because the sponsors aren't going to move.
But what if we do want moving supporters right.
You could put in a situation where your sponsors are going to get through right seems like a show I'm
talking about.
Maybe they'll do this right.
I'm not going to do that because that's going to cause complications for my vision of the.
But if we did we'd need to set as top level design and that takes truly doesn't it.
So we have spawned in a random bystander and we've told it don't take your movement information from
the sponsor right.
Just use your own Moven information.
Now let's actually move to the right starting position so bystander
dot set transform forward and I want its global transform
global transform
and that should be everything I need.
Because I've told it don't take your parents position information I need to use the global transform
for power for the forward.
If I hadn't done that I could have just used the forwards transform but I'm going to set this as global
because I want these things to be fired as projectiles.
Finally I need it to move some bystander got set linear velocity.
There it is.
OK.
So settling in velocity will take a vector 3 so I can't just use the speed.
Well we have a vector 3 right.
We could use the basis of forward plus two that we could go forward.
DOT gets global transform
an unknown basis and I want this on the z axis.
Right so how fast are you moving on the forward backwards axis.
So let's say with a square bracket and that's entry to Y masir Square bracket because basis remember
is an array is a matrix.
Okay so I need a square brackets for that.
It's a good habit to get into.
I'm just going to normalize it in this particular case.
Doesn't matter because I don't have any of my sporn As far diagonally.
But what if he did.
What if your level had sporn is at a 45 degree angle not a 90 degree angle so it's normalized.
OK.
So it's currently set to exactly the same speed as.
Forward.
Forward isn't moving.
Let's multiply that by a bystander speed.
And if I've done everything correctly.
Drum roll please.
When I press play.
We should start seeing.
Pieces coming in.
Look carefully what's happening coming in and then slowing down.
Why.
Because they're hitting the floor.
That's okay.
Let's go into a by saltz plate and start fixing this one.
Gravity scale zero Don't be effect by gravity.
Now an Everest play.
We should just saw through the door.
Fantastic.
In a semi random right.
They're going quite fast.
I could probably slow them down if I wanted.
That's easy enough to do.
But you know what else I can do.
Let's move this to here.
And duplicate it and put it on the other side.
So I'm just going to keep moving over here.
Rotate you by ninety two negative net.
Greece is just tickled.
So a small child.
Whereas the forward no piny to keep rotating you surprise I forgot how rotation works.
OK so there's your forward and let's get this child off again and make sure that they're not facing
each other because then we're going to have weird collisions so let's just move you to here.
How's that.
Too much.
They hit the door.
Maybe get the best players how it looks.
Never do goes it coming.
There you go.
OK.
So I've created a mosh pit simulator.
That's fine.
I can just.
OK.
And after way too long fussing around I've decided to pause the video and come back to it because it
took me ages slightly up properly but just to show you what I've done.
Spawn or one is on the Z of minus one point seventy five and spawn two is facing it.
The Z of minus a point seven day.
So they're just going to miss each other unless something goes wrong.
Okay let's put some more things in bystander.
First we need to do is I need a bystander script.
So let's put in a script for that.
Let's go live in the script solor doo doo doo.
There it is.
Bye bye set a template not she went on a call.
I want to call it by stand a script by Stella Judy.
All right.
One more thing I want to do.
We've got a situation where bystanders could in theory all congregate around the place and eventually
they're going to start slowing things down.
I want to clean them up.
I want a system whereby if they go off screen vanish.
Now this is a little bit of a cheat and you might not want it for every game.
But I would put it here just as a sort of error catching.
So I need a visibility notifier.
This is a type of no we have looked at before but it does exactly what you might expect.
Right.
It tells God how can this be seen and what I want is to connect as a signal on camera.
It's it it's so when you exit the camera and connect that to buy set a template and owner says if the
bystander leaves the camera.
So not if they haven't been in the home yet but if they've been onscreen and then leave delete them
unless you have that looks.
So he was bystander.
And he vanishes.
Right.
Look up look down they're gone.
Now this could get a little annoying a certain type of games.
I know your grand theft auto games you see stuff like this where you see a great car you turn the corner
to try and chase it down and it'll be gone.
But I also don't want bystanders just clogging everything up so I'm okay with this.
Next thing I want to do is at a time a..
And this timer is going to be connected to the by cell the template by set of script.
I'm putting this here so that when the bystander is hit by food it'll vanish after a little amount of
time.
A small amount of time so on time a time out.
Q free.
Let's make sure that I'm not auto starting my timer.
I'm not.
It is a once one shot that's fine and I don't call this three seconds.
What's this going to be used for.
This is going be used for when we're hit by food and we a function called hurt.
And this is a nice simple one on a start the timer so timer start and play the audio player audio stream
player so audio stream player stopped play.
You'll notice we don't actually have a sound and he said let's fix that.
It's SFX which is why sort of scenes and I've got this oh no.
Which I made myself because I'm king of sound effects I'm going to drag that in here and let's see what
it sounds like.
It sounds amazing.
Let's make sure is not looping that import and turn looping off and reimport it.
Now there is a bug that sometimes hits this version of God where you drag the sound in and playing gets
stuck on.
If that happens save the scene close the scene open the scene.
It'll be fine.
Okay.
So I now have a script which has a function called hurt.
That'll start a timer play Ono and play it once and then when the timer goes out it'll keep fruit that
you'll notice.
Hurt is never being called so right now I have a bystander that could in theory be hurt but isn't well
something fancy we can do that was a projectile and as go into the actual projectile scene which I did
do.
Emma there is.
Let's connect the rigid body to itself.
Go.
So I want body entered like body shape entered and neck.
That to itself.
And here is a fun bit we could do this with collision master of doing that a lot.
But here's an easy way of doing it.
If body which is defined as an argument so if whatever the body is has method hurt and this does exactly
what you might expect it's going to see whatever the food has collided with.
And then check.
Okay.
You object just collided with whatever you are.
Do you have a method called hurt.
If you do run it
and if you do I'm out of here.
Now I run the same you'll notice that it won't actually work right.
Not hearing oh no nothing's happening.
And the reason why is I need to switch on.
Both contacts reported and contact monitoring for mouse over that you'll see the rigid body will emit
signals when it collides with another rigid body.
If that is an on rigid bodies won't report each other.
So let's switch it on for both.
Make sure continues.
Collision detection is on and that we're monitoring at least one contact a need to do continuous collision
detection because otherwise fast moving projectiles might not be reported.
Let's Pressplay and see how that works.
Let's tell the time a down to two seconds.
Great.
But that's looking pretty good.
One more thing on do.
I'm like I know a little bit louder Let's make you know decibels to 5 and Max decibels to five is much
less nice loud.
So what I am.
And you'll also notice dopplers on.
Right.
As they get closer to us the test is going to change.
And now we have bystanders that we can increase the rate of fire quite easily even go to the spawning
a scene and change our maximum wait time to three seconds.
For example I could slow down the bystanders but we have a lot of control and we have basic bystanders
which brings us to the end of this video in this video.
We've looked at how to use his method to check if a body should do something which is a really useful
technique right.
I don't have to worry about fancy being a script.
I just need to say this body you're interacting with.
Just check it has a method if it has it tell it to run it don't care about what it is or what it means.
Let the node worry about it which is a really great way of the principle of responsibility being enforced.
We've also use a visibility notifier to check if a note is still on camera.
And we've got some really called bystanders with a very professional sound effect.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.