Elegant alive for God.
People in this video were going to continue adding awesome and we're adding awesome audio because alliteration
is fun.
I will add some critical feedback.
This is the kind of thing that can really make a difference in a game.
The player should know that certain things are happening without even being aware that they're being
informed about them.
So what kind of feedback do we want to put as audia.
And by the way I want thing audio feedback.
I don't mean that irritating thing we put a microphone a guitar too close to a speaker.
I'm talking about things like when the ball is kicked the player should know that they've made contact
should be immediately apparent.
So I want a sound effect to play when the ball is kicked and I've got just the sound for it and I want
a sound effect.
When a goal is scored I know we're freezing the game but we should tell them why the game is for us
the snus.
This isn't a bug.
Something important has happened and I have to adjust the sound for it.
I also have some pretty awesome background music.
Quick note.
You don't have to use any of these sounds you can find your own sounds or if you decide that your game
is best played in silence.
That's cool too but let's add some critical feedback as audio and I'm going to put random pauses in
the sentence because I dont know why.
OK let's get back to normal.
So here we are in game you've noticed by the way I think I accidentally put my camera too high.
I quite like it here.
Keep it for a bit.
I can always adjust it later but that's not all we're doing to that we're doing audio.
Let's start with background music was a good place to start new scene and make audio stream player and
in sound effect you'll see there are these three ounces Elkhorn that's gonna happen the gold place because
reasons.
There's frog Block 0 3 that I found link you to where I found it in the beginning of this section as
a nice link to it.
I have no idea what a frog lock is but it sounds awesome it sounds like this.
Why is that awesome.
Well our whole game has this little toy box aesthetic and these characters look where they're made of
wood and the ball looks like it's made of wood so let's have the sound effect of wood and it doesn't
actually sound like wood but it doesn't get.
And then we've got this lovely piece of music and I really like this piece of music.
Isn't that great.
Now a quick note.
When you bring in audio make sure you know when you want it looping and when you don't.
So let's go over to the airport.
I've already done these.
The sound is an old g.g..
Oh g.g. is a great pick when you doing music because it compresses quite highly which means you have
long pieces of music without taking a lot of disk space or memory space.
However I can take a while to load in.
So it's great for things like this.
It's actually not great for sound effects but we have what we have where it is better for sound effects.
It doesn't compress as well but loads very quickly.
The reason is the more it's compressed the longer it's going to take to decompress.
So here we have our Domino pizza.
Catch me or Catch Me If You Can.
What the track is actually called and I must have said it to auto play so this is set to looping this
piece of music.
Why.
Because it actually loops.
I happen to know this piece of music loops perfectly.
When it gets the end she's can start over and the player shouldn't hear the difference.
However the frog block is set not to loop.
Now if you need to change anything remember you have to press reimport just clicking the box on its
own won't change it and the air horn definitely won't loop because that's going to get annoying very
very quickly.
Or does the sound like.
It sounds like.
Remake's.
Sorry.
OK let's put the song in.
And it's being set to auto play now going to rename all your string player to music or background music
quality music much but name and a save that's seen as music.
And just like we didn't hide my says I'm going to autolog there seems to be a singleton so auto load
the scene for music an add it as a singleton and there it is.
Why am I doing this.
Because otherwise the music's going to restart every time the level is reloaded and I don't want that
at the level to be continuous.
This is one ongoing experience.
We all want to start again.
So to say that now let's take a look.
I wasn't having my goals scored for this one.
I don't want positional audio just like I didn't want positional audio with the music player mean is
an audio stream player so in-game and I make an audio string player.
There it is not 2D.
Not 3D because this isn't positional and I want to call this air horn.
And let's put the airhole sound in and listen to it just because isn't that awesome.
Now if you want to mess with volume and so forth you could do that right here in volume dbe for now
I'm going to leave this.
But if we want to change it we can tweak these settings when I edit this video because just because
it sounds good in-game doesn't mean it sounds good.
Try to explain stuff over the top of it so what you're hearing isn't actually what I'm hearing.
All right so when is this going to happen.
Well when a goal is scored and we already measure what to call a score so let's go into our game.
Where is a gold body.
Great.
There it is.
So under time a star can do air horn which what we called at play.
Now I'm not sure how long the air horn sound is but it is theoretically possible that these two will
play back to back out so we should add some sort of protection.
Let's do that.
Say if air horn got is playing and we don't want that so let's say.
If not air horn is playing so if not air horn is playing air play.
So if there is an already of sound playing play this out I see how that sounds.
And I'm just discovering a way to the people right now.
Can I first restart back in again.
Fantastic.
All right.
One more thing I want to do I want the sound effect from block to happen when the ball is kicked.
OK.
So first thing we do is we go into the bowl scene.
Give us a script.
That's the script.
I want to give it a script we're meant to do anything to put that in scripts and call it bulldog.
Now before we go into this we do actually need to check some sex before I give you the challenge.
There's one more thing I need to do look down here by these contacts right so I've got continuous C.D
continue Cedi is continuous collision detection.
We've also got contacts reported and contact monitor contact monitor monitor the contact and how many
contacts we monitor right now.
This is at zero.
So it's actually not going to check if it's touching things it's not going to report back to the script.
Let's change that to one you could change the two if you like without these.
The challenge is about to come up is going to be a little bit tricky about that challenge.
I'd like you to play this out.
I want you to play the the right sound so whatever sound you've picked uses from block whatever block
is.
But now I'm picturing a frog made of wood.
I want that play when the player and only the player is kicking the ball.
Now you could do it whenever anything touches it.
But I don't want that sound and I want the sound of I don't want a sound effect to play on the floor
or a goal is touching the wall just when the player is king.
Suppose the video give that a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
OK so the very first thing I need to do is find some sort of audio string player and we have three choices
so audio stream I have all issued player with no position information to me.
And three I'm thinking three because I actually care about where the ball is in relation to the camera.
So let's put that in and I don't need to rename that because it's just getting sustainable.
But I do need to put in frog like wax.
Now here we've got the maximum sound.
Put that all the way to the max which I think it's six and let's raise the unit decibels by three something
as three.
So has a glass out for some reason playing stuck on I think my God so is boater's was tapping on evidence
and put that in.
It's a what does the script wanted to.
Well I need to detect collisions so let's go into the signals and do body shape entered and it's just
gonna loop back to itself and that's fine.
I don't need this ready function and I've got these things coming in and one of recalibrates body right
so body is whatever's coming out.
Now there are a couple of ways we could do this.
I could tell the ball okay you can only interact with the player and your college and thus I can go
down you clearly shape and say you only interact with the player but then it's all fall through the
pitch.
That's no good.
So instead I'm just going to figure out what type of thing is touching it.
So if body is the key word gives.
Right which is checking for a certain type a class what note is it.
Is it kinematic.
What if the body is kinematic body and audio stream play a 3D.
Is playing I always forget to put the not there and not all your string player is playing.
So if those two things are true if whatevers touching you is a player and only the players are kinematic
bodies right now and there's not a thing and not audio stream player is playing.
Then I want you to play what a string player that three not play.
And that should be something we need.
Let's check.
Now that should work.
But again my God is bugged.
Right.
There's a thing happening where play is not D selecting So what it will do is save this and I'm going
to quickly restart my computer so I'm just going to pause the array here and welcome back in.
Thank you again.
It looks like just delete in the load and put it back in worked for me.
Yep that's working so let's see if that actually works in getting a switch playing off.
Now that is happening but it's very very quiet.
Let's make it louder so my maximum decibel sex change that the size of that unit is 3.
So let's see how it sounds now.
I get this.
Playing my music is to love to hear.
So that's important information.
Let's turn on the music scene for now.
So I'm going to go into my scenes here.
Open music and just for an hour and put the volume down at minus 10 minus 10.
Yeah.
So how does that sound.
Very quiet.
It's like that the all is happening sometimes.
The ball sounds happen sometimes when others if you look closely it's when the ball isn't on the ground.
That's because I've made a mistake here Kent contacts reported one.
Well the floor is constantly being reported so let's change that.
But there are three ships off the highway set that the more work and giving got in there it is.
Have a nice little kick sound which can be a little bit louder.
Let's make that even louder.
How to make this even louder.
To you that d.b. really let's put that tent I can get this but 15 let's make it loud.
OK.
That's really loud.
Now bring the music back up.
And there
is the sound of home.
Whatever it's called.
Awesome.
And that brings us to the end of the video.
In this video we've looked at how to check for no type with which we've actually done before if you
remember the glorious if button is Button experience.
That's what we've just done.
If body is kinematic body and will look at enhancing the experience by giving audio feedback at key
moments we'll put a cool soundtrack in.
I think it's called sound track if you put something else in.
Go for it.
And whatever you do shaer experience I'm dying to hear what you did.
Did you change the sound track.
Did you decide that no this isn't gonna work.
I really need some punch nails or Taylor Swift or I don't know Willie Nelson whatever does it for you
or the fraggle rock song.
Did you use a different sound effect.
I used some of the boying sound.
Did you want it playing when it hit anything.
Share what you've got so far.
Next up we're going to start putting some visual feedback one of goals scored.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.