Welcome back.
Glorious God.
People in this video.
We're going to add lives that again.
We're going to start with the concept.
How many lives we have at the beginning of the game.
We cannot keep track of the current game and were going to make it more challenging for Bunny as we
go.
So let's put the core game player into the game.
How do you do that.
Well I'll start there.
He starting lives variable in my games script then add the lives variable and then connect the spikes
to game state.
I might even rename the spike script we'll see how we go.
Finally I'm going to make Bonnie react to the spikes and not just lose a life I want money to move to
jump up when hurt so we I do all that in this video.
Let's get to it.
First thing to do is open my games state script.
Here it is.
And I'm going to create an export very.
All you know what let's go to fullscreen mode for moment as an export variable called starting out lives
and we start with three.
Why is this an export variable one notch the variable.
Well if it's an export variable it's shop in the inspector right here on my own that doesn't actually
save that much time.
Right it's it's as easy way to go to the script.
Change it here than it is changing the inspector.
But it's something that I'm probably going to tweak be tweaking quite a lot at the beginning and if
I was a large team of people if many people were working the same project the same time.
This will allow people to tweak the values when they playing the game without having to or going to
the script in all things then don't make a variable called wives and in the ready function.
I'm going to go all wives he calls starting lives nice and easy.
So the moment you Sensi first tell the games state script who you are which is what this line does and
then set the lines value to our starting lives perfect we should now create functionality for being
hurt so let's do this above end game that feels like it should be right at the end.
Let's put it here.
So a function but what's going to happen or function hurt lives minus equal one so lives giving a down
by one.
I also want to check that.
If we have no lives left.
So if you have less than zero lives and game actually right that probably shall we.
MH No more majors.
Typo.
No.
Leave the mage alone and end the game.
Poor Harry Potter being ended by.
OK this might look like an off by one error.
Right so when Ben first saw this he meant don't you mean this.
Actually I don't mean if lives are less than one.
What I mean is you can have ZERO lives left but if you have less than that you will lose the game.
Okay so we now have a hurt function.
Let's connect it let's go into our spike script and it occurs to me the script could do with renaming
and it's ruining the script.
Let's reading spike stop to what we call it has it's and something good.
Name a rename.
Hazards.
G'day.
So.
All hazards one now use the script including enemies.
Anything that you could touch that hurts you will do this.
It's now changed its names are on spikes top entered.
Doesn't really work.
I'm gonna fix that in the moment.
But for now what needs to happen.
Well global dot game States dot hut.
Okay let's see if that works.
So I should be able to answer once twice thrice and dead.
Perfect.
Now we're not updating the gooey yet will do that little later.
But first let's fix this on Spike's top body entered.
Doesn't really work.
Let's go into the subsidy for Spike and into to demote and let's reset this note so I'm going to disconnect
it.
And I'm going to connect it again to itself but give a different name.
So let's just call it on body at it.
And I'm a move this down here.
Get rid of the pass and I can get rid of that line entirely though.
When this body is entered run the hurt function in games state.
I'm doing this because now I can start using this script in enemy so it doesn't have to be spike.
We can have enemies that also use the Hasn't Judy.
Save that.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to make body react create a hurt function in the play A deedy that makes the bungee jump
when hooked up.
Pause the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And work Mac.
Okay so I need to go to play egd right here.
And we need a new function function at heart.
And when we do insert motion dot why he calls jump speed.
Why am I not just jumping because I want this to happen even if the player is not on the floor right.
If I was to just run jump has a function.
This statement here would mean that nothing would work.
So I want Bunny to jump up in the air when they touch a spike regardless of what the keyboard presses
are.
Now that's connected.
One global player got hurt.
Okay Bonnie.
Show me what you got.
One two three.
And there.
And I wasn't press any buttons which precisely in the video.
Congratulations.
With added threat to the game we have the concept of lives we haven't yet plugged the UI into this but
we're about ready to do that.
And a quickset now that you've made more ways for money to die maybe tweak the level.
I'm actually this week mine right now so COME connect to the slide the minute let's go into my tile
map for Level 1 do loop.
I know strange version of the level isn't it.
Tao map.
I actually don't like this starting one I want to go a little bit higher.
Make the process a bit more linear and let's put a cake here and give the player a reason to get there
a minute and then move you.
And let's move this spike was Spike you are the spike spike you live here.
Perfect.
Dramatic entrance and a much more linear progression loops.
I don't know if I can actually play this level.
I can play was level awesome.
So now it really and truly at the end of the video.
So Shane you little tweaks if you made them excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.