Welcome back.
Wonderful God people in this video.
We're going to set up night vision mode which is a key gameplay mechanic and heiss Meister's.
What's going to happen is the play is going to be a switch from that dark vision mode with all the torches
and see where the guards can see but not much else to a very bright night vision mode that doesn't let
them see what the guards and cameras are looking at that does reveal important information.
So very quickly what do we need.
Well we need to let the player see in the dark.
Right now we're using a lot of darkness and shadow which is very atmospheric not easy to move through.
So I'm going to make everything a much brighter green.
And we might look at some way of putting a cool down so the player can't just spammed a different vision
mode and make it easy to play the game.
Where do we start.
Well we're already changing a vision mode right.
We are using canvas modulate to make everything nice dark blue.
So I just copy this value this zero F 1 D 53 which is a hexadecimal red green blue code and look what
happens if we make this a much harsher.
Artificial grainless about us that look good.
Yeah that looks like my vision already.
This feels different.
It's all going to do is when I make a script and canvas modulate that'll switch between this vision
and this vision.
So first I going to rename canvas modulate to something more suitable as call it a vision mode and then
make a script for it which one to put in the script folder because reasons vision mode awesome and the
very first thing to do is put a constant then called dark and that's going to be colour with a capital
C and actually an equal not a minus.
And this is a string and I'm just copying pasting that hexadecimal value I had earlier.
So if I look at vision mode right here RAW mode right here and now let's pick a nice green.
So I'm thinking something very garish and a little bit brighter maybe.
That looks pretty well pretty vivid doesn't it.
That's going to be great.
OK so that is my new colour so what is that that is.
In vision mode and you constant called Night Vision.
And that's to be fi to be see 9 to be.
You can use your own values by all means pick whatever you want.
You can also make more vision modes right so if you want to go for aliens first predator you could make
a thermal vision you could make that we had the quote ultraviolet bit machine vision they use to hunt
aliens.
You could make all kinds of stuff here.
But for now I'm just going take two and to check that I'm doing this correctly.
I'll make a ready function an image ready function.
I'm going to do colour which is the property of vision mode which is a lower case which is that it always
confuses me.
He calls it dark.
Now currently we have this green colour.
If I save everything and press play we should switch to dark vision.
Which shows me that were set up correctly.
Some went back into the script and I want two more functions.
I want function night vision mode on
and not monarchal this night vision mode and the next one dark vision.
The reason I'm doing this is if we ever want to add more vision modes I don't want night vision mode
on night vision mode off vision allowed on.
I just want to switch between them in a nice logical easy to read way.
So all of these do it well.
They kind of do this in at the ready function right so when we get an idea in mode colour equals night
vision and when we go in to.
Dark vision colour.
Colour.
He calls dark alright.
I'm not putting in any conditions that say when you do this in vision mode as a as a..
Because the player's going to control that.
Great so let's go back into the play a script and please set up a variable and will make the variable
called Night Vision and let's start off with a false so we don't see one night vision.
OK this will work we can have a boolean call night vision and every time we switch vision modes Ill
go.
True False True fostering false.
However I've said I would like to make this more scalable right.
I want the possibility to add more vision modes and so instead of this instead of using a boolean which
only has two possible answers let's make an even number and a numerator.
This is kind of like a boolean sets that has various possible things you can pick but it doesn't only
have to.
We get to define what possible values it has and to do that we have none.
And when to call this vision mode equals and we use the curly brackets the curly brackets just like
we have a dictionary and I mean to put in dark night vision.
And those are the two possible things.
None can have one thing I've done wrong I've just realized incomes don't need equal sign is just some
vision.
Awesome.
Okay now what I'd like to do this year this is I'm going to set up a function in put it out.
All right so we have this plate input event now what to do from here is only go into project settings
and I want to find the input map instead of what's the current space but map to space by is Map to you
eisel Lack.
I believe there is and when I remove space from you I select and make a brand new action.
And this is going to be you I.
Vision mode change.
Let's add that and imagine Mikey.
Mikey is going to space I've just pressed the space but don't type in space.
I tried that once.
It's very confusing.
So if input dot is action just pressed.
And we called this you eye vision no change.
What we do we're going to we're going to cycle vision mode and that's going to be on next function.
Vision has a V in it.
Not a c.
Ok so I've set up the script.
When we press the key currently mapped a space you either measure change within a cycle or not.
So let's set up cycle which a motor function cycle vision mode.
And let's make some space to make this work.
We need a default position.
So our default position is going to be vision mode.
Eagles.
Doc are you with the caps.
Yes because our constant thoughts put the knee caps and night vision and that's going to be duck alright.
If vision showed equal Eagles remember two equals is checking a value one equals a setting or baggage.
The word is IF vision mode is dark.
To make a comment here change vision mode and we're going to set the vision mode.
He calls night vision.
If vision mode is night vision.
Make a comment there as well.
About to put sociables in Wiltshire skip it for now.
Vision mode equals dark.
Now I could do this with a boolean.
As I've said I can make this a toggle not a cycle but the beauty here is if I put in some vision right
I could change dark to thermal
and then do.
If vision mode is thermal and and cycle back to ducks I can just make a loop and just change as many
times I like.
So far so good.
Now we actually have to run the vision mode script.
We have to run night vision mode and dark vision.
There's a couple of ways we could do this.
We could use those global parameters and then connect a signal.
Or we could use a group.
Let me tell you very quickly about groups.
Signals are awesome.
They're great way of connecting directly to a node and saying here is a function do this function.
So when the event happens whatever that event is don't worry about it.
That's my business.
But when I send you the signal do that thing I don't need to know that thing is that's your business.
But these are one to one connections.
Right now we're establishing once one connection but later we don't want to.
I'm going to want to do things like have all MP CS turn off their torches in night vision and I will
have a bunch of labels on a map that only sharpened night vision mode so I need a way of doing mass
signal connections.
We could just use a group groups use get tree core group to go to the top of the scene tree and broadcast
a function to all members of the group and then each node decides for itself if that's relevant.
Let me show how that works over here on nodes.
You'll see we have all these signals but we also have groups and we can put in our own group.
We can call this interface and it's the group.
I'm actually not going to do it that way.
I'm going to do it in script.
So you add to group and call this interface is later.
I want a bunch of other things to always change when ever the group interface functions are called.
This is good because I'm going to add other things to this group later and then the player can just
call one function to everything in that group.
Let's show you how that works.
When I go to my cycle vision mode.
If we're dark We're going into night vision.
So what it does is when you get tree call group.
A core group can take a look at its documentation.
It takes a string name for the group a string name for the method and then Vara tag via a haag which
is it's not all keish.
It's variable.
Arguments you put as many arguments as you need to.
So let's look at vision code and see what function we have we have vision night vision mode and dark
vision spiracles dark vision mode the night vision mode Darfur.
So Mplayer core group was the nervous interface as a double check I spelt that right because you know
me in typing.
In fact I got a copy paste.
Just because peace of mind.
Okay what function we call it where we're going in to night vision and the function is called Night
Vision mode.
Note by the way I am not copying the brackets I'm just copying the words and it's going to be a string
so night vision.
And I don't need any arguments.
So now I do the same thing over here.
Get tree call group
interface
and let's just double check what I called it.
I gave him a copy paste because of my typing dark vision mode.
Before I go any further I just realized I can't actually use is here I have to use equal or so equally
equal not it's.
I'm so sorry.
That was my fault.
Let's just put it minus one thing I have noticed.
I've done a very silly thing here.
I've got two if statements so is going to run this if statement.
It won't stop and it'll run this.
So what is actually there.
Do you see.
Are you in Doc mode.
Yes.
Great call.
The vision of change.
Set to vision mode set to night vision with night vision.
Yes you are.
So let's put an elf and that.
Should meme.
That we can all change vision.
Look at that.
Outstanding.
Which brings me to the challenge for you.
So over time around and get the players to have to wait.
What a dissimilar time it could be a second degree five seconds.
Pick a number that feels right to you.
And let's set that up so the player has to wait before they can switch that tallyman again pause the
video give that a shot.
When you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
I feel like the the smartest place to put this is in the players the players time.
So let's put that right here as a child of of player and I'm going to give this a what feels it two
seconds.
See how that works.
Let's rename this vision mode timer because I suspect players can have a couple of times going on and
connect it as a signal so on time out in play are on vision mode timer timeout.
Great.
And here I'm going to put in a another booleans probably put it right here make their own category so
variable.
This is going to be what we call it we call this vision change on cooldown and this can be false.
Let's make this a big screen.
I'll just double check.
Vision mode on.
Down.
Typing.
Alright so.
Put it right here.
And vision mode on.
Cool down.
Is that right.
Vision mode on cool down didn't auto complete So that's double check not dating silly.
OK.
And we don't want to get called elsewhere on and not vision mode or called out.
So currently there's a model called Dallas false.
So that should work tight cycle vision mode and I'm going to go.
There's an old timer dot start then but I actually put the madon call down to true so vision mode I
call down Legal's.
True.
Let's copy that and down here vision my time out let's say that's a false.
Get rid of these random spaces between functions.
We don't need those.
Let's give that a shot an image of span space bar.
Again feels Come along doesn't it.
I get it.
I will set my time at a slightly shorter.
What have I got set to right now.
But that's it's two seconds.
That was two seconds.
That said it's a one point five.
See how that feels.
Yeah looks pretty good.
Okay.
Later on in the Gooly will make we'll give it some sort of feedback to the player and see when it's
charged.
But for now that's pretty good.
One more thing I do want to do I want to give vision mode a sound effect so let's put in an audio stream.
Play up.
And if we go over to sound effects so effects you see here we've got night vision wave and night vision
of where we use those to.
I do want to put these in global So for now we're left click on Want a copy path and then let's open
the global Scripsit back in the scripts global It's right here.
And these are going to be assets as it links we up and make a note must be changed manually so we don't
forget.
OK.
So we have variable night vision on SFX equals that variable night vision off effects equals.
That alright.
Save that and now in vision mode I could put.
The.
Stream we want so the stream property is going to be not stream.
Our audio stream player dot stream he calls global dots night vision on SFX because we're going into
night vision and we want to play that.
Now it's copy that and paste it here if we were using this more than twice and make this a little different.
I would make a new function call.
In fact let's do that let's make a new function called Audio place out effect.
So let's move you go play SFX.
Play us effects is going to live over here.
It's just going to be audio string players play.
And that needs a column.
Now one thing that's going to happen is this is going to crash in our show for press play.
It's going to say what you're loading a string you can't load a string.
Right.
The reason for that stop that the reason for that is I don't want to load a string.
I want to have files and when to cast it as a file using a load and that just tells it this is a file
not a string so convert whatever this is into a file Pressplay and we should have a very exciting.
So we had some an on sound off sound because I made two mistakes one that's off and two I'm not calling
the function.
This apparently is a day for silly mistakes.
So there we are.
Let's give that a shot and we should have some very dramatic on sounds of sounds.
We are in very good shape.
Which brings us to the end of the video.
In this video will introduce groups which are awesome and I love them and the like signals but supercharged
we've actually switched vision modes and we've introduced in arms which are also awesome that the power
of booleans.
But more so.
So we were in really good shape.
Excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.