Hello again you delightful go to people in this video.
We to start work on locked doors now are locked doors won't open by the end of this what going to do
is when a make a basic locked door and have the number pad pop up when you need it and close when we
leave it which I didn't mean to rhyme but it kind of did.
So this is the first part of locked doors and to do this we're going to learn about extending scripts.
We can extend the door script.
We already have four locked doors script.
We should talk a little bit about extending and inheriting.
We've already looked at inheriting scenes which is when we make a simple let's say NPC script and then
the gods will inherit from that scene.
We can add things to it.
It's one thing to note when we talk about scripts and scenes we extend scripts.
We inherit scenes they broadly work the same way.
It's interesting to note that scripting is just extending the functionality of a note.
So if I make a Sprite and then I put a script on it it's going to extend that sprite no so anything
I add to it is sprite.
Plus these new bits nodes extend functions from parent nodes.
So for example a let's say can somatic body 2D extends from physics body 2D which extends from something
else something else all the way up to basic node.
So it'll have access to all the functionality of physics body 2D which will have all functionality of
the next node up and so on.
So let's go into Gaza and I'm gonna make brain you see it do that.
I'm going to open the original door scenes which I click here on Dorsey.
Here's my original dosing and I'm going to I want to make a new scene based on this.
I actually don't need to be in the scene I just wanted to show you the difference.
So going to a scene I'm going to a new inherited scene.
Okay.
New inherited scene.
We've already done this so it shouldn't be too difficult.
I extend from someone to open the bass scene door and before I go any further I'm going to rename it
so I don't get confused on call this locked door.
You'll notice everything here is gray.
This is what is in the original.
That hasn't changed.
Let's say that in the doors folder and we've a brand new inherited scene cool.
First thing let's give a different sprite.
So the texture for this is can be a little different on the graphics on the PMG under tiles is.
Here it is this one right here tile for six three looks.
Can I steel door that looks like a locked door to me.
I think supposed to be a light I'm using as a locked door.
I'm fine with that.
Okay.
Now we want the pop up to be a child of locked doors so the pop up can come up.
So using at child or I could use control.
A I'm gonna find my number pad right here.
I just type in num pad and there it is.
You'll notice right now it's below the door.
That's gonna be in a little bit of an issue for us when we put this into the scene.
You're gonna see this behind bits of scenery and that's no use.
So what we did was save this and go back to level 1.
Now I want to add this to the template.
Remember level 1 is inheriting from the template scene.
So let's go back into the template and add a brand new category for locked doors.
So control a this time new node and when to rename that to locked doors.
Great save that.
And here we are on level 1.
Now on the locked doors I can bring in an instance of locked door.
And here is my sense of locked door and you can already see the number pad which currently is showing
it won't show when the game starts but it's currently showing and I can move this into position lets
you not only get rid of which door is that door three times and delete that for now delete note.
Yes I'm sure of a locked door there and I'm going to rotate this by 90 so transform rotates 90 degrees
and look already you can see this is an issue.
So how do we fix this.
Let's save this.
I don't need template level when I close that locked door.
Control a and I want a canvas layer.
Interesting to note canvas layer is a direct child of node.
Node doesn't have positional information it doesn't have a transform It's a canvas layer doesn't either.
Another could see this is does not have a child no pet is if I right click on it and open the documentation
you can see right here inherits node so it has access to everything node can do but nothing else no
pad has access to a bunch of other things so if I look up in that documentation it inherits control
canvas item node control click here does have access to this information so I'm sure to close that window
we don't need it I don't need to pop up I don't need canvas layer let's just stick to the information
all of this is a way of saying if I put the number as a child of canvas layer it's now inheriting the
property for canvas land and canvas layer doesn't have the translation that we'd have from other things.
Right so we got to transform for x and y we have position information doesn't exist here.
That's important because it means that this is now going to be centred on the camera on the screen not
on the object.
So I save that and go back to level 1.
There's a number of had is now here on the item so far so good but it doesn't do anything.
Now it's time to extend a script.
So back to look all I'm going to delete this script which can use this delete script button.
Easiest way of doing it and now locked doors don't have a script.
Doors do locked doors don't.
Not quite what I want this given new script I'm right here it says inherits area 2D.
So right now.
Doors extend the functionality of area 2D.
But if I click on this I can pick a scene like a script not a scene pick dodgy deals and now it inherits
resources.
Doors door G.D. I want to create it you can see that here in the extends that's what this line is telling
you.
So if I go to door this extends area to the area 2D plus these functions locked door is this plus whatever
we write in here.
So let's see how that's going to work.
What I would do is want to get a door and I'm going to take the.
When we click on it when we click on it's like it's going to happen.
Locked doors don't just open we have to put a combination in.
So I'm going to copy these three lines back to locked doors and put this function in.
This function will now overwrite the one in door so in locked doors until input does something different.
Was that something different.
Well we're gonna pop up the the number pad so I'm going to get the number pad types up typing number
pad.
There it is and it's a pop up so I can just use a pop up sent it will come back pop up there you're
sent it is a sense of that a screen.
OK so now let's see how that looks.
Here I am a level that it just gives us my screen like there's my locked doors in a locked door Now
the guards have to get through that nice and easy.
Perfect.
But when I try and get through this click on it and that's my number pad and look how that works.
Pressing locks it's not wired in right now so I'll do anything.
We've also got a bit of an issue.
If I click away from it it'll close but if I walk around it'll stay where it is.
Let's make that a little bit easier.
Let's give me my challenge to you.
I would like you to get rid of a number pad when the player leaves the door area.
So we already have that detection area when the player leaves that detection area have the pop up varnish.
Use the hide function to make this easier is not the only way of doing this but it's the simplest avoid
using q free.
You don't want to vanish from the scene we do want to come back.
So pulls the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
OK so we've already got here this functionality.
So what I want to do is go back to doors and I want find a door exited and I copy that back to a locked
door and put this in here.
So this is saying on door body exited ignore whatever is here and do this instead.
Well we do want to do this right.
If body collision late equals one.
In other words if you're the player then we want to go to you can click.
We also want to hide the number pad.
And that's very simple we just go.
Number pad is there.
Not hide.
Okay.
Let's see how that works.
Get it again and make it nice and bright sexy we're doing get to the door.
We don't have any penalty being spotters on a care about that.
Let the guard go through first doesn't confuse things to make up your mind.
Thank you.
OK.
Excuse me.
This is my door.
Go away.
OK.
Click on it.
It's right there.
Move away.
It goes away.
So right there we now have a number pad ready to be wired into a lock.
Right now just a pretty UI element that doesn't do anything but it will.
And I think that's a really good piece of progress.
So in this video we've looked at extending scripts we've showed how to what would pop up notes and a
little introduction to canvass lands.
So excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.