Hello again.
God the people of pure liquid awesomeness because I wanted to use a different greeting but it ended
up being mostly the same.
We're going to continue with fun with furniture in this video to make rigid bodies the ones are going
to be affected by physics before we start.
A couple of quick reminders.
One remember that the origin is the centre of gravity so the origin of the rigid body is what we really
care about in terms of how is this body going to behave.
Don't be afraid to tweak values if your desk is moving too fast or too slow.
You can tweak the speed of your projectile linkage.
You can tweak the weight of it and you could tweak the weight of the actual rigid body.
Let's get into it and take a look back and aren't models and our furniture we have all of these different
things we can use.
And you are under no obligation to use all of them but there are some fun ones here by both Kenyan attorneys
that I thought might be fun.
So feel free to use them.
I'm going to start with a simple tiny one I want to put a little radio up here so make a new scene.
And let's make a start.
With a rigid body.
Right.
And the reason I'm going to do this this way is actually not do the other way and show you why.
If I go into the level that seems to bring in a mesh I would bring in my radio was not really a coffee
machine.
What I am seeing right here.
Here's a coffee machine.
And I'm going to just move it down to the actual surface.
Now it's currently way too big.
We know that I'm going to scale it down to zero point five.
Now I want to turn this into an actual rigid body as a couple things I could do.
I could just give it a sibling.
But that's just going to put two things at the same level.
I could also give it a static body but I don't want to be a static body but let's say I give it a convex
static body which is fine.
And I decide I'm going to change this from static body to a rigid body which I can absolutely do is
now a rigid body.
The origin is here and I need the origin in the centre.
Actually with this coffee machine it probably won't matter too much because it's quite plonked down
and let's say I want it you know down the centre.
Actually it's move this off a bit so it's outside the counter.
Great.
If I want to move that I'd have to move the static body and the static body has the collision shape
and that's going to cause me all kinds of problems.
Do I move it like so.
And then just move the colours shake back.
Which is doable but is kind of a pain.
So instead I'm going to use the static body as the parent and add the mesh in.
So let's do that.
I've got my my rigid body right here not static body rigid body call coffee machine
and my coffee machine is going to have mesh and you can drop that in there and scale it down so transform
zero point five zero point five zero point five.
It is awesome.
And let's add in the collisions so I'm going to give you a sibling This time a convex sibling and that's
too big once again so you can scale that down.
I know.
Don't scale them.
But unfortunately this is my only choice right now unless I want to give it just a capsule or a sphere
which I don't.
And now I can move them meche instance and the collision shape but to move them rough and ready and
then type in the numbers to get them much more centred so take that off.
So you are what's zero point five.
That makes sense.
OK.
So on the exar point to Fife.
Oh that's scale.
No don't go.
So translate mazunte point to five minus zero point five.
And I'm guessing on the Y minus zero point two five.
And there is my coffee machine at my coffee machine.
It's looking pretty good.
And the centre of gravity is right in the centre of it which is where I want to save this as a scene.
We go into furniture and make a new folder called rigid body just to make it as organized that can save
the coffee machine and instance one in so under furniture let's make a new organizing note.
I'm going to call this rigid bodies.
And incense in my coffee machine motto and drink my coffee one second.
See I've got this cup of coffee next to me and I keep saying coffee machine and it makes me want to
drink the coffee.
So I did apologize for that.
Are edit out the sound of me actually drinking.
What was I doing.
I can't remember.
There's going to furniture and rigid body and bring in a coffee machine and pretend that that's what
I was doing going to do some scootching so scooched the coffee machine.
And I don't think it needs to be at 40.
Whoops that's just rotate you doesn't actually flush because it's a rigid body it's not for it's not
part of the walls or the furniture.
Was going to put it over here.
Let's see how that looks.
Back in the game and I'm not going to toggle full screen.
And the reason why is occasionally Gado can Tasia which is I'm using to record an end video.
Don't like talking to each other and sometimes I hit toggle fullscreen it will record and sometimes
it won't.
I'm going to use this button and there's my coffee machine and it flies and that's really satisfying
and I kick it.
Yes I can.
Can I Kick It.
If you are not of Generation X if you're a Millennial or baby boomer you might not recognize that song.
I can't help you with that but there is my first piece of furniture.
Okay there's only so many of those I need to use.
I mean I could put in a microwave.
But let's go with something a bit more interesting.
I'm thinking a table and some chairs so we pick a nice table as an ice table but there's coffee table
and quite like the look of that.
There's big table and I've got the small table I think small tables one of what stocktwits here's my
small table.
It's not going to be a child of coffee machines could put it here.
I was taking a look to make sure that the scales go makes sense so I think it should be zero point seven
five.
Yes it should.
OK so here is my zero point seventy five table it's actually a little bit high.
Still that's where it should be awesome.
I mean to use that small table and I will pick some chairs to some basic dining chairs.
I could mix and match between them but I'm happy with that.
However this isn't where that lives.
Let's delete this one.
That was just me checking it's going to fit.
And let's make a new Richard what he called table which I call a small table.
Call it a small table that's keep to the same name the files and you get a mesh instance and you get
a mesh instance every everybody sari goes there and scale that down to zero point seventy five on all
three axis and this is going to need a coalition shape.
Now I think I'm going to go with a trimester for this and the reason why is if this is upside down I
want to able to run through the legs and let the food go through the legs.
If it doesn't it's going to break the illusion some leaves a trimester but I can't see the tremor.
So I'm just going to have to assume that zero point seventy five or work it should do.
I can't see why it wouldn't.
And now let's make sure that they are all actually that's perfect isn't it that's where their origins
should be some so save that as my small table was going to bring a chair.
Let's just bring in one chef and how close those scenes Brando saying and do the same thing again so
rigid body.
This one's going to be called a chair and another mesh instance of a chair and the exact same thing.
Scale it
add a trimester.
Collision sibling and scale that
centre of gravity is good.
I like that.
Save that and I can add those into my scene so let's just see how they look.
I'm going to start.
Are you not rigid body is going to get another child note and that's be for tables and chairs.
Can you make this as organized as I can so let's instance in a single small table.
And it doesn't matter if it's not fully on the ground because gravity will work.
But.
It is nice to get it as close as I can.
So let's put it right there.
It probably shouldn't be in the doorway should it.
Because of reasons it doesn't make sense to block a doorway like that especially not with the by settlers
coming through.
So let's stick with that and start adding some chairs.
So chair.
And you should probably be somewhere like that.
How's that look.
That looks pretty good.
A duplicate a chair and I don't need these.
On the grid or exactly at 90 degrees because they look more real as if they're not this do this church
again rotate it's by roughly that much and zoom it over here.
I'm not going to pull a chair here because I want to know what a light and a chair it
rotates it's Press.
If I rotate not ah.
And how do you look.
You are actually clipping into the other chair you how's that.
Still clipping a cut clip through the furniture on it.
We had objects being thrown up into the air.
Yeah that looks good.
OK.
Start again.
They need to be a lot heavier don't they.
So let's make them heavier.
OK.
Table.
What's your mass.
Pretty small.
OK.
Now as far as I remember those are in kilograms 1 kilograms like a bag of sugar.
So let's go with 10 kilograms as heavy table and shares.
You know I'm going to play with this and see what happens.
I feel like the chair should be roughly the same weight.
Because reasons.
See how that works.
Okay so they now react.
But they're much heavier and I can keep tweaking.
I was right.
Yeah that's looking really good.
I could also make the food less I'm what I'm looking for.
Let's fast.
I can make the food slower.
That's the word.
And I could make it lighter but that's a good start.
So I have those tables and chairs and you know what let's put in one more object.
How about this nice potted plant.
One of these potted plants I think this potted plant looks good.
So just go through the entire thing one more time.
Rigid body with a mesh instance which is a small potted plant which is going to be even smaller not
material transformed there is zero point seven five actually on this one it probably doesn't matter
too much.
But I'm just going to keep it the same.
And that one does get a convex mesh I think which will be the same size because otherwise makes no sense.
And finally I now need to move these to the centre of the origin.
Why is the behaviour that looks.
Pretty good.
Let's call you plant small
that I nailed that right.
No he didn't.
OK.
Plant small save that scene and let's bring in a small plant.
Apparently I have.
I didn't think I did.
I don't have snap on that.
No it was snapping.
How do you look.
You look amazing.
Awesome.
Now those chairs might be a little bit heavy now so I'm just going to make them a bit lighter.
How do you feel about 7.
And that's looking great.
Now Amma's which can sleep off and would do that for that table as well.
And I'm going to do that for the plant as well.
Say all three of those.
Now I could switch on continuous contact detection which is great for fast moving objects.
I'm actually gonna put that on.
It might slow the game down so if your game starts chugging quite slowly once you do this you can switch
it off.
But our project does a very fast so let's see how that works.
Just make sure that haven't broken anything.
Make the screen bigger.
Yes looking pretty awesome isn't it.
I also notice I have a habit of looking down when I'm playing these games before I hand this over one
more trick I want to give you.
In fact I don't know what came out of the game.
Let's go back into the game.
One more trick I want to give you.
And that's I kind of want to see through this wall.
Now currently there isn't an easy way to stop the camera going through the wall.
There is a node we can use in three point one but I'm not using throughput one.
So instead I'm going to change the wall.
Let's pick any one of these was doesn't really matter which one I pick and enter that scene because
I'm picking this dark colour as my front and as white as my rear.
All I need to do is change this material.
So let's open the mesh.
Doesn't matter which mesh and find this surface.
And when I click on it and across the top of the flags and switch on Transparent.
Now this material is transparent and want to go to albedo.
If I switch the Alpher down to I don't know how about 100.
It sounds like a good number.
When I save this material that might save the scene and go back in.
You'll notice
that the white of the walls is now semitransparent.
So let's see how that plays.
It's nice and big.
And now I don't lose track of what's happening and I can actually see them looking through the wall.
It's not perfect but it's pretty good for now.
All right.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I think he can probably see where this is going.
I'd like you to fabricate some fabulous furniture create some rigid body scenes.
Add them to your level share them with the community add as many or as few as you like.
Okay now you do need enough room to wander around and remember if you block off the path of the bystanders
they're going to just bump into it but have fun with it.
Enjoy it.
Other great synonyms for you know.
Have a good time.
Pause the video create a level when you come back I'll show you my level.
And welcome back.
Okay so here's my current level now it's a little bit crowded.
I might have put a few more for you too many tables.
In fact let's move some of these Making sure I've got my select all.
I'm going to select this chair hopes to try again this chair this table and this chair come up.
Just move them over here.
Did you get figure at this can go over there as well.
And a couple of plants in a big plant shut up go out a foot a bigger plant over here which of hilariously
called bigger plants small.
Well I called it plant small too.
That's what I call it.
But that's looking pretty solid.
I think we're getting close to there.
Not sure this chair wants to be here you know what am I might just give myself a bit more space on the
what axis is that x.
Yeah that's Z.
That's X but that's.
In glorious large screen is pretty cool.
And I could if I wanted to fire was this plant just make it top of it.
I got a coffee machine that can bite the bullet for us by coffee machine.
Yeah we're looking pretty solid.
And just before I finish I've realized that I got a Reece's everything wrong so I've just changed the
chairs.
But I didn't mean zero point seven five I meant zero point five.
I'm not quite sure how I managed to get that quite wrong but that's okay I can change these mesh instance
zero point five
and I will do the same with the collision shapes.
I'm going to do that really quickly for all of these scenes I've opened so plant small you could name
one transformer on the mesh instance to zero point five.
And again with the collision shape.
Save that when a seal doesn't need changing the plant small does.
And it came with a collision shape
and now we're back into my level.
That's looking a lot less terribly crowded.
Let's take a look at how it works.
Much better than other plants did fall down quite comically and things are flying way fast right now.
But I quite like that these tables is small.
I know I like that.
I might do as low off the firing forward on the character later but that can't happen later.
So that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video the old looked at working with rigid body objects.
And with that as a slight transparency to material transparency no transparency to material which is
allowing the camera to see through it.
So don't forget to show your progress how your levels are looking.
And if we want to add a lot more levels to this game and excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.