Hello again you fantastic go to people.
Let's continue with locked doors.
We're going to create a random combination for every group of locked doors.
I'm saying group because later on we might have multiple doors with us in combination with give us the
option.
First let's talk about how combinations work and heist meisters first.
All combinations are an array.
Now we've covered this in a couple of videos.
But the idea here is that we can have variable lengths.
We can do a lot of stuff with it which means combinations or varying lengths.
So we need that in our combination.
And we're going to return the combination to another script.
This is because if the player is going to go get a combination by reading a computer know you know hack
into someone's computer find the combination we need the door connected to that computer to know what
the combination is.
So we're going to have to have the combinations in a different place.
So what I want to do is I want to create a system whereby there is one thing that makes combinations
that's just what it does.
I want to follow the principle of single responsibility and we're going to query that and get a combination
back to do that.
I'm going to use an auto load or a singleton.
So let's take a moment to talk about what a singleton or an auto loan is.
Any single script can be made persistently available.
So this means it exists in the background of our game.
It doesn't matter what scene we have loaded.
Remember we can change levels and we end loading screens.
It's still loaded in the background is kind of a layer above everything else the Singleton could be
accessed by any script so any script can query it.
It's always wanting or we can have a scene that's playing background music consistently.
We need to be very careful with these it might be tempting to put everything in there as it also loaded
a global variable all our variables or objects in music accessible from everywhere.
Be very careful because this is how you get spaghetti code.
We want to make sure the only things that need to be accessed in multiple places are access to multiple
places.
Quick Hand on heart here.
The first time I did this course I put everything in singletons everything and also loads.
This solves a bunch of problems but causes a bunch of others let's keep this very clean if we need information
transferred constantly.
We can use group calls we can use signals but in a case like this where combination is going to be generated
for every single computer and door in every single level we could probably put this is not allowed.
So let's look at how we do that.
First I'm going to make a brand new script.
I don't really this scene for this I could in theory go to a template level and make a new node called
combination generation do it here.
But I'm going to do a new script Sysco script view a file new script and it's gonna be empty.
I'm going to put it just show what I pressed on whereas this path is like click on a little follow button.
So it's a little bit fossil element to be let's put it indoors and we're going to name this combination
generator dot G.D..
Perfect.
When I create that and it's now created and saved and got to go.
Now this script is accessible everywhere in this video where outlets come out of template level in this
video would just affect the locked door.
So this locked door here is going to generate a combination.
We're gonna print it out to the output down here and have it actually use that lock.
So rather new 0 4 5 1 will generate a new four digit combination.
OK.
So to do that I'm going to go into this new script I just made it back in the script had the Coalition
generator.
This is a script with no note.
It's going to auto load in the background but that's how going to do that.
How do we get it to auto load project and project settings at the top here.
You'll see general input map and input map is where we changed all of our different keys localization
for languages and auto load.
That's what we want.
Now right now nothing is auto loaded.
You'll see we've got a little list that will populate with a name.
The path to it and what we are actually loving the Singleton to add to this list we know to this folder
by the path I want to find the combination generator we just made the doors combination generator and
press add you have to press add make sure it's enabled because you could have in the backgrounds and
disable it which you could do an engine if we had background music and so on but we just make sure it's
running in the background.
OK.
So now I have this brand new combination generator script that does absolutely nothing so let's make
it do something and we'll give it a single function called generate a combination here and I need to
know how long this combination will be so let's bring in length.
So now whatever is calling this function is going to give it this argument here is this integer here.
And what we need to do well is create our variable so combination and it's just a blank array and then
we could do a simple for loop.
So for number in range of length.
Now remember you look past for now.
Remember this argument here number is being created just for that.
That's nice but length that takes about length this number here is whatever I needed to be this is a
brand new argument so it's going to start at zero and head up until it hits whatever number this is
I could call it I that's traditional I'm going to call it number in length we can call it I don't know.
Headphones.
That's a stupid name but we could go to we have no problem with that.
Doesn't matter what you call us.
OK.
So for the number in range of length what do we need to do we need to append to that arrays.
That's good combination.
Dot append and what we're putting into putting a random integer modulo by 10 and random integer is a
function is that OK so just to talk through what we're doing we are running this as a loop every time
this number is in range of length so zero one two three.
Then I want combination that should be combination to get this array here to add in a random integer
and we're gonna modulo 10.
Effectively we're going to say okay go from zero to nine.
What's going to happen is every time we get some number 10 it just goes cycle round again.
So effectively we're saying pick a number between zero and nine.
Finally we need to actually have that combination commencements go return combination and that is our
combination generator currently I'll do anything for the moment let's put it in a locked door so in
locked door I'm just going to have a nice ready function.
So let's go to function.
Ready so when you're ready to go here's what I want you to do.
I want you to generate a combination now for the moment we're doing this locked door.
Later we'll be making computers and they'll be sending a signal to the locked door.
But for now just to get something working so we can see it actually running can function and generate
a combination.
And let's give us a little bit of space to work with.
OK so the first thing to do is I want to actually get this combination for now let's have a length of
four you know what we could put this up here.
Well now I'm sure to put this in the script for now the computer will be in charge of doing that set
on this the door right now.
But let's say I want to generate a combination to do that.
I'm going to run combination generator and it's already accessible because we've put it as an auto load
at a singleton.
We can access it not just IT but all of its functions.
So look generate combinations we're good to go.
Now we need an argument so that's going to be for right that's all length for is kind of a magic number
I don't really want that there.
So what I want to do is I must say variable length length is a terrible variable but for now I will
say length equals four.
So that is just gonna run this.
But look we're not setting these variables when he thinks that this will work.
This will run.
What we're doing is we're saying to go to.
Okay.
Think of a four digit number.
And then we're not asking for it.
So let's make this a variable.
Of course variable combination equals combination generator generate combination with the length of
four.
In other words gotto here's a new variable call combination and to get the value of that and would you
go to this script and run this function with this argument.
Think of a four digit number that's we're asking to do.
Now we need to set the combination in our number pad so let's get a number pad you see here we have
combination it is set to 0 for 5 1 we can leave as a default but I'm going to keep this as a blank so
I would say that and get back to my lock door and now we want to set that.
So let's make sure in the right scenes that auto completes locked door is the single to me back into
distraction free mode.
Okay.
So now we want to actually change the combination in the number pad so let's go.
No I've had do do do do you not.
Box contain that you're actually the number pad and I can see that by going back over here and there
it is a canvas layer at number pad and another pad has a value it has a value called combination and
that's going to be combination
OK.
Finally I want to know what that combination is so I can use it.
So for now I'm going to put this on the console and I want to print the combination.
But the combination is an array.
This is not a string print needs a string.
So let's make it a string in a cast that as a string and let's just separated out so I can see it nice
and easy.
Now if I've done this correctly come out of here so I can see the output.
Want to get into the game we have a four digit code 8 6 1 6.
If I go to the door open 8 6 1 6 door opens I can sneak past this light.
And there we go.
So we have a working door.
So now here's my challenge for you.
I would like you to change the script to generate an eight digit combination.
Now this isn't especially difficult but lets you see how familiar you are.
How comfortable are with it supports the video.
Give it a shot.
When you come back I'll show you my solution
and walk back.
OK well this is quite simple right.
For now we've got everything in this function.
Right now I've got legacies for put like this eight And look I never actually change this so let's put
this length.
So we have now generate combination of eight digits and I come out of here so I can see the output.
And here we go.
A nice simple eight digit combination.
0 4 8 4 3 7 8 1.
Goodness me that's annoying.
Let's not use too many of those.
But there we have it we have a nice locked door with an eight digit combination.
And that brings the end the video.
So in this video we looked at creating a combination object a script that's going to be auto loaded.
It's gonna be a singleton.
It can exist permanently in the background of a game no matter what seat we have loaded.
We're gonna generate combinations ready for our computers and we've played with more.
So excellent luck and we'll see you in the next video.