Hello again you delight forgotten people.
Let's finish happy days.
Let's give the player a way of beat in the game.
In this video we're gonna talk about portals and particles what's going to happen is the player's going
to hit a portal which is going to be emitting particles.
Let's start by talking about the design of our portal players going gonna beat the level if Bunny touches
the portal.
It's an exit a goal.
The portal is going to float right.
Just hang in the air so give us a slight animation.
Nothing major.
Just something to you know make it look like it's magical and drifting.
Speaking of magical the portal is going to emit particles little sprites that float around the place
with a nice beautiful magical thing finding it hard to find the words for it.
Let's just do it.
See how it looks.
Before we go into that though we should design an end screen right.
We need a scene to go to if the player wins.
Now if we look in levels we've actually got a scene very like that we've got game over.
Try again.
We could make a copy of this scene.
Call it victory a sort of game over.
Say you win or victory is mine or hooray for bunnies and instead of try again play again.
How would we do that.
Well what we'll do is we have seen and we go new inherited scene.
Okay what's the base scene.
What scene I'm inheriting from I'm inheriting from game over which is the default.
Great.
Open that and we're now in a brand new scene which I'm going to call victory and save that in the same
place and you'll see here that everything is great out everything that is great out is what's being
inherited.
Just like if I go to Level 1 if I go to any of these instant scenes and see the player go right click
editable children and then open it up everything that I'm instantly into the scene is great out.
Let's just get rid of the children that really need it right now.
What this tells me is I can change any of these things and I'll be able to see the changes for example
in this text box here or is his game over.
Let's just say you win and I'll try again.
I could write play again.
You'll notice everything has recent in itself because we use the right containers when we made the UI
element.
So that is actually good to go.
We now have a scene we can go to.
So that done let's make a brand new scene.
And this will be a 2D scene.
I'm going to call it portal and let's save that and let's say the under what's a portal maybe an item
I guess is an item similar to that.
OK.
So we have a nice empty scene with nothing in it.
Well we need an area 2D and that's going to need a sprite.
Why not an animated sprite.
I thought going to enemy this well.
Because if we look into graphics and items you'll see that we have a portal here but there's only one
sprite for it is only one pitch.
So I will put my portal in here.
And here is my portal.
And let's give that a collision shape.
So collision shape 2D.
There we are.
And we just make this nice simple rectangle it doesn't matter too much if this is pixel perfect.
If Bunny lands here we're going to assume the bunny wants to land in.
Maybe make a little bit smaller.
Yeah.
Let's get can hide that.
OK.
So we want to animate this let's put an animation player and make a new animation called portal stretch.
That's a strange name but it'll do for now.
Two seconds.
Going to auto play and loop and it can just have a one second step.
That's fine.
Go to my area 2D transform and on the scale.
I'm just gonna create a key right there and one second.
What do we just stretch this to one point five and see how that looks.
Make a key there and then I press play.
It's not bad.
It's OK.
Maybe a bit too farther.
Get back to my key and I can change it right here in the key one point two five.
Let's see how that looks.
Yeah that looks pretty good.
OK.
So now I have a very simple little portal I'm just gonna put it into my level so we can see what they
look like.
I guess now right here's a good place to put it an instance in my portal
and move it to the right place.
I feel like putting it here because that gives us a reason to jump down.
So let's just see if I can actually get to it
took some damage that might do to do my own games a little bit tricky.
La la la la la Oh took more damage but luckily I got life.
That's OK.
Oh this is surprisingly tense.
I made it.
You are animating nice and subtle.
That looks good.
OK.
Whatever some particles in it didn't night.
Let's go back to the portal.
Let's add a new child and this is going to be particles 2D.
And what this is going to do is emit a certain thing.
Now you'll notice right now is a warning straight away.
It says you need a material to process.
There is no material to process material.
It says empty.
This is what is the particle.
Now we can look over here and particles and you'll see we've got this portal yellow particle.
Perfect.
Let's make a new particles material click on that and we have everything we need right here.
So first off it needs texture and we should drag in Portal yellow particle right there.
OK.
Here are our particles.
Now a lot of things we can do with it some of it is going to be inside the material some of it's going
to be in the time so I could give each particle a lifetime.
That's how long will each particle last.
I've told it you're allowed eight particles so at any given point there are eight particles.
After two seconds a particle will die at which point another one will replace it.
I could give it a bunch more particles 64 to and it'll calculate what that's going to look like.
I can also make these one shot which means I'll file once and then they won't replace not what I want
in this case.
So I'm going to do that and let's if I switch that off.
It's easy to go missing off and on.
OK.
Other things we can do.
I can give it a randomness.
What does that do.
Well if I mouse over it'll tell us emission lifetime.
Randomness ratio.
Okay.
So right now a lifetime of two.
But what if there's some leeway in that.
Now you see some are closer together some further apart.
Okay so I've got a drawing process and we've got all these other things here in mission shape is a good
one right now there's a point.
What if this isn't the point what if this is a sphere.
Well I can't see that right now because they're not moving.
You got gravity that's which gravity of okay.
So we've got them here.
They're in gravity.
Now a sphere radius of one mount.
That's too small.
That's right 64.
Huh.
Okay.
We have some magic happening it's starting to look a little more like it.
Right.
And what if we get a velocity let's say initial velocity.
Let's give you initial velocity of 15 I feel like we can have more of these.
I'm basically just playing with options and see what I can make.
Let's have many more to 24.
Okay.
The kind of drifting how going to get them orbiting.
Let's give you an orbital velocity.
Well that's fast.
Zero point five zero point two five okay.
What if I get rid of the initial velocity all right.
That's looking a little better.
I feel its fear radius needs to be a bit bigger.
About 80 128 double it.
Okay.
Not too bad now as you can see there's a lot more.
Play with it.
Get it out another radial.
So much good is spreading out so I can do this linkage to the online documentation so if we scroll down
we see larger different settings and examples where they look like you can really customize.
This is a lot you can do with particles and that feels like a good place to but the challenge.
So my challenge to you customize your particles find some settings you like play with it explore the
documentation Don't be afraid to mess around with settings.
Worst case scenario you can just remove the particles 2D and start from scratch.
We'll just press on do a bunch of times so pulls the video customize your portal and when you come back
we'll move on from the
And welcome back.
OK so we've got everything here except the portal doesn't work right.
So if I run a game and I somehow managed to get to the portal without dying which might happen if I
somehow let's just pretend that didn't happen get to my portal without dying
I should have given myself an easier level.
And here my particles but the portal doesn't work right.
So let's actually make it work.
So what we do is first I'm going to go to Level 1 open a script make sure I'm in game state and I need
to add a win game function of the end game was at win game.
And what's this going to do it was going to exactly like a change scene game over but instead of game
over I'm going to change scene victory.
OK so just go get tree change theme and just drag victory in here.
La la la la la.
Perfect.
Okay so now we need a way of calling this now a couple of things I could do.
I could use a signal right now.
You'll notice that portal the way I've set it up is actually in no 2D no 2D don't have that kind of
signal.
I've got the signals page open here I'm cheating a little bit.
Right so as an area 2D here in the portal seeing right here it has a collision shape.
Let's actually make sure that the collisions are correct so you can interact with players and nothing
else.
That's great.
Here's my collision.
So funny Internet should do a thing.
Woops let's hide the claw shape.
Great.
I was tempted to use a group.
Now I could use a signal.
I'm not going to use a signal because the area do is not actually the parent I'd have to go to.
Eligible children and then connected from here and I'd have to do that for every level.
Now most platform games don't just have one level so that's going to get quite annoying.
So instead I'm going to make a very very very simple script on portal and it's going to go like this.
Create the script and let's connect the area to the signal.
So on body entered you'll connect to portal and I was gonna get 23 dots.
Core group games states I don't think that spelt right let's just double check that it is spelt right
and win games.
Going to copy that so I don't have to go through my weird spelling again.
I'm going to call this function.
OK let's see if this works.
Press Play somehow make it over to that portal.
No I'm not going to die one more time.
Let's pretend that you didn't see that.
I'm very good at games.
Everything is fine.
I know what I'm doing meant to do that.
Totally meant to do that.
Everything is fine and I win.
Excellent.
Look at that with a fully functional game.
And that brings us to the end of Happy Days in this video.
We've had a quick introduction to particles and gotto and we've made a full game now for extra credit.
You could add extra levels.
Right.
Well you'd have to do is put a script in somewhere maybe in game state maybe in portal that keeps track
of what level we're on and moves the next one.
And if there are no more levels go on to victory.
But you actually have the information now that you could start figuring that out.
However I think it's a great place to write this project up so don't forget to share what your game
looks like.
I'm really curious to know.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.