Hello again lovely God to be born in this video we're going to get some better information blending
in at the moment.
We're using animation tree player to blend between Idol and move them as we move them move closer to
the move animation to we're fully there.
And when we stop and move slowly to the idol well not slowly but gradually.
However those aren't the only animations we want.
I also want something for search or in fact not search but reload and punch or not so much punch as
throw food.
Now we have the animations but I want to blend them in.
So we're going to use a blend three note.
Let's take a look at that.
I we get into godda and open my placing and all you do is inside the armature in the animation tree.
I mean look at the animations we've got now currently is going to move these around a little bit.
We've got our idol animation and our run animation and I want to more.
So I want to bring in two more animations and let's rename them so this one is going to be reloaded
and I'm going to live down here and this one is going to be thrown at him and it's going to live up
here.
Now clearly we can't just drag these into the blench too.
So I would do is bring in a blend three before I go any further.
A quick reminder if you want to look this up its pretty easy going a Scripps press classes and type
in animation tree player which is right there it is.
Yeah.
I we have it up in the background and you can find all the documentation.
However that's not what I'm doing right now.
What I want to do is to intercept this move state before it gets that out on a right click on out.
Do you disconnect and drag the move to a position then three will work.
Very much like a blend.
But instead of going from zero to one it'll go from negative one to positive one negative one.
Is this B minus state positive one is this B plus state.
And you will notice as we mentioned before you cannot run B minus and B plus at the same time.
Before going any further let's put the actual animations in so.
Punch is easing with the throw and working is on using for reload.
And I have to connect this to the output.
Otherwise it's good luck.
Why has nothing to do anything at all.
Okay animation tree is valid unslung save that for now and listicle I can blend two wards reload if
I can grab it connec up and towards punch and whatever I'm doing with movement.
Assuming I'm not fully at negative 1 or positive one will also come through is a little fiddly grabbing
this control thing but that's okay.
So those are our states.
What's going to rename this blend three months running this to action.
So we have a very simple state machine.
We have a move which is figuring out how fast between idle and run we are and we have action which is
figure out how far between punch or rather throw move and reload.
We and all of these will translate into this output.
So this is what's going to be play rate.
So now I can close.
May not leave it up in the background of keys in case I need to look anything up but I'm going to open
the player script into scripts.
And in distraction free mode.
All right.
Very first thing I need.
I want a new animation variable.
Now we have a movie State.
I want an animation state and I don't know what actions state has what they need.
Nation state is the wrong word.
A set that is zero.
The default is Europe lets comments it the same way we get up here.
Negative One is throw.
Zero is move.
Slash fiedel is really idle slash move isn't it.
Just keep this consistent idle slash move and a positive one is reload.
I'm also in need some blend rates so let's make a new one for reload planned out for now let's keep
it the same as the run so zero point one.
We'll come back here in a little while and I also want to draw attention to can refill will be using
that in a bit.
However right now it's jumped out to the animation function and rather than scroll through them all.
I'm just going to click on an.
Over here let's refresh ourselves on how this works so we were defining what anime is and it's just
the animation tree player which is within armature.
Now we are going to bring in a different armature depending on which character we are using later on.
But the script should still work for both so that's good.
Now we're checking how much he's moving.
If you're moving more than the minimum move towards then move state.
If not move towards the idle state and then we're clamping that between 0 and 1 so you can never go
below zero because that's what There's plenty and it's OK.
So first thing what to do is I want to bring in a reload animation and we have this very handy if I
can refill.
And what does that mean.
It means if you're within a reload area and you don't have full ammunition which is exactly what I want
so action state is going to move towards.
What do we call this we call this reload blunt about why plus because positive one is going to be the
reload animation.
However just like before I need to klamath this action state he calls clamp and we are closing the action
value.
Now unlike move the minimum is going to be negative one right because negative one is our punch animation
and our maximum value is positive one which is just going to be one and only to write positive one.
Also like move I don't have this L state in here.
Instead I'm going to use a Lerp.
So what can happen is every frame I'm going to try in move towards zero.
So I'm going to go action state.
He calls Lerp lady interpret.
And what are we learning.
Well we're loving the action rate action state rather not rate.
And we are trying to move toward zero.
So every frame if you can move towards zero and how much you to move by one need a new constant hit
on time and then call this action reset.
Copy that and move right back to the top is in control.
And it's going to live here.
Constant action reset rate.
And this should be something quite small and I want to call it zero point to five.
Now we might have to tweak that.
Again that's all looking good.
Let's go back to meat.
Now will this actually change that state.
Right so we need to go to an inmate.
And instead of using blend to node set amount and use the blend three node set out which is exactly
the same.
Let's take a quick look at what I called it.
So where's my animation tree player called it action.
Awesome.
So the string is action and we are blending it towards action state.
And now when I press play assuming I have done everything correctly.
Okay now this love is way too high.
It is changing the animation so one to do is I'm going to reset that lab to a lower amount.
So I actually say reset is going to be zero points.
You know what should probably be lower than the fundamental unit.
That's problem my problem.
Probably my problem.
One zero point zero five.
Let's see how that works.
I'm going like I'm out of there.
And he stands up.
And again I can tweak all these values and I've got that weird stuttering leg thing every now and again.
So let's tweak that as well so my Minimed blender out about it's going to be zero point one.
But that is looking pretty solid now when I don't have at the moment is an animation playing on a fire.
So that's my challenge to you.
I'd like you to have the play a character play the punch animation when the player presses fire.
So pause the video give that a shot.
When you're ready come on back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
So I think the simplest thing to do is to go to try to fire a siegert function for it because we have
this thing it can fire and much greater than zero.
And all I need to do is set the actual state to negative one.
Right.
It could just snap there.
Let's see how that looks.
And I'll go into full screen so we can actually see what we're doing and pick up some ammunition.
Press fire look at that.
He's actually throwing the phone down.
So before we go a couple of troubleshooting tips because I have actually had to record this video three
times because little things keep going wrong.
And the most common thing to go wrong if I go to the animation tree player is double check these connections
because this is a visual note lay out right.
It is quite easy to do stuff like this and then not notice that things are connected or if we go to
the armature and open the animation we here.
This is different.
What I had done originally is I changed it all in here and hadn't noticed that had made this unique.
I shouldn't have made this unique.
However I have.
So I'm going to live with it for now.
In this video we've looked at layering multiple blends within a single animation.
Every player we can start building on this in more complicated games have all kinds of fun three dimensional
animations looking natural.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.