Hello again glorious God.
People in this video.
We're going to continue with this project of adding lives.
Now the players already have lives but we don't have a way of letting the player know how many lives
they have Tweedledee are.
Let's make a goalie now.
We've done some work on going in other projects.
And there's nothing too surprising here.
So instead as break down what we need I think we need a refill.
We need a way of showing the player this is how long you have to wait in that ammo box before you've
picked up any AMA some sort of progress.
I'm thinking a texture progress would be perfect for that.
We also need to measure how much ammo we're carrying.
We actually already have that.
We just need to tidy this up polish it make it a bit more fancy pants and we should display how many
lives the player currently has.
Because when you get to zero you will lose the game.
You should know when that is good.
Let's get into it.
So first thing to do is fix a quick buck.
So a quick look.
If I make this big screen.
And as big as mama.
Oh we crashed.
Why the function hurt is expecting zero arguments in by Senator Dodd Judy.
Let's get to my sendup scripts bystander.
Here it is.
By some of what Judy has a function called hurt.
Right so we are calling it but it's expecting an argument even if we never use it.
It has to be.
So I'm just going to write that in analogy worked fine.
We should get busy bystanders flying around the place.
Perfect.
Awesome.
Okay so now let's get going with this gooey.
Let's get back into 3-d mode.
If you look over here in some tree we already have a going.
So what we do is I'm good.
Right click on it save branch as seen put it in scenes in gooey.
And there it is.
Save it.
Done.
Let's open it up.
Okay.
Let's start with this idea of a texture progress of a make a texture progress note.
There is texture progress and if I go to the root directory to graphics you'll see I've got a couple
of items here.
Circle empty circle full.
Let's open texture's circle empties my under texture and the progress is circle full.
So just to check how it's working.
Let's type in some values so these are out of 100 watts 50 percent look like Order 66 percent look like.
Let's not click randomly there.
OK.
That's not actually how I want to say look I want this to go clockwise when a film mode and clockwise
and that's looking a bit better.
So let's start you at zero.
I kind of got this in the top right and I'm thinking having this label in the centre.
So let's start with this to actually progress.
We're going to do anchor in the top right and positions right cool.
We could give us some margin as well.
So how about 10 pixels for the top drag and eyeball.
There it is.
You live here.
Awesome.
This label is now in the wrong place.
I want it centred here so to do that I'm going to add a centre container make that a child of text press
and drag the label into there.
Now I can't see it.
Why.
Well it's over here.
It wants to be over here.
So is that a container that's making full wrecked.
Now that's the full rectangle of this tax progress.
Finally Let's rename texture progress to refill and Let's rename the label to account.
And that started to look pretty good.
Now I also mentioned and I'm going to go to the Scripsit can see this go to the play script and all
one on the bottom to update good.
We have this comment here move to a group call.
Good idea.
Let's move the gooey to its own group.
So press node press groups and call it good.
OK.
That's all done.
So now let's give Gooly its own scrip so we can start moving the functionality of the good.
I don't really want to tell the gooey what to be doing from another scene because of what we talked
about earlier in the course this idea of single responsibility.
Right.
So let's make a script for going in a call this go and I have put it in my script folder.
Because as you might know of reasons and create.
Now let's move this functionality.
So update Gooly.
I can give you this comment and let's go to distraction free mode for a moment and just give myself
some typing space again.
Alright so I want to call a group so get tree dot core group.
And as you might remember call group takes the following.
You need a string for the group name that string is going to be gooey.
We need a string for the method name.
Haven't written a method yet so let's write a method.
What we do here is refresh Smokeout So function refresh underscore Smokeout why my spelling it like
this with this word capitalisation because an account is the name of the node.
So I'm going to keep that going.
So when I read it I can see oh I'm referring to a note here.
Okay clearly I need to pass an information through it so that information is going to write as ammos
So an argument is going to come through.
As am I.
Let's copy refresh ammo out go back into play.
And that's our string.
Now let's pass through em.
So whatever the value of ammo is that's what we're passing through.
Awesome.
Now there's actually make it work.
So I won't count which is right here.
TEXT equals ammo.
However this text this text property of this AM account label needs a string so just like we did before.
I've got a class V integer value that passing through as a string and that should work fine as go back
into play.
Remove this line entirely because that no longer exists.
And if I've done everything correctly the game should run exactly as it did before.
And it's all updating beautifully.
Awesome.
So it's updating beautifully but I've just made this rather lovely refl note right here and it's not
actually doing anything.
So we need to put that in.
Let's put in a new part of ongoing script some like a new function in those can be back here we go.
You function and it's going to be called the refill
and this is also going to take an argument right it's going to take some sort of melt coming through.
And if I take a look at it you can see the property end to change.
Is this one right here value.
So I grab this refill note and then give up its value and set it to the amount.
Okay.
So we have this refilm out so my do is go into the play script again and let's go up to process I'll
put one more thing in here.
I'm going put a refresh refill count.
Copy that move all the way down to the bottom and make this function function refresh refresh refill
counter.
Well I don't want this to be refreshing all the time.
Only if the amount is going up so I say gif can refill.
Then I want to do something right.
I'm going to pass through a value and that value is going to get tree dot whole group.
I'm calling that gooey and I'm going to call this refill right here as a refill and amount so string
refill.
And here I need a new variable right.
And they call this refill time left.
OK.
So far so good.
Let's define that variable refill.
Time left equals.
So here's my challenge for you.
I want you to finish that line of code.
We have a refilm note in the going.
I want you to update the value of that refund note with the correct value.
Now we already have a time a..
In fact if I go back and take a look at it it's in my player scenes So let's take a quick look at that.
Here we go.
We already have a refill time so we can make use of this somehow.
But exactly how we're going to do it.
Well that's my challenge right.
So don't be afraid to look at the documentation to see if there's a specific property or method of function
you could use.
Also don't worry if you're a little frustrated give it your best shot and then when you've either solved
it or you're just bored of it come on back and I'll show you my solution supposedly.
Now give us your best shot when you come back Oshi my solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
The first thing we ever do is we grab this refill time and let's take a look at the documentation's
press classes and I'll type in time.
And the first thing we notice is there's something here called time left and that looks like deals.
I mean even that.
So back in to my play a script here we go a dot.
Time left.
All right.
So now this girl is going consuming the time left let's press Plie.
A couple of problems.
First my time left is one my steps is a hundred.
So let's go back into the gooey ants into the gooey script.
Let's multiply amounts by a max value.
Right.
I could actually do by max value which can multiply by 100 for now.
OK.
Now my problem here is this is going backwards.
I want to go forwards.
Right.
I want it to fill up.
The closer we get.
Not until that looks and it anticlimactic.
So instead we're going to do is I'm going to go in to this variable here and grab.
How much time is there total.
Right.
What is the timer set to.
Let's give me myself a space here get a bit more rethel timer wrong's seen a
refill timer dot wait time which is the amount of time that it was originally set to minus timelier.
OK.
So we're now showing the opposite information.
And now when they go into it.
Look at that.
OK.
One more thing I need to do is when I leave this area I need to set that to zero.
I always could do this.
I couldn't else in here right else.
And then I'm just going to duplicate this line move it down.
And it sort of felt time left.
I could just set this to zero right.
The other thing I could do is put it here and refill it exited.
I'm minded to put it here as an elf because we're already running this calculation every frame any way
and adding an extra two lines of code isn't going make a huge about the difference.
But it's entirely up to you.
One more thing we need to do.
We need to add in the lives of or greasing for this.
I'm going to add an item list.
Okay.
Our item list is going to live in the top left over here.
And you know what it might give you the margin 10 from the left and 10 from the top.
That's it for now.
And I'm going to give it's three conn's for now we can make this bigger and this probably wants to be
a bit wider so to check it and then add some items.
So let's load in a tax load and we're going back to jefa X lotis Hutton and do this two more times.
Clearly way too small.
So let's make this bigger.
And I also only want the word item.
I don't want any words on it.
So let's get rid of the tax entirely.
It goes pretty good.
Well auto hide this so it should you know unset Max comps to 5 and just make this nice and big and it
will add small lies later like sir.
Now currently I don't want these in there somewhere to delete them delete delete delete they're again
deleted all three.
Instead let's call this all lives and make a function in the U.S. So that's going to call up day lives
and it can take an argument called Life's which makes sense right.
First thing to do is tell it what is this heart.
So variable heart equals preload this in drag that in done next thing to do is clear lives.
So I'm going to call the lives note.
Just to clear.
So every time the switch is run we're going to start from scratch and then it's simple fault for I in
lives and let's go to lives dot ad icon item.
Here it is.
And it's going to be hot.
Is it selectable.
No it's not so hot comma.
False.
Course we have an update lives.
But obviously this isn't being called anywhere.
So back to.
We need to make a function.
So here it goes.
Function update lives.
OK.
So I was going to have that day lives were going to get tree a whole group.
We've seen this before and in fact as we just have duplicated this but didn't get a call.
And we are calling up day lives.
Yes we are were passing in lives.
Update lives lives.
Now lives is not in this script but we do have lives.
Where do we have them.
We have them in character which is also where hurt is happening.
So couple things to check first.
Did I call it lives.
Yes that it's fine.
Secondly most of the time update lives is going to be called.
It's going to be in character and clearly I don't want this happening when robots are hit.
So I need to add an extra piece of logic here.
Right.
Just before we call this I don't know if.
Character type is doubly cause character type Scott player.
Then this should happen.
All right let's actually why this.
First in character under heart which is right here.
Update lives now it's initialise the players are back and the players get all went to the ready function.
And I'm going to play it right here.
Update lives.
So that's all going to work fine.
However I now have this method here that will call whenever a character is hurt the player will respond
to it.
But what happens when a robot gets gets hit right.
So I need to put an update lives method in the robot script so let's find my robot script which means
going in to my script a little robot.
So one thing to do is go a function update lives and fanelle pass.
Now it will do something later.
So I don't mind putting that in for now I just have to stop it from crashing.
I press play and see how this looks.
Big screen moat
Amy wants me twice.
And done.
Awesome.
And that is a fully functional going which means we're at the end of the video in this video.
Look at how to display how long we have to wait in a to actually progress note and we've made a gooey
for food fight.
How does your gooey look.
I'd love to see it.
Don't forget to share what you're doing in our various community sites.
Meanwhile excellent work and I shall see you in the next video.