Hello again you stupendous got people in this video we got to play with labels lights and night vision.
I really wanted to make this a 3L alliteration but I couldn't.
So I didn't know what we're gonna be doing is adding a gameplay reason to come out of night vision mode
right now.
Night vision is simply better.
Right.
So if I'm playing the game and I mean night vision mode I can see the entire level clearly I see all
the guys all the information is there.
I want to add some risks to that specifically I'm going to have it.
So that night vision is going to give him map information.
What computer and locked doors are linked together and the layout.
You can see everything much more clearly.
However you can only see the NPC torches if you're not in night vision.
So it's much harder to see if you're actually in trouble.
This is easier than it sounds.
And we can do this without creating new scripts to do that when he got out which is a good start and
fussing and do is use some group calls.
Now there's three things to play with.
I won't play with these torches and want to play with these labels on doors and labels or computers.
The torches are gonna be a bit of a hassle because they're all Gods and all cameras except they're not.
If I open either a god or camera's open a camera scene you'll see a torch is its own scene.
If I change this scene all other torches will change like that.
I've ordered my group window open but just to show how to do that.
Go to node and if you're on signals press groups good.
So torches are part of the group lights.
I'm going to call it the group lights because I want to make sure that if I add any other kinds of lights
later my game I can just use them as well.
Now if we look at the camera of the torch it's in the right group.
Fantastic.
I can close those too I don't need them at all.
And now we do the same thing with computers and locked doors but they're not lights either.
They can be a different group.
So let's open that and the editor and gets the label for the computer.
And that's going to be in the group labels.
I'm going to add that and save it.
There's a locked door under the exact same thing with this label and it's in the group labels.
Now I do want wanna make sure one that I've added it and to that they're in identical groups always
going to be very silly.
OK.
Everything we need to do is going to be in the vision mode script vision mode handles what we can see.
So let's just extend that scripts and I'll open that script and within vision mode we have all we have
cycle vision mode and don't such that what happens in dark mode what happens in night vision mode.
Let's start with night vision mode and night vision mode.
I want to not see lights.
So to do that I'm gonna use a get tree dot Coal Group which is something we've done a few times.
And at this point I'd like to give you a note called A for deferred.
That's entirely different.
Not letting hold of that today would you learn a core group.
Good.
Let's just pretend that didn't happen because I'm coming to a challenge.
I will look professional.
The challenge here is to see how well you how comfortable you are with core group.
I'd like you to use get tree core group to have the labels only show when you're in night vision mode.
Going to put a line of code in night vision and the line of code in dark you don't need to add any more
scripts.
Suppose the video give that a shot once you've either succeeded or you're a little frustrated with it
coming back and I'll show you my solution
I'm.
OK.
How to do this without adding more scripts right now are torches and the labels don't have a script.
So first thing I do is call the group the group is called Lights.
I believe I should actually double check that shit like that.
Be very silly.
Not.
Let's go over here.
Make sure I've called it correctly.
Lights.
Yep.
I say that because when I just did my rehearsal run I put light into the lights and it was very silly
back into script view and I mean vision mode.
OK.
So how to call a function that isn't in a script.
Here's the thing lights.
Well let's go back into that view.
Lights on.
La la la la la.
Here we go.
A light note.
If I open the documentation by right clicking pressing open documentation you can see that they inherit
from no to D from canvas item from node from object.
So it has everything object can do everything node can do everything canvas item can do anything no
city can do.
It's an extension of the nodes above it.
If you look at any script you'll see the very first line extends canvas modulate what this is telling
gateau is this vision mode is a type of canvas modulate with extended functions and all of this all
these variables and functions everything else we're doing are the extended functionality so I can use
built in functionality on Node without writing a script the script is just be alight.
Plus I don't need you to be a light plus I just need to be a light specifically lights.
If I look at inspector have access to visibility so I could write a script and say visible on visible
off or I could use hide and show so in night vision mode lights are going to be hidden so use hide and
it's nice and easy for myself under control B to duplicate Hold alt and press up arrow to move the line
up and just change hide to show.
So in darkness we'll see the lights in night vision we want as press plays see how that works.
So here are some flashlights.
I press space.
They go away.
Look at that.
Now I see the same thing with labels but in reverse.
So a certificate that is that lights on labels and you want to hide.
And one more time in night vision mode.
I want labels and I want you to show you will notice by the way that we do see the labels at first.
So let's take a look.
I could see the numbers very darkly for space they appear for space they vanish might not be clear on
your monitor but I can see on mine.
So what I need to do is go into those scenes.
So let's go back to Level 1 the one last time going to open computer and on the label it's gonna start
hidden and do the same thing with locked also into that scene.
The label will start hidden now when I press play with these built in functionality in all nodes to
call things with group code calls which I'm quite happy about that we've now added that nice little
piece of risky gameplay I'm really happy with that.
So in this video we've learned how to use groups to trigger built in functions not a big long complicated
thing but surprisingly useful.
So excellent work and I'll see the next video.