Hello again you delightful God people in this video are going to make a game over and victory screen
were about to put in the logic for game over we should have somewhere to go.
But I want to do things a little bit differently in this video going to look at viewport contain a note
that's a way of putting 3-d as a small element in a 2D scene.
Now we've seen hands put to do in 3-d Quite easily right.
If I just drop a 2D element of 3D it'll just render the 2d separately and I can have for example a nice
menu that pops up right so I press Escape.
Here is a 2D degree in my three different fighting.
But what if I want to do something differently.
Let's talk about the game over spring.
We know how to do this right.
This is a simple study seen with a simple graphic user interface.
A couple of buttons some text maybe a picture or two.
But what if I want to put an animated robot in it out like a 3D robot and put it in a small area of
the screen as its own thing.
We could do this for example for a security camera in a 3D game or an inventory system in a 3D up role
playing game right we have the character rotating in three dimensions.
I'm going to use a viewport container and before we get to that fun stuff.
Let's quickly design what the game of the screen screens going to look like.
I'm picturing a simple block of probably dark grey something like that.
And in the middle is something like game over in the middle.
I'm going to put an animated robot doing a thumbs up and underneath some text saying something like
start over with a little button and quit with a little bit nice and simple.
Later on we'll add some music to it.
I will do that later on in this section.
So for now that's our design and this area right here is the key.
This is going to be 3-d in 2D.
OK.
Let's see how that works.
We get back in and got out and make a brand new scene.
And my root node is going to be a control node.
Right.
It's just a gooey.
Nothing else.
They call it game over and let's save that some save.
But in scenes are not going to put it in gooey creative folder and I won't call this game over just
so it's very logical need it find and there's my game overseeing right now there's nothing to it so
let's give it an anchor for rect anger and not anger it's not angry it's very calm and happy and the
lay out to be full rectangle guzzo now I have a control node but it's invisible this does nothing.
So let's give it a colour rectangle as a background.
And again I going to do the full react and let's change that cut to a nice grey.
I'm feeling that colour.
Okay.
So far so good.
Now I want everything in the centre of the screen so I'm going to need a centre container and I got
to put as a child of game over.
So far it should be pretty familiar and let's just make this nice and easy for retting or so whatever
it is it'll stain the sentencing.
Now my elements are split vertically so that's going to be a V box container.
So here's a V box container.
As a child of centre container and this will resize itself depending on what's in there so let's start
with a label.
You know I should add a theme.
So let's go right back up so the game over screen and add theme in here so that every single element
will have the same thing.
So load I put in in scenes for some reason so there we go.
And now my label I can write
you have been defeated.
The next thing I want is this robot.
So let's talk about viewport.
Real quick I'm going to open up the help so into scraps into classes and type viewport creates a sub
view into the screen viewport is essentially what is being rendered on screen.
Now throughout the course I've been telling you that you can only have one camera per scene and that
wasn't entirely true.
It was true enough for them.
But here's the more advance truth ready.
Here we go.
You can have one camera per viewport.
Most of the time this is essentially the same thing so it doesn't really matter.
However it is possible to have multiple reports on screen using a the airport container.
Note the container allows you to put in another viewport in your screen.
So let's close these things that we don't need I don't need that back in too.
I actually don't need any of these scripts do I.
Inside the reebok's container is a child of contentless put in a viewport contain a note and this is
just a container.
Right right now this doesn't do anything.
So instead let's put a viewport.
As a child of you pull container and we've got some things we can do here we can load in a world we
can do this in a script so that if we were doing split screen multiplayer they would all be pointing
to the same world with a different camera.
We don't need to do that.
Instead let's instance in a robot so the scenes of the characters and a robot.
There's my robot see.
See him.
Why can't I see him.
Because you know he's in 3D and we're in 2D So let's give the camera.
Now let's move the camera to where we can see what we're doing.
And we hit preview you know what that's a little bit high.
But now I can actually just tweak it in the transform So I'm going to play with this a moment one point
five.
Now I think one point to five let's have the robot looming over us.
And the distance of three point five now is too far away.
Maybe three.
Yeah that looks good.
I do also want to add a little bit of light and switch the camera preset off.
I also want to add a light.
So as a child viewport let's add in our light.
So there's our on the light it's sometimes known as a point light but hear it and light find.
And let's put this in a good place.
I'm thinking sort of below in front to give that spooky robot look maybe a bit more.
Like that.
That looks good.
Let's preview that the camera.
Now you notice we have this background here.
Right.
So let's go back to a view container.
OK.
So right now we don't see anything.
So the first thing to do is get a viewport And check this size out let's say or what's my width right
now my with right now is 405 will strike three hundred three hundred wide and three hundred tall.
Now right now nothing's updated let me leave the scene and come back and you'll see it's update itself.
Now this grey box is the world and it's not actually showing us the camera but if I just run this scene
and this scene only.
Here is my robot.
Right.
So sometimes God doesn't update the rendering which is a little irritating but let's find spooky spooky.
Hi folks.
Future Yahn here because I realized I was editing that I forgot a basic step and certainly not God's
fault that the rebels showing up.
It's mine.
I forgot a basic thing.
Get a camera pressed current come back.
It should show up.
So if it's not showing up at this point close.
Come back in and it should be fine because it automatically makes Kalachakra current.
Just goes to show you could always forget the very basics.
Ok back to real time yeah.
Woohoo.
You also noticed that it showed the background and I don't want that background or need do is go to
my viewport and a click transparent background.
Now we're on the scene.
The robot is just showing against whatever we put here.
If I put a standard I don't know PRNG or picture of my face or of my cats I like that the robot would
be on top of that so that's looking good.
I also have noticed the robot side here and I really want that somebody who take this view pill container
and the size is going to be 300 x 300 Y.
Just like the viewport board and the do is in the V box container.
I'm going to make a centre container.
And the viewport is going to be child of that.
Now on to run the scene.
March more like it.
Look at this.
OK now let's fix this animation and then click on a robot and then remove the script.
We don't need any script for robot in this scene.
Now this will only happen with this instance of the robots of the robot.
Level 1.
So if I save this we'll still animates of a play the game.
Robots still make great.
Back to my game over seeing and I want to go to the armature and end those children as well because
that is going to have my animation player.
And let's see.
I want a robot running to not overload in this instance only Instead I want robot thumbs up.
Let's take a look what that looks like.
Perfect.
It's going to make that auto load.
I'm going to loop it.
I could loop it.
Let's see how this looks.
Not bad and I could tweak the lighting a little bit make this a little better.
I do that very quickly.
Let's add in another light maybe directional like.
There we go.
And let's quickly put that somewhere handy.
I'm thinking up here.
I'm going to go to local rotation.
And let's give us a different colour.
Let's make this more like a movie and we use the old orange and teal effect which is a little overused
but that's fine.
So you can be team.
And the onlly lights can be a nice warm orange.
And I make this much brighter green energy of three.
Let's put you up here and my directional lights.
Can have an idea you have to see how that looks.
A little better.
Also getting that little bit of back light if I wanted to.
But you know what that's looking pretty good for now.
OK.
So this pupal container is done let's add some buttons.
So back to my reebok's container that's add a great container.
So my columns are to put labels on the left and buttons on the right.
So let's start with a label
next.
Try again.
And back to send a container.
Here's a button.
These buttons aren't in the theme right now so I could fix that very quickly.
I'll go to thien for theme.
An ad class item.
Button up.
There is.
Let's go to our button thing and click on Stiles.
So that's going to be a new texture new style box texture 3-d.
Click on that allergan to look bringing that texture.
So scenes gooey graphics.
There we go.
There's blue button.
Perfect.
Let's give it an actual size.
So a size 30 by 30.
Good looks great.
Cool.
Cases.
At another level
and this one was it quit.
And another button.
So but and do.
And they should still have the same theme.
My rectangle not going give a minimum size on both these for 30 by 30.
Perfect.
And let's give you an insight to just to be nice and clear.
Awesome.
I get this grid container not centred so we'll do OK go back up to my view box container and add another
one to contain.
Let's just drag the container into that.
And that's pretty good.
Let's run this scene see how it looks.
Cool.
Now these buttons right now only have the one texture on I should probably fix that.
But that's looking pretty solid isn't it.
Oh alright.
Couple more things.
What do I need to add a script here.
So let's put a script from a game over scene and put the actual script in my scripts.
And let's connect these buttons again button.
You can be renamed.
You are.
Restart button and you are quick to button.
When I connect restart button as a signal on pressed to game over and do the same thing for quick button
and these are nice easy somersault with quick there's the simplest get tree.
Quite simple.
So let's see how that works.
Run the scene.
Quit the game.
Awesome.
And this one is going to be get tree dots.
Change a scene.
Let's go find that scene.
So for now level one can just go here.
Perfect.
See how that works.
Try again as Level 1.
Do remember we're going to load into this scene but we won't have the mouse which means we won't have
to press these buttons so let's make it ready function.
And in that I'm going to have to bring the mouse back and I'm just going to quickly go in to my scripts
folder and let's go to pause menu and here's where I need.
I need input.
Set mouse mode brackets input mouse mode visible to send a copy that go to my game of the screen and
paste it.
Okay so the moment we go into this scene whether the mouse is there or not which can tell it put the
mouse back before we call the scene done.
Let's quickly finish this theme off as no point leaving it half done.
So back to Game Over.
Go to my default thien should be in button I've got a normal hour.
I want a Prest and they hover.
So let's just go back to my scenes.
Goofy graphics.
Here we are.
I'm actually not feeling this that should be a check button so let's go into the normal button.
I'm going to switch this out.
So right here I've got this blue button 0 7.
There's going be my send a button and let's take a look at hover.
So this can be a new style box and this texture is going to be the same one with a big shadow so it's
like my hand is over it and then pressed is a new style box texture.
And that's going to be this depressed one right here.
How's that looking.
Save that and run the scene one more time.
Awesome.
And I could press quit and is looking good.
We will put music in this later and I can fancy this off of it so maybe try again.
Is going to be.
I demand a rematch.
I may be quit is going to be.
Or can it say I surrender.
Awesome.
Sing as much or as little character in this as you want.
Maybe these buttons are too small.
You can make them bigger or smaller.
But that's looking pretty solid.
And that brings me to the challenge.
I would like you to make a victory scene it's can be very simple what we've done and I want you to include
at least one view contain a note.
I'm going to put a robot in mine but you don't have to.
You could pull word whatever you want.
Remember to include the same buttons we just had.
They could say different things but you want people to be able to either quit or start again.
So pause a video give us a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Mark Mack.
All right so what I would do is make this very simple for myself.
I only use this as a basic building block so I'm going to go see a scene as I go back up to my goey
scene make a new folder and call this victory will save us as victory docs.
Yes.
Why.
Because most of this is going to be the same.
But I don't actually need to inherit newses.
So first off let's call this victory.
It's green.
Perfect.
Next let's go into the view container.
Open the robot.
Go to the animation within the armature And as you change what the define nation is so it's not going
to be autoloader a thumbs up it's going to do robot dance.
It can take a look what that looks like.
So let's play the dance.
That's pretty awesome dance.
I could lose that.
Do I really want to.
But we could.
Is about pressing the loop button.
Be fine.
Okay.
Now all I need to do is rename these buttons right something.
Click on this here and get rid of the animation screen.
And instead of I demand a rematch say once more.
And instead of surrender it can say victory is mine.
I'm out of here and I've now made quite a large gap here.
So when I go back up to this label and align it to the right and click on this label and line that to
the centre and that is looking pretty good.
And I can run this scene.
What's more get me out of here.
Oh it's not actually running the animation.
Why are you not running in the mission.
Run the animation.
Because I didn't auto load or time.
Dance robot darts.
Absolutely.
Now if I wanted to I could change this background.
I'll be honest I kind of like this colour.
I'm not going to but I could if I wanted.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we've learned about view ports and viewport containing notes.
Please do share your screens with me there.
The game over in the victory screen.
What did you do.
How does it look on yours.
Did you pick the robots that you said.
Completely different.
Share it with the community.
I'd love to see what you're getting up to.
Meanwhile we're almost done with this game of I only got a few things to do that some polish and some
music.
And it's looking great so far.
So excellent work.
And I will see you in the next video.