Hello again wonderful God to people on welcome to part three of the locked door in this video going
to make the door actually open and add some polish to a number pad.
I'm a Polish I mean let's get some sound effects let's make it more.
I don't know.
Realistic not realistic but more exciting.
Let's make it more exciting.
So what are we doing.
Well first thing we'll make in a locked door open if it doesn't open it's not a locked door.
It's a fancy wall.
Second thing putting some folks go.
Start with going into God.
An opening a lot.
Dorsey right now the combination is being held in the number pad.
And I kind of want to move it for locked door.
The reason for this is Later the combination is actually not going to be home with the locked courts
can be randomly generated that random generated code is going to be stored on a computer that the CD
player can read.
That computer is going to send a signal with that combination to all locked doors connected to it because
multiple locked doors can open the same room.
Right so if I show a level one if we have a locked door for this area right here one two three four
five I could feasibly have all of these doors have the same combination which would make sense maybe
not this one but you get my point for that to happen.
I want the combination to be stored on a computer and transmitted down to all those doors.
It's going to be easier to transmit that signal to the locked door route node than it is to the number
pad.
Let's go into the script and I'm going to put a variable in here called combination.
And that's an array of four common one common five so the integers for one five as an array is combination.
Now a number pad are probably only navigation to audio.
And let's close that script number pad.
Let's set combination is an empty array.
I'm going to save that.
Let's also close the outputs so you can have a bit more screen space and let's make a brand new ready
function.
Auto complete is not playing so I just type it properly underscore already and unschool ready is going
to get the number pad dot combination and set it to this combination.
Great.
Let's see if that works and if it does one expecting as I go up I'll type in for one five.
The light will turn green and a second later the panel disappear.
We haven't opened a door here.
So walk up to the security panel or the locked door type in the combination.
Awesome.
Let's go to open the door.
Well I'd like to do is put in a brand new signal some back and number pad and let's make this nice and
big.
And I'm gonna put a signature under the variables signal and I'm going to call this combination.
Correct.
All right.
So when we checked the guess if the guess is right the light goes green the timer starts I need to put
this when the timer stops.
So just before you press hide let's emit the signal combination correct.
Save that and back into two devian and out a full screen mode.
Let's connect it so inode you'll see this with the brand new signal just made combination correct us
connect that to lock.
Door to a brand new method.
And this brandnew method in a locked door g-day function on no pad combination correct.
All I do is call open.
Now I could have just connected it to the open function.
I don't really want to do that because it's theoretically possible we might want other things to happen.
So instead let's make this one nice and readable and two nice and open for expansion.
I now can see by looking at script when the number pad combinations correct the door open.
You might have noticed by the way I'm doing two different things here on the ready function.
I am changing the variable of a child node directly but I'm not doing the same thing in the direction.
I'm not running the open function directly from the child node.
Why is that.
It's kind of a personal preference thing.
What I'm thinking is I'm okay with accessing a function or a variable of a child node.
It's within the same hierarchy some.
I'm all right doing that.
I'm not as okay going in the other direction.
I don't want child knows to access functions and change variables of apparent code.
And I certainly don't want nodes being able to do that out elsewhere in the scenery.
So I'm trying to maintain some sort of hierarchy.
Alright so now we should have a door that will open.
I'm sure that the guard go through because if the guard opens the door it can be hard to tell of where
opening at.
To the coalition for one five.
And the door opens.
Fantastic.
This is nearly done.
One more thing I would like to do is I'd like to put some sound effects and let's go into the number
pad scene and I'm doing the number of that scene because if I put an audio stream player here that's
going to be in this instance not an all normal pads if I ever want to reuse the number pad.
It should be here.
And let's minimize all of these things.
What we have to do is when I add an audio string player not as 2D not a 3D but just a basic audio stream
player as a child for another iPad.
Why audio stream player not 2D 3-d.
Because I don't want positional information.
This is happening in the Gooly not in the world of see what I mean.
So I don't want it to be loud on the left there on the right depending where we are.
If you're going to sound effects you'll find that we have three tone one and three and two turn one
and we can play those.
Let's put one in drag three turn one in and I can see what that sounds like.
That sounds like it's correct and two tone one.
That's going be my buttons out clear that for now.
Let's do a couple of things first.
First must let one of these get to import and just make sure loop is off.
So reimport it would loop off and do the same with two tongue one.
Otherwise the sound will never finish.
Second I need to make sure my audio string player doesn't have playing great from here.
I'd like to hand it over to you.
I'd like you to add a sound effect for the button being pushed and another for the combination being
correct.
Now don't worry about putting these in the global g.d. Reps.
And I'm saying that because we're not going to use these sounds anywhere else putting them in the global
g.d. script is just an extra step.
And remember we using all year string player not to do your 3-d because we don't want positional sound
to pause the video.
Put those two sound effects in and when you're ready and pause it noshir my solution.
And welcome back.
OK so we have two sound effects and audio string player can only play one so we could make a second
audio string player right.
I could just duplicate this and give them a different name.
I don't really want to do that mostly because I don't want to have a play at the same time but also
eskies going to make it harder to manage.
If we want to adjust the volume I want to just have just the one for one so that is a way forward.
It's not the one that's calling me the Summerset this script.
So whenever the enter function is called I'm going to make sure that we're playing the right sound effect
by bringing up audio stream player and who got stream.
Maybe you could find that property by just mousing other string.
There is probably stream unless set it.
I'm going to set it to two tone one because that's the sound effect.
I said sounded like but being on a copy that path now this is a string and I can't load a string.
I have to load an object of files on a load and cast the string as a file object.
Now I have to actually play it so let's put that right underneath audio stream player.
Play awesome.
The second thing to do is I want to get the sound effect of that's the correct combination happening
when it is.
Now I could put it right here on time to start but I was going to have as you know and buttons.
Nothing's going to happen for a second and then it's going to work.
I'd much rather put it right here.
The light turns green so if the combination is correct audio stream player stream equals load and then
this 3 tone one path's us copy that.
And pasted in.
I make sure she play the sound of that play and that should be good to get Let's find out.
Let's go in to slightly modes.
Can she see this at the Gulf first guy guard.
Alright.
Awesome.
Now you will notice that what's happening is is going correct.
The moment I type in the last digit I'm okay with that.
If you're not you might want to move this play here too.
When the timer does the time out all put a second time and something like that.
However I quite like that feel.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we finished lock doors and no pads.
They are good to go.
We've got some more things to happen with combination's computers but the locked doors no prison cells
are fully functional.
You could if you wanted even add extra buttons for action numbers so you could see a 1 2 2 2 2 3 and
all those twos would just function the same two button.
I don't know why you do that but you could and would put sound effects on Goofy actions to give a bit
more feedback and make the game feel a lot more playable and fun and vibrate.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next year.