Welcome back lovely God people in this video we're going to add an NPC enter the spike man at the end
of the video.
You to have a spackman OPEC that can hurt money.
What do we need to do.
Well I'm thinking of a very simple non play a character so simple in fact it doesn't really have any
behaviour is not going to react to by it's just going to move left.
Pause right pause.
Repeat.
Let's get that going.
First thing we're do as you might expect is creating You scene before I do that though.
Let me explain more about something different.
What's going to happen is a put spike man on a platform spike that's going to go this way.
Pause this way pause and repeat.
Spike man is going to be an area hoodie just like these spikes just like the jump.
If I animate an area hoodie on this key frame change the position on the x axis to my a 100 it's going
to think I'm in the global position.
Why.
Because the position is always relative to the parent.
And for some reason if you do it that way round it's going to think that the parent is the root note.
Right so just go here.
We don't want that.
But there's a workaround.
Let me show the work around so new scene and let's get to the 0 0 so I can see where things are going
to spawn in and create not an area to see but a Node 2 they call that spike.
And now I'm going to make an area to see as a child of that.
So now the area to me is the bit that's going to move I move left and right and it's going to know that's
relative to the spike.
So Spike man as an object as a node is actually going to stay still but it's gonna have a child that
has a collision shape and an animated Sprite that's going to move left and right.
OK.
So we have an area to see here.
It's going to be a collision shape.
And in order for it to have a collision shape we should know what we're colliding with someone a back
up level to spaceman.
And let's add an animated Sprite.
The enemy to Sprite is going to need some frames so new Sprite frames click on Sprite frames.
I'm going to rename default to idle for no apparent reason but for some reason they want to.
Next into our graphics folder into our enemies.
And here we have Spiderman.
By the way if you'd rather do the same thing with a sun that moves left and right you go ahead.
But I want to you spike the idle animation is just going to be Spiderman standing.
That's all it is that's all we need to see.
Now let's add a new animation.
I'm going to call this walk and that's going to be Spike medawar one spike men walk two just two francs.
That's all we need.
Let's see how that looks.
So go back a level playing.
Well I'll stand still and walk is pretty good.
OK let's go back to Idol now that's put in that coalition ship and I'm going to just make a very simple
collision shaped hoodie.
I'm not going to spend time making a polygon that perfectly matches the outside.
I'm just going to use a capsule a nice easy capital shape that I'm actually going to have to move to
the lowest level so let's move it at Sprite above Italy so I can see the collision shape.
God draws things in the order So pretend you're here right where the word node is.
That's what you can see.
So that's your line of sight remember grab the accidents dont grab the scale handle so drag big drag
drag about there what.
It's that 45.
Awesome.
And let's look at the height.
What's the height of this drag drag.
You don't have to sing dragged out drag but you know you can.
Oh that looks pretty good doesn't it now.
I know that there's a gap here but honestly I don't see how Bunny could possibly fit there.
I'm not making a putt there pixel perfect game this isn't Super Meat Boy so let's see what that would
be.
That would be 65.
Okay so if you don't want to drag the extent you could just set the radius to 45 pixels in a height
to 65 all of these numbers are in pixels.
Let's put a script in.
So add new script and I'm going to load in.
There has at script because we really have one that has everything we need.
So his has it's.
And you'll notice it extends area too deep and it's using on body entered which is for every Tudeh.
If I put this on the know to do this script won't work so I'm going to put it on the area today which
is fine because that's where it's going to end.
And just to refresh our memories here's what it does if anything enters if any body rather enters this
area then trigger the hurt function in game state.
In other words anything that enters here make the player be hurt.
So let's make sure that the only thing that can trigger this is the playlist go over to our collision
layers make sure that we're on the enemy layer not on the player and that we only interact with the
player in the mask.
And now I think I can hide my colours in shape and click on move all children so now whenever I click
on Spike man I will move the entire object not whatever's lowest.
Great.
One more thing I need to do.
I need this to acclimate.
I could do this in script but there's no need.
I'm just going to the Amish and play it just like before.
So animation play.
Let's at some tracks I remember a movie in the area 2d which means that the Sprite action needs to be
a child of area 2D.
I was going to drag it in there.
There it is perfect.
Let's put you slightly higher the colours and shapes of I need to see the clear shape I can.
OK so now when Area 2D moves it's all square with the Sprite.
That was nearly a mistake OK.
A new animation and we got a call this spike man because it's only give me one animation I don't need
to do spackman walks bike man.
It'll all give me one thing.
What's going to happen.
Would take a second to move left by pixels.
I'm going to wait and then I will move at the same speed this way and wait.
That's a total of six seconds I think.
And what do we need to do.
Well we need to get Eric to Dee.
And you know what I could do up here.
But let's show what I'm doing.
Let's go to to do transformer position and make a key.
And at one second I need the position on the x axis to be minus a hundred.
Make a key and repeat the key at two seconds.
See this line.
That means there are key frames here but the value hasn't changed.
So walk here and wait a second.
At the same speed which means at 3 you're at zero at 4 you're at 100 So it's got four seconds and change
the exposition to positive one one key frame and repeat the key frame at five.
Now if I loop the animation like so we play at a go here we wait.
We move at the same speed here here we wait and then we go back to the beginning.
Great okay right now Spike manage just hovering in a weird way.
Let's actually animate this thing.
So animation player I would like you to make a brand new track in animated Sprite.
I'd like you to start with walk and put a key frame up one second which has you to idle two seconds
back to walk out for seconds to idle.
And at five seconds to walk.
Let's just check that.
Very nice.
Now obviously when he's going to the left spackman as moonwalking So we need one more thing here we
need to put flip H we use as before on Bunny.
Now we know he's on Spiderman So let's make it key for flip H.
So the first thing I'm doing is moving left so let's switch that on and make a key.
One second actually doesn't matter because spackman is perfectly symmetrical doesn't need flips at two
seconds.
Let's switch off flip horizontal.
But a key frame and a five seconds switch it on and that should be a perfectly animated Spiderman.
He's taken the area to be in a collision shape with him and it should work just fine.
One last thing I want to do is make sure that he autoloader this animation wants to load in when Spike
mount does do that by hitting this auto load button.
Also play onload.
I cannot close this animation and save the scene go to scenes.
This is studying that bit crowded isn't it.
A fix that later in this for the press save.
And here we go.
Let's see then.
Whereas them to put a spike a man here just to test them so they make a can.
No 2d to keep things in.
Make things nice and tidy.
So no need to keep an eye on all this end pieces unless instance in a spike.
Man.
And despite man put it here.
You know this move so I can not worry about dragging the wrong thing and in a pixel right now he's in
front of the spike.
I quite like that.
If he don't want him in front of the spike remember you're standing here.
You're looking that way so you'd have to drag this in pieces folder to a buff spikes or vice versa.
So you could do that if you wanted.
I actually quite like it the other way around.
I'm going to pull it back right here.
OK.
Let's see if you work.
Well there's Spike mannone is moving and I'm to do damage because I didn't connect this signal.
Okay.
So let's go back to spike man.
What's it called it's called on body enter and get a copy of that.
Let's make it signals.
Click on Node body and to connect.
And you're going to called on body and.
Oh and I put that in the right script.
So on to hoodie on what he entered cannot.
So now he should work Pressplay.
Kellems I can't get out of it.
He killed me works.
All right.
Which brings us to the challenge.
I would like you to place those spackman ads that Spike meant to your level.
And remember keep a challenging keep it fair.
Don't lead the player into a situation where they're going to fall on Spike again and there is nothing
they could have done about it.
The player should at least have a chance to react so pause the video placeless spackman give you a level
a quick play test and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
All right let's play some spike.
I'm going to duplicate you and I'm going to put you as a good place down here.
Don't fall down here this is a bad place.
Let's move on.
How about do.
Here's a nice one let's put you here.
Yep looks good.
Don't do one more.
I feel like should be up here.
So that's why I'm here because reasons.
Okay let's give that a quick playtest.
There already is an awful lot of extra debt at a time like Job I can't just take my time and go around
the level if I want to get these coins I need to figure out when Spike amounts to it which I'm really
happy with.
However before we carry on I've noticed that this scene's folder which I mentioned before is starting
to be a little crowded.
Also coiner affects his script so let's move you right click move to scripts.
OK.
What I'd like to do is make a folder specifically for levels.
So that's right click and do a new folder and call it levels and I'm going to move level 1 into it.
What's that.
There it is.
And that game over into it because that currently Those are two levels.
Now if I try and run this little.
Well first thing I'll do is say I don't know your main level are for press play where is it such you
can find it as a level one.
However if one went on two guys sorry money.
The game's going to crash.
Look at all these debulk areas because it's got a string reference right.
It's pointing to the location of game over.
If I show you the script for game state here we go.
Game over.
Our end game does this.
Let's change that.
Let's go to the global script.
So into our scripts follow in to Blue Bell and let's make a couple of scene parts of variable level
1 equals and let's go to all levels right click and do copy path.
Elliman did the same thing again.
Up up up.
Now because I'm pointing to a physical location on the drive it's a little trickier than it would be
if I'm just using these nodes.
Can auto set their names and positions.
Well there any way to do that.
You say this is me.
Positional drives a lot more difficult.
So let's make a note.
So when people look at the script they know why this difference.
I will call this scene.
Locations must be set manually.
We'll call this nodes.
That's never the nodes set automatically correct.
Say that.
Next thing I need to do is actually use those so instead of that seam path let's go global.
Game over and we'd better open game over some of that double click and game over.
And change that to lowball dot level 1.
And that should fix that.
By money.
Anyone else.
And no debugger is fantastic.
Which brings us to the end of the video in this video.
We've created a simple NPC using animation player.
This is a really great technique for making exciting levels very quickly and simply so before we finish
remember.
Share how your levels going.
I'd love to see your progress.
Put it on the Facebook group put it in discord put it on our forums.
An excellent work and I'll see you on the next video.