Hello again you superb go to people in this video we're going to add some key gameplay to our eyes my.
We've already got an end in condition right.
The player can lose.
So if the guard spots you for too long you can get seen.
But what would a stealth game be without the ability to hide in a box as we all know hiding in a box
makes you completely invisible.
Which is why you can't see the 17 pictures of cats in this slide.
They're all in boxes.
And before we do that let's remind ourselves how stealth works in heist meisters.
We've got the NPC checking if the play is in line of sight in field of view and in range.
Is there a clear line of sight to see you.
Are you within where my eyes would be.
Are you close enough NPC is know what they're looking at the player because they're checking the player
collision left if something is on collision allow one to play a collision later and it's in that field
of view that line of sight and in that range the NPC will see it.
So that means what if we move the player to a new collision lair.
If we tell Gordo when we're in the box we're in a different collision layer.
None of the detectable will work and we'll be invisible.
So that's what we'll do.
First thing I do is I'm going to get back into Gordo and we'll be playing with a player scene.
So let's open that up.
He's replacing and here's my player Hello player.
And you know what.
Let's I'm not the script.
Actually before we open up the script was about to leave you.
Just quickly show you on the graphics under PMG on the tiles.
We've got down here some boxes.
I'm thinking to use 130 lessons small if drag that in about the same size of the player.
You don't have to.
You could use the big one.
You could use that one.
I could be using 130.
That's gonna be my disguises box.
So let's put in some new variables and then make these instance variables they can exist at the top
of this pile of script.
Let's call this player sprite and I'm going to drag in the player sprite.
So that's going to be over here.
MAN 1 drag you in.
Why am I doing this.
Because when it should be changing the appearance of the player.
Right.
So when we press the hide button This sprite which is right here is going to change.
We also need it to change back.
So it stole both of those so variable was its box sprite.
Yes.
Box right.
Equals.
And I would write these in now.
Each spring these variables.
But as a current me this doesn't change at runtime so you know what let's make these constants and as
they're constants let's make those capitals just so we can see the Capitals when we write the code.
So let's play a Sprite and there's box sprite.
Awesome.
Next up let's add a key on abusing E.
So your project settings project settings.
There it is input map and what we've got we've got toggle vision mode.
Let's call this toggle disguises toggle disguise and I'm just gonna put in he e you can use whatever
key is best for you.
I'm on a British quasi keyboards a W as a D movement visual space e is toggle disguised.
Okay so we now have that.
We need that to works under input.
Let's put this in now.
I'm going to put this as an F as she is.
Give us some space.
There we go.
I'm gonna put this is an F not an else or an F because it's quite possible that we're gonna disguise
ourselves and toggle vision but at the same time.
So let's go if input dot is action.
Just like above just pressed.
Fantastic.
And I want to toggle disguise.
There you go.
Boop.
OK.
So what's gonna happen is that we are going to toggle disguise.
Yeah.
This guy's gonna be a branding function.
Let's make a brand new function called toggle.
This is if we don't put that got a plane is everything good.
Let's find out.
Magic magic magic everything is shiny.
OK.
We need to toggle the skies which means we need to be tracking all we disguise and that's another instance
variable.
This one is a variable not a constant.
Let's call that variable disguise.
I'm going to start not the skies.
So that's false.
All that back down.
And this has been this very simple for ourselves.
If we disguised that we're going to reveal all else we're going to disguise.
So what does the button do.
It depends are you disguise.
If so reveal yourself if you're already revealed disguise yourself that way you can use the same button
to switch back and forth.
Let's just put those functions inside function reveal and function.
Disguise
that space that would make this nice and consistent.
Okay.
It's looking pretty shiny.
So what is revealed it will reveal is going to set off sprite back.
So I'm gonna call the sprite which is a child so it's going to use the dollar sign.
Same as getting old remember and was the property we want.
Well let's take a look.
Mouse over it it's texture great so texture equals.
Now I can't just use play a sprite because player sprite is a string.
We need to load in a file.
So we need to use load.
What we're really doing is is changing the nature is horrible we're costing the variable.
But this load player sprite.
And we need to remember that disguise is now false.
If you're revealing yourself you'll no longer disguised.
Great.
So now let's just do the same thing here.
But with a different box so sprite stopped.
Texture equals load box Sprite and disguised equals true.
Okay so I run the game now.
What we gonna get is the ability to press E and switch between the play at a box.
Now at the moment this isn't actually the skies right.
Let's open this 0 9 1 9 2 fantastical 9 1 9 2 guys and see I am disguise but I can still be seen.
Right.
So let's make that luck.
Now if we look over in the collision less back and player looking Inspector you can see that the mosque
is what it can be interfering with is fine.
We still want the box we able to bump into scenery to be able to interact with computers and doors but
the player is on volume 1.
We know if I just open this that one is players two is tile map.
This next one which is 4 is in pieces.
This one is computers.
So the one we've got free is left five.
So if I just take a look at one side that's computers that is value sixteen so we're gonna toggle 16
on.
So let's mouse over what it is and we can just use the property collision layer.
Well great let's do that.
So I'm going to go back into my reveal.
Now when your player collision layer equals one when you disguise the next free one is 16.
So collision layer equals 16.
So what should happen now.
And I press play
Let's do the deal first.
I always forget that 3 2 9 9 3 2 9 9 3 2 9 9 Debbie Bobbi Booth.
Okay I'm visible I am disguised I am disguised as a little hard to see myself here is that I am disguised
but my shadow is wrong I can't to fix the shadow so that's what we'll do now we're going to change the
occlusion lap now this is gonna be part of a challenge to you but before we get into that let's remind
ourselves what's happening.
We have here and a clue to write what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna open up the template character which
is the one that the play is inheriting from and it doesn't like to clutter and honest down our arms
for safe characters I'm going to save this as human a clearer break so there's I on you included.
So we now have a file where we can come back to.
So here's my challenge for you I would like you to change the players occlusion shape to Max match the
shape of the box when disguised now as a few steps and this is a little bit challenging but give it
a shot for extra credit have it change back when the player stops being disguised as actually a little
bit easier but give it a shot so we can do.
Don't worry too much you get lost we can always come back to it but pause the video and when you come
back I'll show you my solution
Welcome back.
OK.
That's the need to do is I need a box to work with now I'm using tile one thirty so got a Sprite and
just drag that in boop OK and we can only see that the occlusion is wrong let's go here and I'm going
to clear this occlusion so it is no longer using what is inheriting I'm like a brand new one and this
only the shape of this box while it's okay I'm make sure on grid mode so on SNAP mode and I'll make
sure I see the grid and that's a little bit out of sequence and it is a little bit too big now I know
that these tiles are all in multiples of eight that did you by 32 or 64 by 64 so in grid settings right
here I'm going to go configure snap so these three little dots here they can figure snap and I will
make this an eight by eight grid new eight by e eight not eight by 256 that's very different and that's
lining up now it's going right up to the blurry edge but that's fine that's why I wanted to be and now
I could just add these beep beep beep beep boop that's why included I'm a save that
as books include A
OK let's reload the human one so that's going to be characters human occluded.
And let's bring that human sprite back in so before any further let's take a look what the properties
called when a mouse over clear.
It's called a cluster.
Nice and easy.
So what I can do when I change the sprite to be the player sprite.
As you note before we do that let's actually bring these in as constants.
So constant player clutter is equal to I don't mean distraction.
Freeman It's hoped for this toy.
Let's go back to my to do characters.
And here we go human include a loop drag that in Nice and easy.
And same thing here.
Box or clutter equals and just drag and drop that.
Awesome.
We're now ready to go.
So now let's bring those in.
So back into structure free mode in reveal insulin here.
Tom I liked to D include a I like to put a 2D rather dot floater is equal to load player of CUDA and
down here when we change our sprite to the box sprite let's also change all white include a dot a cluster
equals load
box cleaner OK let's see if that works
OK.
Let's not forget the computer this time.
So 2 7 8 3 fantastic 2 7 8 3.
OK.
Here we go.
So people shaped box shape.
Look at that.
Now what we could also do is we get that a light source inside the included to make the play glow.
But I think that's a challenge for different video.
I am really happy with that.
I now have a little box we can sneak around and we will in the next video make it so you can always
see the player or the player box when they're on screen so we don't have this black on black on black
but I'm really happy with that and that feels like a really good place to end the video.
So excellent work and I will see when the next one.