Hello again you wonderful God to people in this video.
We're going to get ready for our computers by having a node they can generate combinations and it's
going to generate combinations of whatever length the computer asks for.
So what do you mean by combination.
Well a combination is an array.
So if you remember when we did the locked door test we had an array of 4 1 5 that's three integers within
an array and these arrays are going to be of varying length so maybe one locked or has a three digit
combination.
Maybe one has a four digit combination.
Maybe one has an eight digit combination.
And I want these combinations to be returned to another note.
I want to have one thing one object that is responsible for generating combinations and I don't want
them to be within computers or anything else.
I want a node called combination that just generates combination a single look at God.
So if we look at the sync tree what I'm going to do is I create a brand new node or of it instance one
in that's going to be responsible for generating combinations.
I want to really take advantage of object orientation by having an object that does a thing and then
having other nodes ask it to do the work to do that I'm going to make a brand new scene.
I gonna make a new scene rather than just put it in here because if I make other levels I want to be
one instance in this combination.
You know what we could call it combination generator that feels like a more useful note let's call it
combination generator and then make the simplest possible mode because all it's going to do is just
be an object that holds a script so it's just a node.
But you know 2D doesn't have to be a note day let's call it combination generator.
Great.
Let's save that.
And that's going into science which is here fantastic.
And it's going to have a script so let's give it a script cognition generated GDP and that's going in
the scripts folder.
OK for now I'm going have a variable called length and I'm going to say a four digit code and I make
an export variable so we can change this nice and easily I say nice and easily.
If I click on commentation generator mode there's a link I can change that later on I'm going to remove
this variable because this information is going to be passed in from other nodes.
But this just to get it working.
Let's make it function and I'm going to call it generate combination.
And let's go take an argument of light.
That's how many digits do you want this combination to be to generate a combination of like.
Alright let's talk about what has to happen here.
We need to have the length of the combination and we need to generate an array.
So let's make an array called combination and just make it nice and easy and make an empty array.
I want to say okay take this like while you're in this range why within length.
Iterate through it and add and add another random digit.
Well if I'm reading through Let's use a fall.
So for number in.
Range.
What does in range mean in range means if I put a value in here so it's a link which right now is for
it's going to iterate.
No no no can be anything it could be I.
It can be a digit.
It can be donkey whatever you like but I'm going to call it number as a little easier iterate through
it.
So do this once and then its rate number up by 1 and keep doing that until this number is the same as
length.
So what do we need to have we need to randomize.
Why do we need to randomize.
Well what we need to do is pick a new random number and we need this to happen each time because otherwise
it'll only happen the first time instructions read and it'll always come up with the same random numbers.
Let's make this as random fossils are randomized and then we need to do is do a combination dot append
because were appending to the array.
And what we appending to and remember pend means we're adding a new digit to the end.
Well it's a random integer as a random integer up to 10.
Now we're using up to 10 because remember we're starting at zero not at once of 10 digits from zero
is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
Those are the digits we want.
OK.
How do we know this works wonderfully is finished.
Let's print it.
Right now this won't do anything because I need to put in a ready function.
We're going to remove the ready function later but I need to check this is working and all to do is
generate combination links.
I test just this scene.
I'm not good press the play button and press the play scene button which is this one right here.
You just press F six if you're on with us.
6 2 7 3.
Now you notice the scene is completely empty.
Let's try that again.
1 7 8 3.
Fantastic.
We now have a node that when it's asked to can generate a random combination of four digits.
My challenge to you is I want you to change the script or the export variable to generate an eight digit
combination.
Now for some of it's simply very simple.
And for some of you this might be a little more complicated.
So pause the media make changes so that you're generating an eight digit combination not a four digit
combination.
And then when you come back I show you my solution.
Welcome back.
As a couple of ways I could do this.
The first is I could change the export variables so I just put eight here and then run the scene.
5 9 4 2.
Bring it.
I could also return this back to whatever's in a script and just change it and script.
Now are on the scene.
There's another eight digit combination.
Awesome.
Now let's incense it with.
In this scene so I'm going to instance in level one.
Scenes and cut combination generator.
One more thing where change me go back to my original scene.
I'm not going to change it here I'm a judge in the original scene and go to the script.
I'm going to remove export variable length 8 and the ready function and the print.
I'm not going to print the combination.
I'm gonna return it so as to return combination.
If you return by itself it will just end the script where you are.
So just stop stop doing.
But if you return combination whatever value this is which is the value of just generated right.
This array.
Send that back to whatever function called this one.
So we are going to create a computer that is going to call this generate jeric combination and actually
generate combination not generate or generate combination of length that can be called from another
script and whoever calls that just send it back here.
This is going to be rather useful because if we look at any level one scene we could have five six 12
computers all calling this and they will each get their own combination of whatever length they asked
for which is a really good place to be right now.
And that brings us to the in this video.
In this video we've looked to creating a combination object.
The idea that a node is going to take the position of a script we could have put this in the computer
script or in the global script.
But instead we've created an object and that object is going to be responsible for the function it's
named after.
We've also started creating combinations bready for the computers and we've looked at Flip's again.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.