Hello wonderful God people in this video we're going to put the state of our game.
We're going to put a portal which if it touches will win the game and to make the portal really magical
wouldn't they put some particles into it.
So before we get to it let's quickly look at the design here.
I want the player to beat the level if Bunny touches the portal so that says to me Area to deep right
the portal floats.
So when I give it a slight animation it should feel a little bit magical and it's going to have particles
to look even more magical.
OK.
Nice and easy.
Let's get to it.
Okay let's make a portal.
I want to make a tough map.
Let's make a portal.
And to do that I need a new seat.
So a new scene and a root of area to hoodie.
Why.
Because we're going to measure when Bunny is touching something and the easiest way to do that is with
an area today.
Good to rename this portal
and I dont need this animation window.
This is from my prototyping.
Get rid of that for now.
Okay weve done this a few times.
Right someone make a Sprite and then a collision shape first thing spect.
If you look at the graphics under items there's a yellow portal or portal yellow.
And let's give you a collision shape.
This has to be a child of portal not of Sprite.
So collision segert Judy and then make a nice simple one a rectangle it be very forgiving with this.
It's going to be wider than this.
But it touches Anyway here you have won the game.
Well done you've made it through these challenges.
He was and I know I've said this three times.
Remember scale by the extant not by the scale handle good to hide that and make sure that when I move
the portal I move the portal and all children get again in a couple of things.
First thing I want to see this Sprite of the portals to actually animate.
So let's do that.
Let's do animation player.
OK.
Where are we going.
And then make the Sprite.
I'm not going to animate the area to.
Why.
Because I want to scale this thing right and make it float by scaling it.
If I scale the area too deep I also scale the collision shape and that way bugs can be.
We had dragon way of saying that but time here be dragons that seen scene formation portal float.
We have an underscore because reasons.
There it is.
And I think a nice two second animation and we will just do the scale key Sprite scale.
Perfect.
And make this a looping animation.
And at one second I will change the scale of the spri economical a little bit wider you know what let's
change the scale this way.
First thing is centred good.
So now when I scale it it'll scale on the centre.
That's why I'm taking that scale that say one point to five on the X
and point seventy five on the Y.
I'm going to play a key there.
I'm not going to want the end because if it's looping it's already going back there so let's see how
that looks.
Okay that's a little bit slower than I wanted.
Now I could drag this over here and shot the animation.
Let's look at another way we could do that.
If I go to animation player and I'm going to playback options speed one that shows that too.
And I want to press play.
It's now doing at double speed.
So if I don't want to be moving that off I just want to see what it's going to look like at different
speeds.
I could do that.
You'll notice.
You can also animate the playback speed so if you need to do slow downs and speed ups that's how you
could do that.
OK so we have our portal.
Let's save that other scenes.
I'm a put a signal in.
I'm going to do it right here.
So let's make our portal instance our portal in scenes portal.
No no no no no portal and let's do that on move.
There we go.
Much more like it.
I will put it on a test it before I put it anywhere let's put it right here near Bunny.
I'll move it to another level.
And make sure that I've actually got the animation playing.
Current animation portal float.
Great.
It's on auto load.
It's looping.
Looks good.
Okay.
I want to connect this to a signal.
So let's do body entered and connect that to game state.
And we're going to leave it as on portal body entered.
Couple of things I could do here.
I could just tell it.
End game or I could make a brand new scene saying you win.
For now let's do end game.
So now when Bunny lands on this thing should have a nice easy game over go.
How would I change that.
Well let's go to the end game scene.
As game over and what to do is make a new version of the scene.
I'm going to do new inherited scene.
What scene we inheriting from was the basey.
We are starting from Game over.
And now in this new scene which I'm going to call victory.
I would change the text.
You'll see everything here isn't great out.
That's because this is the inherited value.
But if I change this to you win and save this scene you'll see it saving a brand new song.
So that means I can go into my games state script.
Here it is.
And I can have a victory scene so let's do right here function.
Win again
and let's copy this.
PACE it there.
But we're not going to do.
Game over.
Right.
We're going to do a victory.
So let's call this victory and we need to define victory.
So into.
Global.
Brand new scene and I'll put it directly on the game over hoops.
Victory equals right click on the victory sign.
Copy path.
All of this is a variation on a theme right.
We've done this before.
OK.
So now it's close as I can see you're doing.
So now we're in global we've got victory.
Let's actually make that work.
So on portal body Enter atlus gold win game and a.
When I put that function in there well ago function or win game.
And what are you going to do.
You're going to.
Let's duplicate this cannot be written down and you're not going to a global game over.
Oh need you can't.
You're not going to Global Game over.
You're going to global victory.
That should work fine.
There it is giving a victory saying I didn't notice that this doesn't seem to be an amazing.
Are you in a meeting.
Yes you are.
Awesome.
Naphtali lightning.
Now we have one more thing I'm going to go back into the live portal scene and I'm just going to stop
it planning for now because my eyes.
I'm going to add in a brenan note.
I'm an add in particle to see if I can spell it.
There it is particles to be particles 2D.
Does some really cool things.
First thing I need to do says there's no material in order for this to work.
You need a process material.
So let's make a new particle material and you'll see it's just dropping standard blobs behind it.
I'm also going to put my particles above the sprite and that way you can see that in here.
Now I'm attaching a link to the documentation That'll explain everything that these particles do.
Right so you can play with them but very quickly let's look at some key ones emitting.
This is light enable America.
The default is on switch it off.
Now particles switch it on particles break out how many there are and what do 20 for the moment one
fades it gets respond case perhaps back to eight for now.
Time how long does it last.
So let's say last 10 seconds.
Why is it now dripping.
Because you can only have eight particles if I do 24.
And now we have water dripping on a stunt let's put this down see what's a good lifetime.
Two seconds ago.
All his other variables are a lot of fun to play with but most of them are actually in the particle
material.
This is where the fun stuff is.
So let's say I want things to orbit I want an orbital velocity of what's good 10.
Two right.
Gravity for example so if I move this to minus 98 gravity is now up right here it is back down.
One more thing then do let's give it texture material.
So in particles on the graphics thing you'll see we've got a portal particles just put that right here.
There we go.
OK.
So this brings me to my challenge.
I'd like you to omit some particles customize your particle to decode and a little something that you
like.
Don't be afraid to play with it.
It's going to look bad for a while then sun it's going to look good.
Just explore the options look through the documentation see what the various things do.
Suppose the video have a play when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Mike Mac.
OK.
Let's start at beginning some guy through these Wonder time missing.
I want that 24 actually feels pretty good to me.
Lifetime.
How long is going to last for.
Sounds good.
One shot one shot is interesting.
One shot means these file once and then stop.
Right so these are a one shot and I switch them on.
They'll fire and then they'll stop.
I don't want that.
Pre-process how many seconds have you calculated before you draw.
This is really useful for things like our flaming torches.
If you have a fire effect as a particle they only start drawing when the player can see them.
That means that you're into a room and then the torches flare up or maybe that's not what you want so
you use pre-process.
Let's go in to the material itself.
Now I kind of want these to rotate so what can I do here.
I can change this to a sphere.
Care right now is not doing anything.
Let's change the sphere radius to 64.
Ah now we're getting somewhere.
Let's see.
I'm not going to change the alignment spreads.
Yeah what spread a foot five sounds pretty good.
Gravity well if we switch gravity off.
Okay so now we have this we are twinkly star effect I quite like gravity so I put my gravity back on.
Okay I want these to rotate a little bit so let's give an orbital velocity and I'm going to say point
five.
K there looks pretty good.
What about my initial velocity and the initial velocity point five.
Not that another tug gravity back off.
I quite like that.
In fact I think I'm going to call that done.
So here are my particle so let's save that and go back into our scene.
And they're looking pretty good.
Look at that.
Let's move the portal to the envelope.
I have my move tool selected so I'm not worried about dragging the wrong thing.
And let's move this coin coin.
Let's move you to right there and portal.
Let's move you to here and let's see if I can get to the other level.
So money should she go.
Go.
Ouch.
Ready to go.
However I did manage to win a mug.
I did manage to get an extra boost thanks cloud.
I can't play my own game.
I'm on Bonnie.
Did it.
Awesome.
And that brings us to the end of the video.
In this video we've had a really quick introduction to the particle system in God.
They're really versatile.
A lot of fun things you could do with it.
And particles are not the only ways we could do this effect but they're a great introduction.
So before I sign off of this video remember to share what you've got Show us the particles you came
up with.
Where else have got particles.
Did you use a different graphic.
Have you got yours sort of floating or being stars of the different colours.
Are they slowly rotating What did you create.
Im really excited to find out.
So share on the discord on Facebook on the forum.
Great work and I'll see you in the next year.