Hello again you glorious God to people in this video.
We're going to link our computers with them nicely random generated code to the correct lock doors.
What I'm looking for is a system whereby there can be multiple lock doors with the same combination.
To do that let's get into God.
And the first thing I want to do is I want to find a way of connecting a computer to a locked door.
Well we really know how to do that we can use a signal if I got to my computer and look at the nose
there's no signal here I really want to do so.
Open the computer script and make a new one.
Let's call it signal a combination.
What's going to happen is we generate the combination which is going to find the combination generator
grab a combination of a specific length and then pull it back and then I'm just going to pass it on
to the door.
Some of the emit signal.
OK.
So emits signal just takes a string and the string is going to be combination.
However we can also pass through any argument we want.
I put a comma I can put an argument like combination.
Great.
Right now it doesn't that you have anywhere to send it so just send an empty signal.
That's not going to crash godso is just going to not let anything happen.
So let's connect it right now we only have one locked door so let's connect it by signal.
So click on my computer node again.
There's my combination signal connects find a locked door.
And it's gone away on computer combination exactly what I want.
Let's connect.
All right.
On computer combination is where we get this combination.
So let's erase the value of the combination very well right at the top here.
So we're not going to it to 4 1 5 instead combination is going to be set here and it's going to be set
by whatever value we pass through.
Now we're passing a function with an argument if there is no argument here gotto is going to crash.
So let's put in the argument.
I'm not going to call it combination here.
I'm going to call it numbers now.
Just because we've called it common combination when we have admitted it doesn't mean that the node
that receives it needs it to be called the same thing.
I think God cares about is what's the value of this variable not what's it called.
So I can say combination equals numbers.
Well let's check that works.
So originally we set this door as 4 1 5.
See if that does anything for.
Oh I crashed.
And the reason is look right here.
Function ready.
Canvassed Lare combination pad combination equals combination.
I am passing this value through but I'm not setting the value on before this is being set.
So what's being sent here is combination is an empty variable.
You can have empty variables but that doesn't work.
Instead this needs to be sent after the value is set.
So let's move it on a hold old and down our own windows and just put it down here.
And we don't need a ready function at all.
So is going to raise my ready function.
Let's see how that works.
Nice big screen.
Let's go check what the actual combination is 8 1 7 5.
Awesome.
So first will check for 1 5 4 1 5.
Does nothing.
Oh you should have cleared 8 1 7 5.
Awesome.
I now know I have to clear that.
When we close the pop up that's fine but that's now working.
Let's very quickly make sure we are clearing the number pad.
If you exert not only do you hide you also resets.
No.
Is right here.
Let's do a reset lock.
Check.
That's what I've called it.
Yes Alice.
Awesome save that.
OK.
So this computer is now linctus locked.
Can we have this computer linked to multiple locked doors.
And the short answer is yes that will already work.
Let's find whatever door this is this door to you cannot erase you my daughter don't need you.
And let's not duplicate an instance in a brand new locked door.
I'm doing this just like I say we haven't copy through the values I'm just going to instance in a scene
of a locked door which is right here.
Let's move it down there.
Key move down there and I want to rotate this by 90 degrees but I mean make sure not rotating all lock
doors just this one.
So let's find transform 90 degrees.
And that looks pretty good.
Okay.
So if I want to connect this computer to that locked door what I need to do is just go back to my signal
colour combination connect and just find that new locked door locked door to connect.
And that should work fine.
Let's find out if it does.
9 1 2 7.
And this time I'm going up this way.
Nine one to seven.
Outstanding.
Excuse me out.
So now I'd like to challenge you to add more lock doors add at least one more collection of computer
and locked doors.
Cheer level.
In other words Locked doors are have a different combination.
Don't be afraid to rearrange your level.
We have all these auto tiles for a reason.
If you want to add more rooms or add a door where there wasn't one go for it you might need to tweak
the navigation polygon instance to stop guards from getting stuck or to make use of new roads.
So was the video add another group of lock doors and when you come back I show you my solution.
Welcome back.
So this isn't that tricky but there is one area where you might get a little tripped up.
The first thing to do is figure out where to put the locked door.
I want to put the lock door right here.
I think that's a good place for lock dock and I want to put the computer here.
I must start with the computer so underneath computers I mean instance in a brand new computer.
Move it to the right place and let's rotate it so let's rotate you transform by 90 degrees.
Just put you roughly in right place.
Now let's put in some more lock doors or one more locked on.
Instance in a locked door.
Let's rotate you by 90 degrees opes Let's rotate the lock door by 90 degrees not the node.
Keep doing that.
Awesome.
And it's blocking the light.
It's all looking good.
All I need to do now is connect this computer as a signal.
To that new locked door and this is the bit where you might trip up a little bit so find a locked door.
If I press connect now.
We've just done it on computer two combination because computer is not the same as computer too.
So let's erase that and I'm going to unlink this thing.
Instead let's connect it and rename on computer to combination and get rid of the two.
And let's actually connect it so we'll find locked or three and connect that great.
Now it's using the same function we don't need to pull a new function.
And let's actually make this a little more interesting.
I'm going take computer one out of the change the combinational.
So this is a 3D accommodation and computer too will be a five page compilation.
Let's see how that works.
So just quickly sprint to the computer 474 helo Fallsville break and let's open this door.
Thoughts.
Full time.
That's right.
Sleep behind this guard ups family.
And this is 1 6 1 0 8 5 digit combination.
Let's check that opens up 1 6 1 0 8.
Awesome.
Now one more thing I would like to do right now I have this locked door and if I want to leave I have
to know the combination if I forgotten it.
I'm stuck.
So what we do is we go to the locked door scene.
I'm going to add a new area to do when I add it on this side.
So let's add a new area Trudy.
And I'm on call this exit detection.
And we'll put a college in shape.
Collision shape to.
And that's going to be a rectangle collision shape.
So new rectangle shipped to me and going to move it down here.
I'm holding shift pack my snapper still on.
That's nice.
And we're going to make this.
Let's see.
I don't want to move this don't scale any to use the xanth Somewhere.
Use the sense make it nice and big and let's say like that.
OK.
What I want is when the player comes here I want this door to automatically open.
First thing they do is make sure the collisions.
Good because I only want this to work on the player.
Second thing I want to do is connect it as a signal to get a node on body entered and connect it to
lock door.
I'm going to connect it as on exit detection body and now I could just connect it to the open function.
But the reason I don't want to do that is this signal automatically passes through an argument body.
This means if I put in an open I will have to do open brackets body and then every time I want to use
open if I don't have an argument there it's going to crash godda because it's going to be expecting
arguments so instead I'm going to pull open here.
If you did do it the other way if you just linked it directly to open body and you wanted to then pass
on to variable you could just do novel and pass no through.
This is like okay this argument is not an argument but I have forgotten it.
But I think it is nice and simple.
Let's make sure that on my 2D script that the open locked door things are on the right side and then
not I've put them all on the wrong side so let's make this nice easy for myself and just move the collision
shape up to here save that.
So now.
When I walk up to one of these doors la la la Scuse me Luke 7 8 5.
7 8 5 will open up the doors lubing.
Sorry I need to make sure off if it's not already played the animation will open.
It just won't do that.
It's going to open the door script and check out open function.
Open is animation play open.
So what I need to do is if it's not already playing so if animation.
Player is playing.
I was going to do is false.
Bless you I mean if it's not playing play it now.
I now have this redundant information here right so I can actually remove and not animation playing
from on CD or body and add and that brings the end of the video.
In this video we've linked a signal to multiple nodes so from one script to multiple scripts and how
he might need to rename a function if you've renamed the know that it's coming from and we've connected
individual computers to multiple locked doors with even snuck in automatic exit detection so the player
can't accidentally lock themselves on our level.
Fantastic work and I'll see you in the next video.