Hello again like for God people let's finish customization off in this video and apply the customization
that we managed to get going in the last two videos.
So before we do that let's talk about what needs to happen if we apply customization.
We need to store important variables in a singleton is a great place to do that that allows us to keep
these variables between scenes.
We also need to be sure what we mean by an important variable.
Specifically I need to know which P.S. we've selected.
So which play a model of my loading in and I need to know what material to apply then I need to spawn
the correct P C and apply the correct material and they're going happen in slightly different places.
Let's begin by figuring out where the placement spawn is.
So I've got a play here and what I'm actually going to do is go in to the template some will add the
little template and remove the player.
Dum Dum da Boop.
And instead I'm gonna spawn in a position 3D node record player start player start position as it could
be placed opposition a save that go back into Level 1 and not move the floor move the player start position.
There it is.
Just move that over there leave it up a bit.
Now I think it's probably facing the wrong way but once we get the play going other I'll check.
Next thing I do is make new scripts scripts and make a new one and I'm gonna call this customization.
Judy and let's put it in the script folder scripts folder customization really save done and I need
to save the import information specifically.
Play materials and
play a character.
Why capital B.
Because I'm referring to a.
While we here.
Let's also preload what the players are.
I mean like a new variable called a male.
And I'm going to preload.
And why my preloading.
So it'll be fast.
Right I'll be ready in memory the moment we need it.
But I'm going to preload into scenes go into characters go to players play a M C and that she's going
to live right there.
Elsie the same for female freeload and drag the female loon.
So save that right now I have a script.
Let's make it a singleton.
I'm an auto let this project project settings auto load.
We've done this before right on the path.
Click on the little dot dot dot then and find it says in Scripps.
It's called customization.
Can I add it.
It's enabled as a singleton so we have two singletons that file grabber and customization.
Awesome.
We can now access them.
Let's before we go any further actually make sure that we're resetting these variable supply materials
and player character to do that.
I'm going to go in two scripts folder and open character customization.
Judy I'm going to pass this information through on start that unpressed.
So first thing I do customization dropped player materials equals.
Now I could just put in current material right and current material is just an integer.
So if I do that I'm going to have to scroll up here.
Sure I have to do left the wrong file gabra again get the same files and then load them in again.
So instead let's make a brand new variable and call this selected material and let's make a note so
we remember what it is.
What's the difference Tweenies in the current material selected material.
Is the material that we're passing through to customization.
Judy I wish you'd put that let's put up and change material because we're setting these materials here
so I'm going to do some selected material.
There it is.
It calls and I just need to copy this through it right so I'm going to grab this bracket here load materials
this current material.
Well if I'm doing that then why am I putting this in twice so instead of repeating load materials this
current material let's copy selected material and just put it here apart everything else is going to
get a lot more readable.
Jemmy brackets there it is.
We are setting material 0 with selected material.
Awesome.
Now instead of current material we can pass through selected material and the beauty of this is we are
now passing through the object not the string reference so we don't have to put in any loads or anything
it should just work.
OK we have the selected material we also need customization dot player underscore character he calls.
What did I call this double check.
Current player.
Now this will pass through as a string.
But that's okay we can work with that.
Alright so we now have the Select Committee on the player coming through into customization.
Now we need to apply them first let's open game state.
If you don't have game set up trailer and scripts don't worry.
And on the ready elements set it with a new function and let's call this function.
Apply customization.
Copy that and pull it down here.
Looks good functioning.
Apply customization as per pass for now because it occurs to me.
I could also put something called Count me I must do that count.
Enemies let's copy that and you know you to move this down.
Once you move this down count X..
Now I think that customization is not really a good name because what we're doing is picking the character
so let's call it select character or instance character.
That's a good one instance.
Little good spell again.
P.S. good name instance.
P.S. that's what were doing incensing the tippler player character.
Or I must start with a new variable.
We call this play.
Now let's go to distraction free mode.
I could see more of the screen and now it's a simple condition if customization dot player character
equals two equals because we're checking so is the same as male.
It doesn't actually matter which a pick player.
Equals customization.
DOT.
Male.
OK.
So why are we using this.
I'm using this to load this in somewhere load it in this instance let's just put it in an instance now
because I've only got two characters that I can just do a simple if.
Else if I was using multiple I could use.
If iliff or a match case or dictionary.
But as I've only got to this feels pretty solid.
So if it's not male It has to be female.
Because we have an unfortunate binary thing happening customization dot female dot instance.
All right so we've decided what the play is going to be.
Let's add the child child player.
Now let's get our destruction free mud from it and figure out where this is going.
Player is going to be added to game state dog video game 6.
She's always going to be the root node so whatever level we've got if we keep getting levels it's going
to be here.
Let's check where our player start position.
I need it to move to here.
So back in the Scripps asked of the child let's move of play dot transform equals and now I just need
player start position dot transforms or whether this is moving there too.
I'm pretty sure that this is facing backwards but will check that niman Alright so we'll apply the customization
for which character were doing.
We have done the texture's I'm going to put this in play which again is open twice and a close one of
these and put it here on ready.
Why am I putting in the play a dodgy bit is the player should be responsible for how a player looks.
This isn't a game decision right.
The game is something which player will loading in but the player needs to be responsible for how the
player looks so ready.
I need to update the mesh.
If we look character customization and I take a look over here we can remember that what we actually
need is the armature mesh set surface.
Easiest way to do this.
I go back into the correct script.
Why you.
I won't go into my scenes folder which is right here in two characters players and it doesn't matter
which player picks up I play F. And I need to change the material on this measurement right click on
it and do copy.
Note path back into my script.
I am just going to go dollar omniture mesh.
I get.
Sure Shemesh dot in you the set surface material so millot Copy that over.
That's in customization.
Here we are set surface material.
0.
I don't need set set the set surface material 0 will already loaded this in as an object So customization
dot player material.
Okay so how would check if this works.
Well let's open the customization sinks back into my scenes followed into customization and open customization
and just check on in the right place.
We aren't going to run this scene.
And let's customize the look and press begin.
And here we are.
And we are facing the wrong way but the customization has applied to so many just that.
Now it's a little slow.
I should probably preloading the scenes but we can do that when we polish.
Let's just make sure we're facing the right way.
So I go into my template.
Here it is.
Actually probably not a template because we don't know which way it's facing.
So click play it start position go to transform rotation.
I'm rotating on the green access that's the Y and it's 180.
So one more time run that scene.
Choose My look just begin.
And there we go.
Perfect.
Outstanding.
We have now applied character customization.
Now at the moment there's no way to get into that.
But there is one place we should be put we should be going into it so let's go in to a level template
or just maybe manner which will open the pores manuscript.
So let's open the pause menu scene rather.
So I'm in my possession you must show my pop up.
I want this cat.
This customize character button to do something.
So let's go into the Customize character node and connect it so selected that button breast and going
to connect that to pause menu and I need this to load that scene.
So get free any pass.
Sheesh scene.
Let's go find the scene.
It's right here.
I happened to have it there.
I'm going to going to load that scene in.
OK.
So far we're off to a great start.
But if I play this game now we're going to have a problem.
Check it out.
Oh no.
What is happening.
What's happening is that we don't have an error correction because we're not starting in character customization.
We're trying to load in things that haven't been set.
So here's my challenge for you.
I'd like you to put in some error checking make one of the pieces and the materials spawn.
If we haven't thought through character customization suppose the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I show you my solution.
And welcome back.
First thing I do is I'm going to go into the play a script that's open to play a script.
Now all of these models have a different texture but I am setting it to a texture and that's why that
character went black.
So instead let's do this if customization dot play materials is not null and if I look at customization
you can see it's starting off as noll's is a variable with no entries and an empty string.
It has a null variable.
So what I'm saying is if it's not null applies material.
If it is would just skip this entirely.
So let's see what that looks like.
Great pretty solid.
Now at the moment it's picking the default character for us.
And let's take a look at why.
It's because I've done this else.
If right I've forgotten that that was going to be a side effect.
If we didn't want it to happen we could go to play character and set this too.
I don't know female However this ELSE IF will actually work for us so let's try that one more time.
I'm going to go into a game.
So it brings to full screen.
That's working pretty solidly but look.
And when a postgame press can customize character and nothing works.
Why doesn't it work.
Because we pause the game to get to that menu and we never came out of port so we've loaded paused.
Okay how we fix that up pretty easily.
What I need to do is make sure that when we load this level we come out of ports and open scripts and
go into character customization and on ready right at the top.
I mean do this get tree dot paused.
He calls false.
I don't need a toddler to set the FOSS so straight up one more time.
So go into large screen customize my character.
We are no longer paused.
I can customize to my heart's content Let's bring in Frey and I will where the nice grey shirt because
I'm wearing grey shirt right now.
Press begin and look at that.
Awesome.
Look at that.
We now have a working character customization.
Our game is very nearly complete at this point.
It's just a couple more things we need to do.
So in this video we've looked at storying applying character customization and whether this system will
scale so if you have lots and lots of customization in each character we can just scale this up.
Excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.