Hello again you fantastic go to people in this video.
We're going to build on what we did with the disguised box in the sky you box is a great fun of stealth
games but we went in limited how many the player can have which means the player should know how many
you have left unless it's a really good gameplay reason to hide that information we should make it easy
so we're going to add it to our gooey and to do that we're going to use a node called item list and
item lists are awesome that typically used for inventory or hot bars but they can also be used for displays
so if you can display disguise what do we need to know.
First we're going to have a gooey element that shows the disguise as an icon.
We just got a little picture of a box with a heading this has disguises.
We're gonna update this element with the correct number of icons.
We shouldn't know how many disguises the player has.
So let's jump right into it and first thing to do is I'm gonna open my play a script.
Here's my plan script and I'm also going to poke my gooey script was not the interface and it's under
gooey OK so I've already got the suspicion meter so as a child of this control node we press control
a lot like an item list and let's quickly take a look at what the item list does when a right click
on it and go open documentation and we can take a look at all of this.
What I'm specifically interested in is to do add I can item now there's two things we can do.
We can add an item which is something with text and an icon or just the icon is going to take that the
texture and the selectable and just to really drive that whole here's a little slight for you.
Item list can add items with the texture and or label and we're specifically using add icon item the
texture icon which could be a PSG file going to load in and selectable is false because you don't want
a player to touch it it's not gonna work like a button it can work like a button but that's not how
we're going to use it.
Okay.
So with all that done we should pretty make it look good.
First off I don't want stuff the nightmares.
Let's got to that and I'm gonna make a brand new nine patch rectangles.
Let's go control a line patch.
Don't worry we're coming back tonight and list.
I just got too excited.
Let's rename this because this disguise container
and it's gonna be a nine patch rectangle using one of these.
Now if I look under graphics and under interface and under Pinkie I've got to do it to do to do to do
a bunch of these glass panels and I want the one with the bottom right corner I believe is gonna be
that one.
Let's take a look.
That's the bottom left corner.
You've got Mike on it.
You are excellent.
And I want to about the same with the suspicion which is let's take a look how big this is.
This is to 47.
I feel like it should be round number but I'm going to put it 250.
It's got a width of 250.
And what's the height on this comeback.
Could just press my patch right to go here.
Height is 85.
Probably a little bit higher to be honest not fire taller.
That's why let's say let's call it one hundred and let's go a little bit wider.
I'm just doing this my eye right now.
OK.
Now currently we're not using the corners.
Let's do that.
I'm gonna go to axis now patch margin that we got patch margin and say 12 pixels on each side.
And that's already looking a lot cleaner isn't it.
You know I should know I'm not gonna rename that.
That's fine.
Okay.
Now let's add in a V box container and I'm going to go full rectangle that's going to cover all of that
and let's give it some margin so it doesn't go over the borders.
So I'm gonna go to to do margin say 12 pixels on each side and it's twelve minus twelve from the bottom.
Great.
And while we're here let's move the disguise container.
So I'm was going to you know I'm going to go down to rect and go to a position which could drag over
the X say house where it's about 30 pixels.
Yeah about 30 pixels from the 30 pixels from the top.
Too much it's a little bit too much on the top isn't.
So as you can see if Justin's by eyeball what feels right it's a 20 and that's looking pretty solid.
Okay.
Within that I need a labels as go like
label let me.
I would like to wear disguises.
Now it's using the theme that we've only got logged in because the theme is set to control.
So all of its children will use the same theme.
So that's pretty fun.
Now you put an item list do to do to do item list and one thing you'll notice you want to add in a test
once so items at the top you go at and let's load in graphics PMG tiles and it's fine that box 129 and
you can already see that we can't see it's auto height.
Okay so one is too big and too it's not got anything except for the theme 3 it's got item 0.
Let's fix that last problem first the items that's going to rub out the text but secondly we do make
sure got items selected go down to icon.
Let's say that's a zero point five.
Now if this doesn't update straightaway just change this icon mode top of left or change window.
It just got out.
Not yet updating I think has been fixed in later versions but look in check.
Finally let's fix the themes only go back to control with my theme is click on the thing I want to add
plus item press the three dots and press item list H I.
I know my alphabet.
OK.
So we should now have item list right here on the styles background.
I just want style box empty.
Boom.
Let's do that with all of them just to be absolutely clear.
And now all of our item lists will be completely transparent.
And that is pretty much set up.
I do want to call this disguise counter just so I know what it is when I look at the scenery and I want
to add it to the group.
So let's as the group disguise display.
All right so what's going to happen.
Going to make a group call that's going to tell disguise display.
This is how many disguises you have.
Please update yourself sets out a script to disguise counter interface disguise counter.
It looks good.
And this is a really easy script so it's going to.
And call it up date disguises and we're going to get an argument through from whoever up there.
Yeah.
And watch the screen.
I will give you at the argument of how many disguises we have from the player or whoever calls it the
disguise count counter doesn't really care who calls it.
That's the beauty of using signals and group calls.
So you can get a number pass through.
First thing I do is I'm gonna clear what is clear to Mr. Glick hold control I'm gonna click on it removes
all item from the list so who's empty the list out completely.
So every time this function is called you'll just empty the list OK.
So now we want a for loop.
So for disguises just a variable that we're naming right now in range.
There we go.
And it's in range of number.
So while the integer disguises is within whatever number is surface 3 it'll go 1 2 3.
What do we want to add icon item.
Great.
And it wants two things it wants this texture and we need to load that in and let's go find it.
It's the P and G it's on the tiles and it is tile one 2 Nine is one I'm using or whatever one you're
using.
So first we load them in and that's and say Is it selectable false and that is that script.
So now we can just close the gooey entirely I should left it open just in case do some typos but let's
make this nice and easy.
So we've already got the number of disguises right here.
So that's we're going to pass through.
So let's go get free and cool group and it's disguised display.
I think that we shouldn't close that window.
I might have done it now.
I see if I can do this.
OK.
The method which can be passed through is a string and this is update disguises and we're gonna pass
through an argument and it's going to be number of disguises.
OK so that's going to be doing well you can say call the group disguise display tell it to run this
function with this argument and at this point the play script doesn't care what happens is information
that's important.
If this is type out if this is type owed it won't work and it won't throw up an error.
Let's see if it works if it works.
What I'm expecting to see and I don't know.
I'm not editing ahead but I'm expecting to see three boxes in the disguises.
Let's take a look.
We do.
But they're going down.
That's easy.
We can fix that.
Let's go right back to a facts.
Yes interface.
There it is.
GARY Hello Gary.
OK so the thing I forgot to do is under columns I want to make sure that it's not just one column.
How do you think it fit.
I reckon seven I'm eyeballing that.
So now we press play it knows we have three disguises.
However we haven't yet told it to update when I use the disguises and that is my challenge for you.
I would like you to have the item list update when the player uses a disguise.
Every time the players disguised have the item list update we could later on also put something where
the player could find new disguises but we won't be doing that in this course.
But it's quite easy to do so pulls a video give it a shot.
And when you're ready come back and I'll show you my solution.
All right.
Let's take a look.
So all I need to do is go back to my play a script and let's make this Listen big under the skies.
I just need to call that group call after number of disguises negative equals one as long as it's after
that it'll work just fine.
So let's just grab this back up to I play a thing.
I'm sure.
Copy this line back to the bottom of the script.
I use control end to jump to the left and right off this line.
I'm going to write this in.
I make sure that the right indentation let's see if it works three disguises two disguises one disguise
no disguises can't disguise look at that and we didn't need it because in the top left which is where
we expected to be so it'll work just fine whatever size screen it is.
And I am pretty happy with that in this video.
We've updated the icons using simple group calls.
You can also use signal calls and we've learned the item lists are awesome we can use them to very quickly
show numbers of lives coins and all the rest of it.
We don't want your show text so excellent luck and I'll see you in the next video.