Hello again delightful God people.
Let's actually start making this game in this video we're going to make the character see.
Now the character scene isn't going to be one they're going to see in the game.
This is like a template.
The character is going to be a bass scene from which the player and all SPCS will derive.
So why would we do it that way.
Why wouldn't we just make an NPC scene or a guard scene or a camera scene replacing.
There's a few reasons.
First we want to avoid repeating stuff.
Okay so if we have a single value for max speed that is shared amongst multiple characters it makes
sense to put that in one place.
That way we need to change the value.
We only change it in one place.
It's the same with code.
If for example we have multiple characters that move the same way we should use the same code to move
them.
This can help him for consistency right.
And it also helps us make variations.
If I want to make a brand new type of NPC and I already have a base NPC scene I could just tell God
what the difference is and not worry about everything that starts to date.
Okay so let's actually make the scene.
First you want to make a new folder and I won't call it scenes.
I'm going to go in there and in there.
I'm gonna make another new folder called characters going to make it easier to find all my characters
and I'm gonna rename that so that was the correct amount of letters in the word characters wearing characters.
Let's get to work.
I'm gonna start with a kinematic body to dig all of my characters are going to be kinematic body 2D
kinematic body to D.
As you might remember is going to need a coalition shape but the force of the collision shape in I want
the graphics I'm put in a sprite.
Going to graphics into PRNG and I only use man red.
I'm going to use man red because I don't intend to use them anywhere else so if I see this on my level
I know something's gone wrong.
It's important if you have a template character they don't want to see.
Make sure it doesn't look like they're the player or something you see everywhere to make it very difficult
to find it.
OK let's give the coalition ships are close and ship a collision shape to eat there it is.
And I was going make a capsule because that looks pretty good.
I'm going to move it till it's centred and as I've said several times over the expanse not the scale
so looks pretty good.
This is hand drawn so it's not quite symmetrical.
Yeah I looked solid and let's make sure that whenever I try and move this can mattick body and remove
all its children.
I'm gonna call this character for going further.
Let's say them go to scenes characters and he'll be called character.
So now my challenge to you.
I'd like you to set up your character template.
You don't have to use the same graphic.
You could use a different shape in all the rest of it but just make sure that you've got this character
class done.
Pause the video set up yours and when you come back and add some code to it.
Welcome back.
Okay so the first thing to do is make a script and my script is going to be called character but I'm
not going to put it here.
I need a new folder.
So let's go back into our room folder.
Rose and mega Scripps follow
scripts.
Oh bad timing to that.
OK.
So new script.
Move it to the script folder.
And it's going to be called character dodginess is are basing what I'm going to put in here.
Constance I put in values that I don't expect to change and I want to be the same everywhere.
So this is the concern.
The first thing you put in is a speed not a gun right.
All of my constants in capitals so that when they appear in the code I can see this is a constant.
Don't change it.
God will let me change it but I put it in capitals to remind myself not to if I want to change things
I should be using a variable not a concept.
Again need an actual value to this Summerset my speed to 10.
We can tweak this later but through trial and error.
That's what I found worked well with what the game will be.
So that's only 10 pixels movement.
Every time we do the thing for nelse a bit magic.
But remember we can tweak these.
I also need a max speed max speed is going to be 200.
Finally I want a function.
I will set this zero point one.
Friction is actually going to be how long it takes to stop.
If I set this to 1 or 5 or 10 everything can be made of ice Zero Point 1 means zero point one seconds
I stop the player won't really notice it but then notice it just enough for it to feel real and that
sets up a base character.
So let's say this and we're good to go.
In this video I've looked at how to design from the idea of a template.
We're going inherit all these properties so this allows us to start from a very basic what do all characters
have in common and go from there.
It is going to come really handy.
Next few videos.
So great work and I'll see in the next video.