Hello again you vibrant go to people.
We're now getting to the point now game where we can stop.
Make it exciting right now we have a simple little maze that you can sneak around and see how long you
can survive the we're gonna have an objective.
We're going to add some loot now the way this is going to work in the game is when you put loot in a
secure place and I'll level and the play is going to get to it.
And once they have it they can go back to an exit but there's various ways we can do this.
And today I will talk about using as node to create an object oriented approach to inventory.
What does that mean.
It means rather than using a bunch of variables like an instance variable in the player code I have
some briefcases we're going to create a node under the player at runtime called briefcase and then later
which is going to check does the thing that has entered the exit area.
It's a bit clumsy does the thing who has gotten to the exit have a node in it called briefcase or loot
if it does you can move on for like several if it doesn't do nothing.
So that's what we're doing today to do that.
We're going to jump into here and make a brand new scene and I'm going to use an area 2D.
Why am I using arrow city.
Because it uses collision which means we can detect if something hits it but it doesn't stop things
from going through.
Which is exactly what we want.
Nicolas briefcase and let's see on the graphics under PMG you'll see a folder called loot.
We have two options.
We have suitcase and loot.
I'm going to be using suitcase but you can use folder and you could use both.
I will add a whole bunch to it.
You can make your level is as simple as complex as you like.
I'm using a suitcase want to do that.
Add a sprite.
That was control a drag the suitcase over here.
Now this is 64 my 64 was a little bit too big for me.
So want to transform on the scale and make sure you're doing this on the sprite not on the briefcase.
So don't do it here.
That will mess things up.
I'm going to scale this down by zero point five.
And let's give this a collision shapes on the briefcase control a collision shape 2D and make a brand
new Rectangle.
When I click on that and give it extents of 32 by 32 that may still be too big but we're going to work
with it for now to save that like a brandy folder or.
You call the items you call objects.
I'm gonna call it loot.
So this way you can make as many different ones as you could.
So you can make bigger and bigger levels with more and more intricate ones.
If you're going to be doing that I would recommend making a loot template like we do with the characters
template and each different type of loot will inherit all the properties and just change the sprite.
Okay so couple more things I won't do.
One select briefcase got a collision and we should change the layers.
It will not be on any layer at all and it will only interact with the players.
This means if NPC is walk through it or if they tried to text it nothing will happen.
So we don't have to do any kinds of fancy if conditions we're just going to use the built in collision
filters.
Next up going to create a very simple script for the briefcase press create and first thing to do is
go back to and the very first image to put in there and click on briefcase again.
You'll got a note and we do a signal on body entered physics body 2D.
It's going to connect that to itself.
So on briefcase entered the signal is going to come through with this argument body.
This argument is a thing that has entered it.
Well it can only be the player because it won't trigger otherwise song to go body dot collect briefcase
so when the player walks into the briefcase the briefcase is just going to go Hey you there run your
function called collect briefcase and then it's not gonna worry about anything.
We're gonna keep the data for the briefcase as simple as possible and the next thing is going to do
is go queue free.
He only pick it up once.
We now have a nice simple function and the briefcase is done so we can go back to our player script
suddenly go.
Here's how I'm doing.
Before we do that let's bring in the suitcase.
I feel in here some ways less dangerous.
Yeah that looks good.
And we can add more doors computers this is a simple test level to say what I'm doing but I'm thinking
up here.
And don't forget because it's all Tom maps you can make this as complicated as you like.
OK.
So let's bring in a brand new node because we're using nodes to organize our level to control a no no
control Q control.
A thank you.
There's going to be a node and it's this one loop and you know what I want to bring this up here somewhere
just because reasons all this loot the instance and a child saying What briefcase Hello briefcase.
Make your move and just drag it to the right place.
When you think about who that's mean isn't it.
We could rotate this we do what we want but I feel like that's a good place for it.
OK so now we need to make the player able to pick up the briefcase so the player needs a function as
opposed to placing and go into the script and it's right down the bottom on the get the skies or under
the skies.
Let's make a function called collect briefcase.
I think it's what I call it.
Let's double check on the briefcase collect briefcase.
There it is.
Great.
So player you're going to create briefcase.
OK.
So this is going to be adding something to the scene.
So I'm gonna go.
I'm gonna define what's gonna be.
So then of course will increase that code loot and this is just go be a simple node because doesn't
have to do anything it doesn't have any functionality it's just gonna be a simple node which it can
check.
Do you exist.
OK.
So that's my node looped dot set's name.
I want this no to have a name in this case I want it to be called briefcase.
I'm giving you the capital letter because nodes have capital letters so just to remind me about it that
it's a node.
OK.
So we've added defined a brand new node was told it this node is going to be called proof briefcase
briefcase.
This is what happens when you record videos of the my brain my speeches slurry child looked up and now
that should be everything to test this.
I'm going to go into here and I'm remote and let's go show you what's happening in life.
I'm going to open player and that's my placing so back into the game I gonna keep that there and make
this nice and thick.
And now I've got actually a way over there.
All of a sudden 7 0 6 0.
This is quite difficult 7 0 6 0.
No no no no no don't see me.
This is the first time this has actually been difficult.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm a box
cheese.
Okay.
I'm enjoying this.
La la la.
Now if memory serves there is a camera up here.
And here is my briefcase.
Now we could make the briefcase visible.
Well I like that I can hide behind this desk.
And it crashes what it crash
because I forgot to make that a function.
I will do the same thing.
I might forward a bit and grab it and look the briefcase now has arrived.
So now we'll be able to use has node to detect if there is a node in that call briefcase.
Oh goodness.
We don't have an exit yet so I don't know where I'm running to.
But this is already a lot more interesting.
Right now I've got a reason to go into a dangerous area and I think that's a pretty good place to end
this video.
So in this video we've use an object oriented approach to inventory.
You've already seen this like I'm shown again and we use and we're going to prepare things for has node.
I think that's really good progress.
We've gone from a nice little tech demo to something that's actually enjoyable to play.
Make this as complicated as intricate as you like.
Put has lots of different loops have easy sections difficult sections really make this game your own
meanwhile excellent luck and I'll see you in the next video.