Hello again you wonderful garden.
People in this video we're going to take that briefcase or folder or whatever loot we have.
I'm going to show it to the player.
We're gonna make a gooey for the loot.
How's that gonna work.
Well the gooey is going to start invisible at least this part of it is so there's no sexual mock loot
until the player picks it up at which point we're going to show the loot as an icon let's start to do
by going to our goo gooey peasantry right here Hello.
Aha.
OK so we have disguises.
We have suspicions so it can be very similar.
Those two in fact I could probably copy it and tweak it but that feels foolish under control.
I don't make a new 9 patch rectangle and get an interface and I'm going to put it right here in the
bottom left.
So I want my interface on the graphics interface.
Keep making that mistake PMG down to my gloss thing and he as one of these ones which one is it you
are top right corner.
I think you're at it.
You look like it.
Fantastic.
I don't mean the same with as this one which if memory serves is 300 wide.
You know what I'm a McCoy you loot container.
Got wrecked and make you 300 wide and suspicion meter cause is gonna be here to line up suspicion meter
is doo doo doo doo doo.
Eighty five high let's make you eighty five.
Hi.
And when you use the same patch margins we have a four so twelve on each side and let's go layout anchored
to the full rectangle but it's going to all be aligned to the bottom left.
Now we're gonna play on margins if memory serves is a twelve of them.
Let's take a look.
Margin from the left is thirty okay.
That it is boop and it's now smaller is that something bigger again.
So three hundred.
Boom.
There we go.
And let's take a look at you.
Where are you from the bottom.
You are twenty four negative twenty four from the bottom.
Let's do that.
Negative twenty four is now smaller let's make it bigger Oh I see you can be like that.
Fine.
Movie up at the line you about Harish negative 24 how's that
you little Lulu.
I'm keeping an eye on the bottom one.
That is fine OK v box container the box containing l I wanna make you a full rectangle so you cover
this entire panel let's give you some margins it's to 12 in each direction negative twelve negative
twelve.
Fantastic.
Within that we are putting a label I'm going quite quickly because I cut my label quite quickly because
this is the same thing we did a couple of videos back.
So she's quite fresh but we're going to call this one loot excellent and now on item list and this item
list is going to have seven columns because same with that one and the icons are gonna be zero point
two five not zero point zero five zero point two five.
Why.
I'll show you why.
If we bring in that's going to load in this icon the graphics and PMG on the loot from the suitcase.
The suitcase is actually twice the size of this this crate because it's a different item pack.
So here we go.
We can now see it's got rid of that.
What that's going to look like and I think that looks pretty fancy.
OK.
I'm going to go back to my items and delete this one because when I start with them we're almost there
now.
OK but the script for this one on loot container first let's add it to a group that adds the great loot
loop.
There it is.
And let's give this the script for this to the loot container.
Why.
Because it's going to start hidden and it's going to show itself and everything else going to happen
to a child of it.
This tells me that the functionality for it is going to be a blue container.
Now I could in theory put the script on item list and tell it go to your parent go to its parent and
do that.
But that's really bad practice.
You can use functions to call down to child nodes but you should use signals to call up to parent nodes.
Much simpler.
I'm so like a script on loop container and I'm gonna make the really function and it's not with Hide.
So the very first thing to do is going to hide.
Let's find out.
Press Play can I see the loop thingy.
I can't.
Awesome.
So let's make a function called collect loops call its loops.
I'm not gonna posture an argument this I've only got one type of loot.
But if you have several you're going to want to put a function in that fuzzy as do it's gonna run the
show.
So when you pass of the briefcase it's going to shut and the next thing to do is bring up this item
list item list and we're going to go dot adds icon item just like we did before.
So we're gonna start by loading in and let's go find our briefcase which is boop and the pinky on the
loot can drag in my briefcase.
Awesome.
And the other argument to go of here is is this selectable.
No it isn't.
This is not a menu item you shouldn't touch it.
It's just going to be used as a piece of interface.
Right.
Now let's go back to the play a script.
Play a script which is under play.
Hello.
Play a script.
Jump into it.
And we've already got Collette briefcase so as well as adding this let's call it get Tre
Cool group and what we call this.
I forgot.
I mean I remember back some of how I wrote it.
Let's take a look.
We old you looked with a capital L..
That's a good name for it looked and we are running collect loot.
I believe the gold.
Let's take a quick look at my lips scripts.
I'm tried to do this for my cats climbing my shoulders.
Thank you kaboodle.
Collect loot.
There it is.
And let's close that because we don't have to pass through any arguments.
OK let's see if this works OK.
Let's see.
We are at 0 1 3 1.
It's a little tricky 0 1 3 0.
No go too fast.
OK.
0 1 3 1.
Let's go now now now now now.
Now inside its belt have cellphones and payday 2 as well as fast as you can.
OK.
So we'll pick this up.
So because I change the screen size halfway through it thinks it's over here we can play with that or
we could just lock the screen sizes through the options menu a little later on that we now have a loop
menu that shows up correctly and I am pretty happy with that.
So loop in this video with finished the gooey we can polish it we can add more details but that is starting
to feel like a real game.
That was kind of exciting running around at high speed avoiding gods and trying to find the perfect
time through the lights.
I'm quite happy with that.
I'm quite enjoying playing it.
So excellent luck and we'll see you on the next video.