Hello again you scrumptious got to people why scrumptious.
I don't know.
I'm running out of wonderful adjectives but your wonderful adjectives in this video.
We're going to take those disguises we made and make them risky.
Right now we have a gameplay problem.
We've created an awesome disguise that has no cost to it so there's no reason why you wouldn't just
go through the game as a box let's make disguises risky.
I've got some ideas of how we can do that.
The first is we're going to move slower when we disguise it makes sense right.
Boxes are well known for not moving fast so we're going to be a compelling box.
We should move slowly.
I might be confusing boxes with titles.
We're going to limit the amount of disguises you can't carry an infinite amount of disguise boxes with
you can only carry a set amount.
We're going to put that as an export variable so we can tweak what that set amount is but let's limit
it let's also have the disguises only work for a certain amount of time.
If you take the disguise off before then fine.
But if you don't when the time runs out the disguise will just vanish.
OK how do we do that.
Well here we are in God.
And what are going to do is I'm open for Play a script which for some reason is very small.
Zoom in so you guys can see what I'm doing.
I'm going to start by putting some export variables.
That way we can tweak them quite easily.
And the first one I want to put in is disguises how many disguises do you start with.
That's not how you spell disguises.
That's a smart disguise.
For now let's say three and I'm going to put a note in here.
So anyone who looks at the script can figure out what we're doing.
How many disguises do you start with.
It's not a question Howie the size as you start with.
Next one I also do is export variable duration disguised duration I guess makes more sense.
And this is going to be a time in seconds.
How long did the sky start.
For now it's like five seconds and I'll make a note.
How long disguise can last.
I'm saying can last because you do have the option of taking it off beforehand.
That's a space there.
Just make as nice legible.
One more export variable I want to put in is how much work in the skies will slow you down.
The school is disguised slowdown and I'm put zero point to five.
When you wear a disguise you're going to go a quarter of the speed as when you walk around.
Right now we can change all of these as an export variable so if I open the player and take a look right
here the top script variables disguises your age so we can fix these very easily.
However these are good defaults.
Let's start with the easiest to start with this sky slowed.
I need one more variable for this to work and I'm on to put it right under disguise because they kind
of grouped together.
Velocity multiplier and a default will be 1.
If we then scroll down to move and slide I'm going to multiply motion by velocity multiply.
At the moment motion times 1 is the same as motion.
But when we change velocity multiplier to zero point to 5 it's going to slow us down to a quarter speed
OK.
So now we just need to switch velocity multiplier and the first somebody that is when you disguise or
when you're disguised.
Let's slow you down.
So velocity multiplier equals disguise.
Slow down when you reveal.
Let's switch it back and I want to keep these to roughly the same place if you know what let's put these
at the bottom.
It makes more sense.
Well maybe up I can't disguise trueness outs will put it right here up a little gap between them.
So after college allow one to put a velocity multiplier equals one because that's a default rate.
One is always going to be a default.
All right let's see how that works out.
So here I am as a person and I can spread it around the place very fast.
Here I am as a box and very slow.
Just like in real life boxes in nature as you know very slow.
I am as a human and I zoom around the place like a zooming thing.
Great.
Well that's the first thing taken care of.
So if I had a list in front of me I'd take it off the list.
I didn't make a list but that's okay.
We know what we're doing.
The next thing you want to do is check that we have enough disguises left let's close the outputs so
I can see enough the screen and go into big screen mode to do that.
Going to get a total disguise and I'm going to remove this.
Else I should change it for an IF right else.
If so we know your not disguise so I don't need to pull anything the skies in here.
Why do I need to do is check that disguises is greater than zero.
So if you're disguised reveal itself if you're not disguised check that you have a disguise to wear.
If you do you can put it on.
Otherwise you can't.
Awesome let's Pressplay.
Ellis checked once twice thrice and then I'm out of disguises at the moment.
We have nothing and the going to tell the player you have no disguises left but that's okay we'll put
that in later for now.
That's two of our main options.
The next one is going to be the timer to make the timer work.
Let's actually put it in the player.
Someone open the placing arm put a timer.
As a child of player now let's connect connected with a signal.
Somebody get a node first time out and going to connect the timeout signal to player.
But I'm not going to use this method here on time a timeout.
Instead I'm going to use reveal
the moment this time runs out drop back into revealment Let's scroll back up because on ready I want
to make sure that the timer is set to this disguised duration variable.
So let's do that here.
Let's say a timer dot and asrs WAIT time equals disguise duration.
Now we actually need to start the timer.
Otherwise this does nothing.
So let's head down to the skies and get a print right here so timer dot stopped.
So when I press play when I'm expecting is I can disguise myself and then after five seconds I'll just
pop back and find out disguising myself not touching the keyboard waiting 5 seconds do do do do and
any time now I'm popped back.
OK so I didn't touch anything.
Now what I would like to do is put a label on the player
and put it right.
Let's move the label.
Let's not move the parent just gorgeous with the label over the label.
Right up here and the text is going to be zero point zero is zero.
Just so I can see what it looks like.
Why do we keep it in theme as well something else the theme in lote theme is my theme.
Awesome.
So now it's infant and that's Infoline all looking good.
Let's get back into the script.
I want to go right here on function reveal.
We have to hide the label so label got visible.
He calls phos and when revealed let's do the same thing so the label not visible cause I say the same
thing it's the opposite right so I can see the label.
There's a slight issue that's going to happen here for Pressplay.
You could see especially in night vision mode.
The label is already there now where the skies myself and then come back they will vanish.
So ready.
Going to have to go into reveal mode.
That's okay we can do that.
Let's get ready.
Which going to call reveal.
Awesome.
Now before we start the timer actually working I have a challenge for you.
I'd like you to make sure that the label for the disguise timer is always the right way up.
If you look at what's happening when I move around the screen the label is wherever the boxes.
Right.
And that's not that useful I'd like it to be visible.
So see if you can get the label to always face the right way.
Now we have actually solved this before with doors computers so don't be afraid to refer back to it.
But pause the video.
See if you can find a solution.
And then when you come back I'll show you how I do it.
And welcome back.
Okay.
So what we need to do is on every frame and we do it right here on process.
I want to check the time as the way out a timer.
I don't mean time and do I mean label dot.
And let's find the actual rotation.
Now this is slightly different because this is a gooey element.
It's going to be rect rotation.
That's mouse over it regular rotation.
Awesome wrecked.
Rotation equals and this is going to be negative rotation degrees.
So whatever we're facing going the other way.
Let's take a look.
I hide myself and look at the timer who's just fine.
Awesome.
OK.
Now let's actually display the timer.
So first thing let's go to the timer and make sure this is set to one shot.
Right.
It's going to run once and then stop.
I don't want it to keep running.
Now let's actually display how much time is left so still in process.
I'm going to go label dot.
Text equals.
And I want timer dot time left and I'm going to have to parse that as a string because that's going
to be a float text requires a string.
So I'm going to cast time adult time left as a string.
That's going a little messy though because take a look.
Here I am ingame disguise myself and look at this timer.
Oh that's annoying.
I just want the first two digits if I want the first two digits.
I'm going to use a function within string and logo dot pad decimals and not iPad 2 decimal places.
Let's Pressplay.
I'm disguised.
And look at that.
Perfect.
Disguise.
That's really clear.
Lastly let's make sure we're only updating this label when we need to and we only need to when we disguise
sellers go off disguised
and then would tab.
So they're part of this type.
This code block so now if you're disguised rotate the label update the text and if not done.
Which brings us to the end of the video.
In this video we've learned how to display a set amount of characters or digits in a string using pad.
We've made risk match reward and we've added cost to using a disguise.
Now disguise has become really important.
We have to make sure that the player knows that they have a set amount disguises left but we can cover
that in a future video.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.