Hello again, you energetic, got people in this video.
We're going to keep building our tutorial, going to add objective markers when the tutorials done.
The play is going to be pointed at certain areas that they have to go to and do something so they can
learn the game.
That pointy thing is what we're doing.
So to do that, we're going to give the player a visual indicator, going to move the indicator around
to the next position.
And that's pretty much it.
So let's jump into it.
And I'm going to let you know before we go any further, let's put the tutorial on this level, on this
spy screen.
And to do that, I'm sure to copy these to something to highlight start button and label them on a duplicate
them.
Now they've got over there, which is a city place for them.
So let's just check our grid container has two columns.
That's good.
And I need to drag one of these stock buttons down here.
Fantastic.
Now, obviously, start mission stop mission is wrong.
Let's change the label text for that.
Let's say tutorial or start tutorial or play and automotives will hide the whole thing and bring it
back.
And it's just going to refresh all of our gooey elements.
Okay.
Now, currently we have two stop buttons, one to rename that tutorial button.
And I'm going to go over to the signals and I'm going to disconnect the signal we have and connect a
new signal back to the lobby.
And there we go.
And I can just duplicate this with control.
B, hold open down arrow.
And now I just need to change the reference to the scene.
So I'm going to levels, which is on the levels.
And you know what to do.
This way is right.
Click on it.
Copy path may light level one paste and be good to go.
Let's just take that works.
Best tutorial multimedia tutorial.
Fantastic.
OK, so energy toil.
Let's make the tutorial work.
So we're in tutorial now in the shita.
Let's make this story work.
First thing.
I'm starting to change your mind about these lights.
I think they're a little overpowering.
And all I want to do is turn down the energy on them.
So it's will them go zero point five.
So let the other end call it zero point five and let's refresh us our memory.
Let's refresh ourselves now has refresh our memory on what we're gonna learn here.
So we learn move with this from this foam.
We can learn.
Open the door.
You're going to learn.
Use night vision mode.
We learn briefcase with a briefcase.
It's here and exit.
Each of these is going to be a brand new objective.
I don't put them in the scenery first.
Let's just give ourselves a little bit more room.
Everything is very big right now as doors and new objective.
I feel like the door here is sensible.
Something to slam a door, make chairman move and just drag it to the end of the corridor and let's
just see how it looks on press play.
And you watch a trial and there's a darkened door.
Very nice.
OK, great.
OK.
So with that done, let's start putting some areas in.
Now we don't even area for move.
That's going to happen the moment it comes in.
So we're going to do it on like a brand new organizing notice.
Put a new note in and I'm gonna call this objective areas.
And I'm to fill this with area duties.
The first one is going to be over here.
So we're moving to let's make a brand new area.
Tutti.
And it's going to need a collision shape somewhere at in a collision shape.
Tudi.
Excellent.
And your new rectangle.
It's a good size.
It's a 64 by 64.
Great.
So there it is.
And I'm gonna select the top one.
And let's do.
Don't select children, sir.
Only ever select the parent.
And now I can move that into position.
That's what we gonna move to.
So move over here.
We could make this a little bit more interesting, but putting some some obstacles in this room.
But that's give me my basic move.
Now I'm thinking this door is too close still.
So let's fix that by going to the tile map.
Where is Maternelle map?
It's on navigation, 2D tile map.
Boop, boop, boop.
Too soon.
And that's why the door's going to be.
So now I'm gonna move the door over here.
And the reason I'm doing that is I want the player to actually have top charts to read it.
No, that's not new objective.
So the move this door.
And it's not packable.
It's transform, but change that rotation.
Now, you probably put another light in here.
So I'm gonna take this light to D and duplicate it and let's move it to right here.
This one is a lot smaller.
It's two energy, zero point five.
You know what?
This one is zero point as well.
Go and let's make sure I've got this correctly selected.
And on a scale it right down.
So let's say is zero point two five.
Point two five.
How's that looking?
That's looking much better.
And let's rotate.
It's on first etisalat rotation and w to move it.
Each rotated a bit more.
And that's, you know, that's looking pretty good.
OK, so there's a first objective, and I'm going to move that into the corridor a bit.
UPS not rotate it, move it into the card orbit, and it's renamed this one this move objective.
OK.
It's tweaking the but let's duplicate that and with the new one over to the door and I'm going to call
this objective.
Now, this is what we'll do when we go through the door.
So this so in a move, this objective is going to give us a new objective.
Get the door.
So it's coming with the door objective just to the other side.
And among the planning it through the door, that objective will kick in.
At which point night vision kicks in.
So let's duplicate Dorje objective and move it down to here.
Can I call this night vision objective?
One molas duplicate you and go over to the briefcase.
Nicole, this.
Briefcase objective.
OK, so all of these trigger signals.
I got to let the game know something should be happening about now.
Now I think we should create the Sprite that's gonna tell the player where to go.
So let's go right to the top and add a new Sprite.
If we load a texture.
So on the graphics, on the interface and a Panji, we've got these crosshairs.
I'm thinking this one.
That's the one Anglaise.
So you could use a pointy finger.
You could use her.
So what if your knees.
I'm gonna use this one.
Now you'll notice first.
This is behind the wall.
That's no good.
That's above the wall.
Let's go to that index and go up to.
Now, it'll always be about the war.
Second thing you'll notice is it looks good now, but how do you look in the dark?
Let's find out.
Tutorial.
Terrible.
You can barely see it.
So let's give it its own light.
First, rename it to objective.
Object to the point of.
And let's add in a light two days light tutti.
And the texture is way, do the texture going to get to my objective marker?
Copy this.
Now back to my life, Judy.
I want to pace it in ordinary.
I wouldn't suggest doing that.
But we want this light to always be the same.
Texas.
I'm okay with it for now.
Now, I'm not going to move this into position because the game needs to move it.
In fact, that's not true.
I want to move it to the players.
So it's right here and now we want to happen is we want the cursor to move from here to here.
And then once you get there to that.
So the next area.
The next area.
First thing we need to do is we need to start to connect these by signals and connect to my signals.
Tutorial must have a script.
Let's create a script and let's start connecting these someone to do move objective and body entered
physics 2D.
And each one needs a different signal.
So I'm going to go through them one by one body answered back to tutorial.
Body entered Bachchu tutorial.
Body entered.
Back to tutorial.
Now, usually when we're moving things around and got out, we're going to be using animation play.
Animation play doesn't just move things physically.
It's also it can move properties.
Right.
So we could say, okay, change the color over time.
We could say change the scale.
We could do all kinds of stuff.
But what do you do when you don't know the start and end values?
It's much harder to feed those into an animation player if I know that this area will always be exactly
here.
That's one thing.
But if I don't know that right.
If I need this area to find out where this position is and move there, we're going to be using a tween.
No.
So let's add a tween and I'll teach you how to use it in the moment.
OK, one more thing we need is positioning now.
We could just use the areas.
But I also want to introduce you to a brand new thing that's really used when you're putting levels
together.
I want to introduce you to a position note in this case position Tutee.
And if I move position to the right here for the player, this little cross-hair.
What's interesting about this is this is a position you can use in engine, right?
You could use this as a rotation axis.
You could use this as a place to go.
It's a way that we can mark information.
It's actually just a node to deal with a different graphic.
If I play the game, it doesn't show.
I got go tutorial.
There's nothing there.
Right.
This is gonna be really useful for us.
So I'm going to make a brand new organizing node.
And I'm going to call this objective just how to spell.
Wow.
OK.
Jack, give positions that go and I'm gonna put it right here next.
The objective areas.
I put this position in that and I'm going to call this move objective.
Great.
And let's move that to here.
Now, you notice it's not in the same place as the actual area.
It's a little through it.
That's because when the plant enters it, I want them to still see the objective and then see it move
and where they're going to move to copy that and put it over by the door right on top of the door.
And then I call this door objective.
And I want a copy that is you're going and put it right here.
And I'm to call this nitrogen objective.
I don't know why I put a capital V in that.
And now I need to go to the briefcase under control d duplicate and rename you to Loopt Objective and
Control D..
This was the exit objective.
Now, what's important here isn't what I've called them.
What's important is the order they're in.
You see, I'm about to write a function that's going to go to this objective positions and find them
in order.
Here's how that's going to work.
I may go back to my tutorial.
And.
Am going to make a Branly function, Lefranc functions to be called updates pointer.
Positions.
And it's going to take a point of no objective, no dispassionately objective, no.
OK.
The first is going to happen is we did a fine off there.
It's the first variable I want.
Let's go to your big screen mode.
Let's see, we got a variable called Pointer.
And what's the pointer?
It's this objective, Malkia.
So we gonna go pointer.
Which one's point?
Objective pointer.
There it is.
Fantastic.
Next thing, the place we're going to.
Now, ordinarily upright position, but position is already being used.
I can't use that.
So instead I'm going to call it place.
I could call it objective position.
Objective place.
I'm right place for now.
And what do I want to do?
Well, if we look over here, I will say go to the objective positions node and then get the child that
matches the number.
And remember, we're counting from zero.
Effectively, we've turned this node into an array.
So I'm going to go objective position's objective object safe.
What is so much trouble is what positions.
There it is.
Dot get child's.
And then I want to use objective number.
So if I pause zero through here, place will be defined as whatever node is in position zero, right?
Which is right here.
One, two, three, three is in the wrong place.
Glad I checked that, let's move three Luling, three two over, Larry.
Over here.
So three great.
OK.
Let's go back into our script.
And the first thing to do is go function.
Ready?
And I want to call update point positions or update points, positions, position.
Zero.
That shouldn't be in plural, should it?
Now let's make it actually move.
By the way, I don't think this will move yet.
Explain unexplained in a moment, but just a heads up, that's something that's not going to happen
here.
So what do I need to do?
I need to move it.
To do that, I'm going to use my tween.
Now, tweens are quite annoying to set up with a lot of little variables.
One of the reasons that you really do want to use animation players when that's the right answer.
But sometimes tween is the right answer because we can take any starting value.
Go get an end value and tell it.
Okay, move between them.
Do that.
I want to use interpolate property.
That's gonna take a whole bunch of arguments first.
What am I interpolating.
I'm a interpolating the pointer.
Okay.
Now give me the property as a node path.
In other words, as a string right position.
I want to move it right.
What is my initial value pointer.
Dot position.
So whatever, wherever it is now, that's where we're starting.
Let's go to the next line.
Thank you, very loud motorbike.
And let's say, where am I going to this place?
What position?
OK.
How long is this gonna take?
You can play with this plan, it's say zero point five, so take half a second.
What is my transition type?
You got all these different ones to work with.
These are a lot of fun to play with.
I'm going to use sign, but really try to for once.
Hey, I like them.
Finally, what's my transition?
Do you want to in Georgia, start slow and go into it?
You want to start abruptly and end gently.
I'm Ledoux's ease in and out.
Now this on its own won't do anything.
We also need to run the function.
Tween dot start.
OK, let's give that a shot.
And remember, I don't think this will work.
Let's find out.
Tutorial.
I was wrong.
OK.
So if it doesn't work, his boy Y is going to happen.
I'm really happy it did work.
But if it doesn't.
The reason is Dotto is going to initialize nodes in the tree in the order they appear.
So if I want to start using this folder, it's possible it's not ready yet.
If that's the case, you want to use yield, which means wait.
And then you tell it.
Elliot wakeful to do that.
I'm going to go get tree.
Tree.
There it is.
Comma, idol frame, weight one frame.
All that's going to do is just tell go before you run the next command.
Just wait affright, let's play.
And if you had problems of that before, it should now.
I didn't.
So, I mean, rid of that.
So that was working perfectly.
Now I just need to update my point of position with the next objective.
I actually don't want to be in full screen mode for this Sakiko Maxim Fort's.
Let's take a look at our objective areas.
And let's see, we have an object, various objective positions, so we have move, the next one is
going to be Dorje objective.
So I'm going to duplicate this and move it down and change this value for one.
And I'm sure duplicate this one done to here.
And there should be two different parts.
And same thing, right?
So Troopergate, you move you down, get rid of that lying.
Three.
And one more Troopergate down.
La, la, la, la law for now.
Have we done it right?
Let's find out because tutorial got big screen nose and he's gone horribly wrong.
And I suspect what's happening here.
So if you're getting that bug, go over to your objective areas.
And I think what's happening is the area itself is being triggered immediately.
So just go to areas and each one remove the layer down.
And we should get rid of that bug.
Boop, boop, boop, boop stick.
Look, look.
Tutorial March, we're going to hear.
It's going to move out the door.
We get to the door.
We haven't opened it.
We open the door.
We go through.
Head down to here.
It should go through the briefcase.
So we're going to have to check this area right here.
That is my night vision objective.
It's in the right place.
It was the wrong signal.
That's why they would disconnect you.
And do the right signal, so always check your actual tutorial of working properly.
I can get rid of this line completely.
Move this one up.
There we go.
OK.
Let's check this one more time.
Do you actually check these stories?
A lot of moving parts.
That's gonna move over here to the door.
Open the door.
La, la, la, la, la.
Now, you should have the briefcase.
Fantastic.
And the briefcase should now point to the exits at the exit with my loot.
And I finish the tutorial and that's looking pretty good.
One more thing we should add.
Let's just quickly add to the debate.
An audio stream affect our sound effect for this.
So audio stream player.
And at see under doo doo doo doo doo, sfx, SFX.
We have we used a message.
Wow.
That sounds good.
Let's see how that sounds great.
Make sure it's not looping.
Click on it.
Make sure looping is off and then re-import if I need to.
But right now, that's perfect.
Someone has to drag you into my.
Click on it, drag you back into the stream, and let's make sure the nice quiet Sigmund's five.
And now let's actually play that.
Someone make this up.
I need to rename this.
So let's rename this message and.
And to make that nice and easy, rather than write it for each line and write it here.
So audio straight player, that's our message sound.
Don't play it quickly.
Check that.
I'm quite happy with that.
Still a bit loud.
Let's turn that down.
Let's say minus 10.
And one more thing I want to do, I want to quickly move that point out.
So let's say the subjective point to here should be the other side of the door.
I'll take my door objective point to make sure I move and just move it just the other side, because
they know they have to go through this door.
Now, we will have the text in the next in the next video, not the next level.
But that feels like a really good place to end in this video.
We've looked at 13 notes and again, do play with these are a lot of fun.
We've used position to d to mock movement positions.
So just as something we can look at an engine that just helps us make the level.
And we've looked at using the parent load as an array using get child.
So excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.