Hello again you marvellous God.
People in this video.
We're going to upgrade our game right now.
We've created a game we sneak around a room for no reason.
But this is called heiss Meister's.
Let's come with a heist.
In this video we're going create some loot.
Grab it and have an exit.
Okay.
Let's get straight to it.
The first thing I do is I'm going to make the exit so let's make a new scene.
And I think Cole rectangle why colour rectangle.
Because I want a little rectangle that's of a certain colour that I can put a label on it.
And people know that's the exit so let's do that let's make a nice skin colour or a teal ish colour
and always fix that later.
Maybe make this a bit bigger.
That's looking like a decent size for now.
Great.
Now one thing I do want to do is make sure that this is semi transparent so I'm going to go down to
the visibility and under modulate and lower the Alpher value that makes that semi transparent.
OK.
Let's say this is a scene and the call this exit so we could see what this looks like.
And I may well rename the actual note may be about that size less incidents that in some instances.
As a child level one as my exit.
That's looking pretty good.
Maybe a little less teal a little more blue to match the interface.
Let's just tweak that colour rectangle.
But you get the idea which is going to make a nice block of colour.
So that's looking good.
All right within this point areas hoodie.
Now the two days at zero zero and I probably want it centred on the object.
So let's find out how to drag that to the centre.
I want to put in a collision shape.
A collision shape to a new shape is going to be a rectangle shaped hoodie.
And remember it use the accidents not the scale.
And I can move my area too deep.
Remember to move all children Erica.
And get that more or less right.
If in doubt overlap the area slightly because we want the player to have a little bit of leeway so that's
looking pretty good when they do.
Meaning it's a label that's put in a label.
And I write the word exit and put this in theme.
So thien Load theme theme.
Fantastic.
And that can go in the exit too.
Let's save that the other looks like in-game pretty good.
Now we could put this in the interface so that it vanishes and only appears when you're in night vision
mode.
For now we leave as that is.
But so we have something in the works as an exit.
It's not connected it doesn't have a script yet.
We can do that later but this is just something to watch.
Now let's make some of it.
So a brand new scene and the route now is going to be in the area 2D.
The way this is going to work is the players going to walk over the area pick up the item and the item
vanish from the map.
So I want a sprite so you can see what we're picking up.
And Sprite has that many letters in it and other graphics.
And the loot You see I've giving you two options as a folder and a suitcase.
I'm going use a suitcase and for the texture.
Do you use the folder you use the folder Now area to do requires a collision shapes Let's put that in.
And there's another new rectangle.
And again use the excess to make it nice big.
Speaking of nice and big.
If I save this I call it briefcase.
Probably rename Eric too deep a briefcase to make a nice and easy.
So if I save this and insist in this scene you'll see it's a little bit big.
I mean that's there's a giant briefcase so I'm going to go back in my root node the area to.
I'm going to head down to transform and on a scale at zero point five.
Save that and we'll go back in a level that should be a bit better.
Great.
Make sure I don't click on furniture by mistake.
It.
So we have a basic pick up let's put in a script in the briefcase so it can actually do something somewhere
to get a new script scrip for briefcase put it in my script folder call it briefcase and it's got to
go.
Now let's connect it by node to itself so on body entered connect to briefcase before we go any further
let's make sure that both briefcase and exit are on the right coalition led somewhere.
Click on inspector and make sure our briefcase selected find collision.
There it is OK.
You are not a player some Take player off the player but you do interact with the players.
Let's those unmasked and do the exact same thing on exit.
So head up to the area to Dean because that's where the collision mask is.
And it's not on the player where it is and the player mask so interactive the player it is not a player
that's very important.
We don't want the guards to see the exit that counting as oh I've seen the player.
All right so we have this briefcase script.
And what does it do.
Well let's make it nice and easy.
Briefcase is going to tell the player so global dot player and were going to run a new function in player
let's call it collect briefcase.
All right.
So save that.
And now let's head over to the play a script which I happen to have open here.
And remember if you don't have an open head back up your dad's folder go to scripts and find a player
in here.
It's right there.
And we make a brand new function we put it right at the end and I'm going to go function.
Collect briefcase.
I don't just want the briefcase to be collected.
We also want it to vanish from the maps once it's called this function.
Q free.
There it is say that now we you test what's can happen.
So what I'm expecting is we're going to walk into the briefcase.
It's going to trigger collect briefcase on player which currently does nothing.
Let's make go rent out as we say got a briefcase.
And then it's going to cue free it's going to just erase itself from memory.
It's going to go off the map as Pressplay.
And walk over to the briefcase got a briefcase.
Fantastic.
Right now that's all it does.
I've got a briefcase.
Nothing else happens.
So let's make something else happen.
I don't want it to say print a briefcase.
I want to actually change the game so that we can track that the briefcase has been picked up right.
I need to know the player has a briefcase or doesn't have a briefcase.
And in fact that's my challenge for you.
I'd like you to make get a briefcase case work create a way to track of the player has a briefcase.
Now there's a bunch of different ways to do this and that's going to show you quite a sneaky one.
So feel free to get creative in this instance.
There are a bunch of right answers.
Don't worry if yours doesn't match mine.
But pause the video may get briefcase work and when you come back I show you my solution.
OK Mac.
So how will I do this.
Well there's a few ways as I said before one thing we could do is we could make an instance variable
make a call it got a briefcase and set that to false right.
And then we go back to them on a script and we could just set that to true.
Okay.
That will work.
Another thing we could do is we could create a dictionary or an array called inventory and we could
either make it an array or we could make a dictionary and have them numbered and then we could add them
to the array or add them to the dictionary.
That will work fine too.
However let's actually use got strengths got an object oriented language so when we use an object what
I'm going to do if we go over to level 1 I'm going to create a child of player called node.
And when we need to track if the object is there we're just going to look in player and take a look.
How do we do that.
Well nice and easy.
Let's get back down to our Got brief collect briefcase function.
And within this function we make a new variable called Lift.
Loopt not a lot.
And Lute is going to be a node that's going to get created right so node.
So it's a it's the basic node type right.
So the simplest node we can make and Dot new means make a new one.
Now I'm going to loot dot Saturn Lane and then only give it is brief case.
So what I've done is I've told it OK when I'm saying the word lute.
What I mean is a brand new node.
OK.
So make a brandnew node and set the name to briefcase.
Now add it as a child.
Of the node running the script.
So the player is going to quit brandnew node called briefcase.
So let's take a look if that works.
Now obviously we can't just see it come up on the go because we haven't program that yet.
But if I press play.
And over on the scene tree while the game is running I wanna hit remote and this is what's happening
right now in the scenery.
So I got out a player.
He can see everything that's happening on the player right now.
Let's move over to the briefcase.
Look right here.
We've created a brand new node called briefcase.
It is a child of play.
That's really exciting because now when we go back to the exit we can give the exit the script.
So let's create a brand new script on exit and I put it in my scripts folder.
Do do do do de is can we call it OK.
So now let's go to area to Dee and connect that as a signal to its parrots are on body entered connect
to the exit.
OK.
So let's get sneaky the players going to enter this area and we're going to assume it's the play and
we want to check.
Do you have the briefcase you can't leave if you don't have it.
So if body.
So how would we do this.
Well this too has node briefcase.
And right now we don't have a game over a game one screen we can make those soon so let's make it just
print.
You have a briefcase.
So take a look what's happening here.
We're checking if the body that entered which in this case is the player because only the player can
has a child node has a node with the name briefcase then run this condition.
Let's see how it works out.
So here I am in night vision mode and we can see what's happening.
I can walk into the exit.
Nothing happens but I pick up the briefcase and walk back in.
You have a briefcase.
Phenomenal.
We're now set up to actually have a victory condition.
So next time I do is I to move my briefcase to a more interesting location.
Let's do that let's take my briefcase let's move and drag it all the way down to the sophis.
Which currently isn't locked.
So next thing I do is grab my locked door.
Hit E for rotation mode.
That way up looks good don't they.
It has to be on the side doesn't it.
OK.
So this computer now works for these doors.
Let's move that computer.
Actually let's put it here.
Let's make the plate do all kinds of weird running around rotates.
Yeah.
Perfect.
And that brings us to the end of this video we've now created an object oriented approach to an inventory
rather than create an array or a dictionary.
We can just use the same tree and then has node to check if the player or whatever else actually has
what we want.
You could put in multiple loop type so you put in a briefcase a suitcase purging cat painting now just
grabbing loot from the excellent boardgame burglar Brothers which I read you recommend either way.
Why not share your level as it is now what kind of loot have you got in there.
How many types of loot.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.