Welcome back glorious gotto people in this video.
We're going to start using the engine and get to grips with it by making gotto say hello world.
This is traditional right.
Every time you start a new programming language the first thing you try and do is you make it say hello
world.
So we get gonna say hello to got to do that.
We're going to have to figure out how to start a new project and how to make it say hello world.
Nice and simple.
So here's my desktop and I'm going to open got a three point one.
You'll notice I'm currently using beta released 2 or beta released 2 depending on your accent.
That's because at the time of recording go to the three point one isn't officially released yet but
I'm not expect any major changes.
And if there are I can rerecord the video.
So a double click on it.
I'm going to get this error message.
You don't currently have any projects would you like to explore the official example projects in the
asset library.
I wouldn't say in a press cancel now.
The reason why I've got a blank screen is I download this directly from the got a Web site.
Right.
If you don't have this blank screen if you have a bunch of projects in this area there are two possible
reasons one you've use got before in which case you're probably not surprised that you see things here
the others you downloaded it from Steam because Steam will give you a bunch of example templates and
you could see a lot of them here.
Now look the templates I can see tutorials examples projects you can build on and some of them are very
cool.
However I'm not gonna do that I'm gonna make a new project.
Also if English is not your first language pick your language.
I'm going to stick with English because it's my preferred language it's the one I'm best that I want
to click new project.
OK.
Now you'll probably see that some of stuff in the background is change.
That's because I've gone and rerecorded this Hello this is Yan from the future.
The reason is the screen for a new project has actually changed since I recorded this because I recorded
it originally in beta when I life so it was a new project and I want to get this window so to do it
on the site.
Hello.
Gordo is the name of my new project and you'll see here.
It's not gonna let me create anything and it's got a project file.
I'm going to document dot repos I'll show you how to change your default project file and if I want
this to work I need an empty folders own dos create folder and you'll see this now goes green.
We've created the right folder.
What Renfrew do we want.
You can read the descriptions here.
In this particular case it doesn't really matter if you're using an old machine or small machine or
you want to do something the web use open AGL yes to I won't be doing open yet.
Yes three.
So I'm going to create my project
and here it is and I'll now leave you in the capable hands of me from the past.
All right.
So if you use a previous version of gotto you'll notice that the layout is slightly different.
Not massively but slightly if you haven't.
This is all new to you.
So I'm just gonna switch to this snapshot mode at Windows 10 has a snip and sketch it's called which
is strange right.
And also to highlight these various errors over here we have a scene treat
over here we have the file system
and this over here is the inspector
OK.
The scenery is where we're going to develop all of the nodes in our scenes and we're going to explore
that means a few videos.
The key concept here is the node is like a building block right each node can do a specific thing.
So a node might be a sprite.
It might be an animation player.
It might be an audio player.
It might be a timer.
So if I need a timer on my game I'll put a timer node into the scene seen as a little bit more abstract
for now we could just take the more literal idea of a scene can imagine a scene as a single room a single
place.
Actually the way the got to handle things is a lot more clever than that almost anything can be a scene.
But we'll explore that when it becomes necessary the file system is all the files are in this project
you see here we've got reds reds stands for resource.
This is the folder that we've created for this project.
OK.
So in this case it's.
Hello.
Got her.
And before we go any further if you want to change the layout or you need to do is click these three
dots and change your dock positions.
We'll put this here.
I won't put this here and it's all changed from my import tab over there if I don't like it I can get
to Ed. Ed layout and default and it'll put it back.
Now I did say that there is a way you can change way your default repository folder is to get back to
the editor's settings and all of these settings that will change every time you run the engine.
These are not bound by project.
So I can go to directories and here's my default project path.
I've got it to D.
Which is my harddrive documents repos while we here.
You can also go to theme and change the colors.
We have a bunch of presets I'm going to using default.
You could use alien which is nice and dark with green highlights.
Very spooky.
Maybe you want a light theme has a nice light thing or you can create your on one the base color is
going to be this lovely public color.
And the accent color is going to be bright red.
That is completely unusable so I'm just going to reset my theme and put it back to default
right.
I would recommend you keep the default theme just because going to easy to follow along if my screen
looks like yours.
However if you want to change it change it it's your go.
You should do whatever you want with it.
OK.
That was our Quick whistle stop tour.
Let's take a look over here in the scenery.
The weather got to work is that every scene is built up of nodes.
And there is always a root node and a root node can have a bunch of child nodes.
God I gonna ask us to make the decision of what I'll root note notice if we wanted to do a scene we
should pick this one a 3D scene.
Is this user interface or do you want something else.
If I press custom node here is a list of all the nodes and gotta add we can expand these.
So the no 2D has all of these and joint 2D have all of these and we can keep going.
We don't need to worry too much about what these all are.
But what is interesting is the way that they inherit every node automatically has access to all of the
properties that its parent node have.
For example no 2D is a 2D game object.
The parent of all 2D related nodes it has position rotation scale and z index.
What that means is if I click on any one of these I say like 2D it will have access to z position scale
rotation and z index.
No 2D has access to all the node properties and this is the simplest thing we can have.
This is the base class.
So what I'm to do is I'm gonna create a basic node and over here see the properties of note and it has
access to polls which are not going to worry about for a few games and it can hold a script that's all
a basic node can do.
What if I don't want this on the close this scene.
Don't say that I make a new one.
If I make it a classic 2D scene it has all the properties of node and it has all the properties of canvas
item and it has its own properties.
Okay so anything that's anything that can be accessed by canvas item for example visibility can be accessed
by no 2D and all of no 2D children.
All right.
So let's get rid of the scene and I'm gonna make a brand new node and I'm gonna call this hello world
the convention here is that nodes should have a capital letter for each word but no spaces.
Okay.
This is just the the guidelines within the style document okay.
So right now I want hello world.
And if I click on output here I'm sure of clear it.
This is where any error messages or printouts are going to happen.
This isn't all the places.
This is what we can see so we can use a print command to print things out at various points in the code.
That's a really useful tool when we're debugging to try and find errors.
We'll just try to make sure that something is working as we expect.
So it's click on Hello World and click on this attach new or existing script buttons as a little scroll
with a green plus on it and click that.
And here we have our script thing we can change language.
I'm not currently using the mono build that's the C sharp build I've got.
So I don't have C sharp in here.
I'm not going to use native script.
I'm not going to use visual script which is the visual scripting language mostly because I don't personally
find it that useful.
But if you want to do that's how you access it needs G.D. script it inherits.
Note This is a basic node and we don't need a template for it so we'll leave it as default.
I can also have an empty template.
No comments will look at that later.
Everything else is going to save as is and press create.
And here is our script which is in the script tab.
Okay.
We looked at a file system.
Our new script has just appeared Hallowell stopped G.D. if we look at hello world it now has a script
I can we can click that to get to the script and within the script time we can see all the scripts we
have opened.
We can also press this little button here.
This is distraction free mode of a press this.
We get rid of the other things we don't need.
I can't see the inspector I can't see the same tree.
I can't see the file system.
I could just see the script and let's take a very quick look at what we've got here.
The first line is important extends and then a note type extends node.
That means this script is supposed to work on a node as in the type of node called Node.
If I type node 2 D it could only welcome to Node 2 d it wouldn't.
It will not work on this because this is not a Node 2 D.
This is a node so I want to put it back somewhat extends is a keyword.
Key words are in red.
What does extends mean it means take all the basic functionality that's inside a node which is pulls
a script and extend the following behavior.
Anything with this little symbol here which in England is called hash in America is called pound and
I done what's called in other countries is a comment.
Gordo is going to ignore everything on this line after the hash sign.
So declare member variables here.
Examples variable a equals to verb equals text gotto isn't going to to look at that.
If on the other hand I get rid of it it changes color.
That means Gordo is reading it.
I don't want these comments I'm going to delete them and instead we left with a single code block a
single code block being a single chunk of code that does a thing.
Code blocks and got our declared him functions.
That's what this func keyword is.
Right so every function has to have its own function code block and underscore already is a built in
function.
What it does is it runs the script the moment the node has been created in game so once the node has
been created in the same tree you've put it in.
Now run this script.
There are other things we can do to run it.
Before you finished creating this node the moment you enter the scene Run this script.
Don't worry if you've created the node yet we're not gonna worry about their functions in gotto have
to have these brackets here.
And that's because some of them have an argument that comes in.
So I might bring in a variable called name or player.
This one doesn't need that so I'm not gonna put it in finally.
Let's take a look at what this function is doing.
Function ready pass what is passed do it.
It says Don't do this function.
Ignore this function.
So what we have here is a script that does nothing.
And if I press play first it'll say you've never saved it.
Do you want to say that.
I'll say yes save it as Hello World and here's my go a game and nothing is happening.
Which actually is fantastic cause I sort of told it to do I told it to do nothing.
But nothing isn't a very useful test.
We won't say hello world did you that would replace pass with print.
Print is a function so it's going to take these brackets.
Now if I hold control and click on print the documentation is going to come up for that argument.
Print dot dot dot dot dot and the dots are Varg.
Var ARG is not all cash it's variable arguments.
It means you can put as many arguments as you want to in here and I'm going to close this.
I could right click on it and do close or I could use this shortcut on windows this control to be so
close that you see this little star here.
That means this script hasn't been saved the moment I press play.
Well this is the second time in first place that says you haven't selected the main scene so we just
press select.
Do I have a world scene.
There it is OK.
Nothing has printed here.
What if I want only to print.
Well I mean put some a string in here a string is a series of letters and numbers and spaces and anything
within these quotes.
It doesn't matter what I write gotto isn't going to interpret them it's just going to treat them as
a variable.
So I could say hello world.
And now when I press play hello world is printed in the output.
Now you'll notice it's not displayed in game.
Right.
This is the game section.
It's not showing the play anything because that's not what print does print puts things in the output.
OK I mentioned the word variables into some of you.
This is a pretty simple topic to some of you.
This is new information.
So let's take a moment and we'll get the same page.
Variables like functions are a key concept in programming.
They actually come from algebra.
And Ben once described variables to me as an empty box.
So here is of variable
and this empty box can have anything in it.
Now Gordo doesn't really care what's inside the box.
God who cares about the variable which means we can change what's inside when we need to.
That's why it's a variable and not a constant a constant
is like a variable.
It's called const but we're not allowed to change it once the program starts running.
Okay.
So we're a of change between runs but within the at runtime when the game is running we're not allowed
to go in here variable on the other hand this contents can change at runtime so we can change it during
game play when I press a button maybe the speed or change something like that and a variable is going
to have a name.
So Nicole this word and we could put anything in here and there are basic types of variables as a string
that you don't want to change color for this let's go with a nice well what do we have a nice deep red
a string variable we could also have an integer a float
a boolean there's a couple of others we can have as well.
Colors for example.
These are the most common ones.
Let's define what these are.
A string is is if you imagine one of those celebratory flag strings right.
So we have a string and a bunch of letters on them and each of these characters fits on that string
so this string is a collection of numbers letters punctuation and spaces for the most part.
Gordo doesn't care what's inside the string.
They're all ways you can make it care.
I'm going to do that little bit an integer is a whole number five is an integer a float is a number
with a decimal point point 5.2 five is a float not an integer.
Boolean is a true or false value which is incredibly useful in programming essentially.
Variable is something we can change.
It's a box.
Here is a box called word.
Take a look what's inside.
Now if you're used to a static programming language something like C sharp C++ any of the sea based
languages in fact then you'll use the idea that variables have to be defined by type.
These are called typed languages.
Right so I have to say this variable is a string called this
by default gotto doesn't do this new in three point one.
It can get me to find that Gordo or G.D. scripts to me to be more accurate G.D. script is a dynamic
language dynamic language also known as
duck typing.
If it looks like a duck and it walks like a duck and it sounds like a duck it's a duck that's what duck
typing means.
In other words this word variable could be anything we like it could be a string an integer a float
or Boolean if I say there is a variable called word and I tell you it's five.
God I will say fine that's an integer if I say it's five point two five it'll say okay it's not an integer
now it's a float.
If I put it in a string it'll say Okay now it's a string dynamic languages don't care what type of a
variable you are a typed language will say we you told me that this is a string that's fine but if I
get rid of the quotation marks it'll just say nope that's not a string that's a float you can't have
this.
There are advantages to using type languages.
I personally prefer dynamic typing but it can slow the program down new and three point one.
We can now have typed G.D. script that allows us to define the types of variables in our script so we
can use the advantages of typed but not go into C sharp.
For the moment I a stick with dynamic because it's a lot easier to learn.
Personally I prefer it but there are very good arguments why not.
So we'll look at those little later.
So with all that said let's put a variable in.
I don't put my variable here use the variable keyword var and now it says well you if told me this Val
but you haven't told me anything.
OK so let's say word if you know what I'm not saying a word and as a greeting.
So now I have a variable greeting.
I'm not using it to define it.
I mean whose equals.
And it's gonna be equals.
String Hello.
OK.
So how would I use that.
I wanted to do it and get rid of everything in print and I'm using use a print the greeting.
No that's not the word greeting.
There we go.
When I press play it's now printing greeting and greeting isn't in quotes.
It's looking for a variable called greeting which is learned here is Hello.
If I wanted to say hello world but I don't wanna specify the word hello.
He's a variable I'm going to do this plus
world I'm adding a string that isn't a variable.
You notice up a space here.
That's because this string doesn't have a space.
I could also do that and it would work just fine.
So now when I first play hello world.
Nice.
So what we have here are operators.
We have an equal and a plus equals is interesting equals sets of value.
It doesn't check a value now in common mathematics equals means is the same as.
Right so if I say greeting is the same as Hello.
That's fine.
But what if I want to say check if the greeting is the same as hello.
Well if I put a single equal I'm going to set greeting to Hello.
If I want to check a value I need equals equals double equals his check.
And right now it's saying you can't do that you can't tell me there's a variable and tell me is it the
same as this double equals is check single equals is set this plus here will contaminate these two things
together because they are strings you can't add strings like you can numbers.
So I could do five plus two and print that and it'll press seven print seven but if I do five as a string
plus two it won't let me.
Why.
Because you can't add a number to a word if I want five and then put.
And what in here.
Let me show how do that.
In fact let's define a variable called number and I'm going to call this to write.
This is an integer in number I would say five plus number.
Try and do this won't work.
Why.
Because I don't know how to add a word in a number.
What I can do is turn this into a number.
I'm going to cast it to be a string as TR means cast as string.
And now when I press play the numbers 52.
OK.
So we can tell gotto take this variable and translate it into another things I can turn an integer into
a float a float into a string and so on.
Which brings me to the challenge of this video.
I would like you to change the code.
We're going to print out the words.
What are we waiting for Godot in the console.
And I'd like you to use at least one variable you could use more than one but try and use at least one.
So when you see this slide remember this is a challenge.
So pause the video and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Welcome back.
OK.
So let's get rid of these completely and this completely.
So the first thing to do is defined my variable here.
So I must say people and let's go to a string called we a space at the end and under Corliss engine
actually I'm not going to call this thing and this is gonna be called gotto and I want to type in a
string.
What are space close the string then add in people and add in a new string.
Then I'm going to add my thing variable and I'm a plus space between the operator and the string or
the operator and the variable because it makes it easier to read legibility and code is key.
Gotto will understand who's got to understand this but I as a reader might find that difficult.
One of the most important skills we can develop when coding is making code that's easy for people to
read.
When you come back to your code in six months or if someone else picks up your code they should look
at it and follow what it does.
So now if I press play what are we waiting for.
God oh look at that we've done it.
And that brings the end video in this video we've covered a lot of key concepts how to start a project
where things are in the editor how to start a script how to print on the console basic introduction
to variables and we'll go into a lot more depth here and how to set your preferences.
Don't worry if a lot of this has flown Bost as we get used to the engine in the next few videos this
is going to become second nature.
The first time you come up against the cost of the variables it can be quite confusing.
But I think we're off to an excellent start.
I think we're now ready to start our first real game which is going to be loony lips a word game.
So excellent luck and I'll see you in the next section.