Welcome back.
Gloria's got people in this video.
We're going to go a step further.
We've looked at how to display text to ourselves as programmers how to put it in the output how to display
it to the player.
Now let's talk about how to get text from the player right.
This could be a key component not just in our game but it's also a foundational principle in a lot of
games that we might make in the future.
So what do we need to do.
Well to get text we have to have a place for the player to type that's probably going to be a node or
two we can use going to have to get the words that the player types into the actual script.
Right.
So I'm gonna have to put words somewhere and then the script has to take those words and then do something
with it.
What's it have to do.
It's going to respond somehow or we can have a little exercise to get it to respond and then as we go
on in the course will stop making our stories and display them.
So that said let's get into got a hello gotta and let's take a look what we need to do.
Well there's going to be a new type of node put on the click on looney lips and control a or if you
want to control a press the little button a little plus sign and under control there's a couple we could
use.
There's a line at it and a text edit it.
Now the difference between them is do you want the player to be able to press return to go to a next
line or return to enter the text a line edit allows a player to enter a single line of text for example
if you want to put in a name or single word a text that it is where you want people to fill out a lot
of information.
So if you're making a role playing game and you want the players to write their own journals you would
use a text edit I don't want to do that.
I want a line edit.
So here is my line at it note and it's very small and in the corner for the moment I'm just going to
drag it over here you'll see and a control note by the way when you move things you see little measurements
and let's just make it a little bit bigger and see what it looks like.
Press play.
And here is a box that the player can type in.
Hello.
Doesn't do anything but there it is.
Now this isn't a great piece of layout is it.
What it could do is I could extend it like loops see if the problem already.
I can extend it like this and put it where I want.
But let's try and organize this a little bit better.
I'm going to add a new note on the plus button and I'm looking for a box container.
So if I took a box you'll see there's a couple here there's an H box container and a feed box container.
What do they do.
Well the descriptions isn't showing and this bill have gotta that's a little annoying.
You can see from the icon the H box container contains things into columns.
That's what I'm looking for.
So every node beneath it will be automatically raised in two columns.
This one will do rows.
Let's see what that looks like.
If I click on the box container and I'm going to put one edit within the V box container and I will
put the display text within the V box container.
Now let's make the V box container.
That's kind of a mouthful to say that the vertical box lets make the container thing full rectangle.
And when I click on the line at it you'll see the light it is actually above the display a little hard
to see it as I zoom right in.
And what I can do is I can drag the display text above it and it's the other way round.
So the way that containers and organizers of any kind work in gotto is the order in which you put them
in in the same tree is the order to be organized a couple of things you'll notice one Everything's at
the top here.
And the more text we have the more this will move that really one that's what we do is when I go to
the the options the inspector and let's change the alignment from begin to end.
Now this is about the line at it always at the very bottom a little hard to see there.
So let's put a margin on it.
So with the box container still selected I'm going to hit margin and just to get a repeat that 24 pixels
thing all measurements by the way are in pixels so 24 for the top 24 from the bottom minus 24 from the
right and minus 24 from the bottom.
One more thing I want to do is I want change the font here to match the same font.
So on the custom fonts it's going to give it a new dynamic font click on the dynamic font and then I
can go into my graphics folder and drag it over here.
Now what it could do is I could save this font and if I was using it several times I would click this
little down arrow do save and I could just load that font in but we've only got a few elements in this
game so let's keep it nice and simple.
All right.
Now we've got some it looks almost ready but the display text is going to hover down the bottom.
So how what to do here is give it a minimum size.
So with display text selected let's go over to rect over the size it's at at the moment it's 976 pixels
on the x axis and 63 on the Y.
Let's give it a bigger minimum size I must say the Y has to be at least 400 pixels.
Look at that.
Now when I press play it doesn't work.
Why.
Because my script is pointing to something.
Okay let's let's fix that real quick.
If you look here this get node the dollar sign is pointing to a direct child could display text so we
are at loonie lips that's where our script is and is looking for direct child.
Well if I minimize that you can see there isn't one.
So what I need to do is update this.
So the path is important and as a couple of ways I could do this.
I could type in the display text and let it autocomplete.
I could drag it in and then if I wanted to I could get these quotes.
They'll both work just fine.
So now when you press play we have a text that isn't all white on the bottom.
Quite at the top.
It's not quite there but it's looking better and I can type in here but nothing is happening.
OK so what I want to do is to make this connect somehow to the script.
Now the way I'm going to do that is by clicking on the line at it and I'm going to rename line at it.
Let's give it a better name let's say this is player text the text the player enters and with a selected
on the right hand side you see this Travis's perspective is in the Lawrence's note.
If I click on it I have something called signals.
We also have something called groups which are also very cool but we'll be looking at them later.
For now it's cultural signals and I have all these little options here.
And before we go into those let's talk about what signals and gotto are because they're really key idea.
Each of the nodes in gotto can do something right.
So if we have a line at its node it can take text from the player and over here we have a label mode
and it can display text.
So we want a way of plugging them in.
Now we could do this in several lots lots of little scripts that all tell each other you I've changed
your value of change your function and all the rest of it but this can get very messy very quickly.
You want to minimize the amount of times a node or different script can change values in another script.
There are times where it might be unavoidable but for the vast majority of time we don't do that.
The one exception is a parent node so in this case we have our roots node our control node loop which
has the loony looks script which can directly change the values of its children.
OK we're going to allow that Gordo has nothing inside it by default that will stop the line at at node
from changing the route and from changing the label and the label from changing the line at it the label
from changing the route and is added add more nodes.
It becomes very difficult for us as human beings as coders to track down where problems are occurring
because so many values so many variables and functions.
Everything is being triggered from everywhere else.
So instead we're going to use something called a signal.
Imagine that our label node has a handy mobile phone or pager and a line at it node has another one
when a certain thing happens.
So when the line at it is told on this thing happening it knows send a signal and that signal will be
connected.
Beep beep beep beep beep.
To a specific node.
So we're going to connect a signal from line at it to label.
It's very much like having a mobile phone and just sending a text message.
Now the key here is line it it doesn't care what happens once that signal is set.
It doesn't care what the label does with it.
All it's going to do is say I've got some text in me.
Here's your message.
And the label node I'll display text doesn't care why the line at it is sending that message.
It just cares that it's there.
So every node is just responsible for what it does.
Okay.
So how can we make that work.
We have all these signals here and I can look them in the documentation so we could go over to scripts
and such the help and type in the node type which in this case is a line at it or if we wanted to we
could right click on line at it and go to open documentation.
But as we scroll down we've got the methods it has the themes and we have the signals right.
It lists the signals it can do.
So we have a signal on tax changes every time the any of the text values have been changed within that
node.
So if I press backspace or for a space or P or whatever else send the signal and we have another one
when entries and is pressed.
So that's the one I want I want to text entered.
Okay.
I'm not connected where I'm going to connect it I have to connect it to a place that has a script.
If I try and connect it directly display text it won't work.
Well I can't put a script on display text.
I don't really want to.
I want all of this scene to run on one script as much cleaner way of doing things much easier to see
what's going on and debug.
So instead back on this plaintext note I click on a note button got text entered and connected to looney
lips and it's going to create a new method and you function on player text entered when I connect it
you'll see here it's added a new argument the thing in brackets that was that is empty over here.
This is when this function is called you're going to have extra information.
This is X information is a variable that you're going to call new text and that new text variable only
exists here.
If I try and say new text equals empty string go very quickly tell me why was this variable you haven't
declared that.
But if I use altered down arrow I put it here that's fine.
We've defined that.
Okay.
So this is a new variable defined here.
What is the value of new text.
Well the signal is going to tell us that when we press enter.
So it's a radical way of doing this.
OK.
So when this tax is entered we need to do something.
And here is my challenge for you
I'd like you to have the display text node show whatever I've typed in there.
So we've got a text box no judge I'm calling play a text when I type something into press Enter or Return.
I want the display text node to repeat whatever I've just said to it.
So pulls the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
All right.
So this starts off as pretty simple in fact we can just use this.
So I'm going to duplicate this line with the highlighted and press control B and then ult down arrow
nice and fast and I don't want story modulated by prompts which isn't defined in this function so it
doesn't like it.
I want new text and you know what we don't need this pass because that makes no sense.
Do something now don't do anything.
So when a press play I can type in a word and it works.
Couple of things though.
The first we haven't removed this text
OK.
So what I'd like to do is find a way of emptying that.
So what I can do is I can find my player tax load
and I can use this clear function.
What does clear do clear is exactly the way as saying text equals empty string.
OK.
So I'm going to do a clear function.
Why me using a function.
Because when I'm rereading it I'm not seeing extra variables of values being put in I can just look
at the say oh this is just a clear function.
Don't even bother with it.
So when I bring up my game and you know it's like full screen has like a small play around with it.
Great.
This is a lovely to do.
Way to type.
Oh what a beautiful morning.
I like my coffee black just like my metal.
Awesome.
Every time I press return it'll work.
Now later I'm going to add a little button here as well as a player has a different option.
And we going to find ways of plugging this into our actual code.
But look at this we've got a fundamental thing we can do.
One more thing I want to do before we wrap this up I want to refactor this code a little bit.
If I press play again it in a way close that in the next video where we one after that I'm not quite
sure yet.
I'll put a little button here.
Why.
Because some people automatically press enter when they're typing.
And some people look for a button to press like it's a form and I want to make this as easy as possible
for the player to play by giving them the obvious options that they would expect.
Right you always want to make a game easy for a player to play you always want to meet their expectations
of how the game will behave.
You can surprise them with fun mechanics but they shouldn't be surprised by the way the user interface
the graphics user trace the gooey not behaving the way they think it should.
So if I'm putting a button here it's going to have its own signal and I don't really want to repeat
code.
So instead I'm going to put in a brand new function and you know what let's put an actual line in here.
I like to put two lines between functions and there's one problem here and remove that comment.
Let's just tidy our code a bit.
Awesome.
So two lines I want to call this update Display display text.
That's not how I should be writing that.
That should be updated display text.
Great.
Why does this matter.
Well I'm referring to a node here.
So when I'm reading this in six months or three years when someone else reads it they should take a
look this function and from the name of the function understand what it does.
This is a key concept.
Every function should do a single thing and that thing should be obvious from the name naming things
in programming is one of most difficult things to get right.
This updates the display text.
Now what I want to do is instead of saying go to the display text update the text and then clear this
and remove all of that down.
So let's press ult and move that down here and now I can call update display text.
There it is.
However there's a bug there's an error happening here.
Right.
Line 14 his line 14.
The identifier variable.
New text is not declared in the current scope.
What does that mean.
Well I've got this variable here called new text now that's defined in this function but it's not defined
in this function.
So what I need to do is I need to define it.
Now I could go to a variable new text.
I'm going to get the nodes.
I use the dollar shortcut and go v box container play a text dot text.
What I can do that.
But instead let's do this let's pass the argument in
now I'm passing this argument in and it's saying I'm not expecting argument I can put the same argument
in here.
And we type it correctly.
There we go and now this will work exactly the same way
awesome.
So I'm doing this because it's going to make this much cleaner and much easier to use my start having
various functions that all have to update the display text and there's another secret we could do.
We don't have to call this new tax we can call this words
and this took me a little while to get used to when I first started using God.
If I press play now it will still work.
Why does this still work.
Well G.D. script is based on Python.
And when we pass arguments through which is what these little things within functions are called it
doesn't actually matter what they're called it matters what position they're in.
Let me demonstrate that again here.
I'm calling a function with an argument I can call in several arguments.
So I could call this one colors I could call this one numbers et cetera.
I don't have those defined but I could call them my.
And then over here it doesn't matter what I've called them in that function because these are being
created from scratch.
All that matters is what is the value of this variable.
What is it actually called.
So I can call this one new text and I can call it words here.
What matters is the position that they're in not what I've called them previously and that is a great
place and this video in this video we've seen how to use a line at it node.
We've had a quick introduction to signals which is going to be incredibly useful for every game we make
and gotto.
It's one of the core concepts and got.
And we've looked at how to call a function with an additional argument one that we've defined ourselves
so.
Excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.