Hello again you delight forgotten people in this video.
We're going to add a button and I'm very excited about this because I like pressing buttons buttons
are fun so buttons.
Why are we doing this.
Because some people like to press a button when they're filling an online form.
Some people like to press enter.
I want to give the player an option of doing either so that if you're somebody that doesn't know you
can press and tone a form it won't confuse you.
I want to make this as intuitive as possible to play.
Remember challenging game play should be a decision we make not a result of incomplete interface.
All right.
So if we want to add a button let's talk about what needs to happen.
The first thing needs to happen is we're going to add a textured button.
By this I mean a button with an image on it an image being a texture.
I want to add a label for the button something that tells the player what it does.
I want to make sure that the button and the new label align neatly right.
So when I resize the screen I want everything to look good.
And I want to make sure that the button works just like pressing enter in the player text in that line
edit Note we made.
So when I do it it'll do the exact same functionality.
So let's get it to go.
And the first thing to do is take a look at the button notes.
If I go in here and I type in a button you'll see we've got a few different options.
A standard button if I just create it really quickly.
Is this make you bigger a thing we can press is not textured.
There are things we can do to make it look textured and we'll look at those later in the course of themes
if it does it.
But it can take its own label
and by default it uses the standard gotto look and it's not quite what I'm looking for.
I want a texture button somewhere delete this node and openness and take a look at it texture.
What you got Come back texture button.
They were a texture button is if I go over to the inspector and click on textures a button that takes
different that has a different look depending what's happening.
So you'll see over here in graphics are open.
I've got two different files one is the normal button and one is the button press.
So if I take button 11 blue button eleven and put it into normal there's a button.
And then when I move into pressed there it is I'm not going to hover disabled focus or click mask because
those aren't important for this game.
So if I press play we now have a button in the top corner that when I press it animates but doesn't
actually do anything.
OK.
So let's make it do something.
Well before that let's put it in the right place.
I want it down here and I want it to organize neatly.
If I just put it into the V box container it's going to be vertically sorted and I can put it down here.
But that's not what I want.
Something to move it out of the V box container and within the V box container I'm going to add a new
type of container.
I'm going to add an H box container a horizontal box container.
So let's do that.
And each box container and here it is.
Now I want my label in this I'm a drag the label into each box container and you'll see organizers from
the left and I'm gonna put my texture button in that and it's on the right.
But it's not quite neat is it.
Well let's take a look what we can do if I go to the player textures remember as a line at it node and
I scroll down to size flags which I've already got open because I was just prototyping this.
If I click on expand on the horizontal it's telling the node on the horizontal take up as much room
as you can.
If I switch that off it won't do that.
That's very useful.
However you'll see the button isn't the right size.
So let's take a look at the size of this text.
We'll see 73 pixels.
I could make this texture 73 by 73.
So let's get a texture button and scroll down to rect not hint rect.
There it is.
It's already 73 on the why I want it 73 on the x.
Okay.
The node is the right size.
The image isn't to get the image the right size most grow all the way to the top of the inspector.
And right here it says expand.
I'm so switch that on.
Oh no.
It vanished.
Why.
Because I told it that size I didn't tell it the minimum size.
Let's give it a M. size of 73 by 73.
This means you have to be at least this size and now in a press play note the line edit it won't work
because we've moved its position we have to fix that.
But the button works fine.
All right.
So now let's put a label in so back into each box container at a label
and it doesn't have the default font so I'm going to custom font and I want to give it a new dynamic
font.
Click on that and just like before drag in my felt pen and do you want 40.
We could do 40 settings 40 and what she writes in here that's right.
OK.
Let's take a look at that.
That's looking pretty solid.
And when I resize it look at that the interface resize is perfectly.
Final thing to do before we move into the functionality.
I want to add a little bit of space between the button the line edit and the label so let's go back
to our each box container and you'll see this thing saying custom constants click on that and if I tell
it's twelve it'll say each thing has to be 12 pixels apart.
I could say eight I a 24.
Doesn't any matter what size say 12 for now press play see what that looks like a game and that is a
nice little margin between the text edit the line edit sorry the texture button and the label that nicely
spaced out.
Okay cool.
Now we need to do is actually wired up so it works.
So let's go back into to the loony left script and you'll see right here the play a text is now in the
wrong place right.
It's not in the box container it's in V box container.
Each box container.
So what I would do is make this nice and easy for myself to delete that leave a dollar sign and just
drag in player text into my script.
It vanished comeback script my script mode and drag that back right there and I don't really want the
quotes because I don't need them.
And now the line it it should work just fine.
Awesome.
But the button does nothing.
So here's my challenge for you.
I would like you to have a display text show whatever is in the player text when the button is pressed.
In other words make the button actually work.
And a quick hint if you're not sure to do it's going to be on the signals.
Suppose the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Welcome back.
So first thing to do is wire this button.
Do I like the name texture button.
I'm kind of okay with it.
There's going to node and I've got these signals here for up here that is specific to button.
They're not actually specific to text buttons.
They're specific to button and texture button inherits from button.
How do I know that a right click on it.
And I get to open documentation right at the top here inherits a base button control canvas item.
And when I showed you that button that doesn't take a texture.
That's the base button.
And I can even look in here and see what the signals do.
So button up button as our button down button up pressed and toggled button down is while it's being
held down button up is when it stops being held down pressed is just if it's clicked.
And that's the one I want.
I don't want it while the button is being held down.
But if I wanted a game where that happens let's say I don't know a car horn I could do it that way why
a car home would be control by the mouse on a button.
I don't know.
But if you're making that game that's how you do it.
So I won't pressed and I mean to connect it and I've got my scenery up here and are connected to looney
lips because that's what my script is.
So let's connect it and I'm okay with this method name on texture button press that looks good.
All right.
So here's on text button press and I probably don't need my output right now so what I want it to do
well the first thing I need to do is get whatever the text is.
So I won't make a new variable in here called words this new variable is going to be whatever is in
the player texts.
So let's make a link to play a text dot text.
Okay.
So the text property of that note.
Remember I want that property.
If I just pull the node up as the variable gotta let me do that.
But when I say OK now the display text equals this.
It won't know what to do because I can't make a note be text.
All right.
So then what to do.
Well now I just need to pass these words through to optic display cause we've already put that in.
So I want to go update display text words and you know what just make it nice and neat and select all
three of these lines.
And I'm going to hold alt and down arrow and just move them below so that I've got both methods with
functions that updates the display text above the display text so what I'm reading.
I could see what they do and then they come here.
Let's see if that works.
Press play.
Does this work.
Yes it does.
Hooray.
Awesome.
Look at that.
We did it.
We now have a way of getting text from the player and a functional button and this label can be changed
in text so later when the story is finished it'll work.
You'll also notice that if I have nothing in here and I press it it'll give me an empty string.
There are things we can do to stop that from happening but we're not going to worry about it too much
right now.
We're going to look at if statements ifs else ifs and else later in the course.
But there is something we could do meanwhile in this video we've looked at button and text button notes
H box containers and how to use fill and expand.
We've also played a little bit more with how to pass arguments to functions and how to make sure we're
not duplicating code which is great stuff.
So excellent work.
And I will see you in the next video.