Hello glory glorious God.
People in this video we're bringing cube dude in.
Enter their cube do now have got into salmon stuck in my head.
If you're not familiar with Q dude cube dude was created as part of Michael's character creation course
so if you've made your own characters you can bring them in too.
But for now we're going to use this because it was made in blender.
Another great open source program and a really well together.
So let's start by making a new.
No we're not making a new scene.
Things are different now.
Why.
Well let's go over to models and if we open the cube dude folder you'll see right here we have Q dude
Doc D A.
This is the commodify row we've looked this before.
This is the import.
But this is being treated as a scene.
If I double click it you get this little window here just to tell you what's happening here.
You cannot modify the actual file.
Right it's not actually seen as being treated as a scene if we open it anyway.
It'll let us make changes but any changes we make won't actually be saved so we want a new inherited
scene based on the clodfelter new inherited.
You will notice some weird things going on.
First off can't really see cute dude cute dude is gay.
Why is kudu grey Why doesn't he did have material.
What you did does have material click down here on the actual mash.
See he's got a material on the MASH but the material is the default grey and talk about why in a second.
Ducking a notice of the root node cubed is a kinematic body.
This is important because that's not the default.
If you bring your own assets in that won't be true.
I've gone and change them for you but just in case you use your own assets or for future reference.
Here's what I did.
Click on the cube dude over here in the file manager the file system go up to import and these are the
two things you want.
Root type and root name.
The default is spatial right.
All assets are brought in like this will be brought in a special note.
I don't want the root note to be special.
I want to be a climatic body so I changed the signals root name.
I just changes.
Did.
Otherwise you are imported and it will be called spatial member.
If you make any changes press reimport.
Right let's talk about why Q dude has this bizarre colouration.
Where is the textual we know and love.
Or we don't know it that we will know enough.
Well let's go off to the slides you see when you bring in 3D asts materials.
All the information for the ascent material is buried in a file so there's a that's a dot.
Empty L. file if you bring in an object file.
B.j. jail come with a material file and written in that file is where God can find the texture or material.
If that textual material does not have the right name or is not in the right place you'll get a blank
material created for you with that name.
And that's what's happening here.
If you're working on a large project or with a team of people or just by yourself.
An important part of project management is making sure that the files materials are in the right relative
position with the right names.
Because if at some point only to move more rename them God will just create a new material.
Okay so let's change the material.
This right here cube space dood is our mash and it has this material on it.
I can click on this mash and then click on mature to edit it or because I am already sure that this
material is being applied.
I can just double click on material.
It's the same thing.
It's a spatial material.
The Albino colour is correct.
Right but we actually have a textual to replace and take 11 cube GDP injy and apply it and there it
is a lovely little texture.
Couple things one to make sure of first as get metallic.
I want to make sure the metallic and specular are at ceara.
This is not vital for any normal project but I am going to be using two shadings and I want things to
look like.
Turns out we're not setting up to shading yet but I'm preparing for it.
Also roughness will be at once all I want completely flat light as little reflection as possible.
By the way just so you know how would I apply to unchaining and the primitives get to fuse mode and
hit tone.
The reason I'm doing it yet would have any lighting in so there's no point.
So I'm Cleaver's birley now I've changed this.
The material hasn't updated in order to be sure that this has worked.
You need to save your material if you don't save in materials.
Chance that it just changes won't actually stick.
So all him do is click on the floppy disk and remember if you don't know what that is you should ask
your grandparents.
Click on floppy disk and press Save and overwritten material and there it is.
Later will make a second material for the blue one.
If you want we can actually do that now on a duplicate this material.
And I would call this cube do blue and all I did was I took this texture and bought it again up and
recoloured it so open.
Clue dude.
Blue Cloud to say make sure I've got the right one open and bring that texture.
A save that.
So we have a cube dude and we have a blue material ready for when we have two players.
No point using it yet.
We're not quite ready to go cube dude is a kinematic body kinematic bodies require collision.
So let's put a collision shape as a child of Cupid.
And as is normally the case when we are using any kind of 3D movement the default is going to be a capsule
wire capsule because it has these lovely round cylindrical things so if we bump into things it's not
going be like it's a cube.
I made a cube that can be those jagged corners when things are coming at me from let's say 37 degrees
and they'll bounce off at the correct normal.
I don't know what that would be but if you do have fun with it I'll get a collision shape is one sense
that the feet.
What that's no good only to change that somebody to transform and translation this is a ramble where
you are on the x y and z axis.
So I know that Y is my up I think one will be halfway through.
Yes.
I happen to know that Q duties two units tall.
There was a unit meter and I need to rotate this.
Let's rotate this.
So that's the up point is at the top.
And I believe that B minus 90 looks good.
The collision is way too big.
So what I need to do is I need to bring it in a bit and I dropped the height.
I'm looking for is the feet should be as close to the collision as possible and I don't need Pixel Perfect.
You could in theory make a collision box for each one of these sub measures.
Right so you have a bunch of different measures one for arms what four hands one four fingers.
But there's very few times we need that precise collision.
In this particular instance we really don't need that conclusion precision kaloogian Precision very
fond of say.
I do want to do though is make sure he's on the right collegiately.
So go back up here and a collision layers.
He's not the pitch.
He is the player.
So he's on the collision there and he's got to interact with the pitch the ball and the players or players
have to bump into each other and we can save you as a scene so.
Q Do you now seem elates instance I'm in so I'm just going to create a blank node and call that players
just to organise my players.
Let's bring in cube dood and why we can't play a one.
And here is this cube dude.
In our scene outside we have this player and we have the ball and if I press play.
The ball can drop down the player can't move.
And right now the players looking a bit dull.
So let's give the player a script get back into cube dude and I'm going to add a script to him.
So scripts and keep dodgy looking good.
We don't need any comments.
Great distraction free mode and the first thing I want to do.
I don't really need a real option right now.
What I do need though is a variable called motion and that's going to be a vector 3.
We are now dealing with vector 3s.
What's a vector 3.
It's a it's like a vector to write a vector 2 is a variable with two values in it which we all call
abstractly x and y.
I don't actually have to be coordinates that could be any two but I'm going to call them x and y vector
3 is the same thing but it has 3 x y and z.
So our motion is going to be a vector 3 because we are dealing with three axes.
I also want an export variable called speed and that's going to be the speed that we can move at.
For now as move that 10.
I have a feeling that's really far too fast so if I want to move that's can be happening on every tick
rate and specifically every tick of the physics and its function process physics whereas there it is
physics process that's what I meant.
What's that mean.
Well we have a process that's going to happen every calculation and we have a physics process every
calculation in the physics engine.
These are slightly different.
I want to use the physics one because I want this to be more accurate.
And all that can happen is I'm going to move somewhere make a function called move in the physics process
and also compute one later could fall because kinematic bodies don't have built in gravity right.
They're not rigid bodies rigid bodies have physics happen to them.
Kinematic bodies have to make their own physics so if analogies make moves that look at that move and
not move.
What needs to happen.
Well that's a good question.
I'd like to challenge you to make kudu admit.
Now this is a little bit more challenging than some of your challenges because we haven't done this
in 3-d yet we've done so much in 2D.
And I want you to get a feel of how much you've picked up and how familiar are are and if this is a
little bit overwhelming That's okay.
That just tells you okay I need to figure out these bits too.
So don't panic.
Here are some tips you going to be using move and slide move and slide and move and collide both existing
kinematic bodies just like they do doing kinematic 2D.
Were going to be using move and slide because we want the motion to be calculated.
Once the player has hit the ball we move and collide.
The player will simply stop and none of that energy will be transferred to the ball the ball will never
move.
So we're using move and slide and will be using two arguments.
The first argument will probably be motion which we've already set up as effective 3.
The second will be up and I've defined up for you vector 3 0 1 0.
So an example would be moving slide motion vector 3 0 1 0.
Okay so pause the video and when you're either satisfied with solution or you think you know what.
I just want to see how he does it.
Come back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
So first thing I need to do is I need to get the input from the players and the condition right then.
If so.
If input dot is action Prest keeps pressing too many keys.
And for now let's just use the default.
You I.
Up down left right buttons were going to change those later but for now I'm just confused.
So you I.
Up and we may as well build in the ability to not press two buttons that same time and not copy this
because they feel like type it all again.
So if you're pressing up and not down
pay attention yet if you're pressing up and not down what happens.
Well I'm going to double check this in 3D because I get this one wrong all the time.
I want to make sure I know which axis is which.
OK so let's say Player 1 and on the transform get a translation.
If I move X to minus 1 OK.
So X is my red which means Z is my blue arrows time of the positive is that way so if I press up I want
to move a negative one.
OK let's do that let's go back to Scripps motion Z distraction free mode.
He calls loops equals negative speed.
Note by the way that I am not doing minus equal speed.
What that would mean is every tick.
Take the current value of speed and subtract speed from it.
That's going to be good for acceleration but I don't want acceleration.
I want a very sort of clunky blocky childish movement right.
That's the aesthetic I'm going for.
If I did want that I would then also have to put in a clamp value write some minimum speed and a maximum
speed but only 10 minutes be the maximum speed.
There are only two possible speeds speed and zero.
So let's duplicate these two lines with control B and just start changing things so when you're moving
down and not up there motion Dodd said he calls speed shows this to an L If there's no point doing.
If and if you can't have both the same time and I need one more I need.
Else let's just give you motion on Z equals zero.
So just to run through the code is doing its checking.
Are you pressing up and not down.
If so motion does z is negative speed.
I pressing down and not up.
If so motion not set equal speed.
If you're either pressing both or not pressing either motion does it because now do the same exact thing
just duplicate all that code.
But I go on the left and right.
So if you're going left and not right and left is negative exelis It's put that abss that says it has
not X and if you go right not left.
That's positive x otherwise X is zero and then right at the end.
I want to move and slide.
What's the skinny.
Motion comma Lecter 3 0 1 0.
And I always get this wrong right because I've finished a bracket.
I always forget the second bracket.
Now right now this is a bit magic number three right has put vector freezer or ones your own weak.
It may not be clear what that is.
You could very easy to make this constants.
We make conser caught up and letters vector 3 0 on the axe one and the wiser on the set and then I can
put up in here and just a bit more legible.
Great.
Now if I've done this correctly and I really hope I have we should begin with the cat.
Move left right down and up now there is no gravity applied so right now I can go over the edge.
Later we will put visuals here and I can kick the ball.
What's happening is the ball has moved me up.
Now you can't retell because any shadow or way of measuring height but I'm not too high to touch the
ball right.
The ball is too heavy and I'm not.
I have no gravity.
So let's put some gravity make a function called Fall.
And I'll put this after move and slide makes more spaces so yes you'll be doing going here.
Function.
For now we are using move in slide and you might remember moving slide has access to is on floor and
is floor requires up very defined sort of fights.
If it is on floor for has two O's in it which is an important fact that I'd forgotten.
If you're on the floor then motion dot why he calls 0.
Else motion.
Why he calls.
I need a new concept or it needs and they call gravity so let's write gravity here and let's define
it so constant I'm keeping my concepts together because it's good practice that's going down which is
negative y.
And so five five sounds good.
OK.
Let's find out how that works.
So I can move left right down up I can move diagonally.
You will notice by the way I'm moving fast from a diagonal to about wine a while I want to touch the
ball I don't flap in the air.
Now I can't move the ball for a couple of reasons.
One I'm being pushed up let's stop that let's go back to Cupid.
Click on the root which is I can Carnatic body and let's click access lock.
I don't want to move at all on the angular Y or the linear all right some will apply gravity but don't
be moved by them.
The other reason is the ball doesn't know that it should be moving.
So it's click on the ball and there's a couple of interesting things here.
Because balls a rigid body it can sleep.
Switch that off.
I also want continuous C D.
What a seedy stand for it sounds full collision detection is he got I was trying to save resources by
not measuring if a rigid body needs to be moved unless it knows and if something hits it fast like the
pledge said it will ignore that.
Let's move that now.
We also change the weight of we wanted.
But I believe we move now.
Ha.
By Do Bible look at that.
I move the ball moved off the pitch and it kind of broke everything but it can work.
I make short can sleep as off and continue C.D on.
We don't want these for too many rigid objects at the same time because that's when the game will start
slowing down so if I had I don't know five thousand of these balls on screen at same time and I set
that on that very annoying.
Just for giggles let's put Bout's one and press play and I think the ball should now bounce a little
bit.
In the case now dodge ball.
That's too much bounce.
But I want to play with it when we get some collision walls in in the next couple of videos we can start
playing with that.
But we're off to a great start.
In this video we looked at changing the root node of an important asset which you shouldn't have to
do in this game.
Just in case you using your own assets and going forward how do you do that.
Why 3D objects will have like materials and the basics of moving in 3D.
Excellent start and I'll see in the next video.