Welcome back delightful go to people in this video we took about a pending arrays.
And if conditions see I want to use the player inputs in our story and for that to happen I want to
go through several steps.
The first is I want to prompt the player to type a word.
The player should know what kind of what it is.
Is this a name.
Is this a place a noun an adverb an adjective.
What is it.
Right.
Second I want to add those play words to a new array.
I can't put everything in prompts I need to store them separately.
Third I want to stop prompting the player when we need to and instead display the completed story.
I can't display the story before it's completed because we'll get a bug right.
The lesson is too many arguments or too few arguments I can't put these together as a single string.
So I need that logic in there.
OK so let's get in here and the first thing I will do is create a variable and I'm gonna call this play
out words.
These are the words the player types and I'm going to initialize it as an empty array.
Why.
Because when I start appending to this array and I start adding things into it I want G.D. script to
know immediately I want got to know immediately.
This is an array.
Don't worry about what to do with it it's just an array by the way.
You will have noticed that I've put the variable here not in ready.
Why.
Because that we now at a point where all variables are going to have to be needed in multiple functions.
You see at the moment I've got this story variable here and ready but if I try and do anything here
story equals empty string I'm gonna get an error and the error is identify story is not declared in
the current scope the current scope is this code block okay but what happens if I hold alt and move
it up and then I get rid of this indentation which I can either do by deleting it or I can do shift
in tab give it a second top date and now that works fine.
You see now story is available throughout this script it's only available in this script it's not a
global variable but it's an instance variable is all the way through this script I'm also gonna want
prompts to be here we're going to do going to be using prompts in several functions in this video.
So we now have three separate variables we have play words story and prompts while I'm here.
It's also getting a little bit too verbose I'm thinking here my line 18 variable words equals get node
v box contain a slash x box contain a slash play a text text started to get a little bit hard to read
so I'm going to make a new variable and this variable is going to be cold let's start with the play
a text node
and all I need to do is just tell it what that is so that is play a text and I could also drag it across
but I'll get an error here and the error is use on ready variable I need to put a new keyword before
variable on ready why.
Well gotto is going to make the top note of the scene and then work its way down so it'll make looney
lips then background then V box container then display text it's going to run the script on this or
rather set the script up the moment that note is made however I am referring to something way down the
tree so if I make this script and sell it variable play a text equals this node that node doesn't exist
yet the already keyword allows me to say there's going to be a node this variable is that node note
by the way I'm not going to call it dot text I'm just gonna punch the node because that allows me to
either set the text or clear it will do whatever other function I want this very thing things when I
want later so I want to give myself the option let's also make a new en ready variable called display
text I'm keeping these the same name as the node so it's not confusing and I'm just gonna put that display
text in there to prove this works I can now get rid of this entirely and just write display text and
when I press play we should get the same functionality as before.
Rules like chocolate milk whatever.
I just like typing stuff.
Awesome so now the a place where we've got variables that will work and all the functions and we've
got shortcuts for these words so I can replace words here with plaintext.
Okay now we're going to massively change the functionality at the moment we're at 26 lines of code with
pretty much double it by the end of this video.
First thing I do is I'm going to comment out the entire ready function which is press control okay.
I can also just put this symbol to be in the line we'll put control cake as it allows me to do multiple
lines at once.
Now I won't make a new function and it's add some lines like can see what I'm doing.
There we go.
And this function is going to be called ads to player words
and why I want to do here is I want to take the player words and add a new entry to the array to add
new entry to array I'm going to use append Append is a function built in to an array.
So let's start that.
So I want to play words dot append and just to show what this does.
Hold control and click it append appends an element to the end of an array.
So this is just part of the array search.
I could also go to such and type arrays and hear all the different things you can do with an array.
Awesome.
And a close that with control W because that and that I've got a bunch of things open I don't want I
just want the one script.
Awesome.
So what am I appending because of the moment I'm adding nothing or what I want is the player text not
text.
Isn't that easier and so much easier than all this business.
In fact you know what.
I don't think we need update to display text at all let's get rid of that and let's get rid of that's
passe and let's get rid of this and put pass.
Okay.
Don't worry it's gonna look a lot less scary I mean I know we've just deleted a bunch of things but
that was there to show us what we can do in future.
Okay.
So now I've got a thing where when text is entered I want to add two player words.
Right.
Which is that.
However I don't need to be passing this new text yet I need to leave that in because that is information
that is going to be used by the signal but I'm not using it.
And that's okay.
I mean God will give me a slight warning about that later.
But we can live with that.
Okay.
So we can now add that to the play of words we're not doing anything with it.
We've also got a slight issue the slight issue we've got is that we're going to keep adding to the player
words forever.
So I need to use if and else so let's make a branding function.
And what am I really doing here.
I'm checking if the story's done so let's call this is story done and scroll down here.
And what does this need to do.
Well it needs to say return
player words Dot.
Sighs Okay.
So that's going to say how many variables are within this array size if I hold control and click on
it is a built in function of array.
So we can see here the size that shuffle is resize as remove this whole bunch of other things we can
do.
And it close that with control W and what's returned do return says whatever just call this function.
Send this back to it.
If I put returned by itself it'll say send nothing back to it.
Important point once return has been called in a function.
Nothing below it will be run in that function.
So if I put something in here player words equal Bob this line will never be run.
Now I don't actually want it to say for right.
I wanted to say is the story done in so many ways equals equals which is is equal to and what I want.
I want the size of the prompts array.
Which prompts
dot size.
So this is in return a true or a false it will return true if there are as many things in the player
what array as there are in the prompts array which is gonna come in useful when we want to check the
amount of things in that array.
So let's make a function that does that.
I'm going to put it we think below let's put it below one function.
What are we doing.
We are check.
Player.
Words like that I call it play a word play words.
Let's keep that nice and consistent.
And here I want to use an if condition.
Well let's get rid of this.
Lots of space.
That's what I want.
So what I do I say if is story done do something.
Okay so what is this going to do if is a key word it says there's going to be something after f before
this column.
If it's true.
Do the next code block which is indented underneath it.
I can make multiple if statements
and what this will do is it'll run this line here on my 31 and then when it's done that it'll try and
run 33 no matter what the results are.
What if I don't want it to set to do both.
Right do one or the other.
I can use Elif Elif is else if so it'll try 131.
If it does it will not run 33 right because it's an.
Else.
Else if if it can't run 31 it will try and run 33.
I can also use else else means if none of the things above have worked.
Try this or do this.
Don't even try.
Don't check what it is.
This is a catch all so if is storied on Elif not his story done is clearly redundant.
I just need an F and an LS okay.
So if the story's done we're going to tell the story which is a function that doesn't currently exists
so God is going to complain.
Else I want to prompt the player which is another thing that doesn't exist.
So God is going to complain again.
So let's make a couple of temporary functions.
Function tell story
and function prompt player which is on this line.
Function prompt to do player.
See this is the problem with learning to type by just using computers for years and years and years.
I make so many typos because I never actually learn to touch type.
Let's put a colon into this so it actually works like a proper function.
Okay so what I'm gonna do now is it's going to when I call this function and remember right now this
function will never be called because I haven't told it to call it.
It's gonna check the length of the player words array and is going gonna do that by checking is the
story done.
What's this story done.
Just return this value player what size is the same as the prompt size.
If that's true tell the story in all other cases.
There's only two cases I could have using Elif but elses a little more elegant prompt the player OK
so let's make these functions that start with tell story what's tell story going to be what is tell
story is going to be display text dot text equals story modulated by and this time I want the play of
words right.
I don't want the prompts that would make any sense I want to play words
so I should just go and display the words now the prompt and the prompts going to be a little bit trickier.
Not much but a little bit what I want is the display text dot text equals can I have can I have may
I have may I have is better grammar let's use may may I have space plus and what I want I want the prompts
but I don't want all the prompts I want a specific prompt I need a way of tracking what it is and this
is where it gets fun you see what I can do is I can use the square brackets tell it which entry in the
array I want zero one two three and I can be sneaky here I can go play on words dot size so what it's
gonna do is say okay what's the size of the play what's right.
How many things are in it.
Zero.
Okay that number you've just given me that number you've just returned.
Use that as the position in the array.
This one well while we here let's change this.
I want a name that's probably not a capital A noun an adverb that's an adverb isn't it.
Okay bird what's this tingle an adverb verbally.
I think I've just found the name of my next roleplaying character adverb there we go and glorious is
an adjective if you're not sure of the difference being an adjective an adverb adjectives modify nouns
adverbs modify verbs also.
Okay.
May I have space a name plus please and let's put a space there and close the string because a when
it prompts the player it's going to find what's the prompt at this position and it's going to calculate
the position by counting the things in the play Words Right so we can already use the functions within
gotto to come up with creative solutions to problems.
OK.
Now we still have an issue which is this isn't actually going to run right or it'll run but we're never
going to call these key functions we're never going to check the play on words length which means we
never go check if the story's done we're not going to tell the story or prompt the player.
So at some point we need to actually do that so what I'm gonna do is
bring back this function animate change display text or text.
So now I'm put to check player word life in ready.
So the first thing it's gonna do is that.
So now stop prompting also in add player words I want to make sure that I'm clearing the player text
so let's get plaintext dot clear.
Why am I putting it here instead of text.
Button pressed and play a text because it doesn't need to happen.
I don't need to type it in twice right.
I should just type it in once OK.
Moment of Truth.
Is this going to work.
I don't know.
Let's find out.
It should do.
Man have a name please.
Is cat who's one of my cats.
Oh hasn't displayed the next thing.
Okay so let's double check that.
Why is it doing that.
Oh I see why.
Okay I'm only checking the player word length once so I need to make sure that when we add to the words
We also check the player would like a check.
Player would like selling a stake.
One of the most common mistakes I make when I'm programming is forget to call a function I've written.
Let's try that again.
May I have a name please excuse kaboodle my other cat.
May have a now I'm happy.
May I have an adverb puree.
May I have an adjective joyous.
I'm feeling quite happy right now apparently.
Once upon a time someone called Bootle a happy flavored sandwich which made him I should put a gender
in that feel or parry inside.
It was a joyous day.
Look we're almost there.
There's one more thing I would like to do.
I'd like to welcome the play it's a lips right now.
We're just going straight into a prompt sub so I would like you to display a brief introduction to the
player when they first start the game.
Suppose the video give it a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
I'm OK Mac.
OK so the first thing I do before Czech player words length is I'm going to say display text dot text
equals.
And now I'm going to put my happy friendly introduction.
Welcome to looney lips.
We're going to tell a story and have a wonderful was a wondrous but we spell it wrong time and now in
a little bit of space there as well.
Now I press play.
It goes away.
Why does it do that.
Because in check.
Play a word length doo doo doo.
I'm saying prompt the player and prompt the player.
I'm now setting the display text as something else I'm immediately overwriting it.
So instead of equals I don't use.
Plus equals plus equals means.
Add this to what exists so now in a press play.
Look at this.
Welcome to looney lips.
We're going to tell a story and have a wonderful time.
May I have a name please.
Yes.
As you know let us do Ben.
Ben.
May I have a now please.
Oh we're not clearing it.
OK.
Now I could set display text dot text to an empty string his or clear it out and then add it in.
But if I do that I just remove the solution we just put in right.
I mean the whole point of this plus equals so it wouldn't do that.
So instead cut that and I need to find a place to put this.
Well I can't put it in prompt player because that gives us the same problem.
I want to do it when new tax is added so let's put it on at to player words and then we'll put it right
above.
Play a text OK clear.
Why am I putting it here.
Really because visually that's where they are on the screen and it just makes sense to me.
So this press play welcome to linear lips we're gonna tell a story and have a one time may have a name
please.
Ben.
May I have a noun please.
Always looking promising computer may I have an adverb please.
Confusedly
May I have an adjective please.
Splendid.
Once upon a time some local band aid to compute to flavored sandwich which made him feel all confusedly
inside.
Well that's a good piece of grammar.
It was a splendid day.
Fantastic.
Look at that.
We've now got the basics of our game everything from here is just adding scale.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we've gotten a specific entry from an array based on its position which is sneaky.
We've learned how to use the append and size methods of an array and we've used an if else condition
to check the logic.
Quite a lot happening here but we've already got a pretty functional game.
Now everything else is just making it bigger.
So how do it work for you.
Did you come up with a better solution.
I did.
Did you get confused with the if and else conditions.
How you doing.
Let me know on the discord on Facebook on the forums.
I'd love to get your feedback and meanwhile great stuff and I'll see you in the next video.