Welcome back you wonderful people.
And we're going to get started.
Let's get godso on our computer now for this video.
I'm going to assume you using a P.S. If you're using a Mac.
Ben has a video for that.
Now if you're using Linux I'm going to assume that you're a little more comfortable with file structures
and how to do this.
But honestly you could probably just follow the Peacey version and go from there.
So what do we need to do to that.
Well first we have to figure out where we're going to get godda and the next thing needs to do is figure
out which version to get.
Now there are two places that you could get godso.
Actually there's a few more but two big places.
There's steam and then there's the godso engine dot org website.
So let's look at them and figure out what the advantages and disadvantages of each are.
So here we are over in steam and let's make this nice and big Where's my mouse.
There it is nice and big.
Fantastic.
Here we are in steam and we need to find God.
Somebody go to this search bar thing and I'm a Type in God and I'm just going to press there.
Click this button on my screen says you now on yours it might say install completely free press it and
it's going to get going.
Simple as that.
If it asks you what follows.
Put it in.
Put it in your default steam folder it's fine.
Now why would I want to use the steam version.
Well if I don't really care too much about using C sharp as the main reason I just want a nice quick
install with no worrying about it with all of the templates and export templates it's just done.
Don't worry about it just give me the whole thing.
That's how I'll do it.
This is actually the larger file six hundred fifteen point one megabyte for this version.
But what if I want a little bit more control over this or I don't have a steam account.
Well for that I'm going to open my web browser of choice.
In my case crying is my lovely browser bars and I'm going to get a good scholar engine.
Oh RG And I'll put the link for you in the resources.
So here we are and have got a website.
Lots of fun things we can do.
Great community here.
But what I care about is download.
We have three separate tabs separate linux thing it's sports Lennox Alpha box and the Windows version.
Main thing I need to worry about here is do I want to be able to use C sharp.
Now you can always install this version later in reimport your game.
Personally I'm not going to be using AC sharp.
I'm going to be using g.d. script then will be using it.
If you want the mono version the version with C sharp.
This is where you're going to be 64 bit or 32 bit that's to do the operating system.
I'm using Windows 10 64 bit so I would get the 64 bit version.
If you don't have a 64 bit machine get the 32 bit a quick couple of tips.
The latest version as a recording is got three point zero point to any version.
After that should work fine.
However if for some reason you want to go back to previous version you will find the previous versions.
Right here it says you can find previous releases here and here if you have schoop you could also do
that.
I don't I'm not going to worry about that.
If I wanted to use the C sharp version I need the correct version of mono.
Now this is being patched at the moment but at the time of recording you need to be very careful here
for the mono version you need a mono stk five point four x.
Later versions will not work.
Now this is in the pipeline.
It is getting fixed but if you're having trouble loading it up downgrade your monitor to five point
four.
However I want the 64 bit version so I'm going to download it and here it goes and 30 seconds and downloading.
Let's take a quick look at the steam version so I will reopen my steam.
And George got no engine and it's done.
That's the entire install here is gone.
Oh ready to go because I've got the steam version.
It downloaded all of these demo projects so I could for instance go and look at an example of the gooey
in 3D or circle pops and a whole bunch of other things.
You can also look at these templates a whole bunch of templates in here.
Great stuff to look at.
We're not going to be using too many of these but that's what you'll think will look like.
Now back over to our download I've opened the zip file here.
I'm going to open it up.
And here we have got a version 3.0 to stable with 64.
So I need to put this someplace.
So I'm just going to cut this and I need to put it in my programs folder in my case that's on my drive
and it's under programs and you can make a new folder.
And call it God.
So all of Don's have taken the XY file from inside the zip put a new folder and I'm just going to pace
that in there.
OK so here is my tiny tiny tiny Nixie.
How do I install this.
You don't.
That's the entire engine if I open this here is gonna.
Now you won't have all of these projects here.
These are all my demo projects.
You'll have an empty thing here.
If it ask you do you want templates.
Not especially so assuming yours is empty and you're ready to go.
Let's go the challenge slide my challenge for you is to download and install godso.
Grab a copy of God three point zero to all later and install it.
You hear it from steam.
You could get it from the god of engine if you've sat all the way through and your a Mac user I commend
your patience.
Ben's coming up with how to install for a Mac.
Meanwhile we'll see you in the next video.