Hello.
Fantastic go to people in this video.
Let's make a game more atmospheric.
We're going to add a light to D.N.A..
We're gonna make a torch or a flashlight depending on what part of the world you're from.
I'm calling a torch because I'm Kim.
I grew up in the UK.
But if you're from America or someone else that uses the word flashlight and by that I mean the United
States.
I don't know what Canadians use.
You can call it a flashlight.
It's fine.
We need to know a few things about the way that God handles light.
So let's talk about light duty nodes.
First you need to know is that light to these nodes need a light Map Texture.
I'll show you why in a moment the light map is calculated from the origin of the node not why the texture
is.
Don't worry what that means too much is that the filter into the back of your brain.
When I show you what that means.
This will click into place.
Basically there is a difference between where the light node is and where the texture of the light is.
We're also gonna have to use occlusion other occlusion nodes and inclusions built into top maps.
Inclusion is basically this causes shadow.
If we don't put that in God doesn't know what causes shadows.
We don't want the floor to cause shadows for example.
God doesn't know the difference in a flow on a wall so we have to tell it finally light an occlusion
use layers just like collision.
We're not using that too much in high surmises but it's worth remembering.
You can decide what kind of lights cost what kinds of shadows.
So before we get to God I just want to take a quick moment to do a very professional looking sketch
to explain how light to Dino's use like maps.
So here we are in a nice whiteboard place.
And here is Bob.
I haven't seen Bob in a while.
Great.
Thanks Bob.
Bye.
What's gonna happen is we're going to draw a light to denote in this nice purple.
Okay.
And here is its origin.
Then we're going to bring in the texture of a light.
Now the light to denote is going to say Okay I have this much range.
So is anything in this range that might be blocking that light.
If so block it it is worth knowing that the light to denote is doing this in all possible directions
at the same time.
Just because we see the light map here doesn't mean that's where the light is being calculated.
The light is visible because this is a light Map Texture and we need to be very careful that the light
Map Texture shows where we wanted to show.
But the light is counted from here because when we put it in a second it's going to look a lot more
like this.
That's not a very good drawing but whatever.
So we're going to think the light source is here but it's going to be calculated from here.
We're going to give us some really weird effects.
Let me show you what I mean.
So back into it.
So here we are and got it.
And the very first thing I do is I'm going to add a new note.
It's gonna be a light to denote light 2D.
And I'm gonna call it torch.
We're going to use this in a lot of different scene.
So let's make it its own scene.
So I'm going to save branch scene.
I'm looking right at it and not pressing it safe brunches scene.
And where we put this let's put this it's not level maybe other light maps let's put on the light maps
torch was a good place to put it.
OK.
First you notice we have an error warning to texture the shape of the light must be supplied.
Right now we can't see anything.
OK.
So let's bring in our light about texture on a light maps you'll see here.
I've got a torch map.
I'm going to bring that in.
OK.
Few things.
The first thing is we can't see against the background.
That's OK.
We can bring the player in.
So let's save this and head on over to levels and open template.
And now you'll see what I was talking about here is on light map here is a light to denote Now you might
think that's fine.
All I need to do is move it over.
So if we move it over I just move you like that.
So the torch is just outside the player.
You'll notice it's light in the player but nothing else.
There is nothing to light.
So I was gonna make sure it's outside the player like due to do loops
I was bringing it back a bit let's say.
Position is 3 3 0.
Good.
That's right on the edge.
OK.
Save that back in the template note.
OK so that looks fine right.
Let's run the scene and yep that looks like a real torch we've got no shadows in but we can put those
in real quick in fact let's put the shadows in.
So we're in template.
Let's open the tile map and I want to edit the time maps I click on tiles and click on the tile sheet
and edit and all I need to do is decide I'm editing this bit.
It's got occlusion and a square and just like we did before.
I want to fast forward this bit so you don't have to watch the whole thing
and last one there it is great.
I'm not doing this work because we're not using them.
I'm not doing these frequently using them.
OK.
So we now have occlusion.
So God now knows these these bits cast shadows greatness bring you down but boop.
Well you like so awesome case or on the scene and as you know there's no shadows at all.
Okay that's fine.
Why is that.
It's because not every light needs shadows and God is try to save resources so if we go back to the
play scene go to torch let's open a torch thing.
Let's just get it torch myself and we go to shadow we can enable it.
And the shadow is going to be nice and dark.
OK.
Say that back into the scene and run it.
We now have shadows but that doesn't look right.
What is going on.
OK let me bring up my little sketchpad.
So what's happening is that we think the light is being generated here but if we look at the way the
shadows lie we actually see where is being generated.
I can follow this over here and follow this over here and it's right here off center but it's right
here.
So we know that the light to decode is calculating from here.
Now that clearly isn't good enough.
So how can we fix that.
Because if I'm backing God which I am right now and I just try and move it this problem keeps going
right.
The answer is not to move the light but to move the texture.
So make sure that my light to the node is just outside the character because when we give the character
shadows we want the light to come out and I need an offset.
Let's move the texture offset by 330.
How about 320.
Perfect 320.
OK.
So now if we run this level the shadows behave as we expect right now.
Doesn't look very dark.
Let's make it look even darker.
We need a template level.
I'm at a new type of layer called Canvas modulate and what this does is tints the entire canvas.
Awesome.
Let's give you a nice gray round there somewhere.
And suddenly this is starting to look a little more like a stealth game right.
We have actual shadows have been calculated.
And as these tall maps are rebuilt we're going to have real shadows.
Awesome.
Before we go any further let's give player a little bit of shadows and this template I'm going to bring
in.
Character template so that we can see what's happening with the player shadows or the character shows
and let's open the Templar character as a scene.
We need to add a light a to 2D awesome and these include a need a shape.
So let's give a new polygon.
OK.
First we need to do is add these points.
I'm gonna click on Create points and in a moment.
Press the button and nothing's going to happen.
Why.
Because I'm in move mode.
I need to be in select mode one more time.
Point to point to point.
There we go.
Just want to be reasonably close
and close it off.
Let's look good.
Let's save it and see how it looks like that.
It has shadow Templar character has shadow which means everything that inherits from template shadow
has shadow awesome.
Now you might be getting slightly different results to this if you go to template character and open
occluded 2D.
We have different color modes at the moment it's clockwise so it's calling things clockwise.
If we go counterclockwise say that's good because the scene is now not letting that light through right.
We do want the light to actually hit the character.
We only want to call on one side.
What's that mean.
It means it stops drawing in one direction so the light's going to come inside and it's going to stop
on the inside and say that by the same and there is awesome.
OK.
That's looking pretty solid.
Now I've got a quick challenge for you.
What happens if you want to control the torch being on and off.
We probably won't have this as an actual gameplay element but let's just refresh our memories.
See if you can set the torch to the player and switch on and off of the key press.
Remember you gonna have to go to project settings to input mapping to define a key picture you like
on a no space or something.
But give it a shot.
Pause the video and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
I'm ok back.
OK.
First you need to do is bind a key so protect settings input map.
I'm going to call this torch toggle to get name except that should be lowercase torch toggle.
There we go.
Add that and I'm going to bind space right now the key.
Now let's go to the player script.
Okay so what are we going to use.
Well I'm not making you function and it's going to be input event so input when you input.
Here's what to do if input dot is action pressed.
I want just pressed not pressed when I'm holding it down torch toggle.
Okay.
So when the button marked torch toggle has just been pressed do the following.
First what do we need to switch on.
Let's look at the Torch thing.
Here's my torch scene.
There is probably heckled enabled right mousing over it will tell me the property is called by typing
enabled in lowercase.
Awesome.
Let's go back into our player scene into the script and I wanted to get the torch right.
If it didn't auto complete you're not in the player scene.
Auto complete will only find nodes in the current scene so torch dot enabled.
Now I could put extra stuff here.
I could say and torch enabled.
And so on.
But there's a really elegant way of doing this torch dot enabled equals so it's set to not torch dot
enabled.
And what that means is set this property here to be whatever this isn't.
In other words whatever your not become.
So let's take a look at two demoed and run the sing boop awesome now quite a little trick with this.
If you've made a mistake and it's not working and it's not throwing up an error messages here's what
I did wrong.
Just now all recording it and then edited out so that you would never know torch enabled equals not
torch enabled is not the same as torch enabled.
Does not equal torch enabled.
This says this property is not this property which is nonsense.
I don't change the property.
I want to change the value.
So this will work.
This will not demonstrate that pressing space.
Nothing's happening and no error messages because nothing bad is happening here.
I'm not throwing up anything that is worthy of an error.
So just put that back here.
Okay so now we have torches we have shadows we have a lot of atmosphere in our game.
I think it's a really good place to stop this video.
In this video we have learned how to use a light to denote we've looked at checking lighting and lighting
map to make sure they're aligned remember move the light map with offset.
Don't move the light to denote we've put an occlusion in our alter tiles and we've used a light occluded
to denote to give all characters shadows.
Awesome.
I think we're off to a really good start.
Game sounds like atmospheric and I'm really happy that progress so excellent work and I'll see you in
the next video.