Hello again, you glory has got people in this video, we're going to finish off the pitch and finish
off the pitch.
I mean, make it usable for our game.
We don't have a complete game yet.
There's a lot still to come.
Not that much is quite a simple game.
But still, we have to watch today.
What do I mean by finishing off the pitch?
Well, our pitch needs the following.
It needs some goals when put in some goals.
They're not going to track the gameplay yet.
They just can be physical objects that can stop ball.
But when it goes, we also need some boundary walls.
Right now, the ball and the players can fly off the pitch.
That's the problem.
Now, we could make a system where if the ball goes off the pitch, the game stops, I think, to the
bolts.
And there's a really small patch.
I like the idea of invisible walls and then we need beautification.
But we're not going to do that now because beautification is Polish, not gameplay.
And you want to put Polish in once the game plays an in place.
You don't want to sort of make things beautiful, spend a whole bunch of time getting asses just right
and then decide they're wrong.
So we're not doing that in this video.
So let's get started with what we are doing.
And for some nosegay getting into Gotto and I want to goals.
Let's open up our models and go open.
Gold.
Gold up d.
The Claudia file is going to say, well this is automatically import.
You can't save it.
I will press open anyway.
And here is our goal.
What we have here is a scene route, which is just a spatial noticeboard import from blender.
And because it's been imported as a chloroform, it has an animation plant.
I don't care about add two measures.
No collisions.
Okay.
Now, right now, this is a DEA file.
Like, I make changes, but if I try and save it, I'll say no, can't save as a DEA.
But what I can do is I can take this goal and save that safe branch is scene.
And that is gonna go in my models in my goal.
And I'm gonna call it gold mesh not.
So now I can close this.
OK.
So now let's make a brand new scenes, a new scene, and I'm going I have a three scene.
And right now, there's just a spatial node, which is like a node with 3D transform information.
Very, very basic.
It's like the No 2D, but it's an old 3D called spatial.
And in this, I'm going to insert that gold mesh.
OK, so here's my go mesh inside this special.
I'm going to rename that to Goal.
And you know what?
Right now I've got an inherited scene in this case.
I don't actually want it to be an inherited scenes on the right.
Click on it and I'm going to make it local.
So make local.
And now this is no longer instance.
I'm going to rename this goal here to Goalpost MASH Space, and I'm rename a net to Net MASH, just
some very, very AKCA, a glance on saying tree what everything is.
So right now we have a spatial node that has two measures.
Let's change what the special node is.
We're right.
Click on it because I actually want this to be a static body.
So right.
Click on my static body change type.
Static body.
That's nice.
Well, static body.
That's a spill static body.
Okay.
So here we have a static body.
We have the goalpost mesh and the net mesh.
There's no collision.
And at the moment we've got a little warning.
What's the one thing you have to have collision.
Now, I actually want two static bodies here.
One is a child of the other because I want two different collisions.
I want the player to be able to go through the net, but not the ball.
OK.
So the ball comes in here.
It will stop.
But the playability through that, nothing can get through the actual post Monday through post.
If you hit the mesh of the posts, you can't get through.
Why are we being so cagey with if you hit the mesh of the posts?
Well, I'll show you one.
That's plus press goalpost mesh.
We want to give us a collision.
Now I can make a brand new collision shape, let's say make a box.
But if I do that, the bowl coming here is going to bounce off.
That's no good.
We need to only get the mesh, not just the block to do that.
I'm click on Mesh right here and I can generate an automatic mesh.
I have two options.
I can create a static body.
Well, the goalpost is already a static body, so I want to do that.
Or I can create a collision sibling.
That's a collision layer on the same level of the same tree as the mesh.
And I can create trash or convex.
I don't want to create Convex.
And I'm gonna show you why.
If I create Convex, you'll see here the collision shape is just taking the simplest possible route.
Now, that might look good, but what we actually have is a wall that doesn't work for me.
So we delete this collision shape and I'm going make a tri mesh.
Now, the down side of the tri mesh is it's often much more complicated.
You can see here is such a little difficult because these little triangles.
This is quite simple shape.
But the more complicated we make this collision shape, the more we risk slowing down our game.
Now, I also want a collision shape on this map show.
On this one, I'm just I click it.
And a new static body.
So try mesh static body.
And you can see right now you actually can't because a too small but the blue lines follow each one
of these points.
That might be a little bit too complex.
But given that we have a quite small game, I think we got away with it.
Now, before we go any further.
Well, first, let's save this as a goal.
Someone put this in level.
It's a level asset.
We call it gold.
I said earlier, I want the plant to be able to go through the net, but not through the post and the
Bull Connor through either.
We should really set up some physics lab.
Let's do that project project settings and scroll down to lab names, 3D physics.
Here we go.
OK.
So low level one is going to play.
Let's say let's play.
She was going to pitch.
Level three is gonna be ball unless a level four is net.
And that should work.
Now, I could rename pitch because I'm looking these a boundary walls on that.
But essentially, anything that's going to stop the ball coming through, as I say, that also will
put the goal there.
So why do we call that obstacle?
No, when we call that level.
It's part of the level that's gonna behave as part of the level.
So that should look good.
Let's take a look at our static body.
First, we have the goal.
What collision, Les?
Well, you are not a player.
You are part of the level.
And you can interact with the player, you can interact with the ball.
Great.
I don't need to interact with a level there's no reason for the level to interact with itself.
It's not going to be moving.
It's a static body, on the other hand.
This static body that is a child of the net mesh.
You on the layer net, you nothing else.
And you do not interact with a player.
You do what's right with the bowl.
And that should look good.
Now, that said, we now have to change the collision left the other things.
Let's go back to our main level and very quickly go through them.
Some are open play player one and open play a template and quickly take a look at the collision on the
physics body.
You are a player.
You can interact with other players.
So if the two players hit each other, they can't go through each other.
They can't get to the level.
They can't go through the ball.
They can go through the net.
Some say that.
Now, let's play a one just to double check.
Those mosques and labs rule in place.
Let's go back to the level I want to change the pitch on the pitch and very simply.
You are past the level and you can interact with the player, the level and the ball.
Awesome.
We don't the ball falling through.
OK, so what on the pitch from the players, we've done the goals we have put them in yet.
Let's do the bowls.
Take a look at the bowl openly.
The original seem to want a change.
All instances of bowl.
And this is a rigid body.
Doo doo doo doo doo.
Where's my coalition?
There it is on the physics body.
You want the ball and you can interact with the player, the level.
There's only one ball.
There's no reason for turn itself.
And the net.
OK.
So that should be good.
Close the scenes we don't need.
And just to make sure I'm not dancing, very stupid.
I'm going to press play.
I'll just check that.
The ball doesn't get through the pitch.
And the player.
Cargher through the player.
Great.
Let's put some goals in.
So first thing to do is to make a brand new spatial node.
Call this goal.
Sorry, it's not a spatial.
It's a default mode.
It has no transport.
Information leads us to organize.
Just like we did with high surmises.
So within that, I'm an instance in a goal.
And let's make sure my snap is on and it puts it just about here.
And I want to rotate it 90 degrees on negative 90 degrees.
OK.
So we have our green goal that's moving forward.
One, I kind of feel like I should move back.
These markings aren't entirely precise.
That sketched on on purpose, but I feel like it's going to look at this, right.
That I'm going to Wieseler back a little bit.
There we go.
Shouldn't have any major impact on gameplay.
OK, so we have a single goal.
I'm gonna rename this to go one.
This is the green player's go.
You know what?
Let's get rid of the grid.
I want to see it.
It's getting in my way.
Let's duplicate gold.
And I'm going to move you to over here.
La, la, la, la, la.
Turn around.
Dooby dooby doo.
So you face that bright line.
You choose.
I bring you down here.
Turn off my grid.
Snapping.
And just drop down to the line, feel a bit like Bob Ross right now.
OK, so we have two goals.
We have a green go for the green player on a green golf, the blue plate.
That last bit isn't great.
So click on the goal.
And on the right, click on it to editable children.
It's still instant's, but I can change the properties of the children within this scene.
It doesn't change the default properties for everything.
And the simplest to do, it's got a goalpost mesh and go to material.
I'm going to do the material override.
So brand new spatial material.
I was going to give it a nice blue that kind of matches that plan.
OK, we now have two goals.
See how they work.
So I want to move the blue player the way first thing kind of bluefly go through the nets.
Yes, he can.
Can the blue play go through the goalpost?
No.
So that works fine.
Secondly, I do.
Can the ball go through the net?
It can go through a little hoop.
It can't go through the net.
It stops right there.
Awesome.
Which means in theory, I could push it out to go once the game play.
She starts what happen?
And we have no wall go off.
Let's put in some boundary walls.
OK.
So we've got our goals to minimize that.
Let's make a brand new basic node, basic node renamed to boundaries.
OK.
Now, right now, this ball is quite liked.
I might make this heavier, in which case there could be a point in which the ball gets stopped here
and the plant can't get behind it to push it out the way.
For now, that's not an issue.
But if it becomes an issue, we're gonna have to put a second layer of boundary walls following the
white.
The only stop the ball.
Nothing else.
We'll also have to make sure it's behind the gold line on the Z axis.
With all that said, let's make a brand new rules.
Can be a static body.
And I'm gonna call this backwell.
And why don't you just line it up with his back wall here?
So let me get Brennan collision land collision shape.
There it is, new shape.
It's gonna be a box.
And I can zoom in and see my little box.
Let's play with the extents.
Let's see the X extent.
It's gonna be a point for.
No, that's wrong.
The stealth isn't be point five.
There we go.
The X X stunt is going to be what we think, 12 meters.
Well, that's pretty good.
It's a little off the edge.
We got away with 11 meters, but I'm fine with that on SNAP and just dragging it over to that.
I want to do want to make sure is that actually lines up with the very edge.
Do, do, do.
OK.
So let's try it.
ZF point to five.
And yeah, that's pretty good.
Okay, one meter is no good.
There is a reasonable chance that this ball will bounce.
So let's make it taller.
It is a 10 metre tall, which is five metres tall.
And you know what was going to transform?
And on the y axis, let's move it up by five.
And that's all Backwell.
Okay.
Before we go any further, let's check on collisions.
It is not a player.
It's part of the level.
And just to be double sure, it's OK.
Not play player and the ball.
Now, I've just made a bit of mistake here.
What I did was I moved the collision shape, not the wall.
That's not what I want.
So I don't want to do is just take this five negative eight.
I got here on the back wall going to transform one of that five up and negative eight on the Z, and
then the collision shape should be at zero zero.
Common mistake.
I want to move the parent node.
So there we go.
A collision lay as a mass of goodwill backhaul.
Duplicate that and call that frontwoman
and move the duplicate.
Easiest way to move the duplicate.
It's Tana's negative eight into a positive eight because symmetrical around the origin.
Nice and easy.
Let's duplicate front wall and caldas left wall.
And I want to transform this show on the Y y axis, which is the Green Arrow here.
That's my that's my pivot.
90 degrees.
And let's see.
I don't want you to be.
Off Central to Z, so let's put you back at zero.
And what do you say this was 20 to that, right?
No.
12.
22.
How's that?
That's a little bit too far, isn't it?
So let's try 11 right on the line.
I quite like that, but it's not the levels have been negative 11 and adjudicate that.
Make it the right.
And that is going to be my lesson.
You'll notice I've got this overlap here, but these are invisible collision lines that don't interact
with themselves.
They only interact with the player in the bowl.
So I'm fine with that.
Let's see.
Outplays.
Some big I couldn't kick the ball, it hits the wall, the player hits the wall, too.
Now you'll notice I can't get right into the corner, right.
This could become a problem later.
Right now, it seems fine.
I think it is possible we will get situations with things blocking that wall seems to be high enough.
I think the ball is too late.
It's also possible.
If we had made it to the play, it could hit this net for the weather.
It would be possible for the player to go up.
But because kinematic body has no gravity.
It would be stuck there.
However, because playing the through the net, that's not an issue.
If it had happened, if you decide to play, couldn't go through the net and your game.
That's fine.
You just need to put in a gravity script for your play.
So it needs to be pulled down by the Y.
If it's not on the ground, that is looking pretty good, isn't it?
So there's my ball and you're trapped in the corner.
You know what that is getting trapped in the corner, isn't it?
So, yeah, let's do that now.
Let's make a second load of boundary walls.
While I'm doing him a backwell, duplicate it.
And on this duplicate or change the collision.
This doesn't stop the player.
It only stops the ball.
It goes.
Right here.
So is it on the white line?
I think that she is.
Oh, look at that.
OK.
So that is minus six.
So I'm going to duplicate from all.
That's six now.
I need to be a bit careful on the sidewalls here, because I do need the bull to cross over the gold.
So let's take lawful duplicate that.
And I'm just gonna move this over once.
So the ball can still cross there.
And let's do the same thing on the right will.
Move it.
One unit.
I got Chris, nothing else.
It's nice and easy.
And before I forget, let's actually make sure they've got those collisions on all the walls.
I don't, do I?
OK, so let's take wall two on all those got a collision and just make sure that it stopped the player.
OK.
Let's test how that goes.
Boo boo boo.
OK, first off, the player can cross this line.
The ball cannot suck.
I shouldn't have been a situation where the ball can't get stuck in a corner, including the corner
than that, because I can always come around this way.
Now, of course, the other player can get in the way and stop me from doing that.
It's actually quite awful to control by myself.
There we go.
Let it go.
Now, can the ball go in there?
Can a ball.
Can you go in there?
No.
OK.
So fun failing to do it.
Just make sure that the left the right walls are not quite so far across.
So it's got a left wall.
Look at the transform.
It's of minus 10.
Let's say unity at minus eleven.
Let's double check.
No man's land doesn't work.
So let's put you up minus ten point five.
That should do it.
And right will, too.
You should get to ten point five.
So one more time.
Can you get me the blue planet the way.
Yes, it can just cross the line.
Now, the moment does cross the line.
We're going to stop the game anyway, but that feels a lot better.
So what we have here is a nice closed-in pitch with physics lads working girls working and plays it.
Don't turn around yet.
We'll fix that soon.
But we don't get the vote stuck.
And that feels like a really good place to end this video.
So excellent work and I shall see you in the next one.