Hello again, you lovely guy to people in this video.
He's cute, dude, better movement.
What I mean by that?
Well, we want to make sure we animate cute dude.
I won't keep dude to run when moving and only when moving.
And we want to face forward if we take a look what happens right now in a press play.
Yes, I tweak my camera value slightly.
Cube dude neither animates nor changes direction.
What changes direction doesn't change which way they're facing.
Which means feels a lot more like a foosball table.
I want to change that.
So those are the two things we'll do in this video.
So let's get right into it.
As you might expect, we're going to be in the player scenes as open player of that one open template
player.
Make sure Erving's in here.
Fantastic.
And here is my animation player.
Now, Mikey has provided two animations that actually the same animation because he made this for the
original character, created cause for his play.
You can see this is a pretty good run.
You also notice it stops.
So to fix that, to go over here and loop it and press play.
Now, we could just put that in, right?
We could make Keba, you'd run constantly.
But we want to make sure that it only runs when moving.
So to do that, let's get into the script.
So we'll do it.
But this is the physics process, and I'm going to make a brand new function called.
And it just felt like that.
Alex, scroll.
All right.
Off the bottom.
La, la, la, la, la.
Yes, I know.
There's nothing animals can get rid of the animation window.
Don't need that function estimate.
All right.
So the first problem to solve, I need to know if you do this moving.
Well, to do this, I'm using this motion variable motion is a vector, three vectors vector.
And mathematics is not just a coordinate.
Remember, a vector is defined as direction and magnitude.
And the only reason I know that is a Despicable Me movie.
I'm not great at math, but if we take a look at that and we scroll down, we've see that vector has
something called a length.
I can click on that.
It's the vectors length.
In other words, how far is the magnitude?
How much did you move?
And that's exactly what we need.
So let's try.
If motion dots length is greater than zero now, we might have to tweak that a little bit.
It's not impossible that it's going to flick between zero and a very, very small number and give us
some weirdo options.
But for now, we're live at zero.
If it does go wrong, I could change it to a tiny, tiny number like zero point zero zero zero zero
one.
But for now, though, look, if you're moving, what do we do?
Well, we want to get the animation play out and play arms crosswalk.
OK.
First thing is gonna happen when I press play.
If I start moving, I predict the cube dude will start the move animation and never stop it.
Let's see if I'm right.
Why is that happening?
Because we've told it this is a looping animation.
Now, this is a looping animation.
We need to make sure that this is going to stop.
We're not moving.
Let's put it else in here.
Else.
Animation player Dot.
Stop.
OK.
And that looks pretty good, doesn't it?
You know what?
I want to shrink the bullet limit, but not quite yet.
OK, let's change which way Kube do this facings to do that.
I need a function called face forward.
And I'm gonna put it right here on animates this good face of forward branding function.
I know you don't like it.
And and let's get rid of my output window and just makes more space.
OK, so I.
OK.
Function face forwards.
So here's our new problem.
I need to look in the direction we are moving.
So Cube do need some concept of that.
Now, again, let's take a look at motion and figure out exactly what this is.
This vector three right here is how far we have moved since the last frame.
Well, if we take the negative of that, that should give us how far which direction we are moving to.
Right.
So what I can do is say look at.
Vector three.
Negative motion dot x.
Zero.
Because we're not going to look up.
Negative motion.
Dot zet.
OK, but that's not quite enough because look at in 3D needs us to specify an upper direction, it needs
to know which way to tilt the camera because you might be doing a game with full 3D rotation.
Now, we do already have OP defined, so let's just use that.
OK, so the first thing you notice when we jump in here is that we're facing the wrong direction.
Why are we facing the wrong direction?
Because we are doing this even if we're not moving.
Right.
So we're looking at zero zero zero, not what we want.
So let's go.
If not motion dot, x equals zero.
So if there is an X value or not motion dot Z equals equals zero.
If there is a Z value.
So if either is a value, update this.
Let's see how that looks.
We are looking in the right direction, but something's going weird.
And I think what's happening is a mesh is actually facing the runway.
OK.
So how do you fix that?
Well, one thing we can do is we can multiply this value by speed.
There we go.
So we are now.
So now we're using the actual motion.
The actual amount we've moved, right, not just the motion value, but the distance we've moved.
This makes a big difference because if I move this speed.
The motion that you have got is between zero and one, which means we're getting these weird rotations,
right.
Cuba is trying to turn very, very slowly, multiply my speed.
Actually, give us the real value that we see on screen so that we get.
And you know what I'm going to do with the controller?
And we have this lovely fluid motion.
And that feels really good.
Now I'm getting little bits of an accuracy.
We can tweak that against a polish.
And the ball went through the net, which shouldn't have happened.
But from a basic gameplay point of view that start to feel nice.
I am slipping on the things which isn't great.
But overall, I'm pretty happy with that.
So excellent progress.
And I'll see you in the next video.