Hello again glorious God.
People in this video we're going to lay some groundwork with a talk about transforms bases and matrices
matrices being the plural of Matrix.
And if right now you're thinking of us Keanu Reeves movies are.
Sorry.
Not a fan.
OK.
Let's look at why this has to happen.
If I run the game we have so far we have got some basic mouse look working.
It's very shiny and we've got some movement but the movement is based on global positioning.
I'm pressing forward and I'm not changing what that means with the camera right which is going to get
really disorienting very quickly.
This isn't moving the way I would expect.
What I need is to define movement based on where the camera is and that's going to require some clever
maths because what exactly is forward from this angle compared to this angle compared to this angle.
To do that we're going to rely on Matrix mathematics and very simply a matrix is a special kind of array.
It's what they call a rectangular array and that array can have any kind of mathematical value as long
as those values are the same type.
Now I am going to link the documentation for transfer me for transformations and matrices so you can
look this up but essentially it looks like this.
We have a matrix called a and that is a special kind of array which we're going to use the curly brackets
for even a looks like a dictionary.
But it's not.
And on this we might have let's say it's a two dimensional transform or two dimensional matrix or something
to help ourselves.
And it will get a plot X and Y plot X and Y as a rectangular array and this will be x x x y y x and
y y and we can manipulate these arrays in different ways.
Why would we want to do this.
Well because an array can hold a lot of information in one place and that's going to make things a lot
easier.
Now we're dealing with three dimensional information and God has a special kind of matrix for that it's
called a basis and a basis has translate rotate and scale for X Y and Z.
So that's movement.
Translate how much you've rotated and how big or small you are on each axis.
And that's all in one place.
And to use those.
We're going to use a transform and a transform is very simply something that can compare the basis to
the origin and that's going to give us our global local position.
So let's say I have this simple 3-d space and I've got my x axis y axis z axis my origin is the 0 0
0.
Right we know that that's our global origin or our local origin of figuring it out from a parent for
parent to child.
And let's say we have a play a character play a character is here.
The basis is going to give us not just where are they on the z x and y.
Right so that says 10 that's five and that's one.
It's also to say how much they rotated on each axis and this is important because we've seen how much
rotating on the wrong axis can mess up and when we started in these together that we get really disoriented
to transform allows us to figure this out.
It's also going to handle scale.
So we actually look at what's involved here.
Let me pick a different colour.
We have rotation on each axis.
That's an arrow.
There we go.
We have scale on each axis which can be nice purple colour so like this and like this and like this
and we have and we have translate We have everything in one place and all of that is compared to here
which means we can start comparing values very quickly.
It's a whole lot simpler but it takes a little bit to get your head around okay but it could take a
little bit to get your head around.
OK.
So far so theoretical.
How does this apply to us.
We're about to make movement relative to the camera and that's going to cause some complications because
in some cases I want to move the player where the camera is facing and in some cases I don't.
Here's what I mean by that.
If I rotate left.
I want that to be forward.
But if I rotate Let's do this as a local decision.
If I rotate the camera up I don't want that to be forward because otherwise I'll fly.
I want to separate 2D and 3D movement when I'm using the keys to move.
So w is a d demon jump which I gonna put on that's a space right that's going be locked to the floor.
Again I don't want this to happen.
If I did want this to happen this would be much simpler.
When I jump I want to jump and then apply gravity and these things are going to have to happen separately
so I need to separate out the horizontal movement that 2D movement and then add them in later.
And that's going to be what were going to be doing the next video.
Now there's quite a lot going on here but essentially just remember this a matrix is just a special
kind of array.
Right.
It's it's a multidimensional array a basis is a God or array that handles these.
T R S Translate rotate and scale.
And in fact if we look at any three dimensional spatial object you can see under spatial.
We have transformed and transform is made up of translation rotation and scale right so it's all there
for us.
We're going to access in this in code which brings us to the end of this video.
Now this is a little bit more talky or going to go into the actual practical the next video.
But I thought it was worth separating it out from the actual practice.
So you could refer back to this video for get lost if all this was very very simple for you.
That's fantastic a disease for a fresher.
It is new information.
Dont be afraid to ask questions on Facebook on discord here and usually.
Weve looked at the basics of transform matrices and we've identified how they're going to play in our
game to our placement.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.