Welcome back glorious God.
People in this video we're going to look at Awesome ways to make a to de level.
We can explore tile maps.
Why would we do that.
Well right now we have these platforms right I've created the manually and we put in the Sprite and
the collision polygon.
And we've duplicated them.
And that works fine.
A tile mat is kind of like a paint palette.
We can create elements of scenery a platform whatever paint with them very quickly.
Now it does take a little while to set up but once it's set up we can make really cool levels very quickly.
First thing to do is get reties platforms so by by platform nodes we now have a bunny floating in space
and we press play the bunny will fall.
By bunny.
How do we set up a time map.
First thing we do is create a new scene.
So here I am in my branagh's scene and I'm going to create a Node 2 d as a root node I'm to call this
platform's makes sense right.
I misspelled platforms correctly because that would also make sense.
There it is.
And now only to find the zero point because I've moved it.
A why did that.
Now I'm going to bring in a sprite.
So let's make a sprite.
And what Sprite shall we bring in.
Well it's got our graphics environment and you'll see there's a bunch of platforms.
Now if you downloaded the full jumper pack from Kenny or are using a different thing you might have
a bunch more options.
But I've paired it down so we've really got large and small version of ground cake ground grass ground
sand and ground snow.
Let's start with ground cake which could put it here because you know a cake.
It doesn't really matter where this is positions.
I'm a dragon of his.
I can see it.
And let's switch on our grid.
It's quite a small grid isn't it.
And you snapped on that.
Next thing way to do is give this Sprite a static body.
Now you can create things that are static bodies with spikes as children but for time that doesn't work
great.
We need a sprite as the parent so the static body is there and within the static body end under collision.
You have a couple of options here.
You could do a collision shape and then make a rectangle.
And in a lot of cases that would be fine.
But here it's not going to work out that well.
And the reason is we don't have a regular rectangle so the player is going to expect to hit the side
and it's either the player's going to hit right here and slide off before they hit the platform or from
a get smaller.
They're going to think they're gonna hit the brown thing come down.
I am going use a collision polygon So let's get rid of this.
Brand you can get in shape.
Collision polygon.
And I will try to keep as close to this as I can when I have to tweak it in a moment.
And this is a point where the grid is not actually helping that much is it.
OK so let's switch the grid off.
And there we go.
Get this nice and close.
Getting close to the platform is a really good idea and the reason for that is the more precise things
like collision are the more control the player feels like they have.
In other words if you think of a platform game like Super Meat Boy it was all about a high stakes collision.
No precision not collision getting exactly a pixel off is very challenging.
But the play feels like it's fair.
If the platform doesn't behave in the way that we might expect players going to feel duped trapped not
trapped tricked probably dead.
Let's take a look at that and switch my grid view off so I can see it looks pretty close doesn't it.
This one is a bit off.
Nice.
OK I am going to make sure the whole thing selected it and I'm going to call earning this thing on and
name it.
Ground cake.
Let's duplicate that and shuffle it over here.
Now for this one I take the small ground cake or ground kick small.
You call it ground cake small and you'll notice that the collision is completely wrong.
So let's fix that.
Get on to my collision and move some things around.
Now part of me kind of wants to fast forward this.
But on the other hand setting these up is something you need to do correctly.
If you don't take the time to do it you're getting it.
Had behaviour in your level so I decided in the end I'm sure show you the entire process that would
probably have a few too many points that way.
So if you go over to the edit and just mouse over it you'll see the options so I'm shooting left mouse
button to move points.
You can also split segments of your on ADD.
All right mouse to erase a point.
Sounds good that's a razor point that one would probably do only that once so you can get here and you
can go here.
Looks good.
Some strange things happening there.
Split that segment split that segment.
And let's make sure that you are actually where you need to be.
Okay that looks pretty good.
Before I go any further I want to put these on their own collision layer.
What does that mean.
Well collision layer and a collision mask is a way that we can keep track of what's interacting with
what.
It's quite possible we don't want everything to be able to collide with everything else.
In other words let's say we make an enemy we can write.
If you collide with something.
Check with that thing is and if it's the player then do a thing or we can just make it so that enemies
can only collide with players and that way if it collides.
It doesn't need to run the check a collision layer is what layer the object your editing exists so if
we're the player we exist on the player layer that's one to say the collision mask is what layers you
can interact with.
So where would we find those.
Well on any of the physics bodies on static body on kinematic body on a rigid body you'll find under
a physics body tuley which is their parent class collision.
We can set any of these as layers and masks.
That's kind of irritating though because we can't see what these are.
So let's name them.
Got a project settings and we scroll down to two physics let's call layer 1 we can lay them.
A coal mine player and layer two is going to be touraine.
So I'm going to select the ground cakes static body and put it on the tray there but not the player
layer and it cannot interact with the player to do the same one with a small cake cake now.
So on the static body collision it's not on the player it is on the torain.
I'm also going to go back over here and open the player seen and make sure that the player.
Does not interact with itself because it makes no sense.
It does interact with the touraine.
If we if that's switched off it'll fall through the train.
Okay.
So right now we have a couple of cake based things.
I'm going to highlight both those and duplicate them and then move the duplicate things down.
It doesn't really matter where let's make these ground grass.
So ground grass that this one is rename It's now the reason I did it this way round is that all of the
large platforms have the same collision shape and all the small ones have the same colour shapes on
a click here and on your Sprite.
I'm going to put this in.
If I remove those.
You can see what they look like.
And we some did get some nice pieces.
And just going to take all of those and duplicate them one more time.
You can be ground sand.
And I mean you get this texture.
It can be ground sand small.
Whoops.
Great.
And what do we have left.
This one will be snow.
Ground sand.
And ground snow.
Small you make sense.
I'll get to see what I'm doing.
I'm going to remove all of the polygon visibility so I'm not looking at a polygon.
Collision shapes.
I'm just looking at the terrain.
Well it's pretty good.
OK.
We have these sprites and they have collision.
How do we use them.
Well first let's save the scene.
We're going off to the scene folder and we're going to see this as platforms now going to generate a
tile map to do that we up to the scene and you press convert to tile set.
And I want to put this in a scene's folder and on call it platform tiles.
Must use an extension.
That's right I forgot about that.
We have to have manually type in dot t r e s.
So it's one of these two options here.
Texture resource file.
So platform tiles dot trv espress safe.
There it is.
So how do we actually create a time that this.
Well in level one that's a new node and it's going to be a tile map.
And the tile set we're going to use will be inseams which is not under graphics.
It's in the scenes.
Platform tiles and we'll put that in there.
And look all of these options are here and we care about that because I can just paint with them.
And I press play.
The collision has worked right.
Everything we've just done has worked perfectly.
Now we can tweak it a little bit so make it a bit more interesting and fun.
So now I can actually jump around.
But one thing I notice is the camera isn't following me.
So before we go any further let's create a new scene.
And in this scene we go make a node called camera to me and very important we have to mark this as current.
If it is not current it will not work.
It's going to be a camera that is switched off.
Save that camera scene inside look at one instance the scene remember this little chain icon on the
player so slow.
Play player an instance.
That new camera scene.
And we have some options.
We can change here.
Well we can play those a little later but for now if I press play.
You'll see that the camera is following running around the place a little jerky So get a camera and
I think we need to put smoothing on so it will smoothing.
A little bit better.
Now there are a bunch of options we can play with.
We'll look at those a little later.
We have some more elements.
But look we have a basic level.
So my challenge to you.
I'd like you to make a days.
That way you can make it as large or small as you like but use your tile map to make an awesome level.
If you just wanna do one thing let's say just cake.
Go for it.
If you want to mix them up maybe it starts with ground and and it ends with cake.
Whatever you come up with why not share it with the community.
We'd love to see it share on our forum.
Share in discord Sheraton the Facebook group wherever you want to share it.
We'd love to take a look.
So pause the video here.
When you come back I'll show you the level under the make.
Okay time to make a level.
So I now have this tile map and if I want to erase things I can just go to where it's set and right
click on them so beep beep beep beep beep I'm not gonna start with Kay.
I feel like cake is something you want to build up to.
So let's start with a nice ground piece.
I want to give the player a couple of choices where to go.
Oops didn't mean to play like that.
Maybe a few more Ovie.
Oh there's another one of those pointy ones.
I like this big dramatic drop.
Let's put some small platform jumping bits here.
And let's see that's might actually be awesome.
Let's find out if it's awesome.
It's actually a little difficult for me.
Oh let's see.
I had to jump a little bit earlier than they thought.
Yeah that's working fine.
One thing I would like to do and I zoom the camera out so let's get to carroty hoodie and here is a
zoom instead of one point one.
Um we do two poitou so we can zoom out now when look at it.
We can see a lot more of the level now.
This might be the wrong size.
Feeling going to go for one point five.
I might actually go 4.5 but I quite like to look at this.
Maybe one point I was right.
One point five.
Yeah.
I think that's the one one point five minutes.
One more thing I can do.
You'll notice that I've got all this camera they'll keep going forever instead of that I can set limits.
So up here in tiny tiny tiny numbers I can see that this is positioned 320 on X so I can set my left
to three to zero.
See how that works.
Now you know the camera will not go further left than that.
Right so I have a hard left let's put area we can't go any further down so I don't know we'll call that
me.
Here is good.
3000.
We have a less single level.
And if we drop all the way down.
It'll drop for a while and then stop.
Right.
And that's everything for this video.
So in this video you've seen how to create a tile map how these collision layers and collision masks
and how to set up your camera.
Great work and I'll see you in the next video.