Halloween fantastic people in this video we're going make CUPE do move more naturally as a few things
want to do and here's why.
Here's my cube dude.
When we get moving around.
Right now he just kind of slides around the place Ray doesn't face the direction he wants he is an animator
he looks like one of those old football table toys.
I suppose the kid that had like magnets on the edge of a stick and move the stick and the kaggwa just
move like this.
Also you'll notice when I move diagonally a lot faster than when I go in the cardinal directions.
So here's what we're doing.
We're going to animate cube dude.
When cube dude moves.
Q Did she actually move.
Were going to face forward Mabel Q Do is always facing the direction that he's moving in and will then
be consistent when ever we're moving in any direction so I'm moving up.
That should be the same speed is if I move up and right.
So let's start with the simple thing.
If you look at our kudu scene you'll notice that it automatically came in with an animation player right.
It has two animations that are actually the same animation as a problem.
The file doesn't actually matter which when you use a good press play and he animates.
And if we wanted to we could loop the animation so this loop and press play.
And Q Did a little walk.
So all I need to do is go into a cube dude go into the script and let's make this nice big.
I need to see all the rest stuff and I'm not going to put this in physics process because this is not
a physics calculation writes It's gonna happen on each tech.
So amadou's and make a process function.
And that's going to be called an impact and effect.
I have an early challenge fees of realigns the end of the script as make some room and right here function
eliminate my challenge to you is to make cube dude animated when moving again.
So see if you can figure out how to make you do animator using the animation player.
Actually it should be pretty easy but only when he's moving.
Possibly to give that a shot and when you're ready come back and I'll show you my solution.
Mark Mack.
So first let's actually just test the animations of a pick animation player.
Play.
And that one.
Now animation player is a node within the player right so we already have access to that press save.
And now we're expecting his cube dude should be running.
Except he's not running.
Why is he not running.
So where do is an added condition.
If animation player is playing or it will actually want to do the opposite to that.
So if not animation play is playing.
Then play the walk.
See how that works.
Cute dude is jogging on the spot.
I've also got the pitch a little bit low.
Or is collisions a little bit high and hovering above the ground a little bit.
But we're after a good start.
I only want this to happen when he's moving.
Well let's make this nice some big.
We have motion here with motion and motion y that's a vector right.
In fact we don't have one we have set because of 3.
I can find the length of that right so it's a vector and if I can remember the Despicable Me movie vector
is a motion with magnitude right so it's a direction and magnitude.
Well what I can do is if I can go.
If motion dot or line.
Right so if there is a length that is greater than zero.
Do that while telling it is whatever size motion is if that size is greater than zero move.
Now I should not be using greater than zero.
I shall be using Epsilon.
Epsilon is a mathematical term for the smallest value above zero.
However Epsilon doesn't exist in God.
Some have to define this so for now I'm just going to go.
Constant.
So on.
He calls zero point zero zero as a as reserves are one.
Why am I doing this.
Because we might have a situation where we're not quite zero or almost zero.
We have flickering so let's see if that works.
It's not moving moving.
He's not stopping now.
So I need to do is go down to here and say else.
So if the motion length is Epsilon or smaller.
Animation player dot stop.
Let's give that a shot.
Is my cube dude.
He moves.
He stops.
OK.
Looking good.
Blair moonwalking.
You know what.
I might actually change the collision shape so that it's right by his feet.
Back to kudu in 3D.
And let's zoom down by your feet actually.
Collision shape isn't too bad is Atlas.
It might be our pichler signal that the Petsch over to pitch because our collision shape.
There it is.
See it.
Okay.
So our collision shape is zero point one metre so 10 centimetres.
But our plane doesn't have a depth so if it's not right at the top it's going to weigh it.
And it just keeps moving and I think we should move the meche instance.
Up to in fact I know this don't I need to make it up to zero point to noticer point one light because
that's the height of the collision shape.
OK.
This press play.
And the shadow actually comes to the feet and the character is not hovering.
Awesome.
And look the ball's in the right place.
Everything is looking much much shinier.
Groovier whatever it's not.
I mean is it shiny.
Okay.
So that's Section 1 with with moved cube dude right we've animated him.
Now let's take you dude facing in the right direction for you that let's make sure that the camera could
see everything because I'd like to see the edges of the pitch.
I almost had stage and I why I'm thinking in terms of stages right now I think because we just talked
about lighting plays in this lighting camera I guess.
And look my transform I want to rotate the camera only to rotate it on the x axis by a negative 10 maybe.
And let's move it back so I will move you to a height of Fiver's looking nice and high.
Actually rotate them.
Negative 15 on the X and maybe move it back a bit on the z axis that's moving back to 15.
Might work listicle.
A bit too far.
You know it's small so it moves closer.
It's moving to a set of 12.
How's that.
Well I'm trying to do is see just enough of the corner and I don't lose Cupid.
But right now I am losing Q dude.
Yeah he's lost so that's too far too close for other strife.
14 maybe.
Better.
Yeah.
I could see him.
It's analysis analysis kudu to face the direction he's moving on.
Let's go into the script and what we do is in the process make a face forward as a brand new animation
copy that not animation it's a function and under function an inmate which is an animation and when
a go function face forward.
OK.
So what does this do.
This rotates the character we're going to look at to do this and this is going to be important if we're
changing direction.
So rather than use if motion length is greater than epsilon one of the do say if not motion.
X is zero.
Right.
So if the change in horizontal in our left right movement or left right movement is zero or not.
Motion dot Z is zero.
So if one is changing all the other it's changing.
And what about do we want to look at.
Space more space here that we can look at which is a lot of function.
Now look in 3-d Slightly different we have to worry about what Up is.
And the reason is we could rotate when we're looking we don't want to do that one fixed in one direction.
What are we looking at we're not looking in an object we're looking at a direction we're looking at
a vector right so vector 3.
We need motion dot X on the x x is zero on the y axis.
I'm not looking up or down at all to tilt motion dot the set.
Motion is part of move and slide and that's being reported.
The frame behind where we are now.
I don't want to look the direction we are we have come from.
I want to look away from it.
Why should I use negative waves.
Negative motion Z and negative motion X not going negative 0 on the Y because that's pointless.
And then I need to put popin I could put vector 3.
But if we defined as a constant It's right here.
OK now if I've done that correctly the Pressplay cube dude should now face the correct direction.
I recently had a rotating never look looking good.
Now there's one more thing.
He's moving faster and diagonals.
Why is he moving faster and dying.
Well because.
Well because Pythagoras's really is.
Here's what's happening.
I have here an X and a z value.
Right so this one here is forward.
It is not a top down view.
So if I press up are moving up by speed.
If I move right.
Moving right by speed.
If I press both what we're doing is we're moving both up and then moving twice speed.
Now if I was to draw an intersection here what you'd see is that this is clearly not the same length
I would expect to stop here.
The mathematics work is something like one point for what we need to do is normalize this and we can
do that pretty easily.
We are going to go in to move and slide is motion dot normalized.
What does that mean.
It means bring this back down to 1 OK so that makes sense but now I press play.
I have normalized the wrong value.
I just change the actual movement to 1 so we can do a little work around.
What I do is replace every instance of speed here with the number 1 and then put in motion to normalize
tines speed and put this in brackets.
So in those That's one calculation.
And let's see what that does.
Another diagonal up.
Works the same speed as everything else.
But now you've got a messed up the face form so let's go face Ford is now doing motion and it's multiply
that by speed.
So right here no not right here at the outside of this same speed.
You don't multiply zero times speakers.
That's weird.
That's Pressplay.
And now keep dood.
Look at the direction is travelling in not Adamic when he's not moving and only look the direction it's
travelling in.
The angles are the same speeds everything else and we have the start of a refund.
Now we could change the speed freezes and export variable.
We could change the camera angle but were already off to a great start.
One might do is make the ball a little lighter Let's do that real quick before we sign out.
I feel like doing that.
Let's go to the ball and scroll up here.
The mass is one.
No it's not zero point five.
Let's add some bounciness to it.
It's has at the zero point five bounciness.
Knowing how much better another ball zooms along I zoom along we have a fast frantic game with a bouncy
ball can even bounce.
If we wanted different to go crazy let's go crazy let's make the full bounciness.
Awesome.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we've had a very quick sort of sajan around Pythagoras's because I'm not really great
at John mitre over looked at how to normalize affecter how to make a character face the direction it's
moving in.
And you know how to use animation player in 3D.
And the answer is exactly as you were in 2D.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.