Hello again, you astounding go to people in this video, we're going to start adding some actual functional
goals.
We have the goals for right now, the ball go in and nothing will happen.
Let's change that.
We're going to do is just set up something very simple over in our goal, seen so close.
All these are open for the previous video and open my two to two as my goals has my goals in the goals
just opened.
Go one.
Okay.
So here is a goal.
Great.
I need to detect if the ball is crossing this line and to do that.
I'm just going to use an area note.
Now we've played with areas before.
There are some similarities, at least on the surface, between an area and a physical body.
Specifically, they both use collision shapes.
So going to give this a collision shape.
And this only a simple box shaped, and we can play with that a second.
The central difference is that a physics body needs a collision shape to know how the physics gonna
work.
An area needs a physics collision shape to know when a physics body has entered so that it can do something
right.
So when to send a signal, I want to rename this area to gold detector.
And before I forget, because I almost got a collision and it can only.
It is not part of the level, but it can only interact with the ball.
Nothing else matters.
And now we have that song stuck in my head.
And this wants to be up a little bit, doesn't it?
In fact, I'm not gonna my boldness.
Let's move this up like point five.
I think that's right.
You know, that's about the central goal, isn't it's a one metre high goal.
OK, so excellence.
Let's go to my commissionership.
And my stance on the zeds, the blue line is going to be point one.
And on the X, it's going to be two, not bad.
Now the line does go underneath.
That's not the end of the world economy detectable anyway.
There is a little bit of gap at the top.
Again, not the edge of the world.
Everything else looks good.
However, I've just noticed if it hits the actual post, that will be a problem.
You know what?
It's a one point eight.
And let's actually bring it down to a point zero five.
So if it hits the post, that's not going to count as a goal.
But if it crosses that line, it will.
OK.
So we now have a simple goal.
This is going to have a signal.
Now, what about the signal in the levels?
So both of these are going to connect.
Both go one and go two.
In fact, you know what?
I'm going to make gold one and Edsel as well.
And what I want to do is put a script for it to connect you.
I'm gonna put it here in the level.
I'm going to remain level to game just so that the game script makes sense.
Let's save that and add a script to it.
Could be an empty script for now.
It's good to go.
I'm actually going to remove all of these things and just save it.
All right.
So we have a gold detectors, one and two, and we need a way of selecting the signal.
So I'm going to give you the challenge before I do.
I'm going to give you what you might need to get it working.
If I take, let's say, gold one, which is over here, this is going to school and play to happens.
So my first goal that I'm going to actually make is gold, too, because when the ball crosses here,
I want the school to object to one.
So if we create the signal, which in this case is body entered.
And we connect it to our game.
We can add extra arguments specifically, I'm not an integer.
And just give the number one, because as a player.
OK.
So that can go in here and I got to rename extra AAG one to goal, Heidi.
Both of these will use the same the same signal so I can do the same thing on gold detector here.
He entered Connect and this is gold to Ongo detect a body entered.
They are both connected.
That's going to give a different go, Eddie.
So here's my challenge to you.
I would like you to use print to show when the player scored in the console.
Pretty simple challenge, but we haven't looked at when to use print for debugging and basic gameplay
elements in a few videos.
So just quick refresher.
I want you to print to show which player has scored.
OK.
So your console message should say player one or player to have scored a goal or has scored.
Have you put it.
I do want that information in that.
So it pulls the video.
Give it a shot.
And when you come back, I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
How do we do this?
What?
I'm in his prince.
And this needs a strict, doesn't it, so.
Player.
And then I want to add in Goldie.
But Goldie is an integer player or the print command needs a string.
So let's cast that as a string.
And then add in space has scored a goal.
Jail, not golf.
All right.
So this is very, very bare bones, and if I press play there organism issues with this bit of a move,
play to either way, boop play.
I want to score a goal.
Want to say those issues.
Well I mean.
Well, you could in theory just keep doing that.
Right.
You could kick it through.
But that's what.
Let's see if we can get it in the other go.
Jen, we don't know if I can, but let's try.
Game is a little bit tricky.
I might have turned on the speed, to be honest.
Yes, tell us, Pete.
OK.
So play I want us to go play, who's got to go?
You'll notice when the ball crosses back it's county again.
When I first made a prototype of this game, we had a couple of people playing it for quite a long time.
But interesting fact.
They started using that rebound, that bug as a new game, play mechanics.
So sometimes bugs make it fun game play mechanics.
Also, not sure I like that rotation.
We should fix that in the next video.
But for now, excellent work.
And I'll see you the next video.