To create a consistent code base for us to test against,
let's go ahead and create our own HTML page that we can deploy.
There's a few reasons why you'd want to do this in a real‑world scenario.
You know you're going to have to test some functionality like this,
but developers maybe haven't deployed that content yet or you're waiting on a
server or some other various scenarios similar to that.
I've ran into this a lot with agile concurrent
development going on on a project.
To do that, I want to go up to src, main,
and right‑click and say New, HTML File.
And I'm going to put this under a directory called webapp.
So I'll type in webapp/RadioButtonTest.html.
And I'm going to select HTML5 file,
it doesn't really matter for what we're doing,
and click Enter.
And your directory structure should look similar to what I
have on the left of my project here.
So now I've got a src,
main directory that has a webapp folder underneath it
containing RadioButtonTest.html.
I'm going to change the title of this page to RadioButtonTest.
And inside the body,
I'm going to put some HTML here for a form with
three input types of radio in there.
And you can grab this code out of the exercise files if you
want instead of typing it all in here,
or you can type it in really fast if you want.
But we've got our RadioButtonTest.html here inside of our application
with our form inside of there and our three radio buttons that we can
go ahead and use inside of our test.
I'm going to show you a little trick to do this without having to go
set up anything else inside of your application.
If you right‑click on RadioButtonTest.html and choose Reveal in Finder,
it will open up a file system window to where you are
already at the level of that HTML file.
From here,
you can right‑click on it and say Open With Chrome or Firefox
or whatever other browser you're using,
and this will open up your browser and serve the HTML exactly like
it wouuld if it came off of your web server.
The nice thing about this is it's consistent so we can grab this
address out of the address bar and use that inside of our test
until you have a file deployed somewhere that you can
consistently test against this.
So this will give us a standard environment that we can run our test against.
Switching back to our IDE,
let's go ahead and create a test to now run against our HTML page we created.
So I'm going to right‑click on com.pluralsight and say New,
Java Class, and we'll call this WebDriverRadioButtons.
Hit Enter.
And inside of the body, let's give this a public static void main.
So we'll do public static void main and pass in our
String args signature required by Java.
And we're going to set this up very similar to what our other WebDriverDemo is.
We'll just say WebDriver driver, and we want to use a new ChromeDriver,
so we'll say that's equal to new ChromeDriver.
And the difference here and why I'm typing this out rather than just
copy and pasting it is I'm going to say driver.get,
and we're going to put a URL inside of here.
We're going to use the URL that we just grabbed off of
that page that we served up locally.
So let's switch back over to our browser,
grab that address out of the address bar,
and go back to our IDE.
And inside of that get,
paste in that file:///Users/me/dev, whatever your address is to yours.
That's the address to my workspace.
It's under the user's account,
me for my operating system, and then my dev workspace.
Your path should look something similar to that, the only difference being
what your file system is. If you're using Windows box,
it's going to be C: rather than a / and what your workspace is named.
From here, we can go down and let's create a list,
and the list is going to be of WebElements and select that.
And our elements are going to be radio buttons.
So we'll call this radioButtons, and that's going to
be equal to driver.findElements.
And this time we're going to do a By.name, and the name is
color. And that is referring to the radio button group
that we have in our HTML page.
So that By.name color, if we switch over to our HTML, you can
see that we have that name equals color.
That's the grouping that we're going to put together here.
Let's make this a little bit full screen so you can
see it for a minute longer here.
Now we want to go through and say radioButtons.get. Let's just grab
the first one, and actually not the first one in the sense of it
being zero‑based, but number 1, which would be the second one in our
list and say .click and save this.
Now, when we run this, we can right‑click on this and say Run
WebDriverRadioButton.main, it'll fire up our test and our browser.
And we can see inside of our browser that it has served up the page
and selected the second one or, since it's zero‑based, the number
1, which is green.
So originally, red was clicked if you remember the default HTML we
had that red or the zero‑based index was selected.
And in our code, we said go ahead and grab the item at position 1 and click it,
which is done. So green is selected here.