To begin creating our test framework,
I've gone ahead and closed down all of our other windows,
and we're going to create two new projects.
I'm going to start by selecting to create the new project,
and it's a Maven project, and I'm going to use the project SDK of Java 11.
We'll click Next.
We're going to give this a name of TestFramework,
and we're going to expand the artifact coordinates and
give it a GroupId of com.pluralsight, and we'll click Finish.
And inside of here, like we did earlier,
we're going to enable the changes to auto import.
And below our closing version tag and our closing project tag,
we're going to add in a couple of properties,
dependencies, and a build plugin.
So to begin with here,
I want to add in the property for the Maven Compiler release of 11,
the dependencies for selenium‑java,
and the build plugin that tells it to use the correct compiler version.
Now I'm going to save this, and before we exit out of here,
I'm actually going to run a command that we haven't done yet.
Over on my right side bar, I have a Maven menu.
And if you're not familiar with Maven,
don't worry about what I'm about to show you.
It's not really that tricky or complex.
I'm just going to build our test framework and
install it in our local repository.
If Maven scares you or concerns you,
there is a great course out here on Pluralsight that you can watch on Maven.
But for now,
all I'm going to do is expand that menu on the right, go to TestFramework,
Lifecycle, and double‑click Install.
This will go out and build our package and install it in our local repository.
That's all.
Now this project will contain all of our test framework.
The other project is going to contain our actual tests.
So now we need to go up to our menu and choose File,
New, Project, and it's also a Maven project.
It's going to use the project SDK of Java 11.
We'll click Next.
This one is going to be called Tests.
We'll expand the artifact coordinates and go to com.pluralsight,
and we'll click Finish.
And we want to choose New Window.
This window will close the test framework window.
New Window will actually open up a second editor.
So we want to choose New Window, and it will open up our project inside of here.
We're going to enable auto import of changes.
This is really important with this one because we're going
to continually add things to TestFramework that we want
imported into this project.
So I'm going to select that.
Then I'm going to go up and just like before‑‑‑ You may be asking yourself,
why do we have to do this on every POM file?
It's because they are going for the lowest common denominator of Java 15.
So to use the latest and greatest features,
we have to go below the closing version tag and above the closing project tag
and add in the properties for the Maven Compiler release 11 and that build
plugin's plugin for the compiler plugin of 3.8.1.
Now,
we are going to do one thing different though and that is
going between our properties and our build,
and we're going to add a dependency.
The first dependency that we're going to add is,
in the dependencies element, we're going to add a dependency itself,
and the groupId is com.pluralsight.
And you can see,
it's already starting to suggest com.pluralsight:TestFramework for us
because we did that Maven install in the other project.
So I'm going to actually select that,
and you'll see that it put the groupId of com.pluralsight in there,
the artifactId of TestFramework, and the version of 1.0‑SNAPSHOT in there.
One other side note is when you have a snapshot release,
every time it runs your code,
it goes to look and see if there is a new version of it out there.
So let's save this, and we have one more dependency we need to add.
So below that dependency tag, but before our closing dependencies tag,
I'm going to add another dependency.
And the groupId is org.junit.jupyter, and we want the Jupyter Engine.
And so for our artifactId, we're going to choose junit‑jupyter‑engine.
And for the version, we want 5.7.2, and we will save this.
Now it has a scope associated with this.
It is set up for a scope of test.
I'm actually going to remove that because this whole project is just tests.
And don't worry about what that means.
It's a scoping thing so it doesn't get packaged with
your final version of this project.
But for what we're doing, we can actually just leave that out of there.
So when we save that,
it'll go ahead and download the JUnit Jupyter Engine
so that we can run our JUnit tests.
We have both projects set up correctly now.
Our TestFramework is its own standalone project,
and our test project, which depends on that,
is now dependent on that project. We can begin writing that code now.