The selenium IDE is called an IDE,
but it isn't maybe what you have envisioned as an IDE.
As I mentioned earlier,
I was expecting to install something similar to Eclipse or
IntelliJ, but it's really a browser extension.
Why call it an IDE though? That's because it's used to
record what you're doing inside the browser.
Recording will effectively trace each step of what we want to do on a web
page. While recording, it will generate Selenese, or basically the script
of things that you did while in record mode.
The script is referred to as Selenese.
It really isn't a dialect, but more of a cobbled together bunch of commands.
Once we have our Selenese,
we can then play that script and it will have automated the tests that we did
on our page or even multiple pages to get to that point.
This type of testing is often referred to as record and
playback testing, or clickthrough testing.
Let's look at recording our interactions on a page. Now