We can now set up our Selenium Server in grid mode,
and it's going to be very similar to what we've already done.
We'll start off by creating the hub on one PC,
and that will also have a node on it.
I'm going to use a virtual machine, and then I'm going to run the second
node on that virtual machine. And then we will show you what has to
change to run another node on that same machine and what breaks. What
we'll see here is that each one of these noses just going to be a
separate instance of Selenium Server, and we're just going to specify
what role is playing.
So for the hub, we're just going to specify that it's
in hub mode. And then the nodes,
we're going to specify that they're in node mode.
And then we're going to tell all them where to connect to the hub.
By doing that, we'll have all of these nodes connected to
the hub, and then we can actually see that these nodes are
communicating back and forth.
The purpose of doing this is two‑fold. One,
it allows you to distribute your tests so that you can run them
in parallel all through the same coordinator,
which is the hub. And two, it allows you to run on different platforms or
different configurations and have the hub be smart enough to figure out
what node is connected and which node to use based on what kind of requirements you have for running your test.