To record a test inside of Selenium,
you're going to want to open up the Selenium IDE, and I purposely closed mine
to show you how you can open it back up in case you did.
You're going to click that puzzle piece icon and launch the Selenium IDE,
and you'll notice it comes up in a separate window.
I purposely have set these side by side so that we can see the
interactions that we have inside of our project while doing them.
We'll say let's record a new test, and for the project name,
let's call this one Selenium News and hit OK.
It's going to ask for that base URL, and I'm going to put in
https://www.selenium.dev, and click Start Recording. And
immediately out of the gate it's going to pop up that browser
window, and it's recording right now.
You can also see that by the flashing Selenium IDE is recording logo
down in the bottom right‑hand corner of your browser.
Let's begin by selecting this About menu item and the subselect
item of About in there. Scroll down, and just to make it a
little bit more interesting we can choose News, and we can grab
the first news icon here,
right‑click on it, and say Selenium IDE and Assert, Text.
We've just made a fairly complex little test.
Let's stop this.
We'll name this one News. Click OK.
Let me make this a little bit bigger so you can read it on my screen easier.
You'll see that we opened up the base URL, set the window size, which isn't
super important, but you may be testing on a platform that you want to verify
that the window size looks and acts correctly.
Then it did a click and search based off the CSS nav‑item and the
linkText for about, it clicked on that, and then a linkText for news, it
clicked on that, and then we asserted that that text equaled Public
Project Meeting ‑ July 15, 2021. So it went through and navigated just
like you would as an individual and recorded that test exactly how you would interact with it.