To start up our grid,
it's almost exactly the same as starting up our standalone server.
In fact, this was the command that we used to start up our server before,
java ‑jar selenium‑server‑standalone‑3.141.59.jar.
The only difference is is on the end of this,
we're going to say that this has a role hub and hit Enter.
When this starts up, you'll see that it launched Selenium Grid hub on port 4444,
and it tells you that the grid hub is up and running.
Nodes should register to 10.0.178:4444/grid/register,
and clients should connect to 10.1.78.4444/wd/hub.
Let's open up a browser and go look at what that console is telling us to do.
Opening up a browser and navigating to that IP
address of 10.0.1.78.4444/grid/console,
you can see it pulls up our Selenium Server console,
and we can view our configuration.
Right now, it's currently blank.
We don't have any configuration.
And that's because we have the hub up and running,
but we don't have a server running.
Let's fix that.
When we started our hub,
it told us that new nodes should register to this IP address here,
and yours is going to be unique to your machine,
but this IP address and the URL /grid/register.
Let's open another terminal window.
I've got one here, and I'm at C dev/tools or my dev tools directory already,
and I'm going to do almost the same exact command again.
I'm going to say java ‑jar selenium‑server‑standalone.jar,
and this time it's a role of node,
and the hub that we want to connect to is ‑hub with that IP address.
And it's going to wrap,
but you can see that it's that IP address that it just told us when we
started up our hub that we wanted to connect to it.
So if I hit Enter now, you'll see it launches it,
and it will tell you that it's registered the node to that hub and
that the node is registered and ready to use.
Now if we switch back over to our browser and refresh
that, we should see a configuration.
This is what it looked like before the refresh.
After the refresh, hey,
we see our server. We have our address identified, and it even tells
you the operating system. But it also tells you the capabilities on
that OS, and that is that I have Firefox, Safari, and Chrome available for us to run tests against.