Let's make our demo here a little bit more usable in a more real‑world scenario.
Let's start off by commenting out this driver.get for Pluralsight.
Let's go ahead and create a new one, and we'll say driver.get.
We'll pass in the URL of http://www.google.com.
We'll terminate that with a semicolon.
Now the first thing that we want to do is we want to
search that page and find an element.
The previous slides were showing you all the various ways to find that element.
But what element are we looking for?
Let's switch over to our browser and look at what the search field has for
an ID or has for a name and see if one of those might be the better way to
approach grabbing that element on the page.
Now I'm going to show you a little trick of why I actually will use
multiple browsers to look up IDs or names or things,
and that's because it's not always clear.
So I've got Chrome open here.
I'm going to right‑click on the search box and say Inspect,
and I get a field that is ID input, type search,
and then some other attributes that I don't really care about
for what we're trying to do with our test.
So you would think that the ID for the field that we want is input.
Let me switch over to Firefox and show you the difference there.
If I do the same thing in Firefox, right‑click and say Inspect, I can come in
here and see that this particular field has a name equal to q.
So the input class is nothing like what we saw with Chrome, and
that's because they try to hide some of their things that they're
trying to show you and make it a little less confusing. But in our
case, it actually makes it harder.
I happen to know for a fact that we want the element with the name
equal to q, and that's what we want to search on.
And I was able to find that by using Firefox instead of Chrome. That's
why I'll always keep or look at the development tools for multiple
browsers on my machine because sometimes it's easier to find what we're
looking for in one versus the other.
Let's go back and do a find element by name of q in our IDE.
Now that we know the name of that element, we can do a
WebElement. And that particular one is the searchField, and
we can do a driver.findElement.
We want to do that by name. And the name we're going to pass in is q. If you'll
remember, we found that through Firefox. And we'll say searchField.click, so
we've got the focus on that page. Now we want to click on it to transfer focus
to it. Then we can take that search field and send keys to it. Literally, we're
going to type in pluralsight. And then when we're done with that, we can click
Enter on that field.
So we'll say searchField.sendKeys, and we'll do Keys.ENTER.
Let's save this.
I'm going to go ahead and run it, and it should pull up a browser. Navigate
to google.com. Find the element on that page by name of q. Click on it to
transfer focus to it and then send the keys or type in Pluralsight and then
hit Enter on it, which will then bring up the other page with the search
results for Pluralsight. Let's run this and see if that does exactly what we
think it should do.
And just as I expected, switching over to my browser,
I have a Chrome page that has pulled up. It's actually gone through
and done the search with the Pluralsight text in there and pulled
up the search results for that page.
So a pretty sophisticated little search based off of just a couple of
elements. Pretty easy to do and quick to get that in there.
And I like showing you both of those methods where Chrome will
sometimes give you a better answer or Firefox will give you a
better answer, it depends on the scenario, of which ID might be best to search off of on that page.