To continue building out our framework,
let's go ahead and create another test inside of here to navigate down a
path to the author's pages on the Pluralsight website.
To do so, we're going to create another test.
So we'll give ourselves some space and we'll say @Test.
And the method will be public void canGoToAuthorsPage.
And inside of here, just like we did before,
except we haven't created this functionality yet,
we're going to say Pages.authorPages().goTo. And you can see how
we're starting to walk through that entire structure to test each
piece as we go. And we're going to do the same thing. We'll add
an assertion. Change it,
but I'm going to grab that for now. And we'll say
Assertions.assertTrue Pages.authorPages.isAt. We'll save this.
Let's switch over to our test framework and start adding that functionality to
navigate to the author pages. Inside of our Pages object in our test framework,
let's begin by creating the navigation for us to get here. We'll say public
static AuthorPages, and this will take no arguments. And this will return an
AuthorPages object, we haven't created that yet, = new AuthorPages, and we'll
return that object.
Now we can go ahead and use the quick fix on AuthorPages for us to create
that class, and we want that under com.pluralsight as well.
We'll save this. This is going to look quite similar to the home page.
Opening up that HomePage class, I'm actually going to grab all of this
information. And I'm going to point out something that I did on purpose here
is in that AuthorPages, I'm going to paste in exactly the same stuff that's in
my home page. This is a good example of when you're building a framework to
not overengineer it to start with, but also to refactor it down the road.
If we continue to have URL and title in every page,
we can create a parent page object that all of that information is stored
up in there, and the goTo method is used from that parent class, and the
isAt is used from that parent class as well.
So we can refactor these and clean these up some. To get the correct URL to
put in this object and the title, let's switch over to our browser and look
at what the URL is for that, as well as the title for that page. Scrolling
down to the bottom of our page,
we can see that there is an Authors link down underneath the platform.
If we click on that, that's a pretty easy URL to remember.
It's just pluralsight.com/authors.
But what about the title?
Well,
I'm going to go ahead and view the source of this page and look for the title.
And the title for this page is Authors Pluralsight. So I'm going to grab that
while I'm here and switch back over to our framework. Paste that in for the
title and correct that URL to go to /authors.
Let's fix that URL. And for the title, we'll highlight that and
paste that in there and save that as well.
So now we have the correct URL and the isAt to verify that we
are, in fact, on that page and where we think we should be.
Before we switch back over to our test,
we want to run a maven install. Let that go ahead and build our project and
put it up in our repository for us. And now we can switch back over to our
tests. They'll refresh. And we can now run our tests and verify that we can
go to the home page and go to the authors page, and it closes and cleans up
after itself when it's done.
So let's run this. Right‑click and say canGoToAuthorsPage.
It'll go through and verify both those, and that test successfully ran
and closed the browser when it was done as well.
So you can see we're starting to go through and build out that functionality
as we go through all of the pieces inside of our browser, and it's
navigating and capturing that entire site map for us.
And this is not a spider.
We're not doing this to spider the pages. We're doing this to
prove out that the functionality that we think should be there
is, in fact, there, and we can start checking for other elements and resources on those pages.