How do you guarantee that you don't ship software with bugs in your application?
Or better yet,
how do you know that you haven't broken something else while trying
to fix an identified bug inside your application?
Testing, regression testing,
and automated testing are all things that Selenium and WebDriver can help
you with in ensuring that you deliver quality software.
Hello,
I'm Bryan Hansen, and welcome to my course on Automated Web
Testing with Selenium and WebDriver Using Java.
In this course, we're going to be learning about the
web testing framework Selenium.
We are then going to learn about the Selenium IDE, a tool
that we use inside of our browser that allows us to record
scripts and play them back.
This is a great foundation for us to then transfer to using
WebDriver tests in which we can write tests and automated
tests using Java for our browser.
Once we have a solid base of WebDriver, we'll learn about more advanced
techniques such as Selenium Server and parallel and remote execution of tests,
and all of this wraps up with us creating an automation framework and
reporting on tests that we run in that framework. Let's get started by first looking at a simple Selenium test.