Let's create another HTML page in our application by right‑clicking on src,
main, webapp and selecting New, HTML File.
We'll call this TableTest.html.
And inside of here, we're going to give it a title of Table Test.
And in the body, I'm going to add a table with a tr and,
inside of that, a td for table 1,
row 1 and inside a second td another nested table to
demonstrate our navigation of nested tables with a tr td
for row 1 and a tr td for row 2.
Now from here, let's go ahead and create our WebDriver test.
I'm going to right‑click on our com.pluralsight package underneath src,
main, java.
Say Java class.
And I'll call this WebDriverTables.
Hit Enter.
And like we have on our previous tests,
I'm going to grab that public static void main and
WebDriver from another test and copy over here.
Make sure we get our closing curly brace inside of here.
And let's change that path to our new TableTest.html and save that.
Now we're going to step through this programmatically,
and you'll see it's just not that complex for us to grab all of the
pieces that we need and display them to the screen.
Let's grab the first WebElement,
and we'll name this OuterTable. And that is equal to
driver.findElement, and we'll do that by tag name. And the tag
name that we'll pass in there is just table because that's what
our outer table is named. From this element,
we can go ahead and do a findElement on it. So we'll say WebElement
innerTable, and that is equal to outerTable.findElement.
And we'll also do a By.tagName on it, and that one is also named table.
Then, from the innerTable, we can say WebElement row =
innerTable.findElements. We'll do that plural, and we'll do that
by tag name, and its tag name is td. And let's just grab the
first one or the one‑based index.
Technically, it would be the second one. And we'll say
System.out.println, and we'll print out that row's text.
So since those lists are zero‑based,
grabbing the index of 1 will get us that second value. And
based off of our HTML, that should get us a table 2, row 2
and print that out to our console.
Let's right‑click on this main and say run WebDriverTables.main, and
it'll open up our browser, but it'll also dump out that value to our
console. And you can see at the bottom of our console, we have table 2,
row 2. I can show you the web page, but it's not doing anything
interaction‑wise based off of it.
We're just showing you how you can grab that tag of the table and
then the tag of the innerTable and then the tag of the rows and
grabbing that one at position 1, which is the second position, and
displaying that text to the screen. Let's see what this looks like using XPath now.