Let's dive right in and show you a test with the Selenium IDE.
This is a simple test that's going to do some record and playback for us. To
do this, I want to go ahead and navigate to our Extensions icon, and we're
going to talk more about this later, in fact how this gets installed as an
icon, and choose the Selenium IDE.
You can see that this opens up another dialog where one of the menu
selections is to Record a new test in a new project.
We want to go ahead and choose that. And it's going to ask us to
name our test, so we'll say Test and click OK.
Then it will ask us for the base URL, so we'll enter in
https://www.selenium.dev, and say Start Recording. You'll notice that it
automatically navigated to this page for us, and in the bottom right‑hand
corner of your screen it says that the Selenium IDE is recording.
This is a new feature with the more current releases of Selenium IDE. So
navigate down, and in the center of our page we have this Download link for
the Selenium IDE, and we can click Download. And when we get here, there's
a couple of things we can do. Just for the sake of this simple test, you'll
notice that the title of our page in the upper left‑hand corner for me here
is Downloads.
If I right‑click on this page and go to Selenium IDE, there is an Assert, Store,
Verify,
Wait For. We can just choose Assert for our title and see that
our title matches what we think it should.
So, the title of this page is Downloads, our IDE should now assert that
the title of this page does in fact equal Downloads.
If we switch back to our Selenium IDE, you can see that
it opened up, went to our base page,
it actually set the window size because I'm running this as full screen,
it clicked and chose a CSS identifier for the click that
was our Download link, and it asserted that the title of
that page was in fact Downloads.
Now, it may not be readily apparent how powerful that is,
but if you realize, this just navigated to a page for you and
verified all of that functionality. And if I come up here and
choose to run that test again,
it's going to fire up a browser window very quickly and
run through that test completely again.
So if I choose that, and we're still recording,
you have to stop that, name it, we'll say Test, and run all tests again,
you can see that it went through and did all of that.
If we go back to our IDE again, you can see that it ran once and it's green.
We have a green Test passed successfully bar in that lower left‑hand corner here.