So next, we're going to be talking about management and governance services.
And when we're talking about this category, we're primarily
talking about six different services. First of all,
we have AWS CloudTrail, and then AWS CloudFormation, Amazon CloudWatch,
AWS Config, AWS Systems Manager, and AWS Control Tower.
So over the course of this module, here's what we're going to cover.
First,
we're just going to be reviewing the ecosystem of services that are
provided for management. While we've looked at a lot of services that we
can launch, this is where we transition to looking at what do we do once
we launch resources within the cloud.
Then, we're going to be examining how to create an audit
trail by leveraging AWS CloudTrail.
And then, we'll be exploring how you track
infrastructure with both CloudWatch and Config.
Then we'll be looking at a concept called infrastructure automation,
or infrastructure as code, with CloudFormation.
And then we'll be looking at operational insights utilizing Systems Manager.
And then finally, we'll be reviewing AWS Organizations,
which is a concept we have already explored, but we'll be looking at how that works with Control Tower.