So next, we're going to talk about the third service that provides
resources for managing infrastructure within AWS,
and that is going to be AWS Systems Manager. Now, Systems Manager
provides this unified user interface so you can look at
operational data from multiple AWS services.
And for many of those services, you can even automate some
operational tasks across those resources.
So let's look at AWS Systems Manager at a little bit of a deeper level.
First of all,
know that it provides multiple tools that makes your life easier
when you're managing infrastructure on AWS,
and we will not be reviewing all of them, but we will touch on a few of them.
First of all, it can enable you to automate tasks for common maintenance actions.
Let's say that you have two applications in your AWS
account that you're supporting.
Let's say you have 10 servers that support one application
and 10 servers that support another,
and you want to update those EC2 instances for your first
application with a new version of a library. You can actually write
that action one time and then simultaneously send it out to all the
servers that need to receive it,
and then you could choose to have it update on those servers,
but not have it affect the other servers at all.
That's just a example of how you can use this automation capability.
It also gives you a secure way to access your servers
using just your AWS credentials.
So if you don't want to have to deal with separate keys or separate passwords,
you can utilize this approach for accessing those servers.
Another thing is that you can store commonly used
parameters securely for operational use.
So let's say that you have a specific database password and you don't
want to store that with each of your applications,
but you want your applications to securely access
that password when they launch. You could utilize Systems Manager for that.