Next, we're going to talk about AWS CloudFormation.
Now,
let's say for a minute that we have a custom application, and
this custom application requires two S3 buckets,
five EC2 servers, two SQS queues, and three Lambda functions.
Well, we could go in and set up all of that in the console,
but that creates a problem.
There are a lot of manual steps that need to happen to make that work.
And what happens if we miss one of them or we
incorrectly apply settings to a resource?
Well,CloudFormation exists to solve this problem,
and let's talk about how it works.
First of all,
it is a managed service for provisioning infrastructure based on templates.
So, instead of going in and manually clicking in the console,
or instead of writing a custom CLI script,
or instead of going in and using the SDK to write your own custom
logic for creating your infrastructure, here you're going to use a
service that manages that for you.
Now there is no additional charge for CloudFormation.
So with CloudFormation,
you only pay for the resources that you launch, but the
service itself does not have a charge.
Now you can write these templates in two formats, one is YAML and another
is JSON, and those are both common formats, and many different tools can
support the writing of YAML or JSON templates.
Now this enables an approach that we call infrastructure as code.
This means that we're able to write a template that every resource
on our team can use to launch infrastructure.
And this means that we're taking the manual processes out of the picture.
It also handles the management of dependencies between resources. So if we
require one resource to be in place before we launch another one,
it will go through and manage those dependencies.
Now one of the powerful features that you get with CloudFormation,
and this is going to be similar to what we've seen in services like
AWS Config, but this is specific here to CloudFormation, is that it
provides drift detection.
So if we launch our application that has all of those resources I
mentioned earlier, but somebody goes in and changes the S3 permissions
to be globally available, then in that case,
we can notice that change and we could choose to take action.
Now here's a very quick and limited example of what we can do.
So this is a YAML‑based template, and with this
information included in the template, if we ran it through CloudFormation,
it would create an S3 bucket for us, and it would have the name sample‑S3‑bucket.
Now, this is a very simple example, but you can expand to have very,
very large templates.
You can even have kind of templates within templates that
enable you to launch infrastructure.
So if you have a set of infrastructure, like I mentioned
earlier for our custom application,
you could launch that within one account and then turn
around and launch it within another account.
You could have one environment for production and another environment for
testing and make sure that the two of those were completely identical
because they're both based off the same template. And that's what you get with CloudFormation.