So next, we're going to talk about the AWS messaging services,
and the first one we're going to take a look at is Amazon SNS,
or Simple Notification Service.
And this is a fully managed pub/sub messaging service.
And what this enables you to do is it gives you the
ability to create decoupled applications,
and we'll talk more in just a minute about what that means specifically.
But the way it works is that it organizes information according to topics,
so you can choose to listen to one topic and not listen to another.
And that's what we mean by pub/sub, it is publish and subscribe.
So you can publish messages about, let's say,
new orders,
and then you could choose to subscribe to new orders and maybe order refunds.
Now it integrates with multiple AWS services out of the box.
And in addition to just providing messaging,
meaning one part of your application can talk to
another part of your application,
you also can integrate this in and have end user notifications.
So through this,
you could send out an SMS notification or an email notification
or a push notification to your mobile app.
Now let's see some of this at work.
So here we have a sample SNS architecture.
Let's say that we're a Software as a Service company
and we have a new user sign up, so we have a new user on our platform.
We could choose to connect that process to an SNS topic.
And let's say the first thing that we want to do is we
want to integrate them into our CRM tool.
Well in that case,
we could choose to connect that to a Lambda function that would
then talk to our CRM and put their data in there.
Let's say that we also want to have a queue for some of our
sales people to follow up with them directly.
Well, we could use an SQS queue for that,
and we'll talk more next about how you leverage SQS queues.
But let's say we also want to send out an email so that the
regional sales director in that area knows that,
hey, you have a new customer that's come into the platform.
We could also do that through SNS.
But SNS works a little bit like some of the social networks
that send out messages that then disappear.
In this case, if we aren't listening for a message when it's published,
we are not going to get it.
These messages aren't kept around, they're short lived.
However, there's another approach we can look at,
and that is leveraging Simple Queue Service,
or SQS.
So this is a fully managed message queue service,
and it also enables you to build decoupled applications.
But it also enables you to build fault tolerant applications,
and we'll look next at how that works.
It supports a decent amount of data, you can put about 256 Kb into a message,
and it allows messages to be stored for up to 14 days.
So while we're thinking about SNS being more like some of
those new social media apps that enable you to just send
messages and then they disappear, SQS is a little bit more like a mailbox.
Those messages will stay there until you actually go
and get them out of the mailbox.
Now there are two different types of queues that are included with SQS.
Now,
a standard queue does not guarantee the order of the items that
you're going to be pulling off of the queue,
but if you use a first in/first out queue,
it will guarantee that you're actually processing those messages in order.
Now let's begin to see what happens when you put
together SNS and SQS into an architecture.
So first of all,
we're going to have a user order, and this is going to
come into our ecommerce company.
And the first thing we're going to do is we're going
to send that through an SNS topic.
Now we're going to do something here called fanout.
This is one of the benefits of using an SNS topic is that we can
actually send messages out to multiple places.
The first place we're going to send it is we're going
to send it to a fulfillment queue.
So this is going to connect to a server that we have in our warehouse,
and this is going to be our order fulfillment service.
And so our order fulfillment service knows to go and get a message off
of the queue and then send that out so that we know what we need to
put in the mail to send to our customers.
But we also have another queue, and this is where the fanout happens.
So coming from that SNS topic, we're now sending out to multiple
queues. The next queue is our analytics queue, and this is where we
want to be able to store the information about the products that
we're sending out to customers.
And we want to eventually be able to pull this into our BI
tool so we can see trends for our products.
So to drop this into our data warehouse,
we have a Lambda function on AWS that's going to drop that
information into our data warehouse tool.
But something happens.
We actually send out an update to our analytics integration
service and it goes away, it doesn't work.
Now here's the great thing.
While that's not working, we're still loading up items into the queue.
We haven't lost any information. And the moment that
that service gets back up and running,
it will be able to go and grab messages off the queue
and put it into our data warehouse.
This is what we mean by fault tolerant, is that we can
have an aspect of our system go down,
and it can still work according to its purpose.
But let's say we also have something else happen in the same
day, that server that's sitting in our warehouse just dies,
the hardware itself goes kaput.
Well, in this case,
we're also still able to get orders in through our fulfillment queue.
And the moment we get both our analytics ingestion service and our
order fulfillment service back up and running, we will continue with our normal business processes without any lost data.