So, next we're going to talk about Amazon EC2.
And Amazon EC2 is one of the fundamental core services of
AWS. And AWS defines it as a Web service that provides
resizable compute capacity in the cloud,
and it's designed to make web‑scale computing easier for developers.
So, before we get too deep into EC2,
let's look at some sample use cases where we could choose to use EC2.
Let's say, for example, that we want to host a web application in the cloud.
We could choose to spin‑up an EC2 instance,
and then on that instance, we could install a Web server,
and then on that web server,
we could go in and put the files for our web application.
So, in that case, EC2 would totally meet that need.
But we also could do things like batch processing of data.
So if your organization produces maybe a 1,000,000 rows of point
of sale data each day and you want to pull that in and do some
preprocessing before you analyze it, you could use an EC2 server for that.
You could also use it to just be an API server,
where you take web services and launch them in the cloud and let other
applications access them. Or you could do something like,
even having a desktop in the cloud.
So if you want to launch a windows instance on Amazon EC2 and then be
able to connect to that through remote desktop,
all of those things are possible utilizing Amazon EC2.
Now next,
we're going to talk about the core concepts that we need to know before
we're able to launch an EC2 instance in the cloud.
First, we need to understand instance types,
and then we need to understand root device type.
Next, we're going to look at the Amazon Machine Image,
or AMI,
and then we're going to look at the different purchase options for EC2
instances. But let's start off by looking at instance types.
So,
an EC2 instance type defines the processor memory and storage that are
available to any servers that are launched with that instance type,
and you can't change this without downtime.
So, if you've launched an EC2 instance, which is your virtual server,
and it has a certain amount of memory,
based on the instance type that you chose when you launched it,
you can't simply go to that server and say,
I want to put a new instance type in.
So,
we do want to make sure that we make good choices on
instance types when we launch them.
Now, we have instance types across several different categories,
including general purpose.
So, for most workloads that you're going to put in the cloud,
general purpose will probably work fine for you, but we also have compute,
memory and storage, optimize instance types.
And again, that's three separate categories there.
So, for example,
if we wanted to launch an in‑memory database on our EC2 instance,
we might choose a memory optimize instance type.
But we also have accelerated computing,
and these are for specialized use cases, for example,
machine learning, because in this case, with those instance types,
you could get access to a GPU, for example,
which could be very important for the different
machine learning work that you're doing.
Now,
pricing is based on the instance type. So if you choose
something that has more resources available to it,
and it's a specialized type, it will cost more than
just using a general purpose instance.
But some instance types also have unique capabilities, so
some families of instance types have access to things like
specialized storage, or GPUs, as we mentioned earlier.
So next, we're going to look at some sample EC2 instance type pricing.
Now, I need to make a couple of caveats here.
One is, is that EC2 pricing changes over time,
so these numbers might not be accurate in the future, but in addition to that,
the prices can also change from region to region.
So let's just use these prices I'm showing here,
even though I pulled them from us‑east‑1, let's just use them to help us
understand relatively what different instance types cost.
So I'm going to start off here with a couple of
different general purpose instance types.
You can see here that we have a t3.medium and an m5.large.
Well,
we can see that the m5.large has twice as many vCPUs
and four times as much memory, and in this case,
it's just a little over twice as much per hour,
in this case, coming out to be just a little bit under 10 cents per hour.
Now, here is an example of a compute optimized instance type, a c5d.24xlarge.
We can see here that we have a dramatic jump in all three
categories, vCPUs, memory, and pricing, with this coming
out to be about $4.60 per hour.
But then we have a p3.16xlarge.
Now, this is a very specialized instance type that comes from the
accelerated computing category because this gives us access to some
of the industry leading GPUs for things like our machine learning
workflows. And in this case,
this one comes out to be about $25 per hour, So, even though
it looks here, like it has less vCPUs,
this factors into some of those special capabilities that are
included within the P3 instance type family.
And then, we have a storage optimized instance type, an i3.16xlarge,
which again has 64 vCPUs and a lot of memory,
and it comes out to be about $5 per hour,
but it has some special access to storage capabilities
that the other instance types don't have.
Now next, let's move away from instance types,
and let's take a look at the root device type.
There really are two different root device types that you need to know when
working with EC2. The first is what we call the instant store,
which is ephemeral storage,
and it is actually physically attached to the host that
the virtual server is running on.
So that's one type.
And the next type is Elastic Block Store, or EBS,
which is persistent storage that exists separately from the host
that the virtual server is running on. Now,
when EC2 initially launched,
we just had instance store, but now that we have EBS,
I'll go ahead and tell you that for most work you're going to do
on EC2, you want to use Elastic Block Store,
which is EBS, unless you have a specific reason not to.
It provides a lot of capabilities that will help you, but
one of the key differences is the difference between the
words ephemeral and persistent.
So with an instant store,
if you spin‑up your EC2 server and you actually completely shut it
down, then the data on that instant store will go away.
However, EBS data will be persistent,
and we can even go in and take snapshots of it and copy it and
launch new EC2 instances with EBS volume.
There's a lot that we can do,
and we'll cover that more, later within this course,
when we talk about the different storage services that are available on
AWS. But just know here, that instant store is ephemeral,
meaning that if you shut down the server,
that data will go away, and EBS data is persistent,
that data is still there.
Now,
let's look next at Amazon Machine Images, or AMIs. Now, I should
probably also mention here, that there is fierce debate amongst
the AWS community on whether or not this is pronounced A‑M‑I or
Amy, but in this case,
you'll hear me refer to it as an A‑M‑I. But just know if you hear somebody
else refer to it as an Amy, that's what they're referring to.
Now, an AMI is a template for an EC2 instance that includes configuration,
the operating system, and the data that actually
would go on that specific instance.
And AWS provides many different AMIs that you can
leverage, and when we go through, actually using EC2, later within this module,
you'll see that there are several provided by AWS that are
relatively easy to spin‑up a new instance from. But AMIs can
also be shared across accounts.
So if your organization has a specific version of,
let's say, Ubuntu Linux that you want to modify in a certain way for
security purposes and you want to have it be just exactly the specific way
and you want it to have one extra drive that's attached where you store
other pieces of data, those are all examples of configurations that you can
make within an Amazon Machine Image.
And as I mentioned, you can create your own custom AMIs,
and there also is a marketplace for commercial AMIs.
So if you want to use AWS Marketplace,
you can go and explore the different AMIs that are provided from commercial vendors.