So next, we're going to walk through the process of
hosting a static website on Amazon S3.
And so over the course of this demo, here's what we're going to be doing.
First,
we're going to be creating a new S3 bucket from within the AWS console,
and then we'll be uploading objects to that S3 bucket.
After that, we'll be accessing objects from the S3 bucket using a URL.
And finally, we will be configuring a bucket for website hosting.
So now I've logged into the console and I'm now going to navigate to S3.
I'm going to choose to search for it,
and then we'll select S3 to go to the S3 console.
And from here,
the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to create a
bucket, so we'll hit Create bucket.
Now the first thing we need to do is give the bucket a name.
Now you'll need to choose your own unique name. S3
buckets do need to have unique names, even across accounts.
So now that I've entered in a bucket name and I have the region selected,
I can now hit Next. Now from here, we have additional
options that we can configure for our bucket,
including versioning, but I'm going to choose to not set
any of these values. We can now hit Next.
Now from here, we have to specifically enable public access.
Now by default, AWS is trying to block all public access.
Now this is because organizations that put sensitive data into
S3, AWS wants to be sure they don't accidentally enable public
access to one or more files.
So by default, now, they're telling everyone that the
buckets need to block public access.
But in this case, because we do want to allow public access into our bucket,
we're going to choose to deselect this.
Now it's important to note, this doesn't change the permissions
for the data you put into your bucket yet, it just gives you
the option to make items public.
So I'll go ahead and hit here that I acknowledge this, and then we'll hit Next.
Once we see the information here for our bucket and everything looks correct,
we can now hit Create.
So now that we've created our bucket,
we can scroll to it and we can now click on our bucket. Now from within here,
we can now go to upload files, so now I'll hit Upload.
Now we need to select the files, and I'll go in and select the files that
are included within the exercise files for this module.
We'll go ahead and select both of them, and now we need to go
through the wizard for uploading files.
Now, we can go ahead and hit Next here.
Now the first step is to set permissions,
and at this point we're not going to change any of the
permissions, so we can go ahead now and hit Next.
Now, we have the opportunity to go in and set the
properties for those uploaded files.
You'll see first, we can go in and set the storage class,
and we can see here the different storage classes that we have discussed for
S3. We'll choose to leave it at S3 Standard for now. But now,
once we go down to Encryption, I'm going to select Amazon S3 master‑key.
This will help us make sure that the data is encrypted at rest
that we're uploading into the S3 bucket.
We can now hit Next.
Now once we look at the data here, if everything looks correct,
we can now hit Upload.
Now we have two objects that have been uploaded into our bucket.
Now I'm going to look at the ps‑logo file.
Now we can see here when we click on it,
it presents us with an object URL. As I mentioned,
everything within S3 you can access via a URL. So if I open
up a new tab and I try to go to that URL, we'll see here that
we get an AccessDenied message.
That's because we haven't actually changed the permissions on our object yet.
So I'm going to go back to the console,
we'll choose to scroll down here and go to Permissions. From within permissions,
we're going to scroll down to where it says Public access.
We'll then click on Everyone and we will say Read object.
So this will give everyone read access to this
particular object from within our bucket.
Now, I'll hit Save. Once this is in place, I should now be able to go
back to the tab we were on previously and reload. When I do, we should
now be able to see the Pluralsight logo that was included within the
files that were uploaded into the bucket.
Now we'll navigate back to the Management Console tab. Now from within
here, we're going to go back to our bucket. Now from within the bucket,
we're now going to go under Properties.
We're now going to enable the option for static website hosting, so
I'll click on Static website hosting. Now from here,
we're going to say that we do want to use this bucket to host a website.
Now the first thing we need to do is we need to enter the
name for the index document for our site,
which in this case will be index.html. Now we also can choose
to go in and enter a custom error document.
This document will be shown every time the bucket needs to
throw an error, for example a 404 error,
which means they're trying to access a file that
isn't included within the bucket.
In that case, it would serve this error document,
but we're not going to enter an error document for now.
We also have the option to go in and use the redirect rules.
So, for example, if we wanted to redirect someone from index.htm to index.html,
we could define those rules here, but we also aren't going to add
any of those. We can now hit Save. Now once we do,
we can see here that Bucket hosting is enabled.
So if we click back on Static website hosting,
we can see here that it gives us a unique URL. So we're going to click
on this link to launch our site, but if you remember,
we haven't yet set any permissions for our index.html file.
So when we click on this, we should see, indeed, we do have a Forbidden message.
So now let's navigate back into the console, let's go back to our
bucket, and let's go to our index.html file.
Now from within here,
we should be able to go down to Permissions, we can go in for everyone,
and we can choose to give everyone read access to the object, and then
hit Save. Now once we have that in place,
we should be able to go back to the tab where we had
loaded in the specific URL that was given for static
website hosting, and now reload this.
And when we do,
we can see that we have indeed loaded our index.html file and we're
pulling in both the index.html file, as well as the Pluralsight logo
file that we uploaded within the bucket.
So over the course of this clip, you've been able to create a bucket,
upload files into that bucket,
configure access for the objects within the bucket, and then ultimately enable static website hosting for the contents of that bucket.