So next, we're going to talk about two additional AWS services, and
those are going to be Amazon CloudFront and API Gateway.
Now we've mentioned CloudFront before.
This is a service that leverages the edge locations
within the AWS global infrastructure.
And it is a content delivery network,
which means that there are servers around the world
that you can send your content to.
And why would you do that?
Well,
because it enables your users to get content from
the server that's closest to them, which will increase performance.
It also supports both static and dynamic content.
Many people think about content delivery networks only
serving static content, like images and videos or even
specific text, but in this case,
you can also configure it to support dynamic content.
And it also utilizes the AWS edge locations that we've mentioned,
which we also noted were the most prevalent form of
the AWS global infrastructure.
It also includes several advanced security features,
and those include things like AWS Shield,
which handles distributed denial of service attacks
and their web application firewall.
Now within a later course in this path, we'll be diving more into security and
understanding how that factors in to your use of CloudFront.
But just as a reminder, there are edge locations that exist globally,
so this gives you the power to take your content and distribute
it globally within just a matter of minutes.
So next, let's talk about another service, Amazon API Gateway.
Now what API Gateway is is that it is a fully managed API management service.
This means that you can create APIs, which are just web services that then
other applications can call, and you can make those available. And you can
actually distribute those through CloudFront.
It directly integrates with multiple AWS services,
including several of the services that we have learned
about so far within this course.
It also gives you concepts like monitoring and metrics on your API
calls so that you can understand how your APIs are being used and also
debug them if they're not working properly.
Now you can also integrate this in with both VPC and
on‑premise private applications, so it doesn't just have to be for public API calls.