So now we have already talked through two of the three compute
services that we said we would be covering in this module, and that
would be Amazon EC2 and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
But now, in this clip, we're going to be introducing the third,
which is AWS Lambda. Now Lambda is different in that it lets you run code
without provisioning or managing servers, and you only pay for the compute
time that you consume, and so you can run code for pretty much any type of
application or back‑end service, all with zero administration.
So at a high level, AWS Lambda does enable you to run code
without provisioning infrastructure, and,
as we said, it is only charged for usage based on execution time.
Now the real variable when it comes to pricing with Lambda is the
amount of memory that you make available to it,
and you can choose to have anywhere from 128 to 3008 MB allocated for your
functions that are running on AWS Lambda. Now the great thing is,
is that it integrates with many AWS services just out of the box. For example,
the work with things like S3 and DynamoDB is just
automatic once you configure it.
And because of that, it can enable what we would call event‑driven work flows.
So, you could say something like when I upload a file,
I want you to execute this function. Now this is the primary service in
terms of compute for the serverless architecture approach,
and we'll be talking more about serverless later within this path.
Now, let's look at some advantages for Lambda.
First of all, there are reduced maintenance requirements,
so you don't have to worry about those underlying
servers and keeping them up to date.
In this case, AWS owns that for you.
Also, it enables fault tolerance without you having to build it in.
So this concept of running across multiple availability zones and making
sure that no single point of failure can take down your application,
well that's just built in to Lambda. Also,
its scales based on demand, so irrespective of the number of users
you have that are using your lambda function,
you can know that it will scale. And your pricing is based on direct usage,
whereas with EC2 if you have a server up and running and let's say it
supports 1000 people and you only have 10 people using it,
you're having to pay for that whole server, but with Lambda it
truly maps to usage because it's only going to charge you based on the usage that you have.