So next, we're going to talk through some example scenarios
to see how well you've absorbed the material that we have
presented within this module.
And then in the next clip,
we're going to be walking through the answers to these scenarios.
So, here is our first scenario.
We have Elaine, and Elaine has launched a site that
offers daily tutorials for developers.
And she uses S3 to store the assets that are needed per tutorial.
Now these assets are very popular within the first week that the tutorial is
launched, but then, you know what, after this initial week,
these assets are rarely accessed.
So, how could Elaine reduce her S3 costs while maintaining durability?
Okay, next we have Esteban, and Esteban works for a social networking company,
and they are moving to AWS. Now as a part of this transition,
they have about 2 PB of user‑generated content that
they need to migrate into the cloud.
Now he's trying to determine if there is a faster
approach than uploading over the internet,
because that is just going to take too long.
So in this case,
would there be another approach you would recommend for Esteban's company?
Okay, finally,
we have Emily, and Emily works for a company that produces a messaging app.
And she's looking for a shared file system that'll connect to eight different
Linux EC2 instances. Now the file system would need to support 1 PB of data,
so what approach would you recommend for Emily? Okay, we're going to run through the answers to these in the next clip.