So next, we're going to walk through three different scenarios that
will help you gauge how well you have absorbed the information that
we have presented within this module.
So first of all, we're going to be looking at Sylvia,
and her company is in the process of moving multiple workloads into AWS.
And one of those workloads is an application that will be
leveraged for at least five more years.
This is just a core business application that her company will
be leveraging for the foreseeable future.
However, they're looking to be as cost efficient as possible for this EC2 usage.
So for them, what EC2 purchase option should be chosen for the application? Okay,
next we have Edward, and he's looking to deploy his PHP web
application to a virtual server, but he doesn't have
experience managing EC2 instances on AWS.
He does need the ability to scale, though,
because he does think this application is going to be pretty popular.
So for Edward, what is the best compute option for him based on this criteria?
Okay, and now our third scenario. Cindy's company is transitioning
to the cloud for its data processing workloads.
Now these workloads happen daily and can start or stop without a problem,
so they're configured to handle that.
The workload will be leveraged for at least one year, so for Cindy, what EC2 purchase option would be the most cost efficient choice?