Hi.
My name is Dustin Schultz, and in this module of Spring: The Big Picture course,
we'll get a high-level understanding of the foundations of Spring by
getting more familiar with the Spring Framework.
As the name suggests, the Spring Framework is a software framework,
and fundamentally, a software framework is a universal,
reusable software environment that provides particular
functionality as part of a larger software platform to
facilitate development of software applications,
products, and solutions.
Wow, that was a bit of a mouthful.
Let's take a minute to break that down piece by piece and
understand how it applies to the Spring Framework.
First, a software framework is a universal, reusable software environment.
So in other words,
a software framework is a piece of software that can be
universally used and reused and serves as the support upon
which applications are built,
and the Spring Framework very much meets this definition.
Second, a software framework provides particular functionality,
and as this would suggest, it's pretty straightforward.
So for instance, in the case of the Spring Framework,
the Spring Framework provides functionality for things
like web development and data access.
Third, a software framework is part of a larger software platform.
Again, this is also pretty straightforward.
It's just saying that a software framework doesn't exist entirely on its own.
It's usually part of something else.
So for instance,
like this Spring Framework is part of the larger software platform called Java.
And last,
a software framework facilitates the development of software applications,
products, and solutions.
In other words, it makes the development of applications easier,
just like the Spring Framework makes the development of applications easier.
Now that we understand the purpose of the Spring Framework,
let's take a moment to understand how it began and where it fits in to the larger picture that is Spring.