In this section, we'll discuss Spring Web MVC,
and in order to understand what Spring Web MVC is,
we first need to understand what a servlet is.
The Java language introduced very basic support for interacting with the
web via a built-in framework called the Servlet API,
and the Servlet API is named after the key component called a servlet.
And in simple terms,
a servlet is an object that receives a request and
generates a response based on that request.
Let's take a look at what a standard web request looks like using a Servlet API.
We start off with a request to the web server,
which is initially handled by the Servlet API,
and then passed on to the actual application logic,
or business logic as it's called.
The business logic is executed and produces some result,
and then those results are handed back to the
Servlet API to generate a response.
Servlets are great, but they don't come without their challenges.
Specifically, the servlet API is considered to be somewhat of a low-level API,
meaning that it's more detailed and offers less way of abstracting complexity,
and this typically translates into something that is harder
to use and is ultimately less productive.
Because the Servlet API is so low level,
it's easy to develop application logic that lacks proper design principles.
Code can quickly become unorganized and hard to maintain.
Now that we have a high-level understanding of the Servlet API,
let's look at what a request looks like using the Spring Web MVC Framework.
The request starts off the same,
entering the web server and passing through the Servlet API; however,
instead of going directly to the business logic,
it's sent through to the Spring Web MVC Framework.
The business logic can then make use of Spring Web MVC,
generate a result, and pass control back to Spring Web MVC,
which in turn can pass control back to the Servlet API,
and ultimately generate a response.
The advantage of the Spring Web MVC Framework is that it provides a
higher-level API for the developer to interact with,
and this results in easier usage and more productivity.
The higher-level API also has the added benefit of making it easier to
develop code that follows proper design principles.
And you may have been wondering this whole time what
exactly is the MVC in Spring Web MVC, well,
MVC stands for model-view-controller, and it's a design principle,
or a design pattern, that results in more organized and easier-to-maintain code.
If you want to learn more about Spring Web MVC,
be sure to check out the Pluralsight course called Introduction to Spring MVC 4, by Bryan Hansen.