Let's go ahead and start off with some of the advantages of using Spring.
One of the first ones is that almost everything from Spring,
especially the core projects, is rock solid and well engineered.
Spring has strict engineering practices and is backed
by a company that invests time, money, and resources into the project.
Spring has also stood the test of time.
It's been around for many years, and it's continued to evolve,
it's not a stale project, and it's also not the next shiny or new framework,
it's here to stay.
Spring has a huge community.
You can be pretty sure that if you run into a problem,
somebody else out there has probably already ran into the same problem.
And if they haven't,
you can be pretty sure that there's someone out there that can help.
Spring is very well-liked by many developers,
and in a recent survey from a popular
developer-oriented website called Stack Overflow,
Spring was part of the top most loved development frameworks,
and Spring also made the list as one of the most widely used frameworks.
With Spring,
there's a sufficiently large talent pool and hundreds of open
positions asking for engineers with Spring skills.
So whether you're a hiring manager looking to fill a position,
or a developer looking to learn a new skill,
Spring is very well used in the industry.
As I mentioned before, Spring has been around for a long time,
and the other benefit of that is that there's a wealth of
knowledge that already exists out there,
from books, to articles, to videos,
you can be sure that there are available resources to learn Spring.
Spring is still very actively developed,
and since it's an open-source project,
you can look online and see how active the project is,
and it's very much alive.
Again, since Spring has been around for so long,
it has a lot of built-in IDE support.
Many of the popular IDEs, such as IntelliJ and Eclipse,
already have built-in support and plugins available for Spring.
And just in case you're not sure what an IDE is,
it stands for integrated development environment,
and it's the development environment in which you develop
the code and having support for different technologies makes
it easier to develop that code.
Spring also scales,
and what I mean by that is that Spring is responsible for powering many of the
large and highly-trafficked applications that exist today.
It's proven that it can handle load and it can scale.
Now this is by no means a comprehensive list of all of the advantages of Spring,
but it should give you a good sense of why you might want to use Spring.
Now that we've seen the advantages,
next let's take a look at some of the disadvantages, or drawbacks.