Remember that Spring Boot is a project within the larger Spring family,
and it can be used to build both web applications and non-web applications.
And also remember that Spring Boot is built on top of the Spring Framework.
It has a number of key features that make it unique and easy to use.
I'm going to briefly mention each of the most important features,
and then we'll go into each in a bit more detail.
First, and definitely one of the most notable features in Spring Boot,
is auto-configurations.
Spring Boot will automatically configure and set up an
application based on its surrounding, as well as hints provided by the developer.
Second, Spring Boot is standalone.
You don't need to deploy the application into a web server,
or a special environment, or anything like that.
You literally just run the application with one command,
just like you would any other application.
And third, Spring Boot is opinionated,
meaning that Spring Boot has a chosen way of doing things by default.
And you're probably thinking, whoa, whoa,
whoa, hold on, that doesn't sound like something I'd be interested in.
Well, hold your judgment for now, as being opinionated can actually be a good thing.