The next project we'll take a look at is called Spring Cloud,
and you can visit this Spring Cloud project page by visiting projects.
spring.
io/spring-cloud.
The Spring Cloud project is a project that's built on top of Spring Boot,
and it makes it easier to build distributed systems.
Now if you're not familiar with what a distributed system is,
a distributed system is just a number of different applications
that are all linked together by a network.
And a common and popular example of a distributed
system is a microservices architecture.
And again, you may or may not have heard of what a microservice is,
so let me explain.
A microservice is just a small application that's very well
scoped to a single purpose or domain.
So for instance, if you have something like an account microservice,
its only job is to deal with accounts in the system.
It knows how to create them, and retrieve them,
and edit them,
and a microservices architecture is just a bunch of microservices that
are communicating with one another over a network.
When you implement something like a microservices architecture,
you end up running into a number of well-known
problems that have well-known solutions.
And one example is,
how does a microservice find or discover another
microservice that it needs to do its own work?
And this problem is called service discovery,
and it's exactly one of the things that the Spring
Cloud project helps you implement.
If we scroll down and take a look at the example here,
we can see that there's one new interesting
annotation that we've never seen before.
And that's the @EnableDiscoveryClient annotation.
And by using Spring Cloud and adding this annotation to an application,
the application, or service as it's usually called,
cannot only find other services,
but it itself is also discoverable by other services.
Service discovery is just one of the many things that Spring Cloud
helps with when building a distributed system,
and just like the Spring Data project,
the Spring Cloud project is not actually a project itself.
It's an umbrella project that contains a number of different subprojects,
and those subprojects can help you with things like
configuration and failures within a distributed system.
If you want to learn more about Spring Cloud,
there's a great course on Pluralsight, authored by myself, called Spring Cloud Fundamentals.