In this section, we'll take a quick tour of the Spring Security project.
You can visit the project page for Spring Security by visiting projects.
spring.
io/spring-security.
The Spring Security project is a framework for
securing Spring-based applications.
It handles both authentication and authorization,
and it covers all the standard ways of handling security,
as well as the ability to meet any sort of custom needs if needed,
and it's not only for authentication and authorization.
The Spring Security project also has additional features that help to
protect your application against common attacks,
like cross-site scripting or click jacking,
and you don't really have to understand what those
are to understand the benefits,
just know that Spring Security is also used to make
applications that are developed with it,
more secure.
To see a quick example of how the Spring Security project is used,
let's click on the Getting Started link under the Additional Resources section,
and this will take us to a page that lists a number of different
getting starting guides for Spring Security.
And we'll be looking at the Hello Spring Security with Boot example,
which uses Spring Security along with Spring Boot.
Once you're one the guide page,
locate the table of contents and click the section
Creating your Spring Security configuration.
This is the main part of the application that
demonstrates using Spring Security,
and will really give us a taste of what Spring Security is like.
If you scroll down a bit,
you'll see some code that configures the security in a web application.
As always, the details of the code aren't important,
but let me explain at a high level what some of the code is doing.
First, there's the @EnableWebSecurity annotation,
and this, as the name suggests,
sets up the application to be able to handle secure web requests.
Now let's focus on the configure method.
The code is configuring what paths are allowed and
what paths require authorization,
and it's also configuring the location of the login page for the application.
And if you look at the code, it's very readable.
You can see that any request for the path /CSS or /index,
are always permitted,
but any requests for /user path require the user to be
authenticated and authorized with the role of user.
This is a very real example of code that you might find in an
application today using Spring Security,
and it shows you just how easy it is to allow certain paths
of a web application to always be allowed,
or other parts to require security.
You can learn more about Spring Security by watching this Spring Security Fundamentals course, by Bryan Hansen.