So why Spring?
And oftentimes you'll hear people asking, why would I want to use Spring?
And that's probably something you may be even thinking for yourself right now.
And one of the common answers you'll hear is that
it's a good alternative to Java EE, and while that was true in the beginning,
today Spring is so much more than just an alternative to Java EE.
In fact,
it's actually complimentary to Java EE and makes use of several of the
standard specifications like the Java Persistence API.
The question of why you would want to use Spring is a completely valid and
reasonable question that actually has a very simple answer,
and that's that creating software can be hard,
seriously, and Spring helps make it easier.
You'll notice that regardless of the project within the Spring family,
they all share a common theme,
and that's to make developing Java applications easier.
Let's talk about some other reasons why Spring is a good choice.
First, Spring is really great at being flexible,
modular, and especially backwards compatible.
So Spring is far from an all‑or‑nothing type of choice.
In fact,
you're given the freedom to pick and choose whichever parts of
Spring make the most sense for your project.
And what's really great about that is that you can be sure
that the investment you're making with Spring won't be wasted
when a new version is released.
Spring also has a very large and active community,
and in my opinion this is often one of the things that's overlooked
and taken for granted when assessing technologies,
but it makes a huge difference.
With Spring,
you can be sure that there's a wealth of knowledge
that already exists out there, and if you run into a problem,
it's likely that someone else has already ran into that same problem,
and they can probably help you through it.
And lastly,
what makes Spring a good choice is that it's
continually innovating and evolving.
Being an open‑source project but fully backed by a company called
Pivotal allows Spring to remain healthy and alive,
while at the same time pushing the bounds of enterprise Java development.
It's not uncommon for Java's standards or specifications to be influenced or based on ideas that originated within Spring.