Since this is a very high-level course that doesn't go into any of the details,
it's helpful to know where you can go to actually get those details.
There's two highly-rated courses on Spring Boot at Pluralsight.
The first one, Creating Your First Spring Boot Application,
by Dan Bunker,
is an introductory-to-intermediary course for someone
who's already familiar with Java, but it's their first venture into Spring Boot.
The second course is by myself,
and it's called Spring Boot: Efficient Development,
Configuration, and Deployment.
It's an intermediate course that's a followup to creating
your first Spring Boot application.
It goes beyond the basics of Spring Boot and teaches the learner
how to write their own auto-configurations.
It also uncovers the technology behind auto-configurations,
teaches the learner how to make use of Spring Boot's
external configuration management, and gets them started deploying their Spring Boot applications to the cloud.