Now one of the key concerns for anyone working in machine learning is
knowing how to best secure the data that they've collected.
And we can go here to a quote from the CTO of Amazon,
which he said "Dance like nobody is watching.
Encrypt like everyone is." And there's so much truth in that.
We need to make sure that we are protecting data,
especially when we think about the kinds of data that we're dealing with
when we're dealing with machine learning at a large scale.
In many cases,
we'll have a lot of information about customer
behavior and actions that they've taken,
products that they've purchased, and we're trying to analyze that.
So we need to take time and focus in on how we're
actually working with our customer's data.
So there's two things we need to consider when we're looking at
aspects of data encryption with data encryption being just one area
of data security that we need to consider.
And that is first data at rest, meaning again,
data that's stored on a volume, in a database,
or other AWS service.
So it's not moving from one place to another.
It's actually stored in a location.
That's data at rest.
However, we also have data in transit,
and that could be data that's being sent from the internet to a specific AWS
service or server or even between different AWS services.
So we need to understand how data encryption applies in both of these scenarios.
So let's look first at data at rest.
So first of all,
data stored in Amazon S3 should follow best practices and enforce encryption.
So SageMaker itself works with S3 directly.
However, if you're implementing a machine learning solution on AWS,
one of your first steps is going to be to upload the data that you're
going to use for your model training into Amazon S3.
So you're interacting with S3 in many cases before you even touch SageMaker.
And because of that,
you need to be sure that you know how to work with S3 to ensure encryption.
So first, you can leverage bucket policies to enforce encryption,
and you can utilize a customer‑managed KMS key for encryption.
Now you could use the S3 default key, but you'll see in working with SageMaker,
there's an advantage to choosing to use customer‑managed keys throughout.
Now SageMaker verifies that its data outputs are encrypted at rest.
So if you're thinking about the outputs of SageMaker,
for example, things like your compiled model,
it makes sure that those things are encrypted.
But again,
if you're storing things in an S3 bucket that you've
properly configured for encryption,
you're making sure that even the data you're working with before you jump
into SageMaker follows those best practices as well.
Now it's important to note here that there are some specific
Nitro‑based instances that are encrypted,
but not with KMS.
So if you're using a Nitro‑based instance with SageMaker,
encryption will be handled in a bit of a different way.
Now let's talk about encrypted volumes at a high level.
So if you choose not to specify that customer‑managed KMS key with SageMaker,
it will be encrypted, but it's going to leverage what we call a transient key,
and that means that key is going to be discarded after
it's used to encrypt that volume.
So again,
in most cases you're going to want to leverage a customer‑managed KMS key.
Now let's look at different areas where SageMaker is using
these volumes that need to be encrypted.
We see it with notebook instances.
So when you spin up your notebook instances and you're working on your
different hypotheses that you're implementing for your machine learning
solution, that has an encrypted volume that is attached to that instance
where it's storing the output of what you're doing. Now also processing
jobs, as well as training jobs. Those instances also have volumes that are
attached to them.
We also can look at batch transform jobs that we
talked about in the last module, as well as hosting services endpoints.
In addition, if you're doing any hyperparameter tuning jobs,
those instances that are doing that work also have
volumes that are attached to them.
So all of those are different areas where we need to be
concerned with our data being encrypted at rest.
But in addition to data at rest, we also have data in transit.
So one of the great things is within SageMaker, the inner network, most
of the data is encrypted in transit with TLS 1.2.
Now there are some areas that are not encrypted by default,
and you need to understand these.
The first is communication that's between the actual
control plane and the training job instances.
However, that doesn't really involve any of your data,
so that's still entirely within the service.
Nothing is leaving the service, and it's not containing any of your data.
However,
we also have node communication in distributed processing jobs and
node communication in distributed training jobs.
Now there is a way you can get your node communication and
distributed training jobs encrypted,
and there's different steps you can walk through in
the console to make that happen.
However, in doing so,
you're also going to take a significant performance hit depending on
how you're implementing your model training, so just note that. But
it is important to note that with those two areas where you're
potentially dealing with data, that data is still never leaving the service.
Anytime data leaves the service, it's going to be encrypted with TLS 1.2.
So let's take a look back at our high‑level diagram showing how
we interact with SageMaker hosting services.
So here, in this case,
the client application is going to interact with API Gateway, and
API Gateway can be configured to use just TLS 1.2.
So here we can see encryption between those two points.
In addition,
we're going to see encryption in terms of how API Gateway
interacts with the lambda function.
And then since we mentioned earlier that all of the
communication within SageMaker is going to be encrypted,
we're going to see that encryption between lambda and the
endpoint between the endpoint and the load balancer and between
the load balancer and those instances.
Now we're also going to see encryption between those
instances and the trained model.
But later on within this module,
we're going to look at a better way for interacting with S3 from within our VPC.
Now one of the great things is at a high level, SageMaker has data
security integrated into the service as a whole.
So if you're following best practices for using S3 when you're using SageMaker,
most of the most serious risks have already been covered.
However,
there's another step that you can take when you're
considering data security on SageMaker,
and that's Amazon Macie. And it is a fully managed
service that's focused on data security,
and it actually utilizes machine learning itself to both discover and
report on the data that you have stored within Amazon S3.
And one of the things that it does is that it can alert you if
several conditions are met, things like unusual data access patterns
or configuration errors for sensitive data.
So if it's scanned this data and it knows that it's actual
sensitive data and all of a sudden somebody goes through and
chooses to make this bucket publicly available,
it can alert you on those kind of conditions.
This service can prevent some configuration errors, as well as bad
actors potentially trying to get access to your data.
So one of the great things is that it can enable some automated compliance checking for your data storage that you're storing in Amazon S3.