So next, we're going to talk about how we utilize batch transform.
We've already covered some high‑level use cases in the previous clip.
But let's dive just a little bit deeper and talk about some use cases.
First of all,
we might have a situation where we want to do
post‑training validation of our model fit.
We want to take a large amount of data and analyze that against
the model that we just previously trained.
In those cases, batch transform works well.
Or if we want to change multiple models.
So potentially,
if we're going to have the inference output of one
model be the input of a future model,
that can be a situation where batch transform works.
Also, if we have predictions that are going to be served outside of SageMaker,
this is where it would make sense to look at batch transform.
Maybe we have a limited number of input types,
and we're going to store our inference results in something like
Elasticsearch and then serve them in a different way.
In those cases,
you can utilize batch transform Well let's talk at a
high level about what this process is.
First of all, we're going to train and store the model,
just like we would do with either hosting approach.
We're then going to make sure that our dataset is
loaded for inference into Amazon S3.
We're then going to specify the configuration for the batch transform job,
and then we will execute that job on the dataset.
SageMaker will then take and will actually store those
results in the specified S3 bucket.
Let's talk about some configuration points for how we
adjust how batch transform works.
So at a high level, we'll revisit what we just covered.
We're going to have some inference infrastructure.
It's going to have an input dataset in an S3 bucket.
Those two things are going to communicate.
The inference infrastructure will pull that input dataset.
And then it's going to output the results into an output data bucket.
So let's talk about the different points of configuration.
First, we have the configuration of that infrastructure.
Second, we have the configuration for how we pull data from the input dataset,
as well as where that input dataset is.
We then have configuration for how we write the data to the output data bucket
and the configuration for where that output data bucket is.
So let's look at each of these.
First of all, for our infrastructure,
we can configure our infrastructure with a specific
container and number of instances.
We can also specify in terms of how we communicate with the input
data bucket the strategy parameter which is going to dictate how
we're pulling data from the input source,
whether we're batching multiple records together or
potentially pulling a single record at a time.
Then, we're going to have the ability to specify what that input source is,
what S3 bucket it refers to.
Then, we're going to be able to specify how we write data to that output bucket.
So the AssembleWith parameter will dictate how we're
actually out putting that data.
And then,
we're going to be able to specify what that overall
output data bucket is going to be.
Now there's a couple of different infrastructure approaches
that we can take with batch transform.
First,
we can take the managed approach where SageMaker is going to totally
launch the infrastructure using a SageMaker container and just
loading it up to the specified number of instances that we have
included within the configuration.
But if we wanted to, we can also specify our own custom
container that would be utilized in the same way,
except instead of using a pre‑defined SageMaker container, we're providing the container.