So next,
we're going to be talking about how we configure a VPC
for proper use with Amazon SageMaker.
And really, what we're talking about here is infrastructure security.
We want to be able to secure our infrastructure,
and a part of that is also securing the data that the infrastructure can access.
So to do that,
we want to be sure that we're launching our infrastructure inside of a VPC
that we manage as opposed to one that SageMaker manages.
In addition,
effort should be taken for us to minimize the amount of data
that's traveling over the public internet.
Now that might seem a little bit different to you,
but let me explain it this way.
So let's start off by saying that we do create our own VPC,
and we also have the AWS Services that we're going to be interacting with.
So over within our VPC,
we're going to have things like maybe our notebook
instance or a training job that's running.
Now over on the AWS Services side,
we're going to have things like our training data,
for example, that's going to be stored within an S3 bucket.
And in addition, we'll have our model data within an S3 bucket.
We'll also have the SageMaker Service,
so all of the control plane and ways that we interact with the service directly.
Now we have outside of these two boxes the public internet.
Now when I talk with some clients,
they're mistaken in that they think that launching things
inside of a VPC automatically has some special routing for
working with AWS Services, but that's not the case.
So, for example, on our VPC, we're going to have an internet gateway.
And then over on the AWS Services side,
they'll have their own kind of internet gateway.
And what happens is with our notebook instance and our training job,
when they need to go out and access those AWS Services,
they're going to go through that internet gateway and then through
the public internet and over into AWS and then from there to the
specific services that are needed.
Now what this means,
even though we're using TLS 1.2 encryption as we've talked about previously,
we're still sending a lot of our data out over the public internet,
and that's not what we really want to do.
Now luckily, VPCs provide a way around this using what we call VPC endpoints.
So we can choose to launch two different endpoints,
one for Amazon S3 and one for Amazon SageMaker.
Now technically, these are different types of endpoints,
and we'll talk more about that in just a minute.
But what we can do is we can then,
instead of routing our traffic out through the public internet,
we can now choose to use these endpoints.
And by doing so,
our notebook instance and our training job can communicate with these endpoints,
and the endpoints know how to communicate with the specific
services that they are associated with.
So let's quickly talk about these VPC endpoints.
First of all,
you need to know that there are two different types of VPC endpoints.
The first type that we have would be gateway endpoints,
and those are really just for two services,
S3 and DynamoDB.
Now for all other services, this is where you can leverage interface endpoints.
Now the interface endpoints leverage a technology called AWS PrivateLink.
Now if you have configured this properly,
if you don't have a need for public internet,
you don't require a NAT gateway or an internet gateway on
your VPC. And by configuring it that way,
which you enable, is a completely isolated private VPC so that you can
make sure that you minimize any chance of data leaking out. Now
endpoints are redundant and highly available.
So just like many other elements of the AWS stack,
you can trust that these will work even if there is a failure
that happens in the chain Now in addition,
you also can specify IAM policies on an endpoint. So you can
control what data is accessed through that endpoint.
So maybe you only configure it so specific S3 buckets go through
that endpoint and all other S3 buckets that are unrelated, that would just go through the public internet.