Now the primary way that we implement our machine
learning workflow on AWS is with SageMaker.
However, there are other ways you can go about it,
and we'll cover those later within this module.
However,
here I want to review all of the different services
that are provided with SageMaker.
So first at a high level, let's talk about the general SageMaker process.
We're going to start off with data,
and we're going to need to label our data so we can then use it for training.
So once we have our data labeled,
we'll then be able to go through and build our initial model.
Once we've built it,
we'll then need to go through the process of training and tuning our model.
Once we feel comfortable with the model that we have,
we'll then be able to actually deploy it and then manage it once it's deployed.
And then over time,
we'll go back through this process again to continually
improve our model with the data that we have.
So one of the first key services that we have in this
process is SageMaker Ground Truth,
and this is a service that allows us to label our
data for our training datasets.
And one of the great things about this service is that it can
leverage both human and automated classification.
So we can do a couple of different approaches here.
First of all, we can utilize a provided workforce.
So we can take employees from our organization that
know how to actually label our data, and we can set them on that task.
But we also can do look at leveraging a third‑party
workforce through Amazon Mechanical Turk.
We also have the ability here to use an automated labeling workflow.
So it can actually label data that it has high levels of
confidence in and then simply pass the remainder of the data onto
the humans that would be working on labeling.
Now you can see SageMaker in action here within the console.
Now this is using the image task category.
And you can see here that it has configurations for
things like single label classifications,
multi‑label classification, bounding box,
semantic segmentation, and this is just one of the categories.
There are other categories included as well.
Now the next thing that we have, after we actually have our data labeled,
is to go through the process of building our model.
And here we can look to leverage SageMaker Notebooks.
And this is a managed compute environment for running our Jupyter notebooks.
And the great thing here is that it launches compute environments that
are pre‑configured for our machine learning tasks.
Another great thing about using SageMaker Notebooks is that it integrates
storage volumes that can persist between notebook instances.
So if you want to have storage that you keep the results,
maybe your training datasets and your resulting models in,
you can utilize SageMaker Notebooks for that.
And here you can see an example of a SageMaker Notebook
instance up and running in the cloud.
Now if we want to go beyond that, we have another option that's a bit newer,
and that is SageMaker Studio.
And what SageMaker Studio is is a complete integrated development
environment for machine learning directly within your browser.
And what it does is it provides support for building,
tuning, and deploying and managing your models on AWS.
Now it's built on JupyterLab, but it's also deeply integrated in with SageMaker.
So many of the services you'll see here you can interact
with directly from within SageMaker Studio.
And here's an example of a notebook up and running within SageMaker Studio.
Now the next thing that we have is SageMaker Autopilot.
Now it automates the building, training,
and tuning of your machine learning models.
Now one of the unique things about this over most
automatic machine learning solutions is that it supports
the automation of the model creation.
And again, that's common.
There are several different solutions that exist today that do that.
However, it also allows manual customization.
Now the way this works is that it receives a tabular dataset,
and there is a column that is targeted for prediction.
Now this works really for two different algorithm types,
the first being classification and the second being regression.
Now next, let's talk about something that's similar,
yet different, and that is SageMaker Automatic Model Tuning.
So unlike Autopilot where it creates our model for us,
here, this takes a model that we have created,
and it can utilize machine learning to optimize the
hyperparameters in your model training process.
And one of the benefits of this is that you can set these runs
to be running in parallel so that you can optimize the speed at
which your models are trained.
Now this supports the following type of parameters.
You can use categorical so that you can have different
values that can be substituted in.
It could be continuous where we can pick any number that
exists between a minimum and a maximum.
Or we can use integer values where we need to pick integers
between a minimum and a maximum value.
Now if you're using SageMaker Autopilot or SageMaker Automatic Model Tuning,
you're going to have many different runs of your model training,
and it's going to be hard to keep all of that organized.
And that's where we get to SageMaker experiments.
And what this does is it enables organization of your training jobs and
the analytics related to those training jobs at scale.
And this integrates in with solutions like SageMaker
Autopilot and SageMaker Automatic Model Tuning.
It also directly integrates in with SageMaker Studio.
This was one of those services I mentioned earlier that is integrated with
SageMaker Studio. Now once you have your model in a great place,
you feel confident that it is tuned for your data, you then can do
look to leverage a service called SageMaker Neo.
And what this does is it provides both model optimization and
cross‑platform compilation of your models.
Now one of the great things here is that this enables you to execute
your model both in the cloud, as well is on the edge. And it supports
several different hardware architectures,
including Intel, NVIDIA, and ARM.
Now the next service we're going to talk about has to do with
how we continually improve the models that we're using, and
that is Amazon Augmented AI or A2I.
Now this service integrates human review into the inference process.
As we see machine learning permeate more and more into the business world,
we're now seeing it be applied into situations where we need to
make sure we are as accurate as possible.
And what this does is that it provides a configurable workflow for
these situations when accuracy is critical. Let's say,
for example, you're wanting to read forms that have been filled out by humans,
and we're trying to pull data off of those forms, and maybe these
are critical forms that have to do with financial transactions. And
in those cases, we want it to be right.
And so if our model detects a low level of confidence in
something it's trying to pull out of that, we can then
trigger a human review of that data.
Now one of the great things about A2I is that it is directly integrated into both Amazon Textract and Amazon Recognition.