Now that we've explored SageMaker Hosting Services,
we're now going to look at how you can do A/B testing on your
models by using multiple production variants.
So first of all,
it's important to note that production variants are
defined in the endpoint configuration,
and every endpoint configuration has at least one production variant.
You'll actually configure it in there.
Now if you're using the SageMaker SDK,
you can actually do this without having to do it explicitly by calling deploy.
But there will be an endpoint configuration that will show one
production variant even if you're not doing A/B testing.
However, when you start to introduce multiple production variants,
this is where you can do the A/B testing.
Now it's important to note here we're talking about using multiple versions of,
in essence, the same type of model.
There's another concept called multi‑model endpoints that we'll talk about
later when we're talking about different and unique models.
Now the InitialVariantWeight parameter is what determines how much
traffic gets sent to each production variant. And so the way that it
works is it sums up all of the weights across all of the different
variants and then uses the weight of each variant to determine the
amount of traffic to route.
And so,
if we had three different production variants, each that had a weight of 1,
we would see roughly 33% of traffic go to each of the different variants.
Now the weights can be updated by updating the endpoint configuration,
and you can actually do that without downtime. So you can
seamlessly adjust how much traffic is getting sent to each of
the different production variants.
Now let's look and see this in action.
So let's say that we have our client ecommerce application,
and as a part of this,
we're going to be working with an inference model that's going to
give information on suggested products for our users to purchase
based on what is already in their cart.
And so if we go through, this would interact directly
with SageMaker Hosting Services.
Now, of course, we're not showing the full workflow here.
We're not talking about API Gateway and lambda and all of those things and
the load balancer within SageMaker Hosting Services.
This is just a simplified view of what's going on. But our client
application will eventually work with the endpoint.
The endpoint currently is working with a model,
and this model was put in place by our data science team 3 months ago.
It has worked extremely well. And so this is the tried and true model
for this particular suggested product's engine.
However,
they've worked on two different variations of this model that they want to
try out and be able to actually get some data in production on how successful
this new recommendations engine is going to be.
So we're going to take model variant 2 and model variant 3.
Now at this point, we're not routing any traffic to those,
but we already have them stored within S3.
And we could choose to update the endpoint configuration and
configure these as separate model variants.
Now, at this point,
we still want most of our traffic to go to the original
model, again our tried and true model.
But we want to start injecting 5% of traffic to both of the new models.
So here, we could go in and set a weight of 18 on the original
model variant, set a weight of 1 on each of the 2 new model
variants that we want to test out.
This would allow us to then route 90% of traffic to our old model variant
and then 5% of traffic to each of the new variants.
Now again, with this,
we could use this and then gather data because one of the
things we can do when we get inference back,
we find out which model was actually used for that inference.
And we can then track that and see how successful this is actually performing in production.