Now I mentioned earlier that SageMaker is the primary service that we'll
leverage for operationalizing our machine learning on AWS.
But it wasn't the only way.
And here we're going to cover the different options that you
have if you choose not to use SageMaker.
So here we'll look at the different compute services that
we can leverage for machine learning.
And first of all, we have Amazon EC2.
So we can do both our machine learning training and inference directly on EC2.
Now if you want to do this, I would recommend using the deep learning AMI,
which provides a base AMI with the needed configuration.
Now with this, there are two different options that you can choose from.
One is the Conda AMI that comes preinstalled with
Conda and many popular frameworks.
But you also have the Base AMI,
which comes with the needed configuration for working with either advanced
CPU instances or GPU instances, and you can install whatever frameworks you
want directly on the Base AMI. If you're interested in the deep learning
AMI, I have another course on Pluralsight that'll walk you through how to
integrate with it. Now next, we have the Container Services,
and this includes things like Fargate and ECS and EKS.
And training or inference can also be leveraged on
any of these container services.
And AWS provides deep learning containers that are
pre‑configured for specific frameworks, including TensorFlow,
PyTorch, and MXNet.
And you can get the AWS deep learning containers from the ECR.
Now the next service is one that we've already talked about within this module,
and that's Amazon EMR.
So out of the box, Amazon EMR can provide support for Jupyter Notebooks,
and it also includes support for multiple machine learning frameworks.
And some of these frameworks include TensorFlow and MXNet.
So if you're already leveraging Amazon EMR and you simply
want to have a way to extend that to training and
providing inference on your models, you can continue to use it for that purpose.
Now another option that you have is you can also use an
on‑premise server. So if you have the capability within your own
data centers to do training and inference,
you can utilize the pre‑built SageMaker Docker images even within your
own data center. And you can integrate into SageMaker for either
training or inference, and here's what I mean by that You could if you
wanted to on your own infrastructure,
train a model and then upload for use in SageMaker.
Or if you had a need, you could pull the model from SageMaker for inference on your own hardware.