Depending on the industry or vertical that you're working in,
compliance might be one of your primary areas of
consideration when choosing a platform to work with.
So here within this demo, we're going to be doing two different things.
First of all,
we're going to be reviewing which compliance programs have
endorsed Amazon SageMaker and show you where you can go to
do that research for yourself,
and we'll be extracting compliance documents for an account using AWS Artifact.
So first, I'm here in the AWS Services in Scope by Compliance Program page.
Here, I can go down and see different areas of compliance.
For example, SOC 1, 2, and 3 compliance,
PCI compliance, HIPPA compliance, as well as many other types of compliance.
And if I scroll down on this list or even just search for SageMaker,
I can see, for example, here that SageMaker does have SOC 1,
2, and 3 compliance certified here within this list.
And you can go through and review that for each of the
different areas of certification.
Obviously,
for different organizations that are implementing
different machine learning solutions,
your specific compliance needs are going to be different.
But this page will give you the latest on where SageMaker stands,
as well as all of the other services on AWS.
Now next, let's jump over to the AWS Management Console.
And here within the console, we're going to use one service,
AWS Artifact, to be able to get compliance agreements.
So I'm going to go ahead and click on Artifact.
And from here, I can actually go in and view the different reports.
Now depending on what you're implementing with AWS,
you might also need to have agreements like a BAA, for example. Those would
be found under the Agreements section of AWS Artifact.
However,
we're going to look at reports. If we were wanting to do a
validation on some transactions and we needed to verify PCI
compliance for our solution,
we could simply go in here and search for PCI. And we can see, here
is the current PCI DSS Attestation of Compliance,
or AOC, and Responsibility Summary, the current one.
And so we could actually select this and, from here,
go in and actually download the report. Now to download these reports,
you're going to have to agree to an NDA. So you can choose to go in
and do that within your specific account.
But by using a combination of the services and
scope page for Amazon Web Services,
you can see what services are in compliance with which compliance programs.
And then you can jump into AWS Artifact to get the current documentation that shows what AWS has done to meet those areas of compliance.