So we have covered a lot related to security and
compliance here within this module.
And if you're going to be sitting for the AWS Machine Learning Specialty exam,
there are some areas that I think you should review
from this module before you do.
First of all,
you need to understand which aspects of the shared
responsibility model apply to SageMaker and, even more
generally, apply to machine learning as a whole.
There are things that we need to be very concerned with,
especially in areas like data security and understanding how that's
implemented when you're working with SageMaker. We need to
understand what SageMaker puts in place to implement data security
for data in transit and data at rest,
as well as knowing what best practices we need to follow for services like
Amazon S3 for dealing with data that we're pulling in for our model
training, just for example. You also need to be able to understand the VPC
configuration that is best suited for SageMaker use and look at the
endpoints that you can inject into your VPC for things like Amazon S3 so
that you can make sure that your data does not have to travel over the
public internet, but rather can see a within your VPC.
In addition,
you need to know how to secure notebooks and configure what they can access.
Since notebooks have access to the entire internet to begin with,
you need to know how you could limit that to a specific scope and, in addition,
know how you can leverage services like IAM to control access to your notebooks, as well as to other SageMaker resources.