In this section we're going to make our portal.
This is one of the cooler AAPS right in front of me at the moment is a portal.
If I go into the portal I'm inside of a whole new world.
To start making you school project create the project.
A single application called the project a our portal press next.
And create like always the first thing you want to do is go to the main storyboard and to your initial
view controller and scene if you expand the arcade scene view to the edges of your controller and once
you do that pin it to the bottom top leading and trailing space
you should already know how to get this kit.
If you working once you are on the up.
We've done it plenty of times for the sake of practice.
Pause the video and you try setting it up.
Assuming you've tried it this is what you should have done First off open up the assistant editor and
link to a kit scene.
View to your Wii controller with an outlet called Scene view.
Import A-R kit to use the air framework.
Once you do so close the assistant editor and back to your view controller.
Declare a constant configuration equal to a world tracking session configuration.
Now you must run a scene view session with that configuration by writing self-taught scene view the
session run configuration.
We've done this a million times and another thing we've done a million times is adding debug options
to our scene view by writing self-deceit view debug options is equal to an array type of debug options.
They are seeing debug options that we want to show the world origin.
So we want to know where our starting position is at all times.
And we also want to show feature points last week go to year end for the list and declare the property
privacy camera or use that description to display an alert to the user prompting him to enable the camera
and give de-lurked a descriptive message by writing.
You need the camera to display cool cat conta.
Now that we're done with all of this let's get to the good stuff.
I just reran the final version of this up.
If I keep tapping the phone the portal never shows up.
However if I detect a horizontal surface then tap on that surface the portal shows up right on top of
the surface.
So first off you need to set up the configuration such that it can detect horizontal surfaces.
Small hint.
It's only one line of code.
Pause the video and try to figure it out.
OK we've done this before.
It's as simple as writing self configuration.
DUP plane detection is equal to the horizontal.
Now we're detecting horizontal surfaces.
Now to the main storyboard I had a label on top of the kids seen kid view right over here.
Align the label horizontally and position it below 40 pixels from the top called the label plane detected.
Or give it a text of plain detected and in the attribute inspector.
I'm just going to give the label a font of Avenir next.
So keep it as plain and go to your font family Avenir next right here and the style will be a bold font
with a font size of about 30.
Or this is a little too big maybe 25 or 22.
There you go.
Done.
Open up the assistant editor and connect the label to the view controller with an outlet.
The label will be called plain detected close the assistant editor and back into your storyboard make
the label hidden first so only when we detect a horizontal surface we want to unhide the label and show
it for only 3 seconds.
This is something we already did in our Ikea up thanks to a special delegate function so paused the
video and try to do this one yourself.
OK assuming you've tried it first off.
Inherit from S and every delegate.
Once you do this call the delegate function did add anchor in the plains section of this course we discussed.
Whenever an anchor is added this function gets triggered an anchor is simply information.
This information as we discussed before encodes an orientation position and size of something in the
real world.
More specifically if this anchor that was added is a plain anchor then it would give us the orientation
position and size of a horizontal flat surface in the world that it just detected.
We don't care about the position size and all that.
All we care about is did we detect a planet or not.
So just right guard anchor is of type A are playing anchor.
Else return
so if the anchor that was added is a plain anchor if we discovered a horizontal plane surface then unhide
the label.
So self the plane detected is hidden is equal to false
and after three seconds hide the label again.
So just write dispatch.
Q Dot main dot async after and the deadline will be done now plus 3.
So after three seconds then execute whatever is inside of here.
And what we want to do is just hide the label again.
So is Hedden will be true.
And finally did add get triggered on a background thread.
So you have to make sure that any UI updates happen on the main thread such as this one.
This one needs to be on a main thread so right dispatch.
Q Does it mean that a sync and put the hidden function right inside of it.
This one is already happening on a main thread so you can just leave it as it is.
And one more thing to do before running the app is writing self scene view.
Delegate is equal to self for this function to get triggered whenever we detect the plane.
So run the app start detecting a horizontal surface as soon as you do your label shows up.
Everything is working out great.
So back to your Wii controller lets start making our portal.
So right click on your projects folder click on new file and scroll down until you find the seen file.
For some reason mine has already highlighted so press next and I'm going to name the scene file portal
dots on now into your machine file.
First off delete this camera.
Node we don't need it in an empty node to your scene.
Call this empty node portal and into your scene inspector.
I'm going to change the background from gray to white.
First off we're going to add the red carpet which leads into the portal.
But before doing that let me just place this exactly in the middle of the scene since it will be easier
to view when navigating between perspectives.
Click on your front perspective.
It's always good to see how something looks like from the front.
Their eyes are empty now.
Right now this is just an invisible node where we're going to add the red carpet to it.
Now the red carpet is simply a straight surface a plain straight plane and the plane to the scene.
The material inspector give the plane a diffuse color of red
now paused the video and try to rotate the plane such that its horizontal
so as you learned in the introductory section of this course to rotate something vertically and make
it horizontal.
You need to rotate it across the x axis so rotate it 90 degrees and make the plane a child of your note
your portal.
Now make sure your red carpet is aligned exactly with your node 0 0 and 0 for the X Y and so now the
plane is aligned horizontally vertically and in depth with our empty node.
Finally in the attributes inspector just give the plane a width of 0.5 metres and a height of 2 meters.
This looks much more like a carpet to me name the plain red carpet and our portal essentially is going
to be a small room with our red carpet leading us into that room to make our smaller room.
First we need to make a door opening to make the door opening.
We need two walls surrounding the opening of the door.
We'll use boxes to represent our walls.
So write box and drag two boxes right into your scene.
Give one box let's say a color of green
and give the other box a color of red.
Doesn't matter what color you give it you can give it any color you want.
I'm just giving it colors because it's easier to identify than the default white color which blends
with the scene.
And we went in the attribute inspector give each box a word of 0.75 metres a height of two metres and
a length of zero point zero or three metres.
Do the exact same thing for the other box.
A what 0.75 metres a height of two metres any length of zero point zero or three metres.
Now position one of the boxes relative to the red carpet by making it a child of the red carpet.
Let me just start with the green box by dragging it under the red carpet.
Now it's a child.
And now let me in just a line.
The green box the green wall with all of the red carpets dimensions by just making every one of its
positions 0 0 and 0.
So now the green wall is perfectly aligned with our red carpet horizontally vertically and up.
I need to place this wall to the side of the carpet to what's left.
Having done the math earlier if I simply moved the green wall 0.6 to 5 meters to the left of the red
carpet that should be I did it to the right to make sure it's a negative.
It should be exactly beside the carpet.
Now as soon as I made this wall a child of this carpet it's X Euler angle was automatically rotated
therefore reversing our two axes meaning the blue arrow which represents the y axis and the green arrow
representing the x y and z axis pointing up in the y axis pointing away from the origin.
This would suggest that the Zed axis is responsible for vertical positioning whereas the y axis now
is responsible for positioning the node N-words and networks.
Well as soon as we made the wall a child of the carpet it automatically rotated our Greenwald 90 degrees
since its parent node The carpet was also rotated 90 degrees.
So now if I want to position this wall vertically I have to use the z axis for example right now I want
to vertically align the bottom of this wall to the red carpet.
So increase the Zad by 1 metre and it looks like the orientation was reversed as well.
So change this to negative 1 to move it up and there you go.
Now changes in axes and orientation is a bit annoying to work with but it's just one of the things you
have to deal with when working with the editor.
So try to adjust while you can.
Now I need to place the box at the end of the red carpet which is one metre away from the red carpet
center.
And weirdly enough to change the y position to move the wall inwards behind the tarpit again it's only
because the orientation of the pivot point was completely reversed do the exact same thing for the otherwhile
position at zero point sixty five meters actually before we do any positioning.
Make sure it's a child of the red carpet and positioned this wall 0.6 to five metres to the right of
the red carpet.
And it was I believe negative 1 meters in words and asked for the Zad negative one metre upwards.
There you go.
So right now in the middle of these two walls will be our portal call this box side wall or side door.
And call this box side door B.
These are the signs of our door of our portal.
Essentially for these walls you could have just used planes and everything would have looked fine.
It doesn't really matter.
I'm just diversifying for tutorial purposes.
In fact the roof of the room is going to be a plane.
So right plane and make this plane a child of the red carpet.
It's also going to be positioned relative to the red carpet.
And the material inspector give the roof a color of black a diffuse color of black licorice and in the
attribute inspector give it a what of two metres any height of two meters as well.
Call the node roof.
Let me just fix this positioning.
OK.
So now move the roof two meters upwards so change the Y to two.
And it looks like the axes were reversed for this one as well which makes sense.
So instead of changing the Y to to change the Zad to two and looks like orientation was reversed as
well since the plane went down.
So make sure to put negative to right here.
Negative 2.
And there it is right on top of our portal.
And to move the roof two meters inwards behind the red carpet put a negative two for the Y and there
you go.
There is our roof right on top of our walls.
Now we need a floor
now we need our back wall.
So add another box to the scene in the attributes.
Inspector give the box a width of two meters a height of two meters and the length of 0.03 a depth of
0.03 to make it thinner and now make it a child node of the carpet.
Give the box any color you want.
I think I'm going to choose a color of lemon yellow and align it with the carpet.
So align it horizontally vertically and in depth.
Again the orientation of this box is reversed the way value will be used to move in words whereas the
Zed axis will be used for vertical position so move it in words such as three meters behind the red
carpet.
And finally one metre above its current position so negative one.
OK.
There is our back wall perfectly aligned.
Back to the front perspective
before proceeding let me just read in the back wall and now for the for the floor just like the roof
is going to be a plane.
So right.
Plane and add it to our red carpet as a direct child.
The plane was automatically rotated for us which is perfect into your attributes.
Inspector make a plane with a width of two meters and a height of two meters just like our roof with
a color of black a line horizontally with the red carpet which it already is and align vertically exactly
where the red carpet is which it already is and have the Wib to such that the floor is 2 meters away
from the red carpet center.
So negative 2.
There you go.
Now finally we just need the walls on the side so I add two more boxes.
Box number one in box number two give the box a with of two meters a height of two meters and a length
of 0.03.
Give it a distinct color.
I think this time I'm going to go for something like light blue or cyan whatever this colors and make
the box a child of the red carpet as well.
We need to rotate the box horizontally normally to do that.
We would rotate it across the y axis but remember the y and z axes were reversed.
So rotate it 90 degrees across the said axis to make it horizontal now place this wall 1 meter to the
left of the red carpet.
So right here you put negative 1 and it should be exactly to the edges of these walls.
Now place one meter above the red carpet so negative one.
And as for the white Make sure it's negative 1 meter inwards from the red carpet.
That didn't work out it looks like half of it is out of place so make it two metres in words and there
you go.
Let's do the exact same thing for this wall.
A waste of two metres a height of two metres and a depth of zero point zero three meters.
Let's give this box a color of let's say gray silver
no make this box a child of the red carpet and rotate the box by 90 degrees horizontally.
Place it one metre from the x to the right and two meters in words just like our other wall and one
meter upwards and our box should be perfectly aligned with everything and it is rename these both to
side wall a the right will be sidewall.
And the left box will be side will be.
And if I just look at this from the front perspective this looks really good.
We're finally done building the blocks of our room and the next video we're going to display this portal
in the camera view and create the illusion that the user is going inside an entire new world.