In the section we're going to be looking at plans in this.
Whenever the phone detects a horizontal surface such as the floor or a table it turns that surface into
love.
This is a great app to understand how a plane detection works.
To begin.
Open up X code create a new project.
A single allocation call the project floor is lover press next.
And create the first thing we have always done is go to the main storyboard and do the initial controller
add an arcade scene view to display three dimensional content in a camera view of the real world expand
the edges of that scene view and pin it to the top bottom leading and trailing space opened up.
The assistant editor and to the controller link can see a view with an IAB called Scene view import
our kit to use the framework close the assistant editor and do the controller add a configuration constant
equal to our world tracking session configuration world tracking is used to detect the position and
orientation of the device at all times.
So make sure you run a session with that configuration by writing self that scene view the session that
run configuration and debug options by writing self-deceit view debug options is equal to A R S C and
debug options does show world origin and a r s n debug options does show feature points.
OK we've done all of this before and in other stuff that we've done over and over is going to the infidel
purist right the property privacy kime or ETA's description.
This property displays an alert to the user prompting him to enable the camera to the alert.
Make sure to have a descriptive message telling the user that he needs the camera to display cool a
Arcata.
I hope you've mastered these steps by now since we've been doing them in every single section.
All right so if you remember from the demonstration that I showed you the film detects horizontal surfaces
and when it detects that it replaces the horizontal surface with lover.
But how do we detect horizontal surfaces.
Well it's simple unheated load just right configuration or self-taught configuration to keep things
consistent.
The plane detection is equal to horizontal now our session which has this configuration is now configured
to detect horizontal surfaces.
Now we need some kind of delegate function to tell us whenever the device detects a horizontal surface
to do that inherit from a r s and the delegate.
Remember in the drawing section we use this delegate to find that whenever a new scene was rendered.
This time we'll use this delegate to find that when a new horizontal surface is detected.
So write the renderer did add function did this delegate function checks if an anchor was added to the
scene.
Now an anchor is simply information.
This information encodes an orientation position and size of something in the real world.
More specifically if this anchor that was added is a plain anchor then it would give us the orientation
position and size of a horizontal flat surface in the world that it just detected.
So the device checks for horizontal surfaces if it finds one it adds a plane anchored to that horizontal
surface such that it gives us the position orientation and size of the surface to check if the anchor
that was added is a plain anchor just right guard let slainte anchor is equal to anchor as they are
playing anchor else return.
If this guard Tim and succeeds the anchor that was added is indeed a plant anchor meaning the filmon
detected a new horizontal surface and added a plain anchor to represent the surface.
Then Prince
knew flat surface detected new a plane anchor it.
And before we were on the up make sure to set the scene use delegate itself so that this delegate function
can get cold.
Now we can run the app
the chair has a horizontal surface.
If I point my film to it it prints new flat surface detected new airplane anger at it.
The floor also has a horizontal surface.
If I point my phone to that it's going to detect the surface and print the same thing.
The table also has a horizontal surface so a point point my phone to the table.
The same thing occurs all right now the floor is one surface.
So we have one airplane anchored to represent its position in the world as well as its size.
But the device only detected a small portion of the floor.
So as I keep moving with the phone the film starts discovering that the floor is much bigger.
Therefore updating the floors A-R anchor wolt to observe how a building the A-R anchor go back to your
ex code.
Call the function did a day
and heres what would happen.
Did it get triggered when we update the anchor of something in the real world.
We want to know only when a plain anchor is updated.
So copy this guard statement and remember that a plain anchor encodes the orientation position and size
of a horizontal surface.
For example as the phone keeps discovering that the floor is bigger.
It's going to keep beating the floor is our plane.
Anchor to testis Prince of dating floors anchor
run me up OK.
So first its going to recognize the floor as one horizontal surface and notice the print statement in
the debugger that keeps getting activated its constantly updating the floors anchor because as I keep
moving around and explore more parts of the floor it updates the floors Ankara's it realizes that the
floor is much bigger than it initially thought.
Back to X code.
Notice the print statement.
So first it recognizes the floor and then as I keep moving the phone around it keeps updating the floor
is a play an anchor as it realizes that the floor is much bigger than what it initially thought.
And there is one more thing.
The new flush surface detected new airplane anchor added was triggered more than once for the same floor.
Now the device isn't perfect.
Sometimes it makes mistakes and it adds more than one anchor for the same horizontal surface.
Now every horizontal surface remember this as a rule of thumb should only have a single airplane anchor.
Now the device eventually catches its mistake and it removes the second airplane anchor that doesnt
need to be there when it removes it.
It calls the function did remove
so did remove gets called when the device makes an error and makes more than one airplane anchor for
the same horizontal surface.
Every horizontal surface should only have one airplane anchor.
So we removes the second one and this function gets called in summary every time we detect a flowers
on the surface.
It adds a new airplane anchor and caused it.
And whenever the device discovers more of the same horizontal surface it updates the surfaces plane
anchor and whenever there is an error and the device adds more than one plane anchor for the same horizontal
surface it removes it and calls it removes.
And the next video we're going to use all of this information and these delegate functions to put lava
in every horizontal surface that we detect.