In this video we're going to finish our game.
So first off we need to download this framework called each to get to this framework.
Make sure to write these keywords into Google and this should pop up first in the results.
And so to download this framework first I'm going to go into it and if I scroll down you'll see that
it requires cocoa pots.
So if you don't already have go boards installed.
Go to Cocoa pods dot org.
Scroll down and copy this pseudo gem command right into your terminal.
So to go to your terminal do a spotlight search by pressing command space right terminal press enter.
And right here is where you will copy or should login Command press enter.
Put your computer password.
I'm going to put mine and here you press enter as well.
So I've already installed cocoa pods.
So I'm just going to fast forward this video.
All right so once you're done installing cocoa pods you're going to navigate to your projects directory
to do that.
Go to your desktop and write the command CD.
Our projects name is whack a jellyfish so make sure to drag the right here.
Now we are in the projects directory and now write the command pod in it to initialize a pod file into
your project.
Write an applied file to access to your pod file and right here is where you will put all the pods or
frameworks that you want to install to find the framework that we want to install the pod.
Go to the Get help page and right here is what we have to write into our APOD file to install this framework.
My version says 1.2 years could be different.
So make sure you copy yours.
Not mine.
So copy whatever you have and right here paste it.
Hold the keys control X to exit press the Y key to save and enter.
Now write pod install to install your Pod's and we should be good to go very soon and we are so right
now.
In fact a jellyfish.
You will notice a workspace.
A workspace gets placed into your project whenever you have Pod's with your project.
So make sure to close the project if you have it open and open up the workspace.
So I'm getting this error because I have the XCode project open so make sure to close that stub tasks.
So I'm going to close this and open it again.
And Raggatt.
So before anything let me just give you a quick refresh of how the game works.
So you have a limited amount of time to touch a jellyfish and once you tap a jellyfish another one pops
up in a random location.
You have to look for the other one and top it before the time runs out.
If it takes you too long to top the jellyfish you lose the game.
So first we need to have it such that the jellyfish pops up in a random location not in front of you
every time.
So remember this function it's in your resources folder.
We use that before to get a random decimal between a minimum number and a maximum number.
So don't worry about this complicated return value just know that when you call this function you have
to give it a minimum and the maximum value and the return value gives you a random decimal in between
that range.
So instead of placing the jellyfish right in front of us we're going to place the jellyfish in random
positions every time.
So give the x value a random position between negative 1 meters and 1 meter to the right by writing
a random number.
The first number will be negative 1 so 1 meters to the left and then 1 meters to the right give the
y value a random position as well negative 0.5 meters below the world origin and 0.5 meters above the
world origin.
So we're going to get a vertical position in between this range and as for any set value you give it
a random position as well.
By also putting random numbers and make it negative 1 meter behind these add axis and 1 meter in front
of the set axis.
So we're going to get a depth in between that position as well.
So now that we have a variety of positions of where the jellyfish could be run and the soap press play
and now try and find your jelly fish it could be anywhere.
And mine is right here.
And so when I tap on the jelly fish after it animates I need the jelly fish to be removed from the scene
view.
So back to X code for the jellyfish to be removed right after it.
Estimates go right here.
So right after animate node just right node dot removed from parent node the parent node is the seen
views root node.
So by removing the node from the scene views root node where removing it from the scene view essentially.
So it should disappear.
So run the app again.
So press play try and find your jellyfish.
It could be anywhere maybe on top.
Nope try the bottom
and there it is right behind you.
Now if I tap on the jelly fish it disappears and before it has the chance to fully animates So we need
to make sure that this line of code only gets triggered once the entire animation is done.
And so to do that we need a scene transaction.
A transaction can be used to control animations.
So start a transaction by writing a CN transaction see transaction that begin and make sure to put that
right before animate node.
All right.
So by calling animate node right in front of a CN transaction not begin it's officially part of this
transaction.
And the only animation that I want in this transaction is animate node.
We don't want the removal from the parent know to happen in the transaction as well.
We want the removal to happen after the animation is completed.
So we need to have this in a completion block.
So once we're done animations call seeing transaction completion block is equal to a closure block and
just put remove from parent node inside of the closure minimize all the ugly space.
OK so once everything in this transaction is complete once this animation is done then remove the jellyfish
from the parent node.
Now to finally trigger all of this all we have to do is write a scene transaction document now run the
app press play find your a jellyfish.
I hope it's somewhere a bit more convenient this time and it is and top your jellyfish.
Once the animation is done then it is removed.
So this worked out perfectly.
Now the OP is finally shaping up.
All right.
So now once the jellyfish is gone we need to add a new one to another random position.
So back to X code right after you remove the node.
It's as simple as just adding another one.
So find the function node and call it right here self dot node
OK.
Now rerun the app.
So wait for the device to recognize its surroundings so that things don't get messed up and once you
see the world origin.
So right here then you're good to press play.
Now find your jellyfish could be anywhere and it's right in front of me conveniently.
All right.
Now if I press on the jellyfish it gets removed and I should find another one.
Any other random location.
And there it is.
If I press on this it should make another one right here.
All right so you get the point.
So now in our storyboard we're going to add our timer label.
So go to the storyboard and right here on top drag it down a bit and remove the top constraint by giving
to this ruler symbol the size inspector and delete this constraint for now and add a UI view right on
top of our view controller.
You view put it right here on top drag its edges such that it matches that of the super view.
And drag it down a bit so that it doesn't interfere with the info bar put it 20 pixels from the top
or you know what 0 is fine zero to the leading zero to the trailing and give it a height of 50 pixels.
There seems to be a problem.
And the problem being is that I set the width as 50 not the height.
Make sure to set the height as 50
put the scene view 0 pixels from the bottom of the view.
And write in the view we're going to add a label or line the label inside of the view vertically and
horizontally.
Give the label a text of let's play.
So before the timer starts it's just going to have this playful text.
I'm going to give it a font of Avenir next since that's usually the good one to go with.
It just looks nice and a font size of 22.
You can give it any font size you want and we're good to go.
So open up the assistant editor and right to the top of the Wii controller connect the label with an
IBM let call the label timer connect it close to the assistant editor and back to the view controller
declare a variable timer.
Right on top of all the outlets are actually var timer is equal to each.
All right.
So we haven't imported our each framework yet.
So remember the framework we installed with cocoa pods we're about to use that right now.
So import each and then write var timer is equal to each one dot seconds.
All right so this timer is going to keep counting up by a 1 second.
It looks like these two variables are conflicting names.
So delete the IAB outlet go to the main storyboard.
Make sure you can link this label to what it was connected to before.
And back to the assistant editor.
I'm just going to rename this to be Taimur label
close to the assistant editor and back to the view controller.
Put this on top of all the outlets to avoid confusion and declare a variable count down.
So var count down is equal to 10 seconds.
Now in the bottom of your class.
Now first off this seems to be outside of your class.
So make sure that it's inside.
It doesn't really matter it's just cleaner for it to be that way.
And now in the bottom of your class right phunk set timer which takes a no argument and has no return
value.
When the user presses the play button we're going to make sure to call this function.
So inside of play right here just right self set timer inside of the function call self timer up perform.
OK so right here the timer is going to keep counting up by one second every time the timer counts up.
Second any block of code in here is going to get triggered this closure also has the return value of
next step.
I'll explain what that is in a bit.
So every time the timer counts up by a second decrement the countdown variable by minus 1.
So it's going to go from 10 9 8 etc..
Set the timer label self timer label that text is equal to whatever the countdown is.
But make sure it's the string value of the countdown.
So string self-doubt count down.
And now to get rid of this error discloser expect a return value the return value specifies to the timer.
What to do.
Every time it counts up.
So every time it counts up.
Second just keep counting and continue counting.
OK.
So we're in the up once I press play or the timer should start and it starts now there is a bug in this
and you'll find that once it reaches 0 2 1 0 and it keeps going down.
Now the problem is that in X code we just told them to keep continuing on.
Every time it counts of by a second we need it to stop at one point.
So right here right.
If self does count down is equal to zero.
Set the timer label 2 you lose.
So self timer label that text is equal to use.
So the idea is that if the user can't up a jellyfish before the ten seconds is up he loses.
Stop the timer by returning dot stop not returning return dot stop.
All right so this will not get called anymore because the count down reached zero.
Run the app
so press play the countdown starts and once it reaches zero you lose all right.
Now back to X code we need it such that if the user tabs on a jellyfish it restores the timer back to
10 seconds.
So I think we store a timer with no argument or return value and just reset the count down to 10 set
the timer label equal to the count down the string value of the countdown.
Call this function inside of Hendel tap right here.
So every time user taps on a jellyfish it's going to restore the timer to what it was.
Run the app
and I need to write self-torture storytime or since we're inside of a closure run the app so Press play.
The countdown starts.
Make sure to find your jellyfish before the timer runs out.
And if I tap on it the timer gets back to turn.
And now you have time to find your second one and you get the point.
All right so now that I lost.
Let me just find the other jellyfish which is right here now I need it so that if I lose I can't tap
this jellyfish and have it remove.
All right.
So you shouldn't be able to tap a jelly fish when you lose.
So and handle top make sure that nothing gets triggered unless the countdown is bigger than zero
otherwise do nothing.
OK so rerun the app.
Ok so press play and I'm actually just going to lose on purpose.
I am not going to tap this jellyfish and once it reaches zero if I start tapping on the jellyfish nothing
happens because the countdown is not bigger than zero it is zero indeed.
All right.
So this works perfectly.
Now since we lost I need to be able to reset the game in our recent IAB action when the user wants to
reset the game just start the timer.
And restore our count down by writing self we store timer Nabl the play button.
Self play is enabled is equal to true so that the user can play again.
And now we're going to remove the jellyfish from the scene view by writing scene view scene.
The SS capitalized that scene the root node innumerate child nodes.
The first argument is node leave this one blank and right here.
Just remove the node from the scene view from the parent node.
All right so run the app press play I'm going to tap on the first jellyfish.
Everything is fine.
Now if I wait 10 seconds
I lose the game.
And now I can just press reset and everything is back to normal and I can play again and I can even
reset the game as I'm already playing which is why I gave the option right here to stop the timer.
You've officially just made a small game with a market using notes textures and animations.
Now it's finally time to look up planes.
We'll do that in the next section.