In this video we're going to scale and rotate objects as they are in the scene view.
I need to start if I put my index finger and my thumb on the cup and I pinch words the cup would expand
to accomplish this in the View Controller in the function register just gesture recognizer declare a
pinch gesture recognizer let a bench gesture recognizer is equal to you I pinched just a recognizer
with Target's self and asked for the action declare a function pinch funk pinch with arguments sender
of type you I pinched just a recognizer and no return value.
Make the pinch function the auction of pens just a recognized by a writing selector Penge
selector is an objective argument so make sure that Penge is exposed to Objective C by just clicking
on fix and Raggatt add this pinch just a recognizer to the scene view by writing self does scene view
the gesture recognizer pinch gesture recognizer.
Now every time we print something the Pens just a recognizer it will send us information on what we
pinched in the form of a sender similar to how the tap gesture recognizer works.
So we know that whatever we pinched is inside of the market sink view.
So right last seen view is the pull to sender view as a see and view we need to get the location that
we pinched in the scene view by writing let Penge location is equal to sender that location inside of
the scene viewed that we Pinchon.
Now we need to do a hit test.
The test is going to check if your pinch location matches the location of an object in the scene.
The right let hit test is equal to seen view dart hit test bench location and we don't need any types
so if there is a cup and I pinch the cup the pinch location will match the location of the cups co-ordinates.
The hit test will be a success and this test array will get one element of results.
If I just pinch nothing in the scene view the hit test will fail and this test array will be empty.
So if hit test is empty and add the exclamation mark here to make sure that the statement says if the
test is not empty.
So if you actually punch something in the scene you get the results from the hit test by writing let
result is equal to hit test the first.
I hope this looks familiar to you.
Get the node from the result by writing the node is equal to.
Result.
Don't know who's going to rhenium this to results instead.
So this is the node that you pinched.
Now we need to scale the know that you pinched based on how far you're pinching it.
So right let pinch action is equal to see an action dot scale.
So the scale action changes at the scale of a node based on another value.
We're going to scale the know that we're pinching based on the sender does scale the center of that
scale is given to us by the Pens just to recognizer.
And it's the scale of what you're pinching the node.
If I pinched the node 1.5 metre at words the node is going to grow 1.5 metre outwards.
If I pinched the nose 0.5 metre inwards the node is going to shrink 0.5 metres and put the duration
is zero.
So basically as soon as I start the pinching gesture I want the node to grow or shrink immediately.
I don't want there to be any time in between for the note to grow or shrink according to how I'm pinching
it.
We need to give the node this option by writing node run action the hinge action
run the
wait till the world origin Loeb's right here is the world origin.
Now I'm going to place my phone right on top of a horizontal surface and wait till it detects the horizontal
surface.
I'm going to assume that it did just now.
So I'm going to press on cup tab on this surface.
The cup is displayed.
Now if I pinch outwards the cup just gets exponentially bigger.
This is not how it should be.
So let me explain this.
The more I pinch outwards the bigger the scale becomes.
I need the scale to be constant.
So back to X code to prove that that is indeed the case.
I'm going to print sender dot scale as we're scaling the cut going to rerun the
wait till the world origin loaves had just loaded pointed to a horizontal surface.
Way to let you touch it as a surface.
I'm going to assume it did just now so rest on the lay of the cup.
And if I start sizing it up I pinch outwards.
Notice the debugger.
So back to X code.
If I expand this a little bit.
Notice that the cup first starts growing 1 1 1 times bigger then it starts growing one point two times
bigger and then almost at one point three times bigger and it just keeps growing at an exponential rate.
We need it to grow at a constant rate.
So if it started growing at one point one it should remain growing at this rate the rate of growth should
not keep increasing.
To put the debugger down a little bit so we want it to grow at a constant rate not exponentially.
So as soon as you pinch it the first center does scale of value is about 1.1 1.0 way according to your
pinch your cup would grow at this point 1.0 eight times bigger.
But then make sure to set the standards scale right back to one.
As soon as it grew up so assuming the scale at first is 1.0 it's so D-cup would grow at a rate of 1.0
wait times its original size as you pinch out words the scale keeps increasing which makes sense since
the sender gives us a scale based on how we're pinching the gesture recognizer we want to reset the
scale back to 1.
We don't want the skill to keep getting bigger and bigger.
So once we reach a scale about 1 in the next atwork pinch the center of that scale is just going to
go back to its original scale or something very close to it.
So the cup will keep getting 1.0 eight times bigger every time.
And now our scale is constant.
So run up wait till the world origin shows up try and detect as much of the environment as you can before
it does.
Here is your world origin point your device to a horizontal surface.
I'm going to wait till it detects it assuming interested press on the display of that cup.
And now if I start scaling it it scales at a constant rate.
This is looking good but there is a bug.
Notice as I am scaling the cup the liquid inside the cup remains the same size.
This is not very good.
Go to your cup does scene.
And one thing to notice about the cup is that it's not made from only one node.
It's made from two different nodes.
So instead of scaling the entire cup we're only pinching the part of the cup that we're touching.
So combine these nodes into one node by flattening them so just press on flatten node and do the same
thing for the boxing bag since the boxing bag is made up of four nodes.
We don't want to pinch one cylinder at a time.
So right click on boxing and press on flattened the table and these are fine.
These are formed from one single node.
And as for the phase I've noticed that the vase has been looking a bit small from the previous lecture
change its scale from 0.1 to about 0.8 to that for what this is a bit hard to click on.
Do that for height and 0.8 for that the Vai's should be 0.8 times 0.5 metres wide 0.8 times zero point
six nine eight metres high and 0.8 times your post 6 1 7 meters deep.
OK.
Rerun the up wait till the phone to touch your environment and shows your world origin.
Once it does place the phone on the horizontal surface so that it can detect the plane I'm assuming
it just did so clicked on your cup and display there is your cup now a fine sized cup the liquid grows
along with the cup.
This is looking pretty good.
And now try putting the V's right on top of here and this is actually way too big.
I'm going to rescale it in the seam view.
But back to the scene file instead of zero point it just give it a scale of zero point five for every
single dimension.
Zero point five for height is 0.5 for the debt.
Rerun the app to see how this looks.
Wait till the world origin loads click on your vase and point to this horizontal surface once it detects
it as a surface.
Make sure to place your vase.
This looks pretty good.
This is how it should look like.
Now one more thing to note.
I've been finding it a bit annoying that I have to kind of guess every time the device detects a horizontal
surface.
I need some kind of indicator to tell me when the surface was detected.
So 2 X code in the main storyboard add a label on top of your scene if View buy a writing label add
it to the top line it horizontally and pin it to the top of your screen.
You buy zero pencils for the label give it a text of plain detected.
As for the font I'm going to choose a custom font of Avenir next if I can just find it.
It's right here.
And I'm also going to pull this font OK.
Press on done.
And lastly in the ads which Inspector.
Make sure that the label is hidden at first.
Open up the assistant editor connect the label to the controller with an IBM call the outlet plane detected
cannot close the assistant editor and back to the controller inherit from a r s c and you delegate and
let me just make the smaller it's a bit too big and and call the function did it right on the button.
Did I think so.
When we did the floor is lava you learn that this function gets called whenever an anchor is added to
the scene.
However if a plain anchor was added that means a horizontal surface was detected to check if the anchor
that was added is a plain anchor guard anchor is of type A plain anchor else return so if the anchor
is of type A plain anchor that was detected then unhide the detected plane.
So self detected Labem is hidden.
Is equal to false and after about three seconds.
So dispatch can main async after so after about three seconds from now now plus three.
Make sure to hide the one.
We don't want the label to show up forever cause we're going to be detecting other planes.
Now you call this delegate function.
Make sure to go to if you did load and write self does scene view that delegate is equal to self run
your app OK wait till the world origin loans and in the meantime try and detect as much of your environment
as possible.
There is your world origin point your phone to the horizontal surface once it detects the surface.
The label should show up going to keep moving my phone around
and the label never shows up.
Here is the reason this ad gets triggered on a background thread.
So we need to make sure that all of this happens on the main thread.
So make sure to call dispatch.
Q Does it mean that async and place all of this inside of your dispatch
rerun the
wait till your world orange and Lote's world orange and just floated point your phone to the horizontal
surface.
Wait let me touch it as a surface
and right here it says plane detected.
Perfect.
And it disappears after three seconds.
We know that the plane was detected.
So if I add up it should work.
There you go.
This is looking really good.
Now there is one more thing we have to do.
If I called the cops so if I press it for a long time I want the cup to rotate around itself.
OK.
So back to X code in your view controller in registered just recognizers we need a gesture recognizer
that detects when I'm pressing something for a long time when I'm holding it.
So right let a long press gesture recognizer is equal to you.
I long press just to recognizer with Target's self.
And as for the action make a function called rotate phunk rotate with arguments center of type you want
long press gesture recognizer and no return value.
Make that the action by going to your gesture recognizer and writing selector and the function that
will get called when you long press something is going to be rotate.
OK.
Now rotate is not exposed to Objective-C so we should get an error pretty soon.
The error shows up and it's telling us to expose it to Objective-C by clicking thicks.
And there you go.
Now add our gesture to this scene view just like we did before with every single other gesture by writing
software that scene view that gesture recognizer at Long press gesture writing Nizer.
OK.
So when I hold my finger on the scene view this function should get called inside of the function.
Right.
If gesture or inside of the function.
If sender does state is equal to begin.
So if I'm currently pressing somewhere in the scene view if I'm currently holding my finger somewhere
but a print statement of holding else if sender that state is equal to dot ended put a print statement
of a released finger.
I'm not holding my finger on the same view anymore.
Run the app to see if this works so.
So if I hold my finger on the View it prints holding and if I let go it prints or at least finger this
is looking good.
Now I'm going to add a cup to this horizontal surface.
Wait till the plane is detected.
Once my label shows up the plane was detected I had your cup and now I want it to start if I hold the
cup it rotates.
I explained this before but this is just from there minor.
So if your controller know that the scene view we're pressing on is an arcade scene.
So right last scene view is equal to sender.
Doug you as a market sink you I'm hoping that you're starting to notice the pattern between all these
wide gesture recognizers.
Anyway back to your road take gesture recognizer.
We need to get the location of where you're holding your finger by writing left fold.
Location is equal to sender in that location inside of the scene you
so great seeing you right here.
And now we need to check if the location where I'm holding my finger matches the location of an object
past the video and try to figure that one out.
So as we've done it twice before with the other gesture recognizers we need to do a hit test.
So right him test is equal to seen fume.
Don't hit test hold location.
This checks if the location where you're holding your finger matches the location of an object.
If it does the hit test array will have one element of results such that that element of results is
the first one the hit test will have one element of results.
Otherwise if the location where you're holding your finger does not match the location of any object
in the scene.
And the hit test will be empty.
So inside of your gesture recognizer if hit test is empty and your exclamation mark to make a bully
in shock of if hit test is not empty.
We're going to start rotating our node so right leg result is equal to hit.
Test the first remember that results are always the first element in the test.
Right.
Since we're not spending any other results there's only one get the note from the results by writing
node is equal to result.
Darton code we want to rotate the Snoad with an LCN action.
So when we're building the object one more pressing on it right like action is equal to SC and action
rotate by the X is going to be left as your.
And as for the y value we're going to rotate the note 360 degrees around itself.
But you need this to be ingredients this extension is inside of your resources folder.
We've used it many times before and we're about to use that again to convert degrees 360 degrees tradition's.
As for these add value we're not going to rotate clockwise so make sure this is zero and the duration.
So it's going to take a note about 1 second for it to rotate around itself.
We're going to make sure that this rotation we just call this rotation.
So we're going to make sure that this rotation last forever by writing forever is equal to se an action
that repeat forever rotation.
If you're confused about CNA actions make sure to visit the planet section of this course and we have
a bug which is telling us to convert our values to C.G. float.
Fair enough.
And now right now and you know what.
Just directly apply the animation to result in no.
So delete this.
So right result that node Dot run action forever.
So we just find this forever rotation to the know that we're holding.
So here's a summary by I long press on any node.
The test succeeds and the node rotates forever.
However when I release the node.
So when I take my finger off make sure to start the animations by writing result that node remove all
actions ok delete the Prince came in it was just for a demonstration purposes and run the
wait till the world origin loads try and detect as much of your environment as possible as it's floating.
Here is my world origin and if I point this phone to this on the surface I'm going to wait till my label
shows up here's my signal add your cup.
Now if I hold the cup
the cup starts rotating.
This is pretty awesome.
OK.
There is one more thing to do.
It kind of took a while for it to start rotating.
I can control this by going to X code.
And into your gesture recognizers and the right long press just recognizer minimum press duration is
equal to 0.1.
So 0.1 seconds after I first touch the cup it should start rotating.
OK wait till your world origin shows up trying to take as much of the environment as possible.
There is a world origin right behind us and if I point to this horizontal surface.
Wait till the label shows up to give me the signal that we're good.
It just did add your cup.
Now if I hold the cup everything works fine.
There is a bug however if I rotate the table it doesn't rotate around itself.
To explain this go in X code.
And here is what's up.
For example the cup is rotating around a pivot point.
This is the pivot point right here.
These arrows the pivot point is positioned exactly where the cup is.
So the cup is basically rotating around itself.
As for the table for example the pivot point and the table are located in different locations so the
table will not rotate around that self it rotates around the pivot points location.
We need to position the pivot point exactly where the table is so that the table rotates around itself.
Unfortunately we can't physically position it in the interface builder X code doesn't allow it but we
can do it with code.
So into your view controller this function is inside of your resources folder.
It centers the pivot point exactly where your node is about Make sure to copy this function into your
view controller and into an item when we're first adding that table right after you position your node.
If the node your positioning as a table.
So if selected item is equal to table make sure the pivot point is centered around your table saw itself
does center pivot node run the ones I detect you surface.
Make sure to add your table.
There is a table now five table it rotates around itself not around another position.
Now it's hard to see because the table was perfectly around and it's a uniform black color.
But the bug is actually gone.
Finally there is one last thing I want to add to this app which is lighting by writing self scene view.
Auto enables default lighting is equal to true since lighting just makes everything look better in general
by providing an omni directional light in all directions of the scene if you run the app OK now now
is finally complete.
You learn how to effectively hit test and place objects onto horizontal surfaces.
And add many gesture recognizers such as scaling and rotating in the next section we're going to apply
all our knowledge and make it pretty cool game with planes and surfaces.