In this video we're going to position node's relative to other notes the main theme behind the lecture
will be parent nodes and child nodes.
So let me just remove all of this.
We don't need this code anymore and simply position the pyramid relative to the root node.
So right now the pyramid is a child of the root node.
And as you know from before the root node is basically a node That's position exactly where the world
origin is.
And since the pyramid is a child of the root node it's going to be positioned relative to the node.
So now position the pyramid about is there a point two metres to the right of the root node about 0.3
metres above it and negative zero point two metres behind it.
And your challenge is to try and place a cylinder zero point three metres to the left of the pyramid
point two meters above and point three metres behind it paused the video and give it a try.
So first off just declare your cylinder node cylinder node is equal to see a node the node is going
to have a geometry of n s c and cylinder with a radius.
I'm going to give it a small radius of zero point zero five meters and a height of five centimeters
as well.
Going to give the cylinder a diffuse color of red.
Remember that diffuse is the color that spread across the surface of a node.
You like color dark red and the challenge was to place the cylinder zero point three meters to the left
point two meters above and point three meters behind the pyramid.
So right cylinder node up position is equal to A C and vector 3 and so to place the cylinder zero point
three meters to the left of the pyramid.
Here's what you would do you would see that hey the pyramid is 0.3 metres to the right of the world
origin.
So a fireplace the cylinder node is 0.1 metres to the left of the root node.
It will be 0.3 metres to the left of the pyramid.
So if you put in negative 0.1 here and position the cylinder note relative to the root node by just
copying and pasting this and putting your solar node.
So by positioning our cylinder point 1 metres to the left of the root node it will be point three meters
to the left of the pyramid.
Now we wanted to position the cylinder zero point two meters above the pyramid node.
And so by placing the cylinder is 0.5 metres above the root node it will be 0.2 metres above the pyramid
node and we wanted to place zero point three meters behind that pyramid.
And so by placing the cylinder node 0.5 metres behind the scene of use root node that it will be 0.3
metres behind the pyramid node.
So this was a bit complex we had to do some math to position the cylinder node relative to the pyramid.
So let's run the app to see if this worked out.
Just going to wait till my world origin loads and as soon as it does add my nodes
our cylinder is there a point 3 meters to the left of the pyramid zero point two meters above it.
As you can clearly see and it's also behind by point three meters.
Now what if I told you we could have done this in a much easier way.
So the initial challenge was to place the cylinder node zero point three meters to the left of the pyramid
node.
So why not just write in negative 0.3.
So Point 3 meters to the left and now to place it 0.2 meters above.
Why not just raise 0.2.
And if you want to place it 0.3 metres behind the pyramid node wind up putting negative 0.3.
How will this work.
For example if the cylinder node is positioned 0.3 metres to the left of the root node then it's not
0.3 metres to the left of the pyramid it would be both 0.5 metres to the left of it.
What if I told you we don't have to position the cylinder node relative to the root node by making the
cylinder node A child of the pyramid node.
So by writing node our child node cylinder or node the cylinder is now positioned relative to the pyramid.
So now this should work.
The cylinder should be 0.3 meters to the left of the pyramid point two meters above it and point three
meters behind it.
This was much easier than doing all that math.
So run the app to see if this works so just going to wait till the world orange and loads
and it works out perfectly.
And this was a lot easier.
And doing all that math
what I want you to take from all this is that at first the cylinder node was a child of the scene views
the root node and so to position the cylinder relative to the pyramid we had to do some pretty annoying
calculations.
However once we made the cylinder a child of the pyramid then whatever position we gave the cylinder
was relative to the pyramid.
Having done that it was much easier to position the cylinder zero point three meters to the left of
the pyramid.
Zero point two meters above and 0.3 metres behind it.
As you can see it took no calculations whatsoever.
All you had to do is declare it.
So now using relative positioning we're going to make a custom shape.
So instead of a cylinder No declare a box node with a geometry of an S C and box.
The box will have a whit of 0.1 metres a height of 0.1 metres any length of 0.1 metres as well.
Will they chamfer a radius of zero wherever it's still in their node or replace that with box node instead.
And instead of giving the box a color of red give it a color of blue.
Whereas the pyramid will have a color of red and yellow now the plan is to position this box right under
the pyramid to make a house shape.
So how do I place the box node right under the house.
Well let me start off with a default position of 0 0 0 and see what this looks like.
So if I just wait till the world orange and loans and as soon as it loads your supposed House and this
didn't work out so well here's my assumption.
It looks like the center of the box is positioned at the bottom of the pyramid and from the bottom of
the pyramid half of the box extends upwards.
And I can also conclude that the box is 10 centimeters long.
So if the center of the box is at the bottom of the pyramid and the distance between the center of the
box to the top is five centimeters.
If I place the box five centimeters downwards then the top of the box should be at the bottom of the
pyramid which is exactly what we need for us to form a house.
We need the top to be at the bottom of the pyramid.
So give this a try right now up position is equal to negative zero point zero five meters so five centimeters
downwards.
If I do this the top of the box should be at the bottom of the pyramid.
Now to get comfortable with positioning relative to other nodes it's basically just trial and error.
Start off with a default position like what I just had before is 0 0 and 0 make a conclusion with what
you saw in that default position and then fix that position accordingly.
We fixed that by placing the box five centimeters downwards.
Let's see if that worked.
Run up
if I press add and there is our house at the top of the box is right under the pyramid as I predicted.
Now what if I wanted to give the walls a door back to the school project.
Stop running me up in the right let door know is equal to see a node with a geometry of an S C and plane.
We looked at planes in the last lecture and we determined that planes are simply flat vertical surfaces.
So give the plane a width of about three centimeters and a height of six centimeters.
This should be a fair size.
Give the door node A color of brown.
So a door no door geometry the first material that diffused memory and the fuse is the color that spread
across the surface of a node.
We're giving that surface a color of brown
so I want to place the door node at the edge of the box where positioning the door relative to the box.
So what's the next step be.
Pause the video and give this one a try.
So I'm hoping you did the following.
Since we're positioning the door relative to the box make the door a child of the box so the box no
child node door node.
So now we want to place the door at the edge of the box.
First let me start off by giving the door node a random position.
So a door no doubt position is equal to C-n vector 3 0 0 0.
I didn't even put any thought into this.
And let me just run the app to see what this looks like at the moment.
So just wait till the world origin and loads and as soon as the world origin loads let me add my house
and you can't even see the plane.
The door was even added to the scene view.
Well it was.
It's just that the box node and the pyramid node they both have a coordinate system that's exactly in
their center.
So inside of the box node right at the center there is a co-ordinate system and we aligned that door
node perfectly with the coordinate system of the box 0 meters away from it.
And so since the door node is exactly at the center of the box.
First off we can conclude that the box has a depth of 10 centimeters.
So if the door node is exactly at the center of the box then that means that the door is 5 centimeters
away from the edge.
How did I conclude this.
While the box node has a depth of 10 centimeters and so that could only mean that the distance between
the center of the box to the edge is five centimeters.
So if I place the door node 5 centimeters away from the center of the box it should be right at the
edge.
Run the app.
If I just wait till the world origin loads and then add my house
the door node is 500 metres away from the center of the box which puts it right at the edge.
The reason why the door node is acting this way is because it is right at the edge of the box.
We need to place a little bit in front of the edge so that it stops interfering with the edges of the
box node instead of 0.05.
Place it a little bit in from the edge.
So put zero point zero five three or something three millimeters away from the edge.
And we should be good to go.
So if I just wait till the world origin load and then I add my house there it is.
Our door is right in front of our box about three millimeters away.
And now I can conclude that vertically the center of the node is vertically aligned with the center
of the box.
And so if I go back to my X code so the box node has a height of 10 centimeters so the distance from
the center of the box node to the bottom edge should be 5 centimeters the door node center is perfectly
aligned with the center of the box node.
So the distance from the center of the door node to the bottom edge of the box node is also 5 centimeters.
And so from the center of the box node the door node extends downwards by three centimeters.
So if I just do 5 centimeters and minus three I can conclude that the bottom of the door node is 2 centimeters
away from the bottom edge of the box node.
So if I move the door node downwards by 2 centimeters it should be right at the bottom edge of the box
and I moved it down 20 centimeters it should be 2 centimeters.
So let me run the app to see what this looks like.
If I just wait till the world orders and loads and then add my house.
There you go the door node is positioned right at the bottom edge of our house.
The last thing I can tell you is to be comfortable with making custom shapes with relative positioning.
You just have to keep practicing first.
It's going to be a game of trial and error but eventually you'll get the hang of it.
So if you want to make more custom shapes with the relative positioning.
Always start with a default position which in our case we used a default position at first of 0 0 0
0 and then from that position make conclusions on how you need to modify the position to get the custom
shape that you want.
And that is it for a relative positioning in the next video we're going to look at rotations.