In the last video you saw how there were never seen delegate worked in this video we're going to pinpoint
the current position of the camera relative to the real world.
Every time the renderer delegate gets called so every time the delegate gets called you need the current
position of the camera since it is at that point in the scene that you will be drawing.
So we need to extract the current location and orientation of the camera every time the delegate gets
called.
So inside the delegate function you need the point of view of the scene view to get that guard let the
point of view is equal to seeing a view point of view or else return.
So we just unwrapped it safely using a guard statement.
And the point of view contains the current location and orientation of the camera view.
However the location and orientation are encoded inside of the point of view any transform matrix to
get the transform matrix.
You need to write let transform is equal to the point of view transform.
Now from the transform extract the current orientation of your camera by writing left orientation is
equal to SDN vector 3 0 0 and 0.
I remember from before as vector 3 represents a three dimensional vector with x y and Zed fields.
The orientation is always encoded in the transform matrix such that it's in the third column.
So for the field X right transform and three this takes us to the third column in The Matrix then right
the number one.
Now you're in the third column of The Matrix the transform matrix row 1.
So what you should get from this is that the orientation of the x value of the camera the horizontal
orientation is located in the third column of the transform matrix.
Row 1 now the Y field of the orientation is located in the row.
Number two of column 3 and the Zad field is in column 3 row 3.
So for the Y field right transform dot and three to column three wrote.
And for the that field right transform dot and 3:03 column three row three.
Now you need the current location of the camera so the location just like orientation is a three dimensional
vector.
It has an X Y and Z field.
So right let location is equal to CN vector 3 0 0 and 0.
Now the location for the X field is located in column 4 row one of the transform matrix.
So transform M for one the location for the Y field is located in column 4 wrote 2 and the Xat field
column for row 3.
So you should have gone the following transform
it and for you and transform it.
M. 4:03 column for wrote two in column for 03.
So right let current position of camera is equal to orientation plus location.
This doesn't work.
It gives an error.
The error is that the binary operator plus cannot be applied between two C and vector or three values.
You need to modify this binary operator such diets able to add these to C and vector or three types.
So outside of the class write a function plus to modify the plus operator that takes in two three dimensional
vectors.
The first one the left hand side of type C and vector are three and another one of type A C undoctored
3 with a return value of a three dimensional actor as well.
So now the binary operator is able to take in to see an vector of three types.
Notice that the error here goes away.
Now we need a return value such that when these two are added it gives us their combined value.
So return I see n vector 3 make.
So we're basically making a new 3D vector.
The x field of that new vector will be the combination of the X fields of the orientation and location.
So right left X plus or right dot x.
So you're adding the X field of your orientation plus the X field of your location the Y field of our
new vector will be the combination of the y fields of your orientation and location.
So once again left out y plus right why the same thing will happen first.
So left does Zad plus right.
Does your combining Zad value orientation plus the Zad value of your location.
However before we proceed.
Print the X Y and Z fields of the orientation variable.
So print orientation X orientation dot Y and orientation dot set and run the app.
The rule of thumb is if I orient my phone to the right so if I rotated to the right the X orientation
should be positive.
Notice in the debugger it's continuously negative.
If I orient my phone up the Y orientation should be positive.
So the orientation is reversed and reverse by making everything in the orientation negative.
So what's continuously negative will now be continuously positive.
Run the up.
Make sure to look at the debugger as I test this.
Wait for the world origin to load.
Go to the right the x value increases in the positive direction go up the y axis and the y value grows
in the positive direction as well.
Now you're finally ready to draw it in 3D.
You'll do that in the next video.