Hello everyone this is a brand from the future.
I am pleased to announce the top three kit apps that were submitted this month by students of the course.
The first thing I want to present is the A-R kick drum where you can actually display a drum in a cam
or a view of the real world and play it by tapping or swinging your phone.
You can choose between 13 presets of kick drums and customize options like bass treble echo and reverb.
This is very cool.
The next stop I want to show you is the hied messed up made by Jullian where you can create funny messages.
Your message will stay exactly where you left it for other users to see it through their app.
I have to say this is a very unique idea and I absolutely love the concept of drawing murals with other
people who have the app.
This is a great use.
Of course location to actually have a drawing persist in a GPS location of the world and also a great
use of actually putting your 3D nodes on a database that can be observed by other users.
Great job Julian.
And the last one my personal favorite ghost hunt A-R which was released by Jeff Brown the sap I have
to say is extremely well done.
This is a perfect implementation of the last section of the course where we learn how to detect contact
between a bullet and a target.
But clearly Jeff Brown went above and beyond in creating his 3D models.
And so once again the OP's her ghost hunt hide message and A-R kick drum.
I found those to be the top three jobs that were submitted this month and I'm very impressed with what
you guys have come up with.
I wish you the best of luck.