In this video we're going to set up the user interface of our idea in the app.
You can place household objects on top of any horizontal surface like a table or a floor
to start open up code create in your project a single view application.
Call the project Ikea press next and create the first thing to do and that we have always done is go
to the man that storyboard and to The View Controller.
This time we're going to add a collection view to the bottom of the initial controller.
We're going to expand the collection view very close to the bottom of the super view and pin it to the
bottom leading trailing space with a height of 75 pixels press on the collection tag.
Go to the size inspector and give the collection to you.
So a one of a hundred and twenty and the height of 50.
Make sure every cell is space 30 pixels from one another.
So minimum spacing per cells will be 30 pictures and having said that the first cell is 20 pixels from
the leading edge.
So 20 from the left click on the cell itself go to the attributes inspector click on backgrounds and
add a tangerine color.
You are so add a label to the cell by writing label dragged to the middle of the song and align it horizontally
and vertically and the two constraints the label is going to refer to the household item you're going
to display in the camera view.
So in the attributes inspector write item
and make the scrolling direction of the collection due to the horizontal.
We are going to scroll horizontally through the collection of the arcade sync view is where we are going
to add our items.
So add an arcade seem to you to our Wii controller.
Expand it to the edges of the suit or you
pin it to the top leading trailing and you're right above the collection DuSable 0 right here.
Open up the assistant editor link the arcade sync view to the Wii controller with an IBM CVM
make an outlet for the collection as well by linking this one called the outlet items collection.
Import our kit to use the arcade framework close the assistant editor and back to the Wii controller.
Declare a constant configuration equal to eight our world tracking session.
Vigorish world tracking is used to track the position and orientation of the device at all times.
Run a session with that configuration by writing self dust's scene view session run in figuration add
debug options by writing self-taught scenes you debug option is equal to an array type of debug options
are SDN debug options we're going to show the world origin and we're also going to show feature points
and another step that we've always done before going to the input Up-Hill list and declare a property
privacy Cameron's description.
This property becomes the user to enable the camera with an alert give the alert a descriptive message
by writing you need the camera to display cool stuff.
Now run the app to see if everything works will enable the camera wait for the world origin to show
up in their ads.
So everything works fine but we need to get the collection you some values to give the collection some
logic we need delegate functions.
So back to our controller to get all the delegate functions we need have the controller inherit from
UI collection is you data source
lecturing you in a source now that we inherited from this data source we can access data source functions
such as number of items in actually the return value of this function will be how many cells of the
collections you displays the memory cells are equal how many items we are going to display.
So make an item Zurek let items array with an array type of string inside of it we're going to display
a cup a vase a boxing bag so just right.
Boxing and a table
return the count of the items Theresienstadt the number of items in the array will equal how many cells
will be displayed in the collection.
The return and radar camps now right.
So for item index sell for item inducts path is a data source function that configures every single
cell in the collection.
You declare a cell by writing let's sell the go to collection view that dequeue reusable identifier
where the reduced identifier we need to give our cell and identifier first before we proceed with this.
So into the main storyboard click on your cell and right here for the identifier field just write item
copy the identifier into cell for item and for index if you're unfamiliar with collection use.
Here is how this works.
The reusable cell simply returns a cell type based on the identifier item.
Since this cell has that identifier we're going to be using this cell specifically and for the index
path there are going to be four cells in the collection view according to the return value and number
of items in section.
The index path simply your first you would sell out of the.
We're going to be configuring.
It is a path to each step.
So returning the cell to get rid of this error but before returning it go to the main storyboard to
access this label in our cell for itan section.
You need to make a new file make the file Kokoo touch class of type you eye collection cell
call the class items sell snacks and creep's back to the main storyboard assign the cell to the class
item so
now open up the assistant editor navigate to your subclass by clicking on the assistant editor or symbol
go to manual I yet again.
And two items sell and link the item label to our islands or class by calling it item label in the outlet
now and sell for item downcast the sell to be item so as item.
So now we can access the item label by writing sell the item label or it isn't working right now.
That tax is equal to self.
The items around index Dutrow.
So here's how this works.
Assume the index path is pointing to the second cell in the collection.
The second cell will have the second element in the items around.
So the item label for that cell is going to equal this.
The index path that I wrote for the fourth cell is going to have the fourth element in the items array.
So the label for that cell will say table.
Now these functions are from the data source so to activate these data source functions set the data
source to the cells so self that collection view or items collection for that matter the data source
is equal to run the app and our collection of view works fine.
Now every time I press on.
So I wanted to highlight a green color inherit from you.
I collection's you delegate
by inheriting from this delegate class we can access the function did select either
select item gets triggered whenever you select a certain show declared the cell that you clicked on
by writing so is equal to collection view.
Sulfur item index pass the index path.
As I mentioned before indicates which shell you clicked on whether its the first second or third so
and give that cell that you clicked on a color green by writing SELP background color is equal to you
like color dark green.
Call this delegate function right.
Self items collection you that delegate is equal the cells run me app.
If I click on a vase it highlights the green.
If I click on cut that highlights the green as well.
I need it to start if I touch another shell.
The first one should go back to orange back to X code right.
The function did de-select item in x.
Basically if I click on one cell and then click on another the first cell you clicked on is de-selected
and the function gets triggered for that so.
So the clear the cell that you de-selected by just copying and pasting the following and it shut that
cell to orange so that background color is equal to UI color.
Dark orange
run the press days and then if I press boxing Vai's was de-selected and it was turned into an orange
color.
So everything works fine.
And now that were done setting up the user interface we can finally get to the fun part which is placing
items on horizontal surfaces.
We'll do that in the next video.