The last video you were able to set up world tracking system.
The phone always knows its position and orientation as well as its starting position.
In this video you're going to display a box in the physical world such that it's positioned zero point
three meters away from the starting position the world origin.
So first off go to the main storyboard and to the initial of controller add a button to the bottom left.
Call the button add and pin it to the bottom left by about 20 pixels from the leading space and from
the bottom space with a width and height of about 80 pixels before constraints.
And I seem to have placed the height of 800 where I should have placed 80 instead.
Let me just fix that in my size inspector and it looks good.
Now back to my attributes.
Inspector let me place a background color of white OK.
Open up the assistant editor and link your button to The View Controller with an IAB action called the
IAB action and make sure it's an action not an outlet connect the action.
Close the assistant editor and back to your view controller.
This I.B. action gets triggered every time you press the button.
So every time you press it declare a node by writing letter node is equal to C and
so a node is simply a position in space.
It has no shape no size and no color.
Put the node inside of the scene view by writing self seeing view does see a root node child node node.
So the scene is what's displaying the camera view of the real world.
We want to position our node inside of the scene.
So this scene has a root node the root node also has no shape no size or color and it's positioned exactly
where your world origin is.
So exactly where your starting position is if you make this node A child of the root node then whatever
position we give this node it's going to be positioned relative to the root node.
OK so now the node is inside of the scene.
And as I mentioned before the node is not visible on its own it's it has no special attributes.
We need to give it those attributes.
So first give it a shape by writing node that geometry is equal to A C and box with a width height and
length of 0.1 metres and the chamfer radius is simply howl around the edges of your box or the higher
the value the rounder The edges will play with this in the future.
But for now I'm just going to leave it as zero.
So by giving this a value of zero the box will have firm edges because I'm telling the node to take
away 0 meters from the edges.
Therefore don't take anything away from the I just leave it for now you should give the node A color
to do the right node dot geometry dot first material first material defines the appearance of the surface
of our node of our box.
For that matter I know right.
Diffuse the fuse represents the color that spread across the entire surface of our box.
I'm going to give it a color of blue.
So dark content's is equal to you white color dark blue.
Feel free to give it any color that you want.
So now you gave the Snoad a shape.
It's a box with dimensions of 0.1 meters and no chamfer radius.
It's going to be a firm box.
And you also gave the node a color that spread across its surface a color of blue.
The note is also inside of our scene's camera view.
You're only missing one thing.
The node sure is inside of the scenes camera view.
But where is it positioned.
That's right nowhere.
You need to specify the position of the node for going into this.
Let me just run the map and show you something.
So let me just wait till the phone recognizes its surroundings.
And as soon as it does the world origin should load.
And here is the world origin.
Remember how I said that the world origin your starting position is actually a coordinate system.
While it is the red line you see right here is the x axis the horizontal axis and the green line is
the y axis the vertical axis.
The blue line right here you see is the Zed axis which refers to depth.
How far or how close something is to the origin to the starting position in words or outwards.
So back to X code we're going to position our node relative to the root node relative to the starting
position.
So right node position is equal to a C and vector 3 0 0 and 0 C and vector 3 represents a three dimensional
vector.
We need a three dimensional vector.
Since the nodes position is based on three axes the x y and z axes This represents the x value y value
and your side value.
So according to what we have right now I will root node is going to be 0 metres away from the x axis
0 meters above the y axis and 0 meters from the said axis.
So basically I were node should be perfectly aligned with our starting position.
Run the up to see if that's the case.
So if I just wait till the phone discovers the area and as soon as it does the world origin loads.
Now where do you think the box will be placed.
If I press add.
That's right the box gets placed exactly where your starting position is since that's what we meant
to do.
We placed zero meters from the X-axis zero meters from the Y and zero meters from the Zad making it
perfectly aligned to our starting position.
So now back to X code.
What if I were to give the field a value of negative 0.3.
What will happen is the box will be zero point three meters away from the origin behind it behind it
since we added a negative.
If we took off the negative the node would be zero point three meters in front of the world origin.
Run up.
Let me just wait till the device detects its environment and the world orange loads.
And right here is the world origin.
Now if I press.
What do you think happens.
And there you go.
The box is placed in zero point three meters 30 centimeters from the world origin.
Now if you look at the blue line like I said before that is these that axis and the said axis controls
how far or how close something is to the world origin.
And it's pointing away from the box meaning that the box is indeed behind these that axis by 30 centimeters.
Now here's a challenge.
Try and have the box be 30 centimeters so 0.3 meters in front of the world origin not behind but in
front and below zero point two meters above give it a try
so here's what you would do 0.3 meters in front of these access that would just be a positive value
for 0.3.
And if you want to place something above or below the world origin what you would have to do is change
the y value.
We're going to position relative to the y axis.
So two places are point two metres above the origin just put zero point two for the field and you should
be get to go run the app so I'm just going to wait till the phone detect its environment and as soon
as it does the world origin should load right here.
And if I press.
Where do you think the box will be placed.
So zero point two meters above the y axis and zero point three meters from the blue line in front of
it.
And there is Auerbach's zero point two meters above the y axis and zero point three meters in front
of the blue line the z axis.
Now try and place the box zero point two meters to the right of the world origin.
Pause the video and give this one a try.
So I believe the challenge was to place the box 0.3 meters to the right.
And what's responsible for horizontal alignment is the x axis.
So if you want to place something to the right or to the left of the world origin you have to change
this X field to place something to the right.
The value would be positive to put something to the left the value would be negative.
We want to place it to the right.
So just leave this as a positive and run up.
So as I'm running the app according to this the box should be 0.3 meters to the right 0.2 meters above
and zero point three meters in front of the world origin.
So let me just wait till the world orange and loads while it's detecting its environment.
And I think it just floated right here.
So if I add my box here is what should happen.
The box should be zero point three meters to the right of the world origin.
So let me move to the right zero point two meters above the y axis.
The green line so goes zero point two meters above.
And now if by five point my film is such that it's looking 0.3 meters to the front of the Zad axis.
There is Auerbach's.
So here is your next challenge.
Try and place the box zero point three meters to the left of the world origin zero point two meters
below and zero point five meters behind it.
Pause the video and give this one a try.
I believe the challenge was 0.3 meters to the left and what controls horizontal alignment is our X field.
So putting negative zero point three since it's to the left and what controls the vertical alignment
is our y axis the green line put in negative 0.2 for that once it's going to be below with the vertical
y axis and zero point three meters behind that axis.
Just put a negative 0.3 for this.
Actually I believe it was 0.5.
The challenge was OK so run the app.
Ok so let me just wait until the device has a good read on its environment.
As soon as it does the world origin loads.
And now if I press add the box should be 0.3 meters to the left of the X-axis 0.2 meters below the y
axis.
And look at 0.5 meters behind that axis right there.
And that's it for positioning nodes.
And the next video.
Let's look at resetting a scene view session.