In this video we're going to rotate planets relative to the sun.
So in X code we're going to have the sun rotate 360 degrees around that so do that by writing action
is equal to see an action rotate by with arguments x y set and duration.
Now this is a view but remember that rotating around the X gives a vertical rotation around the Y gives
the horizontal rotation and around the said gives a clockwise or taken.
We're not going to rotate the sun vertically so we've got a zero.
We're going to rotate it 360 degrees horizontally around the y axis or right here right 360 degrees
to radians and convert that to LCG float to avoid an air.
As for these value we are not going to erode the sun clockwise so eat that as Europe.
Now how fast the sun will rotate around that cell will be eight seconds.
Make sure this action lasts forever by writing forever is equal to see in action.
Got repeat forever.
And the action we're going to be forever is the rotation across the y axis.
Action now to activate the forever action right Sun Run action forever.
So the sun was just given this action such that it repeats forever.
All right.
Now before I run the out it's important to note that the sun is the parent node of both Earth and Venus.
And if you remember from before and the Getting Started section in the lecture on rotation if I rotate
the parent node a certain angle around the y axis horizontally then the child node as it needs to preserve
its relative orientation to the parent node is also going to rotate horizontally around the parent node.
So what we should observe is the sun rotating 360 degrees around itself and the planets rotating 360
degrees around the sun.
If you're confused as to why that is.
Make sure to revisit the rotation lecture in the Getting Started section for more info.
So run the app
and so the sun rotates 360 degrees around itself.
And Venus and Earth rotate 360 degrees around the sun although realistically it takes much longer for
the Earth to rotate around the sun than Venus.
And yet in this demonstration they're both rotating around the sun at the same rates.
So back to Mexico it takes eight seconds for the sun to rotate around itself.
And since Earth and Venus are children of the sun it will take them both 8 seconds to rotate around
the sun as well.
So the solution is to make Earth and Venus children of two different nodes so make two notes.
The first one.
Let earth parent is equal you see and know.
And the second one let Venus parents is also equal to an C.A..
So we're not going to give these notes a geometry or anything.
We only need them so that we can give Earth and Venus different speeds of rotation and earth parent
to the scene.
View by just copying and pasting this line of code and instead of sun.
Just what you are there and do the same thing for Venus.
So just copy paste this and it is now in the scene view for Earth parent.
Make sure its position is exactly that of the sun so Earth parent position is equal to seeing that your
3 0 0 and negative 1.
So we're putting the earth parents exactly where the sun is which makes sense since we have to give
the illusion that Earth is positioned around the sun even though it's going to be positioned around
the Earth parent.
So do the same thing for the Venus parent.
So just copy this line of code instead of parent copying Venus.
So make Earth a child node of Earth parent instead by replacing the sun with Earth parents and do the
same thing for Venus make Venus a child of Venus.
So now earth is one point two meters to the right of the earth parents.
However earth parent is positioned exactly where the sun is so it will look like Earth is actually one
point two metres to the right of the sun and the same thing for Venus and Venus where it is also positioned
exactly where the sun is so it will look like Venus is actually 0.7 metres away from the sun.
So run the app
and notice that Venus and Earth are not rotating around the sun any more and that's because they're
not children of the sun.
There are children of Earth parent and Venus parents earth parent and Venus parent are invisible nodes
since we gave them no geometry.
They are located exactly where the sun is basically inside the sun.
So if fire rotate or Haret and Venus parents around the y axis horizontally are children Venus and Earth
should rotate around their parents horizontally as well.
So back to X code.
Let earth parents.
A rotation is equal to see an action does rotate by an it's not going to rotate across the x axis.
It's going to rotate horizontally around the y axis 360 degrees.
It will not rotate clockwise and the duration of this rotation will be about 14 seconds.
So the Earth parent will take 14 seconds to rotate around itself.
Now as for the Venus rotation just copy and paste this.
Replace the name with Venus and instead of it taking 14 seconds to rotate around itself it will take
Venus 10 seconds.
So for both parents they will rotate 360 degrees around themselves.
However the Earth parent rotation is going to rotates slower than Venus or rotation.
It's going to be 4 seconds longer.
And since Earth and Venus are both rotating around their parents Venus or O.T. faster around its parent
than Earth.
Well and since both parents are positioned exactly where the sun is you can say that Venus will rotate
around the sun faster than Earth which is what we intended to do from the start.
So have both rotations last forever by writing love forever.
Earth is equal to LCN action.
Rotate repeat forever.
Earth's rotation
do the same thing for the Venus per rotation by copying and pasting this.
Call that forever Venus and Venus and our wrote Richard no.
Make sure to run these rotations by writing or
a run action forever or SUNO the parent will rotate forever and the same thing for Venus right Venus
parents don't run auction or I heard Miss
OK.
Now run the
and notice how Venus is going around the sun faster than earth is all right now.
Here's a challenge.
Try giving one moon for the earth and one moon for Venus.
Make sure the moon surface is this texture and try to make it such that the moon rotates around each
planets paused the video and try to
download the moon texture.
Show it in Finder.
And in your assets folder add an image called Milman diffuse.
Minimize this and add the moon Yunji into your assets folder and back to your view controller source
file I'll make a new planet node so the moon isn't exactly a planet but we're going to use this function
just because it's convenient.
So that Moon is equal to planets give it age country of a sphere with a radius of zero point zero five
meters so five centimeters he diffused would be the fuse that we just drive into are us older.
We don't have any specular images nor do we have emission or normal and give it a position of zero point
three meters away from the earth and do the same exact thing for the Venus Moon and this should be CNN.
Right now I see a doctor and a moon here just right in unison so this will be positioned relative to
the earth.
This will position relative to Venus so may each moon hate child of its respective planet by writing
Earth dot and child no moon and venus dot child node Venus mirror all right.
Now we need to go to each moon around its planet.
We've done this a million times because if you rotate the parents of certain angle horizontally the
child will rotate around the planet at the same angle.
So let earth rotation
is equal to SC and action.
Rotate byme rotate the earth is 0 around the X-axis 360 degrees horizontally around the y axis and we
are not going to rotate at all.
Why so 0 and give it any duration you want.
I am going to choose 8 seconds.
Do the same exact thing for Venus rotation.
It doesn't matter how fast any of them rotate.
So to make sure that the rotations last forever just right love forever.
Earth's rotation is equal to.
I see an action that repeats forever.
Earth's rotation do the same exact thing or the Venus rotation and just change this to forever.
Venus rotation
and replace Earth's rotation with this.
Now run these auctions by writing Earth run action forever.
Earth rotation
Venus don't run option forever.
Venus rotation.
So Earth will rotate around itself.
And since the Earth Moon is a child of earth the earth moon will rotate around the Earth itself.
The same thing will happen for Venus and its moon.
So you know what.
I'm not a big fan of the way things are at the moment.
We seem to be repeating these functions a lot.
So to avoid this make a function called rotation that takes an a time interval and returns the action
for us instead of always having to write it over and over.
And so copy one CNI action and one forever action.
And instead of these custom names just call them the generic rotation and forever a rotation names change
this to rotation as well.
And Mixtura the duration is whatever time interval we give it and then return the forever option.
And so now instead of always having to rewrite all of this all you have to right now is for example.
This is the sun action.
So it just writes less sun.
Action is equal to rotation.
Aissa
since right here it says eight seconds.
So you can delete all of this.
And wherever we were calling it which is right here just right son action we're going to do the same
thing for the earth parent rotation.
So this is 14 seconds.
Right.
Let earth parent rotation is equal to rotation of type 14 seconds.
Or place that do the same thing for Venus Venus parent rotation is equal to rotation.
Ten seconds and you can do all of this and there is a earth and forever earth rotation you can replace
that with the earth rotation is equal to rotation with time.
Eight seconds and do the same thing for the Venus rotation
is equal rotation eight seconds as well.
So you can delete all of this and right here.
Just put Earth rotation here put the Venus rotation
for Earth parent the earth parent rotation for Venus parent Venus parent rotation.
Notice how much cleaner this is.
Now we can run the
and notice the moon rotating around each planet since the planets are rotating around themselves.
Ok first off Venus doesn't actually have a moon.
This was just for a demonstration purposes.
So I'm just going to remove Venus's moon right here and where it says Venus thought childhood Venus
Moon and then want to remove that as well.
And now what if I want to rotate the moon around the earth at a different speed.
Right now it takes eight seconds for the Earth to rotate around itself.
So it will automatically take the moon eight seconds to rotate around the Earth since the Moon is a
child of the earth whatever the speed the earth rotates around itself.
The moon is going to rotate around the earth at the same speed.
Now remember from earlier when Earth and Venus were rotating around the sun we were able to give them
their own speeds of rotation by making them children of their respective parents.
Earth parent and Venus parent.
So do the same thing for the moon right.
Let moon parent
is equal to see a node.
I'm just going to declare that on top right here with the other parents.
So the moon parent is not going to have a geometry or anything.
Just like the other parents it will stay invisible.
It's only there to control the moon's rotation speed.
Now place the moon parent exactly where the earth is so right.
MOON parent
dot position is equal to see and vector 3.
And just copy the position that the earth has
and since the Earth is a child of the earth parent make the moon parent a child of the earth parent
as well.
Sarette earth parent Dogpatch child node neun parent.
Why did I just do this.
Now the moon parent is always going to be positioned exactly where the earth is.
How while both the moon parent and the earth are positioned relative to the earth parent and their starting
position relative to the earth parent is the exact same.
So wherever the earth is the moon parent is going to be at that exact same position.
And remember that the earth parent is just an invisible node.
We're only using it to control the moon's orientation around the Earth.
So give moon parent a rotation of 1 second by writing let Moon rotation is equal to rotation and the
time it's going to take to rotate around itself will be one second and make the moon a child of the
moon parent by writing moon parent child node moon.
Now just make sure to run this action by writing moon parent run action moon rotation.
In summary here is what's happening.
It takes the moon parent 1 second to rotate around itself which is really fast.
So it's going to take the moon one second to rotate around the moon parent and since the moon parent
is always exactly where the Earth is you can see that it's going to take the moon one second to rotate
around the Earth which is really fast.
Run the app to see if that's the case.
And look the moon rotates around the earth very quickly.
We were able to control the speed of the moon.
Now one second for the moon to rotate around the Earth is a bit too fast.
But X code.
Change it to about 5 seconds run the Afghan and there you go.
We were able to control the speed of how fast the moon rotates around the earth and that's it.
We learn how to wrap nodes with textures rotate nodes and control the speed of rotation.
This has a lot to learn and you've made it this far in the next section.
We're going to look at 3D models.