Hit you guys before proceeding with the course I should warn you about some syntax changes.
So as I was making the course I was using XCode 9 version 5.
This right here is Version 6.
By the time you watch this video it might be a very good 7 or 8 or whatever it is anyway.
As you go through the course you'll see this a lot less configuration is equal to our world tracking
session configuration.
Don't worry about what this is right now.
I've explained that in the introductory section of this course once you get there you'll understand
it very well but just know that Apple renamed this variable to our world tracking configuration.
So as you're following through with the course make sure to write erewhile tracking configuration.
Not our role tracking session.
And that is all.
I hope you enjoy the course.