Breast cancer is the most common cancer among women worldwide accounting for 25 percent of all cancer
cases and infected two point one million people in 2015.
Early diagnosis significantly increase the chances of survival.
The key challenge in cancer detection is how to classify tumours into malignant or benign machine learning
techniques can dramatically improve the accuracy of diagnosis.
Research indicates that most experienced physicians can diagnose cancer with 79 percent accuracy.
Why 91 percent correct diagnosis is achieved using machine only tickets.
In this case study our task is to classify tumours into malignant or benign tumours using features of
genes from several cell images.
Let's take a look at the cancer diagnosis and classification process.
So the first step in the cancer diagnosis process is to do what we call a fine needle aspirin or any
prosess which is simply extracting some of the cells out of the tumour.
And at this stage we don't know that yuman is malignant or benign.
It may seem a ligament or benign it's as you can see these are kind of the images of the benign tumour.
And this is a malignant tumour.
And when we say benign that means that the tumour is kind of not spreading across the body so the patient
is safe somehow it's if it's malignant that means it's it's a cancerous.
That means we need to intervene and actually stopping cancer growth.
Right.
And what we do here in the machine learning aspect so now as we execute all these images and we wanted
to specify if that cancer out of these images is malignant or benign.
That's the whole idea.
So what we do with that we extract out of these images some features when we see features that mean
some characteristics out of the image such as radius for example the cells such as texture perimeter
area smoothness and so on.
And then we feed all these features in to kind of our machine learning model.
In a way which is kind of a brain in a way.
Okay if you guys are not familiar with machine learning techniques in general we're going to convert
to can you separate them from scratch.
But again if you if this is the first kind of a case study or find a first project that's going to work
on machine learning the ideas we want to teach the machine how to basically classify images or classify
data and tell us okay if it's malignant or benign for example in this case without any human intervention
which is going to turn them out of the ones the motherless teen would good to go we can use it in practice
to classify new images as we move forward.
And that's kind of the procedure or the cancer diagnosis procedure.
And by that we conclude the business case.
Now let's shift in to some of the machine learning twirps.
I hope you guys enjoyed that section and see you in the next section.