Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the biggest lecture we're able to get an overview of how
to write them for a loop and we're able as well to kind of see a little bit of keywords just enumerate
and some other keywords as well.
Let's take a look.
Such as range for instance.
Let's take a look here and see how can we use the word break and continue with it within a for loop
or a while loop.
All right.
So let's take a look at what you mean by break and continue this cycle.
Good example.
So assume that I have.
Again my list which is what we have defined before which is let's say list of fruits.
That's actually copy it of writing it again.
So here we go have Apple blueberries mangoes and so on.
All right.
Press enter it.
We go if with a view if we'd like to visualize our list.
Here we go this our list.
Right.
So what we could do.
I'm going to say OK I wanted to print all the elements within my list.
We have done that before we have done in the past.
Say before I in my list colon and then say Okay let's go ahead and print my I entered.
I'll be able to print apples blueberries and so on.
Let's assume that I wanted to for example print let's say Apple blueberries mangoes and that's it.
So I wanted to print let's say the first three elements only.
All right.
So how can we do that.
What we could do here.
We're gonna say okay.
For i in my underscore list.
What I could do.
I'm going to say okay let's go ahead and print the value of i.
Which is exactly the same as before.
So if I leave it like this then I will go ahead and actually print all of them.
All right.
What I could do instead.
I can add kind of a little bit of an if condition in here.
Okay.
If you guys recall call from previously I can say for example if you find for instance if you find I
equals to let's say here identified as mango mango.
If you find that if you find I equals to mango.
So if each of the elements here within my list if you go here and you obtain let's say the first element
second element third element if any of the elements you are obtaining here you found that that was equal
to mango.
What are you going to do.
And that's the power that's the new element that I wanted to.
A new concept that I wanted to introduce in this lecture is we can actually use the key words we call
a break to actually kind of break our love for us.
Right.
Which is kind of very very powerful.
So what I could do here are going to say if you find R equals to mango.
Break the loop which means just don't continue.
Just skip it.
Break the full loop and keep going.
All right shift enter.
Here we go.
So now basically we went in there.
We're able to print the apple blueberries mangoes and that's it.
And once we reach the word mango We actually print it out.
Right.
Because I do the print beforehand.
So I printed the word mango.
Then I came here checked it's i equals to mango.
Yes.
Then I performed this.
So I was able to actually break my loop.
All right.
OK.
Sounds great.
All right.
So now it's time for a quick challenge.
What I want you guys to do is to go ahead and print Apple blueberries mangoes and watermelon.
All right.
And stop here.
OK.
So please go ahead pause the video and you'll see guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
What I got what I ask you has to do is to simply print all these elements Apple blueberries mangoes
and watermelon and stop here right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And I say for I in my list print.
I can print all the elements.
However if you find I equals to my watermelon
OK.
Please break.
Just break the loop.
Enter.
Here we go.
And here we are able to print Apple blueberries mangoes and watermelon and we'll actually skipped the
apricots skipped the last element in there.
All right.
OK let's take a look at another example or another keyword that I wanted us to learn.
So now we're able to know what they mean by break.
So break simply just breaks the loop just exit the loop another way.
In other words that we're gonna be using extensively as well throughout the course is the word call
continue.
All right.
So what do you mean by this.
I actually have kind of a quick summary for you as here.
So again the windbreak is used to exit the loop.
All right.
The words continue is used to skip the current block and return to the for a while loop.
So simply put I wanted to skip what's happening there and just keep going and just continue to loop
without doing anything.
All right.
So let's see how can we do that.
Let's assume that we have let's say a list of numbers I'm going to call my list equals to just bunch
of numbers in there.
So we can define it as one two three four five six seven eight nine and let's say 10.
All right.
And what I wanted to do you're gonna take a for I in my list I'm going to loop on each element within
my list.
And I wanted to only print the odd numbers only.
So the objective here is to print the odd numbers only.
All right.
So what I could do going to say okay go ahead to each of these elements which is what I said here.
And if you find in any of these numbers.
All right.
Was if you divided it by two and was equals equals to zero if you guys remember.
Right.
So if you find any of these element that was even number.
All right.
What I want what I'm asking us to do simply is to continue
else other than that just go ahead and print I.
OK.
So what the hell happened here.
OK let's ahead I actually go ahead and run it for us to shift enter.
Here we go.
So I was able to simply print all the odd numbers in there so I clicked 1 3 5 7.
So what happened here.
So I can say OK for I in my list.
So please go ahead grab each of the elements within my list.
All right let's actually zoom in a little bit and every time I'm gonna go take that number divide by
two and get the remainder.
All right.
If the remainder was equal to zero.
That means it's an even number.
All right.
Please don't do anything.
Continue and it's a continue.
I was just gonna skip that block.
I'm gonna skip all the things that go up again go to the full loop again which means I'm not going to
be executing this command whenever there's an even number.
However if it's an odd number if I said OK if I divided by two as equals equals zero failed that means
I'm not going to execute this or going to not going to do the continue I'm actually going to go here
and print that number.
All right.
And that's why I was able to print numbers 1 3 5 7 and 9.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Let's recap what we have done so far.
So in this lecture we're able to study just kind of two key words that are very important which is mainly
break and continue.
Break is mainly used to actually break a loop continues mainly used to actually skip that specific block
and go back again and perform the loop again.
All right.
That's pretty much all we have for the election epic I enjoyed it.
Let's lectures we're going to walk you through kind of more advanced topics when he goes to for loops
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.