Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I am super excited because in this lecture we're going to kind of step up our game a little bit when
it comes to loops and study what we call it nested loops.
OK.
And that would be going to be extensively used as well throughout the exercises and the practical projects
to please focus a little bit and it's very easy.
We're going to get through it together.
So the first step is what they mean by nested loops.
The idea of nested loops that we wanted to print a loop inside a body of another loop.
All right.
So it sounds crazy but again it's really simple.
Let's assume that I wanted to print for example the multiplication table.
All right.
So I wanted to print let's say 1 times 1 equals to 1 1 times 2 equals 2 to 1 time 3 equals 3 and so
on.
And I would keep going and print let's say two times one equals two to two times two equals four.
And so on.
All right.
How can we do that.
So what I could do I can use nested loops to actually do this to print out multiplication table.
So first I'm going to take a four X in range because remember we use the range and let's assume that
I wanted to print for instance multiplication tables from one till five.
So I can take a four I for x in range one and I want to print to five.
Right.
So I'm not going to write five here.
Five is wrong rather than actually print six figures.
Remember the word range can go up too.
And excluding the value of six right.
We have done that before when now we're experts in it right.
So I can do this.
All right.
So here I know they're going to create a loop that goes through one two three four five and six.
OK.
All right.
What I wanted to do.
They wanted to create a multiplication table right.
So for each of these numbers for the number one I actually when I multiplied by all numbers from one
to 10.
So that's why I need to print one times 1 One times two times three.
Apparently there is another loop within that loop that I need to implement somehow.
So let's see how can I do that.
All right.
So here we are in the body right.
So this is simply the body of the loop right.
So this is the indentation right.
So what I could do here instead of actually writing something like for example print I for instance
No I'm not gonna do this actually in the body I'm going to create another loop I'm going to put an addition
and loop with a different index y for i in range and here I'm going to pass along the numbers from 1
let's say to 10 I wanted to print all the numbers in the multiplication table right.
So going to say from 1 to 10 I'm not going to put 10 action can I put Eleven if you remember range can
go up to an exec loading the last number.
So going to see Collin again every time I'm going to say Okay now we're pretty much ready to print.
And I wanted to print here.
You guys remember I can use the format method.
So I'm gonna say Okay I need to print this something times okay.
Something equals to something and I need to illustrate what they mean by all this.
When I say a dot format and here I'll get a pass along x.
I want to multiply x by y and the results will gonna be X times Y which is amazing.
Okay.
So what happened.
Let's actually go ahead and print let's see what's have shift entered.
Here we go.
Beautiful.
So pretty much you're able to print my multiplication table.
We're able to print one times one equals one one times equals two and so on.
Up until one times nine equals nine.
And then afterwards I print two times one equals two two times two equals to four and so on.
So I printed two up until 10 to 20 and then print all the multiplication tables sorry for three.
So three times all of it.
And then for all of that.
And then five which is all of this.
All right great.
All right.
So let's take a look at what happened here.
So when we did the nested loops we would actually be able to take a 4 x 4 number in range.
There's an image.
This will call it the major loop.
When we think about it.
Actually I would like to write that.
Think of it as a call slow loop and think of this one as we'll call it the fast loop.
So every time I'm going to go here I'm going to take the number one.
All right.
So X equals to one.
Right.
This is the slow loop.
And within that slow loop we're going to go here and loop several times very fast quick.
All right.
So I'm gonna scan through the numbers one two three four and one up until I reach one to 10 and that's
why I multiplied all the numbers you know like x x 0 6 to 1 y you has been changing all the numbers
from 1 to 10.
And we're able to print it up to then and then afterwards after I finish this loop which is a small
fast loop I all go up again.
All right.
To the main loop to the slower loop.
Take the next number x which is to in this case.
Right.
And then go here and do the fast loop and then go up again.
Take this next number go down go up again repeat very fast and so on.
And that's pretty much the idea of doing nested loop.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure it out.
It's really simple.
Well I want you guys to do it.
Please go ahead pause a video and I want you to print out the entire multiplication table from number
is 1 up until 10.
All right.
So simply here we printed out all the numbers up until 5:00.
Right.
I wanted to go ahead and actually do the entire multiplication table up until then.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
If you guys were able to figure out the challenge we're asking us to do is to simply come here.
Let's actually copy it.
This space it again here.
And when I want you guys to do it instead of having six here and I may set it to eleven.
All right.
And that should print out all entitlement application table.
Here we go.
So now we have all the numbers or the numbers two three four five six seven eight nine and ten.
All right.
Awesome.
Up until 10 time sandwiches equals to 100.
OK.
Again what we have done here is that we just stopped.
Instead of having one arrangement and six it's up to eleven again.
So that means the slower loop and the faster the loop goes from one to 10.
All right.
OK.
Let's take a look at another example.
Which is not numbers would get a deal a little bit different kind of an a list of strings.
So let's go ahead and maybe define two strings and it's a color.
Color lists equals two.
Let's assume I have black.
Just list of colors color black white and let's say gold.
And let's assume I have another list I'm going to call it phone on the school list equals two.
Here I define them as iPhone and let's say Samsung just can't.
Couple of the couple of the major brands and then maybe pick BlackBerry all right.
Looks good.
Shift enter.
Here we go.
So now I simply have to list what I wanted to do is simply go ahead and print all the combination of
the different colors with the different phones.
For example I wanted to print black iPhone black Samsung black BlackBerry and then print white iPhone
white Samsung.
Why BlackBerry.
And then gold gold iPhone gold Samsung gold blackberries.
Think about it.
Pretty much the same as the previous idea.
I wanted to do that we have kind of a slow loop and the faster loop the slow loop is this loop.
Right.
And the faster loop is this loop simply.
So simply put I need to have kind of a nested loops in some form and some sort.
So I can say okay.
For I in color list.
So I'm gonna loop on the color list every time I'm going to say for J in phone list K sounds good and
then I'm going to go into print simply I wanted to print what were the content rights I wanted to print
black iPhone like Samsung and so on.
So when I say print I comment Jay OK that's it.
Here we go shift enter.
Here we go.
So simply put we're able to print black iPhone black and so on.
So here I have all the elements and then white or the combination afterwards.
My apologies and then we have gold all the combinations as well.
All right.
OK.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the this concept which is nested loops concepts really important.
Very intuitive.
And let's recap all I've done in this lecture and this lecture were able to introduce how to do loops
within a loop which is kind of a nested loop and we're able to do that using the maybe by applying simply
and fast the loop within a slower loop and doing let's say the printing operation or whatever operation
and we have went through kind of a mini challenge to expand the multiplication table from one to five
that's expanded to 10 by changing this number to 11 and we're able as well to take a look at another
example using the list of strings and we're able to print as well all the content using pretty much
the exact same concept.
All right.
That's pretty much what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
We actually have two more topics to go on that should conclude the entire kind of loops section we're
going to cover while loops and we'll cover kind of a very a little bit advanced concept concepts or
call list comprehension.
And I'm gonna cover that in the next lecture.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.