So let's conclude this case study.
So as we saw that machine learning picnic's was able to classify tumours effectively into malignant
benign tumours with 97 percent accuracy which is really great.
Right.
And that's assuming that we don't have any deep learning or any features detection of whatsoever.
We actually provided the machine learning with with our features.
We created our features our own which is kind of on a very basic elementary are the meek because moving
forward we can actually use directly our images using our deep learning strategies to actually look
at the images directly.
Okay.
All right.
So the technique as we saw lapilli evaluate breast masses and classify them in in other media fashion
we don't need an actual physician to be there.
Obviously you know with kind of a second opinion that would be great.
But you know now we're seeing a machine learning model that can simply look at the features look at
the images and let us walk.
This cancer is meant malignant or malignant.
This cancer is benign.
Right.
Well a tumour is benign.
So as part of the conclusion part of the benefits of that case study in our early breast cancer the
10 minute detection can dramatically save lives especially in the developing world.
OK.
And again as we mentioned this can be further improved by combining computer vision and machine learning
and deep learning techniques to classify cancer directly using tissue images.
And just a quick overview of the results that we paint we actually each their on precision right now
97 percent which is really great.
And if we can see here this is kind of the confusion matrix that we achieve here found that we correctly
classify 45 points correctly classified six to six points.
So in order to classify the summation basically with these two numbers and here we misclassified only
three samples or a key element as well here is the misclassification was actually when the class was
zero.
Okay.
Or the prediction was zero.
However the tolga class wasn't one.
So I think that's because you know with the kids met in Melbourne and one indicates benign which means
our even our miscasts a five point swing actually fine we actually it's okay it's a kind of a type 1
error indicating that okay we didn't say that the patient for example is did it have cancer he had one
actually the patient we said that the patient or we assume that the patient the prediction the patient
said that the patient has cancer.
However he was just okay just fine.
He just had a benign tumour.
I hope he has enjoyed their case study and let's build a cancer free world.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And see you in the next guest.