Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because there's this section we're going to introduce the evolutional new network
and we're going to cover as well as how can we perform deep learning in Keris and in using simple language
in general which is super exciting.
All right so what we're going to do here is we're going to introduce the problem first.
So we're going to learn how can we build convolution more networks.
But based on a specific problem set this is a specific issue or problem they were trying to solve.
So what I selected here is just a really simple but kind of you know fun case study or a problem that
we wanted to solve.
And our objective is simply is we wanted to train a network.
Okay Odom call it a deep network or a convolution and neural network that can simply detect a specific
person is smiling or not.
Okay.
Again it's very very simple suppose to be very easy compared to it or kind of more advanced strategies.
But you know since we're introducing here the concept I just wanted to give you kind of a more fun approach
of a funky study.
I'm going to build from scratch moving forward.
All right.
So again our problem statement is mine detector.
We wanted to detect people smiling happy like faces.
You can think about it you know kind of in some applications.
And then for example for Facebook facial recognition for instance we can detect if a person is smiling
or not.
If you're one for example in Lyca that's kind of you know like an application they can build.
Is that using your camera and you're in your home for.
For instance you can train for example vidor's for instance you know if you're home to open whenever
it detects it person is smiling so it's only smily people or smiley faces are allowed into the house
kind of thing.
OK.
All right.
So let's get started.
So we're going to do here is we are going to look at the problem statement.
OK.
And look at the technical data set.
So the tiddley dataset simply is again smiling faces and sad faces.
So if the person is smiling like this for example we are going to assign a specific label as one we're
going to say give the person smiling.
The network of the fishing network should generate value of one.
If the person is not smiling then it was an AIDS zero pushing it a smiling maybe looking down generate
one the person smiling and a one of the person not smiling but maybe looks sad the Geneva 0 and so on.
So simply put our input to our network is it's an image so I'm going to simply feed all our images to
the network.
OK an hour of the class.
We're going to be either 0 4 not smiling and one for smiling.
That's it.
In a nutshell that's in a very simple form.
Obviously there issue with the problem might seem simple but to train the net or keynoted a team kind
of you know like a computer it's a pretty a pretty intense task.
We're going to learn how can we you know like come like feet.
Or the training data set how to perform testing how to treat all the different convolution in the network
and we're going to learn a lot in this section.
So the dataset and the seeders and images that can be used to solve one of the happy house problem you
can access the data from here and the data as well as contained within the course package.
We need to build an artificial network that can detect smiling faces.
That's the only object only smiling people would be allowed to enter the house.
That's kind of you know one quick application for our for our palm.
Right.
OK.
So let's take a look at the problem statement.
But a little bit more of kind of machine learning terms.
Okay.
So I guess I can see here we have input images or images.
Here are 64 pixels by 64 pixels.
Again if you guys are not familiar with like you know what they mean by pixels and so on.
I included this slide right after this slide that describes what they mean by pixel what they mean by
an image and so on and so forth.
But this kind of you know our our input image.
So here we have these images we actually have 750 images.
They are divided as follows.
600 for training and 150 for testing and images are simply 64 by 64 pixels and they are coloured as
well.
And our objective is to treat a lot of efficient a network in here.
Okay that will act as a kind of a classifier that simply look at the image and can tell us okay if this
person is smiling or not if the target class is one or the other class is zero which is really powerful.
OK.
So the question is what OK.
What do you mean by an image.
What do you mean by pixel.
What the.
All that.
So I just wanted to include.
A quick slide for you guys.
Again this is kind of the dimensions of the image 64 bit by 64 bit.
Let's take a look at you know kind of a view of what they mean by an image.
Assuming that you don't have any experience with computer vision or of any other image processing in
the past.
So in computers we store images in all collagen in a pixel format so let's assume that we have for example
here our Mona Lisa for example.
Image if you kind of you know zoom in this image you would actually find that this image is just a bunch
of zeros and ones a bunch of numbers just zeros and ones.
And simply put if you dig a little deeper into this image you'll find that for example in this case
this image lists 64 bit by 64 bit.
When we say it's 64 kind of you know pixels I'm sorry 6 for pixels by 64 pixels.
That means it's divided into kind of all a granular granular format getting all boxes here like here
like this.
And each of these boxes or each of these pixels would put a certain value.
OK.
Where zero.
If you put zero in here like here that indicates specific colour.
So if you put zero that mean that basically this pixel is totally black like he this big city limits
this because the image actually contains a few open at the actually contain a value of zero.
OK.
What about this one zero or about this one zero.
Okay.
What about weight values.
So for the white pixels we are going to have two hundred and fifty five.
That's the value that contained in a pixel when it's white.
So again zero indicates black 255 indicates white.
OK.
What about in between.
In between That's kind of the grey the grey skill.
So for example this pixel is one hundred and fifty five for example value that indicates as kind of
a grey area and that's kind of you know the different shades kind of you know like some of colouring
or chills of grey for instance.
So if it's all zero that means it's dark black.
If it's all like for example here like White for example pixels that's 255.
And if it's grey like these pixels or maybe like these pixels then you want to find kind of a range
between zero and 255 that indicates agree image.
Right.
So that's kind of you know their presentation of an image here if you haven't had any background for
example in like you know the logical tones or binary
of binding or decimal numbering format just long story short.
Any values are stored in a computer in just a bunch of zeros and ones.
So this zito for instance that's presented in the computer a bunch of zeroes SEALS use it as you like
isidore's.
OK.
That's why we call it a bit because here we have you know like eight places to translate that number
to the decimal number into binary number.
What if we have for example let's say a white collar like 255 that's in a binary format indicates all
once like eight bits and all of them are contains ones.
If you don't have any background in binary form I just don't what about it just here.
Let's take a look at a decimal which is you know what humans are kind of trying to understand value
of zero indicates black values of 255.
In the kipp's WHAT.
That's all we wanted to know.
Alright.
Okay.
Let's recap what we have covered so far.
So again here we have our problem statement.
Again we want to detect and develop kind of in your network that detect smile.
So here we have our images.
We have part of the class of 0 1 0 indicates not smiling one indicates smiling.
And what we going to do here is we have our our data set.
We have 750 images.
They are divided into 600 training and 150 for testing and images of simply 64 bit by 64 sorry 64 pixels
by 64 pixels.
And they're all coloured collars for that.
And in this nutshell will warrior present image any image we're presented in a kind of you know bunch
of pixels and we assign certain values with the pixels average from zero to two hundred and fifty five.
And that's how we present an image in in a computer.
Okay.
And that's pretty much all for this lecture.
In the next lectures we're going to dig a little bit deeper into what do we mean by artificial intelligence
or fission in your network.
And we're going learn how can we bood start building our Confucian work together.
Your kids enjoy their lecture and see you in the next lecture.