Hello everyone and welcome to this new project and this project we're going to do a very interesting
and exciting strategy to actually predict avocado prices using what we call it Facebook profit.
OK we're going to be a lot of data analysis a lot of seaborne usage a lot of data manipulation manipulation
using pandas data frame and we're going to see how can we actually predict you know like avocado prices
you know something you know in the future let's say in 2019 or 2020 using the data that we have right
now and the data in the past the.
This basically case study is really important because now we can apply it to whatever application you
have.
So anywhere anytime seed is that you have you can actually apply the exact same strategy to predict
the prices for example in the future.
You can use it to predict let's say stock market data in the future and so on so forth.
All right.
So let's get started.
So first what is the data.
So the data represents weekly to 2018 retail skin.
That data from national retail volume units and price.
OK.
All right.
So if we scan through the data you will find that there is several columns in there.
You'll find that there is date.
OK.
That is the average price for a single avocado.
That is the type.
Is it conventional or is organic the year as well.
The region which region in the United States basically have been this data have been collected.
The total volume.
How many avocados have been sold.
And here it's kind of you know the total number of avocados within a specific product category.
So those people you you know 40 40 6 4 2 2 5 4 7 7 0 actually not gonna be using all the data per say
because here with that objective is to try to predict for the average price of the avocado over the
entire United States.
And for a specific region as well.
All right.
And that's the image of you know the beautiful girl that we're trying to predict.
So let's get started.
So what we could do first.
Again I tried here to summarize it as much as I can into kind of different steps and I'm going to walk
you through the different steps as we move forward.
So first you need to install what we call the Facebook profit FMG profit package so you simply go to
the Anaconda and you go in and you take this pip install FBI profit.
If you encounter any error please try to install do this install Conda and install dash C and then conduct
dash forge and then FBI profit.
OK please.
If you don't if you have any if you experience any issues downloading the these packages please post
them post your questions in the Q and A and maybe do a quick google search.
If not I will try to solve the issues.
Obviously there is no way that we will let you might run through some issues through content installation.
But that's that's basically the two issues that I've came across so far.
All right.
OK so what's profit.
Profits basic and open source software that had been released by the Facebook core data science team.
It's really really powerful because you know it can give you kind of a prediction of in the future and
it's actually very very accurate too.
OK.
All right.
So let's get started by inputting the data.
Let's see what's going to happen here.
So first we're going to import the important packages.
Now we're gonna be using the libraries we're going to be using.
Let's go ahead and import.
We're going to import again pandas as PD because remember we use pandas mainly for data manipulations
for data frames and it actually has been very very powerful.
It's like words like excel.
Just imagine having excel within a python development environment and then we're going to import num
pi as MP K which is meaning we use num PI for data statistical analysis and then we're going to import
mat plot lib dot pi plot as specialty which is again we're gonna use it for data visualization and we
have we're going to use as well imports we're going to import random and we're going to import as well
seaborne as as an S because remember we can use seaborne for data visualization as well mainly you know
like it's it's really it's way more powerful compared to that plot lib when it plus statistical data
and we we actually had an intersection for the previous part of the course.
If he wasn't familiar with seaboard Don't worry I'll try to cover a in this section if not please go
back and defer to the original notes.
All right.
So first what is the data.
So the data is contained in Estonia C as we file within the court's package.
It's called avocado dot c as V.
OK so if you don't know the court's package you shouldn't have a problem finding it.
And what we need to do here is we need to read our data frame.
Okay read our CSB file and store it in a data frame.
Okay let's do that.
So going I say okay Avo carto we can call it whatever you want data frame equals to PD dot read on the
score C as V and we want to read the avocado that C is v all right.
So let's run that.
Let's see if that happens.
Well you key PD was recognized.
So let's run that first.
Okay.
So it's loading and let's run that after.
All right.
Looks good now.
Okay.
Actually one more package.
My apologies I forgot to install we need the profit which is you know Facebook profit.
So going to say okay from F B profit OK we're going to import prophet OK.
All right.
Looks good.
And if you don't have prophet installed or correct installed using pip installed or using condoms install
second to forge profit you should find that error here but because they have it.
So when I run it you know it might take a little bit more time but again it ran perfectly which means
it's recognized what profit is right fair and that looks good.
Let's take a look at our data frame.
So let's go ahead dig that data frame.
Let's see if this data has been installed or not.
All right.
And here the data what we were getting the data.
So here we have a column called Date.
Here we have our average price for one single avocado one point three point ninety three dollars one
dollars one point to six.
Actually I've got us a really expensive here in Canada or in the United States two in total volume.
That's the total volume that we know of the number of avocados so let's say six 64000 avocados have
been you know like sold for example within that specific date.
Here we have the different call APL new numbers which stands for the specific product.
We're not going to be using all that data that much.
These are the total number of bags.
So there are basically the bags contain certain number of avocados right.
So there are small bags just large bags eggs X large bags.
Again we're not going to be touching any of that information.
This is a type of avocados either conventional or organic.
And that's the year.
Right.
So here is 2015 which is basically going to be you getting the information is contained within the data
as well.
And we have as well the reason.
OK.
Which region within the United States.
You know like there is West that is total U.S..
Okay.
And if there is if you scroll down it is like West like Texas like New Mexico and that's pretty pretty
much it.
All right.
Again we're not gonna be using all that data.
This is just you know like it quick.
This is the full data we're not gonna be using it for a profit.
We're going to be using mainly our price and our time.
That's the two important factors because what's trying to predict the price in the future.
Obviously this data you can you can you guys can use it for tons of machine learning applications right
you can use it for price predictions you can use it for like specific trends for unsupervised learning
and that's again out of the scope of this like case study and out of the scope of this course here the
objective is just try to use the fees that pay Facebook profit just try to predict the avocado prices
along with the using the time.
See it along with the price column only and we're gonna much ignore the entire all the data moving forward.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And in the next lecture we're going to see how can we load media and visual aid load the data again
and visualize the data using seaboard.
See you guys in the next lecture.