Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the previous lecture.
We covered the comparison operators and we we watched how can we actually compared to preeminence together
using either equal equal not equal greater than or equal and so on so forth in this section we're going
to cover what we call it logical operators.
OK.
Which is simply if you wanted to compare two parameters in a logical format from a logical perspective.
All right let's take a look at what they mean by logical.
Let's assume that we want it for example to say or to perform an ending between two variables.
OK.
What do you mean by an end redeemed by an.
Or let's assume they wanted for example to say it is true and false for instance.
OK.
So again two means one false means zero.
So when I say logical operators that means the here the end or OK.
That's pretty much all what I want.
Well look what I what I meant by logical operator operators and and or mainly OK so when I say end all
right.
That means I'm saying OK if this condition has to be true and this condition has to be true in order
for the entire result to be true.
All right what do you mean by this.
So let's take a look.
So when I say true please remember that 2 means one.
OK that's the overall idea.
True that means one false mean zero.
So I'm saying OK is 1 and 0.
What's the answer.
When I do 1 and 0.
Think of the ending operation as simply as of as multiplication.
Think of it this way it's not clearly a multiplication but think of it as multiplication.
So when you multiply one by zero the answer will be equals to zero.
All right.
Which is false.
Let's run that.
And that's actually what we have got here.
So when I say if I wanted to perform true and false The answer is going to be false.
All right.
So.
OK again from a logical perspective when I say.
And that means both conditions have to be true in order for the outcome to be true.
So here I'm saying okay this has to be true and this has to be true in order to generate a true output.
All right.
Let's take a look at another example let's assume true and true which is 1 1 and 1.
Let's compare that.
So the answer here.
What what what.
And so do we expect from that.
That would generate two that would generate one which makes sense heat I'm saying this condition is
true and as well this condition was true.
So the ending both of them will generate a true value.
All right.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume we're going to ending false and true which is simply I'm saying okay I wanted to false
again mean zero ending the true means 1.
So the answer here we're going to be zero.
That's wrong.
That and that will generate false why because in order for the end gate in order for the and logical
operator to generate one both conditions have to be true.
So this has to be true.
And this has to be it's true as well.
In order to generate true output.
All right.
What about false and false.
If I say false and false.
Please make sure it's uppercase.
That should that means zero ending zero and the output should be obviously zero.
So if we'd say zero false and false that would generate output is false.
All right.
And that's pretty much what they mean by the end operation or the end date.
Let's take a look at the Aldgate or the end or the operation.
So when it comes to or OK if any of the two conditions is true that's it done.
We're good here.
I'm saying OK if the first condition is true or the first or the second condition is true the output
will gonna be true as well.
OK.
So or is actually better than the end which is you know the or simply will only get to generate zero
or only will generate false if both inputs are actually false or both inputs and actually zeros.
All right let's take a look.
Mistake Okay let's just let's say true or true that should generate true so I'm saying 1 or 1.
So the output should be 1.
Let's run that they would tell me OK.
True or true is actually true.
So true or false.
All right.
Which is simply again here.
That means I'm saying 1 or 0.
That's run that that would generate 2 Why.
Because when we use or if any of the inputs is true then the output will going to be true as well.
All right.
If I say for example K false or true.
Okay then here I'm saying okay.
0 or 1 right.
Which is FALSE again mean 0 2 means 1 4 and that that would generate 2 as well.
So please bear in mind that for when it comes to all operation if any of the inputs is true.
Again here one of them was true.
One of them was true.
One of them is true.
The outputs were going to be true all along the way.
The only case the order will generate exaggerate false.
Well if both inputs are false so going to say Okay.
False or false which seems simply to mean 0 4 0.
That would generate simply zero.
He's been in mind that he'd 1 or 0 that would generate 1 and 0 or 1 such that she didn't generate 1
gets on that and that's what we got here we got false which makes complete sense all right.
Perfect.
OK.
So that's pretty much all what we're all what I wanted to cover when it comes to end and or let's take
a look at kind of more practical example in an actual combining kind of the logical operators along
with a comparison operators and just one statement.
Let's assume that I wanted to evaluate this condition.
I wanted to say is six greater than two.
OK and is two equals five.
Right.
So please without running for example the cell.
Please tell me what what do you expect.
So simple here I'm saying okay is six greater than two.
Well what do you expect here on that condition.
Well that the first element was actually two.
So that means the first one was true.
And I'm saying end right I'm saying is to heat I'm asking is two equals five.
Well the answer is false right.
So when I perform true and false figures remember if I do true here and true and false the answer will
be false because again when you do and that means I'm asking this condition has to be true and this
condition has to be true in order for the output to become true.
So that means here I'm expecting the answer to be false.
That's wrong that's and that's what we got we got false.
All right.
So here I'm gonna leave you guys for just a quick challenge.
OK.
And I'm going to ask you to evaluate these two conditions.
So again asking is six greater than two or is two equals to five and you're going to have another challenge
as well.
I'm going to say is two equals two three and is four equals two three.
And I'm gonna say is 10 equals to 10.
All right.
So please go ahead guys and and pause a video and just without running these cells let me know what
you expect.
Do you expect here the answer will going to be false or true.
And here the answer is gonna be false or true.
All right.
Please go ahead and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
So here I'm saying OK it's six greater than two.
Well this answer.
Well that's true.
And I'm saying or is two equals to five or not.
Well two is actually not equal to five.
So that means here I'm saying it's two equals five.
Well that was false.
Right.
If I say true or false since we have all here then the outcome should be true.
Because again when it comes to or if any of the input is true the outcome will be true.
All right.
Let's run that.
Well that's pretty good.
Let's do the other next challenged I'm saying is two equals to three.
Well that was false.
And I'm going to say okay it's four equals two three.
Well that was false as well
and it's 10 equals to 10.
Well that was true.
Right.
So when it comes to end if any of the inputs to the end gate is false or a zero the outcome will gonna
be zero.
So here I'm expecting to be false.
All right let's run that and that's what we've got we got folks.
All right.
That's pretty much all what I have for the section let's recap what we have done so in the in this section
we cover the logical operators.
So now we know how can we perform ending operation.
How can form or operation.
And here how can we mix them make them somehow into some of the comparison operators that we have done
in the past in the previous section to come up with kind of more logic or kind of you know like an advanced
logic in a way.
All right.
OK.
In the next section we're going to cover the conditional statements which is very exciting.
I'm super excited because now we actually get to combine all what we have learned so far to perform
what we call it if else condition which is kind of the foundation which comes to programming in general.
I hope you guys enjoy the lecture and see you in the next lecture.