Hello everyone and welcome to this project and this project we're going to do some fun kind of activities.
We're going to see how can we use Python to deal with images.
So we're going to see how can we take an image you know any image.
I'm going to show you how can you do that on basically any image from the Internet.
They're going to convert that image to let's say greyscale.
So change it from a colour to greyscale and then I'm going to show you as well how can we create some
cartoony effects so I'm going to look at some images of let's say politicians or you know like whatever
it may be you can use your images where you were face to and they don't get to make kind of a cartoon
effect so it's a little bit of kind of fun project.
But before we do that we need to understand how can we actually present or store image digitally within
a computer.
All right.
OK.
So first we're going to walk you through a couple of slides just to show you how can we present an image
in general and then afterwards we're going to go into the book.
I'm going to show you how can we perform the conversion again from colours to greyscale and to quote
effect as well.
OK.
So all right so I'm going to represent an image so as you can see here this is the image and this image
is in a greyscale.
When you say greyscale that means just black and black and white.
Right.
So when we say how can it present an image within a python environment within let's say a digital platform.
So the idea is the image here is divided into different pixels.
OK.
And each of these pixels has a certain number that number ranges from zero to 155.
So the number represents zero.
That means black.
So when you say actually when you look at the image are they able to tell when different pixels which
are different.
Let's say like corners or boxes.
Each box is simply a number.
That number range from 0 to 255.
The number is zero.
That means the pixel is black.
If the number is 255 that means the pixel is white.
OK.
In between that's grey.
That's a great value.
And that's pretty much it.
How can you present any image.
So if you actually think that image and break it down you will see that there is basically just bunch
of pixels and each pixels.
If it's black pixel is black like this pixel for instance.
That means the actual numerical digital value in there is actually zero.
If you look at this pixel for instance which is a bit like lighter let's say it's white.
That means let's say it's about 255 of value.
Anything in between.
Anything grey in here that means let's say it's 150 or let's say 100 and so on.
Right.
So here this is simply our image in a pixel format or in a digital format.
That's all the zeros because as a black 155 because it's grey to 155 because it's white these pictures
and these pixels are actually presented in digitally what we call a V in a bind in a format and that's
OK.
And again any any value that stored in the computer is actually a bunch of zeros and ones not actually
decimal values.
I think those can see here.
So these are the values in decimal format.
These are the values in a binary format.
So their value is there's value zero indicates actually bits of zero value all of them as heroes.
If you have to hunt fifty five That means it's all 1 1 1 1 1 1 okay.
If you don't have background in digital logic design just don't worry about it.
Just the whole idea of that and wanted to convey if there were any present image in a different format
Greece can image again as a bunch of pixels.
Each pixel has a value from 0 to 255 on it.
So how can to present the coloured image.
OK so columnist a little bit more complex.
So in general each image as you can see here this is a coloured image.
It's actually divided into kind of three channels.
Each panel represent different colours of red green and blue.
OK so a greyscale image is just kind of one.
They are however a coloured image it's actually consists of three lakes or eight.
And each layer represent again colour which is either red green and blue and by mixing all that then
you can see all the colours.
You can actually see within an image like in all a car they like yellow for instance is a mix of lets
see red and green and so on and so forth and that's how you can actually create different ranges of
colour.
OK so again each pixel contains an x in X Y.
Three values ranging from 0 to 255 and that's whether you want it.
RG B.
College space is presented which is again different layers of different chain of red green and blue
and that's how you present ecology image.
All right.
OK.
So again if we look at this image we can divide that image down into a bunch of pixels.
You will see that this is kind of really a number of yellow coloured yellow.
So the coloured yellows actually consists of three pixels because of three layers.
It's actually two 1 there 55 55 0.
Okay.
So simply put you put.
It's a mix of of red.
And if you go back actually no yellow sexual mix of red and green.
And that's why here you would see it's red is 100 percent or like 155 green is to under 55.
And the blues is here.
There's no blue in there.
However if you want to present to the number of blue it's again it's a pixel.
It has three valleys in there of 0 0 and 255.
The present thing that there is no red.
There is no green.
However it's all blue.
Is there no green.
It's zero hundred and zero.
Prisoner number Red It's 255 zedong's you're on so and so forth.
And the key difference between the colour image and degrease image is that the greyscale image has only
eight bits.
OK.
However for a coloured image actually had eight time three because we have three layers straight.
And that's why is what we call it has 24 bit coloured format.
And that's where the 24 bit colour came into play.
All right.
OK.
So again assuming that we have the exact same image a greyscale and it is a Scollard.
You could see that the image actually three times the size larger compared to the reskilling.
All right.
OK.
So that's pretty much kind of the foundation that they want you to to see them in the next section.
I'm going to show you how can we actually take all that learning that we all seen.
We try to use all of that open CV which is a very famous library within python.
They actually use to make life way easier.
Okay.
Going to use it to load images.
Make it you know converted from greyscale to Colorado from college to reskill.
A load.
How can we make these different cartoon effects.
It's going to be a lot of a lot of fun.
I hope you guys enjoy it and see you in the next section.