Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going and continue solving the for and why loop questions.
So here I am asking to write a code that takes a string from the user and of the words in and print
all words basically afterwards and say OK string equals two let's get an input from the user.
Enter.
How do you feel that today for example how do you feel today.
Okay.
Like whatever.
And these are gonna insert the value and they're going to be put back here into the string.
Right.
And I'm gonna do Gonna take a string dot splits because I wanted to split these basically the string
into words right.
Gonna take this thing and make it into word or words.
Right.
Okay looks good.
What we could do need to sort sorted we're going to use the salt method to do to do that operation.
We gonna say okay word words dot sort.
Right okay.
That will basically just sort our words.
Okay and let's go ahead and actually print.
So basically here to print the ward.
Right.
To do that.
What we need to do here.
We need to create a for loop that basically loops on all the words here.
Right.
Actually before we create the for loop let's go ahead and run it before we jump jump ahead of ourselves
and say OK how are you feeling.
I am happy.
That's correct.
Let's say I am so happy learning Python today.
And if we press enters let's take a look at Ward's what's what's in it.
So if you look at it you'll find that we have m that is happy.
There is I learning python and so on.
So basically a list.
Right.
And that list consists of different strings.
OK.
So what we could do to print them out what we need to do basically for ward in wards.
That's actually kind of you know a very famous way of writing the code.
We have a list for example here you define It's a list of wards.
So this is my list right.
So when you say four ward in were in wards that means you are going into that list and taking elements
out of it and doing something with it.
So every time I'm going to go Take for example the M and print it's going to take a print my word.
Right.
And that's I'm going to go up again take the next one happy printed and so on so forth.
Let's run that.
And that's what we're getting we're getting m happy I learning P S.A. so we saw them basically in an
alphabetical order.
All right looks perfect.
Question number eleven.
So for question number eleven actually here.
Question number eleven as I've done that before.
What we need to do here is go up.
We need to make sure that we have this.
So what we need to do here.
I provided you with two lists basically cut colorless and phone list.
Right.
So here we have list of phones.
So the list of colors black white and gold.
Here we have list of phones iPhones Samsung and BlackBerry.
And I'm asking you to basically using two different methods or two different ways of writing in a way
to print basically or you know combine them together and actually print let's say black iPhone black
Samsung and so on like this.
So it seems like there is a nested loop somewhere and the overall objective here is for us to practice
how to do nested loops.
Right.
That's how can we do that.
I'm going to take before I in color lists
so that would be our bigger loop right.
So that will be my major loop that we're going to loop over colors right.
And then get a for let's define other variables J in phone lists OK.
So every time I'm going to go to the for loop to the I 1 and then we have another loop you know like
at a kind of a faster speed J loop every time I'm going to go in and print I and G.
That's it.
Let's take a look what's happening here.
So first I'm going to say OK.
For I in color lists.
So here I'm basically going to our first list which is has black white and gold.
So first let's assume I'm going to take the black one.
Right.
So for I so I in the first one hit I'm just trying to simulate the entire for loop from from scratch.
So first here I have black right.
So here inserted I started the second loop with the color black here.
I'm going to take a for J informed list.
So basically I'm saying OK there's another loop that goes on on the phone list which is basically this
my list which has iPhone so please remember I'm inserting I has again.
Let's write it down.
So I has black here for the first two.
Right.
So I insert I went in the second loop which is kind of faster with my color black only.
Every time I'm going to go here take up again take the phone list so you can take iPhone.
I'm going to print black versus iPhone.
So black iPhone.
And that's the first one I printed here.
And what's going to happen is I'm not going to go up right.
Why.
Because I still here I'm still stuck in that you know kind of faster loop or like kind of nested blueprint.
So you can say okay I have the same black value so I'm still black.
But Jay's updated.
Now I have Samsung.
That's why I have black Samsung.
And then one more time I see a BlackBerry so I have black BlackBerry.
That's why I have black BlackBerry.
And then once the loop is done I'm going to go up again.
Right.
Take the next color which is white and go in here do repeat again.
So white iPhone white Samsung white BlackBerry and so on so forth.
Keep repeating until the for loop the major for loop ended and that's it.
Let's run that.
And that's actually exactly what I've got here.
Which is great.
Let's do the exact same exact same code but kind of in a different format.
Let's say I can write that going to say OK I have to create basically a new list.
OK.
And you list.
And that's my list.
And what I could do.
I'm going to create my both for my both for loops as follows.
Going to take it for I in color lists OK.
And then I'm going to order to create the next for loop I can do that's going to take before J in phone
underscore lists.
All right.
What's going to happen so basically here.
I have to if you guys remember before that here I write the actual body of both.
So here I have four I am color list.
That's my first full loop for J in phone list.
And then I can write basically my eye comma G that's it.
And I get my new list.
And here I can simply come here and print my new underscore list.
All right.
Let's see what we could do here.
Actually before printing it out that's let's take a look at what's happening.
Let's run it.
So let's take a look at my new on this call lists.
That's what we're getting here.
Getting black iPhone black Samsung black BlackBerry looks good.
And if we print it out and that's what we're getting here it's obvious it's the actual printing is different
but the idea you get the idea right here it's kind of you know where print to get out.
That's kind of you know like a like in pairs right.
We have black iPhone black Samsung black BlackBerry and so on so forth.
All right.
Obviously there are tons of ways of doing it.
This is just you know like two ways you guys can use whatever way you like.
Question number 12.
He'd have asking you to write a code that basically takes a string and calculate the number of upper
and lower characters within the string.
OK.
All right.
Let's take these string from the user NHK input and let's say enter.
Enter a string or enter whatever you feel like.
And we're going to take that and put it in an input string.
OK.
All right so that be the first step and what I could do here because I'm counting numbers that I'm connecting
the characters.
That means I need to have to kind of call it accumulators.
I'm gonna reset these accumulators to zero.
I'm going to say okay upper on this court case equals to zero and then lower on this court case equals
to zero as well.
So here you're basically initializing two accumulators and you're setting both of them to zero.
All right.
Why.
Because you haven't counted anything yet.
Right.
OK.
So what I could do.
I'm going to say okay for every time I take a character in input String
input string.
So basically the user can insert an input in the string and every time I'm going to go ahead into that
string and take a character right.
And the question is here I have to check.
I have to ask myself Is it uppercase if that character was uppercase or not.
To do that I'm going to say okay if car dot is upper is upper basically just confirms or asks is that
character was an upper case or not.
If it is an upper case.
Right.
Well you could do.
You're going to say okay upper on this court case equals to upper underscored case plus 1.
Basically you're just gonna what are you gonna do here.
I'm going to accumulate the upper case accumulator started to zero.
If the character is upper go ahead here and accumulate your upper case.
OK.
If not to what get you're going to say Okay l if if it is if the car dot is lower.
So it's if it's lower case what you could do is say Okay lower underscored case equals to lower.
Actually let's do it in a different way let's say plus 1 plus equal 1.
Because remember you can do the exact same thing here.
If you do it plus equal right.
So plus equals one.
OK.
All right.
What if it's not upper if it's not a lower case.
Well you're just gonna pass.
Right.
If it's like you number or whatever you know just gonna pass past that and that's it's what you could
do afterwards after the exit you followed up what you could do here.
You going to circulates printouts.
Our number number of upper cases of sort of upper upper case letters and you can simply pass along our
upper underscored case variable and what you could do you can print as well our number of lower case
letters and you can say OK it's lower underscore case.
Actually this is underscoring my apologies.
And you can close this.
All right.
Looks good.
Let's run it interesting.
Let's say I am so happy.
Let's add to today because
I am learning Python run it and it looks it looks like it's working so hard say OK a number of uppercase
actually seven.
So let's count them out.
So we have have one right.
We have two three four five six and seven.
Right.
And simply the rest we're going to be the lowercase.
All right looks great.
Let's give it another shot.
Let's maybe insert maybe like like numbers or something let's say Okay I am happy three for example
something like this run it and I tell you OK and the number of lower number of uppercase letters were
actually six.
So here you have I and you have happy.
So it's six a number of lower case letters will only a. m..
So basically here the code skip number three which is exactly what I'm looking for.
I don't want it to count basically digits right or what I wanted to do is to count the upper and lower
cases only.
All right.
Let's take one more example here I'm asking you to write a code that takes a range from hundred to nine
hundred and only print the numbers with all the digits are even.
OK so that's a little bit challenging.
So let's see how can we do this.
Going to say OK let's get the minimum maximum down.
That's pretty much easy.
It's going to take a min in int of input and I'm going to see it enter a lower bound right.
And it's actually copy that.
Let's face it here and make it upper bound and I'm going to set that to Max.
And because it's a reserved word that's make it X underscore an excellent score Max.
All right that looks good.
We have done that several times before.
And what we could do here.
I'm going to say OK.
So what we need to do is that we need to simply take the number right whatever number that is and simply
kind of slice it into three sections or three portions.
Right.
And that's kind of the a little bit challenging in here.
So what we need to do we're going to think the number or get whatever number that is right and convert
it into a string divided or slice it right and then convert it into an integer and compare them if they
are even or odd.
Because we wanted to make sure if all the numbers are even.
All right.
And then afterwards you can print only the numbers afterwards.
It's a little bit you know like weird but let's see how can we do it again.
That's one way of solving I'm not saying that's the only way but there are several ways.
This is just one way that I decided to choose here.
All right.
What we could do going to say Okay I need obviously to have a full loop that go ahead and go from men
from X-Men X on the score men to X on the score Max.
Right.
OK.
First I need to take the whatever number right whatever I that number is and I need to convert it into
a string and I put it into S for example.
All right.
So now I have a string.
OK.
That's great.
And when I need to do here I need to simply create an if condition I'm going to say OK.
If you found any to go ahead into that string and simply take all the elements one by one.
Right.
So going to take it if you found the value of s of 0 OK divided by two and you take the remainder was
equal equals to zero.
Right.
That basically condition simply will get a check here.
Let's put that in within that brackets so here I am saying OK if you go ahead here and found that if
s of zero which is the first element when it would within the string right.
The only problem is that if you do this operation this option will work right.
Why.
Because this actually element is of zero.
That's the first that's let's say two or let's say for example zero or let's say you know the first
element.
That's and say four for innocent.
That's the first element within the string to do the comparison you actually to go back and actually
convert it into an integer.
I know it sounds a little bit crazy but that's the only way or the best way of actually doing it.
So we we converted the string slice it up when we do s of zero.
Right.
And then when we do the comparison we go back and convert into an integer back again.
All right.
Well obviously we need to do that for all the numbers right.
We're going to think the exact same number it here.
Copy copied and pasted here.
Right.
Actually I need to remove that and that we're going to be one because I need to get to know the second
number right.
And so going to copy that and do end.
And that would be as of two.
Again he looks good.
And what I could do if basically the if condition I was satisfied Well that's good.
That means we need again to act to kind of concatenate the numbers into an empty string so can numbers
for example.
This quality let's call it all even numbers so that's where all the numbers are even like two or four
or two a six or two eight with the finance that ends in a string here.
We could do going to say okay if you found let's do that.
I'm going to take a dot append.
So I'm going to append to it the value of s what we're going to do here.
I'm going to say okay if you find all the even numbers if it satisfies all these conditions that mean
all the numbers were even right.
So let's take s and appended to all even numbers and keep looping again.
All right let's run that into the lower bound let's say 50 upper bound let's say to say 300.
Right.
It says there is an error.
OK.
So it's saying OK index string index is out of range.
All right.
So here it seems.
That's because I fed number here 50 which is not so the objective or the design was to make it you know
range from one hundred to nine hundred for a reason right.
The objective is because I'm doing the check three times here.
When I mentioned 50 it will just breaks.
Why.
Because we only have two digits right.
OK.
So what we could do let's run it again.
I'm going to say a.
Let's say two hundred and let's say five hundred and run it and let's go ahead.
It seems there's no problems anymore which is great.
Let's go ahead and actually view it's actually printed out.
You want it to print all even numbers and that's what we're getting here.
Looks like it's working.
So we have 200.
We have two or two to a four to a six.
Looks great between the bounds upper lower bounds two hundred and five hundred that we decided to feed
in here.
All right.
That's a lot of information.
I hope you guys were able to figure it out.
And in the next lecture you're going to keep going and actually going to continue questions 14 up to
16 and that should conclude the four and while loop section I hope you guys enjoy the lectures and see
you in the next lecture.