Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
All right I'm super excited because we're actually getting closer to finish the four and why loop and
you guys can become experts.
We have a lot of we've got a lot of questions in here and it has been an exciting journey so far.
So here I'm asking to write a code that prints I love you for example or whatever text you want it followed
by your significant other name every three seconds.
OK.
So the overall idea is to try to learn how can we use time that sleep.
OK let's see how can we do this.
Okay.
Import that's kind of an external research right.
They need to do import time.
And what I want you to do is to say OK let's say enter or input enter the name of your significant other
significant other.
Right.
OK and these are going to insert that we want to keep it as string.
No problem.
And when I wanted to do here I wanted to keep printing it every three seconds what I could do going
to say it while true forget guys remember while two means that I'm going to keep printing forever unless
I actually stop it somehow mistake every time going to say OK print and say OK I love you for instance.
Right.
And we can you know like print the name that we're going to be fair here.
If we do this that would keep going forever.
Right.
But what I wanted to do here are going to basically add kind of a delay in here so what I could do in
this okay time dot sleep and get specify how many seconds in here.
Three that means you're just going to go and sleep with this three seconds and go up again do it again.
Sleep with this that's kind of you know you're putting the loop on hold for a while.
Please bear in mind that this would get to keep going technically forever.
Okay.
Yes it going be delayed every few seconds where they keep going forever right.
Right.
Let's run that they'd like you know mom for example and I love your mom.
And then three seconds later I love your mom.
Then she sings later.
I love your mom.
OK.
It's pretty interesting and can use it you know to show it to your mom for example you know like you
love her or something.
OK.
And what she could do to exit this who's going to come to colonels do interrupt.
It might not actually like sometimes it might take.
OK.
Now it interrupted looks good and that's pretty much all we have for this question.
Question number 15.
So I'm asking you to write a code that asks users to enter a password and ensure that the password satisfies
the following conditions.
It has to be at least 10 characters has to contain at least one uppercase and at least one number.
All right.
How can we do that.
OK.
So what we could do is say OK I have to ask the user several times right.
So we can have while two as well.
So I'm going to be stuck in a loop.
I'm going to say okay every time I can ask the user password let's call it password.
Music equals to input.
And we're going to ask the user OK.
Let's say it's time to change your password.
OK.
Please select a new password.
You know that.
That's what happened on the act when your password actually expires.
And first here you will find that basically there is because we added It's here.
So it saw that this is kind of you know like like we we concluded this jingle.
The string has ended here but that's not the case right.
So what it could do going to say okay that's double quotes here.
And we can come here and make this double OK.
It's actually going to work the exact same way.
All right looks good.
And here we have to check simply going to do a quick check on the password.
All right.
First I want to check if it's has more than 10 more than 10 elements one of the characters right have
to check if it is digits.
It's simply it contains at least one number.
All right.
And you have to check as well if it is it has at least one uppercase.
Right.
How can we do that.
Going gonna say okay if lengths of my password was greater than or equal to 10.
That's my first check and I'm going to check as well.
I have to check if there is any of the characters.
So how can we check.
How can we check that.
That's actually pretty interesting.
That's this again kind of new we haven't done that before.
Let's.
Can we do.
They're going to take a four car in password so I can say okay every time going to go ahead.
Again that's my second condition.
Please don't be confused and say okay.
If you go ahead and do that password take it a character.
Right.
And whatever is gonna get out of it if you find the car dot is digit
is digit.
If you find that's actually has one digit.
Right.
OK.
So to check if there is what we call it like.
Like only one condition has been happening when you use the any reserved word going say gave any of
this happened so if any of these conditions happened.
If you find in just one single digit then you here are going to return true which is good because this
has to be to have to be satisfied.
This has to be satisfied.
And we actually get to do the exact same thing as well but we need to make sure that it's an upper case
right.
So the second end and here we're going to see if again car.
But here it must not is digit going to see if it's is upper and that's it.
If that is satisfied if that happened what we could do here is take a print password new password
saved successfully.
And all we could do here are gonna say okay.
And basically here we have to break actually.
So here we have make sure that we actually get a break right.
Because the password sucks.
It looks successful.
I have to bring the why loop I don't need to go ahead and as the users to enter another password I would
be annoyed because you know he answered.
He answered all everything is right.
But again it's still illegal ask him to enter a new password Elsa against UK print media say OK password
does not satisfy satisfy the requirements
all right requirements believe that's the way and that's it.
OK let's take a look.
So let's run it and say enter a new password let's say hello.
Well password does not satisfy the requirement and you feel you find that it's you are still stuck in
a loop right.
Okay let's try.
Hello.
All uppercase password does not satisfy the requirement the point is here he obviously can improve on
this and make a little bit more advanced to tell you okay why doesn't satisfy the requirements right.
So simply here you have to check which one have been false.
Going to say Okay Hello.
Let's say 10 let's say world.
So here we satisfy the 10 elements.
And he sets five that there is a digit at least and we're uppercase.
Let's run it.
Well.
Password safe successful.
That's perfect.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
All right.
OK.
The last question here.
I'm asking you to write the code that continuously gets a number of data from the user and can keep
the average and printed on industry.
All right.
How can we do that when I say a print say for example keep keep entering numbers and they will calculate
the average for you.
Something like that.
Something fun like this.
Then when I say Okay now I need to define simply two parameters right.
I need to define a kind of an accumulator that will get a carry the average.
Right.
And we'll set it to zero.
And I need to set this as well to know how many elements have been input and how many numbers have been
going to sort of set it to zero first here.
Take a while true obviously sorry wild and white.
While true and they need to say okay every time I'm going ask the user to input enters a number.
So using an insert the number X..
Right.
And every time I say Okay let's count one.
So n plus equal one figures remember.
Okay.
All right so I accumulated the number because the user just entered the number eight.
So now I have the total numbers of the user have entered.
Actually 1.
Now Masaki my average
equals 2.
And that's pretty little bit tricky okay.
That's kind of you know the equation that we need to follow.
Going to say okay he is gonna say that's my outcome going to Psyche my average right getting multiplied
by when I say okay my N minus one.
All right.
And I'm going to add along and get on top of it.
The value of x which is simply the new number or a new value that users have entered.
So that's kind of my accumulators too.
First when I started when I take my average right now is zero right.
So zero.
OK so zero plus X which is my new number.
Okay that's will be my new number and whatever you're gonna be getting here I'm going to say Okay let's
take that and let's divided by the value of n right.
Okay.
That's it.
That's pretty much it.
So every time I'm gonna go ahead take my average multiplied by N minus one.
Add up to it the new number that I've got and divided by the new value n all right okay.
Looks pretty good so far.
Okay let's let's print my current average is and what we could do.
We could do this and here we're going to say okay let's print out the average.
All right.
Think there is maybe a bracket missing but let's let's see.
Let's see if that works or not.
Let's run that.
So I'm gonna tell you okay into numbers into the average for you.
And it seems that here's and enter a number.
Oh obviously sorry I should have added input.
My apologies.
There'll be input into the number Okay let's run it.
Did you enter a number and say let's say 10 average just 10 let's say insert for example 10 again averages
10.
Then again average just then makes sense.
Let's enter for example 20 average to twelve point five.
Okay.
Obviously because you insert the so many numbers right let's actually go ahead and exit this because
you know like I want to test it on numbers I actually like you know familiar with.
Let's let's interrupt and let's try to start and clear outputs let's run it again.
Okay.
So and So 10 and 10 you average let's say for example 20.
I know that the average should be 15 right.
If I run it great it looks good.
My count average 15.
Let's add another 15.
So there will be again 15 15 at a 20 the average will be 16 at a 20 the average will be sixteen point
six and so on so forth.
All right.
That's pretty much obviously two to exit this maybe you can insert for example like our letter or something
that you OK not that they were going to exit right away OK.
All right.
And that's pretty much it.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lectures.
I hope you guys enjoy the exercise lecture and in the future in the next lecture I'm going to learn
how can we do functions.
I'm going to do lambda expressions it has tons of information tons of learning coming up.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next lecture.