Hello everyone and welcome to this new lecture in the biggest lecture have been able to get an overview
of the functions and what functions do.
And we've been able as well to define our own function and as well call that function.
OK.
And this section we're going to look at kind of a little bit simpler actually example into how can we
use some of the built in functions that has already been made for us within Python environment.
All right.
So if you take a look at this table and zoom in a little bit you'll find that there is a lot of functions
like for example men that is like some.
There is let's say Max there are so many different functions in here that has already been made for
us.
You don't need to go and define them again.
So let's take a look at how can we do that.
All right.
So let's assume that I have for example a list.
OK.
And let's define that list which is equal to let's say 4 5 1 2 8 and 5.
And let's run it.
So here where here we go.
That's my list.
And let's define for example why other lists.
And I'm going to call the Y for instance let's say lists and I'm going to use our word range and get
a list from 1 2 7.
All right enter.
Let's take a look for example at x.
Here we go.
And let's take a look at Y.
Now we have numbers from one till up to and excluding seven right.
So from one to three.
Up until six.
All right.
Looks good.
So what I could do.
We're going to say okay let's use one of these readymade functions for us.
So let's for example pick an easy one.
Let's pick for instance the lens or lens which lens for lens for short.
So if I say Len and I can pass along here my value x shift enter it will return simply how many elements
would contained within our list x.
So here one two three four five six we have six elements.
All right.
Let's maybe take a look at the lens of Y come up as well with six element because we have six elements
in here.
OK.
All right looks good.
What if I wanted for example to pick maybe another function maybe pick let's say the main function or
let's say the max functions.
Let's take a look at it.
So it might take a min X enter you'll come up with number one because this is the least value the minimum
value within my list.
Let's take a look at the Max you're going to see a max of x.
Here we go.
And come up with a value of eight which the maximum value within our function.
All right.
Great great.
OK.
Let's take a look at another function.
So if you go up here you will find that there is a function called tuple OK which you simply can convert
from a list to a tuple extremely powerful.
So it's how can we do that.
What we could do we could say okay z equals two tuple of x.
So simply I took my value x which is simply here my list and I'm going to convert it to tuple shift
enter to take a look at Z.
Here we go now it becomes doesn't become square bracket anymore it became parentheses.
And if I take a look at type of z.
Here you go.
You come up with tuple if you call tuple are immutable.
That means you can't write on it.
Right you can't write to it.
Right.
OK let's take another example maybe let's sum up let's say these two lists together let's sum up all
the x and all the y together.
How can we do that.
So we could do is to print the summation of let's say x plus summation first let's say of for example
first of print summation of x.
So that would sum up all the elements within X first.
Let's take a look at it.
So print some X enter.
Here we go.
That's 25.
Okay.
And what I want you guys to do again this kind of a mini challenge.
Please go ahead pause a video and I want you to someplace to print all the summation of all the values
here of the wine list please go ahead pause a video and see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
Ask us to do is to simply print and I wanted to print summation of all the values within why shift enter.
Here we go.
We come up with 21 which is simply the summation of one two three four five and six.
All right.
What you could do as well.
What I could do as well.
I'm going to take you.
Let's go ahead and print.
Let's say the summation values of X plus Y which are simply adding up all the elements within X all
the elements within y.
And some of them are OK entry we go.
You come up with 46 which is simply twenty five plus twenty one.
All right.
Let's take a look at another built in function we shall call it zip.
OK.
Which is again defined here somewhere.
It's called zip.
This one again there are tons of functions.
Obviously I can't I won't be able to cover all of them because will take me like you know a whole new
course is to cover covered all these functions here.
I'm just walking through a couple of examples you guys can go ahead and read additional have additional
readings and maybe scan through all these functions if you wanted to.
So what he wanted to do is use a zip function to show you what what it does.
So that defined my list one equals two let's say 1 3 and 5.
I'm going to find another list called my list of two.
And here I'm going to put for example let's say 8 to 1 9 shift enter go.
And when I wanted to do is to simply kind of you know like what zip does it just make an iterator that
aggregates elements from each of the troubles.
OK.
I know it sounds confusing but let's see what we're going to do here.
What I could do we're going to take before I and NJ in zip and I'm gonna pass along my list one I'm
going to pass along my list to OK.
And every time I'm going to print I and J.
Or maybe I plus J K shift enter.
Here we go.
So now I've been able to simply kind of think of it as kind of you know like I'm like looking or aggregating
all the parameters.
You know like that are corresponding to each other.
So I'm thinking okay the first element 1 and 8.
So I sum them up.
So that's why I came up with nine and a C plus two US ON THEM UP came up with five five or nine some
of them up came up with 14 something like that.
All right.
Okay sounds good.
So let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to go back if you guys remembered our greetings function so let's define
our greetings function.
So I'm gonna say okay define greetings function and I'm going to pass along here my name and my greeting
right.
And what I'm doing as a print.
Happy New Year.
Exclamation mark here.
Curly brackets.
I wish you well whatever happiness or something and I say dot format format I'm going to pass along
here my name and pass along my greetings.
Just enter looks good.
And let's actually test the function first.
We actually have done that before in the previous section.
Please refer to their previous lecture.
For more details are going to see a function and then pass along key on my name or whatever name.
And I can here pass along as well let's say happiness you enter.
Happy New Year Ryan I wish you happiness.
Okay looks great.
Okay.
Well I wanted to do right now.
I wanted to use a zip kind of function to iterate across all these elements.
So let's actually copy them so now I have two lists Lyla Mitch.
Steve's sin to have happiness success love wealth and health.
And when I wanted to do is to simply go ahead and use the zip to simply call the function several times
and send along Layla.
And then happiness Mitch and then success Chanel and in love and so on.
Actually let's try it as a challenge.
Please go ahead pause the video and try to go ahead.
Use a zip in the exact same format as we have done here to print again.
Layla happiness Mitch success and so on using the greetings function.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge we'd ask you guys to do is to simply
use for AI and let's say J in zip.
It's exactly the same as before and I'm going to pass along the name list and I'm going to pass along
greetings lists all right.
And what I could do are going to say greetings lists which is my greatest function.
Now I need to call the function and I'm gonna pass along I and G in their shift enter and here we go.
Now I have happy New Year Layla for example because it's first name I wish you happiness and then happy
New Year.
Mitch second name I wish you success having Chanel I wish you love and so on so forth.
Okay.
And that's kind of a quick example to show you how can we use the zip function to kind of you know look
like separate or kind of a sign let's say names to each other here and pack them in a way in these variables
and then we can use the variables to sum them up send them through a function or do whatever with them
afterwards.
All right.
That's pretty much what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Let's recap.
And this lecture we have been able to kind of take a look at some of the built in functions.
Be able to take a look at you know look like tuples function zip function and Max min and length as
well.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
The next lecture going to keep going and we're gonna have some more kind of more advanced functions
in the next lecture.
Best of luck and we'll see you guys in the next one.