Hello everyone and welcome to this new project and this project we're going to learn how can we manipulate
PDA files or even deal with PDA files in a python environment.
So we tried here to summarize kind of you know the learning outcomes that we're gonna get out of this
project.
So first we're going to learn how can we extract information from a PDA if kind of you know extracting
text for instance.
We're going to learn how can we copy a single page and paste it or put it in a newly created PDA.
Another learning outcome they want to know how can we rotate PDA FS and write them to a new one to a
new PPF as well.
And then we're going to learn in learning outcome for how can we read multiple pages.
So instead of just reading one single page we're going to try to apply you know of the techniques that
we have learned so far in Python such as for loops for instance just to go to every single page and
actually extract information out of it.
And then finally learning outcome five we're going to learn how can we add watermark to a PDA.
So for example let's say if you have like a file and you wanted to add let's say it's confidential or
something like that then it will learn how can we do that.
All right.
OK.
That's pretty much all what we are going to learn in this project.
It's pretty interesting because you know we're gonna be learning without dealing with real data and
with real you know PDA Fs.
So the first step is before doing anything we need to install a library Python libraries called Pi PD
F2.
OK.
All right.
This is basically a common python library to work with with PDA files and the library can mainly be
used to read text from PDA files.
So we're not going to be able to actually read for example like images.
OK.
It's not like kind of mature yet.
There are tons of packages out there but this is just piping the F F2 which is the one we're gonna be
using.
We're only going to be able to read text files text information and then to install the library.
Please go ahead to the command window and just write pip install pi space pi PDA F2 please make sure
that P here is uppercase Y is lowercase PD F is uppercase and then to write and then it should take
like like in my case it took like almost I don't know five seconds and then you will find that there
is a bar going on and then wants to teach hundred percent then we'll get to go and then that means pipe
EDF when you actually import the library in here I'm going to show you we can imported like non pirate
pandas and once we do that that's it then we'll be able to apply all the all the functionalities basically
Piper you have to.
All right let's get started.
So first of all let's go ahead with the learning outcome 1 Let's see how can we do a very simple task
when we're going to extract information from a PDA.
Ok so my objective here is to just get a PDA file and simply just read it get some information about
it and maybe get some text out of it.
All right.
So let's get started.
So first of all we're going to say okay from pi PD F2 we're going to import what I'm going to do here
is I'm going to I'm going to import PD a file writer and PDA fi reader.
It's pretty much works like a FLAC files if you guys recall in the previous section in the fundamental
section of the course we would able to just use kind of you know like a file reader and fired writer.
It's pretty much the same as here.
We're just gonna use pi the F to module instead.
All right.
Okay.
I hope it's very clear for you guys now.
Let's zoom in.
All right.
Looks good.
So we're going to load PD f file writer.
Actually if you press tab it will show you that there are three options so that a speedy a file reader
and there is PBF file.
Again writer these other two stuff that we need.
OK.
Two classes that will each shift enter.
All right.
Well tell me invalid syntax because I need to insert the comma here shift enter.
Here we go.
All right.
So the first step is.
OK.
What is the PD.
Where does the PD file.
They're going to be dealing with.
So if you guys go here to the course package again you will find that under practical projects in python
there is working with PD files folder.
These numbering might be changed.
OK.
So just go to the working with video files and here you will find that there is a PD f called Harvard
Business School.
Again this is just a PDA file you know readily available online that show showed you how can you apply
to business school.
OK.
Within just just a sample PD.
And you know if you guys take a look at it you'll find that there is you know a bunch of text here.
There is an image here so we're not going to be able to capture that information.
If you go down here to this page you'll find that there's you know 20 18 President and fellow Harvard.
You know you go down here is business school right for you.
I'm just trying to read it for you so when do we actually captured or off in the page.
You guys can know what to expect the text you're going to expecting.
So you know getting the MBA can be found almost any organization standing here what is MBA view by the
industry with an MBA improve your chances of getting hired and so on.
And what should you do to prepare for business school.
And if you scroll down you'll find here like a lot of information anyways the most important information
here that we have almost around eight pages.
OK.
So we have this speech four out of eight.
And if it keeps calling down these are all the information they're going to be dealing with or treating.
All right.
OK.
That's basically the PDA file and the video file is contained within the course package.
Or you guys can download it as well from Harvard Business School Web site.
All right.
So let's get started.
So first of all what we're going to do here we're going to want to open our file so it's very similar
to see as we file operation what we're going to do I'm going to say OK F equals to open and what we're
going to do here we're going to open our Harvard again if you do tap autocomplete.
It should show you OK.
That is a PDA file called Harvard Business School.
The PDA.
Which makes sense because this file is actually contained within the exact same notebook so that you
put a notebook here which is PDA file manipulation project filming you guys won't have this because
that's the file that I'm building.
As we go you guys we're going to have basically the solution right away which is PDA file manipulation
project.
All right.
OK.
So what we're gonna do we're going to open that file.
We can open it merely for reading purposes you can say read and we can read binary because going to
see that file in a binary format and we're going to be dealing with it in a binder format as well and
we'll write as one in binary format shift enter looks great.
All right.
So as long as you didn't get any errors.
That's a great sign.
And obviously as long as you didn't get any error in here that means PBF to have has been correctly
installed.
So the next step is we're going to create a PD f reader object to the overall idea is after we open
the file we are going to use mainly either PDA reader object or PDA right to object and then take the
object do whatever you want to it except pages out of it.
You know write pages to it and that's pretty much exactly the same as we have done in files before.
So what we gonna do is get a key read on the scores PDA if you guys can call it whatever equals two
will get instantiate an object out of PDA file reader because I wanted to read the file.
Right.
So I want to read the file which file I mean are either one of 3D file F so I wanted to read the file
F and using a file either are going to instantiate an object.
OK.
Kind of an object we'll call it three it read PD f or repeat f shift enter.
Here we go.
This is basically contained all the information we would need.
So let's assume that I wanted for example to get let's say some information regarding the documents.
All right.
So let's go ahead and obtain some information.
So going to take a read underscore PBF and then dot and then we can start to get some document information.
So I'm gonna say okay get document and actually if HEB it will tell me okay read get document info.
So if you press on it and then here please don't forget these two just you know empty parentheses and
shift enter.
And here we go.
This is simply just kind of you know like the information related the documents or the author was Andrew
you know Barlow Barlow the company is Harvard University creation date was 2018 you know like of August
and here it shows you like you know even the creator the producer and so on so forth.
It's pretty interesting.
And please go ahead and you don't give it a shot for any of the PD files but please when we are building
here our project let's stick with this because this function what I realize it's just it's not fully
mature.
The PI PD F2.
So it's not like if the file the P A file for example is let's say encrypted or there is like a lock
to it you know or there is any password it would be very difficult to actually obtain that information.
It might you know crash or you might not be able to get any information so please stick with this video
file first and maybe like you know try like all a couple of samples as well.
And and here we go Battier again as we learn as we build up our knowledge please stick with this video
file.
The next step is let's go ahead and maybe get some information and this information gets a free dot
underscore.
And what we could do.
We're going to say OK maybe show me how many pages we're going to say numb as you press tab it will
tell me on pages.
All right.
Just enter.
Tell me Well there are eight pages in there.
All right.
Which makes complete sense.
OK the next step is let's go ahead and actually grab a page.
Let's see how can we do that.
So what we could do.
Okay.
Read underscored PDA which is again our read reader object and there is a method called get page.
So if you press actually get any pressed have you'll find that there's a lot of information here.
Get page get outlines get object get on pages get is encrypted.
You know like I actually have not like I haven't tried all of them but let's go ahead and maybe try
to get page so going to say it get page and what we could do we can specify okay which page do we need.
So here for instance I'm going to grab let's say page number zero.
Okay.
All right.
And the point is here once we grab the page basically you'll be able to grab the entire thing.
Right.
What we need that we need to get it were extracted text out of this page.
So afterwards we're gonna say dot extract text.
All right.
So that will extract the test text out of this page which is coming out of our read PBF kind of object
which is simply the file.
Think of this replay F as the file.
All right.
So we're going to get page number zero out of our file and then going to extract text only out of this
page because this page comes with images comes with tons of stuff.
Right.
OK shift enter.
And here we go.
So there is undergraduate resource seeders carried services.
So if you go back to our PD off file you can have it open here.
So
so here we go.
That's our Video file
so you'll find that because I specified page zero.
So this is an image that I wasn't able to grab that information but I was able to grab that right.
So we were able to obtain you know like 6 1 7 and so on.
Let's actually make sure that we have this.
OK.
So here are the numbers 6 1 7.
And there's Harvard University news and so on so forth.
All right.
Perfect.
OK.
Let's keep going.
So this is simply our how can we expect the text right.
But what we could do is that we can grab that and put it for example in let's say sample under a score
page on the score page on the score text.
Right.
This is simply our sample.
So this shift enter and we can actually go ahead copy this and paste it here and we're going to get
the same text right.
Maybe let's go ahead and try page one.
All right shift enter shift enter.
Here we go.
So now would we be able to obtain you know like all these like information.
And if you go back to page one you would find that there is some information in here.
2018 President and fellow you know like Office of key services and so on so forth all right.
So what I want you guys to do is to simply please go ahead pause a video and please try to print or
try to obtain sample text for page five and Page Six.
So I wanted to simply create kind of two kind of variables in here that has text for page five and text
for Page Six.
Please go ahead positive video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
When I ask you guys to do is to simply obtain page five and Page Six so if you can copy that piece of
here and we can obtain here before page let's say page five.
And if you please press shift enter and if you take a look at it maybe we can call this for example
like page five for instance you know so sample page let's say page for example five underscored text
and we can come here.
Copy it pasted.
And here we go.
So that's all the text that we contain in here.
All right.
What we could do as well is you can say Okay I need Page Six too.
So I'm gonna say Okay page six and I can come here and do this and come here and do this.
And here we go.
All right.
So again that's all the text we get.
With these bare in mind that the documents talked with index zero.
Right.
So what I meant I need page 5 or Page 6 I just need like index here 5 or six.
OK.
All right.
So that's pretty much the challenge.
And the last step they wanted to do after we do that is because we open the file in here we said F equal
open.
Harvard Business School I need to actually go ahead and close the file so I'm gonna say OK f dot close.
And that should cause a shift enter.
He would go.
Now we close the file and that's pretty much how can we read any information from our PDA.
All right.
I hope you guys enjoy this lecture.
And let's recap what we have done so far.
So in this lecture we're able to go ahead and actually extract information out of a PDA.
So here we just obtained.
We first we imported Piper the F two and then we open it read PBF will pin some document information
and then within a couple of number of pages and then we're able to actually extract text out of our
sample text PDF and we're able as well to do kind of the mini challenge to extract so many pages and
as well afterwards we go ahead and close the file.
And that's pretty much all we'll have for this lecture in the next lectures.
Going to walk you through how to copy a single page and put it in a newly created PDA.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.