Hello everyone and welcome to this new project and this project we're going to detect and learn how
can we detect faces and images.
And we're also going to learn how can we detect eyes and images too.
It's actually really really fun project because you know like you can actually apply it and maybe upload
your own picture and see how can you detect for example your face or maybe upload your family picture
for instance and see how can we detect you know the entire families you know like faces and we'll also
be able to see and detect eyes too which is really fun.
All right let's get started.
So in this project we're going to have kind of three parts.
So the learning outcome one we're going to learn how can we detect one face just one single face in
an image and then afterwards we're going to learn how can we detect multiple faces or more than one
face in an image.
So think of it you know that might be for loops in there and we might detect more than one face and
then learning outcome three we're going to take eyes and faces too.
So within that face I want to go inside and try to extract information related to the eyes too which
is really fun.
All right.
So the first step is.
OK.
What's what.
What images are we looking for.
So in the course package OK it's actually go back here's so in the course package you would find that
there is two JP images.
OK.
One of them is called scientists.
And the other one's called Trudeau let's open Trudeau one.
So this is basically the image of Justin Trudeau the Canadian prime minister as we speak.
And he's one of my favorite politician actually.
So we're going to see how can we apply.
Kind of you know like an official intelligence in a way and to just go ahead and detect you know this
specific face and then afterwards we'll see how can we detect the eyes as well within this image.
OK.
This is the first step.
And then afterwards there is another image called scientists.
It's open it.
And these kind of you know one of my favorite images of all this kind of you know a list of all the
scientists basically you would you would have here and we'll see how can we apply you know kind of face
classifiers to actually go ahead and detect all these faces within the image.
It's pretty interesting pretty fun too.
All right.
So that's kind of the two inputs and other input that we're going to have as well.
It's what we call it the hard cascades classifiers.
OK.
So this is a folder here is called Hard cascades.
You open it you would find that there are two files in there Excel files.
OK here this is this course is not about like you know an entire artificial intelligence machine learning
course but the overall idea here and that's what I want you guys to know is that these two classifiers
here this is kind of think of it as two train models.
So these are models that have been trained already.
OK.
They have been you know like like already taking care of what we're going to do here we're just going
to use them in practice.
OK.
This is specifically used for AI detection.
So if you send it to it any image it should detect ice into it here.
This is what called a frontal face if you once you use it.
It would simply going to detect just just basically faces or within any image.
You know it's already trained already beforehand using multiple images to actually detect certain image
within within a picture.
OK.
That's the I'm sorry it detects certain faiths within an image.
My apologies.
That's pretty much all what we need to know.
OK.
That's overall information they're gonna be using throughout this project.
And that's pretty much what I have for this lecture is just a quick overview of what we're going to
be doing.
Let's get started.
In the next lecture I'm gonna walk you through the learning outcome one which is how can we detect a
single face.
Best of luck and see you guys in the next lecture.
Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
The previous lecture I walked through a quick overview of the files what we're going to be doing and
let's get started right away and let's detect one single face.
Let's see how can we do that.
All right.
So first of all let's go ahead and import our important packages.
Case we're going to import num pi as MP and we're going to import open CV which is CV 2.
OK.
If you guys
and we're going to import open service we're going to import CV to.
If you guys please go ahead to the setup lecture and try to see how can you install open CV.
Okay.
And I'm going to have like a lot of detailed instructions on how to install an open CV in there.
Let's press shift enter.
If you have it installed you should you have no problem no error.
We're going to appear here.
All right.
The next step is when I want you guys to do is to simply go ahead and read one single image.
So we're going to be doing we're going to be detecting one face.
So if you guys remember in the course actual course package you'll find that there is
there is two images here Trudeau and scientists.
So what I wanted to do is to read the Trudeau image and that's in that.
That's the main image you're gonna be working with in this learning outcome this section.
So let's get started.
So let's actually zoom in a little bit because we're able to see it very clearly.
So let's go ahead.
We're going to see OK CV two dots image reads.
And here I just need to pass my image.
So the name of the image is Trudeau dot JP.
That should read the image.
And I'm gonna take it and put it in image C stands for color.
So this is a colored image.
All right.
Shift enter.
Looks great.
Let's go ahead and actually visualize this.
Go ahead and see it.
So we're going to use open CV as well to visualize the image.
So going to say CV to dot image show and here I need to specify the title for the image.
She recalled it.
Let's say Trudeau
face.
You can call it whatever you want and actually call it in colors because it's colored.
And I'm going to specify comma and here I need to pass along what image I need to be printing.
So so I can copy this and paste it here.
OK.
Please please do not go and run this.
Because if you run it you know you're going to get into loops and then the kernel will crash in order
to do this.
You know it could only open CV you have to include these two lines as well.
So going to say CV to dot.
Wait.
Qui OK.
And then afterwards we're gonna say CV to dot destroy all windows actually free press tab and you will
autocomplete and say destroy all windows.
Simply put here when we put these two lines because once we show the image OK you will find that here.
It's kind of you know the that's the code is actually kind of you know stuck in a loop.
Right.
So in order to exit that loop we're gonna be waiting for specific keys.
If you enter any key once you enter any key it will destroy all windows.
We're just gonna destroy the image.
OK.
Just gonna hide the image again and that should be able to exit that loop and keep going and actually
run the next cells.
OK let's go ahead and give it a shot.
Press shift enter and here we go.
So first first step is this is our image right.
Actually let's go back then the way it did this.
So if you guys take a look here at our colonel you'll find that there is astro here which means it's
kind of we're stuck here.
The program is just waiting for you to provide something provide an input do something.
OK.
So again this is the image.
This is again we're stuck.
If you press enter it you'll find it here the ASIC is gone and we destroyed all windows.
The image is gone already.
It's like Snapchat we're in a way.
All right.
Okay looks good.
Let's go back here.
All right.
So the next step is what I wanted to do.
Kind of you know quick exercise.
We're going to go ahead and actually convert that image into grayscale and visualize the image again.
So to do that we're gonna see a image underscore grey equals to CV to dot CV t color please make sure
that C is uppercase and what we're going to do here we're gonna pass along our image color which is
our colored image in here and we have to specify what do you want to do with it.
We're gonna say OK CV two dots actually if you press tab it would show you tons of information here.
These are kind of you know everything you could you can normalize image you can do aspect ratio can
do focal lens.
You know like tons of stuff you need like like I don't know like ten peach these to actually go through
all this stuff there is tons of information here.
We don't care about all this stuff.
We just wanted to convert from a color to grayscale so going gonna say OK See I'm gonna say color on
the score BGR which is stands for blue green and red to gray and that's what we wanted to do was to
convert from colored to grayscale.
That's what we want to do.
And the this simply will just going to convert our image color into our image Great.
OK.
And what I'm gonna do we're gonna copy these to actually copy the entire thing here and paste it here.
And they're going to do two though face in grayscale because I wanted to plug the entire image in grayscale
instead of image underscore color.
I'm going to save the image underscore the gray.
OK.
That should plot simply our image gray here.
We can do the exact same Wakey and destroy as well.
All right.
Looks good.
Shift enter.
All right.
It will tell me that you know like this model is not is not defined so CV to see that the colors actually
this has to be all uppercase.
My apologies.
So going to say this all uppercase with color on the score.
Be sure to Gray.
Please make sure that these two are lowercase c v 2 2 and then this has to be all uppercase shift enters.
Looks good.
OK.
Now there is no errors.
Error was gone shift.
Enter.
And here we go.
So if you actually go here.
You will find that this is my grayscale image.
OK.
And looks good.
That means the function actually worked.
And if you go back to our step here we funded what stuck in a loop right.
So in order to exit this loop let's go back to the image and press enter and that should exit our loop
in here.
All right.
Looks great.
So that's pretty much all what we need to know right now at the moment.
Just are just like how can we actually just load the low that image converted from colors to grayscale
and actually plot our image.
OK.
All right.
And what we going gonna do here I'm just going to conclude this lecture at the step at the stage and
in the next lecture I'm gonna show you how can we start to actually like take specific our face classifier
and start to detect specific faces.
But before we do that what I want you guys to do here is to for that mini challenge I want you guys
to insert a couple of new cells in here and I want you to instead of reading through though image I
want to treat the other image which is what we have here provided quality scientist image and converted
crude grayscale as well.
Please go ahead positive video and they will see you guys after the challenge.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
What I ask us to do is simply instead of having Trudeau dodge JP I just wanted to have scientists instead.
We're gonna take a scientists I hope it is exactly the same scientists.
There is an S at the end.
So here which is an add s all right.
And that's it.
So let's run it run it run it.
And here we go.
This is the image of all the scientists right.
And then we're stuck in a loop.
Press enter again it's colored image.
Here we converted from colors to grayscale.
And here we go.
This is our grayscale image.
Okay.
Okay looks good.
Shift enter looks great right.
And that's it.
Let's go back to actually our image again.
Trudeau okay.
Make sure that's actually functioning properly looks great.
Go back here.
Run this.
This looks great.
And here we go.
All right.
That's pretty much all I have for this lecture.
Hope you guys enjoyed it.
In the next lecture we're gonna go ahead and actually start to classify and detect faces.
Best of luck and we'll see you guys in the next lecture.