Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the previous lecture.
We're able to load specific images.
OK.
Which is true though true though image.
And we're able to actually convert the image from color to grayscale.
This lecture.
Let's get started and see how can we apply our face detection algorithm to actually extract the face
and actually locate the face.
Let's see how can we do that.
First of all let's go ahead and import our what we call a cascade classifier.
Again this this course is not about you know like a like machine learning and artificial intelligence
total course there is a section on machine learning and efficient intelligence but it doesn't Google
a little bit deeper.
How can we perform you know all the training for example for using cascade classifiers was kind of an
advanced computer vision techniques.
What I want you guys just to know here that we have trained model already obtained in there.
OK.
These models are ready trained.
It's kind of you know like in here is called ha cascades.
They have already trained.
Excel documents that contains hard cascade AI which you simply just can be used to detect AIS within
any image.
And this one is what we call it hard cascade frontal face default that can be used to actually detect
just faces within an image.
OK.
So we have one that tech faces and we have one that tech eyes.
That's pretty much it.
What we're going to do is just going to import that cascade classifier that said we're just going to
use it in practice.
Let's go ahead and see what I can do that when I see a face underscored detection equals to CV to dot
cascades.
And if you actually press tab it would show you this cascade classifier.
And then here we need to just specify the path of our of our classifiers here because I'm detecting
faces I'm going to say OK ha cascade
cascades and then get a pass along key at our Ha cascade on the score frontal face on the score default
dot X AML.
And if everything works you should have no problem.
So when you press shift enter looks good.
So pretty much now we have kind of think about it that now we have kind of a 3D model called face detection.
You can use it right away deployed in practice to detect faces within images.
OK.
So how can we do that.
What we could do going to say okay please could you please give me the faces give me what can happen
here I'm going to return all the coordinates of the face.
So in those image for instance we cannot attorney OK we're going to turn kind of a rectangle around
his face.
So we're going to do here we're going to take a face as equals to we're going to get our face detection
in here pasted.
And what we're going to do then apply kind of a method called detect multi scale detect multi scale
actually tab it will show you on the face detection there is a detect multi scale.
And what I need to do simply here I just need to pass my image on the school color which is my Trudeau's
image here in color format OK.
And here they need to specify those just two numbers.
I can't tell you exactly what you mean by these two numbers here let's say going to say one point one
and then I'm going to say five.
All right.
So what do you mean by this.
So actually try to include here the information for you guys.
So when we apply a scale classifier or face detection classifier here in this case to detect multi scale.
You would find that we pass along our input image which is here in each color and we pass along kind
of two parameters.
The first one is what we call it scale factor.
The second one is what we call admin neighbors.
OK what do you mean by this.
Again it's very very simple might look a little bit intimidating but it's very simple.
So the first one is called scale factor.
The overall idea is that we wanted to kind of scale our image just just think think of it as taking
just one image and make it you know look smaller versions out of it and larger versions out of it.
And this kind of process we'll call it in computer vision quality limiting you kind of creating like
a different pyramid.
Think of it you know at the pyramids you know in Egypt for example we have like three kind of you know
like copies of them right.
We have like a large you know other pyramid and then there is an intermediate one and there is a smaller
one.
We think they are all pretty much have the same features right they all look like a pyramid.
They have the same color.
Pretty much the same thing but just different sizes.
That's the overall idea.
So scale factor simply when I say one point one.
That means we're just going to reskill the image and you know kind of reduce it to 10 percent of its
size.
When I say let's say for one point two It means image is reduced by 20 percent each time it scale.
That means I'm going to take the image I'm going to reduce it let's say by 20 percent and run the classifier
again and then reduce it again by 20 percent on the classifier again and so on.
So when I say one point two.
That means each step will going to be 20 percent.
When I say one point one that means each step will going to be 10 percent.
All right.
So think about it here it once we go let's say smaller and smaller let's say to one point or five for
example.
That means five percent it will take much longer time because that means I'm thinking the original image
I'm Reese and it get several times just making creating multiples of them.
Why am I doing this.
I'm doing this because the classifier was trained on a specific size of the image.
What I wanted to do is simply when I plot let's say through this image let's actually show it.
I wanted to create the classifier to for example look at faces in here and then look at faces in here
look at facing.
That's one of the classified is doing just scanning through the entire image and trying to look for
the face.
Right.
So for example if my face is smaller let's say here for example if like a little kid in here for example
in here right.
The face might be smaller right.
So what I need to do that I need to take the image and scale it into different multiple scale.
That's the overall idea.
Take the original image and reskill it into smaller ones just to try to look for the face simply.
OK.
OK let's first step the next step is we'll call it Min neighbors and this parameter is used to specify
how many neighbors each candidate rectangle should have to retain it.
Think about it as kind of you know lack of like how many times I won't to be able to detect phases.
So let's say here I'm going to again let's open ours to this image.
So let's say I detected four examples in here.
I'm going to detect one face and then gonna shift my rectangle little bit rights and then I say OK I
detected another face and then one more time I take another face.
So let's say once I detect once kind of you know name in the neighboring in the neighborhood of these
pixels I detect let's say five times faces or five faces.
OK then we're going to say you know what.
That's an actual face.
Why.
Because there's a repetition.
That means you know like a lot of pixels a lot of you know like classifiers when I scan through the
images.
A lot of neighbors within that neighboring area says okay you know what.
There is a face there.
That's the overall idea.
OK.
So the number is generally range from three to six.
The parameter will mainly affect the quality of the detected faces and higher values would result in
less detections but with higher quality.
Simply put if you set high values if you said let's say for example that number set it to 10 for instance.
That means I need to have at least 10 neighbors they say that there is a face there.
Right.
Which we're going to reduce kind of the false positives.
However if you said it to let's say 1 you might have kind of you know like a lot of a lot of.
Like in all wrong for example estimate we're going to say okay you know maybe there is a face there
maybe that is faith.
Because I'm relying on one single point.
Right.
But if I have kind of maybe three to six that should add more fidelity in there and then we're not going
to be detecting you know random faces somewhere.
All right let's go ahead and run this command so we're on it and here we go.
So now what happened is I have been able to detect phases which is really powerful.
You know if you think about it you know we don't need to learn any artificial intelligence or computer
vision or whatever just apply this.
You know it has all the not all the smartness in there.
You literally can create an app right now because now in the faces here actually let's take a look at
faces.
Here we go.
It was just tell us these are the coordinates of the face.
OK.
So again it's not that simple this is going to show you what they mean by all these coordinates but
the overall idea that you know like the that this form this function told me OK you know what I have
detected one single face and here you go.
These are the pixel locations of my face.
All right.
It's really really amazing.
So what what what are these what are these numbers.
So let's go ahead and actually visualize these numbers.
So if you let's go ahead and run the face here so you'll find that there are kind of certain numbers
here 3 3 2 1 1 2 1 2 0 8 and 2 0 8.
OK.
What's happening here.
All right.
So the first two numbers these are the coordinates of the top left rectangle index or corner.
Right.
So what happened is the detect faces will going to detect a rectangle here around the face here.
OK.
So in that rectangle in the top left corner this is simply our coordinates.
So what this saying is saying OK if you go here to this is the X and this is the Y.
So X is and my apologies if you go back here to the image please note that this point in here this is
zero and zero.
No y is doing this.
So at this point again is zero and zero please don't get confused.
Again it's very very simple.
This is our origin.
OK.
This is what we mean when we move to the right.
That means we're going x direction when we go down that means we'll go to the y direction.
Right.
So when I say I went here let's say for example three hundred and thirty two.
So I move to the right.
Three hundred and thirty two pixels.
OK.
OK the next point here was if you go down the next point was 1 to 1.
All right.
What at this point me.
This point is the y coordinate of the top left corner of my rectangle.
So what I'm saying is this one to one point is I go down here one hundred and twenty one pixels.
And that's what I'm getting.
Basically I'm stuck here.
This is the coordinates of the point of the first rectangle that has been detected which is only one
rectangle.
All right.
Okay.
This looks great.
What about the other two numbers.
What about two or eight and two or eight you actually go back here you'll find that is 2 8 2 8 2 8 and
2 8 are simply my the dimensions of the the width and height of my rectangle.
So now I have the coordinate right now I need to know how far I need to go east right here which is
2 8.
And how far do I need to go down which is here do it.
It looks like you know it's basic it won't be a rectangle kind of a square because we gonna be drawing
here kind of a square with two 8 dimensions for both sides.
That's it.
That's pretty much what I want you guys to do press shop press enter or press whatever key and let's
go back here.
And here we go.
All right so let's go ahead and actually name them.
So we're gonna say Okay let's take a look at faces and let's go ahead and grab for example one.
So if I see faces of one shift enter that will give me 1 to 1.
If I see faces of zero that should bring me the first element within my an umpire array which is you
know like 3 3 2 1.
Again this is index zero index 1 6 2 index 3 right.
And Section bigger and let's zoom in a little bit okay.
So faces zero faces one faces two.
Let's take a look at it and face it three as well.
OK.
2 8.
If I made faces for to me.
Well I don't know you because index 4 is out of bounds.
This is in the 0 1 2 3.
All right Felix good right.
So what I want you guys to do and that would be our mini challenge in here to shift enter.
I wanted to simply take these faces and name them like this.
I mean to say X equals to something y equals to something.
X is the coordinates x coordinates of of my top left coordinate within my rectangle.
Why is the y coordinate of my tent top left corner of my rectangle and then I'm gonna say my width of
my rectangle and my height or my rectangle equals something.
Okay obviously we're gonna be faces of something.
Please go ahead pause a video and try to fill out here.
What do you mean by X Y W and H.
It's just simply renaming of my faces array here into a bunch of variables.
Please go ahead pause the video and then I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out what the challenge will ask you has to do simply go
ahead and assign faces of all and zero which is my first element here.
It's so easy to one that would be my X coordinates right and then I'm gonna go ahead and take faces
of all and 1 and that will be my Y coordinate and then I'm going to have faces all and 2 which is gonna
be my next coordinates and then I'm going to have faces all and 3 which are gonna be my last coordinate
in here press shift enters.
Here we go now I have X Y W and H and here we go.
Now I'm pretty much ready to go ahead to leverage these coordinates and actually draw in a physical
rectangle around the image.
Let's see how can we do that.
What we could do.
We can say okay an open CV which we say see CV to dot rectangle to actually press tab it would show
you that is recovered pose a rectangle reduce the map repeat tons of stuff here.
I wanted to draw a rectangle so going to see a rectangle.
OK where do you want to draw the rectangle.
I wanted to draw rectangles actually if you press shift tab shift and tab it will show you here how
can you draw a rectangle to tell you OK.
You need to pass along your original image.
You need to pass along key point one and point two so I need to pass along two points.
Basically where point one and point two actually if you go up if you go down here these are kind of
you know like I tell you the opposite corners.
So I need to specify the dimensions of the two opposite corners.
Top left corner and bottom right corner.
Let's see how can we do that.
Okay.
First I need to pass along my image so my image is contained in here which is image color.
Copy that.
It's pasted here.
And let's go ahead and actually specify my make ordinance first I'm going to say Okay I need my top
left corner which is simply my X and Y.
If you guys remember you're gonna say X might end y.
That's my first point or point one and then it'll specify the coordinates for point two.
So if you guys remember that point one is top left corner point two is bottom right corner.
Right.
So simply if I take my x value and add it to it my width which is to an eight or two eight that will
give me more the other point of the other X coordinates.
And if I do the same thing as well if I say Y plus H if I take my top left point and they added the
height to it which is 2 or 8 as well that should bring me down to the bottom right corner again.
If you guys can visualize it let's go ahead and do it here.
Let's see what's happening here is I have this point right.
So I have X and Y that indicates the top left corner within my rectangle.
I'm going to be drawing here right.
What I need to do I need to specify this is point one here.
I need to specify point two right.
To do that I mean I say okay let's go elastic X and add width to it.
Let's take let's take Y which they have here.
Apologies.
Let's take Y which is this point the coordinates of y and let's add height to it which is you know 2
8 as well.
That will bring me down to this coordinate.
That's the overall idea goes a little bit confused.
Don't worry about it.
I'm going to show you exactly when we actually plot the rectangles what I mean by this afterwards I
need to specify the color.
Okay what's the color of my rectangle.
So I'm gonna say okay.
0 2 4 2 5 5 we can call it whatever 2 5 5.
That indicates I believe the yellow color.
And we'll see what that.
And then here specify the thickness of my rectangle.
So going to take a sickness let's say three.
All right.
Okay looks good.
Now I draw a rectangle.
Let's go ahead and use open TV as well.
So going to say CV to dot image show and here I'm going to take a single face detection because I'm
detecting single face and I need to visualize image C which is the image along with the rectangle drawn
on it.
And please don't forget to add CV to that weight key and please don't forget to add as well our CV to
that destroy all windows
all right.
Looks fantastic.
Shift enters
and here we go.
All right.
Actually open in my next my next window.
Here we go.
This is our beautiful rectangle in there.
All right.
So if you guys take a look at it you will find that we have been detecting the top left corner which
is x and y coordinate and this is simply the point that has X plus W or x plus width and Y plus the
height which is this point.
All right.
That's it.
Amazing.
So that's pretty much all what I have for this lectures.
What I want you guys to do is please go ahead.
Another mini challenge posed a video and pass along here instead of the yellow color.
Pick any other color.
OK.
So just pick whatever color you wanted here and here change the thickness from three let's say to six
for example maybe 10.
And please let me know what you guys notice.
Please go ahead pause a video and I will see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
If you guys were able to figure out the challenge what I ask you guys to do is simply pick any color.
So maybe we're going to set this to 0 for example that would give me another another color and here
instead of three I'm going to make it let's say six and let's take a look what's going to happen here
shift enter.
And here we go.
Now it became red OK.
And the thickness of the line becomes a little bit different.
Let's actually make it maybe 10 for example shift enter.
Here we go.
The line became more thick.
And here we have again the red red color.
Maybe go here and make it all let's say two five five believe.
Let's go ahead to five five and make this maybe 20 enter.
Here we go now.
1 5 5 2 5 5 2 4 5.
It's white and the rectangle becomes way thicker.
Obviously it looks weird.
So let's go back and maybe set it back.
Let's say 2 2 5 5 0 2 5 5 and said this to 10 shift enter.
Here we go.
Actually a draw.
Plotted on top of it.
So.
So let's go back.
And so every time I'm doing I'm doing this I'm basically taking my image color and then adding to it.
Right.
So if you repeat the entire thing from scratch let's go ahead and run it.
So now I know that the new image right.
So let's do the grayscale too if I wanted to.
It looks good.
Keep going.
Cascade classifier detect multi scale.
Go to the faces faces define the coordinates and do the detection.
And here we go.
All right.
OK.
So I only have one rectangle that has been drawn and with the thickness of 10.
And with that specific color.
All right.
That's pretty much all I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
In the next lecture what I'm going to do is I'm going to walk you through my learning outcome too which
is how to detect multiple faces it's very interesting when I take another image and say I'm gonna take
multiple faces and then the next lecture I'm going to show you how can we detect the eyes and faces
as well.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.