Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the previous lecture.
We were able to detect a face and we actually applied it to detect to those face face.
Let's go ahead and actually run it and let's take a look at at it.
So a precious entry shift enters.
Here we have the face.
We're able to actually convert from color to grey OK and we're able to obtain image on the score G stands
for image underscore great shift enter.
Here we go.
This is a great image.
And here we're able to actually run our cascade classifier just load it first and then use detect multi
scales on OUR IMAGE TO RETURN BACK THE COORDINATES FOR OUR FACE enter.
Here we have all our coordinates for our face.
And then here we realize that we've got the coordinates of the face okay.
Which is x and y coordinates for the top left corner point.
And here we have the width and height.
And here we're able to actually draw the actual rectangle on to those face and that's the first step
in our project.
The next step is going to learn how can we detect multiple faces not just one single face.
So say how can we do that.
First of all actually gonna do pretty much the same steps as before.
So that's how can we do it again to see a image underscore color equals to CV to dot image read and
what I've got to do here instead of reading to those I'm just going read scientists.
Actually if I press tab because the image is contained within within the same folder we're just going
to load it here.
Looks could shift enter if I wanted to take a look at it.
I'm going to take a CV to that image show and he'd I need to let's call it something so classic here
scientists in color and I'm going to pass along my image on this court see Oh my apologies I can actually
ask you before never to never to do that.
That's my bad.
So if you actually do that you'll find that you come up with this image this figures showing not responding
and you know the kernel will crash and please don't do it.
You know like like like I did right now let's call the program OK.
And in order to do that in order to avoid this.
OK so going to restart please restart.
We need to make sure that we have CV to the wheat key and destroy all the windows as well.
Whenever we whenever we use CV to image show it.
All right let's actually run it again.
So you're tell me CBT is not even defined says go ahead and find open CV enter.
Good.
Go ahead and load it.
All right.
Here we go.
That's our image basically of all the scientists in color.
So and the image is still running.
If you guys can see the kernel is still running.
So let's go ahead and please press whatever key enter for example just to exit.
All right let's go ahead and actually apply more than one face detection suffering and a Jew going to
say OK face underscored detection equals two.
We're going to say CV to dot cascade classifier if you press tab it will show you a cascade classifier
and then all we could do here is we could say OK ha cascades
backslash ha cascades underscore.
Actually if you press tab it will auto complete.
OK so it found frontal face the default example shift enter.
Looks good and the next step so it could do here.
You could say OK let's go ahead and use face detection multi scale to actually turn my face.
So to say face as equals to face detection dot detect multi scale.
So I'll tell you again tab detect multi scale.
We can pass along our image underscore see and we here specify let's say one point one and five when
five guys remember from previous lecture that one point one.
This was just you know like please kill the image every time at 10 percent of its of its value just
to try to find every single image every single face basically in our image.
And here when we say five that means I need to have five neighbors effect
to simply detect five pages or 35 images to simply detect five faces kind of next to each other to make
sure that this will going to be kind of you know like a positive or a face that's been detected.
All right.
OK.
The shift enters it's taken care of while that's good.
Good sign.
Okay.
And then we can go ahead and instead of just plotting one phase.
What I need to do now think it is to go ahead and actually create a for loop.
I say for every time we're gonna say yeah return x y width and height and I'm going to go into faces.
So here faces contains simply every single face that has been detected.
So what I'm going to do here I'm gonna say okay please go ahead.
Interfaces return x y w and H in every single phase afterwards.
When I say okay CV to dot rectangle I want to draw the right angle.
Right.
And I want to draw their finger on my image color and every time I'm gonna pass along my X and Y which
is a top left coordinate and then I'm gonna say okay let's return x plus width and then Y plus the height
is plus my apologies.
And then here again specify the colors too.
So when I say okay 0 2 2 5 5 and let's say 2 5 5 and then maybe we can make it let's say thickness with
3.
And then afterwards once we do that then we can go ahead and actually plot our image of the Mississippi
to that image show.
And here we can call it multiple face detection or multi multi face detection.
And I can pass along my image underscore see which is the image with along with all the tangles drawn
on top of it.
And then please again don't forget to add CV to dot wait.
Ki and afterwards after we exit the loop make sure that you include as well CV to dot destroy all windows.
All right.
That's it.
Let's take a look.
Let's actually test it.
So let's run that once again my color image looks good.
Let's run this.
We should take all the faces and let's do this.
All right.
So it's telling me something is not right CV 2 is not defined yet.
My apologies should be CV too.
So again we're stuck in a loop.
Let's close the program okay.
Colonel is dead.
Let's go back again and run.
Open CV because that's what we need.
First let's go down here and run its case and I will have my image again.
Zoom in a little bit too.
We're going to run the classifier looks good and let's run this afterwards.
OK.
Another error source telling me CV 2 has no attribute weight key.
So here wait.
Key key K here has to be uppercase.
Again my apologies you guys might be running through all these new like problems already.
So let's close the program again and let's run it again.
So let's run.
CONAN Has died.
Okay so let's run it again.
Shift enters looks good.
Let's go back here.
Run it.
There we go.
My image.
We're going to take the faces good and go ahead here and run it.
And here we go.
So finally.
So here as a guest can see here this.
Let's show you.
You'll find that this is simply my first my first face it has been detected.
OK.
All right.
If you press Enter you find that you know like every face starts to appear right.
So we have another face here that appeared entered one more time on other face another face.
It's really amazing.
You know another face another face detecting every single.
This is like this is a false.
So which means that maybe I can.
I need to increase the number of neighbors maybe from five make it let's say seven or eight maybe.
Again you guys there's tons of improvements that can be done here.
Another face another face.
Amazing so again this is kind of like the petition probably one more time seconding all the faces
looks good looks good and that's it.
It actually missed I think it missed already two faces which is you know like still not not too bad
let's actually go back here to our notebook.
All right.
And that's it.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Please go ahead and pause a video and maybe try to change this for example from one point one maybe
change it to let's say one point three or one point four OK and change this for instance from five and
make it let's say seven or eight.
And again please go ahead try different numbers.
You know maybe pick two numbers and let me know if you realize any difference in your results or not.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hey you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
What I ask you has to do is to go ahead here and maybe try to tune the the colors here and sessions
here.
So I I just went you know I picked maybe two samples you guys are free to pick whatever.
So what I tried first is maybe set one point or 1 and 5.
OK.
So if you guys remember before it was one point one or one point two which means you are scaling it
to 20 percent or 10 percent of its value and then five.
Right.
Which means I need five at least maybe neighbors to detect what I did here is this maybe change it to
one point or one and five.
So when I say one point or one that means they're just gonna scale it every time into one percent.
That means I can have tons of like pyramid zing permitting.
So I'm gonna have like you know like 100 percent image and then you know like scale by smaller by 1
percent and then by 2 percent to 3 percent and so on.
And he'd only keep it to five as well.
Let's see how that would going to impact please mixtures that to run before running this.
Make sure that you load the image again to make sure that you cleared all the rectangles from from previous
step shift enter.
Looks good on the image.
New image right here.
1 point 0 1.
It's taking a little more time which makes sense then shift enter.
And here we go so I guess I can see here first that because now I'm scaling the image it's a much much
smaller.
You might find that a lot of like false rectangles have been detected.
So please shift and so see this is directing this as a face you know which is a joke and then go down.
This is a face.
It says his tie for example.
Why.
Because here I am looking for kind of you know like smaller ranges as well that's missing a lot of information.
So it gets C's just maybe one right face here.
Couple of right faces but there's a lot of like Ed or a lot of lots of mistakes with the tuning of these
parameters actually very critical
because I've been detecting faces right.
So which is good.
But it's a lot of errors right.
See so simply here in this algorithm I was actually been able to detect all the faces so one two three
all of them pretty much at the same time.
This comes with a cost right that comes with a cause I have been detecting garbage a lot of a lot of
where all of this I don't need it.
I don't need to see that right.
And even like this one is even mistakes missed another mistake too.
So detecting tons of mistakes but I've been able to detect lots of these.
However if I go back to the original settings and from what I said at one point one if you guys recall
and let's run it again let's roll the new image and it's going to come here and load the new image to
and faces you'll find that we have been detecting faces.
It's actually pretty accurate pretty amazing right.
Yeah maybe one mistake here but we didn't get a lots of mistakes in there which is good detecting faces
but it comes with a cost too.
What's the cost.
The cost is a missed couple of faces and I'm going to show you.
So right now we have three faces missing right.
So we've got this.
And then we missed two phases right.
So we need to have kind of you know try to find that sweet spot.
What's the best value that we need to put here to be able to obtain all the faces and minimize all of
the garbage in there or minimize all the so-called false positives or maybe false negatives as well
within our image.
All right let's try one more sample a set that here to one point one and instead of having one of having
five my apologies was five neighbors and he just said it one which means whatever you guess in one single
you know like rectangle that there is a face.
Let's take it.
OK let's run it let's run it on that one.
It's good and it's on that one.
And you.
Here you go you'll find tons of you know like random points because we don't.
There is no validation.
There is no like like you know like a confirmation from other from other sample so we're again detect
a couple of faces but there is again more mistakes.
Look there's tons of mistakes here too and so on OK.
All right.
And that's it.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
In the next lecture we're going to do a little bit more exciting stuff as well.
They're going to detect eyes and faces within our within our image.
I hope you guys enjoyed this lecture and see you in the next one.