Hello everyone and welcome to this new lecture and the PBS lectures were able to detect multiple faces
within an image and we have been able to apply that to detect many faces of our favorite scientists.
So let's actually run that again to make sure that guys are following.
So we're able to actually detect this is the image for our scientists and we're going to go ahead and
detect multiple faces.
So if you guys remember that let's actually exit this.
So I'm going to press enter to exit and then here we're going to specify this as five instead.
And press shift enters and here shift enters and we'll be able to detect basically all the faces in
here which is pretty amazing right.
Yes we have missed couple.
Yes maybe we have misclassified something here but that's fine.
You know it's the idea is amazing.
All right.
OK.
In this lecture we're going to go ahead and actually start to detect eyes and faces.
Let's see how can we do this.
It's going to take an image underscore C equals to c v dot image read and he will get a pass along our
to those image.
All right.
Shift enter.
Looks good.
And that's the M.E. the challenging part.
That's the new element here.
What I'm gonna do here I'm going to have two classifiers.
The first one is my face classifier which is equal to CV to dot cascades classifier.
And here's what I'm gonna do going to load our heart if you guys remember ha cascades and within Hart
cascades actually do tab that tells me there are two classifiers so one of them for the eye and that's
what I'm gonna do it for the.
My apologies.
So actually the first one this I am going to do it for the eye classifier so I'm gonna go ahead and
call this I classifier I'm going to have another classifier just copy and paste instead of I I'm gonna
call it face classifier and here instead of having this I'm just gonna go back and do tab and you'll
tell me there is one that is called Cascade frontal face default.
If you guys are confused please don't.
So I guess if you guys remember in the course package you will find that that is hard cascades if you
open it.
That would show you here that we have these are two kind of trained classifiers.
All right.
The already trained to detect faces are trained to detect eyes.
And here we go.
All right let's go ahead and see how can we simply detect detect this in an image.
So first of all first we're going to detect faces first.
We're going to take a faces equals to face underscored classifier dot detect multi scale.
And I'm going to specify Okay I am looking for image C and they need the same scale one put in two and
they need neighbors to be five.
We have done that many times before.
And then we gonna create a for loop for every time I'm going to pass along my X my y my widths and my
height to and we're going to say in faces and every time I'm going to go ahead and do CV to dot rectangle
and I'm going to pass along.
Here's my image on the court color.
Right.
And every time I'm gonna get the ordinance which is a top left coordinate and the width and height of
the tangle I'm just gonna go ahead and actually draw it.
Right.
So I need point one and point to if you guys remember you can have point 1 and then he ain't gonna point
to the need to specify the colors and he's going to specify let's say 3 which the thickness of my line.
So you can say okay X and Y and then he'd say x plus W and Y plus H.
And he's gonna specify the color let's say 0 2 5 5 and 2 5 5 afterwards.
All right.
And then afterwards we'll go ahead and actually visualize it.
Going gonna say image show we're gonna say let's say Trudeau going to call it face and eye detection
in color and he'd have in a pass along my image underscore see afterwards.
Please don't forget this please please CV to dot wait key.
All right.
And maybe you can pass.
You can just leave it like this.
And then afterwards.
So what we have done here simply we have just detected the the face.
So every time I was gonna go detect the get the face.
And here we go right now to the challenge.
Well that's a challenging part.
Now for the new part what I wanted to do here is I wanted to get my region of that face.
So what I'm gonna do we're going to say okay let's grab that face because simply when I wanted to apply
my eyes classifier okay I wanted to I don't want to look for eyes in the sky right.
I want to look at eyes within a face.
So if a face is detected let's go ahead and extract that region which is these coordinates from our
image and look for eyes in it.
That's the overall idea.
OK.
So first of all I'm going to say you know what.
I'm just gonna skip this step.
I'm going to say okay let's select the face region.
OK I'm gonna.
And then skip it.
OK.
What I'm gonna do I'm gonna still apply my classifier the exact same fashion I'm gonna take all the
i's that have been detected is I underscore classifier I'm going to say dot detect multi scale.
And here I need to pass simply my region.
So whatever face I may be selecting here I haven't filled it out yet but let's call it face face region
and he'll face region has to be something right so face region and tell you exactly what you mean by
faith region equals something I'm just gonna leave it for now what I did here I just got the face region
right and put it into I.
All right so here I detected every single eye and here we go it's what we're going to do here we can
do the exact same the exact same code this exact same code we're just gonna copied and pasted here every
single step is pretty much the same.
The only difference is and we're not going to detecting faces right I'm detecting I.
So I'm gonna go ahead into every single eye that has been detected here.
I'm going to call it I X to call it all y I'm gonna call it I w and I'm gonna call it I h every time
I take my here instead of having the image I'm gonna be doing this for the faith region rights exact
same face lesion I'm going to take the face and draw the eyes on it.
To which I with all these coordinates.
Right.
So here we're going to have eye on this X I underscore why and have I underscored X I underscored W
I.
All right.
Looks terrific.
And here we're going to show as well to the face and then here it's color with key and please don't
forget to destroy all destroy all windows and the only missing two bits.
Basically this is our code right.
So again it's tech faces and within the face.
I'm going to go ahead detect I is call the classifier and for every I I'm going to go ahead and actually
perform a loop.
Please make sure that this is all tab because this is a body of the four right.
And this has to be in line with this because every time I'm going to go ahead and actually detect the
face and then go here and detect all the I's within the face as the overall idea right.
Because I have more than one eye interface think of it as nested loops in a way it's a great practice
for our nested loop part of the of course.
So here in order to access this specific image what I'm gonna do I mean to say okay if you go to my
image color which is my image I can go ahead and actually grab my region this region.
So I'm gonna say okay go ahead into Y from Y to Y plus H.
And from x to x plus H this is simply or w.
Basically here w w h where we're pretty much equal but please make it like this.
We're going to say OK let's go ahead into my Y to Y plus H which is you know like from the height of
my image X plus X plus W which my width of my face.
So you're not my image my face just derision of that face.
Extract this from my original image and that will be my face region all right.
And here we go.
OK.
And then within that face let's take a look at the eyes.
So within the face look at the eyes.
And when you get out of the eyes grab all the coldness of all the eyes and draw them on the face.
That's the overall idea.
Okay.
All right.
Looks great.
So let's take a look at it.
So let's shift enter.
And here we go.
So now I detected the face.
That's a good good sign.
The shift and just press enter first I second eye.
Amazing.
And here we go.
Excellent.
That's great.
So now we've been able to actually take the faces and take the eyes.
Maybe you guys can go ahead here and change this for example into let's say zero and instead you can
have different light kind of color for the eyes.
Let's bring in one another.
One more time actually because so what happened is here it detected again another face another eye another
eye.
But the problem is OK.
That's actually very good point because first of all we didn't load the original image.
We are overwriting the image it has already that rectangles right.
You guys can realize here.
Yes we detected rectangles redacted it again here rectangles with different colors but they are a little
bit shifted which is good.
That means the algorithm you know is actually kind of smart in a way.
It's not you know it's not repetitive.
It's not like it's not like I'm like memorizing anyway it's actually detecting kind of you know like
several time detecting the pretty much the same region a little bit shifted but that's fine.
OK.
Actually this one mistake here.
OK we don't need this.
So there is a misclassification.
So what we could do again.
Let's go ahead and actually load the image first load the classifiers and run it again.
Here we go one face when I.
And here we go two eyes.
Perfect.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoy that entire project.
And now it's time for a mini challenge.
I want you guys to pause a video and please go ahead and change this instead of one point to maybe try
one point five for example and let's say here instead of maybe 10 one point all five like smaller number.
Let's see what's going to happen instead of five and maybe select like you know like one for instance.
And please go ahead positive view and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
We'll ask you has to do is to simply go here and I tried maybe a couple of numbers to show you guys.
So first I tried 1 point 0 1 OK and 5.
OK.
So instead of one point two I believe was before.
Let's set it to 1 point or 1.
Let's see what how what impact we're going to have.
Let's run it Run it run it.
Here we go.
Enter enter.
Looks good and it looks like nothing has changed.
That's good.
That means you know even if we change the scale to let's say smaller numbers or maybe larger numbers
it doesn't make much of a difference.
But what we could do here if we change the neighbors for example from five which means I need kind of
you know more kind of you know votes you know from five neighbors.
Are going to set it to 1 and let's see if that.
What impact what they're gonna do.
Let's shift enter shift enter enters and we go.
And you guys can see that we detected eyes.
That's good.
But there's a lot of mess up so I detected a new face here and other new eyes.
Another face.
It's like random basically.
So obviously this parameter is very important very sensitive so please make sure that you here you need
again for number from three to six at least two to actually make sure that there is repetition that
there is neighbors.
There are many faces many like pixels have to say that there is a face in there.
So I'll be able to detect it.
And here we go.
Looks great.
And great job.
I hope you guys enjoyed this lecture.
Let's recap.
We have done so far far in this project.
We have been able to detect one single face with an image.
We have done that was amazing.
And the next one we have been able to detect multiple faces with an image in our scientist
image.
We are able to detect all of them and we have realized that these parameters are actually very important.
The neighbors and the multi scale too.
And then the learning outcome three were able to detect eyes and faces as well.
We have been able to practice some of the for loop skills on some of the nested loops skills as well
along with the open CV along with tons of learnings.
I hope you guys enjoy this lecture and enjoy the entire project and I'll see you guys in future projects.