Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to walk you through the questions that we have four sets of tuples and give you skylander
a quick overview and then in the next lectures we're going to walk you through all the videos that include
the solutions.
So first I wanted to print Hello followed by the name and the age in a tubal.
OK so for example for you to have I found my cuple that has let's say a name and age and they ask you
to print Hello followed by the name and the age within that specific people are pretty straightforward.
Next one is I want to define a tuple with six of your favourite friends.
Right.
And then print all the tuple the last element and the first two elements.
OK.
So for example if you find this tuple I want you to print the all the tuple which is basically all the
elements in here last element only which are Steve for example.
And the first two elements which is let's say here it's Chanel mitsch.
Question three the final tuple with your first name last name and age.
Find the length and the type as well.
So again the five For example you know Tupelo that.
And then you wanted to give the length which is you know how many elements are there.
And then you get together type of that tuple which is going to end up basically with a chop.
OK.
Again these are very simple straightforward questions.
If you guys followed the concepts lechery should be easily able to follow the lectures that we have
here.
Question for print the number 40 here.
So this is kind of you know look out interesting one.
It's a tuple that has kind of list in there and couple of things as well.
So SQL OK.
So I wanted to print the number forty one to in the word the word the word world here when I print the
number 25 print the entire list.
And duple listed below as well when I print the tuple and will print this list or something like that.
Question 5 executed the following commands anticipating what went wrong and what went right.
OK so obviously you don't just write a check.
What do you mean by the way assignments.
When it comes to tuple which is kind of you're not allowed on it.
Question 6 execute the following commands then explain what went wrong and what went right.
Okay so I'm asking you to you know kind of explored what happened here and you question 7 and ask you
for a check of the named Python exists in a tuple.
This is kind of an research which didn't cover that.
Okay to actually search for a name within a tuple but you guys need to kind of do your own research
and see how any search for a word within its people.
Question 8.
Remove the duplicates from the following lists.
Here have a list and then ask you to remove the duplicates.
Ok kind of you know tried to relate to sets as we've done before.
Question 9 add your name to the following set and convert it into a list so wanted to add your name
here and convert it afterwards to a list he did for example added Let's see Ryan for example and then
you can add to a list line and then the last question I ask you to run the code then explain what what
it does.
We will cover that if you know kind of because we are looking to use if condition of conditions is moving
forward.
That's why I didn't ask you to actually run the code or sorry write the code.
I'm just asking you to run it and tell me what do you know.
What do you get out of it.
Okay again again have you known in time lectured that exercise is just for if condition moving forward
right.
And that's pretty much what a half with the section.
Best of luck and see you guys in the solutions lecture.