Hello everyone and welcome to this new election in the PBS lecture.
We learned how can we deal with files mainly text files in this lecture.
I'm going to show you how can we perform pretty much the same operations but on C as V files instead.
Okay so let's see how can we do that.
First step is where is my C V.
Where's my C as a father might be dealing with.
OK so he has to go back here.
You will find again in the course lectures you will find.
There is sample file in here.
It's open it's Gates actually opening it opening up
all right.
So here we go.
That's my sample file.
So if you guys take a look at it you find that here there is a lot of information that is like First
Name Last Name emails.
OK.
That is like postal code the gender.
And that is dollar value.
Maybe the salary of an employee or something.
OK.
Again this is just hypothetical you know like fake data.
Let's see how can we read that data and maybe many play that data using Python.
So first step what I'm gonna do when I say OK import CSB.
All right.
And then going to say with open and they need to specify the name of the file.
So here in my file was what was called Simple on this core file that C is V.
And they're going to open this as C as V file.
OK.
All right.
And now we pretty much have all the information we need.
So what we need to do afterwards when I say OK C is v dot reader.
And then here I open the file as quality as we file right.
So get a good look.
Go ahead and actually read my C is v file and I have to specify the delimiter.
So Quito going to specify the delimiter as just a comma
All right.
And all that content I'm just gonna put it in let's say Red C as V information see as V information.
And what we could do afterwards we're going to say okay maybe take that information convert it into
a list.
So list we're going to take our reality as V and put that into data all right.
I know it sounds a little bit confusing but let's see what's happened here.
So first up as we went to the open seas we open simple file C as V and we opened it a C V or call it
as f for example you again you can call it F if you want.
Or maybe this can call it F if you want to avoid confusion.
No we could do afterwards you could say okay see as v dot reader open read that file with the limited
equals comma and that would be our read C as V and then convert that Red C as into a list format and
that should be my data shift enter.
Here we go.
Let's take a look at our data.
Just enter.
And here we go.
So now we basically have kind of a list of lists right.
So we have a major or big list here.
And here we have lists inside the list.
This the first list that has the header here the list of all the first let's say employee second employee
third employee and so on.
All right.
OK.
So let's take a look at.
That's basically how can you read the C as before.
Let's see how can we.
For example let's assume they want to take all these names and maybe create another list that contains
only the first name and last name.
That's a Noah moron or an for example like Nina Keller and so on.
How can we do that.
So what we could do we're going to say okay let's create a list that lips list we're going to call a
court full names equals to like just a new list.
And what we could do we going to say for row in my data and what I need to do with I need to go into
my data I don't want to go through all the data right.
I just need to extract information from here only.
Right.
So going to see from data from one till four.
OK.
First of all why did it go zero so I didn't go to zero because I didn't want to get the header right.
And when I stopped at four because I go up to and not including four.
So this is simply going to go here one two and then three.
That's it.
OK.
So every time I'm going to go there I'm going to take full names which is my empty list here.
Every time I perform not a pen I'm going to append value to it.
So what I've got appending I'm gonna appending simply I need to append the first name.
Joseph let's say in Python for instance when I want to say OK I'm going to extract row of 0 plus apologies
plus then it maybe to add like a space or something and then add again another plus and then need to
add row of one
all right.
OK.
So when I say row of 0 first of all.
When I say row in data the word row contains all that information contains all that list.
So this is the first index zero.
This is one that is two three four and so on.
When I say row zero that mean Joseph space and then row 1 that means pattern here for instance.
And that's a shift entered.
Here we go.
Let's take a look at full name full underscore name.
And here we go.
So now we've been able to simply take kind of a c as we file read it in and actually be able to as well
kind of print all the first last name for its last name and so on.
All right.
So now it's time for a quick challenge.
What I want you guys to do is to simply go ahead and extract all the information let's say of the gender
in here.
So I wanted to extract male male and male for example.
OK.
Please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge all right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
Let's go ahead.
Well one I what I ask you has to do simply go ahead here extract any column like the gender or dollar
or whatever.
So let's go ahead and accept actually the gender column.
So going to say OK so what we could do we could say let's say genders equals to let's say this afterwards.
Who could say for role in data from one to four.
It's exactly the same as before every time.
Take extract whatever information appended to the gender and say append every time I'm going to go here
and append information and want information to append it to go to row.
But I need to extract the elements in the 0 1 2 3 and 4.
All right.
OK.
Here we go.
Shift enter.
So now we're good.
Let's take a look at genders.
And male female.
OK.
Let's go ahead and maybe try.
For example the dollar value.
So I'm gonna say OK I need to do let's say the same stuff here so I make a dollar here.
I'm gonna create this and make it dollar
and I wanted to print the dollar and here instead of five I want to make it sort of.
So he lets count him again 1 0 1 2 3 4 and 5.
So that should be five minutes of the four shift enter shift entry would go.
Now we're able to accept all the standard information.
OK.
All right.
That's pretty much what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Keep it up.
Should be proud of your newly acquired programming skills.
Let's recap all of them so far.
This lecture I've been able to actually deal with CSB files we're able to actually open CSB files and
extract information out of it and we're able as well to maybe do some full looping and accept information
and with it kind of a mini challenge to extract specific data like dollar value and maybe the gender
values.
And that's pretty much all we'll have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And hope you guys enjoyed the section in the next lecture.
When I walk you through the exercises tons of fun we have tons of exercises ready for you.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.