I know everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to learn how can we install Anaconda which is the development environment.
They're going to be use maybe using their older course to develop old codes or I mean the anaconda is
a famous development environment among Python three developers many for machine learning and deep learning
and Capriccio vision.
You use it as well.
Here it is develop pretty much most of our codes in the beginners section and in the practical section
as well.
All right so the good thing about the anaconda is it's very easy to install.
It's you're going to show you that you can use what we call a Jupiter node books as well in which you
can run the code and actually view the results right away it just in one in one block.
It is very interesting and it's very easy to set up I going to show you right there right.
So the first step is I want you to go ahead then start the course material and unzip it you'll find
a One's a folder that contains all the coarse material.
All right.
And then next step is to install Anaconda for Python 3.
So if you go head to Anaconda dot come back says don't vote and you will see that there is depending
on your operating system if you are windows a Mac you can just click on windows and then you download
Python 3.
We're not downloading Python too well meaning to download Python 3.
And if you have 64 bit or 32 bit most of the time you're going to have 64 bit like a do if you're just
going to click here.
You don't have to enter your email but you can just enter all the information that you wanted here.
Then you get to see it and once you see it is just going to keep keep going keep ahead and with installation
and once the installation is complete I want you to go ahead and install open civi and intensive flop.
We're going to be using it mainly in the in some of the prises and are going to be using this with tons
of flow in some of the machine learning section of the course already.
So if you open here if Anaconda you're going to right click here.
Any save run as administrator.
Okay yes that would open your command prompt here and then what I wanted to do with them wanted to write
simply Conda install deste s Channel hgt s again Conda and a candidate or backslash tempo and then open
CV 3 which is simply what you guys can see here.
Once you do that and click enter then you're solving environment and you get to prompt you for a yes
or no.
You can press yes.
Going to show you right now.
And then here we're going to prompt you to proceed or not.
So you going to say yes press enter.
Then you will see that there is downloading and accepting the packages.
So it will take a couple of minutes which is going to run.
We go back again later.
Then go ahead then install a flow sensor flow.
We're going to mainly be using for the machine learning section in this course.
So if you open a Honda and right click on it and see Run as Administrator look.
Yes and then what.
Going to write Pip install that there ignore that installed a dash upgrade flow and that's what you
can see here as well.
Right in the instructions and press enter and found in N is told to flow for you.
All right so now you are a pretty much good to run the optimal book.
You have open civi installed you have all the packages installed and you have as well offensive flow
installed as one.
So let me show you how can we actually launch a Jupiter book and run through an example.
So if you go here you were simply wrong.
The anaconda prompt if you run that and then you will open the right Jupiter notebook and press enter.
You will see that basically that opens in you kind of window in here and guess I can see you can just
straight A See.
Only a of top for instance just going to go to the installed folder that you already have for the entire
course package.
Whatever you install them on the desktop for example.
So here I just added the python general.
Some course package that's where the data is in store.
And if you open course to practical projects and here let's open the testing environment mainly fall.
And you would see set simply here an environmental testing kind of a sample code.
And there was that image as well that's contained in you as well of you know of two dúchas you know
like a famous politician in.
So if you open that here you would see that kind of you know that's where there's you know look we're
going to show show us.
So I guess I can see here you would see that.
You can this kind of a simple cold that you're already ready written in.
You know as part of of course I'm going to walk you through the code.
You can understand every single line step by step.
So when you open Jupiter modbook that's that's kind of a sample.
That's what we what it actually looks like.
You would see that you can actually see the mounds of code in here.
All right.
And simply if you don't know you want to run this specific blocks you can just press shift centres if
you press shift into that on this specific block.
All right.
If you wanted to run for example the next block you can just come in here and press shift into well
what I want to do is just the objective of this is to see if you actually if the environment is set
up properly or not.
All right.
Well I guess I can see it as well that you can write text in there which has you know kind of lines
of which kind of lines the VA.
They won't be executed as part of the code.
All right.
Speed interesting because now you can actually right kind of you know and that's kind of the standard
that I'm following through the course.
It can include all the lecture notes within the areas you know.
So you have kind of your notes along with the codes Gabby kind of you know intact in one place in one
stop shop are going to be very easy for you to access the optimal books and test all the information
just one place so you can see here for on and on this cell is going to chip into again but shift into
Right and you will see that you know like here it just changes a little bit.
Then it turned out to become like kind of a number which means that the cell has been successfully executed.
If anything goes on you'll see there's an error in you know everything turns red but hopefully you won't
see any of that.
You're going to run this again.
And once you've done this you will see that you know it's still kind of you know like like like running
something here.
If you go here with you there's an image of you know like Justin trudeau here appeared on the Im on
the on the screen.
All right.
Okay.
And you see that basically again I'm going to show you that one more Falwell.
But he did just you know swaying the computer was kind of waiting for you to enter to enter like press
any anything.
So he would press Enter just to give that you would see that he gone already and are going to run the
next cell and you will see that you know that's kind of one fun party would see that.
You know that's kind of our image became kind of a cartoon effect.
And that's one of the you know all kind of fun project we might be working on on how to test for an
image whatever image you can upload even your own image to kind of a to an effect you can you know show
it to your friends and family and it kind of you know like showcase you have Python Python skills.
Once you run that you press enter and exit.
Right.
And let's keep going.
If you keep running.
So is he not running shift into again shift into one more time shift into one more time shift into an
Now to the kind of you know like that again and other fun activity we can be can do if you press shift
into.
You will see that you know like that's pretty interesting you will see that kind of image in here you
know kind of you know through the webcam and you will see that there is kind of you know like etch your
images Well look kind of an edge detection algorithm that's running in the background.
Showing us we're here which is you know hopefully when everything's running perfectly You should see
you know your image and you should see as well that you were wrong.
You're a kind of edge detection showing all the features in here which is very interesting.
All right.
OK.
I hope I hope they called again once you press entrance should exit.
I hope the code will run and everything will be set up properly.
Now we're pretty much ready to start the first letter of the courts.
I hope you enjoyed it and see you in the next section.