What if I won it instead of plodding all the data on one image of one figure I wanted to create or collets
subplots.
So I wanted to create let's say a plot and then separate in order to create another plot and another
plot but all of them with a kind of contained within a single plot.
Okay the talk quality subplot you can do this by specifying Okay I need to create plot that sub plots
and create.
Here is postpone the number of rows and number of columns and then which figures can give you one which
index you're looking for.
So I need to create one row okay in three columns so that means I'm going to have one big figure that
has one two and three images within.
OK.
So it took place the first one to get a specific end in one by three airgap of the first one made again
and one by the same one again but a crippled the second one and one C and explore the third one.
If I do this then can I come up with this so simply put you to all this queries you separate them again
they're still in the same figure.
But they're defining the defining separate subplots array.
OK what if I wanted to plot them for example that below with each other.
You can do that by changing the order of here and specify OK.
I need one row and three columns three what if I make it the other way around.
I make it three rows in one column.
If I just seen the index you really give 3 1 and then three by one see by wanting this suspect in this
one two and three the exact same stuff you kind of come up with this.
Then you specify again it's a subplot that has three kind of you know images in it which is really powerful
two or three.
OK.
So that's how can you do perform just gender while using it using IMET plot lip.
What we could do here is that we can use object oriented programming within a couple of that yet but
we can cover it again later in the course on how can we plot in a much better and kind of elegant way
using the object oriented program.
If you don't have XP with object oriented programming don't worry you're going to show you just kind
of your basics of how can we plot.
Again djinni the exact same plots but in a simpler way.
So all we could do is that we can first define a figure and then you can apply different methods on
that figure.
Right.
OK.
Let me show you what they mean by that.
So here in order to create and you'll figure I'm just going to create a key P L T Dot figure.
Okay.
That would create simply our a kind of a.
Instance.
So here you have an instance fig and then you kind of refer to that figure later on.
Then you can say okay fig dot whatever.
Then you can apply different functions to different methods to it.
Okay.
So you can change for example the with Chief thickness Ed for example different elements to it.
And xii's do whatever you want.
So let's get started.
So he'll keep that figure.
Okay.
And then I'm going to create my thing here and I'm going to do.
Gap like Fig dot Ed axes.
And then you can add axes here.
Zero between range of zero on one.
OK.
And they'll become my axes and they won't get into here.
I'm going to postpone any to plot X versus Y.
So again to create in the little space that would create linear values again between zede on and 10
and get a plot here.
The end paedos sign on it.
Okay let's actually plot that first.
And before doing this is going to go back years do this.
Let's block that for us and see what's going to happen.
So what we have that's what we have got.
We just created simply a figure okay.
We specify X's from 0 to 1 and from 0 to 1 we specified x specify the white.
Let's take a look at X..
Actually let's delete this and it's here.
Create another one.
And let's look at let's take a look at X. That's the value of x.
So you simply specify again a hundred points or between 0 and 10.
And if you want to view why which is simply the sign of this you can simply go here.
Read Why don't we show you why that's my way values again.
It's basically there was a corresponding value for y for each one of X..
What I could do is say okay instead of using P LTE dog plot I can refer to the axes in a ship log them.
OK it's a little bit different.
Little bit we have.
You're kind of.
Kind of way of thinking about it but it's actually we'd get to see how it becomes very powerful moving
forward.
Well I can see I'm going to say okay I have now my axes.
If you all better use the axes Equis fingered axes you know we have these then you can refer to the
axes and do the plodding in.
Yes they axes dot plot and then you specify X and Y can specify.
Again here you wanted to read a wanted Square.
You can specify you label and then if you want to add let's say titles X label way label you can again
apply a method to your object here so you can separate axes darts set X label a time said y label title
and legend put eggs for example set.
Why limit if you want to limit the y axis to that range and set X limit if you want to X that limit
from zero to 11 and add a grid as well.
Create let's actually view all of them altogether.
Actually let's go back here.
Before running it let's do them all together.
Let's actually plot them because they have to be pretty much when you plot it has to be the same kind
of kind of cell.
So if you're under this then you'll come up with that useful curve you have there.
So let's take a look first plotted.
X is the plot X Y that will simply plot my curfew.
OK.
So as you can see it's red the direct and it has square elements.
Because I specify this.
S If I change this for example I make it let's say triangle.
If I had it there.
Do you see a cheetah triangle.
If I change utlity and make a dash that will make it again.
There you go.
That's my label.
If I want to specify a label he has specified dread sine wave.
Again let's say it's red you know red sine wave like number 1 for example or whatever.
And then you can change you can see whatever use Gambia.
If you want to set X label you can use axes dot sets underscore X label and then you specify the what
you want to write on the X X which is time.
Set underscored way label.
Then you specify will do right here on the same week.
That would be siwei if you want added paid all.
My first plot so set underscored a table.
You specify whatever title you want and then if you want to add a legend that's my legendary added.
And here if I wanted to limit simply my ex exes let's say I'll make it from 0 to 11 and that's why he
did set the scene to 11 if you want me it to 10.
If you make it 10 and if you're on it you will see that it simply cropped a 10.
If you want to make it let's see between 0 5 you run it.
You see the mcrobert from you on 5 and so on so forth.
Let's go back.
Make it 10 in here you can again Krab your limits your way axes.
By changing it from minus one point one point five to one point five let's say make it to between 1.
Minus one.
Let's see one if you run it you'll see that actually very smooth and he looks great.
And then if you want to add that grit then you can come up you do X. He's done great.
If you actually do more of this end run it you will see that you've got the curve without the grit.
Right.
If you want to clear the green again you can enable it and done it.
You see the curve with the grit.
And that's pretty much how can you have a foundation of plotting any data.
And that's we're going to be using it throughout the course.
The object oriented programming way of of plodding.
OK.
All right.
Okay.
Looks great.
So the next step is what if I want to let's say plant or do multiple plots.
Let's run this cell and see what's going to happen.
That's actually what we've got here.
I want to say to plop a curve or better.
Wanted to create mini or you know kind of subplots with within.
How can we do that.
Let's see how can we do that using again object oriented programming a way of plotting for say okay
figure equal ability or to figure out that would create our Figg.
And then it would start to add axes.
So you say Go figure.
XY is he living in a collared zino the ranges between 0 and 1.
That would be accedes one.
And what I'm gonna do here I'm going to create again kind of a smaller smaller axes which is you know
the minute figures there's consomme before here.
So you're going to create think up X's as well but he can get a caller to a quote inset axes.
Okay which is again point one point three which is kind of an issue.
Kind of a kind of a smaller version of that mean x is that we find here.
So you have my second access.
You have my my third access.
And what I'm going to do here.
You're going to specify simply the location are going to tell you what they mean by this.
And then what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to plot let's say X and Y which is my beat Are you hitting at a point of say plot X and Y
squared and red and that's the Red Gap.
Plus X and Y squared as well to seem bitter but with let's say Green Collar.
All right.
Okay.
And again I'm going to college you know I can specify X label why label we have done that before you
can basically Name the different these minute plots whatever you want it.
Okay.
So if you've done this you come up with this game.
What if I wanted to see move or shift some let's say X wrote the x or y axis you can actually do that
here.
Let's say if I wanted for example to shift this from the point six which is shift if you let's say I
wanted to shift in this to make a point it's let's drop it.
So you'll see that you actually shifted it you know to to the right.
Right to the X within the X when change say up you can make it it's a point to.
My apologies.
Point two if you run it you'll see that actually moved to the right and up right.
That's how can you change the location simply of it right.
It's put 0 here.
Let's turn it back in to make a point six point seven point two.
OK it looks great here.
And then here you can change the Let's Make It for example point five point five.
You run that run it.
You'll see that you can change the size.
Simply put it can specify the location of the exact location of the Y.
How we're going to shift the curve.
OK.
And you can specify the dimensions as well here.
Using these two.
So simply put you specify the X..
Movement.
Why.
Movement of displacement size of the X and size of the Y with ratio with this with respect to the main
axes.
Or.
Let's assume that when I moved the other one for example make it let's say from point to point two and
she said there's 2.5 in point five.
OK.
You would see they actually move that make it bigger.
Obviously anymore the point to point.
OK.
It looks great.
Let's take a look again at another exercise and another examples.
Let's assume I'm going to run it and let's see what's going to happen.
What we have got here if you want to do let's say some plotting using the object oriented programming
method what we could do.
Then again we can create purity instead of vlt that figure that we had before we do that figure.
You can do with using P L T Dot sub plots and how you specify how many rows and how many columns are
written for.
Okay.
So if you specify t subplots and lemke's not forget the yes I used to forget it all the time to get
it right away.
You'll get the number of rows three a number of columns 1.
And here you get simply two objects you get to figure and you get X's out of it and then you can refer
to the axes because now we have three axes.
Then you get a quality axes of zero.
You can plot something to it axes of one couple or something to it and X is to complete something to
it listicle up.
So what we've done is that ok.
Okay xy is of zero.
Then a plot to its first to mean a plot.
X and Y with the red column.
And you get a column specifically X Lehman a y label and a specific table.
That's what you guys can get here.
For xes of one that's simply this data.
Plot x square and in a plot.
So you why squirrelling in a plot y cube.
Again if you run it that's what the data we've got here.
And that's pretty much how can you do subplots using the object or you and the programming method.
So let's take a look at how can we adjust the figures size spacing and column.
If you can see here you would see the kind of view there's an overlap here so the figure doesn't look
really nice.
So we could do here.
It can again do the exact same plot which is two of them were done before.
But what we could do with it can actually change again the thicker size skew within and specify the
figure size.
You can specify the figures as an MC.
Let's say 10 by 10 make a little bit bigger.
But that doesn't solve the actual problem which is how can we change the difference here which is what
we call a h space or a.
So as a list here you can change using the P T subplots underscored.
Just you can specify whatever you want.
You can change.
Let's say that didn't like the shifting in the left during during in the left direction the right direction.
You can change the width space n the H space as well.
And that's what we're interested in here.
So let's actually go here and enabled that line.
So what's the name of that line.
I want to make any shift so that's why I specify there's none.
And I wanted just achieve the HP distance between the two.
Let's set it a point for point on that.
Then you'll come up with a way better one then you can actually separate the figures or subplots using
the space.
It comes very handy in order to make the image a little bit better or clearer.
Again they may mimic any change here.
Exact same beta or the change we have done that we added their comment.
Just to think of the HS space n again we changed the figure size you're right.
What if I wanted to say to change again the life style or the line.
We kind of took a quick example before when I showed you how can we change let's say the the the colour
from red green blue or whatever.
These are kind of the different combinations they could ever imagine.
So you can actually BLT the plot x y you specify the lines style cones for spite.
Specify the marker you can specify again the colour.
And that's pretty much how can you mix them all together he can instead of writing them you know separately
can specify them in order so they're going to be the line style that will be the marker.
And that will be the colour of of the line.
And the MicroTech.
And here you have tons of combinations you can do like you know stencil for a square you can do Pentagon.
You can do like you know triangle you can do tons of stuff with it.
OK.
So here there's a tons of code in here.
Let's actually run it let's see what's going to happen.
I want you guys to guess you know which one is a liar corresponding to work.
OK.
There looks pretty.
So let's start with let's see the first ones here.
Basically what I've done here is just a couple of hard columns and seams with all of them are blue but
it seemed the width.
Let's see how can we change that with Kate to come up with this.
So simply put you will see that all the curves he'll have shifted by one that's where you come up with
all the shift and the y axis.
So you're plodding X versus Y but the y axis you're shifting them.
That's why you see those plus 1 2 3 4.
Up until 18 and you will see they're the first one all of them are collared equates to Blue which looks
good you know and the differences here we changed simply the width of the line with us from Point 2
5 to 1 to 5 on night.
Obviously here I just created again the blob subplots and specify the figure size and he just added
basically a plot to plot different plots of you.
If you wanted to and if you wanted to change the line styles he kept simply the column the same purple
line which the thing is the same but we change the style of the colour of the of the line so he would
make it.
Let's see desch will make it their diet and column.
That's what you get here so you get pretty much this and then there are darts and then all the dots
right.
Next one.
If I want to let's say to the marker.
Here we were just trying different combinations just to give you an idea of what we could do would how
powerful that is.
You can change you can give the words the same you can line style of the same but each in the moniker
from squares to all to star and that's what we're get.
We got square get Ole's got stars and got plus's as were good which is one clipless.
What if I one for example to change the micro size.
You can actually go and change the microseismic at it's 3 here.
Mixed again 7 making that a bit bigger.
You can me the micro size 10 and make it square.
So there's the square we weskit see here and you can actually as well even column of the actual face
of the model which is you know kind of crazy you Ken.
You can do a really pretty plus using a mad flocculate you can use again like a face column equal to
yellow and that's why you see there is yellow here or.
However you see that the the boundary is green because you specify the line actual colour is green.
What you could do here as well is that you can say okay I need the little even more pretty you can change
the edge.
For example you can change the thickness of the edge you change the thickness of the edge and make a
blue.
Again you can do tons of stuff with it.
I just wanted to give you an idea how powerful that could be.
Right.
OK.