Hello everyone and welcome to this new section and this section.
We're going to cover very important basics in programming in general which is known as loops.
OK.
So we're going to cover mainly two major or two important types of loops and we call them for loops
and while loops.
All right.
And afterwards we're going to have tons of exercises ready for you mainly dedicated to for loops and
while loops.
So let's get started.
Let's see how can we actually create a loop first and we'll see how can we go through it in so many
different exercises and practice through many examples.
All right.
So let's get started.
First of all why do we need loops or what's the point of having for loops.
So the overall idea is that we if let's assume that we wanted for example to let's say print for example
Hello.
OK.
Very simple basic line of code.
So let's say if a press shift enter you would find that you found here.
Hello.
Right.
All right sounds good.
What if you wanted to repeat this let's say 10 times.
All right so maybe one solution.
Someone can say OK maybe we can copy this and paste here and press shift enter and then copy paste it
several times shift enter and so on.
This is obviously not an efficient way of performing or of doing this.
Right.
So obviously there is an easier way to repeat if you wanted to repeat certain command several times.
Then we can use what we called loops which is a way of just instead of repeating the exact same command
several times within the code you just write it once and somehow you create a for loop in there to actually
put it in a very kind of it's just two lines of code.
You can literally print like thousands of these hellos.
All right.
OK that's the overall idea of why do we need loops in general.
And why do we need for a loop for example in particular.
All right.
OK.
So let's go ahead and actually delete all this and let's get started and see how can we create our first
loop.
All right.
Let's assume that I want it to that I for example have the lists and lists this list.
I call it my list and I'd put there one two and three.
OK.
And if I press shift enter and if I take a look at my list you would find that there is here that there
is.
These are the three numbers which is 1 2 3.
Let's assume that I wanted for instance to print all these elements within my list like I wanted to
print one first element within the list.
Second element within the list.
And then third element within the list.
How can I do that.
All right.
So what you could do you can then create a for loop to do it.
So let's see how can we do that.
First of all this is the syntax of a for loop.
We're going to say for I n and then you write here the name of the list that you have here which is
my list.
And then you put column at the end and then once you press enter you will find that here.
Basically there's an indent here.
So you actually have there is a space kind of in here.
And that means that whatever we're going to be writing here indicates that's the body of my four.
OK.
So that means whatever we're going to be writing here we're going to be repeated several times depending
on this I'm going to.
Again I haven't discussed what's happening here but let's see how can we do that.
It's going to take a for i in my list and what I'm going to do.
All right.
So what you could do afterwards you can say OK I wanted to print my variables I.
OK.
And if you press shift enter here we go then you will find that there is numbers 1 2 3 which has all
the elements contained within my list here have been printed.
All right.
So what happened here.
Let's see how can we read it.
OK.
So what happened in is here.
I'm saying ok for I can name it whatever you want to call it index i n.
And then you indicate let's say the name of the list that you have which is my list.
One two three.
And you simply what you're saying is I think OK Please go ahead grab each and individual elements within
that list.
So for instance first one we're going to grab the first element which is 1.
So when the first run of the loop.
I will have no equal to 1.
OK.
So I equals to one in the first loop and then I'm going to go here.
I'm gonna say OK print that number.
Print one.
And that's why we've got print one.
Then what happened is we're actually going to go up again and then we're going to go here take the second
element within my list and that's my second element which is two.
So I in this case will contain that second the value associated with the second element in my list which
is 2 and then going to go here and print to go up again to get third element and then go here and print
it again.
And that's why you print the number three.
All right.
OK.
And that's pretty much how can you run any for loops which is very very easy and very intuitive.
So next step is let's assume that I wanted for example to let's say print Hello world three times.
So when I say okay for I and I'm going to say let's say my list.
All right.
Which is simply what we have here.
Okay.
I know that there are three elements in here and say OK for I in my list I can simply do actually two.
Two things are going to say OK print I can print my variable I.
Which is exactly the same as before.
And I can maybe do something as well maybe I'm going to go and print let's say hello world afterword
afterwards.
OK.
So every time I'm going to go print i.
So we're gonna say let's say print one two and three and afterwards after you print each of these numbers
you're going to print Hello World.
So pretty impressive enter.
And here we go.
So now we come in number one which is here.
And then afterwards we print Hello World up again.
The second iteration within the loop I'm going to print number two.
And then I'm going to print Hello World go up again then print number three and then print Hello World
which is great.
OK.
Correct.
So let's assume that I will have for example a list of strings.
Again I'm just trying to expose you guys with like you know like show you different examples within
the for loop.
OK.
And how to create loops.
So this is what we have another list and my list is defined of this my list equals two let's say couple
of let's say fruits identified them as Apple I mean the five of us let's say blueberries
blueberries.
GATES Actually they are here.
And we are going to let's say specify mangoes specify let's say watermelon actually.
Again here watermelon and maybe grab one more fruit as well.
Let's call it apricots for instance let's shift enter.
Here we go.
Let's take a look at my list.
Copy and paste.
Let's take a look at it.
Then you come up here with Apple blueberries mangoes and Waterman.
Let's assume that I wanted to for example let's say print all the elements within my within my string
and here within my list.
OK.
Which is simply a list of strings.
So I could do say OK for I can call it whatever in my list.
And then again you press column enter.
You'll find that here you have got the tab.
You're going to say print the value of i.
That's it.
Ships enter.
And here we go.
First of all you're going to go here.
I in my lists or first we're going to go ahead and grab the first element within the list which is Apple.
And going I come here you're going to say print apple and then you go up again.
You take a second element within my list which is making blueberries we're going to come here print
blueberries or come again mangoes and so on and that's why you're printing all of it here.
OK.
All right sounds great.
So afterwards let's maybe take another example let's assume that I wanted for instance to loop to create
a loop and that loop was gonna be created over a string.
All right.
So what do you mean.
So what could you take it for I in let's say I have a string here it's called mangoes for example.
OK.
Or just mangoes like this and what I could do.
I'm going to say OK every time.
Please go ahead and print I.
So what's going to happen here when I say Okay Please go ahead.
For I in mangoes so every time you were going to go here grab a letter within the string.
So first we're going to grab the first letter was gonna be M and that's why I printed them up again.
You're going to print get get a.
And that's why I printed a and so on and that's what's happening here.
OK.
So simply put what we have done so far so we're able to go ahead in their print.
If we wanted to print let's say numbers within the list I would be able to do that phone it let's say
to print you know like hello world or whatever I can do with here too if I wanted to have a list as
well.
But that list contains strings in there.
Let's say Apple blueberries whatever.
Then I'll be able to print it as well and I can also be able to go ahead create the for loop that goes
through the letters each individual letters or characters and actually print them as well.
All right then that's kind of the power of full looks you can actually do it in a way that you can print
20 you can print you know like characters within the strings you can print strings within a list you
can print in print numbers within a list you can repeat on whatever you wanted to do.
All right.
OK.
So one more example example let's assume that I wanted for example to have let's say list of numbers
and define these numbers.
Let's say one two three three four five and let's say six.
And what I wanted to do they wanted to sum up all these numbers.
So I wanted to create a loop.
OK.
And this loop was simply going to go ahead here and grab simply like a number.
All right.
And added to kind of you know an accumulator we'll call accumulator and then the next time I'm going
to go in the iteration take the second number edit as well.
The third number edit as well.
And that's what I keep doing until I actually sum all the numbers in there.
So to do that.
OK first step I'm going to take some equals to zero.
So when I say some equals to zero I can actually let's call it let's say some of numbers equals to zero.
And this is simply what we call an accumulator.
This is just a variable that carries or accumulates all the variables or the summation let's say let's
say multiplication and so on and then initialize it to zero first and what it could do afterwards.
I'm gonna take a for number in numbers all right.
And that's kind of a famous way of actually writing kind of a for loop here.
I have a list of numbers right.
What I could do.
I'm going to say Okay I'm going to create the for loop and that for loop will go ahead.
Here take a number.
Within numbers.
Think about it.
Okay.
I'm going to create.
Take one and then for the first iteration and then take 2 for the second iteration and so on.
So number one simply cannot be assigned to each and every individual variable in here within my list
afterwards I'm going to say okay some.
All right.
Or some underscore numbers which is my accumulators accumulator equals to some underscore numbers plus
no.
All right.
OK.
So what happened here.
So what happened is is kid OK.
Let's go ahead and take my some numbers which is initialized to 0.
So let's take a look at the for loop when we actually starting just starting in the beginning.
So what happened is numbers num for number in numbers.
So numbers we have here have 1 2 3 4 5 and 6.
All right.
So first iteration I'm gonna go take number the first one in numbers.
So number here will have the value of 1.
So here I have one right.
So 1 plus some numbers which has initialized to zero so zero plus one equals two one.
All right.
So what we are doing was simply simply kind of overwriting every time taking the some numbers old add
number to it and write it over to some numbers and create a new accumulator.
And that's why we call it some numbers new per.
So in the first iteration we're going to be doing we're actually gonna be adding 0 plus 1 and that should
generate simply the new value is going to be 1.
And what's going to happen is in the second loop we're actually going to go ahead.
Again I'm going I think the next number which is gonna be two.
Right.
So I'm going to come here at 2 plus 1 and that will become 3.
And so on I keep repeating this simply like several times and they'll be going to be actually our let's
say second loop or second iteration.
So second iteration will gonna be let's say I'm going to take the new some numbers play one add to it
the second value here which is 2.
Right.
And that should generate number three and so on.
I keep repeating this several times until I actually finish all the numbers in here.
And that should generate simply our accumulator.
So we could do afterwards going to take a print and print some underscored numbers.
All right.
So please shift enter.
Here we go.
So now we obtain some numbers which is 21 which is basically a summation of six plus five plus four
or three plus two plus one.
All right.
So now it's time for a quick challenge.
What I'm asking you guys to do is to do repeat pretty much the exact same elements in here.
OK.
Exact same code per say but I don't want to attain the sum of numbers I wanted to get the multiplication
of all numbers.
I'm going to get multiplication of all the elements all my apologies all the elements in the list.
Please go ahead pause the video and maybe make some changes.
Again this numbers keep it the same.
Maybe some changes to here maybe some changes to here to just be able to obtain the multiplication of
all these elements together.
All right.
Please go ahead pass the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge
all right.
You guys were able to figure out the challenge.
So what I ask you has to do is to simply copy this paste off here and instead of just summing all the
numbers I wanted to multiply all the numbers in order to do that let's actually remove this confusion.
So in order to do this.
Simply put what you could do.
You can say OK I need to multiply all these numbers.
So first of all the accumulator here I can set it to zero OK because zero multiplied by any value we're
going to be zero.
I need to said that multiple that variable to one and instead of calling it some numbers I'm going to
call it let's say multiply let's say numbers let's say just call it whatever you call them multiply
numbers which is simply contains the multiplication of all the values.
And what I could do here you're going to say OK go to each number grab the numbers right.
I'm going to grab one two three and so on every time instead of addition I'm just going to make it multiplication
and instead of some numbers I'm just going to define it as multiply numbers or copy paste we're going
to copy paste and here I'm going to go ahead and multiply and print multiply numbers.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
Press shift enter and here we go.
We'll end up with seven hundred and twenty which is simply the multiplication of all these numbers together.
All right.
If you guys were able to figure out the challenge and I hope the lecture was was pretty easy and that
would conclude our lecture.
Let's go ahead and review what we have done so far.
So in this lectures we're able to get a get kind of you know what I can and then head start and learn
how can we create a for loop.
All right.
And the overall idea of for loops is that we wanted to repeat a certain part within the code several
times.
And that's what we have done here.
We're able to repeat and print for example all the elements within my list which is one two and three
here and we're able as well to let's say if you wanted to repeat like a print operation like I have
done here with print in the numbers and we printed as well hello world.
And then afterwards we'll be able as well to do is to print elements or strings within our list.
So not just numbers we can actually print as well as strings which apples you know blueberries and so
on and then we're able as well to print characters to such as you know like if we do for I n and then
we define any string then we'll be able to actually print all the characters within our string.
And then finally here we're able to create kind of a mini mini code that would help us to define an
accumulator to repeat or sum all the elements within our list them here and also for a mini challenge
to multiply all the elements within the list.
All right.
That's pretty much what I have for this lecture I hope you guys enjoyed it in the next lecture.
I'm going to walk you through again more examples for the four loops and that should conclude that section
and they're going to move ahead to a kind of more advanced forms of loops such as y loops and different
kind of loops nested loops.
I hope you guys enjoy this lecture and see you in the next one.