Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
I'm going to show you kind of a quick overview of the exercise questions for this section.
So again here.
These exercises are mainly dedicated for the topics that we cover so far.
They are variables datatypes mathematical operations presidents which is kind of an audit of operation
and then how to perform variable assignment.
OK so again I'm going to walk you through a quick overview of the code.
Okay.
Just you know like of the questions I hope you guys we're going to kind of attempt to solve the questions
again if you can find if you can solve any of these questions.
That's totally fine.
Just going to include a video right after this video that includes you know all the solutions and then
I'll walk you through the solutions and the great details.
OK.
Again if you go to any of the of the folder here.
You guys we're going to find for ANY topic for example you'll find that there is to A B and C there
is the concept which is you know introducing the concept you know like we're going to cover for example
a print operation followed by the questions and then followed by the solutions.
OK.
So now I mean the first topic which is one be for the exercise questions.
OK so here for example I'm asking you okay what will this go generate.
So again and I wanted to run the court expecting you guys you know if you're on the court obviously
you can and you know what the cold will generate heat I'm just asking you okay tell me what you what
you expect you know based on your understanding of programming in general which one should it be should
it be 10 20 or 15.
Okay.
Masking looking at what's the type of x for example.
I'm asking you if let's say if we divide x y y and z working in any part of that again please don't
run the cell and make it I'm expecting you just you know maybe write on a piece of paper on the side.
What do you expect to see and then then you run it and then you you know just make sure that you understand
the difference between for example integer and float and so on.
Next question here and I'm asking you okay given the area here over a potential you know which is you
know a year or two sites or the emv and asking you to write the code that calculate the area and perimeter
of a rectangle.
OK.
And then I'm asking you to assume any values for the length and width so you can define again any variable.
Put a whatever vedat value be whatever value.
And then you can.
I wanted to calculate the area and skeletally the perimeter.
That's it.
Okay.
And then you get an idea called here.
Here I'm asking you okay what will this could generate.
OK.
So define a couple of variables here.
Ideas to try to get to you on the president's key which operation going to be performed first.
Again please don't trust the code because if you're not into it then there's no point right.
So you know I'm just asking you to do is simply to run to run this quote here.
OK.
So he is simply I'm just wanted to show this is going to be easy and this is going to be easy.
We don't want to simply run this OK.
Come up with an answer from this.
Come up with an easy answer and then here we're going to find that a Z.
And then I want you to tell me OK.
What's dead value we're going to look like.
OK.
Here I want you to write the code to test if a number is even or odd.
Please try to check and review the mod OK operation and is it is very simple lines of code that can
tell me if number is even or odd.
OK.
OK question number five I'm asking you to write a code that takes a number.
Square it and then take the result and get it square root afterwards.
Okay.
So just take a number.
Perform the square and then get the square root of the results.
But pretty much you're going to end up with the original value that you had before in the beginning.
OK.
That's the kind of you know question for you.
Question 6 I'm asking you to simply write the code that the dimensions of a cube which is a cube here.
And if its area and volume.
So again define find a value a put it whatever and then basically multiple Again these equations area
and volume.
OK question 7 I'm asking you to write a code that takes a number and increment it three times.
So again you can increment it with the basic idea that we had before or with the specials.
You know like why.
Plus equal 1.
For example why.
Plus equal 3.
For example look at.
Question 8.
I want you to tell me what went wrong.
OK so something went wrong here and I am asking you to adjust the code so the answer here or the value
of z would be equal to 255.
Okay.
Here.
Question 9.
I'm asking you to write a code that perform the following mathematical operation simply to get Z equals
to the absolute value of x minus y.
Multiply the answer by experts way gay.
Again kind of a quick exercise for you to know what you mean how to perform absolute and how to multiply
to perform of the placation operation.
Go on.
Here I'm asking you to simply go through again.
This didn't cover that mainly in the.
Lecture.
He this kind of thing more additional reading for you.
Okay here there are some kind of restrictions on some of the variables you know that so you can just
go and name value very whatever you want.
You can for example name a variable would call it.
If for example why.
Because if means something else for Python.
Okay so these are kind of qualities reserved words so you are not allowed to use these words.
Okay so I'm asking you okay go through these valid values and tell me which one should be removed.
And again go here to the print here and remove the values you know so it's basically this called will
run.
So if you're on it right now you'll see there's tons of errors we're going to happen.
OK try to read more for example see which ones should be removed from here.
Which one should be kept right.
And then here in the print of the print again commend by removing the values that you know that you
think should be removed.
Here to perform or to execute this cells successfully.
All right again.
Section.
Question number 11.
I'm asking you to write a code that takes Celsius temperature and convert it to for tonight.
Simply put.
Here we have again if you guys are not familiar in general that are kind of two kind of there's a metric
system and there is another kind of you know system in general that we we use you know compare if you're
living in the US or Canada or whatever.
So there's kind of a conversion between Celsius temperature and Fahrenheit temperature.
Okay so for example if there is let's say 20 degrees C Okay that's equivalent to 68 per night.
If it's let's say zero degrees C that's equivalent to three to four in a night.
So the equation is this.
K. So what I'm asking you to do is to simply dry a code.
It takes any cell system preachers.
You know maybe pick any cell system prettier here and obviously implement this equation.
So you can convert from Celsius to freedom right value.
Right.
Again all these codes are in you know like they are simple but they are very useful.
Because now you can actually use it in practice to like to perform the conversion you call it.
So you can sort of actually implementing that equation mathematically if you write that code then you
can refer to it.
And you know and make use of it basically and then moving forward.
When I'm going to show you with it.
We know we're going to learn how to take input from the user.
So if you're on a code you can actually develop an application and within that application you have
to prompt the user to enter that value.
So you don't have to actually put that value in here.
Okay.
And define it beforehand.
You get to take that value as an input from the user perform the mathematical operation on it and it
can actually even printed to the user afterwards.
In Fahrenheit you know which is you know really completely interesting and functional code moving forward.
Question 12 and the last one I believe.
Okay which is I'm asking you to write a code that converts from kilometre per hour into miles per hour.
And I'm asking you to refer to this equation here below.
So I want you to simply assume any value for kilometre per hour.
You guys can see here again you know for let's say if it's for example like 85 or 90 for example kilometre
per hour that's equivalent to around 55 miles an hour per say Okay.
So what I'm asking you to do is again simply put implement this equation in a very simple form which
is again you're going to come up with a function of code that convert from kilometre per hour to Miles
per hour and you can do it as well.
Vice versa.
Obviously moving forward too.
And again in the future we're going to learn how to prompt the users to input the value in km but our
reform the operation and then printed in mind put out our eye.
And again hopefully once you get finished these exercises you're going to become familiar with how to
define variables how to perform variable assignments perform presidents and basic mathematical operations.
Okay.
You should be proud of yourself.
Once you complete that even again if you if you if you get stuck.
No problem.
Just go and refer to the solutions.
Jupiter notebook and digital solutions as well.
Video lectures.
Alright.
And that's pretty much all I want to have for this section.
Good luck and see you guys in the solutions section.