Hello and welcome to the course.
I'm very excited that you've enrolled and I'm even more excited that you're beginning your first steps
to learning Python before you begin the course.
I just want to explain a few key details that will help give you the best course experience possible.
First let's discuss how this course will work in general.
This course is going to be a bit different than other technical courses you may have experienced in
the past in order to try to make the course in engaging in a fun experience for students.
There will be negative element to the course that includes actors and an immersive story.
The exercises and projects you do in the course will directly sync up with the story and give you interesting
context as to why you're learning different operations with Python.
If that approach isn't well suited for your learning style you can always just skip the story that is
and go directly to the Python lectures and exercises without really missing anything.
And lastly just a few more points to help you have the best learning experience possible.
If you ever want to speed up the videos or change the playback streaming quality you can click on the
gear icon at the bottom of the video to adjust the settings if you want to download the videos for offline
viewing.
You can use the utility app if you ever have any technical or general platform issues during the course
such as issues of video playback buffering or questions about your certification for the course.
Please reach out to you to me support.
They are best suited to answer your questions and finally make sure to check the automated welcome message
of this course for useful information.
The remaining lectures in the section are just the Frequently Asked Questions article lecturer and a
short general lecture on how to get technical help on Python.
While you take the course please check out those lectures as well as they have useful information on
getting course notes and how to access the Q&amp;A forums as well as our chat room for students.
Thanks again so much for enrolling and I will see you inside the course.