Welcome back recruit one of our key tools in the field is python.
A general purpose programming language developed by Guido van Rossum in 1991 has quickly become one
of the most popular programming languages in the world.
Python has many advantages that you'll soon discover.
Developers can learn it quickly.
It typically involves less code than other languages and the syntax is easier to read.
It's utilized in some capacity by pretty much every major technology company in the world and most importantly
has an overwhelming amount of additional open source libraries to help you accomplish any task and pretty
much think of whether it's web scraping working if images reading PDX reading see history files sending
emails.
There there's a library already written in Python that can help you accomplish these things to install
Python.
We'll use the free Anaconda distribution this distribution not only includes python but it also has
many other useful libraries including the Jupiter notebook system and even the spider development environment.
Anaconda can also easily be installed onto any major operating system including Windows Mac OS or Linux.
There's also many Khanda which is a smaller sized version of Anaconda.
In case you don't want to install or download such a large file to be an installation go to w w w the
Anaconda dot com slash downloads.
Let's head to that Web site and walk you through the installation process.
Welcome to the download page recruit so Entercom dot com slash download the website will look something
similar to this.
It may be updated from time to time as far as the look and feel but in general it will have the download
links for the various installers for the Windows Mac OS and Linux systems.
And if you click on one of these you'll be brought down to the actual download links for the graphical
installers or the command line installers.
By the time you view this page it's most likely that 3.7 or 3.8 or even 3.9 has been released.
So keep that in mind.
Any version of Python 3 should be fine for our use cases.
Now if you're on Windows you'll go ahead and download the graphical installer 64 bit or 32 bit depending
on your computer.
Most new computers are going to be 64 bit and if you have any questions on that you can click to learn
more.
But basically this is just a graphical installer so wizard that's going to walk you step by step on
the installation process.
So for Windows users click on the graphical installer download it.
If you're on Mac OS click on this graphical installer and download it and then if you're on Linux you'll
be clicking on this installer and downloading it.
Keep in mind that Linux users have a command line installer and you'll have to type commands that will
show you in just a second once you've decided which version you're going to download.
Scroll down a little bit and click HERE where it says how to install Anaconda and depending on what
operating system you're currently on it will take you to one of these three pages here you can see installing
on Windows and it has step by step instructions for installing the graphical installers are really quite
straightforward.
You just select the defaults hit next and follow along with these.
Step by step instructions.
You don't need to worry about number two as far as verifying the data integrity.
If you're on a Mac OS it's basically the same thing.
If you click on that link on how to install it will guide you through the graphical installation process
for Mac OS.
Again step by step process.
Pretty straightforward.
Just continue on all the screens.
If you're on Linux it's going to be slightly different.
What you need to do is you'll be downloading a s h file and then at your command line or a terminal
you'll be running the following command bash and then right here down tilde downloads and the three
and then whatever version you happen to be clicking on.
Basically just copy and paste this command into your terminal.
A quick note for Windows users and this is a pretty important one.
You'll eventually have a screen that looks like this saying advanced installation options and you can
choose whether or not you want to add anaconda to your path environment variable and call themselves
recommends to not add Anaconda as a path environment variable.
Since this can interfere with other software typically what it's going to interfere with is previous
downloads of Python.
However since this is probably your first download of python we actually highly recommend that you do
add anaconda to your path environment variable.
This will allow you to call Konda specific commands directly at your command line.
Again for Windows users we do recommend that you add anaconda to your path environment variable.
When you click on it you'll notice that it says not recommended.
It'll highlight and read.
Go ahead and click on it anyways and then install.
Now as we previously mentioned these graphical installation files include Anaconda Python and many other
libraries in this distribution so you'll notice that it's actually quite a large file.
About half a gigabyte depending on your internet connection or the space available on your computer.
You may not want to actually download install all these libraries.
Instead you probably just want the basics of Python for that use case.
You can look for conduct I O.
Slash many condo.
H Tim L.
Or just google search for many Konda and it will take you to the Mini-Con the links for the installers
and it's basically the exact same thing except it's a much smaller file and it doesn't include a variety
of the libraries which you don't really need to worry about.
So there's one for Windows Mac OS and Linux.
Interested in a much smaller file download you can use those installers as well.
However we do recommend that if you have the bandwidth and the space that you just download the fool
and a constellation once you've successfully downloaded and gone through the installation steps for
Anaconda you should be able to search your computer for Anaconda navigator.
This is a desktop app that allows you to quickly launch DUPERE notebooks.
So go ahead and confirm your installation by clicking on Anaconda Navigator.
It will load up and eventually you'll see something that looks like this with little quick dashboards
that allow you to launch different development environments.
There is that Jupiter notebook R-Maine development environment.
There's the cutesy cons..
Spider in other integrated development environment.
There's also other things like glue is Jupiter lab and even art studio.
If you decide to later on learn are you can install that as well as a click of a button.
But we're going to be using the Anaconda navigator to quickly launch Jupiter notebooks.
So now that we have Anaconda and Python installed on your computer you should be able to open up the
Anaconda navigator.
Up next we'll discuss how to actually run Python code either as a script at the command line or using
the Jupiter notebook.
We'll see there recruit.