Welcome to your next lesson in the basics of Python today we're going to discuss another basic data
type which is strings strings are an ordered sequence of characters enclosed of either single or double
quotes.
Here you can see two examples strings one of double quotes one with single quotes.
Since strings are ordered we can use indexing to treat individual characters or slicing to retrieve
a subsection of the original string.
When we're saying the word ordered that means there's actually a numerical index that relates to the
position of every character and the actions of indexing and slicing use square brackets which will see
many examples of later on.
But here we can see an example string with characters H E L L O for the string hello and the corresponding
index and Python starts at zero.
Meaning that you can use indexing at 0 to grab the letter H indexing at 1 to grab the single letter
E 2 for the first l 3 for the second L etc..
And Python also supports reverse indexing.
That is you could do the reverse and starting from zero.
H go backwards in the string so that the very last character first to negative one the second to last
character first and maybe two thirds less character negative three.
And so on reverse indexing is useful for when you don't know how large your string is and you want to
grab subsections of it or the last character of it at the very end.
There you can use reverse indexing.
And that way you don't need to know the full size of the string.
You can just intuitively start from the end of the string and work backwards using negative numbers.
We'll see other examples of this later on first slice notation.
It also uses square brackets and it uses the format start colon stop colon step where step is actually
optional start is a numerical index for the slice.
Start stop is the index you will go up to B actually don't include that stop index and we'll see an
example of that later on and step is how large of a jump to make between characters.
OK we've discussed the basics so far but it's going to make a lot more sense in practice.
Let's connect to a Jupiter notebook and see how this is all done with Python.
OK.
Here we are a notebook before we actually type out our first string.
I want to remind you that for comments you can use a hash tag and then type in whatever you want and
this is a comment.
And if I run this nothing is going to show up and no code in a comment will actually run.
So you can do one plus one here run this and you're not going to see any results anything with that
hash tag in front of it is going to get ignored.
Ok now discuss strings so hello.
We hear we have a string with single quotes and we can also define a string with double quotes.
Now there may be potential errors.
For example imagine we're trying to create a string of single quotes and the string itself contains
a single quote such as I'm not a spy
here we can see we try to enclose this string in single quotes but the problem is the string already
has a single quote in sight of it.
So there's a potential error here because Python is getting confused as where the start and where the
stop of the string should be.
So if you have this it will report back an error.
Invalid syntax because it prematurely ended that string in order to avoid this.
Try to use another set of quotes to capture the inside single quote.
So if we're trying to make.
I'm not a spy a viable string will use double quotes to basically encapsulate that single quote.
And here I can see that the syntax coloring is also indicating that this is now a functional string
and I can see I'm not a spy.
Now let's discuss the basic printing of strings in the Jupiter notebook for this particular environment.
A single string in a cell is automatically returned the back.
However this is actually different than printing a string printing a string allows us to have multiple
outputs.
Let's work through some basic examples.
And as a quick note if your running this code in a dot PI file and you're running your script so your
command line if you just have a single string nothing is going to be output when you run your script
unless you use a print statement.
So let me show you what is peculiar about the notebook.
Let's say I have two strings one in two on separate lines.
If I run this it only actually returns back the last string and in that PI scripts you actually won't
get anything back.
So if you want to see results you should really be printing them out using the prince function and the
print function is just print open close parentheses and then whatever variable or string you want to
print inside there.
So now let's say print 1 and I get back 1 and notice the difference here that the notebook is indicating
that you printed something out.
Previously we saw that the output set out and then the actual string.
Now we're printing something out.
We just see the string message displayed.
We no longer see the quotes and we no longer see the output.
And you'll see a similar result if you're running a PI script you'll just see your output.
And if we want to run or print more than one string I can now say prints 1 print to run this.
And now I can see both results.
There's also special characters or escape codes that Python and most programming languages use.
Let's say we wanted to create a new line so I had hello.
I want this in two lines period.
Well if I run this I see this all in one line and I can actually create this with two lines by using
a special character and we use a backslash in space.
And what this does is this indicates a new line.
So now when I run this I get a new line break and then the rest of the string in this case the rest
of the string Sarto for space.
So if I actually wanted it to have kind of the same indentation I could run this in I can see I've gotten
rid of the space.
The backslash tells Python ignored this and it's basically a special indicator that we want a new line.
There's lots of little special Escape codes for this and we'll discuss this later on especially when
we talk about things like regular expressions.
But in one you should be aware of is backslash T and this in the case a tab essentially four spaces
all right now let's discuss indexing and slicing.
Recall that strings are ordered sequences of characters and that means we can actually grab single characters
using indexing.
Let's create a variable called a word and we will assign that the string hello.
And now I can't say a word is hello and I can use bracket notation.
That is these square brackets to actually index individual characters off of this.
That means if I wanted to grab just a single string or STINGEL character H I could say zero.
And then I get back.
H if I wanted to grab the last o I could either count 0 1 2 3 4 and pass and 4 and I get back that last.
Oh.
Or I can actually use reverse indexing such as negative 1 and that grabs that last chunk of the sequence
as we previously discussed.
That's the basis of indexing.
Square Brecken notation and you pasan a single index location in returns back whatever letter or character
is at that location.
Next let's discuss slicing and that's where you can actually grab an entire subsection of a string.
Let's create another example string.
We'll call this example Alpha for alphabet and it's going to be a b c d e f that way we can tell that
there is a distinct order to this.
If I want to grab a subsection of this string for example let's say I want to grab a b and c what I
do is I indicate my starting index my starting index here is going to be at zero.
So I will say 0 then I will say Colan up to the last index.
And this is where it gets a little tricky and a lot of recruits have trouble.
This particular step you may think that you only need to say 0 1 2 in order to grab ABC but the way
Python works you actually are going to say up to index three here and then we can get ABC.
And I know that can be a little confusing because we just mentioned that indexing starts at zero.
So it's actually going on with this command here is we're saying start at 0 and go up to index 3 and
buy up to they mean go up to it but don't include it.
That means we get 0 1 2.
So we go up to D but we don't include the.
And that's why for slice notation it can be a little tricky at first to kind of wrap your head around
this zero indexing and going up to but not including what's a little strange about it is that the starting
index always includes that value at the index.
However for the stop index it doesn't include that value.
It goes up to it let's try to do a little more practice here.
Let's say we want to grab just the letters C and D.
So I'm going to start index 0 1 2.
So that's where da.
Or C is we'll say two.
And then I want to grab D.
So I want to go up to but not include character.
So that's going to be 0 1 2 3 4.
So we will pass and for run that and that's how I can get back CD for practice.
Try to create other subsections of alpha and see if you can do slice notation to grab them.
You can even make alpha longer Finally I wanted to know some special versions of slicing where you don't
indicate a start or a stop if you want to just grab everything all the way to the end of a string.
You can set your starting index position.
Let's say two for the letter C and I want to grab everything all the way to the end.
I can just say colon and it will grab everything starting at index 2 all the way to the end.
Similarly I can do the same thing by saying colon start at the beginning and go all the way up to but
not including a particular exposition so colon 2 is going to start at the very beginning of the string
and go up to benot including index to basically returning back the characters at 0 and 1 which is a
and b.
Those are the basics of slicing notation.
And finally we can actually use the step to indicate how big of a jump we want to make from character
to character.
By default the step size is one.
But you can adjust it with a third parameter in the slice notation.
So if we take a look at Alpha is again let's say I wanted to grab everything from index 0 all the way
up to the very end.
But I wanted to do it in step size of two.
So I wanted to skip every other letter so go from a take a jump of two steps to grab C take a jump of
two steps to grab e to do that.
I can say Alpha my starting position my stop position and then my step size.
So if I say step size of 2 it returns back to straight A's because it's essentially grabbing every other
letter.
So it goes from a takes a jump of to script C takes a jump of Toot's grab E and that's start stop and
step size for slice notation.
Now let's move on to discussing basic string methods.
Methods are essentially actions that you can call off an object and they're usually in the form dots
or period and method name.
Open and close parentheses.
Let's go ahead and explore these just a little further.
I'm going to create a basic string will say hello world run that cell makes you run that cell that way.
Basic has been defined.
So I checked basic.
It's now defined as a string.
I can say basic dots.
And then your Jupiter notebook hit tab here and you'll notice a list of methods and also attributes
which we'll discuss later on but basic methods allow you to affect or change the variable itself.
Some of them are in place.
Some of them are not in place.
And what I mean by in place is that some of them permanently affect the variable itself.
Others just show you and return a version of it that you would need to save to another variable.
Let's start off with one of the basic methods we can do which is the upper and then we have open enclose
princess here and if we run this you'll notice back it returns uppercase version of the string.
So hello world.
However this is actually not in place meaning that if I check basic again the change is not permanent.
If I wanted the change to happen I could create some new variable and then set that equal to a basic
dot upper open close princes and then that new variable would be hello world in if I wanted the change
to be permanent then instead of just saying variable I would reassign basic itself.
But I'm not going to do that because we still want to play around with basic a little further.
So if I check basic it's still.
Hello world.
There's other methods such as the lower open close parentheses and it will lowercase everything.
We can also do something called split and this is a very common method and it's going to lead us into
our next lesson where split splits on a particular string.
So are a particular character or sequence of characters by default it splits the string on spaces.
So in hello world there's a space here and it returns back what's known as a list of all the characters
that were separated by a space.
We'll discuss this later on.
But I want to show you just one more basic example here.
So if I said basic splits and I wanted to split on all the shows all the O's get removed from the string
and you get back everything that was in between those O's including spaces here.
OK so that's that split.
It's a useful method and it returns back a list and the string is split on whatever character you define.
And if you don't define anything by default it's a space.
We're going to discuss what lists are later on.
So keep this in the back of your mind for the lesson on lists.
OK.
That's all I want to talk about for now as far as basic methods as a quick note if you accidentally
do something like this basic thought split and you forget those open and close print CS you'll get back
something that says O function as TR split.
That means you haven't actually called the function to execute or the method to execute.
It means that you have just asked what is this and Python returns back.
This is a function string split will discuss functions and methods.
A lot further in detail we discussed object oriented programming.
For now just keep in mind that variables once are the fine.
You hit a dot right after them there's going to be a list of methods and attributes available to you.
Finally let's quickly discuss.
Print formatting.
And there's a format method off of a string have already seen the split method in the lower method.
There's a doc format method that allows you to perform what is formally known as string and interpolation
which is essentially inserting variables when printing out a string.
Let's imagine that I have a user name variable and we call this recruits.
I have an action variable called just the string run and I want to say the recruit runs.
Well unfortunately I can't just do something like this.
I cannot say the user name action otherwise I literally get out the user name action.
But we want to do is insert not these strings but these actual variables and the values they hold.
The way we can do that is with the DOT format method.
So the simple way of doing this is we have curly braces here.
So note that these are curly braces and then immediately after the string we call the format method.
Open and close parentheses and then we pass in the variable that we want to insert inside where these
curly braces are.
So I can say that user name variable run that and I see the recruit.
Now let's say I want to print out the recruit needs to run.
I can say the curly braces needs to another set of curly braces and I'll just passen these in order
as expected.
So the username and then needs to action.
We run this and we see that it's injecting in order the user name so the first thing and form it goes
to the first curly braces.
The second thing format goes to the next set of curly braces.
However Python allows for even more flexibility by allowing you to define some parameter names inside
a format and then defining those inside of the curly braces.
Let me show you an example of that instead of format.
I'm going to say A is equal to user name and B is equal to action.
And then I will say A and B here and then when I run this will happen as format sees that these curly
braces asking for whatever parameter is then it looks here and it says well is equal to user names so
I'm going to grab whatever user name is and then inject in here.
What's nice about this is then I can quickly adjust my string without needing to adjust the order of
what's in my format so I could say something like.
The run needs to run or I can say do the reverse here B and then a.
Here the run needs to recruit etc..
So this is a more flexible way of quickly injecting variables into your string.
And this is known as print formatting.
There's also special cases such as formatting numbers.
Let's imagine you have a number of very large floating point number such as one two three point six
seventy nine.
And we wanted to print this out.
Well I could say the code is curly braces.
Then say that format.
Run that and it prints back the entire number for floating point numbers.
You can actually format them.
If you don't want all the significant digits past the decimal point the way you can ask for only a particular
number of significant digits is through the following syntax you say.
Inside this curly braces colon dots then the number of decimals you want off of these decimal places
or number of numbers will often decimal place.
So I will say that one and then you say F..
Run that and now it's going to round off to one place after the decimal.
Let's say I want to round off to two places after That's more than I just change this number two to
four 3.
I just changed it to three.
And if you say 4.
Well basically nothing is going to change there etc..
And if you just want it to round to the nearest whole number you could do.
You could say zero here and it's going to rounded to the nearest whole number.
That's the way you can numbers.
Again with this prince formatting mechanism.
OK those are the basics of strings.
We've already touched a little bit upon list.
Let's go ahead and discuss them in your next lesson.
I'll see you there recruit.