Welcome to your first field readiness exam recruit this exam is going to test your basic skills of Python.
Let's commence a quick overview of the exam notebook.
This is where we test your skills to see if you qualify to become a full field agent.
Your job is to complete the tasks below to the best of your ability.
Immediately after this will go over the solutions and check your performance your first task is to open
the exam that text that's in the same folder as this notebook with Python and make sure to only use
the read permission and store the contents of the file in a list called exam underscore lines.
You can code in this cell here and check the matching output in the cell here.
Notice how all these tasks have a cell free to code in and that a cell that you should not code in.
That way you can retain the expected output tasks to ask you to count how many lines does the file actually
have.
Task 3 asks you to print out the fifth line of the text file.
Task for is to grab the last line of the text file and save it to a variable called last task number
5 is to use indexing to grab letter O and the last line of the file number 6.
How can you use Python's count how many words there are in the last line.
Test number 7 is to answer this multiple part question which is what data types are returned by the
following lines of code.
Basically you should just answer these outloud to yourself and then check with Python to see if you
got the right answer.
There is no actual need to write anything down here.
This is more just to check your understanding test number 8 is to check how well you understand indexing
and key calls.
So we give you a dictionary here with some nested levels of other dictionaries as well as nested lists
and your job is to get the single string.
Get me.
Please check out the directions here under task 8.
There's also 8 bonus tasks ask you how many unique integers are in this list and you're your continued
need to use a casting method that we actually haven't shown you yet.
But we will show you the solutions.
That's why a bonus task.
All right.
Best of luck.
We'll see you at the next lesson.