Welcome back recruit Congratulations on completing your first field readiness exam.
Let's check your performance by going over the solutions.
Let's begin by taking a look at your first task which was to open that exam that textfile did this we'll
say with the open function.
And since this notebook is located in the same directory or same folder as the text file it can just
begin to type in the string example text.
And if I hit tab here I should be able to see the option of exam that text in the dropdown and then
for the read only mode that's going to be the string are if you do shift tab here you'll actually get
the documentation string for this open function and we'll discuss documentation strings for functions
later on.
You'll notice that the default mode is read only.
So you actually can just ignore that and leave that blank.
If you only want read permissions Otherwise you can also just type it in here.
Now we're going to say as F so choose f as a variable name and then we will say exam lines is equal
to f dot read lines.
We'll run this and then check out what exam lines looks like.
And here I can see a list of all the lines in the text file.
Up next was the answer how many lines of code are this this file have since they already have exam lines.
I can just check the length of exam lines and it returns back 7.
So there are seven lines in that file.
If I want to print out the fifth line of that file remember that indexing starts at zero.
So I want to print out the index number for if I want the line because it goes 0 1 2 3 4.
So that's a bit of a trick just to check if you remembered that indexing starts at zero.
So pronounce the fifth line it's going to be four.
So you can check on this by coming back up here.
We can count first line second line third line for flying.
The flying is it should be pretty simple so chilling to the basics so far.
Notice if I say for I get back the fifth line should be pretty simple since you only know the basics
so far.
OK.
Test number four was to grab the last line of the text file and save it to a variable called last.
There's different ways of doing this.
The simplest way is to say last is equal to exam underscore lines and then we can use negative indexing
to grab the last line and then if we check out the result of last.
It just says.
Best of luck recruit.
The alternative way would be to count how many lines there are and then pass in the index of the last
line.
But this method allows you to always get the last line regardless of how many lines it actually has.
So negative 1 is a good trick to use their Test Number five is the use indexing to grab the letter O
from the last line of the file.
If we check out what last looks like we have.
Best of luck recruits we can see here we have this character.
Oh and if we start counting off by 0 we can check the index for which is 0 1 2 3 4 for that space and
then 5.
So we will say last and then use indexing pass and index 5 and those brackets and you get back the letter
O.
Task number six was how could you use Python to count how many words there are in the last line.
Well that's simply just using length again and then passing it last here.
Now we can see we have 21.
However that's not the correct answer because 21 is how many characters to are not how many words there
are.
If we take a look at the last line it says Best of luck recruit.
There should only really be 4 words there.
There's 21 characters including the spaces and the period but there's only four words.
So how do we actually do this.
Well recall that strings have a split method you can call off of them which gives you back a list split
on whatever you pass in here.
And by default it splits on spaces and words are separated by spaces which means we can then check the
length of last split.
Run that and then I get back that there were forwards.
We'll discuss more complex methods of analyzing for patterns.
And as regular expressions later on in your training next we have task seven which is what data types
are returned by the following lines of code.
So this is actually pretty straightforward and you can check this just by running these lines of code
in Python.
But the first one is division and division always returns back float.
Here we have an integer being added to a flow which means the result is going to be a float integer
plus integer.
The result is going to be an integer.
Here we have a string to concatenated with the string to which is what happens when you add a string
to another string so that ends up returning a string.
And then here we can see a comparison operation and that will return a boolean past number 8 is basically
asking you to index to grab.
Get me please.
And you can check out the solutions notebook to see how we do this step by step.
But we're essentially just going to do it out here.
The first thing if we say D we can run keys here.
Whoops.
Let's run this cell to make sure we find D.
There we go.
So I see my dictionary keys I have only one key.
Level one on the outer dictionary.
So we'll pass that in level 1.
Run that and then I see I have a list here.
And it looks like I want this dictionary right here which is the third item in the list or index to
0 1 to we run that.
Now we get this dictionary back.
We'll go ahead and grab this key.
Level 2 loops.
Let me make sure we pass that in as a string correctly.
Then I have this list.
And now just indexing off of this.
So I will grab the second index which gets me that sublist where that nested list the first index which
grabs me in the next one and sometimes a lot of recruits tend to end that here.
Number We actually just want the stream.
This object right here is still technically a list of a single string item.
So if we just wanted the string by itself we would add an additional bracket for 0 and then just get
the string itself.
Finally the bonus task was how many unique integers are in this particular list and you're going to
need to use a casting method we haven't shown yet.
Well the easiest way to do this is if you run this you can actually pass in my list into a set and it
returns back the only the unique integers or unique items in the list.
And then we can check the length of this set to see that we have 12 unique integers in this list.
OK.
Excellent work your crew now that you're done with the basics of data types and storage of Python.
Let's move on to learning about control flow with Python.
I'll see you at the next lesson.