Welcome back recruit and this lesson we're going to be discussing control flow basics control flow allows
us to add logic to our code.
It allows us to also specify under what conditions we want certain blocks of code to execute to do this.
We use that if.
Elif.
Else statements.
Now in order to show the syntax for the statements we to quickly discuss comparison operators comparison
operators allow us to compare two different objects.
Typically for these examples we'll be using them with numbers that you can use them for a variety of
data types.
Here we can see the symbols as well as are associated meaning they should be pretty straightforward
things like greater than less than Lessner equal to greater than or equal to.
And then if you want to check if two objects are equal to each other you can use two equal signs for
equality and then exclamation mark and an equal sign for not being equal.
Now that we know that we can understand how control flow is going to use boolean conditions to decide
whether or not to execute a block of code.
Recall that booleans are either true or false objects and comparison operators that we just saw will
always return a boolean value that we can use for control flow.
So let's go ahead and see some examples of control flow the control flow syntax makes use of colons
and indentation otherwise known as whitespace.
This indentation system is crucial to Python and it's really what sets it apart from other programming
languages.
Indentation results in more readable code.
And it also forces a programmer to organize their code as they program.
And this is one of the main factors in Python's quick rise to popularity.
Let's explore some syntax examples for control flow.
This is the syntax of an IF statement.
We will say if and then check for some condition and then have a colon and then beyond that Colon will
have an indented block of code where we can execute it.
If that condition happens to be true for example we can say if one is less than 2.
Print this is true.
And if we were to run that small block of code we would get out.
This is true since one is less than two we can add on an ELSE to the statement.
We'll first check if some condition is true and if that condition happens to be true will execute some
code.
However we can also specify some other condition to execute if that condition doesn't happen to be true
with the addition of the else statement and notice the indentation line up here.
The else is associated with the same if statement above it because there indentation lines up and that's
how Python is able to understand what blocks of code relate to other blocks of code that uses indentation
to understand that.
Let's go ahead and actually put an example here we can say if one is equal to two prints Whoa else prints
everything normal.
And we were to run this block of code.
You should see everything normal because one is not equal to two.
So that block code doesn't execute.
So then we go down to the else statement.
Finally we can add in Elif statements in order to check for other conditions that are not in the if
statement.
That means we check for the original if statement if one is equal to to print something or execute some
block code and then we can have multiple Elif statements below it and this can check for any number
of other cases that are specific that we want to check to see if that condition is true or false.
And if all of those fail then finally we have our L statement.
Notice how there is no condition on the L statement because it's only going to execute if everything
above it happens to be false.
And in this case we can go along the code and see one is not equal to two so we don't print out whoa
the second block of code is true one is equal to one.
Then we print out what is equal to 1.
And that basically ends this entire block code the elso only get executed if everything above it is
false.
Keep in mind the invitation when utilizing control flow porn that station can lead to mistakes or bugs
in your code.
Let's explore these examples in actual practice and see how we can program using control flow.
Let's begin by cutting out a simple example illustrating what we just talked about.
We'll say if one is less than two colon and then notice when we enter here Jupiter notebook and many
other Python IDS will automatically create the indentation for you and then we can say Prince condition
met.
And when I run this notice I get back condition met if I were to reverse this asking if one is greater
than 2 prints condition meant I don't get any output because this block of code will only execute when
the condition here happens to be true.
And keep in mind it doesn't have to be a comparison operation.
It could just be something like.
True.
So we can say if true prink condition or we could say if false nothing's happened.
Typically you're not going to see a straight bully in here.
Instead you may see an assigned variable so you may have something like C O N D for condition.
Say 1 is less than two.
That's our condition right there.
And then we'll say if condition Prince Khan met and then we see conman's.
So when you're reading someone else's code more likely than not there's going to be some sort of variable
here or some sort of variable comparison.
That's the basis of the if statement.
Let's quickly discuss the if else statement.
And now we can add in an alternate action in case that first if statement doesn't actually end up having
a true condition and really take notice of the indentation and how the blocks are lining up here will
say if one is equal to one Prince condition Mets one equals one and then I'm going to line up an ELSE
block at the same indentation level of this if statement.
And notice I don't have any condition in the else block because the else block it's job is to execute
only if all the other ifs checks above it happen to not occur or be false.
So then will Prince last block happen to run.
We run this and we say condition one is go to one.
If we were to change this so that it was something false like one is equal to a thousand and then I
run this.
It says last block happened to run because this statement didn't execute.
So then we see the Q if we want to check for more than just one condition we can have the Ellis statements.
So that allows us to check for multiple conditions.
Let's give an example of this will say if two is equal to zero.
Prince first US first condition true and then we're going to check for an additional condition.
And here we can actually have a condition that checks will say two equals one here will print.
Second condition.
True.
We'll have one more will say else.
Or else if two is equal to two printouts third condition true and then finally will have an L saying
nothing above was true.
So there we have if now you can have as many elist statements as you want.
And if we run this we get back that the third conditional is true because 2 is equal to is not equal
to zero.
It is not equal to one but two is equal to two.
And the else doesn't occur because it only occurs when all the matching up blocks of LFA if conditions
happen to be false.
Now notice what happens if we end up having multiple conditions in a row that happened to be true.
So we'll say two is equal to two appear as well as Ellis two is equal to two.
So here we have two true statements and if you run this well it ends up occurring is you only end up
executing the first true condition.
So keep that in mind.
This third one here even though the condition it had was true the way Python works is it's going to
keep going up until it finds that first true condition.
Let's work out one final example.
That is a little more practical.
We will create a variable called agent code.
Go ahead and just give the some number.
Doesn't matter what number it is can be random and we'll set up access equal to the variable false.
So we have an agent's code and some sort of access parameter and then we'll write some blocks of code
here to check if the agent code matches up will say if the agent code is equal to 1 2 3 4 5 we will
print out code reset and then also printouts call a supervisor.
That's the first conditional check then we'll actually check to see if we have a matching agent code.
We'll see if agent code is equal to what we wrote above here.
I we'll just go ahead and copy this then we'll Prince welcome agents you know just passing that number
there and I will say access is equal to true.
So no what I'm doing here I will actually be reassigning a variable only on the condition of this agent
code matching up.
And then finally I'll have an else statement here that says print Sorry no matching code
and then further down in this block can actually create some other set of control flow logic.
So I really put a bunch of hash tags here comments to kind of separate out this other block here.
You don't need to do this but it's just for visibility.
We'll say if the access code is equal to true print access granted and then we'll say.
Else.
Prince access.
Access denied.
OK.
So let's see what's actually going to happen before we run this.
We have an agent code and we say x is equal to false.
So Python is going to go along.
It's going to check.
Does the agent Cody go one two three four.
Well it does not.
So we won't run this block code that it's going to check because the agent could equal this number.
It does.
So it will say Prince.
Welcome agent.
And it's going to reset access to be true then else it's not going to execute because we had something
true up here and it's going to keep going down.
And here we can see we've now said and started another block of if else statements and the way Python
knows that this block up here doesn't have anything to do if this block down here is because we've essentially
closed off this if statement with an L statement leaving us open to start up a new if else statement.
So let's run this and see what happens.
We get welcome.
Agent 2 3 1 9 2.
And then we also get access is granted because we had an additional check here.
X is equal to true print access granted and we can actually if we wanted to take a look at this last
set we could split up this one into a new cell itself or a new piece or another script.
If you want to analyse what's going to happen here so we say if we run this code says welcome.
Agent 2 3 1 9 2.
And if we run this year you'll still say access granted Let's run this with 1 2 3 4 5 well run this
run this sell again and now it's as code reset call a supervisor.
And if we run this again here since Access is equal to false and we never actually reassigned it in
this block because we instead ran the code reset block when I run this last cell it will say Access
Denied the last point I want to make here is if you already know that your variable itself is a Boolean
either true or false.
So for example if I just ask what access is it's going to be false or if it happens to be a right re-assign
it will be true.
You don't really need to make this comparison because Access itself is already a boolean and this is
a typical example of being able to differentiate someone who's just learning Python to someone who's
a little more experienced than Python.
This sort of code right here indicates someone who's not very experienced in Python because a more experienced
developer would have realized that Access itself is already a boolean meaning it could have just done
this.
They don't need a check if x is equal to true.
They just need to check the access variable itself.
So this is how you're going to see more experienced developers write their code.
They will say if Access print access granted else print access denied and this code you can see here
we ran it again.
Works exactly the same.
Because Access itself is the actual boolean variable.
So writing code like we just did is a little bit cleaner and it also allows you to name your variables
differently to make it even more readable.
So we could have renamed access to be access underscore granted to that it could say if Access Granted
print access granted.
All right excellent work so far.
Now that we understand control flow we can begin to build an understanding of loops.
Coming up next.