Welcome to your second field reading this exam this field readiness exam will test your skills with
control flow loops and built in functions such as the range function in Python.
Let's commence a quick overview of the exam.
Here we are at the notebook for your second field readiness exam.
Let's quickly go over the tasks.
Your first task is to use a for loop and indexing to print out only the words that start with an S in
the sentence and the sentence is right here.
Secret agents are super good at staying hidden.
Notice how this s is capitalized and other essays are not.
So given this string your code should be able to print something that looks like this secret super and
setting tasks Number two is to use the same string.
However now use a for loop that only prints out the words with an even number of characters.
So instead of this for loop you'll have to have some sort of check that the length of each word is even
and if it is then go ahead and print it out.
Test them or three is to use a list comprehension.
Create a list of every first letter in the string.
So at the end of the day you should be able to create a list that looks something like this.
Notice how each of these characters is the first character in each of these words has.
Number four is to use list comprehensions.
Create a list of all the even numbers from 0 to 10.
The next task is to use the range function to create a list of all the even numbers from 0 to 10.
So notice the difference here.
The first one is using list comprehension.
The second one you're going to need to be able to learn how to transform the range function or cast
arrange function into creating the same sort of list.
Task number 6 is create a for loop that uses the random library to create a list of 10 random numbers.
So have to import it ran them for you here.
Go ahead and use it to try to create a list that is just a bunch of random numbers.
Obviously your results won't be the same as shown here.
Use less comprehension and the random library.
Create a list of 10 random numbers.
So now it's a similar task except you have to use list comprehension.
Previously you had to use a for loop test number 8 is to create a while loop that will ask the user
to input an even number and it's going to keep repeating the request until an even integer is provided.
Now you should only expect integers to be passed then if the user provides a string or something else
that can't be transformed if an integer with the I.A. function then the loop is just going to break
with an air.
Again the important thing to keep in mind here when working via loops in the input function is that
it's very easy to get stuck with an infinite loop as you're beginning to iterate on your code.
If you ever get stuck then you going to see this in cell right here.
Get stuck with an Asterix and it happens.
Go ahead and click on kernel and then hit restart.
All right.
Best of luck recruit and we'll see you at the next lesson.
Well we'll go over the solutions.