Welcome back.
Let's evaluate your performance on the second field readiness exam by going over the solutions.
We'll begin by taking a look at your first task which was to create a for loop and indexing that printed
out the only the words that served as in the sentence string right here so we can do that by saying
for word in my string what we can do is as the hint says is use the Split method and recall the split
method by default splits and the white spaces string.
So now that split is actually just a list of the words and we can show this in another cell.
Just to clarify that if we do that split here we can see secret agents etc. all the words in a list.
So now I can iterate through these words in this list and then I can check what the first letter is
by saying take that word lowercase that word and then off that word index the very first letter off
of it and then if the first letter is equal to S then I'm going to print the word and if I run that
I get back the same results secret super and staying.
So key things here was to realize you could use split in order to create this list.
And when you're iterating through it you can use the lower to lower case.
This entire word and then use indexing to just grab the first character of that word and then check
to see if it equals lowercase us test number two is using the same string as previously used.
Use a for loop to only put out the words with an even number of characters.
It's going to be quite a similar setup we will say for word in my string and will again split this.
We can go through every word and this will say if the length of the word maade to is equal to zero print
out the word.
So what's actually happening is basically in the key line here.
Length of word is going to return an integer length of every word in this particular list once we call
that split on it.
They'll check the length for that word Maat by two is equal to zero.
Meaning when you divide it by 2 it has a remainder of 0.
If that's the case then we know that that word only has an even number of characters so it can go ahead
and print it out past number three was to use a list comprehension to create a list of every first letter
in this string.
So there's a little trick here because basically you want to rewrite something similar to this except
you don't need to check out the S anymore.
Instead we kind of really want to focus on this line right here.
So what do we do.
We can go ahead and say the following will say set up the brackets word indexed at 0 4 word in my string
that split again basically saying for every word in this list my string that split.
Go ahead and index off the zero from that word.
And then we here we have the first letters in the string and if we want to we could also done that lower
in order to lower case this first S was optional.
It's pretty much up to you.
Up next was the useless comprehension.
Create a list of all the even numbers from 0 to 10.
So to do that they can easily say and for n in range and we'll go 0 up to 11 and then we can have our
if statement if and Mattu is 2 0 and you can check out the list comprehension lecture for an example
that pretty much looks like this.
The next one was pretty similar.
It was said use the range functions create a list of all even numbers.
So to do that recall that range function has a third parameter which is a step size of two.
And then if we cast that to illest we get back the same results.
Likewise you could have also done the same thing here or you could just said Comet too and then gotten
rid of the if statement and that would have been the same thing task number six was to create a for
loop that uses the random library to create a list of 10 random numbers.
So to do this for a loop we first set up some sort of list as a placeholder and then we'll say for x
in range 0 to 11 so that we do this 10 times the results list we're going to append the random number
and we'll say random Rantz that built in function and then grab a random number from 0 to 100.
And then finally outside of this for loop we can go ahead and print the results and whoops forgot to
import ran them here.
Run this again.
And here we see the results.
And every time you run this you're pretty much going to get a different set of results.
So keep that in mind since they are random numbers you're not going to get the exact same results every
time task number 7 was to use less comprehension in the random library to create a list of 10 random
numbers.
So that's a very similar thing essentially just transforming the list above into a list comprehension.
So it's a random random random ANC zero to 100 for whatever variable and in range 0 to 11.
And then we get our random list of numbers.
So keep in mind you could call this and whatever you want.
So you could say elements run this and still work.
So it's totally up to you but this is essentially the list comprehension method of this your final task
was created a while loop.
That's going to continually ask the user input even number and it's going to keep repeating that request
until an even integer is provided.
So there are lots and lots of ways you could have done this.
So keep that in mind.
Your results may look different than what I have here but I'm going to do this as I will set some variable
called result and I'll start that off as an odd number and I'll say it while this result Mattu is not
equal to zero.
Do the following.
So all I'm saying here is while this number is not even continues to do something so I'll say number
provided by the user is input and then we'll say please input a number and I will cast this because
remember input returns a string.
I will cast this to be an integer and then I will say what if some Matsu is not equal to zero meaning.
This is still not an even number.
I to keep the result as an odd number else.
I will print.
Thank you.
That is an even number.
And then I will set my result equal to some even number such as two.
So let's take a look at the logic here.
We're saying this result variable starts off as odd.
And while it remains on go ahead and continually ask for an even number and once we do have an even
number go ahead and set the result even and then we're good to go.
So if I run this it's going to ask me to put a number or put in three put in five.
Keep putting in odd numbers but then finally if we put in something like 6 it will say thank you.
That is an even number.
So that's one way to do this.
If it's confusing to you then you have result as the main check.
Well we can do instead is have a result be a boolean.
So we'll say boolean right now is true.
And then we'll say while results so continually run while result is true.
And if the number happens to be odd we will say result is still true but if it happens to be even we'll
say result is false.
So this is actually the exact same thing.
And if this is more readable to you or makes more sense go ahead and do it this way.
Basically just have some sort of variable whose condition is going to change based off what you want
it to accomplish which was to get an even number from the user.
All right.
That's it for field readiness exam number two hope you dwell on it.
We'll see at the next lesson.
Recruit.