Many things recruit.
The institute cannot thank you enough for your assistance in thwarting nefarious deeds.
In reviewing our system logs it appears this attack originated with a group of rogue agents agents who
were once part of this very Institute only to defect and engage in criminal acts.
They are now our enemies.
But be warned because they've been trained by the Institute.
This group of rogue agents knows exactly how we operate.
Thanks to your quick thinking we've been able to hold them off for now.
But they will be back.
You've done extraordinary work in your training and we're all very eager for you to complete your remaining
topics so I can welcome you to the field as a full Agent.
I will have a need to contact you to discuss the final stage of your training.
Thank you again recruit.
We couldn't have done it without you.