Let's now discuss error handling and exceptions errors are bound to happen in your code especially when
someone else ends up using it in an unexpected way.
We can use error handling in an attempt to plan for possible errors that may occur in your code.
For example if we were to try to write to a file that was only opened in the our reader mode then an
error occurs and the script will just stop running completely because you need to open a file.
He writes permission in order to write to it.
Now what if we actually wanted the script to continue.
In that case we can use the try except.
And finally keywords to catch errors create a block of code that will run in case an error happens.
And then finally run the rest of the script that way.
Even if an error happens your script can't account for it and then continue on.
Let's explore how the syntax works in a notebook.
Let's begin by discussing the try except.
Else statements put together and then later on we'll introduce the keyboard.
Finally So here we have our tri key word.
And underneath this tricky word is the block of code that you expect might induce an error.
And as we've previously discussed this could be something like trying to open a file with only read
permissions and then you try to write to it and you make it an error.
So if you try to do that a particular exception is going to occur and to give you an idea of what this
looks like if you've ever tried to for instance say one plus two.
So I'm trying to add an integer to a string.
Notice here we have type error.
So we have a special exception code type error and then it has some sort of explanatory text to non-supported
operation for addition with integer and string.
And you can go to documentation under the exceptions list.
So this is Dachs Python.
Or three slushed library slash exceptions.
And there's an entire list of built in exceptions here.
Assertions are actually error.
Import error.
OS error and you can scroll down and you can see all these particular types of errors and what the except
blocks like to do is try to catch certain exceptions.
So for instance if there's a particular exception here such as exception one then we're going to execute
this block.
And then finally we can have an else statement where if there is no exception then we execute this block.
So let's see this simple example.
We're going to try to do the following here.
We're going to try to add an integer to a string and then we're going to say except now we're going
to accept this type error.
So we'll say except the type error.
And if that happens we're going to print out a statement saying you are not adding the correct things
together.
And this sort of print statement really helps out when you have other people using your code because
sometimes these airlines don't give enough of a description and your print statements can do that.
Or your print functions can do that much better.
And then we're going to say.
Else Prince everything ran smoothly.
So if I run this and now we see the print that statement you're not adding the correct things together
that means our script didn't actually break completely.
Instead we accepted that we had a type error here and then we printed out you're not at in the correct
things together and this is a nice message for someone who's trying to use your code and they realize
oh I'm not adding the correct things together.
So you may be thinking well if I know there's going to be an error beforehand.
Why would I not just fix the error.
Well maybe this too is actually an input statement.
Maybe it's something like.
Result is equal to input.
Please enter a number and then we were trying to cast that number as an integer.
So something like this happens then maybe someone types in the wrong thing like the letter A.
So if we were just trying to get this code by itself and we were to run it here so I do shift enter
Please enter a number of Antar letter here.
Then I get a value error.
So it says value error in that invalid literal.
So I can grab this error code and say except type error you're not doing the correct things together
or that I can also add a new exception called value error and instead of saying invalid literal for
base 10 are what I'm going to say is hey make sure you supply a number.
So now when I run this it's going to say Please enter a number.
And if I hit three then it says everything ran smoothly.
However if I try running this again and I input something like y it says hey make sure you supply a
number.
So now you get a very nice looking script.
And even if the user is using it incorrectly you get some results that make a cleaner outlook versus
these value errors which are sometimes hard to understand errors Now you may also be wondering do I
have to memorize every single type of built in exception.
Well you definitely do not.
In fact you can just have a single accept statement with no exception code and then you can just say
Prince Hey an error occurred.
And this basically says just catch any exception.
So if I run this again and input the letter R It says Hey an error occurred.
That way you don't need to worry about memorizing every single exception that's possible.
But what's nice about the alternative is sometimes you may want certain print statements or even certain
blocks of code to execute in case a certain exception occurs.
So now let's look at another example of trying to open a file.
We're going to say Try and we will say f open a test file and we will do it with right permissions.
So that is w permissions.
Then we're going to write test write this
and then we will say except and we'll try to accept an I O error or let's just accept any error so we'll
say except and then we're going to prints Hey an error happened.
And then we'll say.
Else.
Prince everything worked so if we come back here and there run this.
It says everything works.
However if I were to change this to our So read mode and I try to write to it and then I run this again.
It says Hey an error happened because I didn't have the right permissions and if I were just to try
to run these two blocks instead without the use of that try block of code then I just would have gotten
unsupported operation not rideable.
So notice here how my Except allow scripts to continue running even if you have errors that happen in
them.
Now we have try.
Except an else but maybe you want the try block of code to run the accept statement to run and something
else to keep going after both.
Try and accept have been triggered in that case.
You can use the finally keyword and the finally key word we will always execute even after there's an
exception.
So we can write here finally.
Always run this block of code so let's run that again and you can see here that we have try.
So we try to run this code.
We print Hey an error happen.
And then finally we execute this block of code.
So this is different than.
Else because elf's only occurred if everything actually worked.
And here finally this is going to run regardless of things working or not working.
And you can see here if I changed this back to W meaning the try block should work anyways.
And I try to run this then I don't get the exception but my finally block still prints.
So that's how you can use try except.
And finally keywords when you're trying to handle errors.
Excellent work so far.
We'll see you at the next lesson.