Let's now walk through some examples tasks using Python and the various libraries for web scraping.
Let's go to Jupiter notebook
to begin we're going to start with a very simple web site.
We will be scraping w WWE example dot com just see example domain for illustrating purposes.
So the first thing we need to do is import the requests library the request library allows us to send
the request and grab information from a Web site.
We will say Arrius is equal to then we'll type out requests.
We will say Dot get.
And then we need to provide that you are all of the Web site.
So in this case we're going to say HTP for Slash for Slash.
W w w dot example dot com.
And it's important that you add in either HTP or Eesh to P. S..
Otherwise if you just say exampled dot com most likely you're going to get some sort of failure.
Now keep in mind if you have a firewall you're going to need to disable it.
Otherwise Python may get blocked from scraping the Web site.
So if you run this and you've already installed requests then you should see this run with no problem.
And if we check out the result of this we have a response.
Results and this response.
We can grab the text attribute.
And this is essentially the actual each team that's on the Web site and we're going to be using the
beautiful soup to analyze the extracted page.
So keep that difference in mind.
We use the requests library to actually get the content of a Web site and then we use the beautiful
soup to analyze that content.
And if we check out exampled dot com and if we were to right click and view page source we can see that
we have the actual HTML file from example dot com.
This is essentially the information that's returned when you type in a request.
You can see that same information here except it's not nicely formatted but it's the same information.
So what we're going to do next is import B-S for food beautiful soup.
And the idea behind beautiful soup is that we create a soup object that contains all the quote unquote
ingredients of a web page so it will do is say soup is equal to B-S for and we'll call the beautiful
soup method.
And then we will pass in this text we have right here.
So we're going to say yes that text and then we need to pasan l l as a code that allows us to actually
format this and then read it and we need to make sure you've installed Elham L S M library as well.
So make sure you've done pipin Soller Condon's call for both.
B As for the request library and elec Semei library.
Once you run this the beautiful soup is going to create a soup object out of this.
That means you can easily read things off of it or select elements off of it.
So we have this soup object so if we check out what soup is it's this beautiful soup object and we can
call the Select method off of this and then we can pass and tags.
So if we take a look back at the H team L here.
If I zoom in a lot I can see that there's a title here for the web page and it says example domain.
And that's going to be the same title that's appear in the tab of the example domain.
So when I come here I can select the title tag.
Now what is actually returned the back is a list of a tag object.
So let's explain that a little more.
We're going to say that my title tag list is equal to super select title.
I run this and if I check up my title tag list and run that I see I have this and that's going to be
a list of everything that had a title tag inside of this example domains H-2A mail.
Now what we can do is index off of this and then I can see I have this tag object.
So this is actually not a string yet it's still if we take a look at type it's this special beautiful
suit for element tag object.
And what we want is the actual text of that.
So if I take a look at just what that was.
It's this title and I just want the actual text.
So what I'm going to do is say Dot and there's a text method you can call for this to get the example
domain and that is a full example of web scraping.
It's a very simple example but it technically goes through all the steps.
Let's quickly review.
So we have an idea of what we need to do.
You first need to import the request library then send your request to whatever you are all you're interested
in.
Check the text and that should be the HTML document itself and then you're going to import beautiful
soup.
You're going to create a soup out of that text then you're going to use L L S and L as a string code
for reading this text in and created the soup from it.
Then you can select different tags from the actual soup object and that will return back a list of all
the objects to have that tag and then you can extract information from that.
Now let's move on to another example where we attempt to grab all the elements of a particular class
on a Web site.
For example we're going to be using a Wikipedia page and the Wikipedia page will be using is the Wikipedia
page for ROOM 6 4 1 8.
And you have this link in the guide to web scraping notebook so you can go ahead and check that out
or do a simple Google search for this Wikipedia page.
Well we will attempt to do is grab all the section headings of this wikipedia article and what we mean
by section headings are the words here description last to gallery and then see also.
So the actual titles of these headings or whatever these words are.
The text and these headings is what we want to grab.
So how do we actually do this when we first need to actually request the Web site.
So let's do that and then we'll come back in a second and explain what this syntax means.
But we will say R E S is equal to requests.
Dots gets and we will passen that u r l and it will grab that Web site information for us then we will
say soup is equal to B S for beautiful soup and then we'll pass in the text and say x.
L in order to read that in.
And now we have a soup object.
So then I can't say soup select.
However now I have a problem.
Previously I wanted to select the title.
Now we need to figure out what I actually want to select.
And in this case we're going to need to inspect this website or inspect the source code for this Web
site.
So what you need to do is whenever your web scraping a Web site and you're looking for a particular
class or what you actually want to pass into the select statement what you do is you right click on
whatever you're interested in and then say inspect not view page source but inspect.
And then if you're using the Chrome browser you should be able to see a doc h l type come up on part
of your screen either on the bottom or the side and you will see highlighted what you just inspected
and hopefully what you inspected either has an ID or a class.
And if we look at this closely we can see that under each two tab there is a class M.W. that headline
and an ID description.
There's no right answer as far as what we need to select.
A lot of times it's going to take experimentation to see if it makes sense to grab IDs make sense to
grab headers or tags or it makes sense to grab a class.
So one approach would be to try to grab everything that is an H to heading on this page and that might
be all the titles.
However we might get some other stuff really you're going to have to experiment when working of other
web sites.
In our case we're going we're going to attempt to use this class M.W. dash headline because that seems
to be like a good indicator of the actual headers for the content description lawsuit cetera.
So we will do as we were we are going to grab this M.W. dash headline and use that as our selection.
So we'll come back here and we will say M.W. dash headline except keep in mind M.W. Dasch headline.
It's actually a class so there's a bit of a syntax.
We need to use for certain CSSA calls.
And these are the following.
You can find this table as well in your notebook but these are the following syntax calls for the different
things are going to select.
If you just say that selects with a single string that's going to assume that that string stands for
some sort of h m l element such as all the paragraphs.
Everything of a DIV tag everything or title just like we did appear we get everything of the title.
In this case.
Were you actually going to be using a CSSA class if you start with a hash tag that's going to be trying
to grab anything with that ID.
And then if you start with a period or a dot that's going to grab everything with the class.
In this case named notice.
So we're using a class which means we need to store our select statement with Dot M.W. dash headline
and if you were to open up a CSSA file it follows the same convention.
So IDs for hash tag classes start off a dot and if you want to get a little more complex with your select
methods you can also have two tags spaced out and the selects all elements named spanne that are within
a div elements.
And if you use this greater than symbol that's going to select any elements named spanne that are directly
with an element named div with no other elements in between.
So these are a little more complex and sometimes they require you to study up a little more on team
Ellen CSSA.
But in our case we're mostly going to be using these first three either grab all the elements of some
sort of tag grab all the ID elements or grab all the class elements.
Now when I run this select statement for the class it looks like I get a list of all the letters that
I wanted description lawsuit Galerie see also references and external links.
So it looks like we made the right choice.
If we had done another choice like soup.
Select everything from H to and ran that I probably would have gotten some stuff that it didn't want
and you can see here it looks like we're getting more information than we really wanted.
And it looks like it has some other sections in there like navigation menu but it might have been a
pretty close call.
So as I previously mentioned it's going to take some guessing and checking to see what's the right thing
you want to select.
In our case it looks like it's going to be M.W. that headline.
Now remember I actually just want the text of this not the for tag objects.
So instead of that I'm going to iterate through this.
We're going to say for item in this list of tags print out the items text and then when we run that
I get back what I wanted description lawsuit Galerie see also references and external links.
So let's review what we did here.
What we did was we sent a request to the U R L we created a soup out of that by passing in the text
of that and created soup.
And then we said soup that select.
And we had to do was use the inspect tool in our browser to actually figure out what we're looking for.
And that's really the hardest part of any web scraping.
It's not actually getting the stuff or creating the soup it's trying to figure out what exactly am I
trying to select.
And we're looking at pretty basic examples so it's more or less obvious especially if you have a little
experience weps scraping but a lot of times there's going to be classes within classes.
Many I had an idea for a lot of elements and they're going to be tags associated with that.
So you're going to do some guessing and checking to see what you are actually trying to grab or select
in order to grab what you want.
But in our case we figured out that we wanted to grab a class and because it was a class we had to start
with a period or a there and then the class name.
So as a review if it's just an HTL tag you pass in the string.
If it's a particular ID.
So if you were to come over here and you saw the description and you wanted to grab that ID then you
would say hash tag and the ID name.
Keep in mind IDs only occur or should only occur once each team document.
So it's a good indication that describing one thing if you're trying to grab a class of objects you
would say dot and then whatever name of the classes and then you have some more complex methods in case
you want elements within elements.
All right we still have a few more examples to go and we'll be going over them in the next lesson.
We'll see you there.
Agent.