Welcome back agent to finish off our discussion on regular expression syntax.
We're going to discuss just a few more useful methods.
You may find yourself using out in the field.
First off let's discuss the OR operator.
Sometimes you're going to want to search for multiple terms.
You can use the OR operator to do this.
For example if we say our search and then the pattern we want to search for is a string.
For instance just the string cat and we say search the actual string.
The cat is here.
If you run this we get a match for cat but if it says the dog is here as you expect we don't get a match.
What if we wanted to search for cat or dog.
In that case we can use the pipe operator.
So the pipe operator looks like that.
And that stands for or meaning we can search for cat or dog and then we'll get a match if there's a
dog there or if there's a cat there.
So that's the OR operator.
There's also a wild card operator and the wild card acts as a placement that will match any character
place there so please find all to show you an example of the wild card operator.
First I'm just going to search for the string 80 or at and I'll search for the string The Cat In The
Hat.
Sat there Senatus I have three matches of at cat hat and sat.
But what if I actually wanted to grab the actual letter in front of a T.
In that case I can provide a period.
And that stands for a wild card meaning any thing here any wild card there attached to a tee.
And then when I run this I get back cat hat and sat.
So again the period can act as a wild card for you.
So notice how we're really only matching the first three letters.
But if we had something longer for instance such as Splatt.
So the cat in the hat will say went splat.
What I could do is add more wild cards.
So now I have let's say up to three wild cards here.
So the cat in the hat went splat.
So S P L A T.
But keep in mind these wild card characters are also going to grab other letters and other spaces.
So if I were to run this I get back E-Space cat E-Space hat and then the full splat.
And the reason I'm grabbing E-Space is because the wildcard characters are counting the stuff that comes
before this first letter.
So it's also counting this space and this e as well was this space and this e for the cat and the hat.
So keep that in mind as you use wildcard characters the period if you want more control you'll want
to use the character identifier as we discussed earlier.
Again period essentially just a wildcard.
All right.
Let's finally discuss starts with and ends with so we can use this this carrot symbol showing just the
second.
We'll say our Eve find all.
And if I want to find everything that starts with the number what I can do is in the K this carrot symbol
or two power symbol that's just shift number 6 and then type in what I'm looking for.
So what this indicates is that the string I'm searching through starts with a number so say 1 is a number.
And this returns a match for one because the entire text itself starts with the actual digit.
Keep in mind this is only for the entire text not for a number randomly inside of this.
So if I say the two is a number I'm not going to get any matches here because it's only searching if
the entire text itself starts of a number.
So if I say two is the number then I find my match for two.
Similarly I can say ends with.
And the way you do that is sort of a carrot symbol.
You just at the end of this pattern put a dollar sign that says ends with.
So if I say two is number I don't get a match but if I say the number is 2 then I do get a match.
So again dollar sign for ends with And then this card or power to sign for starts with.
And then there's also ways you can use exclusion.
So to exclude characters we again we use this symbol but we use it in conjunction with a set of brackets.
So let's make a couple of our cells here so we don't get confused by the earlier syntax.
I'm going to create a phrase called there are three numbers.
34 is not a number inside 5.
This sentence.
OK.
So here I have a phrase it seems like just random numbers placed inside the sentence.
What I want to do is find or get back everything that isn't a number in this sentence.
So I want to exclude digits or exclude numbers the format for that is the following.
You'll see your pattern is equal to and use inside of square brackets just like you would for a kind
of a python list.
Say whatever you want to exclude.
So in this case I want to exclude digits.
So look at the syntax here.
I have square braces or square brackets this symbol and then backslash lowercase D.
So that just says exclude any digits so anything that matches with this character that the fire and
that if I say find all in and I put a phrase here I'm going to get back a list of every single character
that was not a number.
So I see there are.
And then there's no number there numbers inside this sentence.
And what we can do is if we actually want to get the words back together I can at a plus sign to the
end of this because remember a plus sign if we look back at our quantifiers It just says occurs one
or more times.
So this is a nice way of regular expression to quickly remove things.
So let's run these lines again.
And I can see there are excluded essentially these groups of numbers there are numbers inside this sentence.
All right.
So why would you use this exclusion syntax.
This is a really common way to get rid of punctuation from a sentence.
So we will say test underscore a phrase is equal to.
This is a string exclamation point but it has punctuation period.
How can we remove it.
Question mark.
Well we can do is the following will say r e.
Fine.
All and inside of this we're going to say square brackets this symbol.
And now I can add things I want to exclude So I'm going to just put them in the same order so I can
say I want to exclude an exclamation point.
I want to exclude it period and I want to exclude a question mark and then I can add a plus sign.
So I just want to exclude those wherever they occur.
And then I will say test phrase.
And now I get back the list.
This is a string.
Notice how it's essentially being split on any punctuation but it has punctuation.
How can we remove it.
So there's no longer any punctuation there.
And something else we can do is add a space here so that it will end up removing the spaces.
And then I get back a list of all the words meaning if I say this is clean
the now clean is all these words and I can then join them.
So I will say join clean and I'll join them all with the space itself and then I get back.
This is a string but it has punctuation.
How can we remove it.
So these are some more complex tasks you can use with regular expressions and obviously you can see
here how this quickly can get very hard to read.
So always break down regular expression pattern codes in order to try to help yourself understand what's
actually happening.
We're going to show you two more useful things you can use for regular expressions.
And one of them is actually these brackets are braces here these square brackets.
And that actually is basically just for grouping things together in the context of this carit symbol
essentially says group these things for exclusion.
But you can also use them grouping for inclusion.
So let's show a couple of examples of that.
We're going to create some text that says only find the hyphen dash words in this sentence.
But you do not know how long dash ish they are.
OK so we have this text.
And basically the main point is text is that I have hyphen dash words and then later on I also have
in-dash words but note here how I don't know how many letters are before and how many letters are after
this dash.
So my main task is given this piece of text.
Go ahead and find words to have a hyphen or a dash in the middle of them.
So how would I do that.
Well the general pattern idea would be a group of alphanumeric words or characters dash and then some
other group of alphanumeric characters.
So the way we do that is by filling out the following pattern the pattern is going to be
braces and then inside these braces I will say backslash w and then I'll add a plus sign there.
And what this indicates is just a group of backslash lowercase W..
So remember back from our character in the fires lowercase W. is just an alphanumeric.
So it's basically looking for a group.
Alphanumerics And remember of the plus where it's essentially saying occurs one or more times
so we can check for this pattern.
We'll say are either find all and then we'll pass in the pattern passed in the text and it finds back
any groups of alphanumerics.
Now if I want to find the hyphenated words I'll say a group of alphanumerics that occurs one or more
times.
Dash and then another group of alphanumerics that occurs one or more times and then I can get back the
actual hyphenated words.
Now if we were to remove these actual braces so that it looks like this you would get back the same
results.
However some programmers because this looks hard to read they like two separate groups using this brace
notation and the notation also allows you to kind of combine things together.
So maybe you're looking for a word and then some digits for some reason you can use those braces to
do this sort of grouping syntax.
So just keep that in mind.
Out in the field you see sometimes people using braces like this.
Often you'll see braces used in these sort of exclusions statements but they can also be used for inclusion
and then you can also use parentheses for multiple options so multiple options for matching you can
use print to list out these options.
So I'm going to copy and paste some code here pretty quickly.
Just from the note book that goes along with this video and we say text is equal to.
Hello would you like some catfish text to says hello.
Would you like to take a cat nap and then text 3 says hello.
Have you seen this cat or pillar.
So that is how all of these start with cat and then it says Fish Napp pillar.
So if you wanted to kind of find the different options what you could do is say search cats and then
you can use parentheses to kind of group together multiple options.
So will say fish Napp and then you could say Klaw.
So let's see how this works.
Will say text.
So when I run the finds cat fish.
So that was the first instance of that and then if I say text 2 it says catnap and if I say text 3 it
doesn't find anything because I didn't say basically or pillar.
So I'm going to copy this and put that in there.
Or pillar.
Now if I checked text 3 it finds the match.
So all this is doing is allowing you to basically combine that or statement we saw earlier with other
pieces of text and provide multiple options.
That's the basics of regular expressions and you can check out the documentation page on regular expressions
in the Python official documentation.
It's linked to you at the bottom of the notebook.
For more information or regular expressions.
Again it can definitely very quickly get into some very complex looking syntax that is difficult to
read but always remember just the basics where the main idea is you have some sort of character that
the fire and then attached to it some sort of quantifier if necessary.
All right.
Best of luck out there in the field agent.
I hope this was helpful for you.