Welcome back agent.
Let's now discuss opening and reading files.
In your recruitment bootcamp you've actually already learned how to open a single file.
However often you're going to need to open every file and a directory or multiple directories on the
computer.
Python's built 10 O S module for operating systems can apply to walk through files and folders on the
computer as well as open them the os module functions and commands are also independent of Mac OS Linux
Windows or other operating systems.
Meaning that the same script you use to open and go through the rectories files on your computer will
work on any operating system.
As long as you use the os module Let's explore how to use this module by going to an open book.
Let's begin by quickly creating a file we can use to practice with.
We will call this file practice thought Trixi for a simple text file and will say open with the mode
w plus.
That way we can write this file because it doesn't exist yet.
And then we're going to write a single line to this file.
Just test line or test whatever you want and let's close the file.
All right.
Nlisse discuss this.
Built an os module.
The first thing you need to do is actually import it by running.
Import os.
There's many different methods and functions that are available off of the os module.
Let's discuss a few of the more basic ones.
The first one is to actually get your current directory to do that.
You can type os dots and if you hit tab you'll realize all the various functions and attributes that
are here but the one we're going to be using is G.T. gets.
And then C W D stands for get current working rectory.
And if you run this method or this function off of the os module it basically just reports back where
the notebook is currently located.
And if you were to run this in your script it would run and return back the location wherever your script
is currently located.
So again it returns back your current working directory.
What's really nice about this is it returns back the string.
You can then use to maybe pass along with an open statement to know what location and text files are
in.
So that's getting your current working directory.
If you want to list all the files in a directory you can use OS dot and then l i s t d.
R that's for listing everything in your current directory.
Obviously the results will differ the pending on where you're located but here you can see these are
all the files I have located under this current directory and you can actually pasan any directory you
want.
So for example you can pasan your users directory and it will return back everything that's in the user's
directory.
So again this is a basic list directory command.
And if you just run it by itself it prints out everything that's in your current directory.
Again to find a current directory see there'll be the or if you want.
You can pass in any folder or directory location and it lists everything that's in that directory.
In other very helpful builtin module in Python is the s h util model or as utility module.
Let's show you how to use it.
We're going to import S H U T I L and this basically provides a lot of utilities for dealing with files
on your computer and later on we'll see how we can use it.
We're also zipping and unzipping files.
Right now we're going to show you how you can move files around your computer programmatically using
this module to move the file.
You can say move and you can see here basically it just takes two commands as her see.
That is the source of the file and then the s t which is the destination of a file.
Now remember we actually have the practice text file we just created appear so let's confirm that by
running OS.
Thought list.
Diyar.
And if we run that eventually somewhere in this list you should find the text file you just created.
So it looks like I have it right here.
This text file and want to move this practice text file to let's say in other users file silts move
it to this user's file right here.
So we're going to scroll down here and we're going to move the practice t x t file.
Too one of the user's files
and note the actual syntax here if you're on Linux or Mac you're going to want to make sure that your
forward slashes are backslashes follow the same syntax that is reported back to you when you say get
c d.
Maybe you have single forward slashes on a Mac or Linux computers follow that format.
If you're on Windows you'll follow the double backslash OK so this is saying move this practice text
file to this location on your computer.
So when we run this it reports back.
The final location of the file.
So it looks like it.
Move it.
Let's confirm that it move it by listing everything in our the directory again.
And if we look back to P We no longer actually have the practice textfile there.
So let's try moving it back to our current directory so way we can do that is through the following.
Let's comment this out.
We will again call the move function.
We already know the location because it is reported Baxi can copy and paste whatever reports back as
your source.
And if we want to move it to our current directory all we have to do is say oh yes that's gets current
working directory and execute that function because remember this get current work the rectory just
returns back your current working that victory.
So now this will go and grab that practice text file from this user and move it back to the directory
we're currently in and out report's backward is and we can again confirm by listing out make sure syntax
is right there by listing our current directory and we scroll down and we eventually see that yes practice
that text file is back in our current directory now discuss deleting files the O S module provides three
methods for the leading files and we are going to go show them right now.
There is OS dot unlink and it takes in some sort of path parameter so this deletes a file at the pass
you provide.
So for example if I wanted to delete this practice that txt file I would just copy the entire path to
it and then pass it into unlink and it would delete the file.
Your path.
There is also and will run these commands yet because we're going to still talk about them.
There's also our m Diyar which has removed the directory and that also takes a path and instead of a
file path you provide a folder path and the full there must be empty.
In order for this to work so unlink is for files are MDR is for empty directories and then finally the
one we're going to show you here is there's is sh still dot r m tree and you can pass any path to that
one as well.
This one is the most dangerous out of these results because it will remove all files and folders contained
in the path.
So be extremely careful with this command right here because all three of these methods cannot be reversed.
Which means if you made a mistake and you actually provided the wrong path you will not be able to recover
the file.
So unlike normal delete commands on your computer where you can later look in your trash or your recycling
bin and recover the file using these OS level module methods it's going to permanently remove the file
in a way that makes it extremely hard or almost impossible to get back.
So unlink again that's for a single file or MDR.
That's for an empty directory or an empty folder.
Remove tree if you give it a path.
Again extremely dangerous command here.
It will remove all files and folders permanently on your computer because these are so dangerous and
it makes it really hard to recover files afterwards.
What we're going to show you is the send to trash module.
So to install the send to trash module what you need to do is at your command line.
Type out Pitman's stall send to trash so you need to install this library.
Again you do this at your command line not inside the Jupiter notebook and what you can do to run command
lines inside the Juber notebook is try starting with an exclamation point.
So if you run this it should eventually install send to trash.
And in this case I already have it installed.
So it worked alright.
If you ever get an asterix here that indicates that it's continually running forever just go ahead and
run this Pipp install send it to trash at your command line and make sure to use Pipp install.
This library is currently not available with the install again run Pipp install send to trash at your
command line or you can try running it in the Jupiter notebook.
By providing exclamation point in front of it.
Once you have sent to trash installed we can use that to send things to our trash bin or recycling bin
that way.
Just in case we accidentally deleted something that we still need we can always recover it.
And it's quite simple all you need to do is say import send the trash and then let's go ahead and list
what we have currently here it looks like we have our practice that textfile Let's go ahead and send
them the trash and the command is quite easy to send to trash that send the trash and then the file
path.
In this case because I'm in the same directory as a text file I can just copy and paste that in.
Run that.
And it's been sent to my recycling bin.
And this is the safe way to delete things on your computer using Python because the files are recoverable
in your recycling bin or in the trash.
Programmatically you may see unlink aren't our MDR remove the rectory and then removed tree use in scripts.
But you should be very very careful with these commands because they will permanently delete things
off of your computer in a way where you cannot recover them.
So I recommend using scent to trash in order to safely delete things on your computer.
OK we've discussed getting directories listing everything and directory moving files around on your
computer as well as sending things to the trash.
The last thing I want to discuss is walking through a directory to walk through the rectory.
You can just use the OS walk function.
Now first off I'm going to create a variable called my path and set equal to the same path where the
corresponding notebook for this Lessner this overview is located.
So let me copy and paste that here basically.
I'm just passing in where the orange mission folder is and setting that as my pass.
Or you could alternatively use your current working directory so you could set my path equal to OS dot.
CW.
Just keep in mind your results may look a little different than what we have here.
If you use this approach because you may go through the folders are different folders.
So I'll just set my path to the orange folder location and then what we will do is show you how to use
OS walk.
So OS walk's uses a little bit of tuple unpacking because it's going to return back may three main pieces
of information the folder it's looking at the current soap folders it's looking at and then the current
files looking at.
And then you say and Os thoughts walk and then whatever directory you want to walk through.
So will say my path and then let's just print out the folder we're looking at.
So what this does is it says I'm going to be checking through all these folders first Tharp's starts
with the top folder and then it looks like at different examples example top level example extract the
contents on all these various folders there.
Then there's also the sub folders so we can print the folder and let's write a message here to make
a little clear.
Currently looking at this folder and then we print that folder and then we can print the sub folders
for it.
So folders here are and then so pull there is essentially a list of folders in that folder.
And you can think a folder is another word for the directory so we can say for a subfolder in the list
of some folders plural there print out the subfolder and then we're going to at the end of this prints
Well let's print a new line here.
So I run that and it says I'm currently looking at this folder right here and it looks like the three
subfolder here are the check points folder.
See example top level folder.
This mission.
Orange files folder and then it looks like another folder and it doesn't find any folders inside of
that one.
So notice how it's basically recursively walking through every single folder and subfolder and seeing
what's in there.
Sometimes it won't find that a subfolder.
So you can see here in this python notebook checkpoints folder it didn't find any other folders there.
That means after number folders left there's probably only files left or it's just an empty folder to
see the files.
You can just say for f in files princess and then we can print the new line after this.
And if we run that it's going to look through more things.
So it says hey I'm currently looking at this folder here of the folders and then it prints out all the
files that it found there in those folders and it continues and you'll end up getting repeated results
here because if it looks at certain folders multiple times you'll see repeated results.
But basically what it's doing is just recursively walking through every single folder.
And we've gone ahead and inside the Orange mission folder there should be some clear examples called
Mid example one example two bottom level one bottom level two.
And then there's also top level folders.
Example top level and that's just designed to help you understand how this walk is currently happening.
But basically all it's doing is again you provide a file path and it will look for every folder every
subfolder and every file in that particular path.
And this is a nice way to allow yourself to interact with some sort of or through some sort of functionality
for every file in a directory so you can imagine that if you needed to open every single file that was
in a group of folders inside another folder you could just use the OS walk on that path that eventually
points to every single file.
So eventually here instead of maybe printing f you would say hey why don't I open these files and then
maybe I can write to them somehow.
It's really up to you what you're going to be doing in those files but hopefully you get the idea again
that using the OS the walk function you should now be aware of how to work with computers files and
folders in whichever directory they're in.
Remember that the OS module works for any operating system that supports Python which means these commands
will work across Linux Mac OS or Windows computers without any need for adjustment.
So you can share scripts that use the OS module command across different colleagues working on different
computers.
Keep in mind that the only time you will need to make an adjustment is if you're manually providing
file paths like that appear if you're doing that you're going to want to make sure it's using the correct
syntax for your operating system.
And if you ever need a reminder of what that syntax looks like all you need to do is run the get C-w
the command and it will output the file or the current directory you are in in the syntax it expects.
So for Windows computers it looks like it's expecting two backslashes per folder.
All right.
Hope that was helpful to you Agent.
Best of luck on your next mission.