Welcome back agent.
Let's discuss how to work with CSB files since the orange mission left you with a c a c file and some
instructions.
We can actually learn how to use Python's built in CXXVI module in order to work with that file.
Cxxvi stands for comma separated variables.
This basically implies that the information the file has columns and rows in this sort of format where
you have columns in each column is separated by a comma and then you have rows following that same format.
However keep in mind that many delimiters or separators can be used such as semi-colons tabs or even
pipe operator symbols and that basically just indicates that you don't need to have strictly commas.
Sometimes people use these other types of separators and another word for that is a delimiter.
CSP files are commonly associate of Excel but Python has a built in library that can work with them
as well.
Let's explore this further.
The first thing we're going to do is check our notebook location.
We want to make sure that we're in the same location as our yellow machine file or folder.
So make sure that when you run PWT in a cell it reports back that you're in this yellow mission working
of CACP files.
That way you can open the example that see every file in the same way we are.
If you're located somewhere else in your computer.
Just make sure you passen the entire file path to your example Dotsie s v file.
Ok this is just reading in C files in order to do that.
We need to import CXXVI and then we open the actual C every file will say open exampled C S V and then
you should be able to see that this data is a textile wrapper and the name example CACP mode are now
the next steps would be to use the C S V dot reader function on the data and then try to create a list
out of that data.
However sometimes that may induce an error because maybe you have some different types of symbols that
Python gets confused by for instance the symbol in an email address like at gmail dot com may confuse
Python and I'll show you an example of what I mean by that.
So let's say you opened up your CSP file and you're going to say CSP data is equal to CSFB.
Reader data and then you're going to try to make a list out of this data see the data you'll get a Unicode
decode error.
And this is a very common error to get when trying to open either text files or CSP files and it often
looks something like this.
Kodak can't decode bytes and it gives you some sort of weird code here.
And then in position and then some sort of position.
Basically what that means is there's some character where Python doesn't know how to interpret it without
indicating the encoding.
And this could be anything as simple as an at symbol like in an email.
Or it could be more complex like maybe you're trying to import some sort of Russian text file or some
other language where the alphabet is different.
Maybe it's in Chinese or Japanese.
In that case you may need to provide an encoding parameter for most cases of English text.
You can in code with UTF Dash 8 that show you how to do that.
We're going to say data is equal to open and we're going to again open that same example at c as we
file but this time will add in the encoding parameter and say UTF Dash 8.
So if you ever get this error.
Go ahead and try encoding UTF Dash 8.
If this still fails then you're probably going to want to do a little bit of searching on stack overflow
and give a little more detail about what your actual file looks like because it may have Russian characters
Japanese characters Chinese characters and sometimes this encoding won't work for that.
Then we're going to say CSB data is equal to CSB.
Reader data and then all of this in the same cell we will say data lines is equal to list of CSP data.
And then with the encoding we were able to successfully read in that data.
So let's take a look at what data lines looks like and you notice here it's quite large so you'll get
a lot of output in this.
So let's look at the first couple lines.
By using slice notation and we see here that we have a list of lists and typically in a cxxviii file
the first line of the CSC file is known as a header and that basically just contains the information
about what each column represents.
For example we can see we have an ID column a first name a last name and e-mail gender IP address and
city and keep in mind all this information is fake so let's print this out in a format that looks a
little more in line with what the CC file format looks like.
We can say for line in data lines and we'll just do the first few lines so it will use slice notation
there.
Print out line so if I take a look at this and it can zoom out here just a little bit so we can see
the actual structure.
I see now that data lines is essentially a list of lists where each list indicates after the first one
which is the header the actual rows.
So essentially it's a list of all the rows so I could say more appropriately for row in data lines.
Prints row.
And this is your CSP file.
Now it in Python's memory.
So let's imagine that I only want to grab all the e-mails.
And again these are all fake emails.
What it could do is this.
We zoom back in here.
I could say all e-mails is an empty list and then four line and data lines.
And let's just do one through 15 here.
The reason for that is because I'm going to skip the header so I'm skipping 0 so start at 1 and then
go slice to 15 and say all e-mails appends line.
And then I can say three.
So again let's make this a little clear by calling this row and then saying row here.
So all I'm saying is go through this list of list and grab the elements index 3 which is the e-mail
we go 0 1 2 3.
We can see we have the e-mails there and that's easier to see here on the letter 0 1 2 3 is the e-mail.
So if I run this and then I see all e-mails.
Boom I have all the e-mails for the first couple of rows there and I can do the same thing with full
names.
So if I wanted full names something I could do a save for row and data lines 1 through 15 or have the
first name and last name separate in.
So let's do the following.
Let's say first is equal to row at index position 1 and last to row.
Expedition 2.
And then there full name is equal to.
Well let's just say name is equal to first space concatenated together with last and then we'll say
full names.
A pen name we run that.
And then let's check for names and we get back a list of full names.
So hopefully you get the idea here of how to work with CSC files in Python.
The main idea is that eventually you'll get it.
As a list of all the rows and then you can just do whatever you want with all the control flow you already
understand the CSB module also allows you to quickly either create a new file or append that to an existing
file.
Let's quickly go over how to do that.
The first thing you can do is say file to output.
So basically our new file is equal to open and we're going to make up some CSP names so go ahead and
just make up some new name or whatever you want.
And then we will say with the W and then we'll also indicate that New Line is equal to an empty string.
So notice there is no space there and that's going to allow us to overwrite the default which is the
new line is like this.
So that makes more sense for every file that we just have a blank newline so we don't get confused because
it's not really like a normal text file because we want rows all together no new lines.
So we're going to create that file to output and then say CSP underscore writer is equal to CSFB the
writer instead of that reader passen the file to output variable.
And then this is where we denote our delimiter.
So the delimiter at connectedly be whatever you want but you should try to stick to camos because those
are the most common.
And once your CFC writer is ready to go you can call the right row method off of it meaning off of CSFB
writer call write row.
And this is where you just pasan an example list of what you want the road to look like maybe.
Well the first one let's make it the columns so call 1 column 2 then column 3 and there you go just
wrote that.
Also just a fresh row if you want to do multiple at once.
You can use right rows plural and then this just allows you to pass in a list of lists.
So maybe we want one to three and then four five six.
So if you run that you just wrote column one column to call three then one to three for the next row
and then four five six for the row after that.
When you're writing you can just take the file to output that you created that variable and close it
off.
So keep in mind that creates a brand new file and if you already had a CSP file of this name it would
have completely overwritten it if you wanted to just append to an existing CACP file.
Then you use the a read mode.
So show me how to do that.
We already have this file or here that has the header column one column to column three and then two
rows one two three four five six.
Let's add in the another row that says 7 8 9 to this.
So we open up our existing file which is called make up new CSP and I'm going to open it with the a
mode that is a pen.
So I'm appending new lines to this see we file and I also say new lines have an empty string.
Then once I've done that I can read the find my CXXVI writer as writer on this file.
So C is v the writer on that file whatever we happen to call it.
Last time we happened to call it file to output but now we're calling f and then say CSP writer right.
Arrau.
And here you can just pretty much put whatever you want we'll say 789.
And there we just appended something new to write rule.
And if you're done with it then you can close it.
OK that's really it for the basics.
And that's because espies themselves are pretty basic.
There's really only two mentions I think of the columns or the rows and by getting a list of lists you
already know how to do all of that.
All right let's have a very quick review of CSC module.
So you just open up your CSB file and if necessary if you get a Unicode decode error you open it up
with an encoding try you TFF 8 then by calling the c file or the C module called reader on that data
and then pass it to a list.
And now you have a list of all the rows and you can do whatever you want that using for loops or whatever
method you prefer.
If you want to create a new file go ahead and just open up some make up some new name for us as we file
with W set new line to an empty string.
Create the writer object.
Make sure you know what your delimiter is going to be and then you can write either a single row or
write pleuro rows.
You can close the file if you want to add new information to us.
So as we file it's very much the same thing except you have the mode is equal to a Instead of equal
to.
There'll be two.