Hello again agent and thank you for meeting with me.
I have to say you've shown incredible resourcefulness thus far.
We're very lucky to have you on our team.
Thanks to your exceptional skills.
We're confident we're on the right path to fighting my daughter once and for all.
We believe the e-mail address you discovered holds valuable information exactly what kind of information
we're not sure.
As you know this entire matter is of great personal importance to me.
So I will be closely monitoring your progress.
The instructor will be connecting with you to teach you how to use Python to both send e-mail and check
received e-mails with these new skills you should be able to programmatically send an e-mail to the
rogue's e-mail address in hopes their reply returns useful information.
That is all for now.
I'll be in touch soon.