Welcome back agent the results of the green mission.
E-mail returns back to images.
Let's learn how we can work with images in Python in order for you to succeed in your next mission.
To work with images in Python.
You're going to need to install the pillow library to do this at your command line.
Go ahead and type Pipp install and then if a capital P pillow if you're working with the Jupiter notebook's
system with many large images displaying You may reach the default display data rate limit that is once
you show an image after showing many other large images.
You make an error that looks like the following.
That says something like I O pub data rate exceeded.
If this ever happens to you and your notebook system to fix this issue all you have to do is relaunch
the Jupiter note book your command line.
With this additional flag.
So instead of just typing Jupiter notebook you can type Jupiter notebook space dash dash and then that
line of code right there.
Basically it just raises your input output limit so that notebook says it's OK to display more data
as images.
If you're just using up postscripts then you won't have to worry about this.
Let's not begin exploring how to work with images with Python.
Once you've installed the pillow library you'll be able to type out from L import image and this will
then allow you to call the open function off of this image.
Scrip you can say image the open and then inside the blue mission folder.
We have an example that JPEG file for you and if you check out this it looks like this picture of a
Macintosh computer.
Now keep in mind that this sort of display only works for that Jupiter notebook.
As far as just showing the actual variable and then seeing the direct output if you are running a script
off of this we need to do is type out the show open close princes and then that will display the actual
image for you when running your pie script.
But we don't need to worry about that in the notebook.
Continuing on.
Let's go ahead and grab some image information.
If I wanted to know the width and height of the actual image I can say Mac thoughts and then grab the
heights or excuse me grab the size attribute and that returns a tuple where this first is with and the
second one is height.
So this is w by h in pixels and can also tell you information such as the file name and then it can
also even give you the format description.
So in case you needed more details about the actual JPEG format you can see it's jpeg.
ISO 1 0 9 1 8 which is just some standard format for JPG files.
That is what the images.
We can also crop images of Python and the way we can do that is by calling the crop method off of our
variable storing the actual image we can say a Mac crop and then you'll notice that it expects a box
which is a 4 item tuple defining the left upper right and lower pixel coordinates.
This is a little confusing at first so let's quickly jump to an example of what those coordinates actually
represent.
Let's imagine that we just had a single blue rectangle as our image than what we can do at the top left
corner of this image as 0 0.
And then we can make the x axis go along horizontally and on the vertical axis we can call that y.
So basically now the first two coordinates in that tuple of four are going to be your starting X and
you're starting Y where 0 0 is measured from the top left corner of the image the next to R W and H
for width and height.
And those are also coordinates.
So you would pick the additional two coordinates of width and height and essentially from these four
items the starting X and Y and then the width and height coordinates of the actual pixels themselves.
Then you can end up creating a rectangle and crop out that image.
So let's see this in practice now by jumping back to the notebook.
So off of this we will say zero comma zero.
So I'll start at the very top corner and then we can say 100 100 for these starting coordinates of that
width and height to be 100 100.
So when we run that we basically get the top left corner of that Mac picture.
If we scroll back up.
That's essentially this corner appear in the top left.
So the Mac image isn't really a useful demonstration of cropping.
So we have another image for you called pencils so we will say it equals to image open and we will open
pencils that jpeg.
And if we take a look at what pencil's is it's a very large image of some colored pencils on the left
hand side.
Everything else is gray.
Let's attempt to grab some of the top pencils from the corner in order to do this we need to know the
size of the image we'll say pencils size.
We see it's 1950 pixels by 3500 pixels.
So what we're going to do is if we just wanted for instance these top few colored pencils maybe only
up to this orange colored pencils so the top three were going to start off at the top corner to say
X is zero and Y is zero.
And then the with from there let's go ahead and grab about 10 percent in the y direction.
So we'll say that with or actually this is about a third say 30 percent in the extraction and 10 percent
in the y direction.
So that means the with is going to be 1950 divided by three.
So we're essentially grabbing 30 percent of the width here and we'll grab about 10 percent of this height
say H is equal to 13:00 divided by 10 then we will say pencils crop and they will pass in our tuple
x y w h.
And here you can see we're able to successfully grab those three.
Now let's imagine we want to grab pencils from the bottom.
So we wanted to just grab these three pencils right here.
Or maybe these four.
In that case we'll say X starts at zero but now y is going to start all the way.
So X starting at zero y is going start all the way down here.
Maybe just a little bit off of the heights to the heights 3300.
So let's go ahead and say that now if we just want the bottom for bottom pencils we'll start exercising
so why is going to be equal to 11 100.
So we're starting x zero y all the way down here at eleven hundred and then we're going to go all the
way to the bottom for this height.
So now I will say the height just goes to 3500.
And then the width is going to be the same.
1950 divided by three.
So we want about 30 percent of that with coming off of that.
So we do this again.
And then if we do the same crop now we get those bottom colored pencils.
So again keep in mind that these are coordinates.
It's not exactly a measurement of width and height which is why h is equal to 3300 here instead of some
smaller number.
So it's essentially a start finish.
And then we kind of start finishes well.
So let's go back to the Mac photo and see if we can just grab the computer itself.
So if I say Mac I have the computer here let's see it's size so max size is 1993 by 12:57.
So about the halfway point we want to grab halfway here and then a little bit off of it so we can find
half way as equal to 1993 divided by two and then we'll say that our x position that we're going to
start off at is half way minus 200 pixels.
And with that we're going to end that is half way plus 200 pixels and then we'll say something like
Why is a hundred and you can kind of just guess and check for these numbers.
These are essentially just lucky guesses H because that's always the end.
And let's try this.
We'll see it Mac thought Krop x y w h.
And then here we can see that we were able to successfully grab the computer image analysis Cisco's
copying and pasting images if we want to create a copy what we can do is reassign that crop.
We can say computer is equal to map Krop x y w h and that can call the paste method off of this and
then I provide the actual image.
This case it's computer.
And then the where the top left corner is going to go and that's going to be a tuple of just two coordinates.
So we'll go ahead and put it in the top left corner of the original Mac and then check out the Mac looks
like.
Now we were able to copy and paste this to the top left corner and you can do this multiple times if
you want one further in.
You can find this further and so it can say 7 9 6 or something like that.
Read this again and now paste it another piece of that Mac.
So keep in mind this is personally affecting the variable but it's not permanently affecting the actual
image itself.
This is all just happening in memory.
You can also use the resize method to resize an image so to show you what I mean by that.
If we say Mac size we have 1983 by 12:57 if we wanted to make it much smaller or stretch and squeeze
it we can say MacT resize and you can just use whatever sizes you want here.
For instance if I want to stretch it out or squeeze it I can say Make it three thousand pixels by five
hundred pixels and it will WIPs let's make sure we pass this as a tuple.
There we go.
And it will stretch and squeeze to whatever sizes you want so you can make it twice as big half as big.
That's really up to you.
You just set the new size you want.
You can also rotate images and that's just done with the rotate method so we can say Mack rotate and
you can rotate by 90 degrees and then you can see here that we're able to rotate our image by 9 degrees
to finish off our discussion of work and images.
Let's go ahead and take a look at transparency.
Here we can see that a lot of images have a red green blue a R.G. be a system and that stands for red
green blue Alpha and all the values of red green blue and Alpha can go from zero to 255 if the alpha
value is zero.
Then the image is completely transparent.
If it's 255 then the image is completely opaque.
Let's explore this idea of transparency by opening up to images that we have for you.
So these are in your blue mission folders you can say image the open.
We have a red color.
JPA.
So if you take a look at it it's just a red square.
And we also have a blue jay pick for you which is going to be able to image open and we will open up
that blue color PMG And now we can see we have blue there.
So if you want to reset the alpha one of these you can say put alpha and then pasand some integer value
from 0 to 255.
So if he Passons 0 it means it's completely transparent.
So now I only see white because the background is white.
If I reset the Alpha to be 255 completely opaque and I run this again then I actually see the blue.
If I choose somewhere between has to be an integer.
So for example 128 then I get back the sort of lighter blue.
Here we can see that some White has them extend to this blue.
And to give an idea of what that looks like.
Fred let's say red Alpha to about 128.
And check out what red looks like now.
Now it looks even a little more pink.
OK so what if we actually put these two images on top of each other and they have some sort of alpha.
That means we should be able to see something that looks a little bit purple ish.
So I will say blue and I'm going to paste in the image that I'm going to paste is going to be red so
that red image that we just edit the Alpha will set the box to 00.
And if you want actual transparency to occur and not just straight up have a peek block over at the
blue block you actually want to take into effect a transparency.
You need to say mask is equal to and you pasand the same image you provided.
So in this case it was red.
She sent Maskey to read.
And when you run that WIPs let's make sure that we find the actual box and how we check out what blue
looks like.
We get back purple.
So what are we actually doing here.
We're pasting in the red image at top left corner and then also saying that we want the red image to
work as a mask indicating that we actually want transparency to be taken into effect.
Otherwise if you didn't have that mask you would essentially just see the red block completely because
it's almost like taking two sheets of colored paper and then putting them on top of each other instead
of with transparency or a mask you can think of almost like shining a light through those pieces of
paper to see the transparency effect.
All right.
That's the basics of working with images and I hope that helps you in your next mission.