Excellent work on your mission agent Let's quickly have a de-briefing so we can discuss how you accomplished
your mission.
The first thing we had to do was from Paille import the image functionality and then we could say open
up the links themselves.
So one of the links was under blue mission files.
We had the image link and if we check this you can see size and then if we checked with the actual links
looks like we have some sort of links in here so we can see there's HTP P.S. Google walk and then words
the other image we had was the cover image.
So we can say cover is equal to image open.
And then we have blue mission files and we have a cover image there and then we can check the cover
size and then check the cover itself.
So here we can see the cover.
Now it looks like there was some sort of pattern we had a place to cover on top of this image.
But if you take a closer look at the sizes they don't match up.
So we have ten ninety three by 693 here and then we have 12:26 by 7 7.
So we should be able to resize this cover in order to place it on top of this image to make sure they
fit and then we can't just place them over each other.
We should also add in some sort of alpha that way this White is has some transparency to reveal what
box is on the image links behind it.
So let's do that first let's resize the cover will say cover is equal to cover resize.
And we're going to resize it to the size of the links and we can just pass an attribute which returns
back the tuple So now if I check the size of my cover it's 12 to 6 7 7 7 just like those images of the
links.
Then let's go ahead and add some alpha to it so we can cover the Alpha and we can try 128 and experiment
with this value a little bit.
So if I take a look at my cover now it looks definitely a lot grayer.
So let's paste this over the links will say links paste and will provide cover the box and then also
indicate that the mask is also the cover and when you run this and then check out the links we can see
here that it's highlighting this link we need to go to.
It says go to this link and it looks like there's some sort of shortened google link.
G o o g l l d o 5 and T.
So let's type that in here.
HGT P.S. Colon's for Slash forward slash g o g l for Slash l d lowercase 0 5 and C and let's go to this
link.
If we go to that link it looks like we're on the right track.
Here you can see that there's some information and it looks like there's an encrypted message here.
It says the key for the encrypted message below is the largest known Fermat prime passthrough in S H
A three 256 bit hash.
It also says this number should be passed as a byte string placing B in front of the string.
And then there's some sort of encrypted message that we need to decrypt using that key.
So in order to solve all of this we're going to need to dive in and learn about encryption and decryption.
We'll see their agent.