So now, we're going to launch into a few demos.
We're going to look at the Visual Studio Code extension for Kubernetes.
Then,
we're going to look at a number of examples where we can get some
important troubleshooting information using kubectl.
We're going to look at retrieving logs and events for our Kubernetes objects.
Then, we're going to look at deleting and recreating Kubernetes objects.
Finally,
you're going to see how you can retrieve Kubernetes secrets
in case you've forgotten what they were.
So first,
let's have a quick look at the Kubernetes extension for Visual Studio Code.
If we open up the Kubernetes icon here that you see on the left,
you can see there are a number of different areas that we can look at.
At the top of the screen, you can see that there's clusters,
there's HELM REPOS and CLOUDS at the bottom.
At the top of the example,
you can see the SQLAG cluster that I've used for the
earlier availability groups example.
We can use this to navigate through the deployment.
We can expand the nodes.
We can do the same thing with workloads and deployments,
and you can see the different deployments that are available there.
We can do the same thing with services and pods that you can see here.
If you look on the right side of the screen,
you can see what this does for YAML editing.
If you look into the editing window,
you might notice some various lines that track the
indentation of different objects.
This can be pretty helpful if you're editing YAML because
YAML is very sensitive to indentation.
You might also notice the display uses color‑coded syntax
for the YAML keywords and their values.
And if we move our cursor through and hover over different sections,
it gives us an explanation of the various different
objects that we're seeing on the screen.
And it tells us what kinds of objects they are and
gives us a brief explanation of them, so this can be pretty helpful.
If there are any errors, they would be highlighted with a yellow line.
So now, let's go ahead and run some of our kubectl examples.
Let's look into using kubectl to get some important troubleshooting
information from our different Kubernetes objects.
First, here,
kubectl get all is a quick way to see an overview of your deployment,
so let's quickly run that.
At the top, you can see a list of the different pods and their statuses,
and next, you can see the services along with their IP addresses and ports.
If we scroll down, you can see the deployments and the apps.
And finally, at the bottom, you can see the status of the different replica sets.
Next,
if you want to check on the resource utilization of
the different Kubernetes objects,
you can use the kubectl top command like you can see here.
Here, at the top, you can see kubectl top node and kubectl top pod.
If we run these commands, you can see a summary at the bottom.
And here you can see the CPU utilization,
the millicores that are being used, the percentage of CPU,
along with the total memory and memory percentage
for each of the different objects.
At the top, you are seeing the nodes, and at the bottom, you're seeing the pods.
If we want to get the networking information,
we can use the kubectl get services command like you can see here.
We covered this in earlier examples,
so we're not going to spend a whole lot of time with this.
The important points here are that if we run this command,
you can see how it's retrieving the IP addresses and the ports that are used.
Next,
it's possible to retrieve the YAML for the different Kubernetes objects
that we're using by using the kubectl get command,
along with the ‑o yaml parameter.
So let's go ahead and run that quickly.
And here, you can see its output, and it's pretty lengthy.
Well,
you can see the output here is a bit more verbose than the YAML
that we would use to create these objects.
If we scroll through it, you can find some pretty familiar parts.
Like, for instance,
we can see the specs where you can see the important
definition of the environment variables,
the image, along with whatever volumes are used and the limits that pod is using.
And now let's move along to describing the deployments.
The kubectl describe deployments command gives you detailed
information about one or more deployments.
So let's go ahead and quickly run this.
And here we can see, if we scroll back, again,
this gives you quite a bit of information about the deployment.
At the top, you can see the deployment name.
If we scroll down, you can see the the app labels,
along with the image and the memory limits that are being used.
If we continue to scroll,
we can see the environment variables and volume mounts that are being used.
And finally, if we keep going down, we can see whatever events,
if there are any, that are present.
In this example, remember, we have three deployments.
So first was our mssql‑primary, and here's our secondary1‑deployment,
and if we continue scrolling, there's our secondary2‑deployment.
Next, let's look at retrieving the logs for the different apps that are running.
At the top of this example,
you can see how we're retrieving the logs for a pod
using the app label of mssql‑primary.
Below that,
you can see how to retrieve the logs for a previous
instance using that ‑p parameter.
So let's go ahead and run this code.
And if we expand our view, and at the top here,
you can see we have a few login failure warnings for our current app,
and if we scroll down,
you can see there's a few messages about dump errors with the previous app.
Now, let's go back and look at retrieving some events.
This code shows you how you can use the kubectl get events
command to return Kubernetes events.
At the top,
you can see how you can sort all of the different events by creation date.
Remember, by default, they're sorted by resource.
Below that, you can see how you can get the events for a type of resource,
in this example, pods.
So let's go ahead and run this, and we'll expand our view.
At the bottom here,
we can see the events for a pod where a pod was essentially terminated
and then recreated where it was killed and scheduled.
Then we pulled the image, created the pod, and started it.
And if we scroll back,
we can see similar things for a deployment where a
load balancing service was deleted, and then scheduled,
and then recreated along with a replica set.
Next, we can see how we can delete and recreate deployments using kubectl delete.
So let's scroll up,
and there's kubectl delete where we're passing in the definition,
our YAML file definition, for a deployment.
And after that, we're going to go ahead and get the deployments,
then pause, and then after our pause,
we will recreate it and show you what's happening here.
So first, this deletes the deployment, and that takes just a few seconds.
And then, after the deployment is deleted,
we'll see the output of the kubectl get deployments command.
At this point, you'll notice there's only going to be two deployments,
one for our primary and one for our secondary,
our first secondary, because we've gone ahead and deleted the deployment,
which was defined with sqlAGS2deployment.yaml.
And here you can see our two deployments, and there's our pause.
And now, after we press Enter,
it's going to go ahead and recreate the deployment,
and then we're going to run kubectl get deployments again,
and you can see our new deployment being created at the bottom.
Finally, if you have trouble with your SQL Server passwords,
it's possible to retrieve the value of your Kubernetes secrets by using
the kubectl get secrets command and then filtering the output for the
SA_PASSWORD key and passing those results and decoding it using Base64
like you can see at the top of this screen.
So let's go ahead and retrieve our secret.
And there you can see that we've successfully retrieved
the password that we've been using.
So, if you've perhaps forgotten your password, this can help you see that you're using the correct one.