So now,
let's have a quick demo of using some of these interactive
tools that we can use for troubleshooting.
First, we're going to look at running that Kubernetes dashboard.
Next,
we're going to look at using kubectl exec to run
commands on a singular type of basis.
And then we're going to look at using kubectl exec to open a
remote shell that we can use for navigation,
running commands, and other troubleshooting tasks.
Okay.
First let's look at running the dashboard, and here's the code that can do that.
At the top,
you can see the kubectl proxy command and then a URL that
we could use to open up the browser.
That will work for most instances.
Azure has another way to do this when you're using AKS and that's by
using the aks browse command that you see here.
About Azure, there are a couple things that have to be done to use it.
You have to run the kubectl create clusterrolebinding command that you see here.
And in addition, the dashboard is about to be deprecated in Azure,
as the same functionality is offered through the Azure AKS portal.
This means you need to explicitly enable it in the current release.
And the code that we see at the bottom, the az aks enable‑addons,
will enable the dashboard for this present release.
In the next release of Azure it will be gone.
So in order to run this let's pop down here, and we'll run our dashboard.
And at first it starts up a tunnel between our local system and AKS.
Then it asks us how we're going to authenticate.
So we'll go in and choose our config file,
which has our authentication information that we've been using.
At that point, we can sign in.
And here comes our workloads display.
And the dashboard is primarily focused on performance issues.
At the top we see the workloads.
If we scroll through, we can see the deployments that are out there.
If we continue to scroll, we can see the various pods that are available.
We can also have a look at the replica sets that are in use out here,
as well as the services that are running.
And the services show the cluster IP,
as well as the external IP address for each of our pods.
If we want to look at our nodes we can click the Nodes command over here.
And again, we'll see the CPU and memory usage for our nodes.
And if we scroll down, we can list our various nodes.
And if we want to look at our persistent volumes,
we can click those over here,
and you can see the different volumes that are in use.
Okay, now let's look at running some commands.
You can see the code to do it here.
We're using the kubectl exec command.
We're passing it that ‑it flag for interactive.
We're giving it a pod name, which we're retrieving into a variable at the top.
And, first here, we need to close up our tunnel.
And then we can go ahead and run our commands.
So, let's run them.
The first command is going to be running the top command that you can see here.
And this is retrieving the status of the top running
commands within our container.
Ctrl+C will cancel that.
And then it will go ahead and run the command that you see at the bottom here.
And if we expand our view, you can see it.
We're running kubectl exec, and then we're running sqlcmd,
which is passing a SQL statement into our pod that is actually
retrieving the SQL Server version that you see here.
Okay.
Now let's look at using a shell.
And the shell is very similar.
We're using kubectl exec again, passing in that ‑it,
or interactive switch, giving it the pod name,
and in this case the command we're running is going to be the bash command.
And here you can see our shell is opened up.
We'll expand our window a little bit.
And again, this shell is running in the container.
So, let's go ahead and have a look at our file system there.
We could perhaps change directories into the SQL Server file
system and check our data files there.
And there you can see the different database files that are in our pod.
We could go back to our root.
We could do other things, like perhaps look at the contents of our hosts file.
And there you can see it.
Or we can do other commands like run the top command like you just saw.
And here we can continue to do this until we can navigate to
where we want and view the things we want or run the commands
that we might need to see out here. And when we get done we can type exit to return to our localhost.