Hi, everyone.
I'm Michael Otey, and welcome to my course,
SQL Server High Availability with Kubernetes.
I'm a former SQL Server MVP, Technical Director for SQL Server Magazine,
and the author of many technical books and hundreds of articles and webcasts.
Kubernetes has become the de facto standard for container orchestration as
many organizations are looking to move their legacy applications into a
containerized and microservices architecture.
One of the challenges of running SQL Server in a container is
the need to continue to provide high availability for those
SQL Server database services.
In this course,
we're going to learn how you can deploy SQL Server on
Kubernetes and have Kubernetes provide high availability
for a two‑node SQL Server cluster,
as well as a three‑node SQL Server AlwaysOn availability group.
Some of the main topics that we'll cover include what you need to know
about running SQL Server in a container, the YAML and kubectl commands for
creating Kubernetes deployments with SQL Server, the T‑SQL commands for
creating clusterless availability groups,
as well as some vital troubleshooting tips and techniques.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to create and manage SQL Server clusters and
availability groups on Kubernetes. Before beginning the course,
you should have a working knowledge of SQL Server and know the
basics of running containers using Docker.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn how to run SQL
Server on Kubernetes with the SQL Server High Availability with Kubernetes course here, at Pluralsight.