welcome to Atlantis classes.
So this selective you're going to understand about West variables?
We'll understand what are variables water,
environmental variables and water system variables.
And what are the various commands,
which can be used to,
you know,
assign the variables,
and we'll have a lot of love stations as well on.
Believe me,
this is an important topic to understand.
If you're walking as a Atlantic segment on,
if you won't do it on a start loving,
shallow scripting.
So I would say these are the base off these topics.
So let's start.
What are variables?
So variable is a character string toe,
which we assign a value.
The value assigned could be number,
text filing device or any other type of daughter available is nothing more than a pointed
toe.
The actual data Suppose you know I've logged into a system.
I gotta shell on their cell.
I can type.
Anything I've given is equal to 10.
So what does it mean?
It means that is my variable,
and I have given 10 is the number I can give anything.
It could be number.
It could be,
you know,
text.
It could be filed him whatever but it would be my parable.
Why?
I'm saying variable because I can give anything is going to 10 I for some time.
I can give a visible 20 as well.
So these are my valuables.
So best variables are local toe single cell by before.
So what does it mean?
It means that someone you know I have got a shell on have assigned available is you got 10
.
So that variable is only applicable to my this shell.
If I have taken another shell off the off the same system so that variable is will not be
inherited.
So nobody's let me have long toe the line and so on will show you so that you can
understand about the variables.
So this is my Lennox over.
So how we can give assigned,
available.
It's very simple.
A physical toe.
So here is my terrible on 20 is the number I have given.
Okay,
So that's why the definition of variable is a variable is a characteristic will be assigned
off you.
We can say they're variable is nothing more than a pointed toe.
The actual data how to read the variable a echo dollar A.
Now I'm guarding an output.
What does it mean?
It means that this is my variable.
I want to read what we have in the variable.
I have to use the common core dollar A.
Suppose I'm giving this 30 number.
I want to read.
I can do this.
Suppose I have even is going to ABC.
Maybe only.
Okay,
So,
like this,
you can give any very blessed like these will 34 if you want to read it,
This one.
So these are the commands which can be used to send the variables.
Now,
suppose argument is going to 30 on a busy Quito 40 on.
I want to do the some off two numbers I can give C Is it going toe this expression dollars
kit.
Bless dollars B.
Now what I have done here,
I've just simple used,
uh,
Come on,
mathematic.
This is expression here.
This coming.
I can simply do the addition off to wearables.
So whatever the value we have on a dollar a cancer in a on the that would be some that will
be going to available.
See?
Okay.
I want to read.
See that I have to use.
I can see that I got an output 70.
So whatever you need to be is that you know,
I have available and we have to wearables envy on 3/3 variable is nothing that is some off
to wearables.
So you can see 30 plus 40.
That would be so indeed symbols is my 100 on my bees Equal toe 80.
I have given this and it stood off.
Plus I'm using minus.
If I am using this,
I got an output off 20 100 minus 80.
That would be you,
So this is a simple edible if you are rebuilding their definition.
I said that respirable czar local to a single shell by default.
What does it mean?
It means that support.
You know,
I have open another shell from this shell,
right click and open or have just,
you know,
switch user to some of the shell.
So what will happen?
A new shell will be generated.
So whatever the value have assigned like physical,
30 bees will do 40 so those values will not inherited the another shell.
So those variables is only applicable to this cell.
If I'm going to clear any child shell from this show so those where was will not go to that
show.
Simple.
What I can say.
Suppose I have Kurdish simple chalice scripting on in the shallow script.
You know,
I have just,
you know,
use those capes If I want to use those scripts on Ivan's good in the shallow script.
So what will happen?
A child process will be initiated from that So that child process will not being the values
that you have a sign here.
So from their cell for this lecture in the last lecture will understand more about it.
So thanks for watching.
And if you have time,
please join with me in the next lecture.