Okay,
Now we know a lot.
About what other different type of shells.
How do we start a shell?
How do we get into different shells?
Well,
it's simple at is simply type shelling.
Meaning,
if you are inborn shell and you want to get into,
um,
just shell or seashell Just type S h or just type C show.
So,
um,
without explaining you,
Maurin detail Ah,
log in straight to ah,
my Lennox machine and I'll show you how you could switch from one shell to another.
Okay,
so I have this limits machine and you notice that I have the school he running in.
Medics inside the gui I have this terminal so all the commands that I run from the terminal
is actually a shell.
And that shell is how do you find a show?
You do echo dollar zero and it tells you my shell is bash.
Now,
if I don't want to use this command line and you see in the back I have this directory
called home and I have this trashcan.
So if I wanted to view the contents off home,
what I do a double click.
So this environment right here is.
You see this environment is G.
Norman Mark,
remember,
I told you genome is also a type of shell.
So this is another shell right here,
and this is command line Inside is into the show.
So if I wanted to open this folder,
I am telling genome,
which is the desktop gooey to open up their folders a double click,
and it will open up the contents off that directory.
And these are all the directories I have these.
This is a file I have off off all the directory.
If I want to go into another director and in the file,
or if I wanted to open up this file,
I'll double click and D Genome Shell is interacting with Colonel an operating system and
telling it to open it up.
Now,
what if I do not have the school environment?
Right,
So and not everyone is a windows.
Um,
not everyone.
I wanted to get into windows.
They want to get in the command line.
So what did they do with a?
So if if you want to ah,
view the content off my home directory,
I'm sure you know the leg up output.
I'm sure you know the output.
Um,
off pwd,
which means home.
I have salsa.
Now,
if I wanted to save you the content of my directory,
I do ls minus l And you see,
here is a list off all the directories did I have in my home directory.
So I did the same thing as I was doing here by double clicking it.
But right now,
I used a command Ellis.
So when I use the command,
Alex,
I actually am telling my bash shell to do this.
L s command for me.
Well,
let's do clear.
And it will clear up my terminal.
Now.
If you wanted to see of what other shell that you could,
um,
change too.
You could just simply type S h and you hit S h.
You see yourself shell prompt changes.
You could also verified by running echo dollar zero and you'll see it is shell.
Now,
if you want to exit out of the shell to go back to your bash,
you type exit.
And if you want to go to,
let's say seashells,
so just type seashell and you are in seashell to confirm your in C Shall you do echo
dollars,
zero seashells.
You want to get out?
What do you get?
How do you do?
You do accent.
So had That's how you get out.
Now,
what other shell that we learned?
Let's say if you want to start a corn shell s que S h hit,
Enter.
Um,
this is bash.
Corn shall command not found.
This is similar commanders you could use Regency shall know what I want to use corn show
why I cannot get into corn show.
Maybe because I do not have corn shell installed in my computer.
And how do we verify it?
Simply do cat shells.
Okay,
tell me,
do you see corn shell in there?
No,
right.
That's why I was not able to start that corn shell.
Ah,
shell,
actually.
So anyway,
so that's how you could switch around chills.
Start a new show again.
This is if you want to get into a different shell environment.
Now,
how does it relate to shell scripting the shot scripting that you want to learn,
right?
That that's what you're probably thinking?
Well,
if you are creating a shell script,
let's it in corn shell.
And as you see right here I don't have corn shell.
That script is not gonna run.
So you need to know your environment beforehand before you spend tons of number of hours
and then realize,
Oh,
boy,
I don't You would have a corn shell and,
you know,
even how to install or down on the corner anyway.
Eso That's about changing the shells.
One of the basic things that we should know is how to run a shell script.
So when you created there are different ways you could run it,
you can run it through absolute path,
or there's another one that's called relative Path.
So absolute path is if,
let's suppose,
if you are standing right at the first step off a steer's and you have to pick up something
on the very last year in the top,
you have to actually either shoot from the first year all the way to the last year on top
and grab that thing that you're trying to grab or there's another one.
Another way is relative path.
The relative pat is that you actually walk up to the steer and then grab that thing that
you wanted to grab the same way.
Um,
absolute path and relative pat works.
If you do not know what exactly,
absolute path and relative pats ar,
I would recommend you that you should,
you know,
try to look it up online and see what they are and how they work.
And,
um,
you'll find tons of article there and make sure your type,
Absolute Path and Lennox or absolute path and relative path in Lenox as well.
So the way it works is I have my limits machine up.
Let me log into my Lennox machine,
so I have my script right here.
It's called X Y Z Dash Screwed if you notice I am in my slash home slash I of Salt and
Slash script directory.
I created a directory called Scripts in My Home Directory on Guy.
Create all my scripts in that directory.
So if I am already in that directory,
I could run the script or if I am not in my directory,
let's say if I just do CD and which directory I'm in,
I'm in slash route.
So the script that I want to run it's just a test group that I created earlier.
That's a few tight death script Name.
X y Z Dash script and then you hit Enter,
you'll see it says Bash the script.
Name Command Not found.
Why?
Because the Lenox operating system is trying to find that script and slash root directory.
And I do not have that script in slash root directory.
So I would have to specify the absolute path to run the script.
And the absolute path would be just the same way as if you are standing at the bottom of
the stairs and then you have to fetch something from the top of the stairs.
Then you actually through some kind of means or like a stick or something,
and you could grab it.
So the same way you will specify the entire path,
which is slash home my user directory scripts and now the name of the script.
Now when I run the script,
I'll hit.
Enter and you will see is just the script that is actually echo out or print Hello,
world on the screen.
How does this group created?
I will cover that in the later lectures,
but just to focus.
This is how you need to run a script using absolute path.
Now what if you are in a relative path,
which is that you are already in home I of salt and Scripts Directory.
See you CD into that directory.
You do PWD and you'll see the path is the complete paths.
Now.
Now the script name is again when you do Alice,
my cell tr I have the script X y Z script.
Now when you run this group now script and hit,
enter it still cannot find it.
Why?
Because when you are inside off a directory,
you will always have to specify that you want to run the script but than this same
directory.
And that is the relative path.
And to do that,
you have to specify dot,
slash and then the name off the script you could hit Tab.
It will auto complete.
So now you hit enter and you'll see it ran.
So keep that in mind.
There are two ways you could run the script one through absolute path and want to the
relative path.
If you are,
let's say in slash home directory,
and now you want to run the script.
You could still specify the entire past lying home starting my user directory,
or you could just simply start from the director you are in.
So you are an I absolve from from this home onward,
I have saw scripts and the script name hit,
enter.
And you see it works here too,
because you you have to let the opening system know where your script exactly is located.
So that's the basic about scripting how you run it.
So please remember these two main points about running.