how everyone.
So this,
like trivia going to understand about system variables.
System wearables are created and maintained by Atlantic bash shell itself.
It means that those variables which are basically created bio system itself or consistent
variables.
So when you do the stylish in off any operating system,
the system created Lord off variables for their uses.
They're called system variables.
The admin,
the user admin.
The system admin is not basically catered such variables.
You can modify the system variables.
As for you,
uses so this type of variables that maintain your system that always started with capital
letters.
You can configure the aspects off shell by modifying the system variables.
So these are your system.
Variables like Bs,
one that billions off the best prompt.
When you log into the system,
you always get some prompt.
So at the back,
any food see,
which is basically defined by a Bs one.
So it is already defined when you do that stylish.
But if you want to modify the best prompt,
you can do it.
A system admin can do it like your HIST file size the number of commands in bash history.
So by default,
it is 1000.
But if you want to modify,
you can do it.
And part as well.
That is a directors to look for executive ALS.
So these are your,
you know,
system variables.
So let me log in toe my line X box on.
We'll show you.
So they're to command this basically,
which can be used to,
you know,
see your valuables.
The very 1st 1 is your set.
Come on,
I said,
is basically used to,
you know,
look,
for you're both environmental variables and your cell variables.
In simple words,
we can say that the system variables are also a part off your environmental variables,
right?
So that's why,
from simple fire the set Come on,
It will give you all the system variables that includes the environmental wearable as well
,
plus your local variable as well.
So look a little Suppose I am.
Clayton is equal toe 11 b is equal to 12 season called Tory,
so three variables are have credit as a local variable.
If I'll simple fire set.
Come on,
you can see that it will start showing in the set.
Come on.
So that's why the definition offset.
Come on or we can say Simple.
Father said,
Come on,
it will give you an output in which we have the environmental variables,
your shell variables,
your local variables,
all the variables that is defining your system that will be coming with this.
Come on,
the next command is your e,
and we Come on,
it'll simple fire and we come on and fight.
It will only give you the environmental variables.
Or you can see that your sister very well also.
Right?
So your system is creating a lot of variables by itself.
So they're called system variables are called environmental variable.
If I use a like there's a root user on the road user has created available on that terrible
,
you know,
has been killed as the environmental variable.
So that is called environment available.
So such type of wearable available is called is not a system.
Very well,
right.
So don't be confused with that system.
Variable on environment available.
Okay,
so here,
from simple,
funny and become on you can see that I go to someone on board.
So let me 1st 5 this come on and show you a few more things here.
You can see that I got an output like this one.
The HIST file is showing this one.
It means that this is the location where all your history commands are going in this file.
So this who has defined this hissed file his file is available on a very well.
We have defined this When your system is mandating this fire like this way,
the HIST file size is your 1000.
So who is mandating this?
Your system on If you logged in Currently I have logged in as a route If you have changed
your user from root to some local user So here the variable it will be 10 days.
So let me show you.
Let me log in with us about the user uncle on again.
I'm fighting the same.
Come on,
I can see that the variable name is still same but its value has been changed The party
against is that when I logged in as a food user it waas less rude on dot Bash underscore
History now have logged in as a user Uncle,
you can see the pop.
You can see the value of the variable.
The hist file is available Name it is to train thousands.
So these are your system.
When the system is mandating,
I do come out from here on.
I'm going to create environmental variable like D is called 200.
So if I all 500 is a local variable,
it will not show in this.
Come on.
If I'll simple and we will check the DEA's is not showing right.
These 10 is not showing in this common.
So let me make it as an environmental variable.
No,
my d has become an environmental available.
If all fathers come on,
you can see that these time starts from that,
right?
So in simple words,
the set commands will give you an output off both your environmental,
your system and your local variables.
Whatever the variables that has been defining your system that would be showing in this set
.
Come on on with envy command,
it will only show your environmental Where's all your system variables?
The local variables will not be showing into this car.
So,
friend,
that's all for this.
Like to hope you have got an idea about the variability of system variables,
the local variables.
Thanks for watching.
And if you have time,
please join him in the next lecture.