how everyone in this lecture will understand about the coating.
So that's a very interesting and conceptual topic.
So let's stop your best.
Shell understands special characters with special meaning.
What does it mean?
Suppose you have created available ABC.
If he sees the name off my variable in that terrible ah ha.
Put something like any name,
any number.
And if I want to read that variable I need to use eco on dollar ABC I will get an output
this eco Come on on a dollar which I'm using to read that available.
So dollar is my special character which is basically going toe Honda Come on under.
Execute the variable like this We have some system variables as well in your system,
like it's less homes,
less part ps one.
And also,
if you are using this command arcos less they're less Log Star Law.
This wild guard is going to be run So this is a wild card that last comma.
But suppose you know,
sometimes we do not wish to use variables are wild cards.
Suppose you know I want to print dollar ps one So that kiss what I'm going to use eco on
dollar ps one.
But in result,
I'm getting some output off this PS one.
But this is not my requirement.
I want when I use Accord Dollar PS one,
it should bring the same.
It 1/2 type here,
I notice,
should execute the value of PS one.
So that case,
you know,
you have,
tow,
enable or disable the meaning of a special characters by enclosing them in a single courts
.
So let me show you how we can suppose you know I want to print this echo on this one dollar
PS one.
So in all,
put again.
See that I'm getting this one.
But my comment is that it should bring dollar beers one only.
So you have to type like this way.
I can see that in output.
I'm getting this one.
I suppose I have ABC on this.
I have mentioned my name.
Okay.
If I'm finding this a dollar embassy,
it was he my name,
I suppose I'm just typing this one bc The city is not defined anywhere.
It is not defined it all.
Even though I'm not getting any output,
I want to print this one.
So you have to use a single core like,
I suppose if you want to echo anything and then that's supposed dollar is coming like this
will echo on and putting um,
going with my bus,
you can see that.
And I would put the bus is missing because it is looking for the dollar,
but it's thinks that bus is a variable.
But I want to print all of us so that kids,
you have to use this one.
Okay,
so there is a meeting off,
you know,
quoting Right.
So there are three types off,
you know,
quoting two types off.
God's begins its two types of courts.
Let's understand each growth one by one.
The 1st 1 is your,
you know,
double court.
Okay,
so let's understand where we can use double court on there.
What's the benefit off that on?
Very can use double court.
So basically,
in simple words,
if you have any variable on,
if you want to define that variable,
then you have to use a double court.
So let's take an example here.
So what?
I want to print this echo on that I want to print this one.
This dollar.
Hey,
I'm getting an output here.
If I'm not using this even though I'm getting an output.
So what is the benefit off?
That benefit is there.
Suppose I have a very bill.
And after that,
I want to wear something like this one.
ABC.
I suppose there is nothing in the between the available and the new name.
So here it is,
looking for a variable a home ABC and I would put it's nothing.
So in that case,
we can segregate our variable with some other words.
How we can do that here.
I can use this one like this way.
I'm guarding output like this,
right?
So for variables,
it is Yes.
Let's see for the well cut.
Well,
cups like this one.
This is your wife thought I'm doing here.
Echo this web long the Starland.
So I'm getting an output here.
Right?
But they wouldn't court.
So if I am putting in court this,
you can see that it is just printing whatever mentioning my this under double quoted so
wild cards.
We can say that if you are using any wild cards on the double quoted,
it means that is going to be a dissident.
All right?
Yes,
this one,
but I even in the Commons.
Also,
you can put this one so we have few comes like this one date.
Come on.
I'm getting an output on like Alice.
Getting an output.
So So what I want to use eco today is I can put like this way.
So for command substitution is yes.
So basically these are examples we can say off the double court right now,
coming to the single court,
the single Let's see what all the things we can do with a single court.
All right,
so single court,
Let's take some examples.
Like so in simple world symbol court is disabled.
The meaning of wild cards are any special characters as well.
So I have a special character,
this one that is dollar home.
So this is a special character.
If you're putting in a single correct single,
you know this single court this is going to disable the meaning off your you know,
special characters as well as a welcome as well.
So here we have an example of Why card this one on?
If you found simplifying this,
I'm getting an output.
It is,
you know,
expanding the wild cards when I want to disable the meaning off workers.
I can put it in a single court as well tonight.
So for double coated on single quoted,
one thing is common.
That is wild cards.
If you're putting this and single quoted as well as double quarter,
it is going toe the civil,
the wild cards.
So that is a similar to between double quarter on single.
Apart from that variable,
Yeah,
double couldn't this your valuable is goingto be animal.
But the single court the variable is disabled in simple words with single court,
everything is going to be disciplined Like if you have defined any variable here like you
can see that it is dissemble.
I'm not getting the upper one variable here.
Also,
my wild cards is disabled.
Even if I'm putting any commands inside this one like this one on If I am putting inside
this,
you'll see that the common is also not executing.
Because this is a you know.
Come on,
I'm not getting the output off dead.
So from their cell for this like to hope you have got an idea off quoting on day Still,
we have a few more things to discuss in the coating that we're going to discuss the next
lecture.
So thanks for watching.
So we'll see in the next lecture by Take care.