how everyone.
So let's continue and do the rest part off the coating the next is your backs less This one
.
This is called backslash They this is back slash.
Okay,
So basically,
you know you can use the backslash before you know any special characters like dollar Onda
.
And if you're using the backslash before any of the special character,
it is going to disable the meaning off that character I've taken example Suppose ABC is
called.
So here we have available.
That is ABC.
No,
If I'm using echo on Putting Dollar ABC,
I'm getting an output,
but I want to disable that variable meaning so one way I can put it in a single court,
but that this had wanted off single court.
Suppose you know,
if you have a lot of things in that you know,
single court lot off,
you know,
different,
different.
You know,
special characters are there,
but you only noticeable spastic.
You know,
few off your you know,
special characters than better to use single court.
You can do one thing.
Put it in double court on the here.
You can put like this way.
Okay,
Let's take an example.
Suppose I'm putting like this week.
The pot is dollar pot.
Define one valuable and define one.
What about that is taller EVC.
So if I'm fine,
this come on,
you can see that the output which I'm getting It is really bored.
The special characters.
But my Dick Clement is that it should read only this character.
But it should be,
you know,
printed as it is.
So one way,
Fam putting single quarter.
So what it is going to do?
It is disabling all the single crack,
all the special character that is coming inside that one.
So the best way is there.
Put it in double quarter on which,
you know,
special character.
He wanted a civil.
Put it slash No.
I believe you have understood what I want to convey you like So let's do some more practice
on that.
Okay,
so I'm just using few examples here.
So what?
I want to type this one echo my but cost dollar 10.5.
I can see that I'm getting into some different output.
But it is just trying to read this,
you know,
very body.
So that kids,
what you can do,
you can use Becks list.
Thank one.
And also you can use,
you know,
have an option with that is physically unable the interpretation off the backs less
suspicious.
So let's do some more practice with Echo.
Echo hyphen.
E on Did it?
I'm just doing this one,
I suppose.
I want to put this one serial number.
Name students name and marks two things.
I'm boring.
I'm getting this output.
Okay.
I want that.
There should be something special.
Some,
you know,
Tab.
So how we can do that?
So you have to enable them.
First of all,
you have to enable the interpretation off the backs.
Let spaces.
So you have to use Khalfani on them.
Use this one.
I get this one hyphen de.
I can see that you have God one of space.
If I am not going to use this one.
So this is not going to work.
So here you can see that I have used hyphen t.
So high 20 is basically you know that is for hard,
gentle tab.
It will give a tab.
This is a tub.
Are you mentally?
If you want toe article tap that you have to use hyphen B.
I want to have one tab here as well.
You can use here as well.
Right on,
If you want to,
you know,
give some number as well.
You can give number.
I believe this one.
You can see that one number is coming here.
They So this way you can do it.
Oh,
I think you can do it like this way as well.
One less teeth.
I can see that one has been started with this one.
So it distracted.
We have learned about backs less on.
Also,
we have seen how to,
you know,
enable the you know,
indep additional backs less space is evil fighting like Oh,
come on.
So you have a simple use echo I fancy on Haifa 1,000,000.
After that,
you can use different options,
like 20 for the gentle hyphen V's for what?
Ical on.
If you want to,
you know,
enable one new line.
You can put them so you can see that the next thing is coming into the new line.
So if if you're going to put anything like hit and putting this one number one,
you'll see that we're number one is coming here.
If I want to put like good.
This is also I am one of 41 Here it is Coming one.
I want to be one time here.
Can see that one time is coming.
You have to put it here.
Right on.
I want to put Name is sugar here.
We'll see that she could is coming back.
I don't want time here.
I can remove this one.
She was coming here.
I wanted tub here.
I can put a tab here on marks I put my marks is 98%.
I'm not intelligent.
So this way you can use,
you know,
Echo come on with different options.
So when there's all for this lecture I hope you are understanding what I want to convey you
on Did it If you want to get you know a good hands on on shallow scripting So do it Do it
Start going from yourself as well The more you will practice,
the more confidence he will have.
So practices on leaky toe get understanding on shallow scripting So from that so far this
lecture will see in the next election