how everyone It looks like they will understand about users Input wire,
keyboard.
So basically,
we have a command read.
Come on on.
With the help of read common,
you can take an input from the keyboard on a sign that input into a user defined very
better money times.
You know,
when you run the script,
you need some input from the users.
So with the help of read,
come on.
You can take those inputs and put it in a variable.
So here we have the syntax,
like read hyphen.
B prompt these variables.
Name like,
credible 123 on and number of variables you can give.
And you have to give the,
you know name the inputs on it is going to save into the variables that you have defined.
So,
like we do want,
you know,
a script for you so that you can understand how we can use the,
read common.
So I'm going to create a very simple escape.
Okay,
so in this case,
you know,
it is it will last for you,
to enter your name or anything.
Okay.
Read hyphen.
P on until you're full name for that I'm defining any name,
not his name.
You can give any name.
So that is basically you available Name?
So whatever you're going to try like I'm tapping Shaker Boerma So she cover my eyes.
Going to say Vinto viable?
That his name?
I said that just your good name is dollar name.
You could give any name like I'm giving this one.
You're confusing Continued.
Okay,
let me make it executed.
I'm going to and execute this one until your full name.
Good day,
Michigan.
Warmer.
So here you can understand that it is asking an input from you and you have provided in
footwear keyboard.
Okay,
so that kid one motor script for you.
so So this group basically no addition off two numbers.
So the numbers that you have to provide the user has to provide the number on the is kept
will,
you know,
do the sum of both the numbers and you will get an output read hyphen B and to first number
.
Okay.
On the vegetable name.
I'm giving effort.
You could give any name and to second number.
I'm giving essence second number.
That s for a second.
And then I need to use some,
you know,
calculation here.
That is some expression I'm going to use.
That is dollar fn plus dollar s.
And that is my second number.
Echo some off your and that number is dollars.
Okay.
And if you want to delay,
I can put sleep here for two seconds.
You want that?
It should also delay for some more time.
And I put it on,
put like,
five so that even think that something is going on.
Some calculation is doing.
Otherwise you will get an output immediately.
So I'm just making it was a good different.
Now let's see under the first number,
I'm giving this 13 50 and the second number I'm giving 4 50 It will be for five seconds
because I have used a common sleep.
Some off your enter number is 800.
So there.
So you know,
simple scripts are half culture that the help of,
you know,
read.
Come on.
So you can see that users has given their imports wine keyboard.
So friend herself for this lecture.
We'll see the next lecture.
But thank you.