Hello,
everyone.
Let's continue and do some more practice using did.
Come on.
So I'm going to you know,
Kate,
one more escape,
that is Adidas is a CIA T dog message.
So a few things we forget to discuss in the last lecture.
So let me do it.
Okay.
So,
you know,
if you want to delay off your and in port suppose you want to have some input for the users
.
But user is taking a lot of time,
so you can specify the time out.
Well,
you as well,
like read hyphen.
D w have defined,
but,
you know,
five seconds on the hyphen,
p for that again and first number.
Okay.
Read hyphen.
T for a five to be.
And this is a first number.
It's again number.
This is my first I was asking Do we know until your first number?
If I'm dealing for some time?
Let's see.
I can see that how this is kept has buried for only five seconds.
If you have no supply,
I think you can see that it has moved to the next variable.
So one thing second thing is also here.
What kid?
One more descriptive CR four or less.
Okay.
Several.
You know,
you have to.
Sometimes you have to,
you know,
enter something.
But you want to,
you know,
hide that is on the screen,
Like suppose you want to enter the past passport from the users.
But you want that?
It should be hide so you can use hyphen ass option like the five on s hyphen P right.
And to the bus.
But okay,
we're gonna put honey,
you know well out of it.
Okay?
No,
it is asking for the password.
I'm giving any passport.
I can see that I'm tapping the passport,
but actually,
it is not showing there.
Okay,
so this way you can,
you know,
hide the input from the users I get when that cell for this lecture will see in the next
decade.