All right,
guys,
welcome to the lab set up in this section.
We are going to actually set up our lab.
Ah,
where we will be practicing our scripting skills.
We will be building.
Ah,
are Lennox machine and we will be creating shell scripts.
So let's see,
What exactly are we going to do in this lab?
Set up?
So this is Ah,
quick,
step by step,
the instruction of what we're gonna be doing.
Ah,
following this lesson in this section,
I will be covering about the virtual environment.
This is for those who actually don't know what water environment is or what a virtual
machine is.
So I will be going over some of the fundamentals of virtual environment.
How it works.
Ah.
Then what is,
um,
Oracle Virtual box?
So,
of course,
inversion environment.
There are so many.
Ah,
were actual products that out there,
there's VM where the orca wardrobe box.
There's Microsoft Works environment.
So which one to pick So in our let lab said of you will be installing Oracle warship box,
and that's where we will be setting up our next lab environment.
So after that,
we will be installing Oracle War troll box on it.
Um,
then it's Ah,
it's a complete process.
I have,
actually,
including every single thing in this set up.
So where do you need to get the download file?
How do you have to install it?
How do you have to configure it?
And then we will cover the first virtual machine.
So once you have the oracle box running,
then what do you need to do with it?
You need to create a virtual machine.
What is a word from machine?
If you don't know,
then I have covered that in this section.
You don't have to worry about a thing.
I will walk you through step by step and every all the way through on setting up your
Lennox machine.
And then once you have the Lennox machine up and ready,
then we will do the Lennox installation.
And,
um,
the Lennox insulation I will be covering is the centre west,
which is exactly like Red Hat Lennox,
which is used mostly in the linen environment in a corporate environment.
So this section covers all about setting up your lab.
Now,
let me tell you this.
If you already have a lab or if you already have.
Ah,
Lennox machine.
Then you do not have to do this entire section.
You could simply skip through it.
You could start up your own Lennox machine that you have.
It's either a bun,
too.
It's either sent OS or red hat.
I would put forward that you go with center Wes and,
um,
and red hat because most of the scripting languages and the shell scripts that I will be
using I was using in bash language.
If you're lit Knicks opening system understands the bash programming language.
That's fine.
You could you could use that.
Um,
if you want to install Lennox from scratch on your physical machine,
you could also go.
You are.
You're more than welcome to do that.
But if you do not have any limits machine than this section is really gonna help you.
And once again,
if you do have a Lennox machine not to worry about it,
just go straight to the next section.