Hello World.
Okay,
Yes.
This is the basic script that most of the time that I have seen people,
right.
Whenever there,
star learning,
scripting languages.
So we're learning back scripting languages and the first script that we will write as to
echo or toe output on the screen that reads Hello World.
I remember when I was in college the first script that was given to be by my teacher and or
but my professor was too right.
Ah,
script that will.
I'll put print on the screen that would read Hello World.
So anyway,
I am going to do the same thing for you guys that I want you to create the first script.
If you know this,
how to create a script,
awesome.
But start with me.
Let's go with me.
So we're going to start with creating the first group that will output Hello World.
So I have already my lyrics machine session open and I am logged in as myself.
No,
as a practice,
as I mentioned before,
that always create your script in a Pacific directory,
so it will be easier for you to remember were those scripts are so let's do CD script I'll
have already created that.
You should have that too,
if you follow my early lessons.
If not,
then go ahead.
Run the command make de ir followed by the scrip.
And it will create a script in the script.
If you do ls minus.
L you probably not gonna have anything if you never had a script before here.
If you do.
Ah then go ahead.
And the lead descript the first script.
All the lead is Hello world.
This is permission denied.
Why is that?
It is owned by me.
It is owned by my group.
And I could remove it by looking at this.
W it has write,
write permissions.
I cannot delete it.
That's a good troubleshooting exercise as well.
Right?
Uh,
I know it.
Why I can't delete it occurs when I created the folder or directory called scrip,
I was rude.
So let's go.
One step back.
Cd dot dot Do ls minus l and you will see.
Yeah,
I was right.
See?
Right here says this directory is created by route.
So anything under this directory will be protected by user route.
Nobody could touch it or delete it.
So the best thing I should do is to become route,
go into my home directory,
and I was simply removed the directory now,
so this will start fresh.
Okay,
so now it's gone.
That's exit out off that route.
Make sure you are yourself.
Yes,
we are.
You logged in ourselves also.
You could check by looking at the prompt.
It tells you the,
um,
name off the user logged in and the server name.
So now we are in our home directory,
and now we're going to create a directory called Scripts.
And we will put all our script from this point on to our folder called Scripts.
Now,
make sure it is there.
Yes,
it stares the end,
and now it is owned by me.
Now,
you don't have to run all the scripts as root.
The only time you would have to run scripts as route if the commands that you are adding
inside of your scripts required root privileges.
Yes.
So you could run any any command like PWD Ellis or anything that do not require root
permissions.
If you are running other commands,
let's say ah d m I decode or d message or D f uh,
dis command.
Those are the type of commands a require route rights.
So it's better that you run those commands.
Ah,
those scripts.
you create the scripts as route anyway.
So let's get into our scripts territory.
And now you see a We don't have any file or any directory in our scripts directory.
So we will create our first script and we'll call it Hello World and you could put dot bash
as well.
But since we will be working primarily with Bash Ah,
Shell so we don't have to specify.
Ah,
the extension.
So just simply,
um,
hit Enter.
Once you are in the V I mode,
you specify the shell.
So we want to run this script as bash.
Good second thing.
Who is the author off the script?
I will say it's myself.
Then again,
comment date Script is created.
Let's pick any date.
So let's say if you're picking zero a slash 20 sacks.
Okay,
um,
Daniel put in.
It's a little description description and that will read this script Will output Hello,
world on the screen.
That's it.
Simply that if there are any modification so you could put a date modified and then you
could put the date.
Since we're doing the first time,
you could just put it the same date as you put a did created.
Okay,
so our shell is defined.
Our comment is defined.
Do we have to add anything?
No,
it's just a simple script.
So I will go ahead and write the script that were print Go.
Hello,
world.
And that's it.
Now you could just to escape out of fed and right.
Quit.
And your script is created now.
Verified.
Yes,
the script is there,
but you cannot run it.
Why?
Because it does not have execute herbal permission right here.
So in order to,
uh,
a sign proper execute herbal permission,
you will have to run the command change mod.
Oh,
plus execute herbal.
Hello world.
And by the way,
I'm using tap that auto completes file.
And if the ball does not exist,
it will not auto complete as an example.
Let's say if our instead of h e l l o put h A l l and hit tab.
See,
it's not gonna work,
so it has to have a correct spelling.
Okay,
so we have modified the permissions.
Let's verify it?
Yes.
Now it has the execute permission.
As if you see as soon as we could give it.
Ah.
Gave it executed information.
It's color change as well.
Now,
please remember,
don't focus on the color,
as I said earlier as well that sometime maybe you probably creating a script in Solaris or
in a I X or in any other UNIX or links play were that does not give you that color changing
scheme or that depends on the environment.
A shelf.
So that's why Just focus on that it is executed.
Well,
by looking at execute permission.
Okay,
now,
perfect.
Now let's run it.
So again,
you could run it through the hole,
Pat,
which is Absolute Path script directory and hello,
world and hit Enter.
And there you go.
Your foot script is created.
Isn't that fun?
You have just created your first script,
which outputs on the screen.
Hello,
world.
Now what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna run the script as a relative path.
Sadat slash Hello,
world.
There you go.
It does the same thing,
but it executes it with a relative path if you notice.
Um,
there are no lines in between on top and bottom,
so I wanted to make it more clear.
More neat.
Look.
So what I will do is modify the scrip.
Hello,
World hit.
Enter.
And now I'm gonna put one echo here and one echo here.
So when I put these echoes inside that it will actually generate an empty lines before.
Hello,
Orland.
After hello World and datemodified again.
I could just put it like,
Let's if you're modifying it a day after the first time you created then you just 21 save
the script And now let's run it.
Hello,
world.
Nice.
You see?
Now it is giving the output that you want Now as exercise I would recommend you to go ahead
and create a couple off,
um,
scripts like that that will output on the screen Like my name is Imron.
Absolute.
I love to teach and I am whatever that you wanted to add,
just I'll put on it,
chop the lines which over the way you want it.
This will give you some practice on how to creates him.
Well,
script