how everyone in the selective will understand about my affairs.
So basically,
my offense is important to understand because many times you will see that I first have
been used in a shower scream.
So I first is nothing.
It's a very can,
you know,
for the divide your valuables in tow.
Some variables.
Suppose you know,
have a variable on that.
Very well,
we have different.
Different names are there,
and I want to,
you know,
divide those variables those value of variables into some variables.
So with the help of life as we can do that So let me try to explain.
I first with an example here.
Suppose I have a variable name off city in that very well I have defined,
like Delhi a London,
Singapore.
Okay,
so I have simple variable that is name off Syria.
The names are there late.
No,
What I want I want that with the help of read.
Come on.
I want to simply split my this variable that his name off city Do you know further
variables?
So how we can do the read hyphen?
R I can give my no city name.
One city to on city three on here to specify.
With the wyffels,
we have to use three symbols that is less sign two times and then this dollar name off city
No,
If I'm doing Eco City one,
you can see that I'm getting deli Andi.
And if I am putting city too,
it is giving London and this acidity.
So the read Come on here leaves input from the dollar name off city variable.
So here you can see that the foreign value off this dollar I have This is used to assign
values to three separate variables.
That is city one city to city three.
Your input is broken into,
you know,
tokens with the help off infest dollar on assigned those values to you three variables that
this city,
one city facility or in simple words begin to say that I have has very well walk to Is
there separator?
We can see that.
So here you can see them have available this deli in London and Singapore.
They are separated by this place.
Single spears,
Right?
So in that case,
you know,
if you have a biggest clear if you have any,
you know Vic Berryville in that we have three entries are there,
so you can further divide your enters into the sub variables late.
So from their cell for this lecture.
But my ticket,
we'll soon the next lecture.