how everyone So this factor will understand how to create on in teaser variable.
So what isn't is available are variable on which we have only indeed their numbers like one
number 10 number 15 number 200 number But it always be an intention number So how we can
achieve this supposed ah half catered available A V is equal to town So here you can see
that Ah have available the name off.
My variable is a V on whose values 10 10 isn't in diesel number.
If I want to read this,
I can use this one.
So as of now,
it is not an declared indigent number.
It is an indecent number because we have given.
But I want to make it permanently as interior number that I have to use some different
commands for that.
So some was.
I'm given a visa called Toe.
Next time doing this number,
I'm getting out.
I suppose I'm giving babies some,
you know,
strengths or some,
alphabetic number or some constant variables.
So,
like this one,
I'm even this one.
So here you can see that baby is available.
So I let it was in teacher variable.
Now it has become cost invariable.
But my requirement is that I want This should be on Lee on Intissar variable So this letter
will can have only the numbers.
So in that case,
you have to use declare hyphen I A b is called any number you can get like 100 night has
become.
India is available now So as a mom the value of babies 100 You can change it to some other
you know number as well.
Like this one can give it okay,
But if you try to,
you know,
give babies some constant variable like she Careful tried So you will see that this is
again You're shall is going again toe convert it with some interesting number That zero
number So he warned.
Ally,
you give this variable Abie to some A string of some question variable on Lee you can give
on in teaser toe This valuable right?
So let me care.
A simple variable,
simple scheme for you on did let me show you how we can use this in my script.
Okay,
so I'm just declaring declared haIf and I a b is you call toe 2010 declare.
I my base is called to 200.
Okay,
so these two,
you know,
wearables have declared as an interior whatever.
Right now,
I want this CD's equality,
this one,
this dollar I want toe do the addition of these two numbers,
like B C plus our a b plus B c.
But so I could dollar city.
Let me make it executable.
I can see that I have got an outboard.
But here you can see that I have defined only it is a number,
right?
No,
again,
I'm editing this file.
No,
no.
Is that you can see that is a beautiful town.
BC's my another available which is having some you know,
it is a number.
Know what I'm going to do here?
I'm defining my you know,
babies equal.
Do I'm getting this number.
What amount?
So let's see that whether it is going to accept this valuable not because at the start of
this country can see that I have already defined a b is and in teaser,
okay,
especially half a nice for the interior.
I already find that this variable is going to be only in Giza.
If anybody is trying to give you know,
maybe some a string of some constant Your shall is going to convert into some in these a
number That is zero number.
Okay,
again,
I'm going to do this one.
Okay on Did it let me echo this one dollar bill,
etc.
What babies?
Dollar busy.
Okay,
let me come up again.
Exit Getting it.
I can see that now.
This baby has been tends to zero because we were trying to give you know,
a B as in some a string for shell has converted your baby variable into some indecent
number into theoretical at people.
That is a zero number it will always give.
If anybody is trying to give some string of some constant your shell will convert it to in
desert number That is you.
So friend their soul for this lecture in the next lecture will understandable your the next
variables.
That is constant variables.
So thanks.
We'll soon the next lecture