how everyone?
So the last lecture we got an idea about how to create on in teaser variable.
So here we have commands.
Declare on declare Come on.
We have to use an option that is hyphen.
I hyphen.
I is to make a in teaser variable.
So this selective we understand how to create that constant very bell.
So,
Costin variables are basically those variables whose values has been defined.
So that would be same.
Throw the salad script.
Suppose I have a script on at the beginning,
I have created,
you know,
a few Costin variables like ABC on I'll have another available like BF So two variables
have defined on These are my costume variables.
So once it has been defined,
the value of these variables would be seemed throughout the shallow scrape.
Even in this clip,
in below lines are mentioned some different values,
but it is not going to take those values.
And the starting we have defined these well,
loser as a costume variables.
So these values will be saying on it cannot be changed as well.
If anybody is trying to change these values,
it won't be because these are called,
you know,
constant variables or,
we can say read only variables as well.
So there to commands which can be used to,
you know,
create the constant variables.
The 1st 1 is your read.
Only on 2nd 1 is your declare.
Come on.
So read only the name off your variable on the value Second is declared.
So declare.
Come on.
You have to use one option.
That is hyphen.
That is to clear Costin Variables.
So But the commands are doing the same thing,
like on these other you know,
building commands as well.
So this is my in a box.
I'm going to show you how to get the,
you know,
constant variables.
So I'm going to use this declare.
Come on,
Haifa.
On here you have to give the variable name I'm giving.
Like any name like this is my available in on the value of my values.
You can give any names like you can give in,
Teacher,
you can give you know,
like any string as well.
If you want to give,
like,
this week and also give way,
it is up to you.
Anything you're gonna give here Even you can give number as well.
So I'm giving this one on here.
We have,
you know,
some data files,
some important finds that so any name I have given?
No,
I have defined available the name off.
My variable is warmer and it's a constant.
So I'm doing this.
I call this one.
No.
If anybody is trying to you know t this valuable it is not possible.
So this variable has been defined as a constant variable.
This variable is only applicable for this shell,
right?
It is not any no environmental variable African See the system variable.
That is same for all the shells.
If you want,
you can make it.
No,
if I'm going to try to change this world like I want to change something like this one it
wanted like you got this has been defined.
So at the beginning,
off a shallow script if you have defined,
like this is my,
you know,
costume variables on the script.
If if it is the biggest script and somebody has tried to,
you know,
use the same,
variable name,
like,
warm available.
Um,
if it is being used in the same script and giving some different values.
So it is not going to be taken.
It cannot be changed once it has been defined.
Even you can.
You cannot believe that.
Well,
yes,
using this command as well if you want to use this one like this one and it is not going to
be viewed as well well,
over the same this one.
So,
friend,
that's all for this lecture will do in the next letter.