how everyone?
It was like devil C about the party name expansion.
We'll have a little bit critical on done Will move towards the lab session.
But this topic can only we understand using the lab session.
So best shell supports pardoning expansion as shown below.
So if you want to expand toe clear any patterns,
you have to use the country.
Bess is so like this We like and wanting to win and in numbers.
If you have any file and if you will find that something,
you know,
There,
you know the extension is common,
like file one dot txt file.
Do not dear.
She so you can use,
you know,
curly braces and expand the file as well.
So we'll let me move toward smile obsession on Let's do some practice on that echo.
I'm here.
I'm just typing.
I love my mother.
I'm a father.
Let's see now.
I love my mother Father Right here.
If I am not using any space,
let's see what it is going to do.
I love my mother.
My father.
Right.
Suppose you know I want to,
you know,
type like this 11 to t.
So it will explain file one file to file three.
So here I have used the curly braces.
I can use this one this file one dot txt file to dot txt file to safety.
If I have a number off numbers,
like have type 10 numbers,
right?
For 1 to 10 you can use one daughter town.
So it will type all the numbers,
like,
51 dot 55 to 60 until the number reaches toe 10.
Right?
Okay.
This is one thing I don't think you suppose if you want Oh,
view fights like your am not conference a file you have it is.
See if you have another fire,
like update Davey on the file.
I have this one says Sadiyah.
Okay,
so here you can see that simple.
I'm trying to,
you know,
list out the three fines in three files.
You can see something is common.
That is dot com on starting location is also same.
That is it's less dizzy again,
you know,
use the same.
Come on.
I can use it in that curly braces as well.
How we can do that.
So it is common.
The location off all these three files,
the same that is a dizzy so I can use it easy on this one.
I'm going to use I am not con.
My second file is off dead.
Devi dot com on that file assist CDL dot com No such find some type of mistake is here,
Lindsay.
No,
you have to put slash here.
I can see that I've got output he had again.
See,
that dot com is also common to all the finds.
So what I can do here at the last I can put dot com and I can remove these as well.
I'm going the same outboard.
So basically,
you know,
I'm trying to explain you the part name expansion so you can use such commands as well.
Do you know expand the files as well?
So from their cell for this lecture in the next electoral Understandable the white cards.
So thanks for watching.
We'll see the next lecture