how everyone.
So today we're going to discuss a very important topic.
White guards and system at mean if you want to,
you know,
lunch,
Alice.
Scripting.
So you must be aware off these wild cars.
So we have,
you know,
three while cars that your best support The 1st 1 is a restaurant.
The symbol is this one.
So the meaning off this as triggers,
it matches any sticks,
including the another string.
This can be represented.
Any number of characters,
including zero.
In other words,
do and more characters.
So here they have taken one example like suppose I have used this one Syrian.
After that I've used this.
Estes.
So what does it mean?
Suppose I'm in some location,
Andi,
that is in,
you know,
supposed im and e d.
C.
On.
I want to search,
you know,
the files that has been started with city.
So what I can do here again?
Five.
This Syrian iStar for whatever the fires that is available on that location like city,
and then see after that also like CD ABC,
like,
see the room like silly because it will list all of you.
You have any files which is having the name on the city itself.
Silly itself.
The next one is your question,
Mark.
That is,
matches any single one character,
right.
So here you can see that it is searching for all,
like city,
a city room.
So three correct to say has been added.
But it will look for on a single character like half fire as the cushion lot.
So it will look for as he as D.
C.
S B if you have.
If I like as the baby,
that is not going to list you because cushion mark matches any single one character matches
any one of the characters.
So done.
One is one.
So let me move to us.
My lab obsession on Let's do some practice here support I won't do such You know,
the fires in my this location that has ended with dot com.
So here we have,
although puts So what I have used here ls slash CDC on.
After that,
I have used strips on dot com so you can see that all the fires it's ended with dot com and
I This is one thing.
Now I want to such in the same location that a D.
C.
Who was enough extension would be dot com,
But I want that file should be started with our and how we can do that I can simply pull
are here.
So we'll set for the files.
Who's started with,
you know are after that.
Whatever the name it could be.
Extension would be dot Confidently.
No.
Here you can see the output.
So this is the benefits off the wild cards,
right?
Suppose I'm here?
I'm going to get few fights,
like,
obviously not at it.
Be seated on it.
Hollowed image defies output or no,
I'm going to care Some other fights,
like my daughter.
See,
X y did not see on day like the f topsy.
So few files are crowded into this location.
So I want to search all the fights that has been started with daughter has taken such with
this.
I want to see all the fights that has been started.
That has been,
you know,
ended with dot C five this cover.
So they're simple examples which can be used to find out.
I want to search.
You know all the files whose extension is Darcy and knowledge.
I can use this one my head.
We have got an output.
That is one thing.
The next is you know,
the question Mark,
that is,
you know,
matches any single characters.
So how we can use that?
So that's a very simple,
you know.
So in this location,
Andi and I want to search for the fights.
They So let me do one thing.
Let me get few files here,
so I'm going to use touch file on day one dot 10 Dusty.
I can see that a lot of fights have been killed in here.
Okay,
so what I'm going to do and when we use ls file a star?
It is giving me all the fines,
right?
Who?
The starting is fine enough for that.
Whatever it could be,
it could be anything.
Suppose you know have changes.
Have taken every 5 to 10 more files.
Whose extension is dark.
I get.
I'm fighting.
This company will see that it is giving me all.
Put off all the fights.
Whether it's you know,
extension is you know dot txt dot com.
No,
to suppose.
Start off this.
I'm using this cushion month and not txt.
So what?
It is going toe out where it is going to give me.
So it will search for the files.
You know who's starting bodies file on after that single character like won t five,
you know,
79 This it 64 and two.
There's one more fighting.
This one here.
We have no God that were part of this fight,
because this file is having two characters.
Suppose I have credit one find,
like this one touch file on.
I'm giving this one authority doctor used to.
So you fighting this?
Come on.
I'm not getting this output.
I want to get this out by any news to cushion so it would suffer the fires.
Whose you know,
having two characters.
This one on this 12 characters.
Suppose I am having the file,
which is having three characters.
So I need to use three question marks.
Okay,
So this is one thing on Did suppose I want to use this?
The last one?
This is so how we can use that.
So here you can see that I have a lot of files that is ended with dot com for not txt so I
can use this one.
It's less a T C and I'm I'm already in this location on going to use this one on the this
one file on after that.
Closing it on this is tough dot So it would list.
Told me all the files that has been started with this one.
This is one thing we have here you're going to use txt s.
Well,
we do not have such any fighting.
It's txt.
So for their cell for this lecture hope you got an idea how we can use the wild cards.
Andi,
just google it.
We will see a lot of,
you know,
documents that we have for the wild cards on gets a lot of,
practice lab station as well.
So I've already shown a lot of practice for these wild cards,
Andi,
and do practice from your end as well.
On duh.
If you want to do some more practice,
so just Google and find a lot off exercise on my cards.
So that's very important to have in a practice by your side as well.
That's all.
But I take it will soon The next lecture