que statements groups.
Now this lesson.
We will go over the statements off case where you are given options in a script to pick
from.
So it's like an interactive way off involving user whether they want to select Option ABC
so forth.
So in case statement,
if a option is selected,
do this be selected?
Do that CIA selected do this?
So these are the different options on what,
exactly a or B or C is gonna do?
Well,
it depends on what the variable you assigned to them.
For example,
if you assign a to do,
um,
to up date on the screen,
it will output the date.
What if a is selected?
Now,
let's let's look at the script.
I have a script right here.
Always starts with the show.
Shell is bash.
The next is Echo,
which is just printing out an empty line.
Then it's gonna echo.
Please choose one of the options below.
It will print out a as in for variable equals display Date in time B list file and
directories see list uses logged in and D checks system up time.
Now,
this is all just a display message that's gonna show up.
Once the script is run,
then it will read.
All the choices are put all the choice in a container.
Then the case statement comes in.
It's gonna say choices,
which is this variable choices in And the container?
We put it.
All these choices and what the's choice is going to do.
A.
It's going to run the command Date B is gonna run the command.
L s C is going to run the command list of users War logged in and D is going to run the
command up time.
Remember,
all of these are actual commands inside off your Linux operating system.
When you run it individually,
it will give you the date.
But this script will allow you to automate the task toe.
Pick these commands for you.
So let's copy them.
This is the whole script we have,
and I'm gonna go into our Lennox machine,
which I have already logged in on logged in us myself and this territory.
I'm and I'm in my home directory.
I'll go into my scripts territory.
Um,
I believe,
uh,
my scripts CD,
my scripts.
And in that directory I have already created some of the scripts that we learned in the
previous lessons.
So for this,
I'm gonna create a new script.
Gonna v I and I'm gonna name the file case script.
You could name it.
Anything you want once you are in V I mode hit,
insert by and you could just simply right click on your,
um on your mouse and it will paced everything for you.
The first option is once again it's just a shell.
It's telling you to run would shell environment.
The 2nd 1 is you type in anything this script is created,
but by me or yourself your name or what everyone you want to do.
Second thing it's doing by the way,
empty lines in the script doesn't really marry.
Believe the Empty or you could just put a hash sign.
Next thing echo again.
Echo is just gonna throw in an empty line on the screen.
And as we went over the script,
this exactly what's gonna do.
Um,
and you're gonna save this file?
Do ls my Celt er this is still a file.
It's not scripted because we have not assigned executed permissions to it.
So to assign that secured permission a plus X to assign acceptable permissions toe all user
group and others and the name off the scrip s case script Verify it has all the permissions
.
Yes,
it does.
Now we're gonna run the script by dot,
slash and type case.
Once you're gonna run it,
you'll see it's gonna give you that.
Please choose one off the options below.
So you have the list of options right here?
A to display the date and time.
It's nothing but exactly the display off all those texts that I have typed after Echo,
which you see right here it's everything after echo.
It's nothing but,
um,
and output on the screen.
So now if I select okay and run it it exit of the script and it gives me the date it runs
the command date itself as a few type date.
It gives you the date,
today's date,
the time and you let's run it again.
And this time will pick be once you do be it lists all the files or directories inside off
my current director,
which is the command that you already know,
which is Ellis.
Run it again.
And this time I'm gonna pick D check system up time and to the command to check system up.
Time is just simply up time.
And this script will run up time command and put on the screen.
So this was exactly the case statement does.
So the last option.
If you notice we have a star right here.
What?
It's telling me that if any other option is packed,
it's gonna say echo invalid choice.
So by so let's try to run it.
And this time I'm gonna pick F.
Of course,
F is not one of the listing.
So once I do,
that will say invalid choice by.
So that's how the case script works.
I want you try it out.
Pick different commands that you want to run,
pick different text message that you want to associate with those commands and try to run
it.
Let's say if you want it,
um,
pick A for what is your name,
and it should type who for it,
and it will give you the log in name and so on,
and all the different commands that you have learned