how everyone in the section I'm going to discuss about a script which can be used to fete
all the recording formation from the system.
Information could be like in all the network details.
User details,
Lord average on your system.
Memory tradition,
separate logician horse details,
internal I p up time doubting table DNA's architecture and many more information.
So did we have discos on learn a lot off topics with vertical as well as practice lab
station,
not time has come to explore them.
Loving is important,
but most important is how to explore them.
So this section is only man for exploring all the topics which we had discussed previously
In this course I'm going to show you one off my task which I had God in my previous
president,
task is very simple here.
You can see that this is my environment.
Here we have multiple servers.
So these other sauce,
this is my one somewhat to 17.
So,
like this were we have multiple,
so was present in my environment.
And if the in the middle you can see that I have once and twice over as well.
So what is in twice over?
Sent rice over is the servers from where I can access all my souls.
Wait,
No,
My task was very simple.
I have to create a script on that.
This group is basically fighting all information from the sewer.
And then I have to put that a script toe all the souls in my environment.
So the script Nawas system underscore details.
So I have created that script and put it in all the sourced.
Now you can see that on when that man does the script runs,
it gives Ah,
file that is output file of the script on that goes into this location that Islam on the
name of the finalists ACEA deaths are put off Dxy So this is the file where we have all the
information about them.
So now here we have one simple a So and the sentiments over we have one is clipped,
another is good.
So the purpose off that descript that is present on a central server is to,
you know,
goto all the several one by one,
like this is my central service hereafter added one more script.
So the purpose off that script when it runs it goes to force over on looking for this file
and copy it from their imported in the central I sell.
Then it goes to a second server on.
Do the same thing.
Copy this file.
Output off that script.
Put it in the centralized location on this group that you can see on all the soldiers it is
running by.
Kron,
we have should do the job with the help off con,
which is exactly you know,
running this is Kip on vehicle abysses.
And here also,
we have a script that also runs on the weekly basis.
No word is a benefit off that so benefit is very important here.
Suppose one off my system,
that is first system that goes down on it is not coming up.
So a system admin whose troubleshooting that issue he or she needs all the required
information off the sour If my silver is down,
how would I know that?
What?
Waas you know,
the system details the mammary days on the file systems.
The district is so all those information.
I need to troubleshoot more on that bus.
So in that case,
we already have one centralized servers where we have the information off all the servers
so I can go to that server that is centralized server.
And from there,
I concert for the file of their server.
Right on.
From there,
we can find out like,
Oh,
this is the service.
This is my network retail.
This is the district sales.
These are the file systems that were present on the system.
So all those information,
we can get it from my sin delays over.
So this section I'm going to show you this a script that it's system on the school details
.
So I'm just moving here to my this box that I have Peter Descript and same script I'm going
to discuss in this section.
So I'm just sending for you.
So just see,
you have just executed describe it is collecting the same system Information.
The Internet is connected.
Operating system type.
So tired distribution architecture in the kernel.
Dale's holds name.
I be lobster rolls them slab this.
You know,
Lord,
every system of time,
Colonel.
So it is collecting almost all the information's.
If you want to add any off more commands,
you can add on and here you can see that output,
which I'm getting it isn't,
you know,
pretty good.
Some color are there.
My first is You know,
you can see that is in green.
And after that,
output is in red.
So we have to learn that as well.
How we can,
you know,
put the color in the shallow script so that the output is,
in color so that it is easy to know segregate the output as well.
So,
friend,
that's all for the selector.
The next electorally start with the bash colors How we can,
you know,
put the colors and output off the script.
So that's all for this lecture with you in the next lecture,
but by