do wild scripts do?
One.
Scripts are very similar to four loops for scripts.
The Do Well script or statement.
Continued lead executes a block of statements,
while a particular condition is true or met.
For example,
if you are running a script and you created in a loop,
it will run until a certain variable is met.
For example,
if you have,
if you want to run the script until August 2015 to 2 p.m. Then you will define that and do
well script and a lot of times the scripts or the demons,
the process that never dies,
that keep running and running and running.
They always have do wild scripts because they are running content continuously until a
certain condition is met.
So,
for example,
Rana script until 2 p.m. As soon as the two PM hits,
you're done.
Exit out while condition do command one command to command three.
And once all these commands are done and the condition is done,
then you are done.
You are done with your script.
So let's look at our Lennox machine and let's try out ah,
do a script.
It's clear the screen where you are.
We are in my script Victory,
which is this directory we want to be in.
And this time you're gonna create in this new script and we're gonna call it script,
do a while again.
Um,
it's just the name I'm picking.
You could pick anything you want Hit Enter.
You are in V I mode,
you hit insert and you start typing with the first thing that your type type hash bang been
bash,
which defines your shell environment.
And if you wanted to put a comment,
you could say this script is created.
But in Ron have so on 2018.
Yeah,
that's fine.
And if you want to put a description of the script,
you could do that.
But let's get into the script.
I have already written in the script.
I'm just gonna go in and copy it.
There are two scripts in my hand out.
I'm gonna take the 2nd 1 I want you to do the 1st 1 yourself.
Copy it,
and I'm gonna paste in real quick.
Let's see what this guy does the script is doing.
Of course,
the 1st 1 is defining the show,
which we already have some we're gonna take it out,
but hitting D D.
And then it's telling us that the count is zero.
The number as 10 wild account is less than 10.
Do echo number of seconds left to stop this process,
and the process is the variable,
which is dollar one,
and echo is just empty space.
Empty line.
Sleep Sleep is a command that will wait for the number of seconds that is defined after the
sleep command.
Then it has a few number of expressions.
These are expressions.
You could get it anywhere online.
I have that expression for a while that I tried out many times in my work environment.
It works perfectly.
Any phone is using in your work environment,
you're more than welcome to do so.
The next one is sitting echo,
and then it says echo dollar.
One process is stopped and echo again.
It is telling it that it's giving an empty line.
Let's run the script and that see what it does give execute herbal permissions.
It's his 10 seconds left to stop this process.
987654321 and done process is stopped.
You see that?
So these do Wah scripts are created for a certain value or certain time to be met,
and once that variable is met,
it will stop the process and exit out of it.
I want you to create a new script in your environment,
and this is a script again.
This is also in the handouts.
You could copy and paste the script,
create a new script and run it.
You could also be my guest to go online and just type Do wild script examples.
There are tons and tons of do while scripts that you could try and get get a low,
um,
exposure to do Y scripts.
I'm sure by the time you will run at least five or six scripts,
you know exactly what this statement do.