how everyone.
So let's continue and start creating this group.
So Skip is already created.
I'm going to execute the script on Let's see Ward Stout.
What?
I'm getting.
So with the help of output,
I'm going to create the script with you from scratch.
Okay.
After going position,
this is my second edition.
Andi,
I'm going to get the script.
Okay?
Today let me scroll up.
I can see that when my script started.
Very first information WAAS system information.
So it's very easy.
You can put like this one echo on here again.
Put system information.
All right,
let me make it executive in.
That is okay,
I'm getting this information,
But if you'll see there's a difference here,
you can see there is an underlying as well.
So two unable underlying you have to,
you know,
enable the you know that is interpretation Off backs less escapes.
So,
Father,
do you have to use Hyphen e?
And also for this underlying,
you need to,
you know,
start the bash colors.
So the command was this one.
That is your It's less okay.
That is bracket square bracket on the court number color court number for underlying the
court is four,
and you have to use em.
Andi,
to close this color coding,
you have to use less E.
Coli back in.
So it's crab record zero,
That's all.
No,
I'm going to the same output that is that I'm getting with that descript.
They next is your internet.
It is showing connected.
Right.
So to check the internet connectivity,
I'm going to use this.
Come on.
That is,
you know,
being being.
And I remember you with this one here.
You can see that I'm keep on getting the output.
And if I own two interrupted,
I need to press control.
See?
So I have to use fi option with thing that is C one on google dot com.
Right,
So here you can see that it checks only father one time.
Apart from that,
I'm also using some time on value as well.
That is five seconds,
So it will wait for only five seconds.
Suppose you know I mentioned like,
any website on that website is,
you know,
not responding.
And I have not mentioned this time of value.
That is five seconds.
So in that case,
the ping command will keep on Jack the connectivity till it reaches to the time of value
tomorrow,
will you?
It could be one minute to minute whatever.
So what will happen in the script?
Your script gets hung,
right?
So do a white this I'm going to use this time,
or will you as well,
right?
The next thing is that in this case we will see that it is simply selling Internet
connected or disconnected.
I don't want to see all these outputs.
So after nullify all those outputs for that,
I will be used.
This this symbol that is percentage the same.
That is a redirection channels.
So we'll have a separate section on understanding the redirection channel.
So this channel is basically nullify our genetic all your outputs,
whether it's a useful out port or any other.
After that,
I have mentioned this one,
so it will nullify otherwise if you have mentioned like some file,
so all the output is going into that file.
But I wanted should nullify like now you can see that it is number five like No,
The next thing.
If you remember that in the previous lecture we had discussed,
like one come on,
that is test and we're having one condition like on day.
After that,
we have used some,
you know,
symbol like this.
One person on that that is too common,
Andi.
And if my previous come on,
didn't transit is fully down.
It would be going to this like false Come on.
Like the same concept I'm going to use.
So here,
you know,
this is my come on.
And it is going to check this one.
So if it is satisfied like the condition is satisfied So whatever you have mentioned here
that is going to be executed If this condition is not satisfied,
it will be going here.
So same concept.
I will be used here as well.
So this is my been comma on If my pink connectivity is working Fine.
Then I'm mentioning here I NT is my variable name I have given any name on it would be
saving this connected here.
Right?
And suppose it has not been given.
It means that my command didn't properly so I'm going to put this I m t is equal to this
character.
Right?
So now I have available.
That is I nd it is suing connected.
Same.
I'm going to use in my script.
Okay.
The name off my script.
Waas this one.
Okay,
Electric copy my script.
I did.
And I'm putting this sleep so that it should wait for running.
Should wait for one second before initiating the second.
Come on.
So okay,
Andi,
after that,
I'm putting this echo,
Andi and this I cook and I want that output should becoming like this one.
This is you know,
my grain,
right?
It isn't green.
So I have to use this one on for green.
The court color code is your 32 on a dish going Internet.
I'm putting Internet here on its face.
Colon and I have to close this one.
Because if you'll see that the second,
this one is your different color.
So how to close this one?
It's very simple.
The same I have used that is zero.
They.
So that's let me come out and done it again.
Okay,
now here.
I've got this output.
But I didn't get anything here.
So I have to mention here,
this one as well.
So whether it is connected or not connected,
very safe.
It's saving to this variable.
That is I NT right.
So what I'm wondering.
Use here.
And I want the output.
Should be coming in Red color,
resident.
So I'm going to put this one e and forward.
We have the color court 31.
Okay,
This one I nt I ain't is my variable Right on.
I have to close as well.
So the clothes we have,
This one that's all so simple here.
No discipline connected.
I can see that.
The second is operating system tied that issuing zero Lennox.
So get this.
We have a command.
This one you name hyphen.
Oh,
simple.
Come and I'm using,
Right.
Same.
I'm putting in my script.
So after each come on,
I am putting sleep.
One they No,
I'm giving any variable.
That is Wes Onder dollar,
That is you name hyphen.
Or even for this.
So whatever the output off you name hyphen.
Oh,
it is going to save into available name That is s right after that,
I'm going to put echo hyphen e on this less e on the head again.
See that this is a similar system type.
Okay,
it is in a green color.
So for green Clear,
we have a court 30 toe.
Um on.
This is this Electoral Warner should be coming in green.
Let me close this one.
Okay,
on.
Did you hear?
What about what I want that is in,
you know,
read one forever when we have 31 a m on this is dollar is always is my this one.
Let me close it as well.
Now I can see that I'm getting this as well coming to this one.
That is somewhat time.
That is V ember.
So some time we have the common This one d my discord on guy fund s under this system
manufacturer.
This one See him?
Come on.
I'm gonna be used in my script.
Okay,
so that's very simple.
The same thing after that,
I'm going to put a sleep of one second.
Okay,
on did I'm giving any very blame.
You can put any variable name on the same Come on.
So the output of this command is going to save into my this variable after that echo hyphen
e.
And same.
I'm putting this 1 30 toe.
Um,
that is for,
you know,
green color Onda,
and that is the solar type.
All right.
Okay.
And I'm going to close this one with that on Did tell here on the very real name is my this
type B again on Let me close as well.
Okay,
I can see output.
I'm getting the designer put here against the twenties Time.
This column is coming.
Let's see what the mistake we have no twice time we have mentioned.
That's why I'm getting twice time and it again.
See that used time on Hamedani?
This one?
It is coming like this way.
What I wanted should be,
you know,
started from the top and you can put clear here they Nazi.
All right,
so there.
So for this,
elect him,
We'll continue from the next election ticket.