how everyone.
So let's continue.
So the last,
Lechter,
while defining the variable for operating system time we have mentioned like this way We
have mentioned dollar on in the bracket.
We have mentioned you name hyphen or on in the next line you can see that I have defined
available right,
that is type B.
But the way off,
you know,
defining the variable list differ.
So both are correct.
So if I'm using the same way this one So that is also correct.
So don't be confused.
That's family showing you here as well.
I can see that the same output I'm getting right Next one is your distribution.
That is your that did it.
So we know that we have,
you know,
different distribution off Lenox,
Like your redhead saying toe is Susie Mandrake Debian.
So how would I find out?
So there is a common that is you name Hyphen is so this command will only tell you that
whether it's a Lennix.
But what distribution off Lennox is that it's a red hair sent to is for that I have to use
simple,
you know,
if else condition.
Right.
So one more thing here If it is there,
you know,
read or send to us.
We have a file,
this one that is ready.
So if you have Santos and readers will find this.
And if we get this finally for this redder,
you'll see it's a ready on day for the sender's,
you'll see Same fine.
But that finally will find it is written as a Saint Louis late.
If it is,
you know,
Susie,
the file would be this one.
That is Susan on that is desk release.
So with that fine,
you'll come to know that this is my Susie Lennox on.
If it is Mandrake,
we have this one man drink that is release.
If it is,
you know,
Debian.
So the file would with this one Debian And here it is underscored,
not dish.
So you have to do some r and D on there so that it will find all those things.
So with the help of this file,
I will come to know that what distribution off Lennox we have.
Okay,
because in mind,
woman,
it could be a few that had few sent to his few fedora off.
You know,
Debian and few in a mandrake.
Susie So how would I know that?
So I'm just going to create a script on I'm using.
If else condition.
So I ask,
was this one okay?
So I'm using this variable that is always on guard Dollar on.
Did it?
That is you name Hyphen s.
Great.
So you never happen s that is on Lennox,
right?
Okay.
No,
Maybe in my environment suppose I have some sp UNIX also on do some eggs also.
So you can compared with that.
Come on,
If you are finding your name,
I finance,
if it is showing extended,
will simple print their se x So if I'm going to use if on the file attributes I'm going to
use if I found half Andi before that I want to use this one.
That is bliss.
They on this one,
That is.
You call to line X.
Okay,
Now we have come to know that this is Lennix Now I just want to know that it is a land is
But what distribution is there If it is Lennix Then again,
I'm going to use if on that I'm checking for the file that is D C Is that it?
That is release.
Okay on closing it then.
All right.
And I can put like distribution is equal to I live in they second condition.
I'm putting Elif.
If on death in my Lennox if the file is this one,
that is those through the Atlantic's.
Okay,
then I can put distribution is a no variable name I have given I'm putting this Susan.
some mystic out on this one left symbol of using a lift off the next one.
Is this live on?
If my files this Mandaric that is man drink.
Wes,
you get close check.
You could just log into the box each box and crosscheck the feeling.
Okay,
you can put distribution that is equal to you mending.
If on did.
If you see this one,
that is for Debian on the Debian Voisin.
If you have the file of this one,
then the distribution would be what should be Debian only.
Okay?
I want to close this one.
I used twice time If May know what this is Crap.
I will comfortable that whether it's a redhead,
send us or it's a you know,
Susie on all those for now I need to print as well right.
So how to print this one?
So that is this one distribution,
right?
So after port this one echo on,
uh,
hyphen E that it's less e this one.
Could you do?
That is for the green one.
Um,
on here after port The distribution.
Andi,
let me close this one.
That IHS zero am andi and still s e this one.
I have to put the 31 for the red color on.
This is my you know,
a lot of letters distribution.
I e.
Zero Um let me close.
Okay.
I'm going to run this one.
Let's see,
I'm getting the desired output on maybe some type of mistake.
It is saying that Come on.
Not from let's see.
It should be in bracket.
If we have some space and it should be Becker,
others will take what?
It should not take this one.
You can see that I've got a desired output.
But one more thing.
Suppose you know I told you in the beginning that did.
If you have a file that is for those sent to us in the centres,
you will see that we have the same file late.
Okay,
so let me log into one off my sent box.
So the i p off my centers,
But that 1 90 to 1 60 years,
that is,
you know,
209 and one for two.
I can see that business sent to us right on the center.
They also we have the same fine.
But with my come on,
I will only know that this is my center is only right.
So I'm going to cut this file on.
I'm going to keep this fight here.
You can see this swing.
Let him.
But here it is showing,
you know,
sand boost.
So I can add a few more thing with my script here.
Well,
you know,
deciding whether it's a,
reading or sent to us so I can put,
like,
this way that is Get this one.
Okay,
if you have this fighting so it will cap this friend,
and I'm gonna be used or care So we'll discuss up in that little lectures.
But here and simple meaning,
I'm just,
you know,
bending the column that is calling one on git.
Call him too.
I'm just the morning now.
This has become a common,
so I need to put it in this dollar on this one,
Beckett.
Okay,
I'm gonna maternity.
Let's see,
I'm getting the desire for no Steak is here.
Let's see what is a mistake here.
They can see that twice time dollar has come here.
So the kids have to use this symbol.
This one.
OK,
nitwit again,
some type of mistake.
Let's see.
OK,
but you should if you can see that it started with you know,
this record that is curly bracket after pulled with curly bracket.
I can see that I am getting the proper our Okay,
So what was the common?
The common was this one.
So if I'm going to get here this one,
let's see here the swing sent to is right.
So if I'm going to run the same escaping with this system with a C,
I'm getting the proper or put or not So my skin is this one.
Thank you.
So better.
Likely copy.
This is our city hyphen P on 1 $92 1 68 Doctor,
2091 42.
I'm putting into my Tim on This is my No.
So what message?
So I've covered this Kim Okay,
I'm going to Tampa location,
and I want to execute this one here.
You can see the same escaped.
I'm running.
I'm getting sent to us on Samos crippling.
I'm running here.
I'm getting this.
That it did because I have used this.
Come on.
Right.
So the common was this one.
Let me copy this.
Come on and show you this one.
They So what did this come on?
This one.
So I simply,
you know,
up and cut the column.
So this is my first column.
This is second column.
First column has been donated by Dollar one and second columnist dollars too.
Same thing I've been here as well.
We'll see here.
That is kept there is Reddit release.
This is my first column on this is my second column.
So that's why I'm getting this centralised on.
Uh,
Lennox,
because we had grabbing two columns were cutting to call if there is a dollar $1 too.
So from there,
some for this.
Like to hope you have understood harm.
What logic?
I'm using too,
you know,
fetch the required information.
So thanks for watching Will soon.
The next lecture