everyone.
So let's continue and do the last part of the script.
So I'm going to you know,
added my men escape on cyber side.
Let me execute this.
Kept as well.
They so still here.
We have already discussed right on day and check the architecture.
We have this.
Come on.
That is your name Hyphen.
Um,
here.
You can see that on same.
You know,
I've used the bash color number that it started before the green.
And that is 31 for the red color.
Same concept for commonalities.
You can see that.
I've used your name hyphen.
Our host name in telling like we have used host name hyphen,
Capital light,
simple fire host name hyphen capital.
It is going to print war,
Lynton.
Life is you have on your system here to check the Deena's.
We have used this.
Come on.
All right,
I'm going to cut this and also for the name.
So let's see what our But I'm getting here.
I can see that in the names that I'm getting all the non.
I'd be off.
My name's over.
So if I'm going to cut this file So this is the file which keeps the information about your
names over here.
You can see that I have you.
I'm getting a lot of other output as well.
So first of all,
it is going to,
you know,
use said so we'll have a separate section.
Nobody's SOS here Saturday,
Basically deleting first line one d means the leading first line,
so this line has been deleted.
You can see that in the previous are put.
We have all the airport and I've used third hyphen Wandy.
It's simply deleted the first line,
that's all.
Now I want to bring this one,
this one and this one on this one.
So for that,
I'm going to use the,
you know,
come on on Going to,
bring my second column,
this one local domain on this one on this one.
So I've used this one or are basically for,
you know,
printing the columns.
So here you can see this is my column.
First column,
search name server names ever.
2nd 1 is local domain.
This one on this one.
Let me show you.
So what?
I want to bring the first column.
I can use this one Dollar one.
The first column is printing this one this one because you can see that every column has
been separated by a space.
If I want to bring the second color,
I can put two here if I want to print or I can use tree If I want to print,
you know,
here you can see that only two columns are there.
This is my first column on second column.
That's why I got only one out.
Because in the first line only we have three columns if I want.
Oh,
you know,
bring one on too,
so I can put like this way so it will Brit board.
But I want to have a space I can put,
Kama said will separate 10 hair.
It was separate by a space.
So same concept I've used here as well.
Okay,
Andi,
you can see for logging users.
We have usedto come on and have redirected output into a file.
And then,
in a simple off mentioned this one logged in users.
So it's becoming like they will see the output.
We have something different.
Okay.
Here you can see that Control sampling logged in.
Users are coming here.
We are in the same language getting this outward and this.
But you can see that we have a big output for this.
Come on.
That's why I put it in the next line.
So here are for you know,
this loving user and I have given green color for their and the last have simple Can this
file like this one get this way themselves and using this color and for Ram?
I have used,
you know,
free Haifa net,
and I would think the same.
Okay for Lord,
read everything.
I've used this.
Come on.
OK,
Andi,
for this great deal.
I've used this.
Come on.
Okay,
and nobody's I'm going to it as business script with your you know,
the section so that he Condoned,
described as well.
So from their cell for the selector hope you have understood how we can clear the simple,
simple scripts.
The next part is,
you know,
is to you know how to fetch the information Now have simply,
kid in the script,
right?
So next is you know,
I'm going to in a port,
that description all my source and from central location,
I'm going to fetch whatever the output of these commands.
So there's no for the selective,
painful watching if you have time,
please join victim in the next lecture.