Hey,
everyone here is another newer scripted.
We will go where it's about checking the other server connectivity.
Of course,
you need to know all the time.
If you are in a bigger environment,
you need to know if your other servers are actually reachable and paying global.
Now,
I know there are a lot of monitoring solutions that that are out there that,
um a lot of companies have the actually,
those are monitor the servers,
they monitor the health check and everything.
But still,
once in a while,
you do need to actually paying other servers a remote servers that actually tells you if
they are alive or they are down.
So this lesson is about pinging of the servers.
Ah,
what we're gonna do is we actually gonna create a script to check the status off the remote
host or hosts.
Um,
and we'll find out if it is payable or not.
Very simple script we actually have to combine in this group.
We have this combined.
Um,
if ah else ah state man's view might we will have to actually combine do wild statement
together,
and you will see how we could pink other servers.
Um I have a Mullinix machine open.
And I also have a quick document here.
You could say a cheat sheet,
which already I have a script written there,
because if I go over completely blank with you,
I might forget,
and I might lose time.
And I definitely don't want to do that.
I definitely want to lose my time and your time.
So anyway,
the first thing I want to do is I do want to mention one thing that,
um,
previously be actually created.
Um,
a directory called professional Scripts.
Now,
I noticed this whole directory is a very long directory.
Let's make it short.
So this way it will be easier to actually change,
actually from one place to another.
So I'm gonna just do move professional directory scripts,
too.
Um,
PS this simple is that now you'll see I have a doctor called PS when I goto PS,
which stands for professional scripts.
And now I have all my scripts.
So just to start off with that now,
let's start creating our first group that is going to Ping an I P address.
Now,
the I P address that I have selected is the I.
P address off my home modem,
which is one night to 1 68 $1.1.
And most likely if you are in a home environment,
not in the office than your I P address is the same as 1 91 61 That one.
If it is not the same,
then you could go find out the default gave a i p just to test if you could Pinkett or not
,
Or you could just pink.
Or you could just pick any I p that you could,
um,
test your script against.
So I have picked 19 to 1 $61.
One.
This is my i p that I'm gonna test.
Um,
So let's first create a script,
and I'm gonna call the script Ping.
Okay?
And this is the first time I will copy,
then later on.
So I'm just gonna quickly do the information date description this script.
Well,
ping a remote host and notify,
of course,
Then,
um,
modified.
And since this is the first time and I the okay,
now,
let's get into the real work now to be defined their variable.
Now,
Ping,
I'm sure you guys know what a pink script is pink goes out on the remote host Ping An I p.
Address and tell you if,
um,
host is available or not.
So let me just right Quit out of this script.
Make sure you save it.
And just if you don't know Ping than just typing one I to 1 68 that one.
That one.
And you will see you are getting 64.
Bite back from this.
This machine,
it means there is a machine out there with that i p address and it is reaching anyway.
So now let's go back to our So what we are trying to do with the scriptures you want a ping
minus c is count just Ping once the i p one I too once 1 68 1.1 now you as you go along,
you're probably thinking,
Hey,
how come m Ron knows all those different options to specify How can he remembers How can he
just pick really quick?
Well,
to be honest,
I don't remember there many times.
I just go online,
I google it and and I get the options.
So if I wanted to Google paying only once all type paying only ones in Shell script or Ping
only once.
Um,
remote host.
And it will give me the option that I'm looking,
so don't worry about it.
You're You're not the one that you're thinking.
Hey,
my memory sucks.
I'm not gonna remember that.
Trust me,
my memory is probably worse than yours,
so don't worry about it.
If you forget anything,
go online and search for it,
and you will get it As long as you type exactly what you're I'm moving forward.
So we are paying this.
I p alright.
It will ping Evil Ping one time.
Perfect.
Now what will happen?
What are you trying to do when it pinks?
Okay,
we're trying to say is if single bracket dollar question more now,
what is a dollar question Mark Dollar question Mark is the output off all the command that
you run by default?
The dollar?
Um,
question mark returns to well,
use one is zero,
which is that Yes,
it,
um it ran successfully or anything else.
So these are the exit status.
Um,
if you don't know differences between exit status,
you could look it up,
but there are mostly to exist.
Added that I you leave,
um,
rely on eggs.
Status one and two.
So dollar question mark.
If the return off my command above,
which is ping minus C one d I p address is equal 20 Okay.
To see if the return value is equal to zero.
Which means it did run.
It was successful then.
Since we are if else dense statements,
we have to specified then tab,
As I said previously,
always put tabs so it will look neat and clean.
Then what do you want to do?
You know,
the pink is successful,
The host is reasonable,
and what you want to do will simply se Um Okay,
How's that?
Process him.
All right.
Perfect.
Now what if you don't get zero of status,
which is camping it that what you want to do and is what else?
If that doesn't work,
then what else else?
Echo?
Not okay,
Right.
So if I do this else do that,
okay.
Perfect.
Now,
every time you start,
if you have to end it with he and that's pretty much save your script,
give at execute permissions to your script and now run the scripless created screen and all
Run,
run the script.
Perfect.
You see,
it ran and it ran one time and it came back.
It was successful.
Statistics came back.
One packet transmitted.
This is all part off pings group.
So we came back.
The exit status was zero,
which means it run.
And that's why I said,
And that's why the script said it was okay.
Perfect.
Now,
what if I give an I P address,
so I'll change my I p address right here.
I have specified right here again.
I'm gonna change the i p address to one I to 1 61 to 35.
Now,
how do I get that I p address?
I just paying some off the i P address in my home network.
I'm sure,
um,
if you're in the home network,
your I p addresses are probably used from to to,
like,
15 or 20 at least because we have so many gadgets at home.
But it's very highly unlikely that you're probably gonna be at 235 eyepiece.
So what I did is before I picked that I p I just simply pinned that I p Okay.
Do you see I paying that i p and that I p is not reachable.
So that's why I just picked that I p you could pick any I p That is not painful either.
So I'm gonna go into back into my screen,
and this time I'm gonna change the I P two instead of $1.1.
I'm gonna change it 2 to 35 and save it.
And now,
when I run it,
what should I get camping?
Get right and it's gonna come back and is going to say not.
Okay.
See,
that's how the F L script works.
And to ping other hosts of the devices.
That is something that you will definitely definitely will be working on.
I'm sure if you are in system administrator or engineer or any kind of role,
you probably would have to do that.
Now,
Next one is if you notice right here.
I have this output coming in that I put it's gonna give me that ping,
and then it will give me the not OK.
Now,
what if I just I'm just concerned that don't show me anything.
Just tell me if it is okay,
and if it's not OK,
so what would we do here?
as I have written down here,
you could output cause right here and you do paying it out,
Put to the screen.
If you do not want that to be output on the screen,
then there is this.
Ah,
Syntex,
um that you have to specify its is and percent quicker than sign.
And Deb No,
it means that you are out.
Putting it to a definable definable is just a file in Lenox.
It's ah,
no file.
Every time you throw anything on definable,
it will just disappear.
That's how it is.
And I'm very hopeful.
You probably heard of that as well.
So I'm gonna go back into my pink scrip.
And this time I am going to tell it that you know what?
Don't throw messages on the screen.
I don't care about the message.
All I care about is what is the outcome?
Is it okay or is it not OK?
No,
I will run it if you see.
let me clear the screen.
So you will see it will come up very nice and neat and clean.
She's not doing all those messages.
All I'm gonna get is not okay.
That's what I care about so many times.
You don't really want to see all that junk on the screen because that will not only confuse
you,
but I will take your time to actually read through it.
And what exactly you're looking for?
So if I change the i p back to one,
then I should get okay simply and straightforward.
Just okay.
Perfect.
Now,
next thing I want to cover is what if you want to define that,
I pee in a very meaning.
You put that I pee in front off a variable.
So instead of just pinging the straight i p you paying the variable,
Why do I do that?
Because many times you do want to add multiple host or you know,
certain things that you want to um you want you probably wanted to paying multiple times,
Then you don't want to specify Be again and again and again,
you just specify one time,
and then they do the host to itself.
So I'm gonna go back to into pings.
Quit.
And now I'm gonna put invariable right here,
and variable I'm gonna do is host um,
equal sign coat 1 90 to 1 68.1 dot one close desk,
my variable.
Now,
instead of paying the I p,
what I'm gonna say is paying the host and dollar host,
right?
And this time I'm gonna make my script a little fence here.
I'm gonna say,
if ping this host,
which is this with this variable and I'll put to a definable if the output it's successful
,
then okay,
instead of just okay,
I'm gonna say didn't say hosts the I p is okay is okay.
And else if that is not Ping Global,
then hosts is not okay.
You see,
I use my variable so efficiently.
Now,
I is used in three different in three different places.
I don't have to specify i p here.
Um,
sorry,
i p here.
I don't have to specify I p here.
I don't have to specify i p here I have specified the i p just one time as a variable right
here and now I'm just gonna use that variable as or that container,
and I'm gonna use it again and again and again.
Okay,
so let's run it nice,
right?
I p That I'm trying to ping is okay.
So now it's very pacific.
There's telling me that this is the I p that you're trying to ping,
and it is okay not to worry about it.
Now,
what if I change the i p 2 to 35 which is,
of course,
one of my p.
That is not thinkable.
That is not a sign.
And now let's clear the screen so we could see better Pinks.
He's gonna ping.
And the reason it takes a little longer because sometimes pain just waits for it to respond
.
It's by default.
It's just waits for it anyway.
So you see,
it came back.
It says one night to 1 61 to 35 is not okay.
Perfect.
See how we actually made the Jews off variable here and the use If an l statements and the
are putting the variables in place,
I'll gain.
Um,
Now,
next one is changing.
I p already did that.
Perfect.
Now,
the next one is a little complicated one,
But it's easy if you do it together.
Okay.
Now what if you wanted toe Ping multiple I ps in one screw.
One I p I coping.
Get right.
I could I don't even have to create a script hoping that.
Right?
I understand you're probably thinking that,
but the reason we start off with one eye piece.
So you would understand what if you want to ping 100 servers now where things get
interesting now,
you really need to have that script,
right?
Look,
So,
first of all,
what you need to do is you need to put that I p addresses that you wanted to paying to.
Ah,
file.
So I'm gonna create a while.
I'm gonna call it,
um um my hosts and I'm gonna put in the I p address.
You want me to 1 68 1 That one.
And the 2nd 1 I'm gonna put it 19 to 1 68 I wonder so now,
since we're working on only two eyepiece,
if you have multiple happens,
you want to try?
Please go ahead.
No.
Safe.
Now,
this is just an empty file.
Sorry.
This is just a flat file.
And let's do my host,
and you'll see it has I P address.
Now,
instead of changing the existing script,
I am going to create a new script.
And of course,
I'm not gonna create a new script from scratch.
What?
I'm gonna do is I'm gonna just copy my pink script and I'm gonna name it Ping Script Dash
All.
So this way it will identify that this is for all multiple INEC service Multiple host.
Now the I Ping script Dash all you see,
everything here is done,
but I just have to change the description says Describable Ping I remote host,
not more host Must apple her more hosts.
Make sure you change.
This description is very important.
Okay,
now we're gonna come in,
and what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna simply,
um You know what?
Let's first get rid off this variable host.
And that started from here.
What are those?
Host.
So this is the variable and variables is what you have to specify the location off your
file.
That is slash home.
I saw slash ps ps for professional scripts.
Remember?
We did that.
And B,
what was the name re picked for the flat file?
Was it hosts?
Um,
not sure,
actually.
Let me go check.
So please make sure this location and this host vial is correct.
Otherwise,
the script was gonna complaint.
No,
I specified my host and it is home.
I have soapy hysteric My house.
Okay,
Perfect.
So now here is the location of the file that has all my multiple host.
Okay,
Perfect.
Now I wanted to use four loop for that.
Why?
Acres four loop allows you to go through the script.
Wants twice or as many times until everything is being read or everything has been
satisfied.
So if I don't specify four loop,
what will happen is it will first I pienza list and it will be done.
It's not gonna go through the second i p.
That's why we have to specify for Luke.
Four i p.
Now why I picked I p i p is just a container again.
It's just a variable.
You could just pick anything for I p in and dollar parentheses And where Yeah,
specify dollar hosts.
Okay,
now you see what I did for I p I'm putting.
I'm creating a container.
Another container I pee in and I'm catting this at sea host fall.
What is Sorry?
Not sus What?
I'm carrying this dollar Horse files.
What is dollar host?
Father?
Daughter?
Whose fault is that?
Oh,
my abs.
LPs mild.
So this is what I'm telling for I p in put everything that comes from this result cat host
Put everything in i p All right,
perfect child.
Now what else you wanted?
No do.
Because you have to specify what,
exactly?
Once you do,
four always has to have a do four do done for a while do Okay,
so four.
Ok,
now what do you want to do?
I'm gonna do is I'm gonna move this one tab,
or I'm gonna say Ping see one same thing.
And now instead,
off host I wanted to do I p because right here,
this is I p right.
This is the container.
I'm specifying it right here.
Now you're probably thinking,
Hey,
Enron,
why can't I just use the same variable?
Hmm.
That's a good question.
I don't know.
Try it.
Maybe it was,
but this is how I actually,
um,
go through my practice.
And if you want to try it,
please be my guest.
Tried?
If it works.
Perfect.
All right.
So I p okay.
Going into debt.
Not now.
Coming back to our same script.
If pound a dollar question mark equals zero then and set a host now you're king about I p I
p is put it there.
Pink pass.
I'll just keep leave it as is I p is okay.
And the same thing here I p is not so,
by the way,
this file that I am looking at it,
I will I will attach that file with this lesson.
So you have to worry about it.
You could also copy paste if you make a mistake.
Sometimes when you were writing the script many times I would say even 80% of 85% of times
you make mistakes.
I make mistakes too.
That's why I try to write it so there won't be any mistakes.
Okay,
so this is how he's gonna do again.
So hopefully you understand what I'm trying to get at this is the variable and what
variables going to do?
It's going to specify the name fire.
Okay,
Now,
for I p,
this is another variable.
And it's saying that you know what?
Go and read that file cat that fall.
And that file is that he just dollar host.
I don't know why I keep saying that.
See hoses just so used to it sitting etc host anyway.
Ok,
do Ping.
That whatever is inside of cast cat host and to go through the same scenario.
Now,
another thing.
Don't forget at the bottom.
When you have do,
what do you have to have done?
Same thing.
If you have fee,
you have to have.
Sorry if you have.
If you have to have,
See if you have do you have to have done all right?
Perfect.
Now let's run it.
That's very five.
You have it Could be do Ping.
Oh,
enter when I did 1 60 to $1.1 is okay.
And 1 90 to 1 61 to 35 is not okay.
You see how it works?
So that's how you could actually create a script that will have a multiple i p address or
multiple host name and that you want to ping.
And,
of course,
if you want to run disks script at a Cron job could try that,
but we'll cover that later as well.
So this focus on this one and try it.
And if you if you could seriously try to do it Cron job that will automatically run a
certain time,
try it.
It will work.
Good luck