script schedules and notifications.
Now we have a few scripts that Realogy rondos are useful.
Valuable script.
Now we need to schedule them.
And how do we need to schedule them?
You schedule them through the Cron job.
Cron job is a process and automated service.
Um,
in Lenox are in UNIX flavours that you could specify scripts to run at a certain time.
And then we could notify the users or administrators engineers through the email that this
script ran and they heard the out descript.
So this is something that you,
um,
probably already been doing or you might have to do when you are in corporate environment.
When you create shell script,
then you need to make it more automated.
What I mean is more automated.
Meaning you automated a script to perform certain task.
Right now,
you go one step further,
which is to schedule it so you don't have to run it yourself.
Okay,
That's a second step off.
Automation.
The third step of automation is that you once it runs it,
what he wanted to do Well,
you wanted to either have a file created or do something or you could just described Could
just notify or Cron job could just notify the system administrator.
So this is Ah,
a few steps that we will take.
We will use this.
Ah,
this lessons based on our previous created scripts.
So I log in to my Lennix machine right here,
and I am logged in as myself And which directory?
Um,
in I'm in my professional scripts directory.
And the script that I will use to schedule is ah Ping script.
Also,
when you run the script,
it actually ping Yeah,
an I p address.
That is pinky belittle.
Say okay.
If it's not thinkable will say it's not OK now you could run the script and view that
result on the screen.
Right?
But if you want to schedule,
it does it will run itself and it notify you.
You have to specify that front,
um,
in the Cron job.
So first,
make sure you have the complete path.
Um ps ping script Look.
So this is a complete path.
Copy it.
So you don't make any mistake while you are creating a Cron job.
No type craun before you type Cron type dates.
So you would know what time you want to run at this time.
It is 2031.
Um,
I will schedule it for 20 um 2034 for exam.
So if I do,
Kron Tab minus e is to edit.
So the first field off Cron and I'm sure you are familiar with it is the minute.
So I want to pick the minute 34 And the hour is 20 and the day of the month.
Arana running every day,
month of the year,
every year and day of the week every day of the week.
And now the command so hit right and it will paste.
You're so it will paste it Now how do you know it ran?
You could just output to ah script.
Um Ping,
I'll put So this is the output from the from the script that will run And the reason I'm
putting paying dash up with said this way you wouldn't know that Describe did run.
So let's save Cron 2034 deaths.
The time will run.
What time is it right now?
So we actually have to wait.
What?
One minute and now is 2033 So in one minute scribbled Rana.
So you will see.
We have,
Ah,
a file name called Output Dash Air.
So don't confuse with this one.
The file that will come in ever will be output.
Um,
was it Tab Dash?
Oh,
put,
um,
ping dash upwards.
So this is the file that was spit up my script and ah,
a friend.
Variables are specified.
Now,
as we wait for the script to run,
the next thing that I will cover is about the notification.
Now,
how do we notify?
Ah,
user through the email?
Well,
you could actually take that file that will be created,
which is paying dash output you could create.
You could take that file and send it to them.
The user,
right.
You could do that.
But then you have to cad the file and send it.
But how about we just simply,
instead of going into Ping Dash,
a profile will just specify the the name.
Oh,
sorry.
The email,
An address off the use that is going to.
So that's what that's what we will do on the second step.
So let's check again.
What time is it?
Right now it's 2034.
So the script has already ran.
Let's confirm,
and hmm.
It did not help.
Output is ping up.
Put thing,
huh?
Where did I think it's probably,
um,
putting it into my home directory.
That's probably it's a at minus.
L whom I have so hang output.
Yes.
See,
that's what if I wanted to have this output file to be in the exact same location where I
want,
where my scriptures.
Then I have to specify the full path,
the absolute path.
But since I did not specify it by default,
it will put in to the Users Home Directory,
which is home.
I have salt.
So now,
anyway,
let's go one step back.
This is my home directory.
Let's check and at the oil thing dish.
And you see it is there when I want it to one.
That one is okay and is not okay anyway.
So that's how you could schedule your scripts.
And it becomes so much easier when you actually rely on Cron tabs.
Now,
next one is the notification.
As I said,
you could cat out the file and send it over to the another Cron.
But why?
You wanted to do another cross.
So what you do is you go back to your Cron tab minus e.
And now,
instead of running it to ping output,
what you could do is you pipe it and do Male minus s for subject.
Um,
connective ity status.
This is this is going to a subject.
And where is it going?
It's going to my email,
and that's pretty much it.
So if I schedule this for,
ah time,
that is right now or two minutes from now it will run.
But it is not going to email me.
Why?
Because the email Relais server is not configured in my server.
So if you already have email configured in your Lennox machine and it is able to send out e
mails outside off your environment,
then it will work.
Definitely work.
But in my case,
it's not going to work.
Is just the example that I'm showing you This is how you couldn't notify these use to try
it at home,
try to schedule different,
um,
scripts that be already created in the previous lessons and see how it works.
You could also upto a file just to confirm it works well,
just save it and exit