how everyone in the section we're going to discuss about conditional statements,
our decision making.
So that's a very important section to understand.
In the last few lectures,
we understood about the simple Shall scream we had killed so many scripts in that describes
,
we hardly know simply put the commands on a few variables and executed on Invisible.
We got some outputs,
but those were over simple scripts.
But if we'll see some complex scripts in which we have in our different logics are there,
conditions are there.
Sloops are there,
like four loops,
while lobes the functions are there.
As for the requirement,
so in the section will understandable the condition.
Or we can say this is a base off Sal Escape.
So let's understand this important topic.
You can use the if come on toe destined condition so condition could be like I have a
script on.
I want that my script should be executed or any common should be executed.
If certain conditions exist like the shallows could may execute the backup Onley if certain
condition exists,
like the backup should be initiated on Lee.
If Sunday is there,
if it is Sunday,
so this is one condition.
If the file is existing,
make a backup otherwise print on error message on a screen to such type of conditions.
You can,
you know,
fulfill using If come on toward this condition.
It is an expression that values to a Boolean value that is to or falls.
So if a statement walks on,
you know,
20 falls.
So it is mainly a comparison off to lose that is zero and one in a shallow zero in the
gives falls.
If the condition is not satisfied,
it means the number is zero.
If you're getting number one on non zero,
it means the condition is true.
So a little over will do a lot off in a lab stations and nobody's so home.
We can,
you know,
use the if statement or we can say what this index off distant man.
So it's very simple,
like,
you know,
if on expression on Dennis statement and if I so that's is very simple,
we can see the Syntex off how to use the if statement late.
So this is one thing.
Second,
like here we have used if mouths like if specified condition is not too in that if part
than as far will be executed.
So here suppose you know I've mentioned like,
if I've Andi,
I'm looking for any file.
If this file is existing,
then you know,
make a backup else we got an output like backup is not possible because the file is missing
.
So two conditions we have used here Either it is existing or not.
If my file is existing there than this statement will be executed whatever you have
mentioned there else it will be going to this one.
That is simple.
You know the use off fells.
The next one is your if it lives else.
If I statements so it's just like a letter.
You can see that.
So to use you know,
the multiple conditions in which we have to use a lot off fells.
So here you can see the Syntex like this one.
If this is my first condition on,
we have the statements.
We have another condition here you can put and also we have another condition.
So if you have you know,
multiple conditions you can use a lift for that.
So we'll do a lab session then you can understand that if live nested one,
we can see that.
So friend there.
So for this lecture will start doing the practice.
Then you will have more confidence and more understanding about this topic.
So thanks for watching Will soon the next lecture,
but