how everyone.
So let's continue and do some more practice using if else in your script.
So my next script is very simple.
I'm going to ask for the user to enter some password on that password is going to save into
some variable on that.
Very well.
Im going toe compare with some in award or some safe password using if conditions.
If it is matches,
then I will echo that password verified else.
Password denied.
So let me,
Kate,
this escape a simple script in which I'm going to show you how we can use if else to check
the condition.
Okay,
So echo on.
Then enter the muscling Onda and I'm going to use hyphen s so that whatever the password is
you there's going to type.
It is not visible on the screen.
So that's why I have used have anus option.
Okay,
Now the user is going toe enter some passport.
That password is going to save until this variable.
So this is a name of variable.
Now I'm going to use a felt condition if my this little okay is equal to I'm giving pass
for,
like,
reading then If it is satisfied if this line is satisfied means that the out port,
after the companies and output would leave one zero for it is not satisfied.
One means the condition is too.
It is satisfied.
Then my skin will move to the next line.
That is after then.
Okay.
On here.
I can put like echo plus one verified else.
Suppose you have our enters some other passport apart from Reddit.
In that case,
it will move to the line,
which is started with else Echo bus.
What?
Denied?
If so,
that's a very simple script.
Let me come out dark.
Let me make it executable.
Okay,
so I'm going to execute this car.
It is asking for the password.
I'm going to type.
Ready?
Plus a very fight.
I'm going to type in a 12345 password.
Denied.
Again.
I'm going to type some other like anything by Sunday night.
So here again,
understand?
How have used this,
if else to compare the conditions.
Right.
So here you can see that I have used if it is comparing the entered password with a red
head.
Okay,
Now moving to the next 50.
Now this condition statements.
So in this you know people,
you will see that they have used,
you know,
multiple conditions.
And if you have multiple conditions,
then you can use a lift.
Suppose I was talking with my first sentence.
Like if on some condition are there like condition could be like anything I suppose a user
has,
you know,
enter some number and I want to check that the number is our even our zero.
So that gives our views,
you know,
multiple conditions.
So if you have,
you know,
more than one condition to satisfy or to check In that case,
you can use a lift.
So first condition here.
If it is satisfied,
then it will be done here.
It is not going to with the next one.
If it is not satisfied than it will look for the next expression.
Okay,
If it is satisfied here,
then it will print.
It will do whatever you have mentioned here again.
If it is not satisfied,
you can use another.
You know it live.
And at last you have come to We know that if you feel that now I have left on living one
condition then you can use with else.
Okay,
so here,
you can use multiple conditions.
So,
friend there so far this lecture in the next lecture,
I'm goingto Crayolas shall escape to check if the number you enter is are even on zero.
So for that,
I'm gonna be use a simple,
shallow script in which I'm going to,
you know,
use multiple conditions using if else and l f So thanks a watch.
If you have time,
please join me in the next lecture.