how everyone.
So let's continue.
So I'm going to create a shallow script to chat.
If the number enter is all even a zero.
So here are the use.
You know,
multiple conditions.
So I'm going to use if they lift else they So I'm going to play this escape.
That is good.
So what is my script like?
Come into you?
That is It's a shell is clipped to check If a number is odd even up zero I didn't to listen
time.
First of all,
I'm going to ask for the user to enter the part number and a number Onda And I'm going to
save that number into available.
My edible name is a You can give any name It is up to you know I want to check first I want
to check the enter number is zero.
Nor so for that I'm going to use a condition using If this dollar is my the name of
variable on which the user has entered The number has been saved.
Is it called Geo and I?
If this condition satisfied then simply you know type hit.
It's ah zero number your time.
Okay?
No,
I want the check.
The number has been type is you know,
even a little on.
But I just want to check first.
The number is even or not.
So how do chat So let me come on from here.
So for that I need to use the expression here Suppose user has entered number 10.
Right then B is equal to have a use expression here.
Andan expression.
I'm going to divide this number.
That is a that is 10 on did it This you know,
operator,
I'm going to use that is more jealous on to they.
So if the output off this come on is going to be zero,
it means that the user has entered a number that is even number.
Let's see Echo dollar be right.
Yeah.
If I'm going to type some other number,
it means that when you're going to divide that number with two number supposed,
the user has entered 11.
So obviously,
if you're going to divide 11 by two simple mathematics,
you're there will be some reminder they so again if I'm fighting this come on on this I
could be I'm getting one number.
It means that the number is not even so check whether the number is even but not you have
to use this expression.
So this is called Model s operate.
Every time will be used.
This is dividing that number by two on.
If it is even obviously there won't be any reminder here.
So that would put world with zero here the same I'm gonna be using my It's good as well.
Okay.
So how can use this?
So I have another condition.
I'm going to use this one A lift Here.
You can see that after a left there is a expression They asking for the condition here.
So straightforward.
I'm putting my script that his expression on a dollar A that is the variable name Will the
user has entered on this to okay on.
This is what I have to use this one.
This expression for it is equal to zero output zero.
It means that it's a even number.
Then echo.
It's an even number.
Your type.
So obviously use it has type.
Even our else echo.
It's a number.
Okay,
I'm going to execute this one.
And you know what?
I want to enter this 12.
It's a even number.
Your time I'm going toe,
enter the number zero.
It says,
You know,
nobody time.
I'm going to enter a number like 15.
It's an odd number,
you type.
So this is a very simple tell a script to check if the numbers are even on zero.
So when their cell for this lecture in the next lecture will understand more escapes.
Thanks for watching.