Hello,
everyone to this topic is Charlotte scripting So in this lecture will understand about what
is shallow scripting.
Why shall scripting on what we can achieve with chalice?
Scripting a Charlotte's crib is a file containing a city's off commands.
The shell leaves this file and carries out the commands as though they have been entered
directly on the common line.
So shells are interactive.
So what is interactive?
It means that the shells will accept comin from you.
Why keyboard and execute them So that is interactive.
How you what if you have is store a sequence of commands.
Two attacks fight and tell the shell to execute the text file instead off entering all the
commands one by one that is known as shell program or shall a script.
It can help you to automate your day to day videos dusk,
and also it will make your work easy,
efficient and fast.
So these are the benefits of shallow scripting.
So in a shallow script what older?
You know,
key words we can have.
We will have the Commons simple commands.
You can put it in a Shalit's clipped like your PWD.
Come on back.
Oh,
come on read exit on many more commands.
You can put some keyboards as well,
like you can use if house for new via loop,
you can use some bindi commands as well.
You can use,
you know,
tax processing utilities like share or cut,
grab eager up.
Exactly functions control flow statements.
So with the combination off all these,
you know,
keywords will create a shallow scrip.
And with the help of Shell's good,
we can automate our work.
In simple words,
alteration can be achieved with shallow scripting.
Let me take an example.
Suppose you know Ah,
half tensile was and I want to do the packing on all the tens of hours on our for the
patting All my cell was will be devoted.
So this is a task I need to do it.
So before starting the patching,
I need to do the revalidation off.
All the tens of us in the revalidation have to,
you know,
fire 50 commands from each of the sewers.
So these 50 commands the really important commands,
which is taking the back up off the conflagration files,
your network information,
your hard disk,
your file systems,
your half a step so obviously feel going to,
you know,
reboot any of the box so before to initiate the reboot before the mission.
The batting You need to go up revalidation catching all the commands from all the 10
soldiers for one ways to,
you know,
logging All the so was one by one on fire all your 50 commands on whatever that you all put
your getting capping in a file on putting in one safe location,
this exercise,
you have to do it on all the tensile was after that you can start your patching,
so obviously it will take,
you know,
2 to 3 hours to do this pre validation war.
We can achieve this work with the help of shallow scripting,
we can clear a script and this kid,
we can put all the commands.
And also we can,
you know,
use some,
loops so that we can initiate a script from one location that this kid will go to one
somewhere one by one and fire all the commands on what with output were getting capturing
on putting in,
putting,
putting in one location.
And then it will go to next.
So was fighting all the comments,
Andi.
And what,
without trivia getting put it in a file on,
then seven in a safe location.
So this way,
you know,
you can do this work in a very fast way,
efficient on easy.
So that is called,
you know,
smart World.
We can see that.
So we have achieved this with help off automation on this automation,
we have done with the help of shallow scripting.
So this is what we're going to learn in this entire course.
Morning.
Learning off anything is not a big task.
The big task is to how to explore the things.
So this course model will help you how to explore the things like suppose.
You know,
I have talk to you about if then else.
But how to explore this?
This is what we're going to learn in this course more so what we can achieve with a shout
with the help of,
you know,
shallow scripting.
We can do a lot of things with the shallow skip.
Like you can do pre validation that we discuss.
We can do,
you know,
monitoring off any sores.
You can do the backup.
You can find out,
you know,
water.
The processors you have on the system which is eating your system resources.
Hey,
somebody you know,
you have the box and do then boxes,
you know,
having some performance issue,
and that is basically coming in the midnight.
And at that time,
you know,
the sources are not of living.
So what you can do,
you can simply,
you know,
create a shallow script.
In the Sala script,
you can put all the,
you know,
performance related commands,
like top.
Come on on the Amistad.
Come on.
Which will be capturing,
you know,
you know the resources information.
Like what?
Its CPU utilization,
memory utilization.
You're you know,
so descript litigation.
So different commands.
We have job Vienna stabbed,
shot.
Come on.
So with the help of showers kept in,
you can create a simple Sal escape.
But all the commons on you have is cuticle that skip at a specific time.
That is midnight.
So that so that,
you know,
at that time,
this could well be a secure executed on output is saving in a file.
So next day,
when you're coming to the office,
you can simply check that file like what happened to the sour at that time war with the
resource which was,
you know,
high at that time.
So how we have achieved this simply We have kicked in the shallows kept so we'll do a lot
of things but this course Morning.
So,
friend,
that's all for this lecture will see in the next election.