how everyone.
So let's continue and do some more practice using test.
Come on.
So in the selected,
I'm going to get a simple script in which I'm going to use test,
but with multiple,
you know,
conditions,
multiple statements would be there.
So first of all,
let me tell you what.
That's good.
I'm going to get for you.
So Skip is very simple.
I'm going to,
you know,
ask the each of the A person who is going to execute the script.
Suppose I'm actually good in the script.
So at the beginning,
off the script,
it will ask you What is your it right?
And after that few conditions are there my first condition?
First condition.
Is that supposed The age is less than 20.
So the person who is not eligible for you know this job on what they were like Some job is
there and I want to check the you know,
you know the age criteria for that.
So I mentioned that if you have applied for the job and your age is less than 20 so if
you're it is,
you know,
less than 20 oh,
greater than 50.
You are not eligible you're out of the ridge out of the age.
So here I've used off means either of the conditions.
Either you may be less than 20 or you may be more than 50.
If any of the condition is satisfied,
you are not eligible.
So here I'm using.
Or what means you have to use the symbol pipe sign.
So pipe sign double means more.
So this is my you know,
first condition,
second condition also I'm going to put like you are.
You're is great of them 20 and less than 30.
So both the conditions have been satisfied.
Support?
I'm typing.
My age is 25 so 25 is greater than 20.
Yes,
25 was less than 30 years.
So both the conditions are satisfying If both the conditions are satisfying that I'm saying
that ico like whatever you are in the age of twenties,
right here at the top This one here I've used this army's other of any of the condition
right?
Either you are less than 20 or maybe get other than 50.
Either of any condition is satisfied.
Then you are not eligible for them.
But here both the conditions would be satisfied if you're looking for both the conditions
that you have to use,
December right.
Third condition is my this one gooder than 30 on did less than 40.
Then I can type like you're in the thirties.
I four condition I can put like your age should be in a greater than 40 on.
It should be less than 50 that I could take like you are in the aid off,
you know,
forties.
So I'm going to play this script here.
Okay,
so first of all,
I'm going to ask for the user,
Please and tell you get a gauge.
I get on read with age.
Now my first condition.
If on this dollar it I get on the if it is less than 20 Okay,
So this is my one condition on or I'm using all here or but it is,
you know,
get it over then.
Today,
on day and age is greater than 50.
So either of the condition is satisfied.
Then go.
Sorry.
Yeah,
Out of the age you are not eligible.
Whatever you want to die even type here now my second condition I'm only used fear this
dollar age is good of them 20.
And also it should be less than should be.
You know,
Unless that 30 so good to them don't means 2122 23 24 25 26 27 28 29.
So if you are in the aid off from 21 to 29 that this condition is satisfying here.
Okay,
then I cook.
I can type like you are in the ego twenties.
They so like this with my next condition.
Is this one.
This is quite a break.
It this is my dollar is is better than 30.
On this it is less than 40.
So means you would be the your urine.
The Edo twenties thirties.
I'm putting one more condition here,
so this condition is get to them.
Suppose you have type 44 right?
So 44 satisfying in this year.
Because 44 is greater than 40 on.
But it is also,
you know,
unless them 50 then echo.
You are in Edo forties,
right?
I can close it now.
You can put one more condition.
You can put else as well at the last.
Let's make it executable.
I believe everything is fine with this group.
And it I'm putting this one 19.
Sorry.
You are out of range.
I'm going to put 56.
So you are out of range and the first line?
The condition is satisfied.
I'm going to put this 24 missing.
Something is missing.
Next.
See what is missing here?
Test.
That is good.
If you are having some,
you know,
mistakes so that you can you know,
Lund more here.
So let's see.
What's the mistake?
Me half that if this one is satisfied,
they live.
This is great with them.
Okay,
that is I think it's t e they This is There's this last game,
don't you?
Everything seems friends.
Tell me,
what's the issue here?
Okay,
let's do one thing.
Let's run this in a day,
but more so that we'll understand where we have this.
So how do done it?
I'm just putting Exhale.
Okay.
Desk this one.
Please enter your eight.
I'm putting this 1 25 No missing.
They're saying there's some issue with the line Number seven get hyphen.
And this is a test one.
This one.
So my line number seven in this one.
So they're saying that something is missing in this line.
So what is missing?
I think the spaces here.
OK,
I got really have issue.
So the issue is that we have not given the proper space here.
Okay.
On way have to very much,
you know,
careful while getting his groups Okay.
Let me again then it That is one and a damn putting this one.
It is still like burning in the,
you know.
Okay,
equal.
You are in the age of twenties.
You are in the age of notice.
Type incorrectly.
Okay,
let me.
You know.
Added this.
Let me remove this one day,
but more on going to run this one.
And I am putting 26.
You are in the age of twenties.
I'm going to put my age 34.
You are a native studies.
I'm going to put my age 40.
You were in the age of forties.
If I'm going to put this 1 56 you're out of the range.
So friends,
I believe you understood what I am trying to,
you know,
kind of a with this a script on Did I'm requesting you to please,
create the same escape.
You know you can clearly or your own logic as well.
Whatever coming in your mind,
just try to create yourself and see whether you're getting the desired output on and they
on a still.
If you have any confusion while reading the scripts,
you can,
you know,
put your question in the cushion.
Answer for American pathetically to me as well.
So thanks for watching.
We'll see in the next lecture,
but by