how everyone in this lecture will understand about the exit status off.
Come on.
That's really a very important topic to understand.
Every Lennox or UNIX come on executed by the shallow script or by a user has an exit.
The status in simple words.
Suppose I have logged in tow Atlantic system and I have fired at come on,
like up time.
Or did come on fire.
So in Brazil,
I will get some output.
Because did is a you know,
come on,
which is existing on your system up time is a,
you know,
useful.
Come on,
which is a valid come on.
So if you fire any come on individual get a proper output without any error,
It means that that is the exact status which is due If you're comin Waas successful without
any error,
you will have the devastated zero.
But suppose if you have fired come on which is not existing at all On a system like you
have simply fired a B c.
D.
It was really is not existing on Atlantic system.
It is not a come on.
So in that case you will get some better.
Like this Command is not existed this come on.
Not farm.
So if you have,
you know,
got some other welfare in the common.
It means you will have the exhibit staters a number A non zero.
You're exit.
The status would be a non zero for that case when the common was not unsuccessfully on that
is from number 1 to 255 When means that the common was a failure,
Right?
So that is a simple idea about that.
The status and we'll have a love station as well.
So you need to use a particular shall variable called that.
Is this one here?
You can see that.
That is,
you know,
dollar question.
Mark toe,
get exited.
Staters off the previously executed Come on.
Right.
So dubrin,
we have to fire this dollar.
Kashima used the echo comma or print off.
Come on.
So here we have some example This is the common Echo Dollar question.
Not some would have fired did come on under.
Come on.
And after that I can fire this print,
exit the status so I will get some output.
So first we have to fire this.
Come on,
debt.
So my command has done successfully on I want to check the status exited status.
Then you have to five this.
Come on.
If my previous come on like dead Come on,
has done successfully.
Then I will have the existing zero.
Suppose here.
I have fire this command which is not a valid command.
And after that they filed five this eco dollar question mark I will get some known dealer
number.
So let me move towards my this box Mannix box on.
We'll show you something here.
Suppose I am finding dead.
Come on,
I'm getting some output So let's see what it's like The status.
So to know the exhibit Staters off a previous command which have fired after simple fire
This Come on So this tells you number It means that the previous command that you have
fired that is dead common Waas run successfully without any error.
Somewhat I'm fighting this.
Come on.
So this is not existing at all.
I'm getting some better.
Like did want to take him on,
not found so I just want to know the exit district is off My previous Come on,
I need to find this here.
You can see that I am getting unknown deal number and illustrators.
That means the command was a failure.
The previous commanded to have fire or some failure.
All right,
so this way you can check any you know,
any command that you have fire was successful or not on that is really very useful.
You know,
when you clearly you know,
shallow scrape so many times you will see that in a shallow script.
We're checking by the Destatis core.
They simply can find this It is he resolved.
I just want to check this file is not Is existing are not so I'm getting zero.
Suppose I'm searching for any file this one like a BCG.
I just want to check So it is not existing there.
So if I am fighting this one,
I'm getting some non number.
So if I'm checking in a you know,
shallow script that my shallow,
scripted checking is a file is checking for the file.
I do.
If I'm getting I'm using simple this.
Come on.
Like Ellis on.
If the file is not existed there,
obviously I'm getting some error.
And it means that devastated would be some known dealer number.
So with this non zero number,
I can you know,
judge that the file is not existing at all.
Right?
So,
friend,
that's all for this lecture.
In the next election,
I'm going to use,
you know,
I'm going to kill the shallow script in the Sala script.
I'm going to use exact status.
So thanks for watching and will soon The next lecture,
but by