how everyone in this lecture will understand about the nomadic comparison.
So in the last few letters,
we understood about many Commons like desk.
Come on,
if else come on and many more commands.
So while using these commands many times,
we have to do the nomadic comparison.
So to do that,
no matter cos.
And we have to use different operators.
So this lecture will see what are those operators which can be used to do the nomadic
comparison.
So let's see nomadic comparison using the falling operators.
So these air operators you have used to do the nomadic comparison that is equal toe greater
than and called So that is d get her,
then Only that is DT alleys last night and he called to lt and Annie.
That is less than and that is not equal to that is any.
So I've created a simple script in which I have used all those operators.
So it's a very simple a scrip.
In the starting,
you can see that it is asking,
please under your age.
Obviously you're going toe under your is in some nomadic number.
It's an interior light 25 25 40 right,
so no matter comparison.
That is a number only.
So here you can see that.
Suppose you have enter that I'm a 10 year old.
You are going.
You have enter number 10.
Now let's see if test dollar eight.
Right.
So here Suppose you have entered attempts of 10 is going to save into this variable name
That is age.
Now in this line,
it is going to compare this one.
Here it is type headed with 10 is less than on equal to 13.
My condition has been satisfied here.
Then it will immediately echo that you are a child.
Suppose I have entered that I'm a 15 year old.
So what will happen here?
It will desk like 15 is less than or recorded.
13 condition is not satisfied here.
So it will move towards the next statement.
This one.
So this is Tim and I've used live.
And here you can see that I have used this one.
That is 1% twice time.
So my this condition on this condition we have to condition in this line.
So both the conditions should be satisfied then only it is going to tie that you are a teen
age.
Suppose I have type 15.
Let's see,
15 is greater than or recorded Harding?
Yes,
15 years less than on equal to hearing years.
My condition has been satisfied.
Here it is going to type that you are a teen age.
Suppose you have type 25 number So 25 number that is greater than 30 years.
25 number is last than any cold waiting.
No,
it is not satisfying here.
So it will move towards the next condition next statement.
So this 25 is greater than getting Yes,
25 is less than and equal to 40.
My condition has been satisfied.
It is going to tie that you are so this way you can do the pneumatic comparison.
So these air operators you have to use to make sure you keep in your mind that these
operators we have to do for the nomadic comparison.
So moving to the next property that is father a string comparison.
It stings some,
you know,
letter some war.
This team comparisons can be done using test if else left commands.
So here we have some,
you know,
examples And Syntex.
The strings are equal.
So you have to use this operator is equality.
Single time is toasting one called twisting toe.
These things are not equal.
So here this is a symbol for that exclamation is involved.
It is that my sting one is not equal to string Toe the land of the sting is zero.
What does it mean?
Suppose I have asked that Skip that please under your name on you have not entered anything
you have just simply press enter.
So how would I know that the user has not pressed anything while the salad scream are you?
This is stream hyphen,
dead and history.
So it will come to know that Oh,
you have no time Anything So we can respond back that if user if anybody who's executing
the script and if they have no time anything,
it will immediately reply back that you have to type something so you have to use hyphen
develops way have a lot of other options as well.
So here,
after the simple script here for the fitting comparison Now it is asking toe under your
name.
So obviously you're going toe under your name.
It's a string on Lee was my name is Shaker so I'm going to type Chicana Suchai Keita It's
not a nomadic.
It says thing.
So it is going to save and Oh,
this variable the name off my variable His name now Echo test.
This variable is equality,
John.
So here you can see that I used single time is equal to So this is what I want to tell you
.
What are the operators we have?
The use further ist in comparison so dissatisfied him.
Suppose I have time,
John.
Only then you are selected for this job,
right?
Suppose have time like some other name.
Like sugar So let's see So she could is not satisfied here,
so it will move to the next line They live so here we have to condition first condition
that shakers should not be called John.
Yes,
that is satisfying One more condition.
It should not be an empty as well.
Right?
I used this sign.
It means that it should not be on empty as well.
I have type something So my condition is satisfying here then.
Sorry.
You are more selective.
Suppose you have not time.
Anything you have pressed enter Only then it is coming to this condition.
Suppose our press enter and I'm checking this here and remains.
This one is not equal to John.
This has been certified here.
Suppose I have press,
enter only and press.
So I'm just checking with this so empty is not equal to join.
This has been 70.
This has been satisfied.
But I have to,
you know,
check for this condition as well.
It is saying that it should not be an empty.
So this this condition is not satisfying here.
So it will be coming here it live.
It should not be an empty please.
Under your name cannot be except on empty name.
So there's a simple,
you know,
escape in which I have tried to show you how to do the distinct comparison So made motive
off the selected is to understand the operators.
That is for your string comparison This one This one on this one.
Hyphen!
Jared!
Exclamation!
All those things!
So friend there.
So for the selected banks in the next lecture will show you what are the you know,
file attributes comparison.
So thanks for watching.
If you have time,
please join with the next lecture