how everyone in this lecture will understand about the best shell born against him.
That's the full form off bash.
It's a free UNIX el that can be used in place off the bone shell bash is the shell or come
on language interpreter for Atlantic's operating system.
And it is also the before Lennox's best was written for the Genome Project by Brand Fox.
So in simple words,
if a user wants to talk to the Atlantic's colonel,
did it cross a medium so that medium is your show?
And we have a different type of shells,
the most common and important on before one is your best shot.
So whatever the shallow scripting we're going to learn in this entire course model that is
based on the best shell we do have other you know,
shall as well,
like you gone shell,
she shell and E Cell has its own,
you know,
importance on properties.
The best is largely compatible with asset and incorporates useful features from the
conscious and see sell.
It offers functional improvements over asset for both programming and interactive use,
so there's a basic idea about the best shell.
So friend,
that's all for this lecture in the next lecture,
we'll understand about the logging.
Like if I have a user on the user wants to,
you know,
connect to the box.
So what does it require?
It requires credentials on.
Once the user will supply the credentials,
he or she will get the logging shower or its home directory.
So what's the user will belonging to the box?
What are the different?
You know,
profile.
The startup scripts is going to execute.
So this is what we're going to learn in the next election.
So thanks for watching.
We'll soon the next lecture.