tap completion and up arrow key In this lesson,
we will learn how When we run the tab button on your keyboard,
how can it completes your directory or your command that you're trying to run and how the
up arrow key works and how returns you last round command hitting tab key completes
available commands,
files or directories such as when you running change.
Meyer mod this command,
it has o.
D at the end as well.
So if you just type C h M and hit Tab,
it completes the command for you the same way when you do ls Space Jay and a tab,
it will list all the files that starts with J.
Then you have CD D s.
So if you do see d d as headed tab,
it will bring you any all the directories that matches the 1st 3 letters uppercase de es.
So basically,
the tab makes ah typing a lot easier and Lennox,
so you don't have to run the whole long commands again and again,
you could just simply tab if you know the command and it auto completes it for you.
This is very useful feature and Lennox I'm telling you,
this is very useful.
Once you're gonna become a riel export in Lennox,
you're gonna be using this tab button almost every day.
And every time you logged into Lennox Machine,
then we have another cool feature off.
Lennox is heading the up arrow key.
What that does is every time you hit up arrow key,
it will bring you the last ran command on your Linux terminal.
Isn't that cool?
It is cool because you don't have to run the command again and again and again.
So you just hit up a rocky and boom and hit Enter and we'll run that last comment.
So let's see how these Katou,
um,
tab and a park He works in our Lennox machine.
Let's clear the screen.
Um,
so the first command I want sure use.
Let's say if you have C h m and more deep,
this is the commands of what if I just take out CH OD and just right now hit tab.
It completes that command for me.
But if I just do see it and hit tab twice now,
it will give you all the commands you see that starts with C H Now,
you know,
there are many other different commands that start with C.
H.
And you could try different commands to see as long as you know about the command.
So don't run in command that you really don't know.
Or you I would recommend you run man command on that before you running it.
So another way we could check our tab is if you wanted to do ls And I want to do Ah,
J.
I wanted to list all the father has Jerry and I will have tapped.
There you go see it.
Auto completes my jerry.
Why did that?
Because most likely,
I only have Jay fall starting with just one file,
which is this is the one J Let's say they are to files that starts with three files.
Actually,
that starts with L,
lex,
Lisa and Lois.
And let's see what happens when I do ls and do l and hit tab twice.
It gave me all three files that starts with l.
Isn't that cool?
You don't have to actually go into the directory.
Full do ls minus.
L look for your father.
As long as you remember the first letter and you hit tab.
It will give you everything that starts with it.
Same way we'll do ls minus.
L and let's say for want to do desktop.
I wanted to see the into desktop,
etc.
There is this,
um,
folder we have in our home director desktop.
Right.
We could do CD this de es Kate s top type.
The whole thing Get enter ongoing.
Let's go one step back again.
Or we could just do CD desk and hit tab and it auto completes it for you and you hit enter
.
Isn't that cool?
Will save you a lot of time.
I love this this feature off Lenox,
and I'm sure you're gonna love it too.
Now,
the 2nd 1 what I was talking about is the up arrow key.
So if you hit upper key right now on your desktop,
you'll see it will return the last command that we ran.
If you hit it again,
it will keep bringing all the commands that we ran in the sequential order seats.
So far,
we have ran so many commands and it's bringing everything.
So now if you type the lower case,
the down key,
it will bring you back to all the commands that you were last friends.
Now we didn't run any command.
Um,
after CD desktop,
if we wanna go back again.
Up arrow key,
desktop leg.
So now,
um,
let's say I want to do this m I want to do so.
Um Ah,
Let's see.
What is,
um,
Ellis?
And what is pwd and clear?
And one more command.
We will run.
Let's say date Date is another commander will cover later on.
And so you're on it.
It will give you the date off your system.
So now,
um,
you ran a few commands 45 commands.
Now,
instead of typing all those commands,
you could run.
You could up arrow key.
One time,
two times,
three times,
four times five times.
And it is bringing all the commands you ran.
So,
guys,
this is what it is all about.
The up arrow key and tap key.
I'm telling you,
this is gonna make things so much easier once you're gonna become expert at the end of this
course.
All right?
I hope you really like this one.
And I really want you to practice this tab and a perky again and again,
again.
So you will know how these both features work.