how everyone So in this,
like tell will understand about the log in.
Now we have the shell we understood about the Shadow.
Now the next party,
the users.
Now,
if he harbor land X box.
Obviously there will be a lot off users who is going to long that box.
Suppose I have a box on that is a production box on some dollars is an application is
running on that box so there would be in a few users that belongs to,
you know,
application team.
And also there would be some users that is,
from the database team on future users from your units.
All Annex Team backup team is tourist to him.
Who is going to manage the entire server infrastructure?
Suppose a normal user like Devi user who wants to in a long into the box.
He has to supply some cutting share,
so allocating the user we also create.
It's possible as well,
so user needs to supply the user name and the passport,
and after that,
users would look into the box on by before the user will always go to the home dedic two of
the user.
So let's understand.
Ah,
home directory,
also called a log in directory and in the directory online.
Next likes operating systems that solved at the repository for users,
personal files,
directories and programs.
It is also directly that a user is forced in after logging into the system.
So that is rest home.
Suppose I have a user,
Sam,
when Sam is going too long into the box,
so by before it will be going into slash home and that we have for the subdirectory that
it's Sam.
So all the,
you know,
users home directories would be created inside Celeste Holm by deformed.
You can care some,
you know,
other part as well.
But by the fall is your slash for Ah,
home directories kitted automatically for every ordinary user in the,
you know Celeste Holm as tender sub directly for the rude attitude that this list.
So for road users,
the home directories less rude.
Only apart from that other users,
their home directly would be in slash home in that we have the subdirectory that is with
the same name as the user name.
It is Sam over this John.
So it will re slash home slash John,
Apart from having ah home director toe create and store files.
Users need an environment that gives them access to the tools and resources.
When a user log in to a system,
the users work environment is deter mined by in this location files.
These initialization files are defined by the use of this terrible script shell which can
very depending on the release,
the default initialization files in your home directories enable you to customize your
working environment.
So what does it mean?
It means that you know,
when I use a log in to the system so But before you know different initially in size and
files will be executed toe customize their,
you know,
environment.
So here,
we need to understand if you file So this is a file this the 1st 1 that it's less disease
less profile.
This is system white file that a system administrator,
man Danes.
So this file can be,
you know,
modified by a good user only on its ah,
system wide.
Fine.
We can see that this vile defines task that the shell execute for every user who logs in.
So if you're going to put anything on that file so that would be applicable for all the
users.
Suppose I have 50 users in my box?
I want something for all the users that I have to put in this file like I want that
whenever the user log in,
they will get some message like some warning message or welcome toe.
You know this environment this is a critical.
So where you want.
Whenever I use a lot sin,
they will get some message on.
That is for all the users.
Then this is the file.
It's a system wide on.
It is applicable for all the users who log into that box destruction in the file.
Usually second cell variables such as party,
user and host name.
So you will see different,
different and please.
But the main meaning off this filers that if you want to,
you know,
apply something for our entire users in a system that you have to look for this file.
No,
there's another file that is dark bash profile.
So these file that is doctor profile or dot RC and dart lagarde file.
So these files these are the confrontation files you will find in the inside the user's
home directory.
Every users has its own in isolation file.
Suppose I have a stand user So Sam User has its own bash file own RC file.
Best underscore ossified own Lord file.
If I were John User so John User would be having its own you know,
this file profile file,
RC file and longer file.
So don't bet Bashar see profile is a confrontation file for configuring user environment.
The users can modify the default settings and at any extra quantification so we'll have a
lab station is also nobody's.
So there's another file that is dot best ourselves a shallow script vigilance every time a
user opens a new shell.
So when a user log in so you will see that the first file that will be executed If you have
put something in that file,
it will be executed on,
then this file will be executed on.
If we'll go inside to this file,
you will see that this file calls you this file that is best underscore R c.
So it will be executed by this file on then.
This file is already executing on this is the longer form.
When you let go from the system,
your dot best underscored lago file will be executed now.
One more thing dot Best profile is executed for logging shells while dot bash our seas
executed for interactive logging Non log in shells.
So what does it mean?
It means that suppose you know there is a user,
Sam Sam is going toe to toe any of the server.
So that is the logging shell.
They will get some log in shell.
So at that time,
what will happen?
All your system Why file will be executed?
That is your slash city profile will be executed on Apart from there,
you know,
it's in this latest and file will be also executive that is dot best RC and dot best
profile will also executed.
But if you are already,
you know,
taken discretion you have taken,
You know,
your log in session on from that session.
if you're going to,
you know,
simple fire the best common.
So that would be a non logging shell.
So in that case,
you will find that on Lee.
This is executed.
That is taught Boesch RC.
So when you're logged in type user name and password by counsel at the sitting at the
system or remotely.
Why,
Asset doctor?
So at that time,
you'll find that dot that profile is executed to configure yourself before the
initialization.
Come on.
But if you have already logged into your system,
it means that if you have only taken log into the system and open a new 10 minute like
extra,
so that gives a new best.
Shelly will get they.
But at that time on this five millions of dot bashar see So dog best RC they executed
before the window.
Common problem So dark Best arses also run When you start a new best instance like if you
fire this coming so nobody's I can understand that that is little bit,
you know,
take it for you on confusing so resolute is tryingto tell the difference between dot bash
profile.
In this we'll have a live fish in as well.
So in the last session I will be,
you know,
telling you and in detail so that you can understand the difference.
So when did so for this lecture?
Well,
it started Lab session on will understand more on that.
So thanks for watching will soon The next victim