system utility commands.
These are very basic commands,
um,
that are being used in Lenox environment.
Some off Those commands are just like and Windows.
We have time.
You have a calendar.
Now Windows is a qui environment.
You could view those time and calculators and stuff like that by going to the accessories,
but in Lenox,
it's not possible.
So so that's why they are commands that are being built to tell you to the date.
The up time information.
The host name the You name the about the operating system,
which means where the commands are located.
Their calculators Sorry,
the calendar and the B C is binary calculators.
Now let's look at our Lennox machine and run these commands one by one Lennox machine.
When you logged into the going to the council,
you'll see the time here.
You also have the option to go into the applications and pull up a calendar,
and you see all information that are automatically viewed.
Um Vidal running any command.
But what if you are logging in through the party or the terminal client?
And as I said before 98% of the time,
you will be logging in to the party client to the terminal where you're not gonna be able
to see all those qui environment.
So let's look at the view through the party again.
We will put in our I P addresses 1 90 to 1 68 $56.1 a one and I remembered by now.
And if you don't,
you just simply go back to your consul and type.
If config enter and the top right here,
this is the I P address.
You punching that I p address right hair and click on open terminal A little pin up your
log in as yourself put in the past and you are locked in.
Once you clear the screen and you will see here there is nothing but the black terminal.
So and you wanted to run when you wanted to find out.
What time is it or what dated it?
It is just type date.
Tell you.
Today is Tuesday,
March 13th the time and the seconds and Eastern daylight saving time and the year.
So that's what the date command is used for.
It's very simple,
and sometimes that they commend is used to combine with the script.
So script will wake up checks the date and it will run.
Certain scripts will cover that in our scripting session.
Ah,
the next one is up.
Time up.
Time simply tells you along Been the system up for and how Maney users have been logged
into the system and the load average the next one.
It tells us about the host name.
Uh,
right here the host name.
Let's move this little to the side.
First name.
We could go back to our council.
They could do the coast name and you'll see this is the host name off our links machine.
And host name is one of the important command that I would recommend you to run every time
you log into the system shoe.
So you would know you are not logging in to the wrong system and you're not running very
critical commands on the wrong system.
Clear the screen.
The next one we have you name and you type you name.
It would tell you it's a little machine again.
The Lennox machine.
You do need to run this command because sometimes in an environmentally have Lennox you
have Solaris.
You have X many different links uh,
UNIX flavours.
So it's good to run your name if you want to know more details about you.
Name you type you name minus a Ever give you a lot more detail than just let me give you
the host named the kernel version the time it was built and other architecture information
.
The next command we need to learn is which Which command tells you the location off your
command that you run.
Let's say you run the command PWD right?
Andi tells you that the command is telling you which director you are in.
So where is that command located?
Of course.
Every command is a file itself and is located located somewhere to find out your type which
pwd And it tells you this command PWD is located and user Ben P W d.
If you want to know more attributes about this command,
you're on ls minus l user been pwd and you will see right here.
This is the script.
Actually,
the command itself is a script.
The script itself is a text file that has been written by developers and it tells you right
here it is owned by route and the group is owned by a route and that these are the
permissions off this file.
Everybody has the right to execute it.
If I take this bit out than I cannot run or nobody else can run this command.
So this is what which command does?
Let's clear this out.
If you want to know where is date command located it.
Command is also located,
and use have been date.
So as you can see,
most of the commands are located in user.
Been,
you do ls minus l.
And you see whole bunch off commands.
If you want to view one page at a time,
you could do more.
And you could see all these commands that we have there.
A bunch of commands that Lennox has.
What if I wanted to know how many total commands are in lyrics?
Very simple.
You do?
Ls minus l.
And if you remember you,
Piper,
you do board count minus tell.
This would gives me the total number of all these lines.
That coming up is telling me there are 597 commands that are inside off this next machine.
Moving on.
Um what if I wanted to know the calendar.
If I just typed Cal,
it was Give me the calendar off this month and this year.
Ah,
what if I wanted to know the month when I was born?
Let's say,
for for training of Do Cal September 18 1977 salt type Sept.
99 start September which is the month 1977 and it will give me.
I could look at its Sept 18 Waas Sunday so you could type any a month followed by the
calendar.
If you just wanted to know all the months in the year 2016.
So you just have Cal to down 60 and I'll give you all those months,
uh,
starting with,
of course,
January ending in December.
That's what the cow of command is used for.
Next Commander,
you have as clear in this B.
C.
B.
C stands for binary calculator.
If you want to do the calculation,
of course,
you could go in here and bring the calculator,
but you don't want to bring the country and going more.
You are in terminal mode,
so you want to use a calculator than what you do.
You type again.
BC it enter No if you wanted to,
Plus to enter and give you four.
What it 2 56 times.
Greed 21.
That's the answer.
So this is this the basic calculator You could do division,
multiplication,
anything that you want.
If you want to quit out if it just type,
quit and you will be at If it's that these air a fuse system utility commands,
Um,
and you could run that these are fun commands.
Come up with the different options.
Enough great,
of course,
to look at the options you could do man on every command and run with few.