Let's go over the raid.
What exactly a raid is?
A raid stands for redundant array off independent disks or sometimes all often referred to
as inexpensive disk and raid.
Why do we need raid?
Well,
to create a redundancy,
meaning if one disc dies,
you have another desk,
right?
You don't want to lose your data if one the fun of your primary disguise.
So that's the primary reason we have raid.
And there are different type of rates.
The main ones that you will cover in this lessons are three rates raid 01 and five.
And how do they work?
Let's go over them.
In raid zero,
you have one disc.
That is,
let's say,
five kick.
You add another disc that becomes 10 gig.
So you put them together and that five plus five becomes 10.
Gig,
right.
Perfect.
So you are writing to both disc one.
And here,
when they're its going across,
is faster,
of course.
But what happens if you lose one disc?
Well,
you're out of luck.
Why?
Because you have lost all your data.
So there is most of the time.
Raid zero is used for,
um,
like data warehousing or backups that you really,
really gonna use.
So things like that.
So you do need to add a couple of disk physical disk together to make one big disk.
That's how rate want.
Zero is mostly used.
Let's talk about raid one that will eliminate the disadvantage of raid zero where we lose
one disk and then you're out of luck.
In raid one,
you have one disk,
and then you have another desk.
But you mirrored them together.
Meaning,
if you have five gig off space on one,
you have to have five.
Give another one.
But that does not mean you have.
You're gonna have 10 get together because you're not adding them together you have
mirroring,
mirroring them together.
So if you lose one desk,
that's fine.
You still get the get your data from the other disk.
But there is another disadvantages to raid one,
and that is slow.
There it is slow because it has to,
um,
replicate everything from one days to another so that some sometime gets are slow readings
,
little rights,
then to solve.
All these problems are on zero and one.
What do we do then?
01 has,
uh,
uh we have arrested lose date as your raid one.
We have slow reading,
right.
So we come up with Raid five in raid five.
You have one disk,
right?
Then you have another disc.
But this time you don't just add to it.
You actually copy everything to a 2nd 1 as well.
But in raid five,
you have to have three or more disks.
Why?
Because the way the way rate fireworks is,
it will write to the first disc.
And it will put some information about that data to the second disc.
It will write to the second this,
and it will put some off that information that it's has written to the third disc.
And it goes around like a round robin like that.
So,
in case you lose one desk doesn't matter if it's the 1st 2nd 3rd you will have the
information off the lost data on one of the disk that you still have.
That's how you create rate five.
But in this case,
you're not gonna have,
like,
555 15 because you have to write some off the desk information.
That's parity to some other desk as well.
So they say you could retrieve that information.
So in order to put that information somewhere,
it needs to reserve that space for it.
And that's why we get out of it,
like 12 with their team gig of space.
So that's how raid works.
And the reason I I am covering raid.
And this training is because that's one of the where basic questions often been asked
during interviews and as a system administrator.
When you do become a system administrator in Lenox Environment,
you will have to create raid at a hardware level.
When you have a silver coming into your corporate environment,
you would have to configure a rate.
And the difference between the primary difference between grade and L V.
M is that raid is mostly configured on the physical system,
physical servers and sorry,
not physical physical disks,
whereas L.
V.
M is mostly configured on a virtual or logical disks.
So that's a primary difference.
So please remember it.
If you want to learn more about other rates,
I would encourage you to go online and find out about other rates