how everyone.
So let's continue.
So in the last effectively understood about,
you know differently now in installation files that we have in user's home directory.
So these are the important files we have dot bash,
profile.
So I have put cement in that file in the last you can see that I have some useful message
like,
this is my box.
And I want that when this user John log in to the boss,
he will get this massive these time.
But this is only for the John User.
If some other users going to look into this box,
he or she will not get this message.
If you want for all the users that you have to put the same entry in the ABC profile No,
I'm coming to the point.
This one the difference between your dog bash profile on this one dot Boesch RC so dot best
profile is executed for logging cell andare Boesch arses executed for interactive non
logging shells.
So what does it mean?
So here,
if you'll see that I have locked into the box as a user,
John So I have run into the box I got you know,
let me come on from here.
This one.
So you will see that when I logged into the box.
So this is Collier blogging.
Shall I got some logging shell?
This is the best shell I've got on.
But this is the process I d.
So when you look into the box when he supplied the user name and prosper So in that case,
you know you will get along in show on all your profiles will be executed.
But some would you know,
I have,
you know,
already logged into the box and open a new terminal.
So that would be your non log in shell.
So in that case,
on Lee ah file which will be executed,
that is a dark best RC.
Not other files will be executed.
So here you can see that I'm in this.
I have got this best profile,
right?
So if I want to check the process i e.
It is already there.
You can fire this command as well.
They No,
I'm going to fire this.
Come on.
So what will happen if I'm going to fire this?
Come on,
I will get it Another Siachin another shall.
I will get right that would be,
you know,
my interactive but non log insurance.
They this is inducted,
but non Long shell You'll see that I again I've got a new shim.
So if I'm fighting this come on,
you'll see that a new process i d.
So I believe it was 5637 Now I have got 5916 So this session is already hit.
If you will see in the system,
you'll see this session is already there.
But I have taken,
you know,
another not interactive logging shell Interactive normal again.
Shell No,
when you get a,
you know,
non long and shell.
So at that time only you know dot best R C profile will be executed.
You will see that in this home in this file we have this file also and that finally we have
some empty cell.
So there.
But when I fired this common been bashed again,
I'm going to get a new shell.
This file has not executed.
You know I did.
This fall has not exhibited.
That's why I didn't get this message.
So which fight has been as good?
Onley this Bashar see So let's see what all the things that you have So here again.
See that in Bashar See,
we have this message I want to put one more message like Hello again I'm going to take a
new you know best So if it is that you know non logging shell then on li dot Bashar see
escaped will be executed Not any other escape.
All right,
so this is what they want toe say And that is the basic different between your dot best
profile and your dot Peshawar.
See?
So when their soul for this lecture hope you have got some idea thanks with you in the next
election.