the next Colonel.
Do you know there is a kernel in every Lennox distribution or UNIX distribution?
What,
exactly a colonel is?
It actually interfaces between your hardware and your software.
So let's look at this diagram.
Here,
you will see you have at the bottom is the hardware and what others?
Hardware hardware is like CPU memory,
hard disk and any,
um,
outside hardware peripheral devices.
Then you have Colonel.
A kernel is a program that is stored inside off your operating system.
It's like a program,
a command that keeps on running.
And what it does is it takes the commands from shell and shell.
What is a shell shell?
Is anything like a gooey Davey having windows or a gui in Lennox?
Or if you don't have going Lennox,
we have terminal that runs bash shell or sea shell,
which will cover later on.
So when we are in that bash of seashell terminal environment,
the execute commands.
The commands are being forwarded to a colonel,
and it's kernels responsibility to talk to the hardware that's inside off your computer,
and then you on top of that,
you have a browser,
send mail,
all the application that we're only calculator,
calendar office or any limits related applications.
And,
of course,
on top of that is are the users and that is you.
So Shell and Colonel together,
that's offer built together in one package,
and that is called operating system.
And that operating system is any operating system like Lennox,
UNIX,
Mac or Windows.
Every operating system has that little program that actually talks to your hardware and
anything that is a shell,
which is written in C programming languages.
Well,
that shell or that those applications are actually the software.
So this is what the real colonel means,
and we really need a colonel in any operating system to talkto our hardware.