With the last module, we took a major step forward because whilst still a lot of useful things like working
with the database, authentication and so on are missing, we now have the general pattern set
and you should have a general understanding of how a node and node express application works, how the
flow is, how you connect your different pieces and which part of your code plays which role.
So therefore this was a crucial part
and now we're going to work a bit on the course project and therefore we'll practice what you learned.
We'll add a couple of new views and we'll try to move this a bit further
in the direction
of a more realistic online shop.
Now one important note, this module is completely optional,
you can of course skip it and simply download the finished code which we'll add to this module at the end
of this module or in the first lecture of the next module.
So if you're not interested in practicing this and adding all these new views and controllers and you
simply want to learn the next concept, you can skip ahead,
you can skip this module or fast forward through it
otherwise
let's dive in and let's continue working on our course project.