In the last module, we continued working on our application
but now we need the ability to pass some dynamic data through our routes.
We want to be able to encode some information in our url so that we can for example pass a product
ID as part of the url. In this module, you will learn how you can do that, how you can actually submit
or send data
through the url and when you would not do that and put it into the request body instead and we'll also
continue working on our models, to be precise you will learn about how to pass route params, route parameters
and how to use query parameters,
both important things that the express router supports.
But besides that we'll not just pass that information, in this module we'll also use it to enhance our
models
and with that I mean will add more functionalities, we'll even add a new model.
So with that, let's start and let's learn how we can pass data and how we can use that data then.