Now that we know how to work with errors and now that we learned a lot about node express in general,
let me dive into a little more advanced or specialized topic, file uploads and downloads.
Now it's actually not something that rare, you'll often have a feature like this on your web page and
therefore it is important to understand how you can allow your users to upload files and how you can
handle that on your server side and which different possibilities you have for returning files to your
users.
So this is essentially what we'll dive into in this module. We'll have a look at how to upload files and
most importantly how to handle them on the server
and of course we'll then have a look at the different options you have for returning files.
So let's dive in.