In the last module, we had a closer look at NoSQL or especially mongodb and how you can use
such a NoSQL database in our course mongodb, the most popular NoSQL database in a nodejs
application.
Hopefully you saw that it wasn't too difficult and still just as with SQL,
we can abstract some complexity away from us and focus more on our data than the queries we write and
here just as we had sequelize for SQL, we got mongoose for mongodb and mongoose is indeed pretty
similar to sequelize in terms of what it tries to do,
it tries to enable you to work with the data instead of with the queries.
So what's in this module? We'll have a look at what mongoose is in detail and how we can add it to our
project and how we can start using it and then we'll,
well we will use it,
we will use it in our nodejs application,
I will give you a thorough introduction to mongoose, also show you where you can learn more about that
if you want to dive deeper
and we will transform our project once again to move from a
we write all queries on our own approach to we just define how our data should look like and then
work with it approach.
So with that, let's dive in.