We had a very detailed look at how you can use SQL based databases like MySQL to store your application
data and most importantly for us as node developers, how you can interact with your MySQL database from
inside
nodejs.
Now SQL based databases are popular, are great and are used a lot but there is another very popular
alternative which is used heavily and that is NoSQL or NoSQL based databases especially mongodb
.
And in this module we'll have a look at
mongodb, what it is and how you can start up a mongodb database
and most importantly of course, how you can use it from inside your node code.
So specifically I'll give you a short introduction to what mongodb is and why we would use it,
what the difference to SQL is,
I also had a brief discussion about this earlier in the SQL module.
And then most importantly, we'll see how we used the so-called mongodb driver,
basically a package we install to interact with mongodb from inside our nodejs applications.
So let's dive into mongodb and see why it's awesome and why we could use it and how we use it.