We're able to parse incoming request bodies with the help of the body parser package which is pretty
neat
but right now as I mentioned, this middleware always executes, not just for post requests but also for get
requests, what can we do regarding that?
Well instead of app use, we can also use app get. This is basically app use, it has the same syntax
as app use,
we can use a path or don't use a path but it only will fire for incoming get requests,
so this is another form of filtering besides filtering for the path, app get allows us to filter
for get requests
and on the same page, we also got app post to filter for incoming post requests and just by changing this
word, this middleware will now only trigger for incoming post requests with this path and not for get
requests.
So if I save this and I go to /product, you see I get hello from express,
so I don't end up here even though I entered /product but it was a get request
but if I send a post request through that form I have on add product, if I do this here, book too, you
see we get this output,
so we clearly made it into this middleware due to our filtering.
So this is another way of using that middleware function, instead of use which will work with all http
methods,
we can also use get or post to filter for these.
And additionally you also have delete, patch and put which are other http works which we'll use later
in the course because we can't really use them from a normal html document.