So we added the session middleware,
let's now start our server again and let's use the session middleware
and how do we use it?
Well we can use it in our auth controller in login instead of setting that cookie, we can reach out to
request and then the session object, this is added by the session middleware, this session object
and here we can add any key we want, for example is logged in but you can name this however you want and
set this to true.
Now if you save that and you go back to your browser, go to the login page maybe, reload and get rid of
that logged in cookie,
you can simply delete it here.
Now click login
and what you should see is that a new cookie was added here, this connect SID for a session id cookie,
if you expand the value here,
you'll see some strange string and that is what I meant,
this is this encrypted value so to say. And this is now the cookie, by default
it's a session cookie so it will expire when you close the browser.
It's a session cookie
that will identify your user here, your running instance of this website you could say where you are
browsing around, this will identify you to the server and to this session
and I can prove this to you. If we now go to the get login page here and I console log requests session
here like that,
let me then go back and click on the login page here again and go back to our server and there you see
the session object is logged.
Now let me also output is logged in here by accessing that, go back, login again,
it's undefined because I added the this code only after submitting this for the first time,
so let me save this again
and now simply click that login button here again
and now you will see if you go back to the login page, you see true here because now indeed in the session
is logged in is stored. And we can go to a different page and come back to login and these are all individual
requests which technically are totally individual from each other, totally separated and still we see
true here because we still store this in the session on the server side by default, just in the memory
not in the database yet and the session is identified for this browser because we have that cookie. And
I can prove that to you by starting another browser and this will technically be treated as a totally
different session and environment, could be a totally different machine.
So I am on localhost 3000 here
and if I click on login here, you see undefined and that undefined is coming from the login request I
just sent because this browser, this user, technically this is a totally different user even though
I'm the same but it's a different browser, different user, this user does not have this cookie set for
him, does not have an active session on the server.
And this is how we can store data that persists across requests
as you saw, I clicked around and still that was sent, the true value was sent when I came back to log
in,
so this is saved across requests but not across users, as you can see
this is a different user,
I go to login, I have undefined down there and that is the power of using a session.
It still needs a cookie to identify the user but the sensitive information is stored on the server,
we can't modify it
and that of course will be super important for authentication
and what we see here already is the core mechanism behind authenticating users in the web.
There are other techniques too,
for example when building a rest API, something I'll come back later
but this is a core thing on how authentication generally works especially when rendering views as we are
doing it with ejs and this is what we will build up on in the authentication section where we then
also dive into things like validating credentials, logging users out and fun stuff like that.