With the user model set up, let's make sure we can use it together with the product model.
Now obviously every product should be assigned to a user,
so first of all we need to change our product schema a little bit.
A product should also have a user ID field let's say, just as we had it before in the last module.
Now a user ID field is of type and now which type is this?
Well it will be a reference to a user, so this will actually be of type schema types objectID
and now we can set something special here, we can add a special ref configuration and ref takes a string
where we tell mongoose hey which other mongoose model is actually related to the data in that field.
We know that we will store a user ID here but just because the type is objectid, this is not obvious,
this could be any object ID of any object.
So I will add user here and you use the name of your model to which you want to relate this,
so since our model here is named user, I will name it user here,
so I refer to my user model here
and with that I got a relation set up. This also means that in my user model where I do store
the product ID, I can also add a reference here and refer to product because I know that for every user
in the cart items, I will store products where I refer to some ID and that ID happens to refer to a product
stored or defined through the product model.
So now we got relation set up with ref,
of course you only need this when using references, when using embedded documents as we do with the cart,
you don't need to do anything because well you use an embedded document, this already has kind of an
implicit relation that is managed inside of one document.
So now with the references set up,
let me also add a required to true here and now I adjusted my schemas. Now with the schemas adjusted,
we of course need to adjust our code like in the admin controller when we create a new product. When
creating a new product, we also want to make sure we store the user id and that is super simple.
We just add user ID here to the fields we pass in the object to the product constructor and now remember
that we did save the user in our request, so I can just do request user_id like this and
this should give me access to the user id and assign it here. Now conveniently in mongoose,
you can even just store the entire user object,
so this is really the entire user object not just the ID and mongoose will just pick the ID from that
object,
so that's another convenience you got there.
Let me save my code,
let's go back and let's add a new product, a nice book.
Let's use that image url we used before,
let's give it some price,
you should not miss that and click add product. Now you see
that looks good, it was added
and now let's have a look at compass and see if the user ID was added too.
So if I refresh there, indeed we see the user id here and just the ID, not the entire user, just the
ID as we want it.
So this is pretty awesome,
this is how we can manage relations through mongoose.
Now let me show you something cool
when it comes to fetching these relations.