In this module we had a look at some advanced authentication related topics, namely we had a look at
password resetting and there it was important to understand that you of course have to implement password
resetting in a way that prevents users from resetting random user accounts.
Therefore we implemented such a short lived password token so that it's not valid forever
to reduce the chance of it being generated by some brute force attack and therefore, our reset token
is a great mechanism to identify the user for whom we want to reset the password. The token has to be
generated in a way that is random,
unguessable, at least in a reasonable amount of time
hence the expiration date and unique
and in this module, we implemented a token in exactly that way.
We also had a look at authorization and authorization is all about locking down access for authenticated
users because just because you're authenticated, you're not allowed to do everything. You might be logged
in in your udemy account but you can't edit my course because you are not the creator of the
course and that's the idea of authorization and that is also what we did in this module when we ensured
that only users who created a product can actually view, edit and delete it.
So authorization is a crucial part of most applications
and together with authentication which is the surrounding topic of having users in general, you can really
control which visitor can do what in your web app in your website.