So time to parse the incoming requests and get the data that is part of the request because that data
should be whatever we entered here.
Now how do we get access to that?
Well we get requests url and request method,
you might think there is something like request data but there isn't.
Instead the incoming data is basically sent as a stream of data and that is a special construct javascript
in general knows
but nodejs uses a lot,
now what is such a stream of data though?
There is a connected concept, buffers and we'll have a look at both here.
So let's take our incoming request as an example,
there also are other streams like for example when working with files, we can also work with streams
but let's stick to requests here.
Our stream here is basically an ongoing process,
the request is simply read by node in chunks
you could say, in multiple parts and in the end at some point of time it's done
and this is done so that we theoretically can start working on this, on the individual chunks without
having to wait for the full request being read.
Now for a simple request like the one we're working with, this is not really required,
we only got one input field data,
it doesn't take so long to parse that. But consider a file being uploaded,
this will take considerably longer and therefore streaming that data could make sense because it could
allow you to start writing this to your disk,
so to your hard drive where your app runs, your node app runs on your server
whilst the data is coming in, so that you don't have to parse the entire file which is of course taking
some time and you have to wait for it being fully uploaded before you can do anything with it.
But this is how node handles all requests because it doesn't know in advance how complex and big they
are.
So you can start working on the data earlier,
the problem is with your code, you can't arbitrarily try to work with these chunks. Instead to organize
these incoming chunks,
you use a so-called buffer,
a buffer is like a bus stop.
If you consider buses, they're always driving
but for users or customers being able to work with them, to climb on the bus and leave the bus, you need
bus stops where you well you can track the bus basically and that is what a buffer is. A buffer is simply
a construct which allows you to hold multiple chunks and work with them before they are released
once you're done and you work with that buffer. Now that's pretty abstract but it's pretty easy to work
with fortunately
so let's see how that works in practice. When receiving a posted message before sending the response
and before writing to the file, we want to get our request data, right
and we do this by going to our request and registering an event listener.
We haven't done that thus far but as I mentioned, node uses these heavily. For create server,
it implicitly creates one for us,
now we do this on our own by using the on method. Now on allows us to listen to certain events and the event
I want to listen to here is the data event,
you see my IDE even gives me some help here and tells me which events I can listen to for a request.
So here I want to listen for the data event, the data event will be fired whenever a new chunk is ready
to be read,
you remember that buffer thing, this is basically helping us with that.
Now here we have to add a second argument which is that function that should be executed for every data
event, you remember create server,
it had a similar concept. There we defined a function that should be executed for every incoming request,
now we're defining a function to be executed for every incoming data piece.
So here I'll again using an ES6 arrow function,
you could also use the function keyword without that arrow then
and as you can also see on data, this listener receives a chunk of data.
So here we receive a chunk and this chunk is something we can work with here and now we have to do something
with this chunk to be able to interact with it.
For this I will create a new constant here and I'll name it body because I'll try to read the request
body,
you can name it however you want but it is the request body
we're working with. Now
the body should be an empty array
and now in that function here in the data event, I'll take my body and push a new element onto it.
By the way if you're wondering how we can edit a constant value, this only means that we can never
re-assign a new value, so we can never use body equals something again
but with push we're changing the object behind that body element, that body object, we're editing that
data in that object not the value itself, not the object itself.
It's a bit strange to wrap your head around but this is in the end how it works.
So we can now push a new element into this array to make it non-empty and we push our chunk here. Now nodejs
will execute this so often until it's done getting all the data out of our request,
that can be once, that can be multiple times and we can even log this to see how app, how often it does this
and what's inside of this
chunk. Now we need to register another event listener and that is the end listener, this will be fired
once it's done parsing the incoming requests data or the incoming requests
in general. Here it will again execute a function we define as a second argument and in this function, we
can now rely on all the chunks being read in and they're all stored in the body now.
Now to interact with this
and don't forget the comma after end, to interact with that, to work with all these chunks,
we now need to buffer them.
Remember that bus stop concept,
we get all these chunks we now need to do is something to be able to work with them, to basically have
one place where the bus stops and we can interact with it.
So here I'll now create a new constant, parsedBody and there I will use the buffer object which is available
globally, made available by nodejs
and I can concat my body.
So this will in the end create a new buffer and add all the chunks from inside my body to it.
And then on this buffer which I got here, parsed body is now a buffer, there I can call toString to convert
it to a string.
So this is a utility method offered by nodejs where we do something to our buffered chunks,
remember the bus is now waiting in the bus stop so to say, the buffer is our bus stop and now we do
something with it,
here we convert it to a string and this only works because I know that the incoming data will be text
because the body of that request will be text.
If it were a file, we would have to do something different
but it is no file and I know that it isn't because we're writing the code,
we know what we will receive,
right.
So this is the parsed body
and this is now finally what we can work with,
so let's also output the parsed body.
And this was a lot of talking so let's simply have a look with the server, with control c and restart it and
then send another request with some message here.
And now if you have a look at what's being logged, you see two elements.
The first one is coming from this console log
and you see that is a chunk, that is a chunk we can't work with
but now the parsed body receives or yields this line and that is something we can work with and it's
message equals something because we named our input here message
and as I said, that form will automatically send the request where it takes all the input data and
puts it into the request body as key value pairs where the names assigned to the inputs are the keys
and the values are what the user entered and that is what we have here,
a key value pair separating the key from the value with an equal sign.
Now and with that, we can now work with that and finally store the input in our file and we can do that
here in request on, request on
end to be precise by creating a new constant, message, taking the parsed body and splitting it on the equal
sign and then taking the element with the index one which is the second element in the resulting array
which is the element on the right of the equal sign.
And now we can move write file sync into the end function,
we don't want to execute it here because this will actually run before this function is called
because here we just register a function to be called in the future,
it's not executed immediately,
remember node doesn't wait and pause, it will not block the script execution,
it just registers this as a to-be-executed action
and then right away continues.
So if we have something that depends on the incoming data, we have to move it into the event listener
too so that it's also part of the to-be-executed code
sometimes in the future and doesn't run too early
and now we can write message to the message.txt file.
Let's now restart this file one more time
and enter
hello here and hit send
and now if you look into message text, we see hello, you see the exclamation mark was encoded.
Now that is something we can worry about later
but in general, this worked just fine.
And if you're now totally frightened by how complex nodejs is, this is the raw logic, we'll later
use expressjs which hides all that raw logic
but to understand why we use that, you first of all need to understand what is happening and why using
tools like expressjs which will make all of this much easier are great.
So with that, we've got our basic logic down,
let's now dive again into that event listener and writing files thing because there is something really
important you have to understand.