So what is wrong with this write file sync line here?
Well it's the sync keyword.
I earlier mentioned that there also is a write file method but we use write file sync, the sync here
stands for synchronous and this is a special method which will actually block code execution until this
file is created.
Now working with files is available in two modes,
here is the synchronous mode and we block execution of the next line of code until this file is done.
Now for this short of a text we enter, this is super fast and we won't even notice it
but think about a huge file, a couple of hundreds of megabytes or even bigger, if you do something with
that,
read it, copy it, whatever it is and you block the code execution,
then the next line and all the other code will not continue to run until that file operation is done
and even new incoming requests of other users would not be handled until that file operation is done
and you don't want that, therefore you should not use that syntax here.
You can if you know you'll only have a very short file operation but even then, it's better to use this
write file method here which actually does not just accept the path and the data but also a third argument
and that is again such a callback,
so a function that should be executed when it's done.
So here again just as with create server, nodejs implicitly registers an event listener for us.
So here, I pass another function and this callback here actually receives an error object which will
be null if no error occurred
but if some error occurred, missing permissions or anything like that, you would get it here and you could
then handle it gracefully by returning a different kind of response, an error response showing to the user
that an error occurred
and otherwise return a normal response. Now here
I won't do error handling and there is really nothing that could go wrong here,
we'll of course dive into error handling a bit more later in the course
but I will move my normal response code in there because this response should only be sent if we're
done working with the file because that is ultimately the action
we want to do upon our request, right.
So now we actually have our event listener with some method or function that will be executed once we're
done parsing the request
and in that function that will be executed sometime in the future,
we have yet another event listener, this nested function here which will be executed once we're done
writing the file and this is actually pretty standard for nodejs.
You have this event driven architecture where you basically tell nodejs please do something and
it will then go ahead and offload that process to the operating system which does use multi-threading
and so on and will then continue its event loop to listen for event callbacks and always just dispatch
tiny actions like that to never block the code execution and then always just come back once an operation
is done by the operating system and so on.
So this is what nodejs does here and why it is high performant
because it never blocks your code,
it never blocks the server,
it just goes ahead and tells the operating system do that, do this and then eventually comes back and
does something in the callback, like send a response which is not a blocking operation because this
is super fast, just a couple of headers and off you go.
So I hope this is clear
and with that let's restart this by quitting the server, re-running node app and going back to just slash
nothing,
let's enter hello again here and send. And in message.text we see that, again concatenated with an extra
character, not something we have to worry about right now.
So you see write file also works
but this is the way you should use it due to the asynchronous nature of nodejs which I hope now
became clear because it is a crucial concept of nodejs and one you absolutely have to understand.
With that, let's wrap this module up with these core basics and let's from now on to move to a more easier
route where we will make our life simpler and not write
all this nitty gritty detail code on our own
but it is super crucial that you understand what's going on here.