That's it for this refresher module. Obviously this is no complete javascript module,
there are way more features which I didn't touch on
and the reason for that is simple, I do require very basic javascript knowledge at least. If you've got
none,
check out the resources linked in the second lecture of this module,
these resources allow you to dive into javascript for free or with paid courses, whatever you want.
And with that plus this refresher about next-gen javascript items or features as well, you are more than
prepared to continue with the course and now understand the code
we will write throughout the course.
I hope this was helpful,
let's now dive into nodejs and write exciting applications.