There is one other notable feature about the express router that I want to show you,
now we have a catch all route and we got our outsourced routes here.
Now sometimes these outsourced routes have a common starting path,
so let's say all the admin routes actually are triggered with admin/add-product and admin, maybe
also add product,
we can repeat the path here because we got different methods, get and post, so these will be two different
routes too.
So that is one important take away already, the same path can be used if the methods differ. Of course
here in the form,
I should also point at add product then but there is another important take away.
If we have such a setup where our paths in such a router file start with the same part or with the
same segment here, we can take that segment out of this route here and then go to the app.js file
and add it here, so add that segment as a filter.
Now only routes starting with /admin will go into the admin routes file
so to say and not only that, it also will or expressjs will also omit or ignore
this /admin part in the
url when it tries to match these routes,
so now /add-product will match the /admin/add-product route because /admin was already
stripped out
here you could say, let me show this to you in practice. If I reload my add product route, we get page not
found because this does not exist anymore,
this is now /admin/add-product and indeed, here is the form
and if I now add my book again here and hit add product, I get page not found
and the reason for that is that of course here in form action, I'm leading to /add-product
but this should be /admin/add-product too because we want to reach that route which is the admin.js
file which is only reachable through requests that have /admin at the beginning.
So let's give this another try,
let's go to /admin/add-product and let's try adding that book again,
now we are redirected and now we can also see that we are logging this here.
So this filtering mechanism here in app.js allows us to put a common starting segment for our
path which all routes in a given file use to outsource that into this app.js file so that we don't
have to repeat it for all the routes here.
Implicitly, this route is reached under admin add product and so is this route here,
this one with a post request and this one with a get request.
Now this can be a bit challenging to wrap your head around but this is another core thing you have
to understand, how these requests are funneled through and how they may reach this file
if they start with /admin because we are filtering here and how in that file, the /admin part
is then not checked again but it only checks the second part and therefore reaches this or these requests
route here.