If you remember that slide from earlier, file uploads require no changes on the server side, only
on the client side.
So what do you learn now is not that important to you if you're not working on the client side yourself,
on the server side
the logic is exactly the same or pretty much the same
we used before, let's still implement it again. Here
I'm back in the node application
and I want to accept uploaded files. Now in the past
we did this with a special body parser, a special middleware and that was multer.
So let's install that again with npm install --save multer in the node rest API project, not
in the react project.
So there we install multer just as we did it earlier in the course and with it installed, let's go to
the app.js file and I will implement exactly the same logic as I did before.
So I'll go through that really quickly,
you should check out that file upload download module if you want to learn all the details.
I will first of all import multer into my app.js file and with it imported, I will configure some things
for it,
maybe here.
I will configure the file storage with multer disk storage to control where the files get stored and
there, we have a destination key which is a function in the end, an arrow function where I get request
object, information about the file multer detected and a callback I should call once I'm done
defining the destination. I'm done immediately here, got no error and the destination is images pointing
at that images folder here.
So that's the first thing here,
we add another function to the disks storage object and that's the file name function which defines
how the file should be named, get the same arguments as in the destination function and I call that
callback with null as an error and the filename will be a combination of the date which I convert to
a string and then a dash and then the original filename, really simple, exactly the same logic I used
before.
I'll also define a file filter where I also have or which also is a function which gets request, information
about the file and a callback and in here,
I'll check for a couple of mime types.
I'll see if my file mime type is equal to image/png
or if file mime type is equal to image/jpg or if file mime type is equal to image/jpeg with an
e, that is my if condition. If anything of that is true, then it is a valid file and therefore I return
no error
and true as a second argument in the callback
otherwise it would be invalid and I still have no error but I return false here and this is again something
you learned in the file upload module.
Last but not least, I need to register multer and I will use it here,
maybe after the json body parser. I will use multer as a function, pass an object to configure it,
assign a storage to my own file storage constant we just created and add a file filter which points
at that file filter constant
we just created. On that multer function, I'll then also call single image to inform
multer that I'll extract a single file stored in some field named image in the incoming requests.
Now every incoming request is parsed for that file or for such files. With that, multer is registered
and now we can use the file in our controller where we create a new post. For that in create post,
I can first of all check if request file, if that is not set because if it is not set, then I'm missing
a file so I will create a new error here,
no image provided
maybe, I will set my status code to 422 because it's also kind of a validation error and I will throw
that error,
that's the first check.
Now if I do find a file then everything is good,
multer was able to extract a valid file,
so then I'll just set up an image
url constant and access request file and there the path variable which multer generates which
holds the path to the file as it was stored on my server. And now this image url is what I use
here as an image
url of course instead of my dummy data.
Now we should be able to extract files and really store them.
Let me now run this
but of course now we also need to tweak our frontend to be able to make that work
and I didn't do this in advance because there is something special which I want you to know. In the react
code,
so on the frontend, go to that feed.js file in pages feed and there, let's go to the finish edit
handler. There
we're setting up everything we need to send a request to the backend to create a new post and right
now, we're doing this with json data.
Now we won't use json data anymore because json data is only text, so only data that can be represented
as a text which a file can't be or not easily, it will be very big quickly and very big files are a
huge issue or impossible to upload like this. So we can't use json for data where we have both a file
and normal text data,
instead we'll again use form data.
Now we did use form data automatically when earlier in the course where we had a traditional app with
rendered views, when we used a form with this multipart form ank type which we added to the form html
element
if you remember. So this form data is what we'll also use here but we'll not use anything to any form
element, we'll do it all in javascript instead.
Here where I have this marker, this comment, we can create a new form data object with a built-in object
that browser side javascript offers, the form data object.
This now allows us to append data to that object,
for example the title, first argument to append is the name of the field, second argument is the actual
data.
So here we'll have post data.title, exactly what we passed to the json data before.
Of course we don't just append the title,
we also append the content,
so let's append that
and now we also want to append an image because we can append files as well.
Now this should be named image because we'll be looking for this field on our rest API
and now here, I can reach out to post data image because that is where I will get my image in my frontend
code. With these three fields,
I got form data prepared that now has mixed content, text and a file and now I want to use that
form data as a body for my request.
We should not set the header to application json anymore because that would be incorrect and would
break our app because we would try to parse it incorrectly on the server side,
instead the form data will automatically set the headers,
that is kind of convenient.
All we need to do is we need to set form data as our body and the rest will be done for us.
If we now save that and we create a new post,
let me create a post here, a duck and choose that lovely duck image again,
this is a duck and click accept.
Now this was pretty quick,
if I now click view here, I see my duck here which is looking good and on the server side,
I also see this image which was generated, which has a time stamp and this is the uploaded image,
I got no error here so this is all looking good. So uploading files also works, as you saw on the server
side
it has exactly the same logic, on the client side
things need to change but of course this is a node course, so it depends on which client you are using, how you need
to adjust your code
there.