So now we had a look at how we can use sessions and what the advantage of a session is
and we also of course learned about cookies, what a cookie can be used for and how it plays together
nicely with a session to identify a user, a client and then store the sensitive data on the server,
so in the session and that difference between the sessions server side and cookies, client side is really important
to understand and
you also learned how to set a cookie and how to use a session.
Now by the way if you're wondering how that session cookie, this cookie here, how this is set, well this is done
automatically by express session
so by that middleware we're configuring and
that's also why you can add cookie related configurations here because this middleware automatically
sets a cookie for you and it automatically reads the cookie value for you too,
so it does all the cookie parsing and setting for you. Now with that, you actually rarely need to manage
cookies on your own
because that session cookie
and with that I don't mean a cookie which gets lost after you close the browser but that cookie that
identifies a server side session, that is the most prominent, the most common use case for cookies besides
advertisement, tracking which you typically don't implement on your own but you use third party tools
like Google for that.
But that session cookie, so that session identifying cookie is an important thing
and sessions on the server are often used for authentication
but as I mentioned, you could use them for any kind of data you want to store.
We happen to store the information whether the user is logged in
but you could be storing the carts, the shopping cart of the user here or anything which belongs to a user
which should be shared across requests as I highlighted.