So we added authorization to our download option here.
Now that's not all we can improve,
we can also improve the way we are serving that file because right now, I'm simply reading that file
and once I read it, I return it.
Now for small files this is probably fine
but you should be aware of one important fact,
if you read a file like this, node will first of all access that file, read the entire content into memory
and then return it with the response.
This means that for bigger files, this will take very long before a response is sent and your memory
on the server might actually overflow at some point for many incoming requests because it has to read
all the data into memory which of course is limited.
So reading file data into memory to serve it as a response is not really a good practice, for tiny files
it might be ok but for bigger files, it certainly is not,
instead you should be streaming your response data and that is what I will do now.
So I'll comment out this code where I read my file and instead here, I will now start streaming it.
For that I'll create a new constant, I'll name it file and I will use the file system and create a read stream
because I want to read some data in.
Now I want to read in data at a specific path and the path hasn't changed, it's the invoice path,
so now I have to read read stream and node will be able to use that to read in the file step by step
in different chunks.
I will then take my response code here where I set the headers,
I still do that on the response object
and then here, I will use that file read stream and call the pipe method to forward the data that is
read in with that stream to my response because the response object is a writable stream actually
and you can use readable streams to pipe their output into a writable stream,
not every object is a writable stream but the response happens to be one.
So we can pipe our readable stream, the file stream into the response and that means that the response will
be streamed to the browser and will contain the data and the data will basically be downloaded by the
browser
step by step and for large files,
this is a huge advantage because node never has to pre-load all the data into memory but just streams
it to the client on the fly
and the most it has to store is one chunk of data.
Again we're back to the streams and the buffers,
the chunks are what we work with, the buffers
basically gives us access to these chunks
and here we don't wait for all the chunks to come together and concatenate them into one object,
instead we forward them to the browser which then is also able to concatenate the incoming data pieces
into the final file.
So with this setup here,
let's try this again,
click on orders, click on the invoice and again we see the invoice as before but now this is actually
streamed data created with that create read stream thing which is the recommended way of getting your
file data especially for bigger files.