Now that we learned how to save files and how to return them in different ways statically
as one big file or as a streamed response, let me show you a little bonus so to say where we can create
a pdf on the fly on the server,
instead of serving that hardcoded pdf here,
let me create it on the fly instead.
So I will delete my invoice here and instead when we get the invoice for an order, I don't want to serve
a file that already exists but I want to generate that file based on the real order data. For that
I first of all will still check if we have that order and if the user is allowed to access it
but of course this will now change,
well actually the name will be the same and I will store it in the same way
but I now can't read the file,
I need to create it
and how can we create a pdf?
Well there are third party packages which we can use which make it a lot easier and pdfkit is a very
prominent or popular package for creating pdfs on a nodejs server.
I strongly recommend checking out their documentation to learn more about all its many options because
it's super powerful, it can do a lot of stuff, so definitely worth having a look at this and we will use
it to create a very simple pdf in this course here.
Now for documentation, it's important to know that this documentation uses coffee script which is like
a superset to javascript,
it's not supported by node,
it's just a tooling for writing your code,
it's compiled back to a normal javascript and therefore this documentation can be a bit hard to read.
In the end you could say something like this new pdf document, here we would have curly braces after it,
require would be using curly braces so some stuff here looks a bit different but I will show you how
to use it in this module, in this lecture actually. Let's start by installing it, so I will simply run
npm install --save pdfkit,
that's the name of the package,
you'll also find these instructions on the official page, npm install pdfkit and then we can start using
it
once it's installed. So let me start that server again
and up there in my shop.js
controller file, I'll import pdfkit by requiring pdfkit,
so this package we just installed. Actually pdfkit exposes a pdf document constructor,
so let's maybe name it like this,
so pdf document,
the name is up to you but this is closer to what this package really exposes.
Now I want to create a new pdf document
when we get an invoice at this point here.
So let's create a new pdf doc, whatever you want to name it by calling new pdf document and that's
what I meant,
you need to add normal parentheses as we always did for all constructors.
So now we have a new pdf document.
This actually also turns out to be a readable stream,
therefore what we can do here is we can use the pdf document and
we can do two things.
First of all we pipe this output into a writable file stream,
so create write stream is a function we can call on the file system package and to that we pass a path
where we want to write it to, the invoice path
in my case and this ensures that the pdf we generate here also gets stored on the server and not just serve
to the client.
So we create that and of course I also want to return it to the client,
so I also pipe the output into my response, just as before,
the response is a writable read stream, pdf doc is a readable one so we can do that.
Now we have this set up and now whatever we add to the document will be forwarded into this file which
gets generated on the fly and into our response.
Now let's start simple and let's now use pdf doc and let's call the text method which exists there,
this allows us to add a single line of text into the pdf document.
So here let's add hello world maybe
and then you have to call pdf doc to tell node when you're done writing to that stream because you
have to be done at some point, right.
So here you simply call end
and when you call end, these writable streams for creating the file and for sending the response will be closed
so to say or will know that you are done writing and therefore the file will be saved and the response
will be sent.
And now with that saved, just make sure you also change your setup down there at the bottom.
I will keep the headers but I will not pipe any file because we now, well pipe the file up there
when we create it
and I just need to make sure that I set my response headers accordingly.
Now with that if you save that and you click on that invoice link, you should get a pdf with hello
world in there and this pdf also can be found here.
Now it might look a bit strange here but you can open it with a normal pdf reader and it should look like
a pdf.
So this is how you can create a pdf on the fly,
now in the next lecture let's actually populate it with some order data.