Now we learned a lot about validation and providing a good user experience,
now sometimes you also want to sanitize user input.
Now what does sanitising mean? For one on this validator page,
so the package which is used behind the scenes, you don't just find all these validators, you also find
available sanitizers here and there you also see what they do.
For example what you can do is you can ensure that there is no excess whitespace in a string passed
by the user on the left or on the right,
you can normalize an e-mail which means it's converted to lowercase and things like that.
So there are a couple of things you can do to make sure the data you get is not just valid but also
is stored in a uniform way,
so without extra whitespace or anything like that.
So sanitising input is also something that makes sense to be done.
Cross-site scripting attacks sanitation which is a security feature is by the way something I'll
cover in the security module of this course, so we'll focus on the visual sanitization for now not on security
relevant sanitising.
So this is what you can also do,
now how does sanitising input work though?
Well you do it in one step with validating,
so in the routes folder in the auth.js file in our example, let's say the email here, I want to
make sure that it's stored in a normalized way,
so lowercase not starting with an uppercase character, no excess whitespace.
Well I can do this by chaining another method after my validation logic and there I can call normalize
e-mail which is one of these built-in sanitizers which I showed you. For the password we could trim it,
so here we could trim the password to remove excess whitespace. Of course we can do the same for the sign
up here,
besides our check here I also want to normalize the email once I'm done with it, with sensitise, with validating
and for the password I want to trim excess whitespace.
So again this is something which I can do here to sanitize user input and to see the result of that,
let me actually connect to my database real quick with the help of compass, my visual user interface here
and there in the users,
I get a bunch of users because I created some users throughout this module. Let me delete a couple of entries
here really quick just to clean this up,
well actually delete them all
and now let me create a new user,
keep in mind I added sanitization.
Now if I enter test@test.com like this with an extra blank after this and I enter my password
here with an extra whitespace at the end, so our blank at the end,
then I do already get an error because for signing up, I do actually trm my password here but I don't
trim the confirming password,
so I should trim this as well
otherwise the whitespace is removed here and indeed it is, this is one character shorter. Now if I sign up, both
passwords were changed and keep in mind the email started with a capital character and also had an extra
whitespace,
if I now reload my users, we see the email is stored with a lowercase t at the beginning and without
that extra whitespace at the beginning and this is now simply the case because I sanitized the input.
So sanitising data is also something which makes sense to ensure that your data is stored in a uniform
format and well that your email addresses look equal and so on.