So now that the csrf protection was added,
let me quickly fix that error where I was not able to order an item and there, the path username is required
is the issue which is thrown,
let's quickly check the shop controller and there, the post order and in there, I indeed store the username
and I'm not storing the username anymore here.
When signing up, users only have the email,
so here we could store the e-mail for our user with request user e-mail on the order, like this.
So instead of the name, I now store the e-mail of the user in here or you also omit this and just store the user
id, whatever you want.
Now in our order model, this means that here I also don't expect the name but the email which still is
a string and still is required,
So this is a tiny change that needs to be done to fix that issue
and if I now go back to products and I add this to my cart and I add it to my cart
again let's say therefore I have to order this,
now this works
and the cart is empty.
So this was just a little node something that was required,
let's logout,
this all works.
This is this bug fixed.