Now that we learned a lot about validation and
sanitizing input,
let's practice this one last time for adding a product and for editing it as well and there, feel free
to again pause the video and try out some things on your own. Add your own first validation steps, after
the pause we'll do it together of course and you're free to add any validation that you want to add that looks
good to you for the different fields we have here
and thereafter, I'll show you my suggestion on how we could validate this,
so here's your chance to pause the video.
Successful?
Well let's try it out.
We get four inputs here,
title, image url, price and description.
Now what would make sense to be validated here
and again there is no single true solution here,
you can have different requirements for the app you're building.
Now I want to have a title which should be alphanumeric, so only normal alphabetic characters and numbers,
it should at least be let's say three characters long. The image url should be a valid
url,
the price should be a floating point number, so a number with decimal places and the description here
should also be not alphanumeric,
there should be special characters like the exclamation mark should be allowed but it should be at least
let's say five characters long. And with that information, let's add validation to the admin.js file which
is where we have these post routes for, whoops, for adding and for editing. For that
first of all, let's import the body or the check function, whichever you prefer
by requiring
express validate or /check
and then let's add it here to add product. There
I'll add an array to group all these middlewares together and then I'll validate my different inputs
step by step.
Let's first of all have a look at the views real fast, so there at the edit product view and there we
see we got a field named title, one named image url, one named price and one named description,
so these are the four fields I want to validate,
title, image url, price and description.
So back in the admin controller, excuse me in the admin route not in the controller, in the route,
I'll start with the title.
Now there, you're free to add whatever you want,
I will add isAlphanumeric as a validator and isLength should have a minimum length of 3
let's say. We can also add some sanitization and trim excess whitespace at the beginning or the end of
the title.
Now this is the title I want to validate, I'll
now copy this and continue with the image url,
however there I will check isUrl,
that is the only thing I want to validate there,
that this is a valid
url and that is another built-in validator that checks whether this fulfills the characteristics
of a url,
then I'll add my validator for the price here.
Now for the price, I want to have, I could check isNumeric to allow either integer values or floating
point numbers
But there also is isFloat to ensure that this has to have some decimal places.
Now I'll add my last validation here and that will be on the description and there, I just want to trim that
and have a length of at least let's say 8 or 5 characters, whatever you want,
you could also add a max value of course,
let's say we have a max of 200 or 400 characters, something like that.
Now I added validation to adding a product, I'll already copy that and add it to edit product here, to the post route
edit product as well,
so there I edit the exact same fields because we'll be editing the exact same fields there
so I want to have the same validation in place.
Now with that in place, let's go to the admin controller and make sure we collect these validation errors
and return them. For that
we'll first of all import something from the express validator by requiring express validator
/check and there, I want to import the validation result function. And in post add product, here before
we create that new product,
I will actually collect all my errors by passing the request to validation result and I'll then check
if not errors is empty which means we do have errors and in that case, if we make it into this if block,
I will actually render my edit page,
so here on get edit page, I will call this render function here in the end
but I'll do that in this if block I just edit.
I'll also set this status code of 422 which is a good practice for indicating to the browser that some
data that was passed was incorrect.
I'll have add product as a title
and now if we have a quick look here at edit product, we see that there we already set the value
if editing is set to true and then we output product title, product image url.
Now we can tweak this a little bit,
I'll still set editing to false because we still are not editing and I don't want to change anything
else on the page but what I will do is I'll set my product here equal to an object where I do set the
title and so on to these fields, to these inputs which I did fetch. So I'll set the title, the image url and
also the price and the description to these fetched inputs so that we can use that old data in the way
we are already using it
but I'll now add another field here, hasError maybe and I'll set this to true here.
Now that simply means that I should ensure that hasError is also set in other places where I render
this page, like here where I set it to false for get add product and for get edit product down there,
I will also set it to false,
so it's only true right now if I'm in the if block of my post add product route here.
Now in my view I can now take advantage of this new has error field and I can say I want to output the
existing product title if I'm editing or if hasError is true,
so that is my alternative condition here to ensure that the old data in this case then is output like
this.
Now of course it would also be nice to display some error message, so we can grab that from the login
page and check for the existence of error message here above my form and output it
if we have one, this just means that again back to my routes and not to my routes, to my controller in
the admin.js file, we should have an error message which simply is null by default.
And here in my if block where I do have validation errors, I will set the error message to errors array,
the first error which we are guaranteed to have
and there the msg property property as we did it before
and of course I'll also set error message here when we get the edit page, there I set it to null. And
now with that, if I hit add product here, I get invalid value because I set no custom errors
but it did to re-render this and if I enter first book here, then this is also kept if I click add product, it still
gives me that default message of invalid value because I never set my own one,
you could of course do that with the techniques I showed.
We also have no red borders because we didn't add that logic yet but it is reloading the page, it's not
submitting the request and it's keeping all the data which we did input
right, so this is not thrown away and that is of course worth a lot.
We can of course also edit products and for this,
let me quickly add a valid product,
this also allows us to test whether this works.
And it looks like it failed but actually if we go back, we see we get a double headers sent error which
is stemming from my admin controller, I should return this otherwise after sending this error response,
we continue with the rest of our code which I don't want to.
So now if I hit add product here,
this still fails though.
The interesting thing is if I go back to my products collection, first book was added before though,
well that was added because I did not return in case of an error as I'm doing now,
so now the returning works but still I get this invalid value
and if we want to find out for what I get it, I can log errors array here so that we can have a look
into this errors object. If I add this again, now it fails of course, we see it's the title. The title failed
somehow, the title somehow is valid in a way that tells us that it does not fulfill our criteria
and the title for adding a product should be alphanumeric, have this length and be trimmed.
Now the thing is my alphanumeric check, the whitespace here is neither alphabetic character nor a number,
so maybe we should just check if it is a valid string because that will allow whitespace as well
and now if I hit add product, now this succeeded and it did add it therefore. So now I've got two first books
here,
let me delete this real quick.
Now if I try adding this again though, maybe a second book,
it does work
and now it also shows that image correctly, so seems to have been a bug.
So this is now working, now we added validation for adding this
and how is it for editing? If I add an exclamation mark here,
this is accepted, we see the exclamation mark up there
and if I now enter something incorrect like the price is missing, well then this seems to break it doesn't
continue
and indeed I do have an error down there
which makes a lot of sense because what didn't we do yet?
Well we didn't add our error collecting and error returning to the edit route,
we only worked on add thus far, post add product.
So in the next video we'll take care that for editing a product, we also get validation errors instead of
a broken app
when we do submit invalid values.