We're now using sessions everywhere and we have our dummy authentication process in place, it's missing
crucial features like log out and so on and that will all come in the authentication module
but we have something in place and you might have noticed that of course
regarding the log out, I always just deleted the session cookie.
That is what I did in the assignment too, I deleted the session cookie to demonstrate what happens if
we then try to do something that is relying on data that is stored in the session,
it will fail because the session cookie which is required to identify the correct session is not there.
Now deleting just the cookie is of course not ideal because right now for example if we have a look at
compass and into our sessions collection, I have three sessions here because I always just deleted the cookie.
Now there is a cleaner way of doing that and that cleaner way is to use a method provided by the session
middleware,
now let me show this to you and for that, I'll
first of all go to my views and there to the navigation and next to my login button here,
I'll actually add another field, another list item into which I'll add a form which should lead to log
out and use a post method
and in that form, I'll have a button like this which is of type submit where I'll say log out.
Now if we save that and we reload our page, we see log out next to login,
now to make sure the styling is correct, we need to add that list item class here which we also have
on the list item here
and after adding this, if we reload this looks better
and now I've got my log out button here. Now when I click this, I want to clear any session I might have
and for that I of course need to register a new route.
So let's head over to our auth routes and let's add a new post route here because we will send a post
request which goes to log out and there, I will trigger a post log out action in my controller.
Now this action of course does not exist yet
so let's head over to the auth controller and maybe duplicate the post login route here, name it
post log out and in there,
what I want to do is I want to clear my session.
We can do this by reaching out to our session object and then we can call destroy there,
this is a method provided by the session package we're using.
Now this also takes a function which we pass to it which will be called once it's done destroying
the session and in there, request session will then not be available anymore because we got rid of that
session.
We can recreate it for the next request
when we do this again, then it will be set again
but in here, all the session data will be lost because the session was destroyed.
So here I will then actually redirect back to my starting page with res redirect slash,
we also get a potential error here which we can try to log to the console.
Now with that we have the post log out button registered.
Now let's head back to our application and first of all, let's login.
Now let me open the developer tools again,
I've got no session cookie here,
I can click login and redirected session cookie is set and we can now use that session.
Now if we go to compass real quick and we refresh, we see we have four objects now which makes sense,
we had three before,
now we have four
and now let me click log out.
We are redirected, the session cookie here actually still exists
but you see the session was deleted over there and the session cookie still exists but that is no problem
because no matching session will be found
so that is fine, it's basically not doing anything
and it will be renewed once we login again,
then this will be overwritten
and when we close the browser, it would also be deleted because it's not a permanent cookie,
it's a session cookie which means it's a cookie that does not have an expiry date in the future,
it does not have a max age,
it will simply get deleted when we close the browser and it's worthless in this state here.
So now as you see if I click around, I have a problem with my orders here,
I'll fix that in a second
but you see the cookies there,
most importantly the session was cleaned up
back there though.