So let's wrap this module up
and right before we finish, let's actually start wrapping it up by improving our code a little bit.
We've got all this code in this file and actually typically you write multiples or work with multiple
files
and why don't we create a new file that actually contains our routing logic,
so the logic where we check the url and do different things.
So I'll create a new file here, routes.js,
the name is up to you and I get this special icon by my IDE,
it is a normal javascript file,
don't be confused.
And in that file, I basically want to have my if statements here and my default response code,
so I'll cut all of that out of here so that this is a pretty lean file and move it into routes.js.
Now this wouldn't work like that,
let me say that, we'll have to tweak that
but this is now the code moved over.
I don't need the file system in
app.js anymore so we can remove that import,
we do need http because we still use that there and we don't need the url and method here so let's
remove that, go over routes.js,
add this fs imported on top
and now start working with that.
Now what do we need to do in this file?
We somehow need to be able to connect app.js to routes.js,
right
because we need to be able to send our incoming request to that file
so to say. And for that, let's create a new function, I'll name it
request handler and we can either create a function like this,
it should receive request and response as arguments, just as this function does because we'll effectively
replace that function or we use an ES6 function,
storing it in a constant, request handler which looks like this. Bit of a strange syntax if you've never
seen it before but we're essentially creating an anonymous arrow function which we store in a constant
and this therefore is the function name.
Now here we again receive request and response and in that function, we now move all that code because
that code obviously uses the request and response object,
so we need to have them available as local variables and we do now because these arguments are now named
this way.
We also use url and method,
so we need to re-add these constants by getting that data out from the request, request url and request
method and now we just need to export this handler. We're importing with this require syntax
but how are we exporting in nodejs?
There are two ways of exporting,
the first one is to go at the bottom and add module.exports,
this is another keyword or object which is exposed globally to you by nodejs which has an exports
property
and we can assign a value to this, like our request handler,
so this constant which holds this function, it's now stored in module exports.
And since this is a global object exposed by node, node is actually able to work with this
and we can now import from that routes.js file by requiring it and node will look for module exports
and see if something was registered for this file here
and we do register something in module exports, the request handler and you can register anything here.
You can add a new javascript object with multiple key value pairs, whatever you need, here
I'll just register my function.
So now I can go back to app.js and import my routes, the name of that constant is up to you,
by requiring it
and since this is now not a global module, we don't just type routes,
instead we want to add a local path to it with ./ and you can omit .js because nodejs
will automatically attach this at the end.
You can add it though
but I'll just type
./routes separated from the core modules to make it really clear that this is a custom
file
and now node will go ahead and look for a routes.js
file in the same folder as app.js which it will find and in that file, it will look for module
exports and see what's registered in there
and now we export that request handler method and now we can use that,
it will be stored in that routes because we assign whatever is exported from that file in that routes
constant,
so this routes constant will ultimately hold this function
and now we can use that here as a handler,
routes. Don't execute it,
so no parentheses, just pass the name telling node hey please execute the function that's stored in
routes for incoming requests.
And now if we save that and we restart the server and we reload this page, this is looking good
and this is also looking good,
we should have tests stored in message.text and we do.
So now we simply split our code over two files, having one file which is very lean that just spins
up the server
but and that's important,
that also creates a connection to another file through that import and through that export where we
export our request handler function here.
This is how that works,
now one important note about nodes module system, the file content here is actually cached by node and
we can't edit it externally,
so if we somehow would define routes as an object and we tried to add a new property on the fly here, this
would not manipulate the original file,
so this is basically logged, not accessible from outside,
we can only export stuff that we can now read from outside. Though
you could have functions which you export that start changing stuff inside of that file
but let's not make that too complicated for now,
we'll see all of that throughout the course obviously. For now we have that connection,
there's one other syntax you could use, instead of module exports,
sometimes you export many things and you could do that by having an object which has like the handler
key and that is my request handler function
and then also it has some text key which is some hardcoded text
in this case, now we would export two things and that is how you can group that or separate these two
things and still have one export being managed here which is the most you can have
and now in app.js, routes would be that object and not that function.
So here we would have to access the handler property,
so this property which holds the function reference we want to use and we could also simply output console
log routes some text here.
So this is how we can have multiple exports in one file,
now you see some hardcoded text here from this console log and we still have the same functionality
as before.
Now there also is a different way of exporting multiple things,
besides this code which you can of course use, you can also have module.exports.handler request
handler and then also module.exports. some text, some hardcoded text.
Now it might look different but we still only have one export,
we still have module exports which bundles all the exports but we explicitly assigned the different properties
like this,
so this is basically equivalent to this code.
If I now save this and restart my server, we see some hardcoded text and if I submit this, it also
still works.
Last but not least, there is a shortcut for this syntax,
you can now omit module and just write exports,
this is simply a shortcut supported by nodejs, not some general javascript magic,
it's just an explicit shortcut supported by nodejs where now we also have multiple exports being merged
together into one export,
so therefore again when I execute this,
we see some hardcoded text and some last value being submitted here still works and still ends up in
message.text.
So this is how we can connect multiple files by exporting either one element, one function as we had
it initially with module.exports equals request handler,
right
this is what we had initially,
let me comment this out with two slashes in front of it or module exports pointing at an object to combine
multiple things or using module.exports.handler equals request handler and module.exports.
some text equal some text or again,
this shortcut which is the same as this, just with this shortcut offered by nodejs.
So this is how imports and exports work, how the module system works and we'll work with a lot of files
throughout the course
so this is important to understand.
With that out of the way, let's now finally wrap this module up.