I'm outputting that error message, I just want to style it a little bit now
and for that I'll give it a css class and I'll simply name that user message and then maybe user
message --error using some BEM styling here,
that's a css styling convention or a convention of naming your classes. Doesn't matter too much,
you can name this whatever you want in the end,
I added these two classes, one to have a general message look and then one for errors because maybe we
also want to be able to output success messages later.
So with that, let me quickly add this to some css files and you can skip this lecture if you want,
in the next lecture you find the finished code attached which you can use. In the main css, I'll
quickly add this, let's say at the bottom of this file,
it's up to you right before the media query maybe, I have my user message,
so this css class I just added here
and let's say such a user message should use a margin auto to be centered, get a width of 90%
by default,
I'll also set up some styling in case I'm on a bigger screen,
there user message will have a width of let's say 30rem and then here I'll give it a border of one
pixel solid and let's use maybe some bluish color here, maybe not that blue,
well basically which ever blue color you want, maybe this one and a background color,
I'll also use a blue here, also a different blue, so some light bluish color here
so the general info message should have maybe some neutral color, so some blue like this
and let's see how that looks like.
With it added, let me try entering an invalid email again,
looks like that,
well not too pretty,
that should be much lighter.
I also want to have some padding in here,
maybe 1rem and let's give it some rounded corners as well and
now with that, if we enter an invalid email that looks much better.
Ok so now this is my general info message, let's also maybe also center the text if we want to
and now let's give this an error version basically with --error, that's the other class I added to this specific
box in my login screen and there I will change the border color to be red and the background should
be a light red,
so let's start with red and then turn this into a light red
and now if we try this again, now it looks like this. Ok so this could be the error message we're outputting
here,
you could also turn the text red if you want, so you could also say text color should be red here maybe
and reduce the padding maybe to .5, that could look a bit better,
so an invalid email or password,
that looks good.
Now I always have that stickaround
now, reason for that is if I go back,
error message seems to be set to something even if we're not having a message in there and that is something
I'll check in the next lecture.