That's it for this module. We added a bunch of validation logic for signing up, logging in and creating
products and you learned that this is a two step process of adding validators to your routes with that
third party package we're using, express validator so that it's a two step process with adding these validators
to the routes as middleware
and then for this package we collect errors in our controllers and then we do something if we do find errors.
Most commonly you would re-render that form page, so that page which wanted the user to input something and
to provide a good user experience.
You want to make sure that you keep the original input the user entered and that you show at least some
error message that gives the user an idea that nothing was wrong on your server but that something was
wrong with the user input instead.
These are the core takeaways and other than that, I can only encourage you to play around with the
different built-in validators, build your own ones
and of course there are other solutions, other express or node packages for validation out there as well.
This is a pretty popular package, pretty easy to use and I can only recommend using it
but as always it's most important that you play around with these things and that you practice using
it.