Let's make sure we can also delete items in the cart and for this in cart.ejs,
I will change my list item a bit, in there
I'll add a div first of all
or maybe let's add a paragraph to be semantically more correct which will output the text for this cart
items, so things like the name and the quantity
and then I will also add a little button there,
wrapped in a form. The form should go to cart
delete item maybe, the method will be a post method and in the form I will of course have my button with
a class of button with a type of submit which says delete. If we now reload the cart here,
we see delete this is the button, we can certainly work on the styling but for now I just want to make sure
that it works.
Now this is the delete button
and if I click that, it well should delete this item of course.
So cart delete item is a route
we now need to add and therefore let's go to routes here in shop.js
because of course this is a customer action,
our customers will manage their cart and there below the cart
I'll add a router post method, cart
delete item.
Now we need a fitting action in the controller,
so in a shop controller here and there I got get cart and post cart,
now I will also have exports post cart delete product maybe, you can of course use any name you want
and in here we'll have to remove that product from the carts but only from the cart, not the product
itself.
Well to do that, let's first of all extract the product ID from the request body product ID and therefore
we need to make sure that we pass it there too,
so in our form let's again add this hidden input with a value of our p product data.ID and then
a name of product ID so that we can extract it by that name on our backend.
And with that added, with this hidden input added here, let's now go back into the controller and with
that ID let's access the cart and then there, we can delete a product right. Now that delete product function
takes the ID of the product and we do have that
but it also takes the price and therefore, we should get that product information first.
So let's also call product find by ID here and get that product for this ID and add a callback with the retrieved
product, simply so that we can get the price before we well issue the delete request.
So in there, in this callback I will call delete product and now I can pass in product price too
and of course we could have also used a hidden input to pass the price to the backend
but I think this is the cleaner approach,
if we only pass the ID through the request and then we do all the data retrieval on the backend in our node
express code.
So now we get delete product
and with that we can also send a redirect request back to cart and in theory, this should be all we need.
Now of course the missing thing is that we connect our cart delete
item route to the newly created shop controller action, the post cart delete product action. And with that
added in the shop.js file in the routes folder, we can reload our cart page here,
click delete and we see our products and
by the way you can ignore these errors on the right,
these are related to my local network here.
So now I got no products in the carts
and if we have a look at our cart.json it's indeed empty, product.json still has the products though.
And if I quickly add another product with no real image, like this
so that I have more than one and I add both to my cart
and I delete just a book here, only that is removed, also in carts.json.
So this seems to work just fine,
let's also delete this one now,
seems to work good and with that, we improved our app a lot and you hopefully get a bit of a feeling
for how you can pass data around and how you can work with your models. Now correctly you would say that
of course
our current approach here in the modules is a bit suboptimal because working with the file and so on,
it's not that great,
we can also improve some things in the controllers because for example as I said, we should redirect if
we know that the deletion succeeded and not right after this line
because since we access a file in there, theoretically we should use a callback here too.
But these are all things I will do once we finally also added the database, something we will do in the
next module now.
So time to move on to this exciting big block of the course.