Now let's see what was causing that issue
and for that let's console log user cart
items to see what's in there
when we place an order. So if I click order now now and I increase the console, we see product ID indeed does hold a full
object and not just the ID which is what gets stored though,
if I refresh my orders, now I got two but both orders actually just have the product ID in there, not
the full product,
I want to have the full product data though. Now one thing we can do is here when I store the product
ID, I can wrap that in curly braces to create a new javascript object, use the spread operator and use that
not directly on the product ID but on a special field
mongoose gives me, _doc. I can access this here because product ID actually will be an object
with a lot of metadata attached to it even though we can't directly see that when console logging
it
but with .doc we get really access to just the data that's in there
and then with the spread operator inside of a new object,
we pull out all the data in that document we retrieved and store it in a new object which we save here as a
product.
And with that if we save that and we go back to the cart and I click order
now, I get no error
and if I go back to my compass interface and I have a look at this new order, there I see indeed I got
all the product detail data in there too.
So this is now working
and this now allows me to store all the data I want to store with every order.
Now with that being stored, of course the missing part is that we also clear the cart.