I will create a new controller, auth.js that is related to my users, to my user data, to my authentication
logic and in there I'll first of all import my user model by requiring it from my models folder, the
user file.
Now we need at least two actions here and the first one is of course the action to sign a new user up.
So I'll name this action sign up and I'll get my request, my response and that next function
and in here I want to add all the logic I need to create a new user in the database. So for that
let's extract the email from request body email, let's extract the name of the user from request body
name and let's extract the password from request body password.
Now obviously to extract all of that, we need to know that it's there,
so we should add validation. For this
I'll go to my auth routes again and just as in feed.js,
I will add this express validator check,
so I will copy that import from feed.js and add it to auth.js
and on sign up, I'll then add an array of validation related middleware.
I'll check my request
body and there, the email field whether it is an email, you can also just to bring this back into memory define
our own messages if we want to,
please enter a valid email,
this will then be stored in the error object we can retrieve.
We can also add our own custom validator here to check whether the email address already exists, for
this
I'll import my user model, so require that from the models folder and then custom and you learned
that in the validation module by the way in case you want to dive deeply into that again.
The custom function or the custom validator method here takes a function as an argument which retrieves
the value we're looking at
and then an object from which we can extract the request as a property with this destructuring syntax
and this function then should return true if validation succeeds or return a promise
if the validation actually uses some async task,
so if the validation does something which takes a little longer as in our case.
So I will return user find one and I want to find one user where the email of that user as stored in
the database matches the value of the e-mail we're looking at.
Now then I have my user document here, so my user object as I've found it in the database and if that
is set and that's the only case I'm caring about,
if that is set then I will reject a promise, so I will return promise reject and that will cause the validation
to fail,
all other scenarios will cause it to succeed and then I'll return email address already exists.
So that's just another validation we can add.
Of course I don't just want to validate the email though,
so let's also validate another field in the request body,
before I do that though, just one step I forgot,
I will normalize the email as well
but now I can look at other body fields like the password. The password can be trimmed and should then
have let's say a length of at least 5 characters or whatever you want and I'll add another check where
I'll look into my body, there to the name,
trim it to remove excess whitespace and this should now not be empty.
With that, I got all my validation logic added,
now that I'm in here I can also already import my controller,
so my auth controller can be imported from controllers auth and now I'll use that auth controller as the
last middleware on my sign up route
and reach out to the sign up action in there. Now validation was added, now back in the auth controller,
we want to collect any validation errors right at the start
and for that I need to import something
from the express validator package again
and that will be that validation result function which I require from express validator/check,
so this validation result function here and I collect errors by calling that and passing the request
to it
and now if not errors is empty, so if we got errors, then I know that something went wrong or that I have
errors
and in this case I want to create a new error where I say validation failed, something like that and I'll
set a status code of 422 and I can also maybe pass some data, a new property I'll add where I store
my errors array like this
and then I can throw my error here.
Didn't do that before but this would allow me to keep my errors which were retrieved by that validation
package,
I now just have to go to app.js, to my error handling function and there retrieve the data from
error,
the data property and also add this to the response I'm sending in case of an error.
This is totally optional but just to show how you could keep your original errors and pass them to the
frontend as well.
So now I'm doing this, I'm doing that validation and throwing an error if it fails, if we make it past this
if check, we know we have all that data we need and now we can start storing the user in the database.
Now there are parts of the authentication module which still matter here
and one of them is that we should encrypt the password.
So let's finish
sign up in a secure way in the next lecture.