So let's clear the cart after storing an order
and for that, here once I'm done with saving the order, I want to clear the cart
and one way to do that would be to go to the user model and add a new method there.
We can go to the user schema, to the methods key and then add a clear cart method,
so simply a function we can call to clear the entire cart
and how would we do that?
Well we would simply set this cart equal to an object where we have an empty array of items and then
we just return this, whoops, return this save and that should be it. That updates the carts to have no
items in it anymore and we then save this and therefore we update this. With this, let's go back to the
shop controller
and here once we know that the order was placed, let's simply call request user clear cart,
this method we just added and then I will return that and move my redirection into a new then block
after the previous one which will only execute once the cart was cleared.
So now with that, let's save that, let's now also go to products and maybe add another product to our cart.
Let's order that cart
now, let's click on cart again, no products in cart, this is looking great.
Let's quickly check our orders in compass and this new order should now have two products, that is looking
good,
one with quantity two, that was our nice book and one with quantity one, that was the second product
and in the users, the cart is empty.
So now we got an elegant way of managing orders and the cart through mongoose.
However let's of course also add the functionality to get the cart in the next lecture.