So that's it for this module. I'll actually dive into some other authentication related things in the next
modules, for example we'll add password resetting but these are the basic things you need to know about
authentication. You learned what authentication means, that it means that not every visitor of your page
can view and do everything, that authentication has to happen on the server side to ensure that users
don't trick you into thinking they are authenticated and that you therefore use sessions to store the
authentication status and that you can protect routes by checking that session controlled login status
right before the request reaches your controller action or the code in general that is executed in a
route.
Now authentication obviously also is strongly tied to security and providing a good user experience
and therefore passwords should absolutely be stored in a hashed form. If you store them in plain text,
if your database gets compromised, the attackers have full access to your user accounts.
Additionally csrf attacks, cross-site request forgery attacks are a real issue because your session
can be stolen there so to say and therefore you should implement csrf protection as shown in this module
in any production ready app you're planning to ship.
Now for a better user experience, you can look into flashing data or messages as we did it in this module
into your session store,
flashing means that this data will be removed from the session automatically by the package we used once
we used the data and we can use that data to persist data across redirects because redirects technically
trigger two different requests or we have the old request we redirect and then a new request starts and
if we want to share data across request as you learned, we need to use a session.
So these are the general authentication related things you need
and with this knowledge, you already get very very far.
Now in the next module, we'll have a look at how we can send mails from inside our node application because
we'll need that feature to then enhance our application a little bit regarding the authentication so that
we can also add a password resetting mechanism.
We'll do this in the module thereafter but in the next module,
let's first of all have a look at how we send mails.