To store the password we should hash it so that if someone gains access to our database, the password
is not stored in plaintext. For that,
I'll install a new package which we used before and that is bcryptjs which allows us to hash
a password in a secure way. After this was installed,
we can rerun npm start and now in my auth controller, I'll import bcrypt by requiring it from the
bcryptjs package and in there,
so in down there in my sign up action, I'll use bcrypt and there, the hash method to hash the
password which is plaintext here with a salt of 12,
so a strength of 12
so to say
and I'll then continue or face errors here.
Now if I have an error here somewhere,
then it'll be a server side error,
I'll copy the logic from before,
so from my feed.js controller where I just check for the existence of a status code, if no status code
exists,
I'll set
500 and
well throw that error like this.
In the then block however, we'll have our hashed password and that is the password I now want to store
in the database.
So in here, I'll now create a new user with the help of my user constructor, so my user model created
through mongoose and I'll set the fields I need to set on the user,
so that would be email, password, name, status.
Actually we can change the status here from require true to default of I am new,
so now we don't need to set it when creating a user, instead
every user will start with this status here, just a little adjustment.
With that we don't need to set the status but we do need to set e-mail, password and name. So the email
is the extracted e-mail, the password
is the hashed password, not the extracted one but the hashed one to secure this and the name is the extracted
name.
Now last but not least, I will call save to save that to the database and I will return that so that we can
add another
then block where we get the result of that database operation and here we know it will have succeeded,
so we can return a response with a status code of 201 because a resource was created where
I can return some json data with a message of user created and then maybe the user ID which I can extract
from the result which is the user object, result._id.
So now we're creating a user here,
let's now save that and to see that on the frontend, we need to go into the frontend code and in there to
the app.js file
and here first of all, we need to correct our url and I also need to change something so that we start
in unauthenticated mode.
Currently we are starting as if we were authenticated,
I'll have to change that in the frontend too.
Now first of all in the sign up handler, let's fix that url and there, the url will be localhost
8080/auth/signup and that will reach this route here right
because it's /signup
and we only end up there for requests that start with /auth.
Now we defined a put request here on the backend so we have to set the method in the second argument in
this object we pass to fetch,
we have to set the method to put.
We also need to append some data and that data will be of type application json,
so we should add the content type header and set this to application
json. Last but not least, let's add the request body and here we'll need to use json stringify to convert
an object to json and that object will be a javascript object with the e-mail which we can retrieve
from auth data email, auth data is an argument we'll get here
and I wrote the code to make sure that we get the data the user entered.
So we'll get the e-mail,
we'll get the password
so let's also extract that from auth data and we'll get the name from auth data,
so everything which we extract on the server side. This is now all passed to our backend, now in app.js,
scroll up a bit more to the very top, here in this state, you
now should change isAuth to false
so did we start unauthenticated. Now
when you when the page reloads, you start on the login page and you can switch to sign up and there,
let's create a new user, you can enter any name you want
and I accidentally hit enter which is good because we now see validation is doing its job
but now let me enter a valid password which you should remember and click sign up and it still failed.
Let's see what's wrong here,
let's inspect for which field we're getting this
by inspecting the network tab and then here we see ok all three fields give us the error.
That's kind of a strong signal that the data is simply not passed to the backend at all, so something
seems to be wrong there,
indeed we can validate this by clicking on headers,
there we see there is no request payload added to this request
and that's simply a little mistake on my side. In app.js in the frontend code in sign up handler,
here where I extract after the e-mail and so on,
that should be signupform.email.value and the same for all the other fields too.
So let's add sign up form in front of that and .value at the end, the same for the name and
this is how the data is stored here internally in the react app and this how we should extract it.
So let's give this another try,
let's pick an email address, a name and a password
and now this looks much better.
I get back user created, I'm forwarded to the login page here in my frontend, I get that user ID
and of course we can as always use
mongodb compass to also take a closer look at our database,
there I got this messages database,
if I reload it now, I got a users collection in there
and here I have that user.
So that is working,
the user also has a starting status,
now we have no posts of course.
Now we can continue and we can work on logging the user in and that will now be the interesting part
because I already mentioned that authentication will now work differently.