So SQL or NoSQL, that is the question and to answer that question,
we first of all have to understand the differences or what SQL and NoSQL databases are, how
they differ, how they differ regarding how we store the data and so on.
Our goal always is to store data and make it easily available or accessible so that we have an easy
way of accessing our data and not just easy from a code perspective
but of course efficient, it should be fast.
That is why we use a database,
it's simply quicker than accessing a file especially as the data in there grows,
it also helps us with things like we don't have to read the entire file to just find one piece of information.
Now as I mentioned, we can opt for a SQL-based database,
MySQL would be an example database engine that you can use or a NoSQL database and there mongodb
is one of the most prominent and well known alternatives.
So what is SQL, how does it work then? SQL database
thinks in so-called tables,
so we might have a users, a product and let's say an orders table and in each table, you have so-called
fields or columns, for example a user could be defined by having an ID, an email, a name and a product
could have an ID, title, price and a description.
Now we fill in data for these fields, so-called records,
so basically the rows in our tables. For example here we got a couple of users with their data and we
get a couple of products too. SQL based databases
also have
one important thing, they allow you to relate different tables, for example an order could simply be described
as a connection of a user and a product right
because a user might order a couple of different products and a product might be ordered by a couple
of different users.
So basically we have such relations in SQL based databases, here
we can see one example relation.
This is one of the core things about SQL and in general, the core SQL database characteristics
are that we have a strong data schema so that for each table, we clearly define how the data in there
should look like,
so which fields do we have,
which type of data does each field store,
is it a number,
is it string, is it a text,
is it a boolean?
So that we have this strongly or strictly defined schema and all data in the table has to fit the schema
for this table,
this is really important,
so this schema, this definition of how the data has to look like is one core thing in a SQL database.
We also have relations between our data, that is another core characteristic of SQL based database,
we relate our different tables with basically three important kinds of relations, one to one, one to many
or many to many,
this simply means that we can have two tables where each record fits one other record,
a record might fit multiple other records or multiple records in table A can fit multiple records in table
B and you'll see this in practice and in the code in this module.
So tables are connected,
that's another important thing.
Now SQL simply stands for structured query language,
so queries are a crucial things,
queries are simply commands we use to interact with the database. And in SQL, a query look something
like this,
of course there are different commands,
this would be a command that selects all users, so all entries, all records in the users table where the
age is greater than 28.
So this is a so-called query,
we've got a couple of keywords there which are making up that SQL language, so the structured query
language simply has these keywords and then we insert some parameters or some data we connect with
these keywords,
this is how SQL works.
Now let's have a look at NoSQL
in the next lecture then.