So how bad are errors?
Now errors are not necessarily the end of your app,
you can recover from the errors,
you can inform the user that something went wrong and that he should try again
for example, you just need to handle errors correctly
that is the key takeaway and there are different types of errors.
We can have technical or network related errors where you have very little influence on at least if
you're not the system administrator,
we have so-called expected errors and this is not an official term,
that is something I came up with and I'll explain what this is in a second
and we also have bugs or logical errors in your code.
Now for technical errors, our mongodb server might be down and therefore any interaction
with the database will fail. In such a case,
there's not that much we can do,
the best thing might be to show some error page to the user to let the user know that something is wrong
on our end, that we are sorry and that we're working on fixing the issue.
We also might want to behind the scenes send an e-mail to the administrator or anything like that.
We also have these expected errors as I like to call them.
There are certain operations,
let's say we are interacting with a file or with a database that can fail,
not very often
and of course it's not really expected for this to fail but that can happen.
Maybe because there are too many simultaneous requests to a certain file, anything like that. Here informing
the user and giving the user the ability to retry
might be a good solution.
For example the validation errors which we also implement in earlier module, these would also be expected
errors, users will input valid and invalid data and for invalid data, we want to inform the user and give the
user the chance of retrying
and of course we also have errors in our code where we interact with a user object in a place where
it just can't exist or at least not in all circumstances.
We should fix such errors during development,
we should test our code and we should fix such issues of course,
these are not errors
we should handle at runtime,
we should not show a message to the user because these errors are not the users or the network's fault,
they are our fault.
So how can we work with the different types of errors then? We have to differentiate.
There are errors where an error is thrown, an error is a technical object in a node application.
So there is a built in error object which we can throw
that's also a javascript language features,
basically all programming languages have such a feature.
We also can have scenarios where we can't continue with our code but there is no technical error.
An example would be that we try to log a user in but the email address does not exist,
this is not really a technical error,
there is no error being thrown but we know we can't continue
and so we want to check for this scenario as well and handle it appropriately.
Now for the errors thrown part, we have certain tools we can use to test code and catch potential errors
so that we can handle them gracefully
and for synchronous code, that would be try catch blocks. For asynchronous code with promises, we have
then and catch which you already saw quite a lot throughout this course.
In the end in both scenarios, we then have the choice if we want to directly handle the error or if we
use a mechanism built into express, a special error handling middleware which we haven't used thus far
which you can use to catch errors and then return a response to the user and I'll show how this works
in this module of course. For this scenario that no error is thrown,
well we just have to check values with if checks for example and then we can decide whether we want to
throw an error, to kind of enter the left world here and then kick off that error handling process
or if we want to directly handle the error which is not a technical error but where we simply add some
code that can continue with the missing input data
for example. In all cases, we've got different ways of communicating with our users.
We can return an error page,
so a dedicated page that informs the user hey we have a problem and that of course should be kind of
the last resort because there the user loses all his input, can't continue.
We also can return the page which user was on and just give some error information,
that is what we did for validating for example, there we returned the page the user was on, kept the input
values and just added an error message.
Or we could redirect,
for example if we try to access a page which we are not authenticated to visit, then we can redirect the user.
So these are the different tools
we have, the different ways of working with errors we have
and now let's dive into our code and see what we're already using and what we can use.