So what is a cookie?
Well here's our setup, we got a user using browser and we got our server where our node application runs
on.
Now the user interacts with the frontend with the views we render with the ejs templating engine
in this course but of course I'm talking about any views you might be rendering in your project with
which ever templating engine you are using and from inside that view,
let's say we have a form there to add a new product,
we submit a request to our node server.
Now let's say that request requires us to store some kind of data in the browser,
let's say we're not working with the add product page but let's say we have a login page and when the
user logs in, we want to store the information that the user is logged in somewhere so that when the
user reloads the page and therefore technically a new request is sent, we still have that information
around that the user is logged in
and for that, we can send back a cookie with the response we send back upon the request.
So the user submits the login data and we return a response which can be a new view to which we redirect
to user
but we also include our cookie and that cookie simply is important to well telling the user or to storing
that information that the user is authenticated. We can store that information in the browser,
so in the frontend so to say, in the environment the user interacts with and we can send this
with subsequent requests to include the cookie there to send the data we stored in the cookie, like for
example that information that we are logged in to the server,
so cookies are stored on the client side.
Now this is really abstract,
let's simply try it out
in our application.