So what is mongodb?
Now let me first of all tell you that I do actually have a complete course for developers on mongodb,
so you might want to check that out if you want to learn way more about mongodb than I'll be able
to cover in this course
but now with that let me start with a brief introduction to mongodb at least, what is it? Mongodb
is both the name of the company which developed mongodb but also then of their most famous product,
a database solution, a database engine you could say, a tool you can use to run very efficient NoSQL
databases.
The name stems from the word humongous because mongodb was built for one major purpose, that you could
store and work
and that really is important, the work part, that you could store and work with lots and lots of data.
So mongodb is built for large scale applications, mongodb is built to quickly query data, store
data, interact with data,
so it's really fast and it's really awesome database philosophy that is behind NoSQL databases and
therefore also behind
mongodb.
Now how does it work?
Well just like in the SQL world, we spin up a mongodb server and there we can have multiple databases,
for example a shop database. Now in such a database in the SQL world, we would have multiple tables,
in the NoSQL mongodb world
we have multiple collections like the users and orders collection for example.
Now inside of each collection, we don't have so-called records but we have a couple of documents. Now
documents also look different
than records did and it's not just about different names being used,
the core philosophy behind the database really is a totally different one.
For example mongodb is schemaless, inside of one collection, your documents which is your data, your
entry so to say don't have to have the same structure. In SQL that was totally different,
we had a users table there and in that users table, we had an ID, a name, an email, a password.
Now here that is different,
here we can have any kind of data in one and the same collection.
Often you will still end up with an at least similar structure but you're not forced to have exactly
the same structure
and this gives you more flexibility, also for your application to grow and to change its data requirements
over time
without that being difficult to depict in your database world.
So this is one thing, a document in mongodb looks like this
and this looks a lot like javascript object notation
and to be precise it kind of is. Mongodb uses json to store data in collections,
so every document you store looks something like this,
it follows the javascript object notation format. To be very precise mongodb uses something which
is called bson for binary json but that only means that mongodb kind of transforms this behind
the scenes before storing it in the files
but you don't have to worry about that,
you will basically use it as json. Now such a json document is basically the same as a javascript
object you could say and there as you see, we can have nested or as mongodb calls them, embedded
documents, for example the address here would hold an embedded document.
And you can also have arrays inside of that document and that array can
like in this case hold other documents, other objects or it could also just hold strings, numbers,
anything of that kind.
So again for the data, you have great flexibility and the existence of these nested documents also means
that relations are managed a bit differently in the NoSQL mongodb world.
So let me come back to that in the next lecture.