So in this module, you learned about mongoose and I can only encourage you to dive into the official
mongoose documentation to learn all about it and the many features it offers
and I do really mean it as I said in the last lecture.
Play around with our application,
try adding sub-totals or totals to our orders here,
play around, feel free to experiment with the data and with our application,
this is what coding is all about
in the end. The official docs for mongoose and mongodb or sequelize and SQL if you want to
stick to that should give you everything you need to dive deeper and play around.
At this point in the course though, you have a solid understanding of the different database solutions you
could use, how you would use them,
why using tools like sequelize or mongoose might make a lot of sense and how you can integrate them
into your application.
Now what exactly you use,
which database and which features of which package always depends on your exact application.
I hope that these last modules gave you a great overview over the pool of options you could choose
from and what you can do with them.
We will continue with mongoose and mongodb in this course,
however feel free to of course play around with SQL if you need that for your next project.
But we will continue with that,
we will therefore add some other features throughout the course, do a bit more with the database when we are able
to do it
like for example validate input and build our application whilst at the same time learning way more
about node and express in general throughout the rest of this course.