Now talking about deleting, there's one more thing we should do in case we do succeed. We should clear
the relation of posts and users.
If we refresh the post collection, we only have one item there
but if I have a look at my users there now, the first user has a couple of posts
and the second user has so too because right now we have no logic to clear posts
when I delete them, to clear relations and we should of course do that.
Now how can we get rid of a relation? Well we delete the post anyways, so there's nothing we need to do
there
but on the user, we need to pull our reference. To do that we should find the user after we deleted a post
let's say, so here I'll find a user by ID and I can use my request
user ID here
and I will return that user object in there.
Well let's grab that code and add another
then block where I will have that user mongoose model fetched from my database.
Now in there,
I will use my user model and there, the posts array and then there is a pull method mongoose gives me,
there I need to pass the ID of the post I want to remove.
Now I deleted the post already here but the post ID is still available of course, so I can pass post
ID here.
Now I can call save here to save that updated user and return that, grab the response one more time and
add another
then block with the result of that operation
and here, I'm done with clearing the relation.
Now to see that in action,
let me actually get rid of all users manually by using mongodb compass,
also get rid of all posts and logout here and let's create a brand new user because we cleared all
users,
like this.
Let's login with that user and let's create a new post, a duck, use that duck image, it ducks around for sure and
click accept
and before we do anything, let's go back to mongoose, to mongodb compass I mean, there we can see that
this post has this creator and this user
more importantly has this post in his posts array.
Now I'm logged in with the right user, let's click delete.
This worked and now if I refresh posts, we got no posts in there because I deleted the only post we had
and in users, this array is now also empty,
so now we're clearing this as well.