In our project as I mentioned in the previous lectures, we already got some views and we'll leave that
exactly in the state it is.
We've got that views folder with all our templates inside of them.
Now what's missing is a folder for the controllers and the controllers themselves and for the models.
Right now that is all mixed into our route files or into our route functions here, the way we route won't
change,
we use the router and we have such a middleware function but actually, the logic that is executed here
that is the typical controller logic, we're interacting with our data even though that's just one line
here but still
and we're then returning a view and that's exactly this in-between logic that makes up a controller.
So therefore you could of course say well we already got controllers, these two files hold our controller
logic and you would be right
but especially as our application grows if you put everything into your route files, this can quickly
become a very big file and therefore separating this into separate files can be a good idea because
you can then quickly see which routes you have and if you want to see the code which executes per route,
you simply go into the respective controller file and function.
So therefore let's create a new folder here and let's name it
controllers, like this.
Now in that controllers folder, I will create controllers for the functionalities I have.
Now you can have a one to one mapping between your route file names and route file number and your controller
files but you can also split this differently,
maybe you want to group your routes by prefix, like here,
these are all our admin routes
but the thing you execute there might fit two different controllers.
Let's say you have admin routes which allow you to change your admin user profile and products, you might
have all these routes in the admin.js file in the routes folder but you do have two different controllers,
the users controller or admin controller and the product controller.
So this is up to you and I will indeed create different files here,
I'll have my product.js file or products.js for my product related logic and I will put all
the product logic in there,
so even my shop route here where I also work with products, I'll put that logic in here because all logic
I have in my app thus far and this will change later
but all logic thus far is related to products and therefore, I want to have it in a controller that only
works with product logic. And if I later add some user logic, that will go into a user controller and maybe
we even split the product controller into a user product and an admin product controller
but for now, we'll leave it like this.
So in that products.js file in the controllers folder, I now want to add that code here basically.
So this middleware function we're executing here,
this code for add product right where I just render this add product route,
this can now go into there and
the question just is how
because this would be incorrect.
Well in the end we want to link to this function and we want to link there from inside our route,
so here we basically want to add a link to this controller function here.
So therefore what do we need to do?
We need to export this function in the product controller file and we can do this and we'll have multiple
exports by using exports
and then any name of our choice.
Remember with this syntax, we can have multiple exports in one file easily.
So here I will now export my get add product function here and the name is up to you but I name it like
this because in the end this is what we do,
we get the add product page.
Of course you could also name it get add product page here but I will just describe what this in the end
helps me do and it helps me get everything I need to add a product
but you can name this to your likings.
So now I get this product and I still have my function which receives the request object even though
we're not using it here but we still get that, the response object which we are using and next because
this still is a normal middleware function expressjs understands because I will now import get add
product into my admin.js file and still using here on my route,
this will not change,
I just split my code differently. So with that, let's
add an import,
by the way we can get rid of this root
dir import because I'm not using that utility anymore,
you can also therefore delete the entire file or even folder
but that's just a side note.
So let's now import our controller and there, I will import products
controller by requiring
my controllers folder and there, the products file.
So since I'm doing this from inside my admin.js file here, I need to go up one level until I'm in
the root project folder and then I go into the controllers folder and then I pick that products file.
So now products controller bundles all the exported functions and right now, this is only one of course
but it will become more. So back in admin.js here on this route where I want to use that, I can now simply
say products controller.get add product. And we don't execute this function
so please don't add these parentheses,
instead we just pass a reference to this function.
So we're just saying or we're just telling express, the express router that it should take this function
and store it
and whenever a request reaches this route, it should go ahead and execute it.
Now we can repeat this for adding a new product,
I'll cut this code and go to my product controller and simply add a brand new export and I'll name this
post add product because this is what I do here,
I post a new product I add the product therefore through a post route and this will be the function
I just copied.
Now the problem here is that we refer to products which is of course something we don't have in that
file yet, so I should also go into admin.js and take my products array which I have
there, cut it out of there and then in products.js in the controllers file,
I will add this array and I'll change this later too but for now, let's simply add it here,
products should be our empty array.
Now back in admin.js, we can now also use our new products controller function we just added, post add
product in exactly the same way we use get add product
and of course we can now tweak our exports here,
we no longer need to export products in our admin.js file because we no longer have that array in here.
So instead I'll just export my router again as I'm doing it in the shop.js file.
So with module exports equal to router, that is what we have here too
and this just means that we now have to adjust the app.js file where we are importing this, there I'm importing
admin data, now
a more fitting name is admin routes again because now we just export routes and nothing else
and of course that also means that here where we use that, we just use admin routes because we change
that export. Ok good,
so we get this set up,
now let's also do the same for shop.js.
There I also get a function which is related to products,
so let's cut it
and in products.js here,
I will add a new export, exports get products like this.
If I do this, I have my function here which will in the end return or render that page with my products
and one important note, obviously products is now an array which is available in that file,
so products here doesn't have to be extracted from anywhere
and again we will change this.
So this is now my finished products
controller in shop.js,
we can now remove these two imports because we don't need them anymore
instead I import my products controller by requiring it from the same path as in the admin.js file
and here for this get route, I will simply say products controller get products. With all that,
let's save this and see if it still works.
If I reload this page, this all seems to work
and if I add my first book here, this also works.
So it's still working as before but now we're using a controller.
Now let's see what else we can do here.