So we want to be able to enter an email address here and then receive an email with a link that allows
us to reset the password.
Now for that, we need to first of all create a unique token that also has some expiry date which we will
store in our database so that the link which we didn't click includes that token and we can verify that
the user did get that link from us because if we just, well let the user now change that password, we
got no security mechanism in place, so we need that token to put it into the email we're about to send
to only let users change the password through the email that contains that token,
that's an additional security mechanism.
So let's work on that token creation then and for that
first of all, I'll export a new action in my auth controller and that will be post reset, so that will basically
the action that should get triggered once we clicked that reset password button here and in there,
I need to generate that token.
Now nodejs has a built-in crypto library which I can use for that,
so I'll name that crypto and require crypto like that. This is a library that helps us with creating secure
unique random values and other things but we'll need that unique secure random value here.
So here in post, we settled and use that crypto library which I stored in a constant here
and I will call random bytes to generate some random bytes, I want
32 random bytes and this will call a callback function here, so this is the second argument, a function
will be called once it's done and there I
either get an error or a buffer, a buffer of these bytes.
Now I have an error here
then I want to return redirect back to let's say reset and we could flash an error message here if we
wanted to, I'll also log the error so that we can debug it
but if we make it past this check, we do have a valid buffer
and then we can generate a token from that buffer, simply by using buffer toString and there we just
need to pass hex because that buffer will store hexadecimal values
and this is information toString needs to convert hexadecimal values to normal ASCII characters.
So then we'll have a token.
Now that token should get stored in the database and it should get stored on the user object because
it belongs to that user,
so let's first of all go to our user model and there, I'll add two new fields,
I'll add a reset token and I'll just assign a type of string here.
Now important, this is not required because not always this token will be there, only if we requested
a reset and we'll have a reset token expiration or however you want to name it
and that will be of type date
and now I want to store that token on the user which we plan to reset.
So first of all I need to find that user in the database and I'll use the mongoose user model for that,
to find one user where the email matches the email we're trying to reset and that email which we're trying
to reset can be extracted from the request body email field because on our reset view here, we
do have that email field.
By the way important, the action here should be /reset to reach the right route but with that, this is
prepared and now in our controller, I'm finding a user who has this email. Now let's add then and catch, handle
any potential error we might get by logging it for now
and then in then, we should get a user or undefined if that user does not exist.
So in here I want to check if we don't have a user.
If we don't have a user, then I will flash a message as you learned it in the authentication module
onto the error key, no account with that e-mail found or whatever message you want to show
and then here I'll return a redirect to /reset.
If we make it past this if check, then we are looking for an e-mail address that is stored in the database
and now for that user which I retrieved for that e-mail address, I want to set the reset token
equal to the token which I generated and I will set the reset token expiration equal to date now which
gives me the current date and the time plus one hour
and this now has to be expressed in milliseconds,
so you should use 3,600,000milliseconds,
this will be one hour. So now I'm assigning these two fields and we can call user save to then update
our user in the database.
Let's return this so that we can now chain another then call here, another
then block which will execute this function when user save succeeds.
So at this point of time, we know that the updated user was stored in the database and now we want to
send that token reset email.
Now I showed you how to send e-mails in the last lecture, in the last module I mean,
so make sure you through that because I will now use that transporter again which I created there,
the node mailer transporter which we use for sending email
and I will send an e-mail to the e-mail of the user which we found, so to user e-mail, excuse me, to
request body e-mail we can say, so to the e-mail we're requesting the reset for, the subject could be
password reset and now in the html code,
I'll use a next gen feature, back ticks which allows me to write multiline strings which makes it a bit easier
to read.
I'll add a paragraph where I say you requested a password reset, so users should be worried if they get
that
if they did not click this link to set a new password and you could include more information like the
fact that this is only valid for one hour.
Now this link here, this will be anchor tag leading at some url and that url will be in
our case your localhost 3000
and then let's say reset and then the token which we have. Now since I'm using this back tick syntax,
I can dynamically embed values with a special syntax where
I use ${}
and now I can inject variables and their values into this string and the values of the variables will
be placed in that string.
So here, I can now output that token which we generated here,
so now I am placing that in the url because that token is then what we'll later look for in the database
to confirm that this link was sent by us because only we know the token.
So this will send an email and at the same time, I will redirect back to the starting page let's say
because the next instructions are received in the email of course.
Now let's try this out in the next lecture.