I'm setting these query parameters and I can use that data on the backend to control which data I want
to fetch,
obviously I do that in my controllers and there in the shop controller. Here.
we're working on the index page so I'm looking for the get index controller action. In here I need to
retrieve the information on which page we are,
so which data for which page needs to be displayed,
so I'll store this information in a new constant named page and in that constant, well I will store
request and then we can get query parameters on the query object provided by expressjs
and there I can access page, page because I named that query parameter page here.
So now with that, I'm getting that page number and I'll store it in this constant.
Now with that, we just need to define how many items should be displayed per page
and that's something I will store as a global constant in this file,
I could also store it in a different file, export it there and import it here
but I will
name this items per page
and this will be let's say 2,
it should be some number lower than the number of items you have here so that you can see a difference.
So I have two items per page here and with that in get index,
I know that I if I'm on page one want to fetch the first two items,
if I'm on page two, I want to fetch items three and four, on page three I would fetch four and five and so
on.
Therefore we now need to control the amount of data we're retrieving from the database, find right now
gives us all the items but we can actually control this. In mongodb
and therefore also mongoose,
there is a skip function. We can add this on a cursor and find does return a cursor to skip the first
X amount of results and here, that would be page -1,
so the previous page number in brackets times items per page.
So if I am on page 2, I would skip the first page -1, so the first one times items per page items.
So on page 2, if I have 2 items per page, I would skip the first one times two, the first two items.
I don't just want to skip some items,
I also want to limit the amount of items I retrieve though, so that I don't just skip the items of
previous pages but for the current page, I also only fetch as many items as I want to display there and
this can be done with the limit method.
The limit method as the name suggests limits the amount of data we fetch to
the, well number we specify here and here I can pass items per page because that is my item limit per page.
With that if we save this code, we can reload this first page with the query parameter set to page 1 and
we only see the first two items.
If I now click on two down there, I only see the third item because I'm on page 2,
I skip the first two items and I fetch the next two items and I only happened to have one other item.
On page 3 if I would enter this, we would not find any products because I have no items for this page
but Page 1 and 2 were just fine.
So this is the general idea behind pagination.
Now obviously the idea would be that
we update our pagination buttons here based on, well the page we are on and the maximum number of pages
that are available or something like that.
So let's see what we can do
there.