So let's use multer now on our backend. We can restart the server already because we installed that
package
and now let's go to our admin controller and let's work on post add product here,
we want to use multer to extract incoming files. Now multer is actually not a package which we will
use in here, instead just like the body parser we use here,
multer is some middleware which we execute on every incoming request and it then simply has a look at that
request,
sees if it's multipart form data and tries to extract files if that is the case.
So it is some extra middleware we add
and therefore we can import it here in our app.js file.
We can import multer by requiring it from the package like this,
multer and thereafter we can use it,
so maybe after the body parser, we can use multer.
Multer has to be executed as a function and then we have to call another method on that
and that simply defines if you expect to get multiple files or only one file and we will only expect
one file,
so we use the single method
and then we define the input name which will hold the file and in our case, that is image
and this is not a random value,
I'm using image here because in my view, this input which holds the file, so this file picker here is
named image as well.
So with that, we initialize multer
and let's now see if that works.
Now to see that, we need to know how multer will actually store the incoming file and for that, let me go
back to post add product and instead of extracting request body image, let me access request file here and
let's see what this gives us,
I will also console log image url now.
Now let's save all that and see what that gives us.
If I now try to add a product again, I'll choose that same file from before, enter any values up here,
click add product
and I still get an error.
Now if we go back, we see something interesting though, indeed here
this part is what I log here.
So here what we see is that multer seems to have done something,
it seems to have stored something in that file property on our request object
and that is what we print here essentially and it stored the name of the field where it extracted
that, it detected the file name, it detected the mime type
so which type of file that is
and that buffer here is essentially how node handles the binary data.
You'll learn about streams and buffers earlier, in the end
this is the result of the streamed data, the file basically was sent to our server as a stream or was
handled as a stream to handle it efficiently if it was bigger and then this is the collected data in a
buffer which as we learned is like a bus stop,
it gives you a way of working with the stream data, here in this case it's the combined stream and data
and we could indeed work with that buffer to turn it into a file.
Now you can actually configure multer a bit differently if
we go back to app.js, when we set up multer, we can pass an object to the multer function and there
we can set some options
and one option is the dest option.
Now here we could specify /images or just images, like this.
What this will do is that when I again add a product here and don't worry that it still fails because
we're trying to store the file in the database right now and we'll do all kinds of stuff with it for which
our code is not prepared but the upload works
but with this option set, you also see that the output down there changed a little bit.
We don't have the buffer because now multer is able to do something with the buffer, instead of just
buffering it all in memory,
it can then turn that buffer back into binary data you could say and it stores it in this path here.
So indeed if you have a look at your folder, you should not have an images folder with some file in there.
Now that file has some random hash name, does not have a file extension and is not recognized as an image
but indeed if I change that and I add .png at the end, this is the image I uploaded.
So this does work.
All we now need to do is we need to tweak the way this file is named and that is something we'll do
in the next lecture.