We added multer and as you can see, multer is able to accept our incoming data, extract the files and
store them for us and then store information about the file upload in this request file object here
which we output which in the end contains this data.
Now all we have to do is we have to ensure that our data gets stored correctly
and for that we specify the destination folder
but we can do more,
we can set the storage key here which gives us way more configuration options than just the dest option.
Now for that, to configure a storage here, I will actually set up a new configuration object, maybe up
there,
file storage, the name is up to you.
It's a constant
and the value will be something I get from the multer package, there
it's the disk storage function. Disk storage is in the end a storage engine which you can use with multer
and there you can pass a javascript object to configure that.
It takes two keys, it takes the destination and it takes the file name.
These are two functions which multer will then call for an incoming file
and these functions then control how that file is handled regarding the place where you store it
and regarding the naming. So destination therefore is a function, we can make it an arrow function which
will be called by multer which receives the request object, the file object and a callback which you have
to call once you're done setting up the destination,
so this is all to interact with multer.
So in there, you can for example call the callback with null as the first argument,
that would be an error message you throw to inform multer that something is wrong with the incoming
file and it should not store it
but if that is null, you tell multer that it's OK to store it and then the second argument is the place
where you do want to store it, like that images folder.
Now file name also is a function,
so it's also an arrow function where we also received the request object, some data about the file and
a callback which we have to call to let multer know how to name it and there, we can also call this
with null to still inform multer,
ok we're fine store it please
and then the second argument is the file name which we want to use
and here we could name it image.png
but of course that would be a bit boring,
instead we can extract file and then there is an original name object which holds the original file
name,
there also is a file name object which holds this random hash
and in the end what we can do here is we can of course combine this. We can for example say I want to ensure that
if we have two images with the same name, they don't overwrite each other.
So I will use that file name which is auto-generated by multer
and then I'll concatenate it maybe with a dash in-between with the original name. With that
I also ensure that I end with that extension and now I set my own filename here by calling that callback.
Now we just need to inform multer that we want to use this storage engine and we do this by setting
this as a value for the storage key in the multer options.
Now with that if I go back and I added my product again,
so the same input, both png elected,
you will see that in those images folder you have undefined boat.png.
Now it's simply undefined here
instead of that random hash because since we did set our own filename with this function here, multer
does not generate that hash
but all we can do for example is we can use the current date,
so new data to ISO string gives us a snapshot of the current date and that should also ensure uniqueness.
If you need more, you can use some third party package that does give you a really unique hash.
But with this we're now storing files with the right extension and a unique name
and this gives us more power because now we can control the path and the filename.
And of course, we can also use that for even more because maybe we want to validate that we only support
certain mime types,
let's say png and jpg but not gifs or pdfs.
Let's do that in the next lecture.