So let's start working on the rest
API again
and for that I'll run npm start in my rest API nodejs project too and that is also the reason why
I'm using different ports by the way. Here I'm starting the application on port 8080,
my frontend application automatically takes port 3000 and this simulates that these two ends
of my application are served by different servers
in the end which is a pretty common scenario since frontend only applications like react can be served
on so-called static hosts which are optimized for applications that only consist of html, javascript
and css and hence you might indeed have two different servers even if you created both the backend
and the frontend.
So we have different ports and therefore we have different domains and therefore we definitely need
our course headers
otherwise nothing would work
and with that, we can now start working on our feed routes.
We actually got two routes already, /posts and /post for creating a new post and for getting
existing posts
and now let's add some logic so to our controller actions to actually return something useful and to
enable the user to create new posts.
Let's maybe start with getting posts because that would allow us see at least some dummy data,
so that is something useful. For that in get posts, we actually already return a list of dummy data posts,
each post has a title and some content.
Now it's of course always up to you how you want your data to look like in an application. In this application
because my frontend also expects it,
I want to have a post which in the end consists of a title which has a user attached to it, a creator
or an author which has a creation date which has an image and which has some content.
This is what I want to output in my frontend
so the data we store on the server should have all these fields in the end.
Now we don't have to start with the full package though,
I already have a title and content here,
now let's maybe add some image url here
and for that I'll create a new images folder
and for the moment I will just copy an image into that folder,
later we'll of course add image upload. I'll copy in my good old duck image which I used before in the
course
and here it is, the lovely duck.jpg
and I want to serve that duck.
So here in image url
I will actually provide images/duck.jpg as a path because that is my local path on the server
here. It's missing my domain and so on, we'll have to attach this on the frontend
but this is now a post as I could serve it. If I now save this, we can actually fetch that data with a get
request to localhost 8080/feed because that is what we have as a filter to reach the feed routes,
so /feed/posts.
Now let's try that out in our frontend application, there
we fetch our posts in a feed.js file in the source pages feed folder, in there you should find a load
posts function.
Load posts is a function that is called by the react code and so on in the end and what we do here is
I also support pagination which we'll add later,
for now I just want to reach out to my url which is http localhost 8080,
written like this
and then /feed/posts like this.
So this route I just talked about in the rest API.
This should fetch all these posts, then
here I just check if the status code is not equal to 200
which would mean that something went wrong and then I throw a new error which is handled in your react
application
otherwise I extract my body and then here, I have my body and I use some react logic to load that body
in the end and to hopefully display it.
If I save that and I go back to my application, I'll get an error regarding the name,
the author name which is missing,
I'm not supporting users yet so this will be a problem for the moment and we'll also get an error regarding
the date eventually.
So to avoid this, we should go back to our controller and add some dummy data for this too.
Let's add a creator object because that is what I'll be looking for in my react code which should be
an object with a name where you can enter any name you want,
later we'll of course connect this to a real user in the database
and let's also add a date
and here you can simply create a new date with, well new date like this.
Last but not least, you also want to add some ID and that should be _id because I'll be looking
for _id in the frontend code
in the react application
because later we'll use mongoose again here and that of course or mongodb in general and that of
course simply adds IDs with _id,
so here you can enter any ID you want.
Now if you save that updated controller code and the server therefore restarts, you can reload and
you'll still get that error
which is related to our status, our user status which we still can't fetch
but if you simply click that away, you see that first post here and that is looking better than before.
The invalid date is a problem because actually the field should be named createdAt, not date, there was
a tiny mistake on my side, on the server
it should be createdAt.
With that if you reload, you'll see this post.
So fetching posts works,
of course it's just dummy data though. To work with real data,
I want to be able to create new posts by clicking new post, so that is something we can add as a next step.