We are able to skip and limit the amount of items we fetch and we can control that with query parameters
but my buttons are hardcoded right now and that is not ideal of course,
instead I rather maybe want to highlight the page I'm currently on and then show the next page number
or the previous page number. For this
I need to fetch more information.
I will find my products and call count here, then I can also add then and catch.
The important thing is I don't need catch because I'll concatenate my other promise chain later,
the important thing here is this will now not to retrieve all the products but simply just a number,
so number of products is what I get back in this then block function here and in that function, I then
want to kick off my request where I really do fetch all the data. So we'll return product find in here
with skip and limit chained after it, that's important
and then I'll add this
then block to continue.
So I'll first of all find the count, then I have this number of products here and then I kick off my normal
find method where I then really fetch the items and I skip and limit them. Here
I'll add a variable, total items and I'll set total items equal to num products in here.
So now I will have the total number of products stored in that variable here and when I render the index
page,
then I want to return that information as well, so not just the products but also total products and
that will be total items, so that will be a number in the end and I also want to pass the information
whether there is a next page, so maybe has next page which only will be the case if the total number
of items is greater than the page we are on
times the items per page.
So we have a next page
if items per page times page is smaller than total items because if we have 10 total items and we are
on page 4, then we have 2 times 4, 8 items which we are seeing or which we saw and
we have 10 left so there will be a next page. Simultaneously
I can add has previous page here where I can simply return the information whether the current page
is greater than 1.
If that is true then there is this a previous page because there will be page one, if that is false because we are
on page one already,
well then there is no previous page because we can't go lower than one.
I can also return some extra information like the next page and that will be page plus one of course,
if we are on page 1 the next page would be page 2 and previous page would be page -1
obviously. We can also add last page to have a way of displaying the highest page number and that is math
seal
total items divided by items per page.
So if we have let's say 11 total items and we have items per page of two, then the result would be 5.5
and then math.seal would return us 6 which would be the correct value because we would need 6 pages
to display all 11 items
if we show 2 items per page. So now I'm passing all that information to my products page, to my index page
here to be precise and there, I now want to use it.