So we added a very basic validation and we get back a message which we want your output.
So this already shows us how we can work with that validation middleware, we see it rendered that page
again and now we just need to make sure we don't output object object here
but a real error message. We can do that in our sign up view of course,
here we got our error message thing and the error message which I am outputting here is simply an object
because it's that array and not a single field in there.
Now we just need to adjust something and in the controller instead of returning an array,
let's say we always want to return the first error message.
Now obviously you could change this to change the overall logic
and you need to change it in other controller actions then too to output all messages
but for now let's say we simply take the first one which we are guaranteed to have because we'll have
at least one error and then there, the message. And now if I save that and I do send just test again,
now I get invalid value, so
this is how we could output that message.
We cannot just output the message,
we can also customize it
and we have to do that in the place where we added our middleware,
so in the routes file. After isEmail,
you can add do you with message function and this will always refer to the validation logic that was
right before it because you could add multiple checks here,
you could also add isAlphanumeric to check that it only contains numbers and characters, number and characters,
so you could add multiple ones but with message, we'll always refer to the validation method right in
front of it
and there you could add please enter a valid email, something like that. And if you add this with message
here, you will see that if I enter just some text here, I get
please enter a valid email.
So this is a way of working with the messages and also of customizing it
and I also mentioned that you can add more validators.
So let's have a look at this in the next lecture.