We connected to mongodb and this is nice but it also means that we can't do anything else right now,
the rest of the app is not working anymore
and of course it should work.
So let's get there step by step and let's start by re-adding the admin routes,
so let's add this middleware again and for this, I also need to import admin routes again
and if we now have a look into our admin controller, here we do of course use the product model, in the
product model if
we have a look into that does rely on sequelize of course because we define the product model with
the help of sequelize.
Now that is all something which we won't do anymore
instead we now want to use mongodb.
So to get there, I will remove these two imports up there and instead in here, I want to create a new
class again because I'll create my own model again
and this is something we did before already in the pure MySQL module. So I'll create a product class
here, like this
and of course I will also export this, so module exports will still be my class here.
Now in that class, I'll have a constructor and in that constructor here, I want to store the title, price,
image url and description of the product when it gets created.
So here I will simply get the title, the price, the description and the image url and then in the constructor
I'll say this title equals title, this price equals price, this description equals description, well and
so on,
you know the game,
so here image url equals image url.
Now we can create a new product in javascript, a new object which follows this form
and now to save it in the database, I will also add a save method here,
so a function which can be executed on this class and in here, I now want to connect to mongodb
and save my product.
Now to do that, to be able to connect,
I'll need to import mongodb or mongo connect,
so I'll import mongo connect from my utility folder and there from the database file.
So I will simply import that method,
the function I created here where you pass a callback to, where we do connect to mongodb inside
and then we basically execute the callback and return the connected client so that we can interact
with it.
However if we would do this, we would have to connect to mongodb for every operation we do
and we would not even disconnect thereafter,
so this is not really a good way of connecting to mongodb since we will want to connect and
interact with it from different places in our app.
So it would be better if we could manage one connection in our database and then simply return access
to the client which we set up once from there or to the different place in our app that need access. And
to do that, I'll tune my set up here a bit. Let's tune it together in the next lecture.