Now we added our multer configuration to rename our file and to control the storage place in detail,
now we can also add a filter to multer to only allow certain kinds of files
and for that 2D object where we configure multer, I can add the file filter function here.
Now I'll again create in a separate const up there to make it easier to read, file filter will simply be
a function,
I'll use an arrow function here where I get the request,
some file data and a callback which I have to call and in there, we should call the callback with
null as an error and true if we want to accept that file so if it should be stored or false if we
don't want to store that file.
Now how can we determine whether we want to store it?
Well we can write any logic we want here,
now I will check if the file mime type is equal to an image/png or if the file mime type is
equal to image/jpg or if the file mime type is equal to image/jpeg with an e.
If any of that is true, so if I have a file which is of that type, then I will accept that so I will call
the callback with true as a second value
otherwise I'll call the callback with false as a second value which means I'll not accept that file.
And now we can use that file filter and pass it as a value for file filter in our options here
and with that set up,
we got some logic here that should filter out invalid files.
So if I go back now and I submit a form here with let's say my boat.png, I succeed here, well I get
an error here but I succeed because it stores the file
but if I try to submit a different value, let's say I'll pick a pdf here.
You can use any pdf, any non-image file, then you see I only get undefined here and that undefined
is stemming from my admin controller from this line,
so then multer did not store anything
and this is how we can filter out files.
Now I will remove all these files up there and I'll also clean up my database soon because right now
we're not really storing the data appropriately
and that is the next step we should do of course.