So let's make sure we can save our product to a file and not to this array here anymore.
For this when we call save here, I want to save it to a file
and of course in that file, I want to have all products, the old ones and the new one.
So therefore first of all, we need to be able to work with the file system,
so I will import fs from the core fs module.
Now that file should then also be created in special path, so I will use the path tool,
the path module to construct a path that works on all operating systems.
Now here in save, I will then create my path and I will do that with path join,
so using the path core module, whoops,
and I name this p so that I avoid namespace clashes and the path should be my root directory
and we actually still have that helper function
but if you deleted it, you can of course recreate it as we did before or simply copy this code here if
you want,
you also find it attached to this lecture again in case you deleted it.
I will simply copy that logic here
and move it in there
but of course I could absolutely simply use my helper function I created there. But this is of course
just the root directory, in there
I will have a new data folder and I will create it ahead of time so that we don't get permission issues.
So I'll have added the data folder to the root project folder and in that data folder, I want to store
my file,
so that will then actually be a file and that should have a name of products and I will give this an
extension of json because I want to store my data in json format.
Ok so that's products, now to store a new product in there,
first of all I need to get the existing array of products,
so I will first of all read that file.
So let's use fs read file and this reads the entire file content of a file
and by the way for very big files, there are more efficient ways because you don't want to read them
all into memory before you work with them,
you can read them as a stream then,
there is such a function,
you can create a read stream with this function but we can read the entire file here, this is ok
and I will read the file at this path, p which is that file I'm interested in
and then I will do something once I'm done reading it
and there we either get an error or we get data, so we get the the file content
you could say, there will be a buffer though.
Now let's log the file content here
and let's see what we get if we now call save. If I go to add product and I'll type something here,
it crashes and it crashes, if you the scroll up because products is not defined in fetch all of course. In
save however, it didn't throw an error but we get undefined here as you can see
and we did get undefined because this file simply doesn't exist,
there is no content in it
therefore, you can see that here we've got no file with that name
so reading it therefore kind of failed.
And if I add an error here to print the error we get
and I try this again,
so let's go back to add product, click that and we scroll above this error message here, you see this is the
error message
we're now logging with this line
and there we see no such file or directory
and that makes a lot of sense because indeed, it does not exist as I just mentioned.
So obviously if it doesn't exist, then I also want to continue and I can. I will simply check if we got
an error and this will be null if we get none
but if we have one then I simply want to create a new empty array because we have no existing products.json
file,
so we got no old products stored and otherwise I want to use the existing one. Put in other words I'll
add a new variable here which I'll name products
and initially this is an empty array and I will actually keep it as such if we do have an error
but if we get no error
and therefore I will add an exclamation mark here,
so if we got no error, if this therefore is null
so if we got no error, then I want to read the products from the file which I extracted.
So therefore here I know that file content will be something, it should be the content of my file
and since that is a json file, I will store it in json format there so then I will set products equal
to json which is a helper object existing in vanilla nodejs,
so you don't need to define this on your own
and there we have the parse method which takes incoming json and gives us back a javascript array or
object or whatever is in the file.
So here I can parse the file content and that should work
or at least we should try that.
So now I know that product will be an array, either the one I read from the file or an empty one and
therefore, we can now append our new product there,
so I will call products push and push my new product which is this onto it. Now important, to ensure
that this refers to the class, you should use an arrow function here because otherwise this will lose its
context and will not refer to the class anymore.
We have this setup though where I do use an arrow function,
this should refer still to my class and therefore now I can push this onto this array, either to the new
one or the one I read from the file
and now the remaining work is that I need to save it back into the file.
So again I will use the file system module and now I'll use write file and I will write it to the same
path as where I read it from
and I will put my json data into it,
so again I will use that json helper object
and now there is the stringify find method which takes a javascript object or array and converts it
into json
so that this has the right format,
so there I will take this products array and convert this to json
and then this gets written to the file.
And here I also have a callback where I may get an error and I will simply log that error here to see
if that works. With all that,
let's go back,
let's go back to the add product page and click this button.
This error of course still exists
but now if we scroll up, let's see if that worked. Here
that is looking good and in data, we indeed see a products.json file which does contain that one product
we created.
Now that was the
we have no old data case,
let's now go back and add another product here
and see if that also works. If I scroll up,
well we also see it here I guess, this also worked out just fine.
So this is working, we are able to read a file, append data to the existing data or create it if it
didn't exist yet and therefore our data storage in the file seems to work,
obviously it's a very basic storage but better than nothing.
Now obviously we also want to be able to fetch the data from there,
so in fetch all I also want to read this file here I will read the file at my path and I also will therefore
get my error or the file content using arrow function here and this will then hold the data I want
to use. Now if I got an error here, I want to return an empty array because then I got no products right,
I always want to return an array because that is what fetch all expects but it should at least be empty
in case of an error
and of course you could also throw an error message and show one but here it'll just be the empty array
otherwise
and I don't need an else block because after return, we would finish the execution of this function
anyways, so after this if block, I will return my parsed and that's important,
otherwise it will just be a string,
my parsed file content and this is important to keep in mind because this here is in the end retrieved
as a text.
So to return it as an array, you need to call json parse.
So now I return my file content in a parsed form and therefore, I get rid of the return product
statement here and I will now always return my objects or my list of products.
So let's see this in action, let's save this and reload this page here, key is not defined, makes sense,
I'm trying to read something from this path but that path is only defined in the save method.
So for now let's copy it,
we can of course refactor that but let's copy it for now
and now if I reload this page,
I still get this error and this can now be very hard to debug or to understand
but do you know what's going wrong here?
We'll fix it in the next lecture.