So validation in the database is missing. Now I'll start by adding validation here and for that,
I'll quit my server side npm start process because I need to install a new package and I'll use the same
package which I used in the validation module of this course. Therefore
you should definitely watch that module to learn how validation works because I'll not repeat everything
here,
we already learned it after all.
So here I'll just install that package which was express validator,
that is a package that helps us with implementing validation into our node express applications.
After that is installed, you can restart npm start and now do you remember how you add it?
Have a look at this module I just mentioned
if you don't. You go to your routes and there, you add some middleware which does that validation. For
that, you
first of all need to import something from the express validator package and there from the
/check sub-package and that something is either the check method or the body method to check the request
body or with the check method
also the headers, the query parameters and so on,
I want to check the request body here. Now for a get route, validation makes no sense because no data is
submitted
but for the post route it makes sense and there I'll add an array of middleware that will be applied
which will be related to validation. There
for example I will use body to check the title field.
Now the title field can be validated in any way you want,
I can tell you that on the frontend however, I am validating that title field and you can see that in the
components, feed feed edit component, that I am validating this to have a minimum length of five characters
and to be non-empty which is of course the case if it is at least five characters long,
the content also has to be five characters long.
So that's just a little side note on what I'm doing on the frontend and the backend should of course
meet that same pattern.
So my body title will first of all be trimmed to not have any whitespace in there and then I'll use
the isLength validator with an object to set a minimum length of five.
Now this is the title, now after a comma, I'll add my next middleware where I will validate the content,
we can also trim that and basically set the same validator,
obviously you can be more creative than that but I just want to re-iterate how validation works and
really show you that it works in exactly the same way in rest APIs because you build a normal
node in express application in the end,
that does not change here.
So with that, we added these two validation steps for our incoming data, for title and the content and now
we can implement some logic to send an error if our server side validation logic is not met. For this
we go to our controller, to the feed.js file in our controllers folder and there we also need to import
something from that express validator package,
so here I also require express validator/check
and that something which I am importing here is the validation result function. With that imported
in create post,
we can simply create a new errors constant and use that validation result function on the request, it
will then automatically extract any errors that validation package
gathered and we can check if not errors is empty which means we have errors.
If that is not empty, we have errors and then I will return a response with a status code of 422 which
is of course our validation failed status code where I send some json data
and there you can have a message of validation failed,
validation failed, entered data is incorrect or whatever you want, it will be on your frontend to
do something with that message or not and you could add the errors here by using that errors constant
and then using the array method to extract an array of errors and also add this to the json object.
So with that, we're returning this response if validation fails.
Now thanks to our client side validation, with the correct rules we could not reproduce that because
I'm already checking for a minimum length of 5 on the frontend
but if we increase the title minimum length to 7 for now on the server,
now if I go back to the frontend and I enter a title which is only 5 characters long and therefore
long enough for the client side validation but too short for the server side validation which is of
course a mismatch
you don't want to have in a real app but it's great for testing,
if I do that and I
accept here, I actually get an error, creating or editing a post failed,
that is an error message I'm just showing on the frontend.
But if you have a look at our console log in the dev tools, we see a 422 error here and if we click
on that we're taken to the network tab, we see that read request and if we inspect that, we see our response
here and that indeed has that message we sent on the server side, validation failed and so on and it
has this errors array where we see that the title failed.
So you see that the server side validation is working and that is all I wanted to show you here,
of course I revert back to 5 characters minimum length on the server now too so that the client side
validation logic and the server side logic are in line
otherwise we would have very bad user experiences because users get the feedback that their input is
correct and then the server would throw an error.
So with that, we added validation for this post route and now we can move on to adding a database.