So how can we add authorization?
I want to ensure that I can't delete or edit this book with or this product with the wrong account.
Now we do have important information stored on the product,
we know which user did create it,
so in the end we just want to check if the currently logged in user is the user who created that before
allowing any edits to that item.
And that means that on the admin controller where we render our admin list here, get products here,
I only want to render products that were created by the logged in user because there is no sense in
showing products on this page that were not created by the user because we're in the admin section,
you are not able to do anything with it if you weren't a creator.
So authorization simply means we restrict the permissions and we can do that by restricting the data
we return for example,
so here when I find product, I dont find all but I'll add a filter and I'll filter for products where the
user ID is equal to the user id of the currently logged in user, so user ID is equal to request user
id, whoops, ID
and keep in mind request user exists because we do extract that user in app.js in a separate middleware
here, there
I do store the user in request
user, so I know that only products which were created by that user should be retrieved. With that changed
if I reload this page, I find no products for test2 but if I do login with my other account with
test@test.com and I go to admin products, I do find that book,
so that is the first important step forward.
The problem is I could theoretically still issue requests behind the scenes where I do try to delete
a product which was not created by me,
so more protection is needed.
Let's add that next.