Our sign up validation is looking pretty good
but there is one thing which we are validating in a bit of a strange way right now and that is the fact
whether the e-mail address is taken or not.
Right now I'm doing that in my auth controller and there by the way we will not need confirm password anymore,
we're checking this ahead of time but in auth.js
I do check for e-mail existence here.
Now logically it would make sense to check that as part of our validation right
and the good thing is we can do that.
Let's grab this code where we find one user here, let's grab that code
and let's head over to the auth.js file in the routes folder. In there
let's first of all import our user model by requiring it from the models folder and there from the user
file
so we need that
and then here on my e-mail field, I got this custom validator.
I'll comment this code out because I want to keep it for you as a reference but now we'll add a more
well a check that makes more sense.
I will add my code here where I find one user with that e-mail address,
now that e-mail address on the right side here is the value of course which you are validating because
we're doing this on the e-mail field,
so value will be the entered email, I'm searching for that e-mail
and then here if I have a user document, well then I will not do it with this flash message and so on
anymore
instead I'll just take that error message and inside of this if block which is inside of my then block
here, I will return a new promise reject call. A promise is a built-in javascript object and with reject,
I basically throw an error inside of the promise and I reject with this error message I used before.
What this means is that now after this then block, I could another catch block to catch this but
I will not do that here
instead let's close our function curly braces and the normal brackets from the custom function
and now what I'll do is I will return user find one.
Now what will this do?
The express validator package will check for a custom validator to return true or false, to return a
thrown error or to return a promise.
If it's a promise as it is the case with this because here we ultimately return a promise because
every then block implicitly returns a new promise,
so if we return a promise then express validator will wait for this promise to be fulfilled and if it
fulfills with in our case nothing,
so basically no error, then it treats this validation as successful. If it resolves with some rejection
in the end though which will happen if we make it into this if block, then express validator will detect this rejection
and will store this as an error,
this message will then be stored as an error message. And this is how we can add our own asynchronous
validation, asynchronous because we have to reach out to the database which of course is not an instant
task but express validator will kind of wait for us here.
So now we have our own async validation in place and now we should still check for email existence but
we don't do this in controller anymore because there, I will in the end get rid of that entire user find
one thing here, instead I will instantly start with b crypt and I'll also remove one pair of brackets
at the bottom and this semi-colon and this catch block. And now what I do have here is I instantly start
with hash in my password and so on creating that user because I can rely on the user to not exist already
inside of my controller because I do check for its existence ahead of time in my auth.js route with the
help of that validation middleware.
So now let's go back and let's add an email address and a valid password
of a user that already exists and indeed I get e-mail exists already, so that is great. If I however
do add an email address that does not exist yet and I do enter valid passwords, I get my sign up page
here or
my login page
because the user was created successfully. So this now works and this is how you can add async validation.