Let's make sure we do set this active class on the right link depending on which page we are. Now for
that, I will go to my routes and there since I'm working on the add product to the admin.js file where
I do have that add product route, this one.
Now I will return a new field here,
the path field and I will set this to admin add product. Now you can set this to whatever you want, it
doesn't have to match the path this route has, just a pattern I like.
So now I pass this path into my view so that the view can find out what is the path for which this was
loaded.
Now in main layout, we will get this path
and now I can do something interesting. In the main layout here,
I know that I want to add the active class to this add product
if the path and the path now simply is a variable i get passed into the page,
if the path simply is this one and that is something we define and therefore you could pick any path you
want.
So now I will add a check here.
Now a class can be added, a css class as an attribute here too,
you don't have to use that dot notation,
so class is equal to
and now I'll have some javascript code which we can enclose with brackets here and now here, I simply
check if path and path is simply just what I pass in here, so this key,
if path is equal to this value and that is why I meant you can use whatever path you want, you are defining
the condition here.
So if path is equal to this, then I know that add product is the page I'm on because only for the add product
route I do set this path.
So then if that is the case, I want to render active as a class here
otherwise an empty string,
so otherwise I basically set no class. With this set up,
now if I reload this page, you'll see add product is yellow because now it is marked as active,
if I go to shop that's not the case but on shop, we also don't use the layout yet.
So let's continue
now. For the shop I also want to use the layout, so I will go to add-product.pug, copy my code here and
move it up over to shop.pug,
let's keep the original code for now,
extend the main layout therefore. Now I do need the product.css file here
but I don't need the forms so let's remove that from the styles block and for the content I will
need main
but we don't render a form here,
instead we render this if loop, so let's or this if block,
so let's copy that entire code and put it in here,
make sure indentation is correct that you don't mess this up
and now we can get rid of all the other code here.
Now again for the styling of the header, we would have a problem if I now reload because it's not marked
as active because I need to use that same approach I did for the add product route. I pass in an additional
key path and there, I pass slash like this or /shop,
again you don't have to use the real path that led to this route.
I'll use slash though to keep this matched
and now in main layout, I copy my code from down there where I dynamically add this class and add it here
for the shop too
but the part I'm checking for is just slash here and now I do add active here
if the path variable which gets injected into the template matches slash which is only the case for this route.
So now if I save this, I got an error here
yeah
this should not be an equal sign here,
this should be a colon in shop.js
.
because we're creating a javascript object
and now if I reload here, this is active,
this is active
and if we try adding a book, this also works.
So this is now working.
Now there is one thing I saw that I forgot and that is the title for the page,
it's always page not found
and that should of course not be the case.
Now you could turn this title into a block which you then set from inside the template or you do
add a dynamic output here with hashtag curly braces and give this a name, page title maybe
and now you just need to make sure that every render function passes in a page title.
So for the 404 page, for the add product page and the shop page, we have to pass in that page title key.
So starting in admin.js, here we already got page title so we're fine, in shop.js here it's doc title
so let's rename this to page title to be in line with the other file and with our layout and in the app.js
file where we have our 404 route,
I'm not passing anything
so there let's also send some data into the view and let's also set
page title here,
page not found.
If we now go to our page and reload it, we see shop here as a title, for add product we see add product
and if we enter something random here, we see Page Not Found.
So now this is working
and now we're using pug.
Now you can do way more with pug and you can combine all these features and do crazy stuff,
I recommend diving into their official docs
if you plan on using that, I instead want to show you the alternatives too
now that we learned the basics of how templating engines work and how you can use them to output dynamic
content in your views.