Now we learned about cors in the last lecture,
now let me show you how it affects our post requests.
So I'll use my post button to also add an event listener there, click like this
and in there I'll also use the fetch method to send a fetch request to the same url as before but it ends
with /posts because I'm targeting this
url here which is just post, not posts.
So if you name this differently, you should of course use your path. Here since it will be a post request,
I need to pass a javascript object as a second argument which allows me to set some options.
Specifically I want to set the method to post here to send a post request and then I will copy that
code from up there for handling the response so that I can, well extract the data or log a potential
error. If I now clear that and I hit create post,
I get post created successfully but if we inspect the post object, we see that the title and content are
missing.
Now that makes a lot of sense because we didn't send that data.
Instead on the post request in the client, we also want to set a body object and that object will hold
the title, a
codepen post and content created via codepen,
whatever you want. If I clear that and
now I click that button again, hmm I still don't see that here.
Now on the server side, nothing goes wrong here but actually on the server side, if I would go to my
controller and I would log title and content here or use the node debugger to see their values, if we
log that and I click create post, then we see that
undefined gets logged here.
So we are not able to extract that data
and the reason for that can be found if we go to the network tab and have a look at this post request
that was sent, there in the request headers,
we see that the content type was text plain and that is the problem. It should be application json
but we also see that the request payload was not json data which in the end is just text but in
a special format
but that it was a javascript object which just can't be sent or which can't be handled.
So there are two things we need to do.
First of all on the body, I will call json stringify which is a method provided by default by javascript,
it will take a javascript object and convert it to json. We can see that immediately if I click create
post again and we inspect that request,
the payload now is indeed text in the json format but we need to tell the server that our content
type is of type application json
and therefore besides setting the body, on the client I'll also add headers or one header, the content type
header, content-type which is application/json.
And now with that, if I click create post again,
now in the created post we see title or title and content because now that data is sent and extracted
correctly because we send it in the right format and we inform the server about the content type.
Now this also allows me to demonstrate what happens if I would comment out this header here, the access
control allow headers header on the server side.
If I save after commenting this out and I try to create a post again, I fail because I'm not allowed to
set content-type,
I do allow this by adding this header on the server side.
So this is how you communicate between client and server,
of course the client code differs depending on the client you're using.
This is javascript code using the fetch API,
there are different ways of sending asynchronous requests,
for example you can send Ajax requests through libraries like axios and if you are building a mobile
app, you might have a totally different object or helper methods for sending such requests in Android,
in swift and so on.
So this client code differs, this is the javascript code using the fetch API, the server side code does not
really differ.
You want to make sure your clients can communicate and that everything works just fine there.
Now before I conclude this though, one more word about the post request we're sending with this click.
You might see that I actually have two requests being sent,
the second one is our post request, what is the first request?
If you have a look at it and we see the response is just post, ok,
the headers are interesting though. We can see that in the general part,
the method here is options and that is this last method I showed on the slide earlier.
I mentioned it would be sent automatically by the browser and also
for example by many mobile app clients. What is the idea behind options?
The browser simply goes ahead and checks whether the request you plan to send which is a post request,
that is why here in the request headers which are generated automatically by the browser,
it checks for the post request, it checks if that will be allowed
otherwise it will throw an error.
This is simply a mechanism the browser and many other clients use and there is not too much you need
you to do to make this work,
it just works out of the box,
you just want to make sure that you set the right cors
headers here. You can add options to the allowed methods but as you see, it was able to make this request
before,
this is not really something you need to do
but you can do it but the important thing is that you are not confused by that extra request.
It's simply a mechanism the browser uses to see if the next request which it wants to view, the post request
will succeed if it is allowed. And this is all I want to tell you about cors and client server communication
for now.