Hello and welcome to this news Tauriel.
So in the previous one we started implementing the policy class which basically built the AI because
the ear is nothing else than a policy and the policy is nothing else than a perception.
So we initialized the matrix of weights of that perception and now we are going to implement an essential
part of the algorithm which is this one right.
We already normalized the states.
So we are about to implement this version 2 of the algorithm because Version 1 is applying the perturbations
without normalizing the States and us we are about to implement version 2 which is applied to perturbations
after normalization of state.
So we already implementing this part.
And now we're going to implement that part that consists of applying some perturbations in one positive
direction and applying the same perturbation on the opposite direction.
We will call the positive direction positive and the opposite direction negative.
OK.
And what does that mean.
What does it mean exactly applying the little perturbations that just consist of adding a very small
value that you will see will follow a normal distribution.
We will add those very small numbers following a normal distribution and for each of these very small
numbers will also add the negative same small number.
So adding the positive small number will be the positive direction and adding the negative small number
will be the opposite or negative direction.
So we'll apply that to each of the weights and then we'll observe the reward that we get and then we're
going to do that for many directions actually you know it's 16 directions because we initialize the
hyper parameter and the directions to 16.
So for each of the six indirections we'll apply those perturbation to positive one and the opposite
one the negative one and we'll see which direction gives us the best we want know the highest reward
because indeed our ultimate goal is to increase the reward.
So let's do this let's implement this part here.
We will implement that through a function that will call evaluate.
All right.
Def evaluate which will take its argument self then input because indeed these perturbations will be
applied once we feed an input to the perception of the policy and therefore we need an input to apply
the perturbation.
So that's why it is one of the arguments here.
So input then it will take actually an argument the perturbation itself that we'll call Delta.
So Delta you know will be these very small numbers following a normal distribution.
And you know by using plus or minus We will choose the direction of the perturbation.
If it's a plus it's going to be a positive direction.
And if it's a minus it's going to be the opposite or negative direction.
So Delta will just be a matrix of small numbers following the normal distribution Delta.
And since this Evaluate function will actually also be used when no perturbation is applied.
You know just to get the output when we feed the perception with a certain input.
Well we will set the perturbation by default to none.
So that's when we just use the evaluate method to indeed evaluate the policy when we fit it to certain
books.
Well we will indeed get the output without any perturbation and by default this will be the case because
Delta is by default set to none.
And now the less argument direction.
So this argument will only take three possible values.
First one is positive.
The second one is negative or opposite.
And the third one is none and saying we want this evaluate method to return the output when we feel
a certain input without applying a perturbation.
So by default direction is also going to be equal to none.
And there we go that's all the arguments we need to make this evaluate method that not only can return
the output when we feed a certain input but you will see that also can apply these perturbations according
to the paper.
So since you understand that this method can actually do three things which are first just returning
the output when we feed a certain input.
Second returning the output when we feed the perception with a certain input and we apply a perturbation
in the positive direction.
And third returning the output when we feed it with certain inputs and we apply the perturbation in
the opposite or negative direction.
And therefore we want to return the output in these three specific conditions.
And that's why the best thing we have to do here is an IF condition.
So we are going to have three if or rather two is in an else telling what will happen in these three
specific conditions.
So let's start with the first possible condition.
The first possible condition is when the direction is none.
That is by default.
So the direction is.
Well in that case it's very simple we will just return the output of the perception without applying
any perturbation.
And how can we get that.
Well we just need to take our matrix of weight theta that we're going to multiply by the vector of inputs.
No it's a matrix product.
You apply basically the matrix to your input.
And how can we do that in Bison.
Well there is a function for that.
That is the gut function.
Here we go.
And that is taking as arguments the input of course because we were playing the matrix of weight theta
to our input state vector and that's it.
That's what is returned by the Evaluate function of our policy when no perturbation is applied.
And when we fill it with our input.
Perfect.
So that's the first case then the second case is when the direction is positive.
So here I'm going to add another.
If but when we add an extra if it's not and if we start with it's an elif elif which means an x f basically.
So Elif if this time the direction is then in quote We can say positive.
So you know the positive direction that is basically this one.
No that's the positive perturbation or perturbation of positive direction.
Well what will happen in that case what will we return.
Well we will return same we take our matrix of weight theta But remember too each of the weights of
the Preceptress the positive perturbation that is to each of the values of the matrix of weight we're
going to add this noise times the little perturbation that we called Delta and Delta.
You have to see it as a very small value like an epsilon.
But that is not going to be always the same very small value because it's going to follow a normal distribution.
And why will it not be the same value that because we're testing several directions right.
So we're testing several possible small values.
And of course for each of these small values that we're testing as directions we're going to test the
opposite small values mean in the opposite direction.
And so that's what we have to add right here to our matrix of weights that they called and that we called
in our algorithm theta.
So let's do this.
Let's go back here.
So solve the theta.
Exactly.
And we're going to add exactly as in the paper.
Well first the noise that we called self that noise but self refers to the object.
And we will call the object H-P with minimal letters.
So I'm thinking for our future object H-P which we haven't created yet but we will later on.
So our object H-P from object HPN going to get the hyper parameter noise so noise here and then exactly
as in the paper I'm going to multiply this noise by Indeed the perturbation Delta.
OK.
We multiply the noise by the perturbation.
Delta perfect.
So that's basically applying the positive Britz aberration or you know the perturbation in the positive
direction to our metrics of weight theta.
And now of course we need to get our input because we apply this disturbed matrix of weight to the same
input.
So I'm adding here that input.
Perfect.
All right.
So we've just done this and now we're going to do this that is applying the exact same perturbation
with the exact same small value here.
But in the opposite direction which we're going to call the negative direction.
So let's do this let's now implement this.
And since all the conditions here are complimentary.
Well we don't have to add an Aliff but an else no.
The last remaining condition else and we're going to return exactly the same but with a minus because
it's the perturbation in the opposite direction but with the same noise and the same Delta and therefore
what we only need to replace Here is the plus by the minus.
All right so let's recap.
If the direction is none if there is no perturbation we will just return the output that is the actions
when we read the policy perception of the policy with discerning put here then if the direction is positive
that is if we apply a perturbation in the positive direction Well we will return the matrix of weights
where we applied this positive perturbation here.
Adding a small delta value within noise of 0.03 to our input to this same input.
And lastly if the direction is negative Well we will apply the same perturbation but the opposite one
with this man sign here to our matrix of weights and we apply this perturbed matrix of weights to the
same input and we have the three possible conditions.
Therefore we now have a tool to evaluate method that can return the input whether or not you decide
to not apply any perturbation apply a perturbation in a positive direction or apply perturbation in
the opposite direction.
So we basically implemented this part here and more specifically the version 2 here because indeed we
normalized the state for us.
Exactly as in the paper.
Great.
That's a good thing done.
And now the next step is actually to make a function that will simple these perturbations dealt us.
Because indeed right now if we go back to our code right now the delta is only an argument right.
We didn't sample it anywhere.
So we have to make a function we have to make an additional method that will sample these deltas here
these perturbations deltas following a normal distribution.
So we just need to sample the Deltas using the rand and function.
By and by.
And this will output some small values deltas following a Gaussian distribution of mean zero still zero.
But of standard deviation the noise.
So we will make that method which we'll call by the way simple deltas in the next tutorial to sample
these deltas so that later on when we apply the evaluate method to apply some perturbations well in
the delta here we will put our simpled deltas which will get things to this future simple deltas method
that we're about to make in the next toile.