Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this video we are going to prepare everything for the fast API project by the end of this section.
We are going to have a fully functional plastic API that receives an image from a user and gives back
a prediction to them and all of that over the Internet and not only that while building this API we
are going to learn how to put a train model into production using the tensor flow to point 0 and flask
Python framework.
If you haven't work with the plots before don't worry we are going to cover just enough to get you up
and running so you can build your own custom flask API.
With or without machine learning Okay let's discuss a few prerequisites for this project.
As you can see this is the route for the flask API project and I already have three files prepared for
you in section three of the course your work with artificial neural networks and train your own for
fashion and energy data set at the end of the section you've saved your own model and got two different
files.
I renamed them to fashion model flask daughter Jason and fashion model flask about age 5.
Both of these files are used to load the pre train model and use it to make predictions in production
the first file is project helpers which is just an empty python file that file will be used in this
lesson in this course we want create a front end for the API we will focus on creating a backend that
uses deep learning to help users in some way and to demonstrate the fully functional API we need to
create a new folder and save a few images to it.
Well that's created and call it uploads.
The next step for us is to save a few images from the test set to our newly created uploads folder.
This will demonstrate a case where a user has already uploaded a few images to our server at the end
of this section.
We are going to use those images to test the whole API.
Let's get them more excited right now.
At the end of this section we want to use Python at all to make those predictions.
Instead we will demonstrate the whole API use case by using bossman software to demonstrate sending
data over the Internet and getting a prediction back to us.
Let's start with a code for this with you in this section we will use spider IDC as we discussed.
This is the project helpers python file which is just empty for now.
But before we start with the code make sure that you selected the root folder of the project in your
idea of choice.
The first step is to import all dependencies for this lesson the data set of choice for this section
is fashion and the data set.
So the first thing to do is to import the data set itself from tens of low dot carriers.
Though the data sets import fashion analyzed this is the only tens of flow related thing that we have
to import for this video.
The next import is from library called side by import.
I am safe and as you may already assumed this I am safe.
Function is here to save an image to a local uploads folder.
Lets select these two lines and execute them by using control.
Plus enter before we try to save an image to our local disk.
Specifically to our uploads folder we need to import the data set itself the data set load function
returns to outputs 1 for training and other one for testing each of these parts can be split up into
two different parts features and targets so let's write X train.
Come on.
Why train in brackets comma x test come out y test in other brackets and that is all equal to fashion
then is that low the data.
This function will try to find data set for us downloads it and store it into these four variables.
Select this line of code and executed.
As you can see it created four new variables in memory X train y train x test and Y test.
Now it's time to use this IMC function to save a few images from the test set to our uploads folder
to completed this task.
We are going to use a simple for loop and iterate through the test set right.
For I in range of 5 this 5 represents how many images we want to save.
I chosen 5 but you can select whatever number you want and inside of these for loop.
Let's call the aim save.
Function let's inspect arguments of these function by using control plus I the first one is the name
of newly created image and the second argument is the array or the image itself let's provide a path
for our images.
Right.
Names equal to then specify the folder uploads slash and curly brackets dot TMG with a simple byte string
format we can change these curly brackets into the index if we didn't perform this step each time we
save an image to our local file it will override the previous image with the same name and we wouldn't
end up having five different images but only one so write the format and provide eye to it the next
argument is the right and that is the image itself.
In our case it is X test of I and this is all what we have to do to save images locally.
Select these two lines of code and executed if we want to take a look at our uploads folder it will
have five different images and that's it for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise assume the next tutorial.