Hello everyone and welcome to this biking tutorial.
In the previous video we talked about the fine tuning methodology and how to perform it.
It is pretty straightforward and in this video we are going to build on top of what we learned in the
previous one by compiling the model that we um throws a few layers from.
We don't have to specify a new model.
We have to recompile the model and it will be ready the compiling method is the same as before.
So it copied and pasted the code here.
As you can see we are using the same optimizer what we used with the same learning grade for our loss.
We are still using binary codes entropy and for our metrics accuracy and that's it.
The same step execute the cell and our model for fine tuning is ready to be used in the next video.
We are going to fine tune or to train this model.
We defeat the generator function for now.
If you have any questions or comments please buzz them in the comments section.
Otherwise I'll see in the next tutorial.