Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video we started with our A.I. traitor
project.
By setting up our environment and installing all libraries for the section and now in this video we
will start with the implementation of the A.I. trainer model itself.
It is the deep human network that we have traded stock for us.
But before we jump into that part of the video let me walk you through libraries that we are going to
need for the project.
The first one is math later in the section that we will implement our own sigmoid function to scale
our stock prices.
But more on that later.
And that's why we will need the math library.
Then we have this random library.
It will help us to generate random numbers.
No.
As always is here to help us work with matrices and umpire race.
Then we have the pen this library tends to flow our library of choice for a neural network modelling
then for data visualization.
We have met blood to leap then we have this Panda's data reader.
This library is used to download and work with the stock market information TDM is here as always to
visualize any progress in the product.
And lastly we have these De Q data structure in this product.
We will implement experience a replay using this data structure.
You have the intuition lecture about this concept included in the annex of the course execute the cell
and just execute the next cell as well to make sure that we are using the Tanzer flow 2.0 and finally
we are done with the first part of the video.
It's time to start working on the A.I. trader class later in the course.
We will talk about states and actions.
For now let's define the algorithm itself to get that part out of the way we will use python class to
create our structure of the A.I. trader bot so right class a trader.
The next thing that we have to do is to define the init function of the class or its constructor death
in it.
And this function is called.
Each time we define an object of the class so all things that we have to define right away are initialized
in this function for its arguments just right self which is the keyword that connects a function and
attributes of a class to a specific object.
Then we have to specify a state size.
More on that later and action space which is by default free when trading.
We have free actions state which is does don't do anything.
Buy and Sell and our agent will be able to perform these free actions as well.
Lastly we have model name as an argument and this can be anything you want.
Just put me for example a traitor for not now that we are done with the arguments part of the constructor
let's define all hyper parameters of the network.
The first two parameters are just state size and action space defined as an object attributes now have
more model related parameters.
The first one is the experience of replay memory cell Dot.
Memory is equal to the Q.
The problem with this function is it doesn't have a good dog string.
You can Google it and find what arguments it can receive in this course we will use only one Max land
is equal to 2000.
Or how many elements we can store inside it.
In our case it just put two thousand then initialize an empty list call in the three and this list will
hold all both stocks since we cannot sell a stock we haven't bought before.
And lastly we have this model name is equal to model name.
OK now we have to initialize for more arguments before the end of this video and that is our gamma parameter.
And if you remember the formula of our discount the total reward the gamma parameter helps us to maximize
the current reward over long time reward.
So right self doubt gamma and said it's something between zero point nine and one I will set it to zero
point ninety five.
There are only free variables left to define and they're all connected to the same thing.
We have this Epsilon parameter that is used to determine whether should we choose and the random action
or to use the model for it.
Start by defining it to a 1.
This means that at the very beginning of the training process when our network is not trained at all.
All actions are performed randomly but over time we want to decrease this number so we can stop using
random actions and start using mostly our train network.
Even though we have a fully train network we still want the agent to take some random actions and that
is for our environment exploration and that's where the next variable comes into play set epsilon final
and set it to 0.01 for example when the value of epsilon is equal to or less this number we will start
decreasing it any further.
And finally we have an argument that determines how fast to decrease and epsilon defined a variable
called Epsilon decay and define it to something less than 1.
I will set it to zero point nine on five and that the whole a trader set up in the next video we will
start building the brain of the algorithm.
Stay tuned for that and if you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments
section.
Otherwise I'll see you in the next tutorial.