Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In the previous video we created our project structure and we created a few images for pipeline testing.
So from this video we are starting with our code for the flask API project.
The first step of the project and the goal of this video is to import all product dependencies.
Let's start with the first one called Ice.
Ice is a native python library used to work with parts and files from locating them to removing them.
The next one is a request.
This library is used to create a post or get the request to our server.
Now we have our non-paying library as always.
It is used for mathematical operations and Working with matrices then we have tens of flow the Library
of choice for neural net for building as we did in the previous video.
We need to import a few functions from the side by library specifically to read and save images from
the local disk.
And lastly let's import the project dependencies from flask import flask which is used to create flask
application itself.
Then we need to import request and this one is used to send the request to a specific path from our
flask and backend finally Jason ify Jason ify is used to return data in the Jason format when you're
building an API.
The Jason is the most common way of returning data to a user.
That's why we need to use Jason ify for this project to complete this tutorial.
Select all of your libraries and press control plus enter to import them.
Now all of these libraries are at your disposal and ready to be used from the next tutorial.
For now if you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll
see you in the next tutorial.