Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
Today we're going to talk about the Belmont equation.
It's quite a complex topic and we're going to introduce it in a step by step manner.
Throughout this whole section of the course so we're not going to just jump straight into the most complex
version of the Belmont equation right away but instead we're going to introduce it slowly in order to
gradually understand how it works.
And I hope you call off that approach if you're if you are.
Let's get straight into it.
So we're going to have a couple of key concepts that we're going to be operating with and these concepts
are S stands for states.
So the state in which our agent is or any other possible state in which it can be a represents an action
that a an agent can take.
So an agent can have access to a certain list of actions and actions are very important when they're
looked at in a state combination.
So when you're in a certain state and then you look at actions and it starts to make sense what's going
to be the result of those actions because if you look at an action by itself of a states does it really
make sense because you don't know where you are and where you can possibly end up.
Then we have we'll have AAV which stands for reward.
And that's the reward the agent gets for entering into a certain state and Gamma is the discount factor.
And we'll talk about the discount factor in a second all make sense.
Just now but just take notes.
Make a mental note that we are going to have this letter a gamble that we'll be operating with later
on.
So the person behind the Belmont equation is Richard Ernest Bellman.
He was a applied mathematician and came up with the concept of dynamic programming which we are now
which we now call reinforcement learning or which we call the Belmont equation.
Now in.
Well that's what we call now in 1953.
He came up with that concept and that's when the Belmont Belmont equation came to me.
So let's have a look at how this all works.
There's our lovely agent in the bottom left corner and he is in a maze.
And this is quite a classical maze where you've got some blocks the white blocks are blocks in which
the agent can step into the gray block is the one one that is just not accessible says like a wall in
this maze the green is where the agent is should be aiming to end up in and that's where we want the
agent to go that's the finish.
And the red is a firepit so if the agent falls into the carpet he will lose the game.
So in the firepit the reward which is are is minus one.
So that's our way of telling the agent that's not something we want you to do.
Like remembering the example of when we're training dogs we want to tell them like Bad Dog if if it's
not doing the right thing that we wanted to do something here we want to tell the agent that this is
not something that you should be doing it shouldn't be ending up in the square so every time it doesn't
up in the square you'll get a minus one reward so we'll be punished with a minus one reward.
On the other hand if it ends up in the Green Square it will get a plus one reward meaning that that
is what we wanted to do.
So those are the two rewards that the agent can possibly get.
And how does it learn how to operate in this maze just like in that example of the robot dogs that learn
to walk.
We're just going to let it not we'll just tell it that here are the actions you can do.
You can go up right left or down.
Those are the four possible actions that you can take and that's it.
How have a play around with that see what you can come up with.
So the agent might go to the right then they might go to more to the right they might go back to the
left they're just randomly pressing his button and they're trying to see what happens and they go back
here they go up go up go down go up go right.
So for now they haven't learned anything they just so far nothing's happened.
They go right and then bam they end up in the Green Square.
So they realize wow I just got a plus one reward.
So as soon as I stepped into the Green Square they got a plus one reward and that triggers the algorithm
to say OK that's really cool.
I am rewarded for ending up in the square.
So I want to end up in the square.
So what does that mean for the agent.
That means it starts ask the question how did I get to the square.
What was the preceding state I was in and what action that I take to get at the square and then it looks
back and says OK.
So the preceding stage was this one.
It turns out to be valuable in that state.
The one that spoke with the Red Arrow because from that state you're I'm.
I'm just one step away from getting the maximum reward I can possibly dream of of Plus One like a biscuit
for a dog from as soon as I know if I ever am in that state that square marked with a red arrow all
we'll have to do is press right.
So how do I tell myself how to remember that that state is valuable Well to me there's no difference
actually as the agent.
There's no difference in whether I am in the Green Square or in the white square right in the Green
Square I get the reward of one.
So I'm going to mark for myself that the white square is got for me it has the value of one because
it leads exactly to reward 1 so as soon as I'm in the white square I know I'll just take one more action.
I'll be in the Green Square and I'll get a reward of one.
So that's why I'm going to say that the value of this square is equal to one because it leads directly
off on any sort of subtractions.
As soon as I mean here I know my reward will be once I'm going to mark this square as equal to one.
That's the value that's the perceived value of being in this state.
Next the agent is going to be like OK so how did I get into this square.
And you know he might walk around again and so on and up in the square again and be like Okay how did
I get into this square before that.
And the way I got into this square was from this square.
Interesting.
Okay.
So as soon as I get into this square I know that all I have to do is go right.
And then from here I already know that I'm going to win.
I know exactly how everything is gonna unravel from here and I know the value of being in this state
is equal to 1.
And since there is no nothing is stopping me from running it from here to here.
The value in this is going to the perceived value.
I'm going to value being in here as equal to one as well because this is I mean here I know be here
and I'll be here pretty quickly.
So I'm going to win.
And then how do I get into this square before that.
Well I got into the square from this square so the value is similar approach the value of being here
is also equal to one and so on so the value of being here is equal to one value of being here is equal
time because each one of them leads to the next one and leads to the finish line.
So that's all like pretty logical at this stage.
This is us pretty much designing the Belmont equation right now.
So this is we could possibly think about designing an equation that helps an agent go through the maze.
So look at the reward than the preceding state.
Give it a value of equal to reward the preceding sentence also that kind of like creates this pathway
is all great and well but the problem here is OK what happens if our agent for some reason starts in
this state instead of starting here and taking these actions and it actually starts in the state.
How does it know how does it remember which action to take.
Should it go right or should it go down or should maybe go left or should go up.
How does it remember.
Which is the next continuation from here.
If the only values it has is these values of equal to answer you cannot see what's further away.
It can only see.
All right.
What I have here and what I have here.
How does it know which way to go.
Well at this stage it doesn't it's as pre identical for the agent which way to go.
And so that's why this approach doesn't really work.
It's a very very simplistic explanation.
Of course there's much more to it.
But in an intuitive way.
That's why we cannot just assign just carry on this value backwards like that because one of the reasons
is once the agent is in between these two values which whereas you're going to go it doesn't it can
get confused like that.
And so how do we solve this problem.
What are we going to do here.
And this is where we're going to start introducing the Belmont equation in its actual form slowly step
by step.
So the Belmont equation looks something like this.
So we've already talked about the value of being in a certain state as is your current state or any
given state.
And there is s as well.
And s prime is the state the following state the state that you will end up in after this state.
And by taking concerted action.
But we know that there's many actions that a agent can take and that's why we've got this Max over here.
So by taking an action what will happen to an agent.
So let's say we're in State s by taking an action in state s and we take action a what will happen is
will instantly get a reward by getting into a new state.
And remember that reward can be won or plus 1 or minus 1 if it's at the end of the game where it can
be a zero if it's throughout the game.
In this case our reward throughout the game is zero.
So that that's the reward.
Plus we will get into a new state which has value of as prime.
So that's the value of the new state and gamma.
We'll talk about that in a second but the point I'm trying to raise here or the point I'm raising here
is that we've got many different actions that we can take and that's why we've got the maximum.
So by taking action we get a reward plus we end up in a new state.
And so for every out of though in our case for our possible actions for every one of the possible four
actions we're going to have a equation like this.
So this is going to have a value for their will have different value for everyone and for actions.
And we're going to look at only the maximum because of course the agent wants to take the optimal state.
So if he's in state s he's going to look at these values he's going to find the maximum based on the
action and going to take that action that leads to the maximum of these values.
So hopefully that makes sense why we're taking a maximum here.
Then once we got the reward and the value the state why do we have this gamma parameter here.
Well it's there exactly to solve that problem of where the agent doesn't know which way to go because
it cannot it's comparing the values of two states on the on both sides and they're the same.
That's why the game is the discounting factor so we're going to have a look at that in now to better
understand.
So let's take our formula we'll put it here on the top right.
And now we will analyze what the values of the different states are and every state here is a square
and army.
So one of these any one of these white squares is a state and we were going to calculate the value of
being in that state.
So let's start with the square.
What is the value of being in this state.
Well we need to take the maximum of this value across elections and we know that this value represents
is maximized as we get closer to the finish line.
That's how it's constructed and by just by looking at you can see because here has got the reward.
And here has got a just counting factor multiplied by the value of the next state.
And it just makes sense that that's how we would construct that equation.
So it makes sense that from here the maximum of this value will be if we move to the right.
So that's how we calculate the value of a state this value of this state is equals the maximum or equals
to this value.
If we move to the right.
If we take that action of moving to the right.
So what will this value be.
Well the reward of moving to the right is equal to one.
And regardless what comment gamma is.
We don't have a value in the state because we are already in the best state possible.
So this is the final state.
It won't have a value we just get a reward here and that's the end of the game.
So the value will be of this maximum will be equal to one.
And that's why value of state as here is equal to 1.
Now things get interesting when we move to the left when we move backwards a bit.
So now let's calculate the value of this of being in this state and for that we're going to need karma.
So let's say our discounting factor is zero point nine.
And it all makes sense.
What a discounting factor is once we calculate that.
So from here just based on our intuition and based because we know how this maze is working how this
maze works we know that the best possible action is go to the right because from here we go here.
So that means a maximum will be achieved when in this state you go to the right.
And so let's see what happens if we plug it in here.
So if you go from here to here you don't getting your rewards will be a zero but then you'll get gamblers
who get zero point nine times the value of the new state which has won.
So in this case the value the hold result of this is 1 times or zero point nine times one equals zero
point nine.
So that's our values.
So if we calculate this now you'll see that from here we know just by looking at the maze we know because
we as humans because we're understanding how this equation works of course an A.I. the agent would have
to experiment with these things.
But because we have like a crystal ball we can see this whole maze.
We have the bird's eye view right now.
We know that the best action is going to go to the right.
So if we plug it all in here it'll be zero no reward plus the report 9 times the value in the state
zero point nine is zero point eighty one.
And so on.
So here it will be zero point seventy three.
And he will be zero point sixty six.
So you can see that the way the discounted factor works is it discounts the value of the state as you
are further away.
So if you're familiar with finance theory then it's a simple thing similar to time value of money.
Like what would you think about it this way what would you prefer to have five dollars today or five
dollars in ten days from now.
Just if somebody was to give you a choice I will give you five dollars today.
All you five dollars 10 days from now.
Well of course you would choose five dollars today.
Why is that.
Well because you can take those five dollars and you can invest them at a certain interest rate which
is very similar to Gamma and your five dollars in 10 days will actually grow into maybe five dollars
and 73 cents or something like that.
And that's how.
Time value of money works and very similar concept here.
And the important thing to understand here this is just a theory a way that reinforcement learning works
so.
Richard Belman came up with this equation and from then now that's how we use it.
So.
So you could go ahead and come up with a different equation.
It doesn't have to have gone might have some other factor it might not even have a factor.
But this approach works and that's why we're using it.
And this this is what it visually looks like.
So the further away you are the less value of it being in this state.
And in terms of time value for money if I could say to you.
Where would you rather be would you rather be here would you rather be here.
You would say I would rather be here.
So we're creating that hope that same phenomenon as in time value of money we're artificially creating
it through gamma.
So that in order to incentivize agents or inspire agents to be closer to the finish line.
So if an agent were to be asked which rugby hero here because of the way this equation works it would
choose to be here.
There's nothing more to that.
Nothing less.
It's not something that the world works this way.
No it's just something that we're artificially creating in order for our agents to understand that this
is this is good.
This is good.
They're all good.
But this one is better than this one and this one is better than this one and this one has been in this
one and that way you can see the old agent can see in which direction needs to go.
So it can see that if I'm standing here remember that problem that we had or was he standing here Yeah
so if he's standing here.
Do I go down or if I'm standing here to go up or do I go down.
Well now there's no it's not a problem anymore because he can see that it's actually better to go up
because the value is bigger here.
And then from here it is better to go right.
Because the value is bigger here than here.
And then from here is better to go right.
Because the value here is bigger than here here and from here.
He already knows that he needs to go right because he'll get a reward here of one.
So that's how this whole approach works.
Now let's have a quick look at the rest of the square.
So how do we calculate the value in this square.
Well here here is where things get tricky.
So from here you might not actually go left right you might actually go right.
So we can't just keep going like that because it might actually be shorter to go this way.
So what we're going to do is we're going to calculate the value in the square first and because obviously
from here are the best ways to go is up again.
That's because we see the crew we have the crystal ball we can see things and you'll see further down
in the section you'll see how the agent actually explores this understands this on their lives through
experimentation.
But for us we know that it's better to go this way so we're going to calculate the value here and that's
why we're going to calculate the value in this square first.
So here we have three possible actions.
In reality we actually have four we can also go left.
The agent could hypothetically press left and bump into the wall and stay here but for simplicity's
sake we're just going to show the actions that we knowing what we know and having the crystal ball we
know which actions are the ones actually to lead lead to something other than the same state again.
And so here from here we know that again just because we have a crystal ball we know that the best way
to go is this way.
And agent of course would have to experiment and find the best way and you will see how that happens
to further down in this action you'll see actually how an agent walks around and how you would experiment
trying to find these values.
But for us we know it's that way.
So here if we plug everything in once to the maximum the best output is when you go up here is a ones
point nine zero so you plug that in.
You get zero point nine.
OK.
So we calculate that one this calculate this one same approach.
This is you have three ways you can go actually four for the agent but for us we can see it's only three.
So zero point eighty one from here.
You have zero point seventy three and it actually ties in nicely with this value because then you just
kind of getting a three point sixty six and here you have zero point zero three because this is the
optimal right.
So there you go.
That is the values all of these states.
And now you can see that because we've created this equation we've created synthetically this whole
concept of the closer you are to the finish line the more valuable that state is not because we've created
that now it's pretty obvious for the agent which way it should go.
And we'll talk more about that in the coming Charles.
I hope you enjoyed today's session and I know it's a bit it might sound a bit very basic at this stage
but as we go through this section we will add a bit more complexity to it at the same time.
If you cannot wait if you want to jump into it then there is a paper which you can look at and it is
the original paper by Richard Bellman.
It's called The Theory of dynamic programming from 1954.
And you can find it at this link and they go so you can jump straight into it and read from the author
of the Belmont equation but just bear in mind that this is quite a mathematically heavy paper.
And on that note I look forward to your next.
And until then enjoy a.