Hello and welcome back to of course on deep learning.
All right.
Today we're talking about activation function.
Let's get straight into it.
So this is where we left off previously we talked about the structure of a one neuron.
So there it is in the middle we know that it has some inputs values coming in it's got some weights
then it adds up the weighted it calculates a weight at some of those inputs and then applies activation
function and step three it passes on the signal to the next year.
And that's what we're talking about today.
We're talking about the value that is going to be passed over so we're talking about the activation
function that's being applied.
So what options do we have for activation function.
Well we're going to look at four different types of activation functions that you could choose from.
Of course they're are more different types of activation functions but these are the predominate ones
that you'll be hearing about and that we'll be using in this course.
So here is the threshold function.
This is what it looks like.
So on the x axis you have the weighted sum of inputs on the y axis you have just the values from 0 to
1.
And basically the threshold function is a very simple type of function where if the value is less than
zero then the threshold function passes on zero.
If the value is more than zero or equal to zero then threshold per function passes on a 1.
So it's basically kind of like yes no type of function.
Very very straightforward very kind of like rigid type of function either yes or no.
No other options.
So there you go.
That's how it works.
Very simple function.
Let's move on to something a bit more complex now.
The sigmoid function very interesting formula that we have here you'll see just now there is one divide
by one plus E to the power of minus X..
Whereas in this case of course X is the value of the sum of the way that sums and.
So yes.
So this is what the sigmoid looks like.
It's a function which is used in the logistic regression if you recall from the machine learning course.
So what is good about this function is that it is smooth unlike the threshold function.
This one doesn't have those kinks in its curve and therefore is just nice and smooth gradual progression.
So anything below zero it just drops off above zero.
It looks approximates towards one and this sigmoid function is very useful in the final layer in the
output layer especially when you're trying to predict probabilities.
And we'll see that throughout this course.
And then we've got the rectified function rectified a function even though it has a kink is one of the
most popular functions for artificial neural network.
So it goes all the way to zero it is zero and then from there it gradually progresses as the input value
increases as well.
And we'll see that throughout the course we'll see that in other intuition tutorials and we'll also
see that how we use this function in the practical side of the course and I will comment on this a bit
more in a few slides from now.
So just remember the direct fire function is one of the most used functions in artificial neural networks.
And finally we've got one more function that you will probably hear about.
It's the hyperbolic tangent function.
It's very similar to the sigmoid function but here the hyperbolic tangent function goes below zero.
So the values go from 0 to 1 or approximate to 1 and go from 0 to minus 1 on the other side.
And that can be useful in some applications.
So we're not going to go into too much depth on each one of these functions.
I just wanted to acquaint you with them so that you know what they look like and what they're called.
If you'd like to get some additional reading then check out this paper by.
So you have year Laura what have you got called Deep sparse rectifying neural networks 2011 paper.
And there you will find out exactly why the rectify function is such a valuable function why it's so
popular used but nevertheless for now you don't really need to know all of those things for now we just
need to start applying them when you start using them more and more and more.
And so when you feel comfortable with the practical side of things then you can go and refer to this
paper and then you will be able to soak in that knowledge much quicker and it'll make much more sense.
But just keep this in mind that when you're ready when you feel that you're ready then you can go and
refer to this paper and get some valuable knowledge from them.
So I just to quickly recap we have the threshold activation function which looks like this the sigmoid
activation function which looks like this.
We have the rectifying function and we have the hyperbolic tangent from and now to finish off this tutorial.
Let's quickly do a few exercise soldiers do quick two quick exercises to help that knowledge sink in.
So first one is we've got an example here of a neural network of just one neuron and then right away
the output layer.
And the question is assuming that your dependent variable is binary so it's either 0 1 which threshold
function would you use some out of the ones that we've discussed.
We have the threshold function the sigmoid function there rectify our function and we've got the hyperbolic
tangent function in it's in there all forms.
Which ones would you be able to use for a binary variable.
Okay.
So the answers here are there's two options that we can approaches with.
So number one is the threshold activation function because we know that it's between 0 and 1 and it
gives you a 0 under certain rules in an otherwise it gives you once and only can give you two values
it fits perfectly fits this requirement perfectly and therefore you could say Y equals the threshold
function of your suite at some and that's it.
And in the second case which you could use is the sigmoid activation function it is actually also between
0 and 1 just what we need.
But at the same time you want it's just 0 1 right.
So you it's not exactly true that what we need but in this case what you could use it as is the probability
of Y being yes or no.
So we want y to be 0 0 1 but instead will say that the sigmoid function similar activation function
tells us whether it tells us the probability of Y being equal to 1.
So basically the closer you get to the top the more likely it is that this is indeed a one where a yes
rather than a no hand.
Yeah.
So that's very similar to the logistic regression approach.
And those are just two examples.
And if you have a binary variable Now let's have a look at another practical application let's have
a look at how all this would play out if we had a neural network like this.
So in the first input layer we have some inputs they are sent off to our first hidden layer and then
an exhibition function is applied.
And usually what you would apply here and what you'll see throughout this course is we would apply a
rectify activation function.
So it would look something like that we apply the rectify activation function and then from there the
signals would be passed on to the output layer where the sigmoid activation function would be applied.
And that would be our final output and that could predict a probability for instance.
So this combination is gonna be quite common where in the hidden layers we apply the rectifying function
and then an output layer.
We apply the sigmoid function.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed this.
DOYLE Now you are quite well versed in the four different types of activation functions and you will
get some hands on practical experience with them throughout this course we'll be using them all over
the place so you'll get to know them quite intimately and you should be quite comfortable with them.
But for now this is the knowledge that you need to progress and understand what is going to be happening
further down in this course.
And on that note I will look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.