Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video.
We started with our model architecture.
And now in this video we will complete it at this point.
We have free hidden layers in our neural network.
And there are only two parts missing from the model.
Our output layer and to complete the model compile it and that is our goal of this video to add both
things to add the output layer to our model.
Let us copy and paste the last layer and modify it because this is our output layer.
The number of units or neurons should be the same as number of classes or in this case actions.
And for the activation change rally to linear because we are going to use a means squared error for
our loss.
You will see why in a few windows.
But basically we will modify our actions with our rewards which is a continuous number and not a class
now that we are done.
We the model structure it's time to compile it write model dot compile and here as always we have to
provide a few arguments because these what we perform here is not classification but regression task.
We can't use the accuracy as our metric instead in this case we will leave it and empty okay for loss
provide MSE shorter for means squared error and for the optimizer specify optimizer is equal to DB DOT
cameras dot optimizer.
And here we will select Adam optimizer in the Adam provide L are shorter for learning rate and set it
to be equal to zero point zero zero one and return the model and now our model builder function is done
but for now the model function is not called and our model is not defined so let's do that in the in
its function at the end of it.
Right.
Self-taught model is equal to model builder.
This function will create a network initialize it and store it in this cell.
That model argument for us and that's it for this area.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.