Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in this video we are going to define our first class
application and briefly explain what the flask framework actually is.
If you haven't worked with the flask before the flask is a python library used to create a backend for
web applications.
With this framework we can easily create parts of our Web sites and functionality connected to a specific
path we can even specify what type of request that path expects.
Is it a POST request or a GET request.
There are other Python frameworks for building web applications as well.
But the flask is the easiest one to learn.
It provides just enough to get an ad up and running OK.
The first thing to do is to define the application right app equal to flask and if you remember this
is the main class from the flask library and if we take a look this class takes only one argument.
This name This name is built in Python variable that the reference to the current python file let's
execute this line of code and it will define the flask application.
That's it for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comment section.
Otherwise see in the next tutorial.