All right.
Exciting tutorial ahead.
Welcome back to of course on deep learning.
Today we're talking about holiday neural networks work.
Now we've led a lot of groundwork we've talked about how neural networks are structured what elements
they consist of and even their functionality.
And today we're going to look at a real example of how a new neural network can be applied and we're
actually going to work step by step through the process of its application so we know what's going on.
So let's have a look.
What example are going to be talking about.
We're going to be looking at property valuation so we're going to look at a neural network that takes
in some parameters of a property and value values.
And the thing here there's a small caveat for today's tutorial and that is we're not actually going
to train the network.
So a very important part in neural networks is training them up and we're going to look at that in the
next tutorials in this section.
For now we're going to focus on the actual application so we're going to work with a neural network
that we're going to pretend is already trained up and that will allow us to focus on the application
side of things and not get bogged down in the training aspect and then we'll color off the training
when we're ready know the end goal we're working towards some good.
All right let's jump straight into it.
So let's say we have some input parameters.
Right.
So let's say we have four parameters about the property we have area in the squared feet we have the
number of bedrooms that distance the city in Miles.
The nearer city and the age of the property and all of those four are going to comprise our input layer.
Now of course they're probably way more parameters that define the price of a property but for simplicity's
sake we're going to look at just these for now in its very basic form a neural network only has an input
learn and output layer.
So no hidden layers and our output layer is the price that we're predicting.
So in this forum What's these input variables would do is they would just be weighted up by the synopsis
and then the output there would be calculated basically the price would recalculate and we'd get a price.
And for instance the price could be calculated as simple as the weighted sum of all of the inputs.
And again here you could use pretty much any function you could use.
What we're using now we could use any of the activation functions we had previously you could use a
logistics regression you could use a squared function you could use prior to anything here.
But the point is that you get a certain output.
And moreover most of the machine learning algorithms that exist can be represented in this form.
This is basically a diagram attic representation of how you deal with the variables by changing the
way it's the formulas you can accomplish quite a lot of the machine learning algorithm that we've talked
about before and put them into this form.
And that just stands to show how powerful new neural networks are.
Even without the hidden layers we are already where you have a representation that works for most other
machine learning algorithms but in neural networks what we do have is an extra advantage that gives
us lots of flexibility and power which is where that increase in accuracy comes from.
And that power is the hidden layers and there we go.
That's our hidden layer we've added it in and now we're going to understand how that hidden layer gives
us that extra power.
And in fact to do that we're going to walk through an example.
So as we agreed this neural network has already been trained up and now we're just going to plug in
we're going to imagine that we're plugging in a property and we're going to walk step by step through
how the neural network will deal with the input variables and calculate the hidden layer and then calculate
the output layer.
So let's go through this is going to be exciting.
All right we've got all four variables on the left and we going to first start with the top neuron on
the hidden layer.
Now as we previously saw in the procedurals all of the neurons from the input layer they have synapses
connecting it.
Each one of them to the top neuron in a hidden layer.
And those systems have weights.
Now let's agree that some weights will have a non-zero value some weights will have a zero value because
basically not all inputs will be valid or not all inputs will be important for every single neuron sometimes
inputs will not be important and here we can see two examples that X1 next three the area in the distance
to the city in miles are important for that neuron whereas bedrooms and age are not like let's think
about this for a second why how would that be the case like why would a neuron be linked to the area
in the distance what does that what could that mean.
Well that could mean that normally the further we get from the city the cheaper real estate becomes
and therefore the space in square feet of properties becomes larger.
So for the same price you can get property of the further way you go from the city.
That's normal right.
That that makes sense and probably what this neuron is doing is it is looking specifically it's like
like a sniper it's looking for area properties which have which are not so far from the city but have
a large area.
So for their distance from the city they have an unfair square foot area.
Right.
So something as as abnormals as higher than average.
So they're quite close to the city but there's still large as opposed to the other ones at the same
distance.
And so that neuron again we're speculating here but that neuron might be picking out laser picking out
those specific properties and it will activate and hence the activation function it will activate it'll
fire up only when the certain criteria is met that you know the distance and the area of the proper
distance city and there of the area of the property and it performs his own calculations inside itself
and it combines those two and as soon as certain counter-terrorism and fires up and that contributes
to the price in the output layer and therefore this neuron doesn't really care about bedrooms and age
of the property because it's focused on that specific thing that's where the power of the neural network
comes from because you have many of these theories and we'll see just now how the other ones work.
So but what I wanted to agree here is that let's not even draw these lines for the Simpsons that are
not in play so that we don't clutter up our image that's the only reason we're not going to draw on
them.
So let's just get rid of those two and that way we will know exactly OK.
So this neuron is focused on area and distance to the city.
All right.
So as long as we agree on that let's move on to next.
Let's take them one in the middle here we've got three parameters feeding into this neuron.
So we've got the area the bedrooms and the age of the property.
So what could be the reason here.
Let's again let's try to understand the intuition that the thinking of this neuron how is this neuron
thinking why is it picking these three apartments what could it be.
What could have a hit like found in the data.
Right.
So we've already established this a trained up dataset.
The training has happened a long time ago maybe like a day ago or somebody already train opposites.
And now we're just applying and we know that this neuron through all the thousands of examples of properties
has found out that the area plus the bedrooms plus the age combination of those parameters is important.
Why could that be the case.
Well for instance maybe in that specific city in those suburbs that this neural network has been trained
up in perhaps there's a lot of families with kids with two or more children who are looking for large
properties with lots of bedrooms but which are new rights which are not old properties because maybe
in that's in that area almost all properties are kind of like big properties are usually old but there's
lots of modern families and you maybe there has been a social demographic shift and or maybe there's
been like a lot of like some growth in terms of employment and jobs for the younger set of population
maybe just you know the like the population demographics have changed and now younger couples or younger
families are looking for properties but they prefer newer properties so they want the age of the property
to be lower and hence from the training that this neural network has undergone it knows that when there
is a property of a large area and with lots of bedrooms at least through at least three bedrooms for
the parents for the first shelter the second child for at least three bedrooms maybe a guest room where
a new property with a high area and lots of bedrooms that is valued that in that market that is valuable
so that neuron has picked that up it knows that's OK.
So this is what I'm going to be looking for.
I don't care about the distance of the Syrian Miles wherever it is as long as it has high area lots
of bedrooms.
As soon as that criteria is met the neuron fires up and the combination of these two parameters and
this is again this is where the power of the neural network is coming from because it combines these
three parameters into a brand new parameter into a brand new attribute that helps with the evaluation
of the helps with the valuation of the property and combines them into a new attribute and therefore
it's more precise.
So there we go.
That's how that neuron works.
And let's look at another one let's look at the very bottom one for instance this neuron could be could
even have picked up just one parameter it could have just picked up H and not any of the other ones
and how could that be the case.
Well this is a classic example of when age could mean like as we all know the older property is usually
it's less valuable because it's worn out probably the building is old probably no things are falling
apart more maintenance is required.
So the price drops in terms of the price of the real estate whereas a brand new building it would be
more expensive because it's brand new but perhaps if a property is over a certain age that could indicate
that it's a historic property.
For instance if a property is under 100 years old then the older it is the less valuable it is.
But as soon as it jumps over 100 years old all of a sudden it becomes a historic property because this
is a property where people used to live hundreds of years ago.
It tells a story it's got all this history behind it and some people like that some people value that
in fact quite a lot of people would like that and would be proud to live in a property and especially
in the higher socio economic classes they would show off to their friends or things like that and therefore
properties that are over 100 years old could be deemed as historic and therefore this neuron as soon
as it sees a property over 100 years old it'll fire up and contribute to the overall price and otherwise
if it's under 100 years old then it won't do work.
And this is a good example of.
The rectifying function being applied.
So here you've got like a very like a zero until a certain point and then let's say 100 years old and
then after a hundred years old the older it gets the higher the value the higher the contribution of
this neuron to the overall price.
And there's just a wonderful example of a very simple example of this rectify or fan function in action.
So there we go that could be this neuron and moreover the neural network could have you picked up things
that we wouldn't have thought of ourselves right.
For instance bedrooms plus distance the city maybe that's in combination somehow contributes to the
price maybe it's not as strong as the other neurons and it contributes but it still contributes or maybe
it detracts from the price that could also be the case or other things like that and maybe you and your
own picked up all for a combination of all four of these parameters and as you can see the that these
neurons this whole hidden layer situation allows you to increase the flexibility of your neural network
and allows you to really look allows the neural network to look for very specific things and then in
combination that's where the power comes from it's like that example for ants right like an ad by itself
cannot build an anthill but when you have like a thousand or one hundred thousand ads they can build
an anthill together and that's that's the situation here.
Each one of these neurons by itself cannot predict the price but together they have superpowers and
they predict the price and they can do quite an accurate job if trained properly if set up properly
and that's what this whole course is about in understanding how to utilize them.
There we go so that is a step by step example and walk through of how neural networks actually work.
I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I can't wait to see you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.