Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're talking about a real Lou which is rectified linear units.
And this is an additional step.
On top of our convolution step.
So it's not a separate big step it's a small step it's step one b basically.
And what is going on here.
Well we have our input image.
We have our convolution layer which we've discussed.
And then on top of that we're going to apply.
Wait for it.
Our favorites rectify our function.
And you're really familiar with the rest of our function from the previous section on artificial neural
networks and in our so sometimes authorized or instructors instructor's separate the convolution and
the rectified as two separate steps in our examples we're just going to consider them the.
Just one big step for a second solution then rectify.
And the reason why we're applying the rector fire is because we want to increase non linearity in our
image or in our network and our commercial neural network and direct fire acts as that filter or access
that function which breaks up linearity.
And the reason why we want to increase non linearity in our network is because images themselves are
highly nonlinear especially if you're recognizing different objects next to each other or just on this
background and stuff like that like the image is going to have lots of nonlinear elements and the transition
between pixels adjacent pixels is often would be non-linear.
That's because as borders is different colors is different there's different elements in your images.
And but at the same time when we're applying a mathematical operations such as convolution and to running
this feature detection to create our feature maps we risk that we might create something linear and
therefore we need to break up the linearity.
So let's have a look at an example.
Here is a image an original image.
Now when we apply a feature detection detector to this image we get something like this.
So you can see here that black is negative White is positive values well when you apply a feature detector
to a like a proper image which has not just zeros and ones but has lots of different values and you
apply as we saw previously featured.
Texas can have negative values in themselves.
Sometimes you'll get negative values.
And here there are black ones are negative white ones are positive.
And what a rectified linear unit function does is it removes all the black rated anything below zero
turns into zero.
And so from this it turns into this.
Right.
And so it's it's pretty hard to see what exactly is the benefit in terms of four in terms of breaking
up linearity.
I'll try to explain.
I'll try to like show an example on this image.
But at the end of the day it's this is a very mathematical concept and we'd have to go into a lot of
math to really explain what is going on.
But let's let's try.
Let's have a look.
So for instance let's look at this.
This building here.
Right.
So this is a building on its own.
Then you can see this shadow this black part of this shadow over here.
Well you see that it's white the reflection of the light.
Then it's a gray and then it gets darker and then it gets darker again.
Right.
So and when we take it out we take out that black part.
So think of it in terms of linearity right.
So it looks like when you go from white to gray the next step would be black.
Right.
The next step would be black it's it's linear progression from bright to dark and therefore this is
kind of like a linear situation when you take out the black you break up the linearity.
Let's try another one.
Let's have a look here and at the same time it's still that same building right.
It's not it's not like you or you're like It's not like you're blending two buildings into each other
but that is secondary.
The main point is breaking up the linearity.
So let's have a look here.
Same thing.
So you see white gray black gray white.
And when you break it up you don't have that anymore.
Right.
You don't have that progression a gradual progression that you just have like a an abrupt change.
And that helps introduce non linearity into your image.
So it's a very rough explanation very kind of like on the on the fingers explanation rather than technical
but hopefully it kind of helps you understand a bit better what we're talking about here.
So here again you can see white gray is a better example even see bright darker darker darker darker
darker and darker.
So this part looks like it's linear.
Then you break it up like that again so this is a very rough explanation is not absolutely perfect but
at least gives you some idea of what's going on.
But if you'd like to learn more there's a good paper as always there's always a paper.
This one is by C.S. J.
Cole from the University of California.
And it's called Understanding evolution all neural networks have a mathematical model.
And basically there he answers to questions and you need to just look at the first one.
And the question is why in a non-linear activation function is essential at the filter output of all
intermediate layers.
So that kind of explains it in a bit more detail both in terms of intuition and mostly in terms of mathematics.
So that's an interesting paper where you can get some more additional information on this topic.
And if you really want to dig in and explore some some cool stuff here then there's another paper that
you might be interested in so-called delving deep into rectifying surpassing human 11 level performance
on image and that classification.
And here the author is combing hair and others from Microsoft Research.
They propose a different type of rectified linear unit function or they propose the parametric rectified
linear function which you see here on the right.
And they argue that it delivers better results with faults sacrificing performance.
So interesting read if you'd like to get a bit more into this topic.
And that's all for today.
The real you layer is pretty simple preset for adjusting just applying the rectify function and I look
forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.