Hello and welcome back to the course and deep learning.
Now that we've seen neural networks in action it's time for us to find out how they learn.
So let's dive into it.
There are two fundamentally different approaches to getting a program to do what you wanted to do.
One is hardcoded coding where you actually tell the program's specific rules and what outcomes you want
and you just guided throughout the whole way and you account for all the possible options that the program
has to deal with.
On the other hand you have neural networks where you create a facility for the program to be able to
understand what it needs to join it's on to basically create this neural network where you provided
inputs you tell it what you want as outputs and then you let it figure everything out on its own two
fundamentally different approaches.
And that is something to keep in mind as we go through these tutorials.
Our goal is to create this network which then learns on its own we are going to avoid trying to put
in the rules and a good example that I can give you right now is this will come further in the course
but it's just a very visual example for instance.
How do you distinguish between a dog and cat four on the left side on the process depicted on the left
you would program things in like the cat's years have to be like this look out for whiskers look out
for this type of nose look out for this type of shape of a face look out for these colors you kind of
you describe all of these things and you'd have conditions like if if the years appointee then cad if
the years are sloping down then possibly dog and so on.
On the other hand for in your network you'd just code the neural networks you called the architecture
and then you point the neural network at a full the reform these cats and dogs with images of cats and
dogs which are already categorized and you tell it.
OK I've got you I've got some images of cats and dogs go and learn what a cat is go and learn what a
dog is and the neural network will on its own understand everything it is to understand and then further
down once it's trained up when you give it a new image of a cat or dog it'll be able to understand what
it was.
So they're there they are.
Those are the two fundamentally different approaches and today we're going to slowly start getting into
how that second approach works.
All right.
So let's get straight to it.
Here we have a very basic neural network with a one layer is this is called a single layer of feed forward
a neural network and it is also called a perception.
Now before we proceed one thing that we do need to adjust is that output value.
Right now you can see that it's just a Y.
We need to put a white hat in there.
And the reason for that is usually why stands for the actual value and that's what we're going to be
using.
So why is gonna be the actual value which we see in reality output value is the predicted value by the
algorithm by the neural network white hat is the output value basically that's the denomination for
the output value and the perception that was first invented in 1947 by Frank Rosenblat and his whole
idea was to create something that can actually learn and adjust itself.
And this is what we're going to be looking at now.
So we've got our perception.
Let's see how perception learns so let's say we have some input values that have been supplied to the
perception and or basically to our neural network then the activation function is applied.
We have an output.
And now we're going to plot the output on a chart.
So there it is our output y hat.
Now what we need to do is in order to be able to learn we need to compare the output value to the actual
value that we want the neural network to get.
Right.
And that is the y value Y.
And so if we plotted here you'll see that there's a bit of a difference.
Now we're going to calculate a function called the cost function is calculated as one half of the difference
of the squared difference between the actual value and output value.
Now there are many ways you can come up with a class function.
There are many different cost functions that you can use.
This is probably the most commonly used cost function and why it is specifically this function that
we use we'll find out further down when we're talking about a gradient descent.
But for now we're just going to agree that this is the cost function and basically what the cost function
is telling us is what is the error that you have in your prediction.
And our goal is to minimize the cost function because the the lower the cost function the closer that
y hat is to wait.
Okay so as long as we agree on that let's proceed.
So basically from here what happens is there is our cost function.
And from here what happens is now we're going to once we've compared now we're going to feed this information
back into the neural network.
So there we go there's information going back into the neural network and it goes the weights and the
weights get updated.
Basically the only thing that we have control of in this very simple neural network are the weights
W1 W2 all the way to W..
And our goal is to minimize the cost function.
So all we can do is update the weights so we update the weights and tweak them a little bit.
And how exactly we'll find out for the done but for now we we agree that we have.
And then we continue.
So.
But here I've put up this screenshot of the data just to make some one point very clear that right now
throughout this whole experiment everything we're doing right now we're dealing with just the one roll.
So we're dealing with.
We have a dataset of one row where we have for instance we're dealing with.
How long you study it like the variable that we are predicting is what what's results you're gonna get
on an exam and the dependent independent variables that we have is how many hours did you study for
how many hours did you sleep.
And what did you get on the quiz.
In the mid semester or so in the middle of the semester is a quiz what percentage did you get there.
So based on those variables we're trying to predict what score you'll get for the exam exam.
Ninety three percent that's the actual value.
So that's why.
So.
So we feed these three values into our neural network.
Again for the second time now and then we're going to be comparing the result to white.
So let's see how this works.
We feed these values into the neural network.
Everything gets adjusted and weights get it just so as you can see this is again we're going to feed
the values.
Again the point here is that we're feeding in these same values.
So we only have one role we're trying to we're training on one row.
This is because this is just a very simple basic example.
Then we'll see what happens when there's more rows.
So again we feed these rows in our cost function get adjusted as you can see everything happens along
those lines again.
So as you see every time our white hat is changing because we've tweak the weights all I had is changing
our cost function is changing.
Let's have a look again.
So we feed those in.
Why had is changing cost function is changing.
We get information back feedback to the weights so that the weights get adjusted again.
We feed in the same values every time everything gets adjusted goes back to the weights.
And one more time.
Feed in.
OK.
And another time.
So we've adjust the weight adjust to the ways we feed and the information.
Aha.
And there we go.
So now this time the Y had is equal to y cross-functional zero.
Usually you won't get cost function equal to zero but this is a very simple example.
So hopefully all that made sense every time we feed in exactly that same row.
Because just in this case we're just dealing with that one row into our neural network where then the
weights get the value get multiplied the ways the activation function is applied we get why had why
y it is compared to why then we see how the cost function has changed.
FEEDBACK The feed that information backwards the neural network and adjusts adjust the weights again
and then we repeat the same process again with the same exact row.
We're trying to minimize that cost function.
So up until now we've been dealing with just that one rule.
Let's see what happens when you have multiple roles.
So here's the full data set.
We have eight rows of how many hours you slept or maybe these are different students in day taking the
same exam how many other hours they studied how many hours they slept before the exam what to get on
the quiz and their final result on the test.
And as you can see here on the left I've got eight of these perceptions actually.
They are all the same perceptions so this is also important to understand.
I just multiplied it all I duplicated eight times just so that we can conception is that.
But the important thing here is the same neural network we're going to be feeding these into one Samuel
network.
So let's go let's get started.
So one epoch as you'll hear had Lun mentioning one epoch is when we go through our whole dataset and
we train our neural network on on all of these roles.
So let's go let's get Sara.
So there is our first row and there is y had for the first row there is a second row there's Y had for
the second row.
So again is being fed into the same neural network every time I've just copied them several times.
So we can visually see how this is happening.
Then again it's happening again.
That's third row fourth row.
There is our way ahead for the fourth row and so on.
Basically then we get the same values for the remaining four hours as well.
So every time we just feed in a row into our neural network we get a value and then we compare to the
actual value.
So there are the actual values.
So for every single row we have an actual value.
And now based on all of these differences between y had and why we can calculate the cost function which
is the sum of all of those squared differences between why it has and why and how all of that is halved
and there's our cost function.
And basically now what we do after we have the full cost function we go back and we update the weights
we update W1 W2 W3 and the important thing to remember here is that all of these perceptions all of
these new networks is actually one neural network.
So there's not eight of them there's just one.
And when we update the weights we're going to update the weights in that one neural network.
So basically the weights are going to be the same for all of the rows.
So it's not the case that every row has its own weights.
Now all the rows share the weights.
And so that's why we looked at the cost function which is the sum of the square differences and then
we updated the weights and now from here that was just one iteration.
Next we're going to run this whole thing again we're going to feed every single row into the neural
network.
Find out our cost function and do this whole process again.
So just as we saw previously where we had just one row and we were doing everything again and again
and again.
Same thing here.
But now we're going to be doing it eight rows or eight hundred rows or eight thousand rows home.
I mean you rows you have in your data set you do this process and then you calculate the cost function
and the goal here is to minimize the cost function and to get as soon as you've found the minimum the
cost function that is your final neural network that means your weights have been adjusted and you have
found the optimal weights for this dataset that you're training on and you're ready to proceed to the
testing phase or to the application phase and this whole process is called back propagation.
So some additional reading that you might want to do for the cost function.
And I know we just talked about one and there are many different ones.
A good article is located on cross validated.
It's called a list of course functions used in your own networks alongside applications.
So the URLs there but you can just google for that exact search term or a search phrase and you will.
This one will be the first one that pops up.
It's actually got some good examples and application or use cases for different cost functions so if
you're interested to learn more about cost functions check out this article.
And on that note I hope you enjoyed this material.
I look forward to seeing you next then.
Until then enjoy deep learning.