Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're talking about Max pooling and we've got some very exciting slides coming up ahead.
And even a special surprise at the very end of the tutorial.
So let's get started.
The first question is what is pooling and why do we need it.
Well to answer that question let's have a look at these images on these three images we've got a cheetah.
In fact it is the same exact cheetah on the first image.
The image is positioned properly.
The cheetah is looking straight at you on the second image.
It's a bit rotated and the third image is a bit squashed.
And the thing here is that we want the neural network to be able to recognize the cheetah in every single
one of these images.
In fact this is just one cheetah.
What if we have lots of different cheetahs.
Here's a cheetah here's a cheetah here's another cheetah here's a cheetah here's a cheetah and here's
a cheetah and we want the neural network to recognize all of these shearers as shearers.
And how can it do that if they're all looking in different directions they're all in different parts
of the image.
They're like their faces our position in different parts of them if somebody is on the right hand side
somebody is in the left corner somebody is in the middle.
They're all a bit different.
The texture is a little bit different.
The lighting is a bit different.
There's lots of little differences and so if the neural network looks for exactly a certain feature
for instance a distinctive feature of the cheetah is the tears that are on its face going from the eyes
or the share the share shadows that look like tears the texture of the pattern that is going from its
eyes down it's on the sides of its nose it looks like tears that's a distinctive feature of the cheetah
but if it's looking for that feature which it learned from certain cheetahs in an exact location or
in the exact shape or form or texture it will never find these other cheetahs.
So we have to make sure that our war neural network has a property called spatial in variance meaning
that it doesn't care where the features I can not.
Not so much as in which part of the image because we're we've kind of taken that into consideration
with our MAP WITH OUR POOL WITH OUR convolution there but it doesn't have to care if the features are
a bit tilted if the features are a bit different in texture if the features are a bit closer of features
or a bit further apart relative to relative to each other so if the feature itself is a bit distorted
in our neural network has to have some level of flexibility to be able to still find that feature and
that is what pooling is all about.
So let's have a look at how pooling works.
Here's our feature map.
So we've already done all convolution and we've completed that part and now we're working with the convolution
layer.
Now we're going to apply pooling.
So how does it work.
We're going to be applying Max pooling there's several different types of pulling it can apply as mean
pooling Max pooling some pooling and we'll comment on those towards the end of the tutorial but for
now we're just applying Max pooling.
So we take a box of two by two pixels like that and again it doesn't have to be two by two you can choose
any size a box and again we'll comment on that towards senatorial and you place it in the top left hand
corner and you find the maximum value in that box and then you record only that value and you disregard
the other three.
So in your box our four values just disregard three you only keep one the maximum which is one in this
case then you move your box to the right by a stride you select the stride once again.
So here we select a strata of two and that's what you normally select you can select the straight one
you can select.
So there are overlapping boxes you can select any kind of stray that you like or even three if you want
but we're selecting Australia to here and that's what is commonly used.
And then you repeat the repeat the process you can record the maximum here if you crossover and doesn't
matter.
You just keep continue doing what you're doing.
So you still record the maximum here zero here the maximum is four here the maximum is to hear the maximum
is 1 0 1 0 2 and then 1.
So as you can see a few things happen.
First of all we still were able to preserve the features Right.
The maximum numbers they represent because we know how the convolution layer works we know that the
maximal or the bit large numbers in your feature map they represent where you actually found the closest
similarity to a feature.
But by then pooling these features we are first of all getting rid of 75 percent of the information
that is not the feature which is which is not the important things that we're looking out for because
we are disregarding three pixels out of four.
So we're only keeping 25 percent.
And then also because we are taking the maximum of the pixels that we or the values that we have we
are therefore accounting for any distortion.
So for instance two images in which for example the cheetah's tears on the eyes are in one image they're
a bit to the left or a bit rotated to the left and another one they're a bit and are how they're supposed
to be or how we like if we take one as the basis and another one there which rotate to the left the
pooled feature will be exactly the same.
So you can see here if we are talking about the cheetahs tears then let's say this is the four and this
is where it was here then if it was a bit rotated.
So for instance the four ended up over here then when we're doing the pooling we're still going to get
the same pooled feature map and that's kind of the principle behind it.
There is a very rough explanation again intuitive explanation but that's the point of pooling that we're
still being able to preserve the features and moreover accounts for their possible spatial or textural
or other kind of distortions.
And in addition to all of that we are reducing the size.
So there is another benefit.
So we've got we're preserving the features we're introducing spatial and variance.
We're reducing the size by 75 percent which is huge which is really going to help us in terms of processing.
And moreover another benefit of pooling is we're reducing the number of parameters so we're reducing
again by 75 percent we're reducing number of parameters that are going to go into our final layers of
the neural network and therefore we're preventing all refitting.
It is a very important benefit of pooling that we're removing information and that is a good thing and
that is a good thing because that way our model won't be able to over fit onto that information because
especially because that information is not relevant remember like at the very start we were talking
about even for human us as humans it's important to see exactly the features rather than all this other
noise that is coming into our eyes.
Well same thing for neural networks they by disregarding the unnecessary non important information we're
helping with preventing of overfishing.
So there we go that is what pooling is about.
And the question here is of course why why Max pulling right there's lots of different types of pooling
and you know why why astride of two why a size of two by two pixels lots of all these things.
And on that note I'd like to introduce you to this lovely research paper called evaluation of pooling
operations in convolution all architectures for object recognition by Dominic Shara from University
of Bonn.
There is the link and the beauty about this paper is that it's very very simple very straightforward.
So if you've never read a research paper before which you'd like to give it a go.
This is a great place to start it's very short.
Only 10 pages very easy to read and plus the extra benefit is that now that we've discussed convolution
and pooling you will be totally comfortable with everything that they're talking about in this paper
and you this is a great way to actually reinforce and also I highly recommend checking this paper out.
I'll take 20 minutes to read it and you can even skip part 2 which is called related work if it feels
a bit farfetched or alienating just don't read that part just go straight to from part 1 to part 3 and
the one thing that you do need to know about this paper they talk about a concept called Sub sampling
while sub sampling is basically average pooling.
So remember how here we were taking we were taking the maximum so in our square we're taking the maximum
value.
There's a concept called mean pooling or some pooling some pooling is you just some of these values
up average pooling or mean pooling you take the average value out of all of these and sub sampling is
kind of like a generalization of mean pooling.
It's it's a more kind of generalized approach to taking the average of all of these values and you can
read a bit more about in the paper but otherwise just think of it as average pooling when you're reading
that paper.
And so that's where you can get some additional information on this topic and now kind of let's recap
where how we got into it.
So there is our input image then we applied the convolution operation and we got the convolution there
and now to each of those feature maps that we get we've applied the pooling layer.
So we've got we've done these two steps convolution and pooling and now we're going to do something
very fun something exciting we're going to experiment with this.
So this is a screenshot I took from a tool created by Adam Hartley from white back when he was at Ryerson
University of computer science and now he's at Carnegie Mellon I think doing his PGD and great tool
so let's open up let's have a look.
So you can find it you can't actually find it through Google you have to know your URL it's as but it's
just hard to find Google because there's no tax here.
SC we're just this year.
Yes dot Ryerson dossier and then this stuff and then.
And basically this is exactly what we're doing.
But visualize.
So here you need to draw a number so let's say I draw on number four and this tool will put the number
four here.
That's your image in our first step.
Then this is the convolution step right.
And this is the pooling step and also pooling by the way is also called down sampling so pulling and
down sampling are the same things.
So you can see it's applied convolution then it's applied pooling and you can see how it exactly works.
You can see what kind of convolutions it has applied or what kind of filters it applied what they look
like to see what features is looking out for.
And then it's applying pooling so it's reducing the size and you can see here that this is important
right.
So you can see that this is the convulsive image and this is the pooled image and you can still see
the same features.
It's just less information but same features right.
The features are preserved.
That's the important part.
And moreover if you know if all four was a bit to the kind of like rotated a bit to the side it would
still be able to pick up very similar pooled layers.
And then after that it's got more layers we haven't talked about that yet.
So then it's got another convolution all convolution layer here which we actually won't have.
And then it has another pool layer but it's basically just repeating that same process.
And then after that this is what we're going to be talking further down in the course he's got the fully
connected layers and so on.
But you can definitely play around with that.
So if I delete that you like if I draw a seven you will see that it actually tells you that the guesses
it guesses that this is a seven and the second guess the second likelihood is a three.
So you can draw some some challenging things and see if it can pick them up so let's say if I draw something
that looks like a zero but it's not a finished zero will it pick it up.
No this this time didn't pick it up it looks like a nine to it to the image.
What if I kind of like finished like that.
So now it thinks it's a zero or a nine.
And you can see over there what's lighting up the zero or the night but we'll talk about that part for
the dark.
There's one more let's say like like eight.
I think it's a pretty hard for this now picked up an eight.
So you can see that goes into an eight and then like after that it stops being recognizable the stops
be making sense to us humans right.
These features that it's working with but at the same time it is correctly recognizing that it's an
eight.
Yeah.
So definitely play around with that you can draw a smiley face see what happens then looks like a 3
to this to this store because the tool is obviously trained up only on digits from zero tonight so it
has to recognize something there are of those and it recognizes a 3 is like in life when you when you
see something like a a type of fruit that you've never seen before like a custard apple or something
and you think that's it's like it's it's a pear because you've never actually seen one before you don't
know what to classify it as same thing here so it hasn't actually trained on smiley faces and that's
why it thinks that a tree is the three.
So there we go it's a very powerful powerful tool it'll be helpful for you to play around of it actually
when you put your mouse over a pixel pixel you'll show it shows you where the feature detector was to
pick up that pixel so you can see where those this pixel is coming from and also so you can see how
the filter was kind of like going through the image exactly how we talked about it of course and here
you can see you can see the the pooling you can see that the pulling is done with the pulling is done
with a little square size of two by two and you can see that it is the straight of two as well just
as we discussed in today's tutorial.
So there we go.
Player have a play around with that and I hope you enjoyed today's session.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then enjoy deep learning.