Hello everyone and welcome to despite an editorial in this video.
We are going to complete maybe the most exciting part of the whole distributed training project we are
going to dig through with our mole to multiple use or to be more specific to multiple devices superiors
or peers depending on what you have in your P.C. here.
I copy the model from previous videos.
The only difference I made here is to rename it from model normal to model distributed we had to make
that change so we can have some way to distinguish between models since they are the same.
The most exciting part of these distributed trainings strategy is that it is effortless to implement
in a similar manner when implemented mirror strategy.
This only single line of code to distribute our model what we are going to do now is to use this newly
created model and distributed to multiple use NCP use that we have on our disposal.
It is very straightforward process.
Let's start by defining the scope right with distribute which is the name of our variable for our strategy
and followed by scope and column.
Now we have to indent our model so it belongs to the scope that we defined by doing so it became the
part of the scope and also distributed to multiple abuse executed the cell and our model was defined
and well-prepared to be trained on multiple pillars or multiple devices.
Congratulations on coming this far and learning how to distribute any model in very easy and simple
way.
And that's it for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I seen the next tutorial.