Hello everyone and welcome to despite an editorial in the final video of distributed training project
in this video.
We are going to compare the training time for the normal model and the distributed one before our lesson.
I prepared only two lines of code where I define this starting time before our training process is started
and the simple string formatting where I'm going to print out how many seconds a training process took.
I've done that twice once for a distributed model and other one for the normal one.
Right now we are going to ride the same training process for both models on the same data set with the
same parameters but only different strategies one is distributed one and other one is on the single
GPO.
Let's start by calling model distributed that we defined above and let's call FID function on it.
We are going to provide X train and Y train that we had in Emily's data set.
It is followed by epochs which is going to be equal to 10 and batch size which is going to be twenty
five.
We are going to do the same thing for our normal model.
Copy the line and paste it in a dedicated cell for our normal model instead of model of distributed
change to model normal.
Now we are ready to execute these two cells and start the train process for a distributed model and
the normal one.
Are you ready for that guys execute the cells and by doing that we are going to start the board train
processes firstly it is going to complete the training process of our distributed model and then we
are going to jump in a normal model of training.
I will skip to the part where the training process is done.
Welcome back.
We finally have the results for our distributed and normal model training.
Let's see which one performed better.
We did expect to have our distributed system work better and to have better performance than our normal
case let's check if that is the case really as you can see here distributed training took around one
hundred and seventy three seconds.
Well the non distributed one took only one hundred and fifteen nine seconds.
Why is that the case well in this scenario we have the Depew and the CPI in the device pool and the
CPO works worse therefore it will slow down the GPO system.
If you have a single drip you in most cases it is going to perform better and faster without distributing
it to you.
And the CPO combination I would say that this was the edge case where the normal training performance
is better than the distributed one.
But if you have two or more deep use you're most certainly going to have better results by combining
speeds of both the GP use.
So if you find yourself in a situation where you have two or more deep viewers use this to be the training.
This outcome was probably unexpected to many of you but these were results and that's it for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.