Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this video we are going to create our tensor flow light converter the converter is there to convert
saved model to tens of low light version of it so it can be loaded and served over a mobile device OK.
Let's create it now right converter or you can name it whatever you want and equal to of the light which
is the API for our tens of low light dot of light converter and now we can choose what resources our
model comes from.
For example we have this frozen graph version or a session that are used for denser flow one models.
In our case we have these tend to flow from Kara's model file this function takes one argument which
is the model name and in our case this is the string that has H5 extension.
You can copy it from the cell above and paste it inside the brackets execute a cell and this converter
is going to define all frozen variables and OBS that can be found in our model.
And now we have officially created our converter for our specific model.
That's it for our video.
The only thing left to do is to call this converter and convert our model for now if you have any questions
or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.