Hello and welcome back to the course on the deep learning.
So we've learned quite a lot in this section of the course.
Let's summarize what we've talked about.
All right.
So here we go.
We started with an input image to which we applied multiple different feature detectors or also called
filters to create these feature maps.
And this comprises our convolution layer.
Then on top of that crucial layer we applied the red blue or rectified linear unit to remove any linearity
or increase non linearity in our images.
Then we applied pooling layer to our can relational there.
So from every single feature map we created a pooled feature map.
And basically the pooling layer has lots of advantages.
The main purpose of the pulling layer is to make sure that we have a special special in variance in
our images.
So basically if something tilts or twists or is a bit different to the ideal scenario then we can still
pick up that feature plus pooling significantly reduces the size of our images.
Also pooling helps with avoiding any kind of overfishing of our data or of our model to the data because
it just simply gets rid of a lot of that data.
But at the same time pooling preserves the main features that we were after.
Just because the way instruction and the pulling we used was Max pooling then we flattened all of the
pooled images into one along a vector or column of all of these values and we input that into an artificial
neural network.
And that was step three flattening and step four is the fully connected artificial neural network where
all of these features are processed through a network and then we have this final layer final fully
connected layer which performs of voting towards the classes that we're after and then all of this is
trained through a forward propagation and back propagation process and lots of lots of iterations and
epochs and in the end we have a very well defined neural network.
And the important another important thing is not only the weights are trained in artificial neural network
part but also the feature detectors are trained and adjusted in that same gradient descent process and
that allows us to come up with the best feature maps and in the end we get a fully trained evolutionary
neural network which can recognize images and classify them.
So there we go.
That's how can the volitional neural networks work.
And now you should be totally comfortable with this concept and ready to proceed to the practical applications
if you'd like to do some additional reading.
Then there's a great blog by alluded to Deshpande there from 2016 you can see the link over there at
the bottom so the blog is called The Nine Deep Learning papers you need to know about understanding
CNN's Part 3 and this blog actually gives you a short overview of nine different CNN ads that have been
created by people like young kun and others which you can then go ahead and study further.
So there will be a lot of new things that will be totally new to you and that you will have to get your
head around but just keep this blog in mind or these nine papers in mind and even if you're not ready
to go through them right now maybe after the Practical Tutorials maybe after you do some additional
training in the space of deep learning slowly you can then reference these works and ideally I think
you will get a lot of value through looking through other people's neural networks and how they structured
their can relational nets and that will help you understand what are the best practices and why people
did certain things in a certain way.
And that will help you with your architecture of neural networks because neural networks and kind of
delusional neural networks are not an exception.
They are like an architecture challenge you have to come up with a idea and then structure it and then
adjusted and tweak it to get the best possible design and the best possible and optimal performance.
So there we go.
That's us for today.
I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and this whole section and I look forward to see you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.