In this demo,
I'm going to show you how to use JUnit to write some simple
tests and how a good unit test is structured.
We are going to test the services for the types of rewards
Wired Brain Coffee can give to its customers.
Let me show you the code.
We have two packages, product and reward.
In the product package, we have a class that represents a product.
It has three properties, the id of the product,
its name and price, along with a constructor,
getters and setters, and the equals and hashCode methods.
On the other hand, we have the reward package Here,
the abstract class, RewardService,
is the base class for our three types of rewards.
All of them will have a field to store the points needed for the reward,
the method that will decide if the reward is given, and a helper method that
calculates the total of the order given a list of products.
The method applyReward returns an object of type
RewardInformation that tells the points that were redeemed
and the discount given by the reward.
Then we have a RewardByConversionService.
If the customer points are greater than the points needed for the reward and
the total of the order is greater than the reward amount,
it fills a RewardInformation object and returns it.
If these conditions are not met,
we just return a RewardInformation object with the default
zero values for the points and the discount.
In RewardByDiscountService,
if the customer points are greater than the points needed for the reward,
the discount is calculated to fill the RewardInformation object.
And in RewardByGiftService, once again,
if the customer points are greater than the points needed for the reward,
it checks if the gift product is in the order to fill a
RewardInformation object with the product's price as the discount.
All right, let's start by testing the RewardByDiscoutService class.
In the test, java directory, there's a package for each clip of this module.
And in the package for this clip,
you can find the class RewardByDiscoutService test.
This is a convention.
You can name your test class whatever you want.
However, by default, Gradle, Maven,
and the console launcher will pick up test classes with certain name patterns.
Of course, you can override this setting.
But for now, we'll use the default naming convention.
Each method of the test class must test exactly one thing.
Let's start with something simple,
like if the setter method of the field Needed Points works.
Some people follow very detailed naming conventions for methods.
But for now,
the only thing you need to know is that you can name
your method whatever you want,
but you have to annotate it with the Test annotation so JUnit can execute it.
Now I'm going to instantiate the RewardByDiscoutService class.
Set that 100 points are needed for the reward and assert
that getNeededPoints should return 100.
AssertEquals is a static method from the Assertions class,
and it's a helper method that allows you to check if the behavior
you expect from the class is correct or not.
Now I'm going to run the test, and here we can see that the test passed,
that the assertion was correct.
You might be thinking, well, of course it's correct.
It is just a setter method.
Yes,
but it's important to test every behavior or functionality of a
class because we could never know if some method,
like a setter, could be the source of a bug.
All right, in the same way, we can test the setPercentageForPoints method.
And yes, the test passed again.
Note that the setNeededPoints method was defined before
the setPercentageForPoints method, but the latter was executed first.
This is because, by default,
JUnit doesn't run test methods in a predefined order.
And it's fine.
Tests should not depend on the order they are executed.
But if you want to control the order in which test methods are executed,
you can annotate your Test class with TestMethodOrder and
specify a method order implementation.
You can also use the configuration parameter
junit.jupiter.testmethod.order.default if you want.
You can implement a custom method order implementation or
use one of the built‑in implementations,
for example MethodName to sort test methods alphanumerically
based on their method names and parameter lists or
OrderAnnotation to sort test methods numerically based on the
values specified with the Order annotation.
Let's specify this annotation and add an Order annotation to these methods.
So setNeededPoints is executed before setPercentageForPoints.
Let's see.
There you have it.
Now if one test fails, for example let's change this assertion,
all the test methods will be executed.
But JUnit will tell us how many tests failed and why they failed with an
AssertionFailedError thrown by the assertion method.
It also tells us the value it was expecting,
the value it got, and the stack trace of the error.
Let's change it back.
And now, let's test the case when the customer has no points.
Let's create the reward service,
setting a 10% discount for 100 points, and creating an order of 1 product,
let's say a small decaf for $1.99, pounds,
or whatever.
Then, I'm going to call the applyReward method,
passing the order and 0 as the customer points.
Then, assert that the discount should be 0, as well as the redeemed points.
And if we run the test, great.
They all passed.
Now look at the body of the test methods.
Do you see something in common?
These methods have three parts or phases.
In the first one, you set up the objects you need for the test.
In the second one,
you perform an action, and, in the third phase, to check
if the result was the one you expected.
So these methods have three phases.
However, in general terms,
every test has four phases that are executed in sequence.
The first one is arrange where you set up the state that
will allow you to perform the test.
This state is also called the test fixture.
In the act phase,
you call the function or perform the action that you are
testing and, in the third phase, to check whether you got
the expected outcome or not.
Finally, in the annihilation phase,
you put the system back into the state in which you found it.
This phase is not often explicit.
For example,
if we just create an object and set some of its
properties, at the end of the test,
Java's garbage collection will take care of that object. For that
reason, this phase is often neglected. And you may hear many people
talking about only the first three phases,
but that final phase can be important when working with resources that must be closed, for example.