Let's talk about a few of the benefits of unit tests.
They reduce debugging time.
A good suite of tests and some good practices can reduce bugs and debug time.
Unit tests also work as low‑level documentation.
They are written in code.
Instead of reading a manual,
you can read the code of the test to see how a library works and even
copy/paste snippets of that code and modify them to fit your needs.
And tests can help to improve the design of your application.
Think about this.
Tests are another client of your application.
A good design makes your code accessible to those clients to your test.
So tests can have a big influence on the design of
your application to make it testable,
especially when you write tests first in a practice
called test‑driven development.
Maybe you're thinking all right, this sounds very good. But in the real world,
it would be very hard and time‑consuming to create
a test suite that I can trust.
Well, yes, it's hard, but not impossible.
And at the end,
you'll save time by reducing debugging time. And if done
correctly, you can also get something that is worth more
than all these things put together.
Think about this.
What if we could have tests that were as easy to run as the click of a button?
What if the test of the whole application could run in a matter of minutes?
What if those tests were so complete that almost no bugs could
escape from them? What if those tests were always up to date
with the code of the application?
Well, something like that will give you courage,
courage to change the code to make it better.
Sometimes, we are afraid to make changes because if something breaks,
it will be our fault, and we'll have to fix it.
But over time, we'll have to make changes or add new features anyway.
And eventually, the quality of the code will degrade.
What do you think is better? An ugly and terrible designed system, but with
a good suite of tests or a system perfectly designed,
but with a horrible suite of tests or no tests at all. Over time,
you could improve the ugly system because you won't be afraid to
change it. But the perfectly designed system,
it will degrade and become an ugly system,
all because you didn't cover your back with a suite of
tests of enough quality to give you the trust and courage to eliminate the fear of change.