To right tests in JUnit 5, you have to include,
as a dependency of your project,
the Jupiter API with org.junit.jupiter as the group ID
and jupiter‑api as the artifact ID.
Now here's how a simple HelloWorldTest class looks like.
If you have worked with JUnit before,
you'll notice there are a couple of differences.
The name of the annotation package has changed.
It's now org.junit.jupiter.api.
And now classes and methods are not required to be public.
They can have package visibility.
However, you still have to annotate test methods with the Test annotation.
Now regarding IDEs, the most popular ones support JUnit 5,
IntelliJ since version 2016.2, Eclipse since Eclipse Oxygen 4.7.1a,
NetBeans since the 10.0 release,
and Visual Studio Code supports JUnit 5 via an extension,
the Java Test Runner extension.
It's easy to get started.
For example, in IntelliJ, I'm going to create a new class,
HelloWorldTest, and I'm going to paste our HelloWorld class.
Now I can position the cursor on the Test annotation and,
with this menu, choose the option to add JUnit 5 to the class path.
This option adds the JUnit 5 version that comes with
the release of IntelliJ you're using.
But you can also search for another version and choose
options like where to download the file or if the source
files should be downloaded too.
I'll click OK.
And in the External Libraries section,
you can see the JAR files that were added to the project.
In addition to the JUnit JAR files, there's an apiguardian file.
It contains an API annotation that is used by some JUnit classes.
An opentest4j.
This JAR belongs to the open test alliance for the JVM, a proposal by the JUnit
5 team for an open‑source project to provide a minimal set of classes that
testing libraries and tools can support consistently.
All right, now that the compiler errors are gone,
we can run the class, and everything should work.
Other IDEs work similarly.
But of course, this is great when you only work inside of one of
these IDEs and with the tools they provide.
But most likely, you have your project set up with a build
tool like Gradle or Maven. So let's look at how to set up JUnit 5 with these tools.