In JUnit, we use the Test annotation to mark methods as tests.
The behavior of these tests has to be specified at compile time.
It cannot be changed at runtime.
For example, if we want to execute this method on multiple sets of data,
one way to do it would be to create a list and iterate it to
act and assert on different data each time.
We can also use the RepeatedTest annotation and the
RepititionInfo interface and remove the for loop,
but still act and assert on different data each time.
However, there's a better way.
JUnit 5 introduced dynamic tests,
which are generated by a method annotated with TestFactory,
which is not a test method by itself, but rather a factory of tests.
The restriction is that this TestFactory method must not be private or static.
Otherwise, they won't be executed by JUnit.
To create a test, the TestFactory uses as data source Collections,
objects that implement the Iterable or the Iterator interfaces,
Streams, or Arrays.
All these sources must contain elements of type DynamicNode,
an abstract class that is the parent of DynamicContainer and DynamicTest.
DynamicContainer is a container of DynamicTest that has its own display name
and contains either an iterable or a stream of dynamic nodes.
In other words, it can contain other DynamicContainers or DynamicTests.
The class DynamicTest represents the tests generated at runtime.
It is composed of a display name and an executable,
a functional interface that wraps the code of the test so it can be
provided as a lambda expression or method reference.
However, BeforeEach and AfterEach methods are not executed for each dynamic test.
Dynamic tests have no notion of the test lifecycle.
All right,
it's time to see how the lifecycle is handled and how to work with
the classes DynamicTest and DynamicContainer.
I have already created a class to test the RewardByGiftService with
dynamic tests with methods to get a stream of random numbers and a
sample order that we'll use later.
Let's start by creating dynamic tests from the collection.
The first thing I have to do is annotate this method as a TestFactory, not Test.
Remember, this is a TestFactory.
Then, I'm going to return at list of DynamicTest instances.
For this,
the DynamicTest class has a static method with the same name to create
DynamicTest with the supplied display name and lambda expression,
which represents the functional interface executable.
In this case, I just have an assertEquals method,
but I'm going to paste another dynamicTest and run the class.
Here on the left side, you can see the two dynamic tests.
Now let's modify the assertion of the first test to make it fail.
The first test failed, but the second test was executed.
These tell us that dynamic tests are executed independently from each other.
I'm going to fix the assert method and add a setUp method
that right now just prints a message.
If I run the test, you can see that only one message is printed.
The setUp method was executed once for the whole factory,
not for each dynamic test. BeforeEach and AfterEach methods
are not executed for each dynamic test.
Okay, instead of a collection,
you can use an iterable. List implements this
interface, so there are no problems here.
Or you can use an iterator.
Just let me add it here.
Great.
We can also use streams.
So let me add a RewardGiftService variable to initialize it in the setUp
method and change the method to test. If the gift product is not in an
order, the reward should not be applied.
So I'm going to get a stream of random numbers. Limit them to 5.
And using a map method in a lambda expression,
I'm going to take that random number and call the dynamicTest static method
with the display name Testing product ID and a lambda expression to set the
random number as the GiftProductId. Apply the reward and assert that the
discount and the redeemed points are 0.
If I run the class,
you can see that the test was executed five times with
a different product ID each time.
Now let me show you another way to implement this test with
another method from the DynamicTest class, stream.
This method takes three parameters.
First,
an iterator that serves as a dynamic input generator. Then a
function, the functional interface function, generates a display
name based on an input value. And a consumer that executes a test
based on the input value.
The last two parameters take the same type as the iterator.
So we need an iterator that generates random numbers.
Luckily,
streams have a method to convert the stream to an iterator. So we only
need to call this method on the stream of random numbers.
Now as we are using an iterator of type long for the display name generator,
we need to have a function that takes a long and returns a stream, in
this case Testing product ID plus a random number.
Finally,
we just need to wrap the code of the test in a lambda
expression of type ThrowingConsumer,
which is a regular consumer that throws exceptions of type throwable.
Let's run the test.
Great.
Once again, five dynamic tests with random IDs. Finally,
let's create a dynamic test with containers.
Let's add another factory test method.
This one will return a stream of DynamicContainers.
I'm going to start with a stream of numbers from 1 to 6,
which are actually 5 because the upper bound of this method is exclusive.
Then, I'm going to convert these numbers to dynamicContainer objects.
Their display name is going to be a Container for ID plus the
given productId. As a second parameter, the method
dynamicContainer can take a stream of DynamicNodes.
The first element is going to be a dynamicTest to test if the given
productId is valid, in other words if it's greater than 0. And the second
element of the stream is going to be a DynamicContainer.
Remember that both DynamicTest and DynamicContainer extend from DynamicNode.
For this container, we are going to have a dynamic test, this time, to test
that a discount has been applied because the numbers generated are the ones
that happen to be in our sample order.
All right, let's run the class. DynamicTestsWithContainers, 5 containers,
1 for each productId from 1 to 5.
And then we have the test to validate the ID and the nested container with the Discount applied test.