The first difference between JUnit 4 and 5 is that
JUnit 5's API uses a new package, org.junit.jupiter.
All classes and annotations are now under this package This way,
a project can contain tests from different JUnit persons without conflict.
About API differences, in JUnit 4,
you have to declare the test methods and classes as public.
In JUnit 5, public classes and methods are not required.
They can have packaged visibility.
About lifecycle annotations, in JUnit 4,
you have to annotate with BeforeClass the methods you
wanted to run before all tests,
with Before the method you wanted to execute before each test,
After to execute them after each test,
and AfterClass to execute them after all the tests.
In JUnit 5, well, you can remove the public modifier,
and the annotations change their name to BeforeAll,
BeforeEach, AfterEach, and AfterAll.
And if you're using a PER_CLASS lifecycle,
you don't have to mark the BeforeAll and AfterAll methods as static.
In JUnit 4,
you use the Ignore annotation to ignore or temporarily disable a test.
In Junit 5, this annotation changes its name to Disable,
but you can still use Ignore with JUnit 5 tests.
Just add junit‑jupiter‑migrationsupport as a dependency of your
project and annotate your test class with ExtendWith
IgnoreCondition.class or EnableJUnit4MigrationSupport,
which automatically registers the IgnoreCondition extension
and adds limited JUnit 4 rule support.
IgnoreCondition is an extension of type ExecutionCondition that disables test
classes or test methods that are annotated with Ignore.
In JUnit 4,
you use the Category annotation to organize your test methods
or classes into categories so you can choose to run only those
elements of a given category,
and you use classes or interfaces as categories and
subclasses as subcategories. In Junit 5,
this functionality is done with the Tag annotation,
passing a string as a tag identifier and without support for subtyping.
Now about assertion methods, first of all,
in JUnit 4, you can find them under the class org,junit.Assert.
Because of the new architecture of JUnit 5,
the assertion methods now belong to the JUnit Jupiter project and they
were moved to the class org.junit.jupiter.api.Assertions.
But the biggest change regarding assertion methods was the parameter order.
In JUnit 4, the first parameter is the error message,
then the expected value, and, finally, the actual value.
In JUnit 5, the expected value comes first,
then the actual value, and, finally, the optional error message.
Also, with lambda expressions,
we can have lazy error messages that are only created when needed.
In JUnit 4, we have an assertThat method that took a Hamcrest matcher,
which caused to always include Hamcrest as a dependency of JUnit.
Well, not anymore.
In JUnit 5, assertThat is gone.
If you want to use this method,
include Hamcrest as a dependency explicitly and use it directly from it.
In JUnit 4, to continue the execution of a test after an assertion failure,
you have to define another collector.
In Junit 5, there are no rules, methods don't need to be public,
and we can use the assertAll method that takes a variable number of
lambda expressions that wrap each assertion method to execute the
null and aggregate all the possible errors.
Next, we have methods that test timeout.
In JUnit 4, you can specify a timeout with the Test annotation,
but this only applies to one method.
If you want to apply a timeout to all the methods of a class,
you have to use a rule. In JUnit 5, you can use the assertTimeout method,
passing the timeout as a duration object and a lambda expression or
the method assertTimeoutPreemptively, which takes the same
parameters, but aborts the execution of the lambda expression if it
takes more than the specified duration.
Also, in JUnit 5,
there's a Timeout annotation that allows you to declare that a test,
TestFactory, TestTemplate, or Lifecycle method should fail if its execution
time exceeds a given duration. That defaults to a second,
but can be configured, and it can be declared at the class level too. To test
if an exception is strong, in JUnit 4, we have three ways. First, the old
school way with a traditional try‑catch statement.
If the execution flow reaches the end of the try block,
the test fails. Otherwise,
one or more assertions are made inside the catch block.
The second way is with the Test annotation, declaring the expected exception.
And the third way is to use a rule, ExpectedException, to test the type of
the exception thrown and something about its message.
But in JUnit 5, you can use the assertThrows method to declare that the code
of a lambda expression can throw an exception, and this method also returns
the exception thrown in case you want to assert something about it. About
JUnit 4 extension model, on the one hand,
it was based on runners and, on the other hand, on rules or class
rules. JUnit 5 pays special attention to extensibility, and now it
is based on interfaces that you can implement to get control on
certain extension points.
In addition,
Junit 5 comes with new features not available in previous
versions or at least not in a native or easy‑to‑implement
way, features like nested tests, custom display names,
Java 8 support,
parameter injection, dynamic and parameterized tests, and meta‑annotations.
If you're thinking about migrating all your tests to JUnit 5,
please don't migrate them all at once. Do it gradually.
You can run your JUnit 4 tests with the JUnit Platform and JUnit Vintage engine. In the next clip, you'll see how to do it.