JUnit provides a command line Java application that allows
you to launch tests from the console.
I'm talking about the JUnit ConsoleLauncher,
an executable JAR that comes with all the dependencies it could
require to run JUnit tests, like the Jupiter API or the Vintage
Engine. It's published in the central Maven repository under the
JUnit Platform project.
You can download the junit‑platform‑console‑standalone JAR directly from there,
and you can run it like any Java application with java ‑jar,
passing some options,
for example the path to the compiled application and test classes
and an option like scan‑classpath so it can automatically look for
methods with the Test annotation.
However, when using a lot of options,
you may run into system limitations on the length of the command.
So the ConsoleLauncher supports argument files for long common lines.
For example, suppose we have a file with this content.
The arguments within a file can be separated by new lines or spaces.
And if an argument contains whitespace,
the whole argument should be wrapped in double or single quotes.
This way, the command is invoked with the @‑file argument,
which will be expanded to the contents of the file.
So let's see how to use this ConsoleLauncher.
I have prepared a project with test classes we reviewed
in the other modules of this course.
In the root directory of the project,
I have downloaded the junit‑platform‑console‑standalone JAR.
So I'm going to open a terminal and build the project with Maven,
but you can also use Gradle if you want.
We can see that Maven found 67 tests and skipped 3.
Okay, remember these numbers.
The ConsoleLauncher should execute the same number of tests.
Now,
I am going to execute the ConsoleLauncher with java ‑jar
junit‑platform‑console‑standalone.jar.
And with the option ‑cp,
I'm going to provide as classpath entries the classes of
the application and the test classes.
I'm on a Windows machine,
so I have to use a semicolon as the classpath separator.
If you're on Linux or Mac, remember to use a colon instead.
For Gradle, you'll have to specify something like build/classes/java/main,
build/classes/java/test, and built/resources/test.
Finally,
I'll use the scan‑classpath option to run all the test methods of the project,
so let's see.
Okay, it gave us more details, but here are our 67 tests,
3 of which were skipped.
The ConsoleLauncher presents a summary of the tests in a tree format.
However,
in this case, it is not displayed nicely. Under the hood, IntelliJ's
terminal uses the Windows command prompt. On Mac or some Linux
shells, the summary will be displayed nicely. But here on Windows,
we'll have to use another terminal.
One I like is ConEmu. It's free to use. It has a lot of
features, and it's pretty customizable.
I'm going to execute the command to launch the tests from
the console. There you have it. This time, the summary is
printed in a nice format.
However, if we don't want this level of detail,
we can use the details option with the value summary. You can see just the final
summary and the statements printed to the standard output.
You can see all the options you can pass to the
ConsoleLauncher with the option ‑h or ‑‑help. All right, now let's review the configuration options for Gradle.