JUnit 5 provides an easy upgrade path,
but you don't have to migrate all your JUnit 4 tests to JUnit 5 if
you don't have a compelling reason to do it.
JUnit 5 is backward compatible.
The JUnit Vintage engine allows you to run your existing JUnit 3 and
4 tests using the JUnit Platform infrastructure.
But it turns out that this JUnit platform is also forward
compatible with the help of the JUnitPlatformRunner,
meaning that the tools that support JUnit 4 can execute
JUnit Jupiter tests with this runner.
This, and the fact that all JUnit Jupiter classes and annotations are
located in a new package, allows having both JUnit 4 and JUnit 5 libraries
in the classpath at the same time without problems.
In this demo,
I'm going to show you how to run JUnit 4 tests on the
JUnit 5 platform using JUnit Vintage,
having in the same project JUnit Jupiter tests.
I have created a project named JUnitVintage with
configuration files for both Maven and Gradle.
Let's open the build.gradle file.
The project has JUnit 5, JUnit 4,
and JUnit Vintage as dependencies. The pom.xml file, let me
open it, contains the same dependencies. In the test directory,
I have created a class to test the RewardByConversionService
using JUnit 4 annotations.
So I have a setUp method that is executed for each test
and one, two, three, and four tests.
I'm going to run the class with IntelliJ. There you have it. Four tests
passed. Now I'm going to create another package for the JUnit 5 version of
this test and create the class RewardByConversionServiceTest. I'm going to
paste the import statements I'll need. Notice that I'm using the Jupiter
API, now the setUp method, the four tests, and the helper methods.
Now I'm going to execute the test class from the IDE. Four tests
pass. Great. And in the terminal, mvnw test. Tests run: 8 because it
executed the JUnit 4 and the JUnit 5 tests.
But that's not all.
If you have watched the module Integrating JUnit 5,
you'll know that with Gradle, we can filter the execution of tests by engines.
So I'm going to modify useJUnitPlatform to add a filter to
exclude the tests of the JUnit Jupiter engine.
Now I'll execute gradlew test. And if we open the report located in build,
reports, tests, test, it only found four tests, the JUnit 4 tests executed
by the JUnit Vintage engine. So there you have it. You can have in the same project JUnit 4 and JUnit 5 tests.