In this module, you have learned about dynamic and parameterized tests.
Dynamic tests are created by TestFactories, and they don't
support the life cycle of regular tests.
These TestFactories use as data source collections,
objects that implement the Iterable or the Iterator interfaces,
streams, or arrays. These sources must contain elements of type DynamicNode,
an abstract class that is the parent of DynamicContainer and DynamicTest.
On the other hand,
parameterized tests are more like regular tests because they have
support for lifecycle methods. To use parameterized tests,
you must add to your project the dependency junit‑jupiter‑params.
The test parameters can be provided by more than one source.
You can use annotations like MethodSource that use methods to provide those
arguments, and you can even implement your own custom sources.
You can also provide custom display names with the help of
predefined placeholders and custom converters to convert
one argument type to another.
If you need to choose between dynamic and parameterized tests,
it may be helpful to ask yourself these two questions.
Do I need to support lifecycle methods, and where am I
going to get the data to create my tests?
I'll see you in the next module. Take care, and thanks for watching.