At the time of this recording,
JUnit comes with a built‑in extension, TempDirectory, that
creates and cleans up a temporary directory if a non‑private
field in a test class or a parameter in a test or lifecycle
method is annotated with TempDir.
The type of the field or parameter must be path or file.
Here's an example of this extension in a test method.
After the method finishes, the directory and its content will be deleted.
However,
most extensions are packaged and maintained in separate libraries.
On the Wiki of the JUnit 5 GitHub repository,
you can find a page about third‑party test engines and extensions.
There are some extensions for running tests with other engines. But as you
can see, most of the extensions are for JUnit tests.
There are extensions for Docker and JPA, for example.
Also, there are projects, such as JUnit Pioneer, that pack many extensions
into one dependency. On JUnit's GitHub, you can find another repository
that contains a collection of sample applications and extensions for
JUnit. About extensions in particular, there's a project that, at the time
of this recording, contains two sample extensions that show you how to use
ParameterResolver,
which we already covered in this module, and
TestTemplateInvocationContextProvider and TestTemplateInvocationContext.
Take a look at the code of these extensions. And if
you have questions or problems, don't hesitate to contact me. All right, let's wrap up this module.