Now in this course, we've created serverless environments,
we've created containerized environments,
we've even created networking environments.
We'll end this course by creating a virtualized environment in the cloud.
So in this module,
we're first going to talk about how to create EC2 instances using the CDK.
We'll then use the JSii interface to implement CDK interfaces in Python.
Lastly,
we'll end with some final tips regarding the CDK project and
how to stay updated with the CDK project.
Now, going back to our scenario,
you can think of these instances as Globomantics wanting to
implement a more virtual machine type infrastructure.
Maybe they realize they have something that they cannot run on a container.
So what we're going to do is,
with the network we created from the previous module,
we're going to set up a bastion host that can connect to our private subnets,
our EC2 instances, which host a web application, and a load balancer, which will distribute the traffic to these EC2 instances.