In this demo,
we're first going to learn about how you can use local
assets to build a Lambda‑backed API.
So you're going to see how although the Lambda function is stored locally,
CDK is still able to deploy the Lambda function.
Secondly,
we'll talk about how you can use additional CDK
modules using Python setup tools.
Remember that each AWS service can actually have its own CDK module,
and you will need to import each one.
Third, you're going to actually deploy the app using the CDK CLI.
And finally, we're going to view these resulting resources on CloudFormation.
Now,
let's first take a look at the Lambda function that we're
actually going to end up deploying.
You can see here on my left side,
I have a Lambda API folder with a welcome.py file.
This is a very straightforward Lambda function.
All it does is it takes in a query string parameter,
and then it returns that query string parameter as a Hello message.
So if we pass in the query parameter name,
then it's going to say Hello name or Hello, Zenon.
This just returns a plain text type, so nothing fancy, just a simple API.
We need to put this, however, behind an API gateway.
Now, let's look at the app.py file.
We will need to change this app.py file into something that can
create our Lambda function and API gateway.
Now, let's first look at what we have so far.
So far,
we have this app.py file which creates an app object from the core CDK library.
This app object is actually passed to the infrastructure CDK
stack constructor as the stack's scope.
We're also passing in a label for this stack.
This label will actually be the name of the CloudFormation stack
that the CDK template is going to provision,
so this is just an arbitrary label.
Finally, we need to pass in the context information.
Particularly,
we need to pass in what environment information we need to deploy this stack in.
In this case, we're deploying this stack to the us‑west‑2 region,
and we'll show later how we can change this to whatever default
region is configured in your CDK environment.
We will also need to edit the stack that was created
from the default CDK template.
This current stack just deploys an sqs.Queue.
We don't want an sqs.Queue.
So we're going to remove all of the contents of this stack,
and we're also going to remove all of the libraries that we
imported because we don't need any of these libraries.
Let's actually import the libraries we're going to use for this Lambda function.
So I'm going to import the Lambda library,
and I'm going to import the AWS API Gateway library as well.
Let's also choose more meaningful names,
and we're going to call this class the LambdaStack.
We're also going to rename this file into Lambda_Stack.
Now, let's take a look at the components of this function.
First off, the constructor of this class again takes in the scope,
which is the application that we're creating in app.py,
the id, which is of type string or just the label for this stack,
as well as additional arguments that could be the context,
for example, the environment you want this stack to be deployed in.
Now, like any Python class, we're going to start by initializing the constructor,
so we're going to keep this line from the original CDK default app.
Now, let's create our hello_function, so we're going to create hello_function,
which is of type lambda.Function.
Now, lambda.Function takes in several arguments for its constructor.
So we're going to pass in the self,
we're then going to pass in the label for this lambda.Function.
In this case, WelcomeHandler.
We're also going to pass in the runtime environment for this lambda.Function.
So the runtime environment for this lambda.Function is going to be Python 3.7.
This lambda.Function runtime is actually part of the AWS CDK libraries,
so we just put lambda.Runtime.PYTHON_3_7.
Finally, we need to specify where our code is located.
Notice here that our code is located in our local environment.
Finally,
we need to specify what the handler function is
going to be for this Lambda code.
Next, we need to specify our API gateway,
or we need to provision our API gateway.
So we're going to create an API gateway.
So here, you can see that I am creating an apigw,
a LambdaRestApi, then I am passing in the stack,
as well as part of the constructor.
I'm just naming this a generic name, Endpoint,
and then I need to specify a handler.
The handler here is going to be hello_function.
This links our lambda.Function to this apigw, and that's actually all you need to do to create your Lambda function.