Now,
what is the next step in provisioning your infrastructure efficiently in
the cloud? This is where Cloud Development Kit comes in.
First off, it supports multiple programming languages,
so this syntax should be familiar to the developers among you.
You don't need to learn a new language to use the Cloud Development Kit.
Secondly, it provides you with high‑level and easy to use constructs,
which you can use to define your infrastructure from
within your favorite programming language.
And lastly, if you cannot use these high‑level constructs,
you can actually fall back on low‑level CloudFormation
constructs. So anything CloudFormation can do, Cloud
Development Kit can do in your favorite language.
Now what is in a CDK app? A CDK app consists of constructs,
which are grouped together in stacks.
This may look familiar to you, for the people who use CloudFormation,
as stacks are also what CloudFormation provisions when it creates your
resources. There is actually a one to one mapping between a CDK stack
and a CloudFormation stack.
These constructs actually represent one or a collection of AWS resources,
so you could have multiple AWS resources defined in a single construct.
This is how AWS can abstract more complex designs from the developer.
Now, how is your application provisioned?
Well, let's take this from the analogy of a program being compiled and run.
You're CDK application is your source code.
It's written in your favorite programming language.
Afterwards,
the CDK CLI will execute your application by generating a
CloudFormation template much like how a compiler compiles your
code and generates assembly language.
CDK also deploys this CloudFormation template to AWS
CloudFormation much like how a processor runs your code. So it very similarly follows the code compilation and running process.