Now let's start by duplicating the lambda_stack file so that
we have a starting point for our ECS stack.
We'll rename this file ecs_stack, and then similar to what we did before,
we're going to erase the contents of the LambdaStack.
And we're also going to erase the import that we made for the LambdaStack.
Now instead of these LambdaStack imports,
we're going to be importing ECS libraries.
So we're importing ecs, we're importing ecr_assets,
and we're going to be importing ecs_patterns.
Now we're going to add these dependencies to our setup.py file.
So I'm going to be specifying that the install comes from the CDK
set of libraries, and I'll copy‑paste all of the libraries that
we're importing from our ecs_stack.py file.
I'll again specify version 1.58.
Now I am not deleting our previous imports.
This is because perhaps I also don't want to get rid of
the lambda functions we actually wrote.
So if I don't want to get rid of those lambda functions,
and I just want to create a new stack,
then I can keep these dependencies here and just add new
libraries as we create more stacks.
Now let's actually begin writing the function.
First off, I am going to be creating an ECS cluster.
So we're just going to look at the ECS library,
pass in the stack, as well as the name of this resource.
In this case, I'm just naming it Globomantics‑Cluster.
That's all we actually need to do to create an ECS cluster.
The next thing we'll need to do is we'll need to create our image_asset.
So this is an example of a local asset on ECS.
We're going to use ecs_assets,
and we're going to specify that we're going to import a DockerImageAsset.
So the DockerImageAsset takes in as an argument the location of your file,
as well as the label for your asset.
So in this case, I'm just labeling it Globomantics‑Landing‑Page,
and I am specifying the location to be the contents of the
globomantics‑container‑app directory.
So I just pass in the directory argument, and I put the
location of the globomantics‑container‑app.
Now the next thing we actually need to do is we need to specify that
we want this image_asset in an ECR repository.
So I'm going to create an ECR resource named image, and I'm going to
specify that this is going to be an ecs.ContainerImage, and I'm
going to specify that I'm going to be getting this from a
docker_image_asset or from a local asset.
So I'm going to pass in the image_asset that we
just created a few lines earlier.
Afterwards,
let's create the actual cluster that our containers
will actually be provisioned in.
So let's create an ECS cluster.
From the ecs_patterns library,
we're going to load in the ApplicationLoadBalancedFargateService, and
we're going to pass in a lot of different arguments.
First, of course, the stack and the label as usual,
and we'll need to also pass in the cluster.
In this case,
we're going to specify that the cluster we're using is
the cluster we declared earlier.
Secondly, we need to specify the CPU we're going to use.
Now since we're using Fargate, there are predefined CPU and memory ratios.
So if we have a 256 CPU unit allocation,
we need to have a memory limit allocation of 512.
These are, again, fixed configurations of Fargate, which we cannot change.
Afterwards,
we need to specify the desired count or the number of
tasks we need to run for this app.
Now we also need to specify the listener_port.
We're going to specify port 80, the normal web listener port,
and we're going to now specify the task_image_options,
or what image we want provisioned here.
Let me just clean up my code a little bit.
And now let's specify our image.
So I'm going to look at the ecs_patterns library, and I'm going to
get an ApplicationLoadBalancedTaskImageOptions.
So in this TaskImageOptions,
I'm going to specify the image I want provisioned for the containers to use.
Now here, I'll specify the image.
Again, as the image we declared earlier.
So these two are the same image.
And then, I need to specify the container_name,
the name of the container that's going to be run.
So this container_name is going to be Globomantics‑Landing‑Page.
This is because this container_name matches the container_name we
actually declared in a previous line of code.
Let me just lower it a bit,
and now you can see that these two container_names need to match.
Finally, we need to specify the container_port.
In this case, the container is running an app on port 80,
as specified in the Docker file we viewed earlier.
Finally,
we're going to just specify that the load balancer used
is going to be a public_load_balancer.
So the load balancer in front of these containers will be a
public_load_balancer so our users can access the application.
And now we have all of the resources we need.
Let me just rename the class to EcsStack, again, for organizational purposes.
Now back in the app.py file,
we're going to need to specify that we also want to declare an ECS stack.
So I'm going to import the EcsStack similar to how I imported the LambdaStack.
I'll just change the file name that we're importing and change
the class that we're importing to EcsStack.
Afterwards, again, similar to the LambdaStack,
I need to declare that we're going to launch an EcsStack.
So I'll just copy this LambdaStack declaration,
and I'm going to specify that instead of a LambdaStack,
we're going to provision an EcsStack.
And of course, we're going to change the label.
So now we have declared the EcsStack that our app is going to provision,
or that our app can provision.
If we run cdk ls, you can actually see now we have two stacks that we can launch, an EcsStack and a LambdaStack.