Now, before we start using the CDK on Cloud9,
we have to make sure that we assign the appropriate
role to the Cloud9 environment.
Now to do this, go to Services, and then look for IAM.
From IAM, we can actually create the role needed for Cloud9.
Once you're on the IAM dashboard, go to Roles.
In my case, I already have several roles here.
However, I will create a new role for this Cloud9 environment.
For the new role, I'll select EC2.
This is because Cloud9 actually runs on an EC2 instance.
Afterwards, click Next.
Now I know that this is normally bad practice in production; however,
for the purposes of this course,
we're going to assign this role administrator access policies.
This is to ensure that Cloud9 has all of the permissions it
needs to provision infrastructure with the CDK.
Afterwards, click Next.
You can add tags if you want.
I'm leaving this blank.
Afterwards, just click Review, and make sure you give your role a name.
In my case, I'm naming my role CDKRole.
Create your role, and now your role should be ready to attach to an EC2 instance.
Now go to Services and look for EC2.
This should take you to your EC2 instance dashboard.
Go to Running instances,
and you should see all of the instances you have available in your account.
In my case, I have several Cloud9 environments running,
as well as several other EC2 instances.
Make sure that in case you have other environments,
you select the one that you created for the CDK.
In my case, it is the CDK Cloud9 environment.
Afterwards,
just click Actions, Instant Settings, Attach or Replace IAM Role,
and then select the role that you just created.
Afterwards, just apply these changes,
and now your role has been attached to the EC2 instance,
and your Cloud9 environment should have no issues creating infrastructure with the CDK.