Now let's look specifically at how the CDK works in Python.
First of all, the CDK has stable Python 3 support,
and secondly,
it is fully integrated with the pip package manager and
with Python virtual environments.
Later on,
you'll see that we'll have to install a package for every set of
resources that we need to provision using the CDK.
This makes the integration with pip and virtual
environment very valuable for the CDK.
Python also has dynamically typed variables. While
dynamically typed variables make it much easier for you to
write your code, at the same time,
it may also make it more difficult for you to perform type checking.
You have to find some way to integrate the type
checking into the build or test process.
So as your Python code is being interpreted,
you need to find a way to make sure you catch any type errors.
Now,
how does the CDK actually do this multi‑language support? CDK is actually
written in TypeScript. So how can TypeScript translate to Python code?
Now, CDK does this using an interface called JSii, or the JavaScript
interoperability interface. This JSii + TypeScript compiler is what allows
your different other programming languages to interface with the original
TypeScript code.
AWS didn't brute‑force the creation of the
libraries in these different languages.
These different languages actually connect to the original TypeScript code using the JSii.