Now let's actually deploy this ECS stack,
and the first thing that this is going to do is ask for confirmation,
as usual.
Let's just say yes. Next, what's going to happen is, as you can see,
it's building the Docker image.
We didn't run docker build at all, we didn't trigger any build manually,
all we did was trigger the deployment of the stack and CDK is
automatically handling building the Docker image for you.
So it's updating the image, it's copying the files
into the Docker image, and so on.
This is how local assets work.
The CDK will take care of running and building the local asset for you.
Now, it's actually pushing the local asset into ECR, so we
didn't even need to push it ourselves.
CDK actually pushed the local asset to ECR. Now if we look at our ECR service,
you can see we now have a cdk/assets ECR repository.
This is actually where you'll find the container images
that were built and pushed by the CDK.
Next,
if we actually go take a look at the CloudFormation template that was
deployed, you can see that it's provisioned several resources. It's
provisioned a VPC, it's provisioned a load balancer.
Now,
I didn't declare a VPC, I didn't specify network configuration in my CDK file.
This is what I mean by abstractions via the constructs.
So the constructs have abstracted all of these resources from you.
The constructs actually created the VPC, created the
Internet gateway and all of the networking components that
are being used by your ECS cluster.
You didn't need to specify anything about the networking
environment, that was all automatically provisioned.
If I go to Outputs,
you can see the URL to the Globomantics app, and if I click it,
it brings you to the Globomantics web page.
You can see the Globomantics app here, we have again all of our content, I
can browse through the different contents of this app.
This is, again, a fully working Globomantics app that was deployed by the
CDK. Now to end we can actually call cdk destroy again to remove all of the
infrastructure that was created by the CDK app.
So let me run cdk destroy, and it's going to delete all of these resources.
So now you can see that the destruction has completed, it's torn down
all of the resources. If I go to CloudFormation,
the resources that we provisioned are no longer there.
However,
if we go to ECR assets, the local assets that the CDK actually
provisioned have not been deleted, so that's one thing you may
need to do if you're cleaning up.
If you are getting rid of the infrastructure completely,
take note that these local assets which were uploaded to
the cloud are not automatically deleted. You need to delete them yourself.