In the client credentials grant, effectively no user is involved.
The resource owner is the requester,
most likely a non-human entity like another service.
This is a great flow for when you have a batch job that needs to start up
and make some requests to some services for reporting,
etc., or in the case of our demo, the pricing service,
which doesn't have any user resources on it.
It's just the price of the crypto.
So passing the access token is a bad idea for reasons
described in the previous section.
Also,
the portfolio service might want to cache the prices and might not make
the call to the pricing service for every request.
It might use a thread that makes the request every 30 seconds,
even though there is no active request taking place.
With the client credentials grant,
the client_id and secret is passed directly to the token
endpoint in exchange for an access token only.
No refresh token as the service can just rerequest a new
token if the existing one expires.
Now let's compare the pros and cons of the token relay versus
client credentials and which part of the application they are suited for and also some alternatives.