Previously, we had an opaque token, now a JSON Web Token.
You're probably thinking the first one is better.
It's smaller.
Hold that thought.
As you can see in its small format,
it's simply a string as the JSON is Base64 URL-encoded.
This is so you can transmit it easier in the header and even in the URL.
Although if the payload is large,
it can exceed the maximum length of a URL or header.
The message is split into three parts separated by a period.
If we decode it, we can see the two JSON maps and the signature.
The first part is the header,
which specifies the algorithm used to sign it with JSON Web Algorithms.
JWA essentially is a registry of standard names and algorithms.
So anyone reading this will know which algorithm the token is
signed with and be able to easily verify it.
Next is the payload.
The JWT specification doesn't mandate what you need to put in here.
It's solely based on your requirements.
Finally, the JSON Web Signature, which uses the algorithm defined in the header.
It's basically the signature of the header and payload.
As mentioned,
the JSON Web Token doesn't mandate what fields you
can and cannot put in the payload.
However, it does have standard optional fields, which you should definitely use.
Now the best way to think of a JWT is a signed cookie.
So with a JWT, a mobile user can authenticate with an identity provider.
The identity provider will gather the user information
and permissions into a JSON map, sign it,
create a JWT, and send it to the client.
So now rather than the state being in the server, it's client-side.
The client then includes it in every request it makes.
That's powerful.
Firstly,
if you have tens of thousands of users signed in on a mobile
app making hundreds of calls per minute,
having your server stateless and not maintaining and
looking up state scales really well.
As you can see,
JWT in itself is a collection of standards from Java Web Algorithms,
Java Web Signatures,
and even Java Web Encryption where you can encrypt the content.
Basically, it's a standard token format.
Hence, we need other standards, like OAuth2,
to define how to use the tokens for delegated access or which
identity fields are required for federated access,
such as OpenID Connect. In the next section, we'll describe how OAuth2 and OpenID Connect achieve this.