Victoria wanted to encrypt her holdings with our demo app, Crypto Portfolio.
Facebook and Crypto Portfolio have a trust relationship, i.e.
Crypto Portfolio is a registered client with Facebook and
has a unique client ID and client key.
Hence,
Victoria can authorize Crypto Portfolio to perform actions
on her Facebook account on her behalf, such as access her profile data,
post to her wall, or access her friends list.
Crypto Portfolio will display the option you have probably seen before,
like log in with Facebook.
If Victoria clicks on it,
Crypto Portfolio will send a redirect request to Facebook's
authorization server via her browser.
This begins the OAuth process with Facebook.
First, Facebook will need to authenticate Victoria.
If she is not already logged in with Facebook, she will need to do so.
Once authenticated, Facebook's authorization server,
using the client_id and scope, sees that the client,
Crypto Portfolio, wants to access her profile and email.
At this point, it will ask Victoria for her consent.
You have probably seen these before clearly stating that Crypto
Portfolio wants access to her profile and email.
In this case,
Facebook even gives the option for her to edit and remove certain scopes.
If Victoria agrees,
Facebook will then send a redirect response to the client
via her browser with the URI specified by Crypto Portfolio
and an authorization code.
The authorization code can now be used by the client
to exchange for the access token.
The authorization code is a random number and
effectively is a sender constraint token,
meaning only the client can use it to get the access token as the
resource server will also expect the client_id and secret be included
with the request to retrieve the access token.
Access tokens also have a very short expiry time.
The reason for using an authorization code and not passing the
access token directly is that transmission via the front channel
between the authorization server, browser,
and client cannot be completely relied upon as secure,
especially the browser.
It could have some malicious plugin.
So sending the bearer access token would be risky.
An authorization code, on the other hand,
is useless without the client's secret,
and that exchange happens via the back channel where the client
goes directly to the authorization server.
There is one other token that can be returned along with the access token,
and that is the refresh token.
Because access tokens are bearer tokens,
they should have a very short expiry time.
This is to limit the damage of an access token being leaked.
However,
often clients need the access token for longer and don't want to keep
bothering the user to reconsent each time the token expires.
This is where the refresh token comes in.
It can be used by the client to get a new access token.
Refresh tokens need to be stored securely on the client.
If they are leaked,
they can be used by a malicious party to keep re-requesting access tokens.
Hence, ideally they should also have an expiry date and be single use,
meaning each time a new access token is retrieved,
a new refresh token is also issued.
There are other grant types like client credentials for machine-to-machine
authorization where the client is also a resource owner,
is not a user,
but an application or a service or implicit where you have
a public client like a single-page application that cannot
store the secret securely.
We will also go over these in more detail in later modules.
Now there is a lot of confusion around what OAuth actually is.
The name adds to this ambiguity.
Does it mean authentication or authorization?
It's actually neither. We will discuss why in the next section.