One of the key new features of OpenID Connect is the identity token.
It's a JWT that thinks claims about how the authentication
occurred for the end user by the authorization server and allows
your client to validate that authentication.
Now to do this,
it has a number of mandatory claims about the authentication process,
such as the subject, which asserts the identity of the user.
Now it must be unique and never reassignable.
This allows a client to confidently use that field as
a unique identifier for the user.
The issuer field, this describes who's the issuing authority,
and it allows the client to verify the user was
authenticated by the expected source.
Audience, this is a very important field.
It basically identifies the client that was authenticated.
Now it must be a client ID.
The reason for this field is that your typical OpenID Connect provider,
like Google, will support thousands of clients.
Hence,
your client can use this claim to ensure that the user
was authenticated for your application.
The expiration time,
now one great feature about including this is that they also specify the
format of the expiry time that the provider must use,
which is great as before you had to deal with all the
various different formats for each provider.
Now there were also some useful optional claims as well.
However,
you generally find that most authentication providers will include these.
Some key ones is the issued at, when was this token issued,
and the auth time, when was it authorized.
These are great for customizing your validation of a token.
So for example,
you might decide that even though the token is not yet
expired according to the expiration claim,
your application will only accept tokens that have been
issued within the last 2 minutes.
So it allows you to have your own expiration policy rather
than relying on the authorization server's.
Now OpenID Connect also introduced some standard scopes,
and some key ones are the OpenID,
which is mandatory and must be included as the first scope and
indicates that this application intends to use OpenID Connect
to verify the user's identity.
Some of the other keys ones is a profile indicates that
the user's profile claim is required, email address,
and, of course, offline access, which is for the refresh token.
Now you could also include custom scopes.
Now there are many more other scopes.
But the key feature is that for each scope,
there are default standard claims associated with them.
So if you user consents to a scope,
the authorization server will return all or a subset of the standard claims.
Now this is a great feature.
You will see the benefit of it in the next module.
Basically,
if your application is looking for their user's email claim or
the address and you're using OpenID Connect,
then you know that that claim will be named address and email,
not ADR or ADDR or EML or some other format the provider might use.
Now additionally to the scopes, there are standard endpoints.
So once you know the provider's location,
the endpoint URLs will be the same for every OpenID Connect provider.
Now some of the key endpoints are the UserInfo endpoint
where the client can request previously consented user
claims using the access token.
You're probably thinking if we have an ID token,
why do we still need the access token?
Well the ID token might not have all the claims about the resource
owner that were requested as it might be a thin token,
meaning it has a subset of only the essential claims
you might require for authentication.
The ID token only mandates claims about how the authentication occurred
and what format the user's claim should be in if the authorization
server decides to add them to the ID token.
Now this is generally to keep the size of the ID token small
so it's compatible with mobile clients.
However,
if you need all the user's claims like say it's the first time the user is
accessing your application and you need to register them,
then you can go to the UserInfo endpoint and get all the claims.
However,
that's an implementation decision with the provider
whether they provide a fat or thin token.
The main point is the access token combined with the refresh token
allows for rerequesting approved user claims without having to
bother the user to reconsent each time.
The WebFinder endpoint,
this provides a way to dynamically discover the OpenID
Connect provider for a given user.
Provider metadata, this is a very useful endpoint.
It returns a discovery document with all the OpenID Connect
details of the provider and what it supports,
such as support response, grant type, URL of the JW keyset,
the asserted issuer, supported scopes, token endpoints,
basically everything a client might need to dynamically configure
itself with the provider and validate tokens.
There's also a session management endpoint, which is quite useful.
This checks if the user still has an active session with the
authentication server as the client might also want to log the user out
from their end if they log out from the provider.
There are many others.
I encourage you to check the spec.
But the great thing is if you're dealing with an OpenID Connect provider,
the endpoints follow a standard.
So that makes them super easy to find. Next, let's look at the differences between OAuth2 and the OpenID Connect flow.