In addition to being a resource service,
the portfolio service will now also be a client as it will
source a new token using the client credentials grant to
access the pricing service.
Hence, in the POM file of the portfolio service,
we add the OAuth2ClientStarter dependency.
Then in the configuration file, we add our client details.
Add portfolio-service as the registration ID,
client-id and secret,
which we can get from the Credentials tab from the
Keycloak admin console for that client.
The grant type will be client_credentials.
And for the provider,
we will provide the token URI and add the provider to our client.
When we configure our web client,
we use the ServletOAuth2AuthorizedClientExchangeFilter Function again,
passing in the ClientRegistrationRepository and the
OAuth2AuthorizedClientRepository and adding it to the WebClient builder
before building an instance of the WebClient that is exposed as a bean.
Additionally,
because this is the only client registered with the portfolio service,
we can set it as the default by adding the registration ID.
Basically, any time this web client is now used,
the ExchangeFilterFunction will look up the
OAuth2AuthorizedClientRepository for an authorized client with that ID.
If one doesn't exist,
it will look up the ClientRegistrationRepository to retrieve
that client's information that we added via the properties
file and contact the provider, which in this case is Keycloak,
to retrieve an access token using the client credentials grant flow.
Once the token is retrieved,
it will be added to the authorized client repository for future access,
and the token will be added to all outgoing requests via the WebClient.
We can now use the WebClient to make the request to the pricing service.
It just looks like any ordinary request with no requirement
to add to header or attribute property.
The ExchangeFilterFunction will now take care of the
OAuth authorization side of things.
One thing to note is that as of the current version of
Spring Security 5.1 .6 that I'm using,
once the OAuth2ExchangeFilterFunction authorizes the client,
it will not refresh the token if it expires.
The client credentials grant doesn't support the refresh
token as that would not make sense.
However, ideally,
the ExchangeFilterFunction should check the expiry of the token before using it.
And if it's expired,
it should simply rerequest a new token using the client credentials grants.
However, in Spring Security 5.1 versions, that doesn't happen.
So when the token expires, it will keep using it in the requests,
and you will eventually experience 401 exceptions as the
pricing service will just reject the token.
The Spring team have said that they will fix this in 5.2.
So, if you're in the future and you're using 5.2 and higher,
the ExchangeFilterFunction will check the expiry and get a new one for you.
If you're using 5.1 like me,
then you can either request Keycloak to have a longer expiry time.
You can do that in the advanced settings.
But that breaks the OAuth2 best practices.
Tokens should have a short expiry time in case they
are leaked to minimize any damage. Next, we will look at a workaround for this.