For non-OpenID Connect providers,
the OAuth2User object is created by the OAuth2UserService and then
packaged up as the principal in the authentication object.
By default, Spring uses the default OAuth2UserService,
which creates a default OAuth2User.
Hence, we need an OAuth2UserService that can return a custom OAuth2 user,
and it just so happens that Spring has an implementation we can use,
the CustomUserTypesOAuth2UserService.
Now let's first create our custom user type for Facebook,
which is the only non-OpenID Connect provider at the moment.
We override the getName authorities and attributes method.
Next, we add the claims we want to extract.
We saw previously Facebook provided the id, name, and email claims.
So we can add these as fields.
We add the accesses for these fields.
The setters need to match the exact name of the claim.
The CustomUserTypeService will then resolve them from what is
returned by Facebook's userinfo endpoint response.
For authorities, we will default to user for now,
but you could add additional ones here based off the claims.
We can now customize our attributes.
Let's return the attributes Facebook provides.
And in addition,
let's also return the given name and family name in
the same format as OpenID Connect.
Okay, now in our configuration adapter, using the OAuth login builder,
under the UserInfoEndpoint,
we add our new class under customUserType for Facebook
using its provider registration ID.
That's it.
Spring will now plug in the customUserTypes service into
the OAuth2LoginAuthenticationProvider,
and this provider will now return our custom OAuth2
user implementation for Facebook.
Back at our OAuth2AuthenticationSuccess handler,
after refactoring, we no longer have separate code to handle Facebook.
We can also refactor our controller.
This is cleaner, but we can do better.
Let's create our own CryptoAuthenticatedPrincipal
interface and the fields we care about, so FirstName,
LastName, and FirstAndLastName combined.
If we force our Facebook Connect user to implement
it and also our MFAUser class,
we now no longer have to cast between the two types in our AccountController.
Now there is no custom user implementation for OpenID Connect
as OpenID Connect is already a standard.
So, to also force the OpenID Connect user object to implement our new interface,
we have to create a custom OpenID Connect user service. So, let's do that next.