If you recall back to the OAuth2 authorization code grant flow,
the client sends the function or authorization request to the
authorization server via our redirect from the user's browser.
Our authorization server needs to authenticate the user and then
ask them if they consent to this client request.
Now to authenticate the user,
it can ask them to provide a username and a password.
So let's set this up.
You can create a configuration class that extends
the WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter.
By now you're probably already very familiar with this class.
Now when an instance of a configuration adapter is added to the Spring context,
you're essentially creating a filter chain.
Override the configure method that gives you access to the HttpSecurity builder.
Because you can have multiple filter chains configured in Spring,
in fact, by adding the AuthorizationServerConfigurerAdapter in the previous clip,
that created a filter chain.
So now by adding the WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter,
we will have two filter chains.
We'll see these later.
Now by using the requestMatcher,
we can configure this filter chain to handle requests to the
login page and to the oauth/authorize URI.
Next, we need to configure how we want to authorize these requests.
Now in this case,
any request to this URI requires the user to be authenticated via form login.
So what this means now is this filter chain will intercept
authorization URI requests from the user's browser.
It will then require the user to be authenticated.
If they are not, it will prompt them to authenticate via form login.
If the user is authenticated,
the request will be allowed to proceed to the authorization endpoint.
In order to authenticate the user,
the authorization server needs to know about them,
like the username, their password hash.
And authentication in Spring, if you recall,
is done by the AuthenticationManager.
Hence,
we can override the configure method that gives us access
to an AuthenticationManager builder, which,
as the name suggests, allows you to build an AuthenticationManager.
The builder allows you to either create a JDBC version where it can
retrieve the user's credentials from the database.
However for now,
we will create an in- memory authentication version
and add a user Joe with a password.
We'll give them one role, user.
Now passwords in Spring Security need to be encoded.
So let's return an instance of a BCrypt PasswordEncoder
and use it to encode our password.
Let's expose it as a bean as we also want to use this encoder
in our authorization server configuration.
This configures the AuthenticationManager in the adapter.
We now need to expose it as a bean.
We can do that by overriding the AuthenticationManagerBean method,
which will return the configured version of the manager,
which will then be used in the application throughout.
Now once the user is authenticated and they consent,
the request will hit the authorization endpoint,
which will return an authorization code to the client.
The client will then exchange it for an access token via the token endpoint.
Then the client will want to use the access token against a userinfo
endpoint to get the user-approved claims back.
Now we need to create a rest endpoint for this.
Create a rest controller, annotate the class with the RestController annotation,
and let's create a UserInfo method and expose it via a Get method.
For now we will just return a user object with the name,
first and last name, and email all hardcoded.
Now in your implementation, you can customize this any way you want.
You can interrogate the authentication object to retrieve any approved scopes
and selectively populate the response back to the client.
Access to the userinfo endpoint requires a valid access token.
So the authorization server also needs to play the role of a resource server.
To do this, we add the resource server annotation.
This will add a third filter chain that will look out for the access token in
the header before allowing access to the userinfo endpoint.
We will go over resource servers in more detail in later modules.
Now because we're going to have free filter chains,
we need to make sure that they're in the correct order.
Now if we drill into the EnableAuthorizationServer annotation,
you can see it has an order of 0.
If we do the same for the resource server, it has an order of 3.
And in the UserConfigurationAdapter, that has an order of 100,
which would mean that the filter chain created by the
AuthorizationServerConfiguration would be evaluated first,
followed by the resource server and then the user configuration.
Now in the OAuth flow,
you wouldn't have an access token until the user is
authenticated and they consent.
So we need to allow requests to the authorize endpoint through.
Now to address this,
we could create a third configuration class that extends the
ResourceServerConfigurerAdapter and configure the request matcher to
either ignore requests to the authorize endpoint.
However, changing the order is simpler.
In the UserConfiguration class, set the order to 1 using the annotation.
So it's before the resource server, which has an order of 3.
This way the resource server filter chain is only evaluated if the OAuth2
flow was successful and the client has an access token.
Now back to our application.yml config file,
let's set the port number to 8081 so that it doesn't clash with our web app.
Also, we need to provide a context-path.
This is because we are running the demo on a localhost domain.
Now a browser doesn't consider the port as part of a domain.
So if you started the client web app and the authorization server together,
the browser would store their cookies under the same domain,
localhost, and that would cause a clash.
The context root will ensure that the client web app
cookies will be stored under localhost and the
authorization server under localhost/auth. Next, let's configure our crypto web app to use this authorization server.