The key takeaways from this module is that for authorization,
it is not adequate to solely rely on the validity of the access token
and whether it is expired or from the correct issuer.
Distributed applications are as strong as their weakest link.
Any service could become a backdoor into the application, so be vigilant.
Now in addition to the authorization endpoint,
there is also a token endpoint where you can add a custom access
token response client to customize the outbound request to retrieve
the access token from the token endpoint.
Use the audience attribute to ensure the token is used in the proper context.
Although the RFC doesn't provide much restrictions on what
the audience field should be used for,
it's important not to get too granular with your audience validation.
It should be for who can receive and process the token,
not what resource or actions the bearer of the token can
perform on behalf of the resource owner.
That's what scopes are for.
As you have seen, you need to rely on multiple layers of defense.
In the next module,
we will look at more finer-grained authorization using scopes, roles, and authorities.