You can download Keycloak from their web page.
As of the creation of the course, I am using the latest version,
which is 6.0 .1.
Unzip it into a directory of your choosing.
Then in the bin file,
simply execute the standalone command with the jboss.http .port to 8081.
Now the reason for the port is that, by default,
it uses port 8080, and that would actually clash with our web app.
If we access localhost on 8081,
it will ask us to create the initial admin account.
So fill that in.
I'm just using admin and password for now.
Now once logged in as admin, the first thing you need is a realm.
This is like a container around users, applications, clients, etc.
It's a core concept within Keycloak.
Once your realm is created, you can start to see the power of Keycloak.
With a few clicks, we can enable user registration,
password recovery, remember me, email verification,
SSL, select themes for our login page,
configure security headers and content policies,
enable user federation, like social sign-in with Google and Facebook,
and much more.
We need to register our application as a client.
Under Clients, select Create.
Give it a name.
The protocol will be openid-connect.
We can add a name and description.
Make sure enabled is on.
Consent required,
this is if we want to prompt the resource owner to approve the scopes.
Leave it as off for now unless you really want it.
For the access type, select confidential,
meaning a client secret is required and direct access grant to off as having
it on would effectively enable the password grant flow.
Service account enabled off.
This is for the client credentials grant for machine-to-machine authentication.
We don't need this at the moment.
Below are some more advanced settings.
a useful one is access token lifespan where you can set
how long the access token is active for.
Next, we preregister our redirect URI.
This is the same one we provided in the Spring config.
This needs to match as Keycloak will not redirect to any other URL.
You could also add additional ones.
Save this for now.
In the Credentials tab, we now have the client ID and secret,
which we will need to provide Spring later.
Now that's it for the client.
Let's create a test user.
Select Users, Add user, fill this in and enable them.
Add a password for them in credentials.
As you can see,
there is a lot of customization Keycloak allows you to do right out of the box.
We are just scratching the surface.
Now that's the hard part done. Next, let's set up this client in our Spring web app.