You now have the practical knowledge of how to apply OAuth2 and
OpenID Connect to a basic monolithic MVC web application or a
public single-page application,
which communicates with a number of RESTful services.
However, there are still some missing pieces to this puzzle.
In the real world,
you're more likely going to come across more complex security
requirements where your MVC or SPA client communicates with
multiple services where requests require multiple hops between
these services to resolve.
Or what if your resource server is not a human?
How can you use OAuth2 for secure, machine-to-machine interactions?
In the next module,
we'll look at various security patterns you can add to your knowledge toolbox to deal with such scenarios when they come your way.