We're now familiar with how to enable, disable,
and expose or not expose actuator endpoints.
Let's take a moment to compare the two as it's
often a common point of confusion.
I believe I've made it pretty clear by now,
but let me reiterate,
enabling an actuator endpoint is not the same as exposing an actuator endpoint,
they're two different things.
Enabling an endpoint is mainly about creation.
It controls whether or not that endpoint is actually created
as a bean in Spring Boot and exposing it,
on the other hand, controls whether or not you can consume the endpoint,
whereas almost all endpoints are enabled by default,
almost all endpoints are not exposed by default,
at least for HTTP.
Enabling or disabling an endpoint is more of an efficiency thing than anything.
Disabling an endpoint results in the application using slightly less memory,
whereas exposing or not exposing an endpoint is actually related to security.
As I mentioned previously in prior versions of Spring Boot prior to 2.0,
enabling an endpoint was the same as exposing it.
This was a cause for security concern since the endpoints contained
sensitive information and sensitive operations.
In one case,
security researchers found that one of the endpoints
could be used for remote code execution,
which in terms of bad is really, really bad.
It's pretty much the worst-case scenario for a security vulnerability.
Luckily, this security vulnerability was closed rather quickly, and in Spring Boot Actuator 2.0, they've improved the security greatly.