It's really, really easy to get started using Spring Boot Actuator.
Literally, all you need to do is add it to your project as a dependency,
and just by doing that without any configuration on your part,
you'll get a lot of the built-in features.
You can, of course,
take it further and provide additional configuration and
customizations which we'll explore throughout the course,
but seriously, if you learn anything from this course,
just adding Spring Boot Actuator as a dependency to your
project provides you with a ton of benefits.
We'll briefly cover the three most common methods for adding
Spring Boot Actuator to your project using Maven,
using Gradle, and using Spring Initializer,
or start.spring .io.
If you're using Maven,
all you need to do is add a dependency on Spring Boot Starter
Actuator in your pom.xml in the Dependency section.
If you're using Gradle,
you add a compile dependency on Spring Boot Starter
Actuator in the dependencies block.
Alternatively, if you're starting a new project,
Spring Initializr makes it really easy to add Spring Boot Actuator to a project.
Open up a browser and visit start.spring .io.
Then you simply scroll down to the Dependency section and start typing actuator.
It should pop-up on a list of dependencies,
you can choose it by clicking it or hit Enter, and it's now part of your project.