Since we recently discussed the importance of ensuring that
exposed endpoints are properly secure,
let's talk about how you actually secure them.
Spring Boot has made it extremely easy to add security to endpoints.
In fact, if Spring Boot detects that you have Spring Security on the classpath,
it will automatically secure exposed endpoints with HTTP basic authentication.
There are two exceptions to this, the health endpoint and the info endpoint.
With the default configuration,
the health endpoint only returns whether the app is healthy or
unhealthy if it's requested without authentication.
It can, however,
be further configured to show additional details if credentials are provided
and the info endpoint is not meant to contain sensitive data.
There is, however,
nothing that enforces this so please be aware that it's not secured by
default and should not contain any sensitive information.
We'll cover the info endpoint in a bit more detail in the following sections.
So in short,
adding security to your endpoints is as simple as
adding a dependency to your project.
Let's quickly cover how to do that with Maven and Gradle.
With Maven,
you add a dependency on Spring Boot Starter Security to
the Dependency section of your pom.xml.
With Gradle, the process is similar.
You add a new dependency on spring-boot-starter-security to
your build.gradle in the dependencies block.
Without any additional configuration,
Spring Boot will automatically create a random password if
spring security is on the classpath.
This random password is printed to the console on
startup and the default username is user.
Spring security can also be configured with the specific username and password.
Simply set this spring.security .user .name and .password properties in
the application.properties or the application.yml.
Since endpoint security is controlled by this spring security framework,
it should come as no surprise that it's entirely customizable.
To customize this security,
create a new class annotated with the @Configuration annotation
that extends WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter.
The web security configurer adapter has one method to implement
called configure and it passes in an HTTP security object that can
be used to implement your customizations.
In this example,
we customize the endpoint to also require
authorization in addition to authentication.
In order to access this endpoint, the requestor must have authenticated,
as well as have the role of admin.
At this point, we've talked about enabling,
disabling, exposing, and securing endpoints.
Now let's talk about customizing endpoints.
A subset of the overall endpoints come with inherent support for customizations,
particularly the health endpoint, the info endpoint,
and the metrics endpoint.
We'll take a look at each of these in a bit more detail in the following sections.