In this demo, we're going to very, very quickly go over the demo code.
The intent is really just to introduce you to the demo
code and to get you familiar with it.
Feel free to pause or rewind at any time if you'd like to
inspect the code in a bit more detail.
As we saw previously, the demo code is a simple API for storing to-do lists.
It follows a fairly standard pattern of exposing an endpoint via a REST
controller and ultimately fetching data from an in-memory database.
The path to the endpoint is /todo/lists and the controller
delegates most of its work to the service layer,
which in turn delegates most of its work to the repository layer.
The repository layer is implemented with Spring Data JPA and the
actual data is stored in an H2 in-memory database.
The schema is autogenerated from the JPA objects and there
is a data.sql file in the source main resources that
contains the initial to-do list data.
That's really all there is to it.
Now that we're familiar with the demo, let's get back to learning about actuator endpoints.