First, let's take a look at the health endpoint.
The health endpoint allows for adding additional custom health
checks to the already built-in health checks,
and the great thing is is that it's really easy to do so.
Simply create and register a new bean that implements the
HealthIndicator interface and implement its one method,
the health method, with any custom logic.
The health method returns a health object which is used
to indicate the appropriate status, such as up or down.
Let's take a look at some example code.
We first create a new class annotated with the @Component
annotation so our class is registered as a bean and we
implement the HealthIndicator interface.
Again, the HealthIndicator interface requires you to implement one method,
the health method, and in this method, you would perform the custom health check.
For instance, maybe you have a legacy system that your application depends on.
You could write code to perform a check on the legacy system,
inspect its status, and then hopefully return a healthy status.
Alternatively,
if after inspecting the status you determine that the system wasn't healthy,
you could return a new health object using the down method to
indicate that it's in an unhealthy state.
The health object also provides the ability to add additional details.
This could be useful for returning details about a healthy response,
but it's particularly useful for returning additional
details about an unhealthy response.
For instance,
we could add what response code we received or how long the
response took or the number of times that we retried.
This would all be useful information when inspecting why the health check failed.