Alright, enough with the slides.
Let's go ahead and add a custom HealthIndicator to our demo application.
In this demo, we'll write our own custom HealthIndicator.
Remember that our demo application utilizes an in-memory
database to store its to-do lists and items.
If the amount of memory configured for the JVM is not big
enough to store our in-memory database,
we'll definitely have problems with our app.
Ensuring that our application is started with an adequate
amount of memory is critical to its health.
We can capture this by writing our own custom HealthIndicator.
First, create a new package inside the main package called health.
In the new package, we'll create a new class called MaxMemoryHealthIndicator.
Annotate the class with the @Component annotation,
then implement the HealthIndicator interface along with its one method,
health.
In the health method,
we'll retrieve the maximum configured memory by
calling Runtime.getRuntime .maxMemory.
We can then compare this to an arbitrary value.
For demo purposes, we'll use 100 MB.
We set the value of this to a Boolean to indicate whether
or not we have a valid amount of memory.
Then we create a new status object called status and return status.down
if don't have enough memory or status.up if we do.
Lastly,
we used a health class to build and return a new health instance
with our particular status set by calling Health.status and then
passing in the status followed by build.
Before we start our application,
it'll be helpful to configure a property so that we can see the
details in the response of our health endpoint call.
By default, no details are provided.
Navigate to the src, main,
resources folder and open up the application.properties.
In the application.properties, add a new property,
management.endpoint .health .show -details and equals always.
Now typically you wouldn't want to set this to always unless you had an
adequately secure health endpoint via other means.
However, for demo purposes, it's okay for now.
Alright, now we're ready to start that application up and try things out.
Right-click on the main application class and go to Run.
Fire up a browser and visit localhost:8080/actuator/health.
In the response,
you can see that we get a much more detailed response than what we
previously saw where it was just up or down.
We could also see that there is now a check called maxMemory
and it has a status of UP indicating that our application was started with enough memory.