Up until now,
the communication between the user's browser and the web
application in our demo application was over HTTP.
This is fine for development, but in production you need to use HTTPS.
The reason being is in reality,
your browser doesn't communicate directly with the target web server.
On the internet our requests and responses are handled by many different
third parties on the way to their final destination.
Hence anyone snooping network traffic could intercept the
authentication request and steal the user's credential.
Or they could hijack to the user's session and impersonate them,
not to mention exposing the user's sensitive data.
With HTTP,
there is also no way to confirm the destination server is who they claim to be,
exposing your users to man‑in‑the‑middle attacks.
Hence, some sort of encryption is required to provide confidentiality.
There also needs to be a way for the client to confirm the identity
of the web server they're communicating with.
This is where HTTPS comes into play.
HTTPS is HTTP over TLS, Transport Layer Security.
TLS is the protocol used by the client and server to initiate
encrypted communications between themselves, and also a way for the
client to confirm the identity of the server,
which is important when accessing sensitive resources like your online banking.
You want to make sure that you're actually communicating
with the bank's web server and not some malicious party
impersonating them. With TLS,
there is a handshake that takes place before any data is transmitted.
The client and the server agree on the protocols and
algorithms they're going to use, then that follows the
server sending its X 509 certificate.
This certificate is key.
It contains the information about the server.
Here I am on the HSBC Bank website.
If I click on the lock, you can see Chrome confirms the communication is secure,
meaning HTTPS, and that the certificate provided by the
server is valid and belongs to HSBC.
The reason it knows it is valid is that the certificate is issued by DigiCert,
which is a trusted certificate authority that Chrome
trusts. Now on the other hand,
if we access Crypto Portfolio, because we're using HTTP you can
see that Chrome has marked it as unsecure.
Next,
let's look at how we can generate our own certificate and configure HTTPS in our application