If the wrong username or password is entered by the user,
by default,
Spring will redirect them back to the login page with the query parameter error,
hence,
in our login page we could look out for this parameter and
provide the user with a generic error message.
Now best practice is not to be specific as to
whether the username exists or not, or the password was wrong,
just a simple generic message that either could be incorrect,
as this will prevent any malicious party trying to get a list of usernames
in your application through any brute force attacks.
If you wanted to redirect the user to a different page,
you could use the formLogin builder to configure the authorization filter.
Again, if you were using Basic, it would be the Basic login builder method.
Here we can specify what failureUrl we want.
You might also want to perform some tasks when authentication failures occur,
like keep a count of them and log out or _____ accounts to
protect against any brute force attacks,
or perhaps to simply log them or notify the user by email.
You can do this by adding an AuthenticationFailureHandler.
Simply create a class that implements the AuthenticationFailureHandler
interface and override the onAuthenticationFailure method.
Here you have access to the request and response objects and exceptions objects.
Add your logic here,
and add it via the login form builder using the
AuthenticationFailureHandler method.
If the user accessed the login page directly without being
redirected to an authentication entry point,
then you could set the default success URL where the user will be
redirected to after they successfully authenticate.
After authenticating, if dave accessed the admin page,
gets this generic Spring Whitelabel Error Page,
and does not have an admin role, this doesn't look nice.
It also gives the hacker a hint that we are using Spring Security.
So, to create our own error page, all you need to do is under resources,
static, create a folder called error with an HTML page named 401.
That's it.
Now Spring will display this custom error page when a 401 exception occurs.
You can also do this for other error codes, such as the 404 Not Found, etc.
And if you want,
you can configure your own URL using the exception
handler's access denied page builder method.
You might also want to perform some tasks like auditing any unauthorized access,
which you can do by creating your own implementation of an
AccessDeniedHandler and override the handle method.
Here you have access to the request, response object,
as well as the AccessDeniedException where you can
perform some tasks like logging.
Once you add your logic here,
you can then add the handler using the exceptions handler builder method.
You can add your AccessDeniedHandler to the ExceptionTranslationFilter,
and you can even have different handlers for different URLs. As you can see, Spring Security is very flexible.