Since this is a course on securing applications with Spring,
let's fast‑forward the development to our crypto app.
There, much better.
As mentioned before, Spring Security is very customizable.
Here I have a custom login page to match the look and feel of the application.
As you can see, just like the default,
it submits a POST request to the login endpoint and sends the
username and password in the body. Now to configure Spring Security
to use this page instead of the default bland one, on the formLogin
builder method, we can set the loginPage URI. Now as you've
probably already noticed, the builder has a lot more features.
You can even change the login processing URL in case you wanted to submit
it to another endpoint and the field name of the password and username the
filter will expect in the body. If we access the application now, hmm, our
login page is not displaying,
and there are a lot of redirect requests and access denied exceptions.
If we go back to our SecurityConfiguration class,
all the endpoints require the principal to be authenticated.
But if we can't access the login page, there is no way we can authenticate.
Hence,
we can use the mvcMatcher and configure the login
endpoint to permit all requests,
while everything else will require authentication.
Hence, the login page can be accessed by anonymous users.
There, we can now see the log in page, but it doesn't look quite right.
All our CSS and Bootstrap, JavaScript is being blocked by
Spring as by default Spring blocks everything.
Now to get around this,
we can override the configure method that exposes the WebSecurity builder.
And here we can define the URL we want Spring Security to
ignore completely, like our CSS and webjars.
And if we restart and refresh,
you can see the page is now being styled correctly.
Now the difference between WebSecurityIgnore and permitting access to
HttpSecurity is if we look at the filter proxy,
it now has three filter chains.
The first two are for CSS and webjars endpoints,
and the filter chain has no filters in them. And the last one is
the filter chain with all our security filters.
Essentially,
requests to these endpoints defined in ignore completely bypass
Spring Security. Whereas the login request will still get
intercepted by the last filter chain,
which has all the security filters like the username and password
authentication filter, which is why we can't ignore the login endpoint
as it requires the authentication filter.
Now Spring allows for more finer‑grain authorization.
Here we can define that our admin URL, in addition to being authenticated,
the user must also have the role user or admin or
anything else you might require.
Next, let's look at the filter chains in more detail and how we can
leverage them to support different authorization strategies for different parts of our web application.