Okay, it's time to test our web app.
Let's quickly pop into the basement, and don't forget to grab your hacker hoody.
The website has now HTTPS enabled.
The hacker can no longer sniff the network traffic or
perform many of the previous attacks.
There is still one vulnerability here.
If we look at the communication between the browser and the server,
the initial redirect request and response is via HTTP,
hence it's susceptible to a man‑in‑the‑middle attack.
The hacker could intercept the response from the server and inject
malicious content like scripts or simply change the redirect to their
malicious site by changing the header.
And it's a lot easier than you might think.
Here is the GUI for the WiFi Pineapple, which costs around 100 bucks off eBay,
and it can open up a fake Wi‑Fi endpoint with any SSID you want.
Here I have set one up for CRYPTO_CONF.
Now if the user connects to this SSID,
they are exposed to a man‑in‑the‑middle attack,
and these days, users expect there to be free Wi‑Fi everywhere in restaurants,
cafes, conferences,
you name it. Even planes and trains are starting to implement them.
And the user doesn't even have to specifically connect to this network.
When they connect to an SSID at home or anywhere,
their device remembers that point,
and it will automatically reconnect to that network when it is in range.
It does this through probe requests, continuously searching for these networks.
The Pineapple can actually detect these probes and
masquerade as the exact same SSID, tricking your device into connecting to it.
Now once a user is connected to this malicious Wi‑Fi spot,
they would be using the DNS server of the device,
and the hacker can use DNS spoofing.
Here we add the AWS domain and map it to a malicious server IP address.
Now if the user decides to check their portfolio while
connected to this malicious Wi‑Fi,
they receive a familiar bland default login page.
But notice, it's not HTTPS.
Now the user probably wouldn't even notice this.
If they log in, the hacker now has their credentials.
Now you can imagine if this site was popular among crypto investors,
the hacker could gather quite a lot of passwords in a conference.
Now fortunately, Spring, by default,
helps protect against this by adding the HSTS HTTP
Strict‑Transport‑Security header. We will discuss this in the next section.