In your typical Java web application, you have a server,
which manages a servlet container.
The containers host the servlets that process the incoming request.
When you configure Spring MVC,
you are effectively adding a Spring servlet called the dispatcher servlet,
which intercepts all requests for your MVC application.
Now in addition to servlets, there are filters.
Filters sit in front of the servlets and intercept all requests.
These are great if you need to perform some operations on the
request before it actually reaches the servlets.
Now filters can also prevent requests from reaching servlets,
making them perfect for performing security checks.
Hence, when you configure Spring Security,
you're essentially adding a Spring Security filter
called the DelegatingFilterProxy,
which intercepts all requests before they reach the dispatcher servlet.
Now this filter then delegates the requests to a FilterChainProxy.
The FilterChainProxy, as the name suggests,
manages the routing of the requests to Spring Security filter chains,
which are collections of filters that perform security checks.
Now different requests can be configured to be
handled by different filter chains.
Generally though, you would have just one filter change,
but you could configure multiple ones for different parts of your application.
Example, all requests for /portfolio could go through filter chain 1,
and all requests to /admin to filter chain 2.
This allows you to customize your authentication and authorization for
different parts of the application if the need arises.
If we put a breakpoint in the FilterChainProxy and
try to access the application,
you can see the filter chains configured by Spring Boot,
which comprise of around 14 filters.
We can see a LogoutFilter to handle logout requests,
the UsernamePasswordAuthenticationFilter,
which, as the name suggests,
retrieves the username and password from the body of the login
request and essentially authenticates the user.
There is also a BasicAuthenticationFilter.
So in our application,
we can actually also login via basic authentication and so on,
each filter vetting the request or performing some sort of security task.
Now when it comes to authentication, the authentication filters are key.
There are many flavors of these from the username and
password to form authentication, digest,
basic, OAuth, and you can even create your own.
Essentially, an authentication filter will intercept an authentication request,
create an authentication request object with the user's credentials,
and it will then request the AuthenticationManager to authenticate the request.
The AuthenticationManager will, in turn,
delegate authentication to an appropriate authentication
provider as there are many ways to authenticate other than just
simply comparing a username and password.
You have RFID, LDAP, OAuth, OpenID Connect, you name it.
Hence,
Spring Security has a selection of providers you can
configure for the most popular types, but you can also create your own.
Now the manager is responsible for delegating the request to
the appropriate authentication provider that deals with that
type of authentication request.
If the authentication is successful,
the provider will return an authenticated principal object,
and the authentication filter will then store this principal in an
object called the security context where it can be retrieved by
other filters lower down in the filter chain or your application
code to access any of the authenticated principal details or to
confirm authentication.
Now in a web application, this would generally be stored in a session.
Now if we go back to debug mode, you can actually see all these components.
Here we have the username and password filter.
You can see it has an AuthenticationManager,
and the AuthenticationManager has an authentication provider collection.
In this case though,
we just have one authentication provider as we're just
authenticating using the username or password.
Now this is a lot to take in, but don't worry.
In subsequent modules,
we'll be configuring these components to meet different security requirements, so you'll become very familiar with these.