Spring also protects your site against cross‑site request forgery,
or session riding,
which is an attack that forces an end user to execute unwanted actions on a
web application in which they're currently authenticated.
The way it works is your user authenticates with your
website. The web server will return a cookie,
which is stored by the browser against that domain.
This is so all future requests to that domain do not have to reauthenticate.
The browser will just automatically include the cookie
for all future requests to the server.
If while the user is still logged in they access a malicious site,
perhaps in another tab,
and submit something to that malicious site, the malicious site can
submit a request to the target server domain,
and the browser will automatically add the cookie to that request.
Now cross‑site request forgery attacks are only viable
for state changing operations like PUT, POST,
or DELETE as the response is returned back to the user's browser; however,
the malicious site could submit a change of content,
deleting content, transferring funds perhaps,
or even trying to reset the password to give the
hacker access to the user's account.
Spring, by default,
protects against cross‑site request forgery using
the synchronizer token pattern.
The way it works is when a user logs into your web application,
the server returns the response,
which includes both the cookie and, additionally,
a randomly generated token.
The browser will store the cookie against the domain,
but it has no knowledge of the token as it's application‑specific.
Spring Security then expects both the cookie and the token
to be returned for all future requests.
The malicious site has no access to the token.
Hence, when it submits the request to your domain,
Spring Security will reject it.
Like most things in Spring Security, there is a filter,
the cross‑site request forgery filter,
that performs the checks and adds the token to the
response bed. From my experience,
this is the most common default security feature disabled, mainly because
developers just don't understand what cross‑site request forgery is and the
implications to their users of disabling it.
So when they first experience the error,
they simply Google it and see the first solution,
which recommends disabling the filter.
Well,
let's see the consequences to Victoria's portfolio if we
disable this protection in our application.
Previously, the hacker was able to view Victoria's sensitive cached page.
So they now know her details, her email,
her crypto portfolio position,
and hence they can now target her with a phishing email,
and using her personal details makes it look more legit.
Now the hacker sends her a malicious link where apparently she can
get free crypto by submitting her wallet address,
and who doesn't want free crypto?
Now if she's also logged into her portfolio at the same
time as accessing this malicious site, perhaps in a new tab,
and then she submits the malicious form,
her portfolio is now empty.
She will definitely not be impressed.
If we look at the source code of the malicious site,
it's simply a post request directed at the crypto portfolio domain.
And on the way out, the browser included the
cookie. It's stored for that domain.
Now, if we re‑enable the cross‑site request forgery protection,
you can see that Spring Security now blocks the malicious site,
as the request did not include the cross‑site request forgery token.
Now the hacker still has another option up their sleeves. Let's look at that next.