You can now see what makes Spring Security so portable as all you really
need to do is add one filter to your servlet container,
and Spring Boot does this for you right out of the box.
And, as you probably already noticed,
Spring Security is made up of filters and filters within filters,
each of which perform some sort of security checks or routing
or tasks on the request before a request is actually allowed
to reach its final destination.
Now in Spring Boot,
it's super easy to get a barebones security implementation up and
running as soon as you start working on your project. So security
no longer has to be an afterthought.
It can evolve with your application from day 1,
and that's important because security is one of those
nonfunctional requirements that's like technical debt. The longer you leave it, the more interest in effort you will pay in the future.