This concludes the module and the course.
Thank you for taking the time to understand the framework at
a more granular level as, unfortunately,
security tends to be an afterthought with developers as you
don't tend to get recognition for getting security right as
you would releasing a feature early.
However,
the implications of getting it wrong for your users
and organization can be dire.
So even if you don't get recognition, dig down.
You'll know that you are doing right by your users, and that's good karma.
This will be the first course in the series that will be
released. In subsequent courses, we'll cover more advanced
topics on security storing credentials,
multifactor authentication, session management,
advanced authorization techniques from URL, method, and domain objects, how
to outsource your authentication using OAuth 2. You can follow me to get
notifications when these new courses are released.
If you can't wait,
then you can check out my previous courses: Spring Security
Authentication/Authorization: Layers of Defense,
which is a little out of date but contains most of these advanced topics.
Also, my course on OAuth 2 and Spring Security.
Thank you for taking the time to view my course. Let me know in the comments if you have any questions or feedback.