Now very often I hear students ask me about, "How can I become a freelancer?
I want to work in Bali or I want to travel and I want to be able to at the same time work as a freelancer."
One of the best ways to get started is to build a portfolio and to build up a list of clients who can
vouch for you because if you want to get that top gig right at the beginning then it's going to be very
very hard without some references without something to show for it.
So the first thing I recommend students do is to go onto a website like Fiverr where people are not
paying very much for any sort of service. But you know to practise working with a client to figure out
what it is that people want, to establish how you can better communicate with your clients and make them
happy and build the things that they want.
So even though you're not getting paid a lot in the beginning, at least you're working with real projects
and real people.
And as you build up your skills, as you build more projects, then you'll be able to go to websites like
Upwork or Guru or Freelancer and be able to offer your services for slightly more.
Basically, don't shoot for the moon right at the beginning.
Instead build up your reputation and build up your skills while you're getting your clients excellent
service
for not very much money. And this way, within a year or so, you'll have enough projects to show off and
enough clients will vouch for you, then you can shoot for the moon.