Hey, it's Angela again and I'm here to congratulate you on coming
really really far in the course.
Not everybody gets to see these videos that you're watching.
And just in terms of your perseverance and the level of dedication that you have to be able to reach
here, it's fantastic,
and it really sets you apart from other people.
So congratulations.
You deserve a back.
You deserve a pat on the back.
Now I also want to talk about something that I've heard a lot of students say when they reach around
this kind of time point, where they say like, "Oh, you know, even though I've been going on and learning
for so long, I've done like a 100 days, one hour a day, and I still feel like I don't know anything, I don't
know everything.".
And, firstly, nobody knows everything.
Even if you just take something as simple as like one particular technology, there's too many things
to know.
You only learn the things that are relevant to what it is that you're trying to achieve,
now aside from the fundamental skills of course. So the thing I tend to tell students is, you've actually
made huge leaps in terms of where you were before but it's just that as you keep getting more advanced
and there's more advanced topics coming up around you your level of struggle seems to be kind of constant,
right?
It doesn't ever really get easier and I can testify to that like even at my level,
there are still loads of things that really are mind boggling.
I sit there thinking like "Oh, I wish I was smart and I could just understand this immediately". But this
is just, it's fantasy.
We all have to work hard in order to get what we actually end up with, our results.
So what I want you to do, whenever you feel like "I've done so much work and yet I don't, I can't, I don't
feel like I know everything yet" is to go to the early parts of the course,
have a look at the questions that the students who are just starting out, you know, maybe in the first second
and third modules, see what questions they're asking and see how easy it is for you to answer those questions
because of where you are now.
Those struggles that they have and you probably had at one point as well are so much easier for you
to be able to understand. And you can see at a glance like "Oh yeah, that's totally because of this,
because of that". And just by answering some of these student questions, the people who are at an
earlier stage, you actually feel like you've gone further and you know you have achieved a lot since
when you first started.
So try it out.
Let me know how it goes.
And I hope you will keep going and that you will achieve your potential.
So keep going.