All right.
So in the next lesson you're going to tackle the interactive challenge where you have to write the code
and I will check your solutions
behind the scenes.
So this is what you should see.
This is the BMI calculator challenge, and there's a little bit of description about what BMIs are and
what they’re used for.
Now the most important thing is that I've included the formula to calculate the BMI which is the weight
divided by the height squared.
And this is weight in kilograms and height in meters.
So your challenge is to create a function that takes the weight and the height as inputs, like so,
and to be able to give the output, which is going to be equal to the BMI, so that if I run this line
of code using the function that you create, which is going to be called bmiCalculator, I should be able
to get the BMI inside this variable called bmi.
Now, the order of your inputs matter in this case. You’re going to have to put the weight as an input
first and then the height as an input in order to satisfy this line of code.
So you can copy what's inside the index.js file in here, and you can paste it into the Snippets
tool here to write your code and to test your code inside the Chrome Developer Tools and use the console.
So, if you’re here, you can activate this line of code, and try to write your function here, so that when
you console.log your BMI variable, you should be getting the same value back as any BMI calculator online.
Now once you're happy with your function then you can go ahead and click Check solution in order to
check to see if you got it right.
And once you're done then you can go ahead and continue on to the next lesson, where I’ll go through the solution
with you step by step.