Right.
So in this lesson we're going to be building our very first web site. Now, because we've only talked about
HTML so far, so how to structure web sites using HTML elements, and we haven't yet gotten to the part
where we've learnt about styling using CSS, then we're kind of limited in terms of the kind of web sites
that we can make.
But, fear not, our web sites are going to be right up there with the Internet titans but just way back in
1997.
So do you remember what Yahoo looked like when it first launched?
Or do you remember what Google looked like when it first came out?
No, don't remember?
Well it was a great web site.
I can show you exactly that.
And it's called The Internet Archive Wayback Machine and you can find it at web.archive.org.
Now in here you just enter the URL of a Web site that you were interested in, say yahoo.com,
then it shows you what this web site looks like all the way from 1996 to current day which is 2017.
Now let's have a look at what Yahoo looked like originally on the first day it was crawled,
so 17th of October 1996.
So let's go ahead and click on that snapshot.
And this is exactly what it looks like.
So if we close off this frame you can see it's almost like as if you've time traveled back to 1996 when
Yahoo first launched and you were visiting this web site for the first time.
Now as you can see most of this is just pure HTML.
It's a lot of structure and a lot of formatting but it looks really ugly.
But it's OK because it's a great place to get started with.
So this is the sort of web site that we're going to be building by the end of this module.
Now I hear you say, ‘Oh but this looks terrible.
We're in 2017.
Surely nobody builds web sites like this anymore.’
Well this is an interesting anecdote that you might not know. If you have a look at some of the world's
top computer science professors and you look at their personal pages that they've built,
they all look a little bit like this, not so dissimilar from the web sites in 1996.
So this is Thomas Cormen who's a serious algorithm guy and this is a web site of Jon Kleinberg,
another huge name computer science professor, and of course the king himself
Donald Knuth has a website that looks like this.
So if it's good enough for these computer science titans then it's probably good enough also for our
very first web site.
So by the end of this module we're going to build a web site that looks much like this, something that
we can put up online to show what we've done,
our CV, as well as our hobbies and things that we like to do.
So you can use it as a personal site or somewhere to list your CV online.
So I hope you're excited because I'm super excited and once you're ready let's go ahead and create our
very first web site.