Hey.
Well done on
completing yet another module.
Now I want to talk to you about something that I find helps me with motivation.
Now I know that as computer programmers we have this kind of reputation for not really wanting to interact
with other humans but you know that doesn't have to be true right?
And we can in fact interact with other humans.
Let's say you're in a library where like everybody is doing their own thing and you don't have to talk to
anybody.
But the point I'm saying is that when you're working at home and you're all alone and you're trying
to study through this thing it can get really hard.
But if you're in a place where everybody else is working and you look up and you look at the intenseness
to which everybody's working, it makes you want to work hard as well.
So I find even though I've graduated from my university many years ago now, I have an alumni card which
means I can still go back to the university library and I do that whenever I have to do something that
I procrastinate a lot on.
So if I have to do something difficult and when I'm at home I just keep passing it over
when I'm at work
I just can't really do it,
I go to the university library and this is really really helpful.
It's just like the exam time when everybody's studying really hard.
It's like you know you feel inspired to work hard because you're kind of twiddling your thumbs while
everybody else is studying really hard you feel kind of silly
right?
So see if you can find these opportunities where either you have a study buddy or if you have a local
library that you can access where everybody's quiet and then working hard.
See if you can try to use that to increase your own level of motivation and see if that helps you get
further.
But the key thing is keep going keep going keep going keep going keep going.