So now that we've completed all of the first column where we have pre planned how our server should respond
when somebody makes a HTTP request with get or post or delete to our articles route, the
next step is to move on to the next column.
And now in this case our route is actually a specific article
in this case and it could be anything. And when we're writing our server code we're writing it to be
all encompassing.
But when the user or the client rather targets a particular route, they will put in something like
/articles/jack-bauer or /jquery or whatever it may be
that is the specific resource that they're looking for inside the articles collection.
And now we have to write our server code on how it should handle these requests.
So as an example in this table you'll see everything referring to a specific article say an article
on Jack Bauer.
But when we write the code as you'll see in just a minute we're actually writing the code to encompass
any single article within the articles collection.
So let's get started.
So first things first we have to make provisions for how to handle the GET request on that particular
route.
Now previously, we've been using our trusty app.get method but now that you've learnt about chaining
these route handlers, I want you as a challenge to write the code for our next GET request using the chained
syntax that you saw in the last lesson.
So pause the video now and try to complete this challenge by writing the code for our GET request.
All right.
So how did that go?
So now that we're no longer using app.get instead we're using app.route.
And if you had any trouble at all, always remember the first point of call is the documentation and it's
super detailed on how you can use it.
So it shouldn't be too difficult to get started there.
So now that we have app.route and then inside the parentheses we add in the actual route and then
we chain on to that method a .get method and then the rest is exactly the same as we've done before.
So let's see it in practice.
So right up here I'm just going to add a quick comment and this is going to be the "Requests targeting
all articles". And then I'm going to copy and paste that down here.
And this one is going to be "Requests targeting a specific article."
So now that we've got our sections divided up makes it a little bit easier for us to see the next time
when we're just going through our code.
So now I'm going to write my app.route because we now have a different route whereas previously
our app.route and all of its chain methods dealt with the articles route,
now we are dealing with a specific article.
So the way that we structure this will be articles,
so the same as before, but then we have another forward slash and then this is where the client should
specify the particular resource that they want.
Now again if we go back to our Express documentation you should remember that previously we had talked
about route parameters and this is where inside that particular URL we added in a colon and then
basically kind of like a variable name which we will assign to whatever the client assigns to their
URL request.
So in their example here you can see that the route path is /users/:userId
and when the client makes the request the URL looks like this.
And so you've got /user/34.
So when that enters the server then 34 will get assigned to a variable named userId and we'll be
able to use it inside that callback.
So this is exactly what we're going to do for our specific resource which is a single article.
Now in our case let's say that the client has to use the article title as that parameter.
So I'm going to call it articleTitle. And now we've basically completed our route.
So it's time to chain on our method which is the get method and I'm going to separate it out so that
we can see it a little bit easier.
So the get method is going to be the same as what we've done before
minus the route.
So it's simply just going to be a callback function with a request and response.
Now if we're going to run our code right now before I get the chance to write the other chained on methods
then we have to add a semicolon here to cap all of those chained methods off so that it doesn't flow
on to the next line.
So now inside my app.get essentially.
So now inside the callback function in my app.get effectively
then I'm going to need to read from my database to look for a specific article with that article title.
So in this case I'm only expecting a single match.
So instead of using the find method I'm going to be using the fineOne method. And then I'm going to
specify the conditions that it has to match namely that its title has to match that title parameter
that we got in through the URL.
And then we're going to add the callback to see if there were any errors or if we got the resulting
document.
So inside our app.get I'm going to write article which is the name of my model .findOne. And
then the condition is that the document has to have a title that is the same as the one that was requested
by the client inside here.
So now if we had say something like localhost:3000/articles/Jack-Bauer
then inside our app.route we should be able to tap into the req.params.articleTitle
and that will be equal to whatever the value the user put in to that URL.
So in this case it'll be Jack Bauer.
If they were looking for localhost:3000/articles/ say
jQuer,y then this will be equal to
jQuery instead.
Now if that is at all confusing and this feels new to you then be sure to flip a few modules back and
revisit that lesson where we covered Express parameters in more detail and also be sure to read through
the Express documentation on this.
So I'm assuming that this is all very familiar to you because we've used it many times before.
So now I'm gonna go into my get method
so when a user makes a get request then we should be able to tap into that request or req and we should
be able to tap into the params that were passed in with the request and also the name of the variable
which in this case is called articleTitle.
So this is going to go over here and that is going to be essentially the search condition.
So we're going to look through our collection of articles, we're gonna find one document where the title
is equal to the one inside the request parameters
that is the articleTitle. And once that is complete then we're going to carve a callback function with
an error
and also the foundArticle. Now in this case it should be singular because we're only expecting one document
to come back whereas up here we use find I tend to have that variable name as plural.
So now that we've got our found article the next step is to add our curly braces and inside here is where
all the action is going to happen.
So what do we want to happen?
Well if there indeed was an article that was found inside our articles collection that matches the title
that the client put in the URL, then in that case we're probably going to send that back to the client.
So in this case we'll say something like if there indeed was a found article then we're going to res
.send that found article. But if there weren't any articles that were found then we're going to
res.send the text "No articles matching that title was found."
And now we can close off everything with semicolons and get rid of all our warnings and errors and we're
ready to test our code.
So let's go into our Postman and let's change the method from delete to get
and we're going to change also the URL from /articles to localhost:3000
/articles/ whatever it is that we want to put in as the articleTitle parameter.
Now if we were to search for say an article on
JQuery then we would write /articles/
JQuery.
Now before we can test it, if you look inside Robo 3T
remember that the last HTTP request that we made inside Postman was to ask the server to delete
all of our articles.
So if we clicked on view documents you should be able to see precisely zero documents inside that collection.
So remember where previously I said copy what already exists inside our collection so we can quickly
fill it back up,
well this is the time for that.
So we want to go and add or insert our documents all in one go.
Now if you have, for some reason, lost that copy and paste then don't worry because if you go to that
GitHub page for the project and scroll right down then you should see a section where it says repopulate
database.
And I've got all of these documents over here for you to copy and simply paste into Robo 3T.
So we're gonna delete the existing braces and then we're going to paste everything that we copied over
and now we're gonna hit save.
And when we view documents again then voila! We've got all our documents back
which is wonderful.
So we're now ready to go into Postman and query for a particular article. So you can see we've got articles
with titles such as REST, API, Bootstrap DOM,  Jack Bauer.
So let's go for one of those.
Let's just put REST in here and I'm going to type it out exactly the same way as I see over here.
So now when I click send it should be making a GET request to the route that is /articles/
REST.
And that will fall into this method right here and we're going to look inside the request parameters
for something called articleTitle which is of course whatever comes after the slash after articles.
And then we're going to look through our articles collection to find a document that has that title. And if
we did have a found title that matches it then we should get it sent back from the server.
So let's go ahead and click it. And you can see I have now got back my article on REST and I've got the
title and the content.
So now if we wanted to make a request and we wanted the client to be able to access a articletitle
that has a space in it, you have to remember that the way that URL encoding works is that a space
is usually represented in URL form as %20.
And we've looked at this previously but if you'd just wanted a quick reminder then if you go to the reference
page on HTML URL Encoding then you can take a look down on this table and see that the space character
is represented by %20 and all of these other characters which also have their representations.
So that means that if we wanted to make a GET request to find the article that has a title of Jack
Bauer, then we would write something like Jack%20Bauer
and when I hit send I get back my title on Jack Bauer and my content as well.
So remember that when it comes into here that %20 gets decoded into a space and we get Jack
Bauer that we get to used to search our articles for.