So now that we've completed the HTML section and we have our completed web site but we can only access
it locally because when we open up our index.html you can see that we're just opening a local
file, right?
In this case this file’s inside my Users folder inside my username inside my desktop, but that means
nobody else can actually access this web site which makes it a bit pointless, right?
The whole point of a web site is so that we can put it on to the Internet and everybody will be able to
see our personal site or our CV.
So how can we do this?
Well in order to do that we need to host our web site somewhere.
Now there's a whole bunch of hosting sites such as Go Daddy or Blue Host, but because we're learning
at the moment we don't want to have to pay for this.
So there's also a free solution that I'm going to show you. By the end of this lesson
you’re going to have your personal CV up on the Internet proudly displayed somewhere and you'll be able
to share a URL or a link to it
so that anybody across the web can be able to access it.
But first things first. We’ll need to do a little bit of setup.
The service that we're going to use is GitHub, and we're going to talk about GitHub in a lot of detail
a little bit later on.
It's a really really useful tool that is pretty much essential to a developer's workflow.
But for now we're only going to use one of its features which is hosting our web site.
So first and foremost if you don't have a GitHub account then you'll need to set up a new one.
So I'm just going to set one up while we're at it.
And now it’ll ask you to choose a plan.
Now we're going to choose the free plan and then we then click Continue.
Now I'm going to skip this questionnaire and just click on skip this step. Now once you have signed up to
GitHub it's really important that you go ahead and verify your email address so check your emails and
see if you have something from GitHub and then click on that verify link.
And once you've done that you'll be able to add new repositories to Github.
If you head over to the upper right corner and just click on the plus button and then we're going to
create a new repository.
Now, this repository, I'm just going to call it cv, and this is going to be the name of my project and
all that a repository is it's simply just a folder out there on the cloud that's going to store all
of your project related files and you'll be able to make changes to the files and update the files and
you'll be able to track all of those changes that you've made in the past.
So now that we've given our repository a name then we're going to leave the description as empty and
then we're going to keep Public selected
if you are on the free tier of GitHub, and then down here make sure that you check this box where we initialize
this repository with a README.
And it's really really important that you do this for the next few steps to work.
So now that we've done all that we're going to go ahead and click on Create repository and this will
take just a moment and now you should see a page that looks like this which means that your repository
has been created and the only file that's in your repository is just a README file.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and upload our files for our CV web site.
So now if you bring up the folder which contains your CV web site, so the place where you see your
index.html, your images folder and any other pages you have.
You're going to select all of these and you're going to drag it into this box here and that will upload
and add all of them to our online repository.
Once that's done we're going to give this particular version a name so we'll say that in this version
we added initial cv web site files, and then make sure that this part where it says ‘Commit directly
to the master branch’ is checked, and then go ahead and click to commit these changes.
And that will upload all of those files that we dragged on.
And we are now ready to set up or our GitHub page.
If you head over to the Settings tab here and if you scroll down on the Settings page, you'll see that
there is a section called GitHub Pages, and GitHub Pages is designed to host your personal organization
or project pages from a GitHub repository.
So we already have the repository.
We now have to activate our pages.
So it's currently disabled.
All we have to do to enable it,
we just have to select a source where our files reside.
So if you click on this part where it says None,
you should change it to where it says master branch and go ahead and click Save.
So now GitHub is going to do some behind the scenes stuff and it's going to be publishing towards a place
which is going to be your user name.github.io/your project name, so that will be your CV.
And you can see this is an https web site, so you'll be able to access the site from anywhere across the world
as long as you're connected to the Internet.
Now this publishing process takes a little while.
So if you refresh this page you'll see that it says your site is published at this address.
And if you click on that address you should be able to see your web site show up.
Now if at this point what you see instead is a 404, then that just means that you have to be a little
bit more patient,
the GitHub servers are probably working overtime, and come back in maybe half an hour and check that
link again.
But once you are done though, then your web site should work exactly as it did locally.
But now you can go ahead and share this link with anybody you like across the world and they can access
it because it's now hosted on the internet so you can go ahead and go over to angelabauer.github.io/cv
and you too will be able to see this web site that I just uploaded and I'm looking
at right now.
So now it's time for you to go through this process and upload your CV and your web site onto the worldwide
web.
And be sure to share a link to your project in the Q&amp;A of this lesson so that we can all admire your
hard work and what you have created.
That's all for me for this lesson.
I'll see you on the next.