Hello and welcome to Shopify Theme Development with Vue.js. I'm Christopher Dodd.
I'm a freelance web developer and top teacher here on Skillshare.com,
covering all things web development and online freelancing.
In today's class, we're going to learn how to integrate the JavaScript Framework
Vue.js into the product and cart pages of a Shopify theme.
This class is ideal for those of you who have taken some of my other classes on
Shopify theme development here on Skillshare.com and are
ready to take their theme development skills to the next level.
With Vue.js, we're able to bring Shopify data structures onto
the front end and allow for the user to live
update elements without reloading the browser.
Using Vue.js over other JavaScript libraries like jQuery,
we can create a more optimal experience for both us as developers,
as well as the end-users of our e-commerce store.
If you're ready to get started,
click on to the next video and I'll see you on the inside.