In this short bonus lesson,
I'm going to show you how to move our Vue apps into
section files as opposed to leaving them in liquid template files.
The reason I'm showing you this is because of Online Store 2.0.
If you're not familiar with Online Store 2.0,
I encourage you to check out my first class here on Skillshare,
Shopify theme development: How to build and customize your own online store.
I've added three additional videos in there to account for the Online Store 2.0 changes.
Essentially, what has changed is that template files can now be either JSON or Liquid.
To adapt for this new way of making themes,
I want to show you how we can move our apps intersection files,
and then transform those templates into JSON files instead.
I'm going to dig into the theme here,
I'll just show you what I mean.
Here under Templates, you've got
all the template files coded as Liquid that, of course,
allows us to insert liquid code HTML,
CSS JavaScript, all in this template file,
and that's what's used as our template.
But if you click on this nowadays,
you will see that there is an option for a JSON template.
What I'm going to do is I've duplicated the theme to keep that one untouched,
and in here, I'm going to click "Edit code" on the duplicate,
and let's start to refactor our project here.
First things first, we want to create a new section to house.
Let's do product template first,
so I'm going to create a new section,
and I'm just going to call it Product Template.
Don't have to put the.liquid in there because that will be automatic,
and now we're just going to have to populate the section name,
just going to call it Product Template or Main Product,
something like that because we may want to put some other stuff on it.
Main Product Template.
Now I'll just hit "Save" on that,
and I'll go over to our product.liquid template.
This is where we have our Vue app for the product page.
I'm going to copy all of the code using Command A on a Mac.
I'm not sure what it is on a Windows,
then Command C. Then I'm going to go over here,
create some space at the top,
and paste in our code there.
Now that we have our code pasted in and saved,
we can delete this template file,
and this will give us the space to create a JSON template.
I'm going to click "Add new template",
and go down to product,
and here you can see we can create a product.JSON template now.
Going to hit "Create template" and now we've
got the basis of our product template. All right.
I'll go more in depth into this in
Lesson 11 of Shopify theme development:
How to build and customize your own online store.
I'm going to breeze through this a little bit,
but essentially what we need to do here is add the required fields in order to use this.
It doesn't allow me to save unless I make a change,
but you'll see that if you don't include this, it will error.
We need to include these compulsory fields.
First of all, we need to give this product template a name,
and I'm just going to give it the simple name of Product Template.
Now inside our section's object,
we need to link up that product template that we just created.
I'm going to start off by calling it Main-Product,
and let's open up an object as the value of that.
Then all we need is to put in a type,
and the type needs to be equal to the section name;
the section filename minus the.liquid.
That's just going to be product-template. All right.
In our order array,
we need to put in the name that matches this, so main-product.
This seems redundant at this point because we only have one section,
but if we had multiple,
we can define a different order for them here in this order array.
I'm going to hit "Save" on that.
As you can see, no errors.
Then I'm going to hit "Customize theme".
Now that we're inside our store editor,
we need to click up here to change to the product template that we just created.
It's just going to be default products because it doesn't have
a dot after product, it's just product.JSON.
If it was product dot something else,
then it would come up as an alternate like this one.
I'm just going to click on that,
and here you can see we've got our product template still.
If I go to Shop the Tee,
you can see we've got our app,
and it's still working.
That's because we've included our section file here,
it doesn't have any editable sections,
but it has been linked.
Now this isn't the most exciting lesson because we
haven't added any new functionality whatsoever,
except for the fact that we can now add other sections and reorder them.
Because this is a bare-bones project with no other sections,
we don't actually have the ability to add another section here
because there are literally no other sections.
But using the Online Store 2.0 system,
if we were using a modern theme,
we could actually now move this around,
add new sections if we wanted to.
That has been essentially what this video has been about,
adapting to Online Store 2.0.
You might be using a newer theme that has all of its templates as JSON.
In that case, we need to adapt our practices just
a little bit to adapt for this new change.
All we've done here is just moved the Liquid code into a section file,
and included that section file inside our JSON product template.
We can still do it the old way,
we can still throw in or keep this code in a product.liquid template,
but now we're moving in this direction with Online Store 2.0.
I just wanted to throw in this video here for
those of you who are working with modern themes,
or have opened up a modern theme,
and wondered what the hell.
Hopefully this video has provided some context for you.
Any questions, as always,
feel free to leave them in the discussion box below,
and I'll see you in the final video for the conclusion.