This concludes this class on using Vue.js in Shopify themes.
For your class project, I encourage you to integrate
Vue.js into whatever Shopify theme you're currently working on.
Keep in mind that most production level themes already use a fair amount of JavaScript,
so you'll likely have to refactor some of
that JavaScript in order to make room for Vue.js.
As I've mentioned throughout this class,
this topic is quite a specific one within Shopify theme development,
so if you're unsure about anything regarding the foundational topics of HTML,
CSS, JavaScript, Shopify liquid,
you can find plenty of lessons on all of that here on my Skillshare channel.
All you got to do is click on my name and
then check out my other web development classes.
As always, if you would like to learn more about
Shopify theme programming and theme development,
follow me online and check out my YouTube channel for additional tutorials.
Finally, if you need any tips or guidance on what we've covered in today's class,
be sure to leave a comment in the discussion box below,
and I'll do my best to point you in the right direction.
Thanks as always for watching and I hope to see you again on some my other classes.