Today's class when using Vue.js inside Shopify themes is an advanced topic and therefore,
you will require some prerequisite knowledge in
order to understand and get the most out of this class.
Before taking this class,
you should understand the difference between
front-end and back-end when it comes to web development,
this is also known as client-side and server-side.
If you're not familiar of why we would need to transfer
data from Shopify Liquid into JavaScript,
for instance, then I recommend you take a look at Lesson 4 of
my previous Skillshare class, Understanding Web Development.
Secondly, you're going to need to know JavaScript.
If you need a refresher,
you can check out my Skillshare class,
Web Development Fundamentals: JavaScript.
Third, you should have at least some familiarity with the Ajax API and Shopify.
In this class, we'll be plugging it into view and using it to update our cart on the fly.
If you'd like a refresher of the Ajax API,
check out Lesson 8 of my class, Shopify Theme Programming.
Of course, last but not least,
you should have some general experience with
Shopify theme development and writing Shopify Liquid code.
If not, I definitely recommend my two previous Skillshare classes on the subject,
Shopify Theme Development and Shopify Theme Programming.
Other than that, even if you are new to Vue.js,
you should have enough knowledge to continue on with the following videos.