In this lesson, we're going to refactor the product page here to use Vue.js.
If we look at the code now,
the content and all the dynamic values are coming from Shopify liquid.
What that means is,
that it's rendered on the server side once when the page loads.
No matter what we do,
the current variant is going to be small white
because that's the variant that's selected on page load,
and no matter what we do here to update our color,
the color in the product image is not going to change,
and that is a bad user experience, of course.
Currently, we don't even have this setup to change the variant id.
When we click "Add to cart" it's going to add the small white
T. I'm going to clear my cart quickly by running fetch.
You can do this as well.
This is just the end point of the cart Ajax API to clear the cart.
Just fetch cart clear.js,
and that refresh the page that'll clear the cart.
Back to this page right here.
If we go into the code,
we're rendering all of this Shopify liquid on the page,
but of course we want to update certain things
depending on the selection here in the variance selection.
This is why we want to use Vue.
The first thing I'm going to do is set up the data. We saw that before.
We're going to have to create a data function within this object,
and then inside this function,
we return an object which holds our data.
Let's think about some of the things we want to track in this app.
Of course, we want to track the current variant id because that's
what's going to get added to the cart when we click "Add to cart".
I'm going to start with that current variant id,
and the starting value of our current variant id is going to be
equal to what we currently have here in our value.
As I mentioned before, the value that's been inserted
into this hidden field, and therefore,
what gets added to the cart when you click "Add to cart"
is the selected or first available variant.
Let's move this value into here, our Vue instance,
and that's going to ensure that the current variant
id on page load will get set with that value.
But then we can update it as we interact with our Vue app.
Now what I'm going to do here is something very subtle but very important.
I'm going to put a colon in front of value,
and that's going to transform that field into a dynamic Vue field.
Instead of putting an explicit value in there like here,
the value is going to be one,
we can put a variable name in there from our data object
and it will update depending on what happens to this data.
This is where the reactivity comes in.
Here, we're going to put the variable name in here.
The idea is that if this changes over time,
this will also change automatically.
But for now we should see the exact same results.
I'll refresh the page.
Let's go over to our Vue tab,
and you can see here we get to inspect the data and we can see our current variant id.
If we inspect the form and look for that hidden field,
you can see that's the value.
Actually what we can do is go in here and edit this on the fly.
If I put this as 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, for instance,
I've changed the value,
and then you can see here it's changed in the DOM as well.
You've got this data binding happening here. It's pretty cool.
If I refresh the page,
that value will get loaded in again. That's pretty cool.
The next thing I want to capture,
the different variants available for this particular product.
The way I'm going to do that is by doing a liquid loop.
This is not the cleanest code,
but it's just the way we have to do it in Shopify liquid.
I'm going to create a variants array here,
and inside this array,
I'm going to use Shopify liquid to give us our variants.
We're going to put in a for loop here,
variant in product variants.
Basically what I'm doing here is transferring the data from
Shopify liquid into our Vue instance so that we can interact with it inside of Vue,
all on the front end without having to rely on Shopify liquid.
For each variant in product variants,
I'm going to have an object with a comma.
Don't forget the comma,
otherwise there won't be any separation between variants,
and I'm going to copy across some of the data from Shopify liquid.
First one, variant id,
we're going to need to know if the variant is available.
We can set that without quotations so that it can just insert as a Boolean value there,
and then we're going to grab its option values.
Within the three options that we have available to us in Shopify,
what is the selection?
If you're unfamiliar with any of these objects,
you can always look them up on the Shopify liquid documentation.
I might show you that right now just as
a quick point of reference, Shopify liquid reference.
If you're ever confused about what attributes you have on a particular object,
you can just go into the reference, go down.
Look at variant is the one we're looking for,
and then you can see explanations of all these attributes
that I'm putting in to our Vue data.
I might just keep that one open just in case,
and let's go back and build in the rest option 2 and option 3.
Then I'm going to put in the variant price,
making sure to filter that through the money filter in Shopify liquid,
otherwise it's going to come out as sense with no formatting.
Next I'm going to grab the image for that variant,
and I'm going to add in an extra step here to check if the variant image is blank.
Because in Shopify, if the variant image is blank,
it still loads an image,
it's just the wrong image.
I'm going to create a variable here first,
and you'll see what I'm doing in just a second,
grab that image URL using all the filters available in Shopify liquid.
Again, check the reference if there's anything here that's confusing to you.
Then in here what I'm going to do for image is put in unless statement.
Unless image URL contains no image,
which is the image that comes up when there is no image set on that particular variant.
I'm going to output this image URL that I've set in this variable just above,
and there's no else statement there.
If it is, a no image,
is just going to show up as blank.
Sweep. Now, just on the issue of images,
what I'm also going to do is create a fallback image.
In case the variant doesn't have an image,
which is going to be a lot of instances,
I'm going to just use the featured image of the product.
I'm going to do fallback product image is going to be featured image,
which is a variable we've set up here.
I can take that featured image and then grab the URL of that featured image,
making sure we put that in quotations.
Now let's have a look inside our Vue DevTools,
make sure we haven't made any syntax errors.
Refresh over here.
Looks like we might have unexpected token.
Here we go, available.
I've typed in varian rather than variant.
Let's refresh the page.
No JavaScript errors, head over to Vue.
Here you can see we've got an array with all the variants and that data that was set up.
We've got our fallback product image.
We've got our current variant id.
We can use all of this information now within our Vue app.
We can bind it to elements on the page or we can use it in calculations.
Now there's actually just a little bit more data that I want to add here,
and that's to capture our selection here.
We're going to just above variants,
put in our variant selection,
and we're going to bind this to our form.
Make sure that the comma is in there.
This is just option 1 is going to equal
the selected value of our options with values, selected value.
Here what we're doing, if we go into the documentation,
we look at product.
There is an attribute here called options with values,
and it will return an array.
Inside the array will give you the values and the option name of all the options.
You have name and value here.
You can have a look at that particular object here.
Name, position, selected value, values.
We're using the selected value of the first product option in our products.
That's going to be option 1.
Make sure to put that in quotation marks there.
I'm just going to copy for the next two.
For this 1, 2, and 3,
we just need to update the position in the array and that should be all good.
Now let's go back over to our page here.
You can see we've now got our variant selection,
which is small and white.
We've got this variant selection here loaded into Vue on page load.
But what we don't have currently is data binding so that when this updates,
our data in the Vue instance updates as well.
Let's do that right now.
Let's go over to our code.
I'm going to drag this down because we don't need that so big.
What I'm going to do is bind these values to these selects right here.
As we can see here, we're looping through
the options with values attribute on the product,
which for each item in the array gives us the name of the product option,
the values that are available,
and the selected value.
We can use this logic to figure out what the current selection
is and create a select in order for the user to change that.
What we need to do is bind this value of the select to our data model here.
The way we can do that is by adding an attribute here of v-model.
We add this to the select because that's the one that's carrying the value.
Within here we can start at the root of the data object.
We're going to do variant.
Actually, it might be worthwhile to have this side by side.
You can see both sides.
Here's our data object right here.
Here is the HTML code.
We want to go into variant selection and pull off the relevant option.
I'm going to go variant underscore selection option.
Then what I'm going to do to select the particular number that I want is use
the attribute within this loop on the product option objects of position.
Product_option.position.
That's going to insert a number from one in here,
and that's going to link it up with this.
Now we've Vue model on our element.
We can go back to the page over here, refresh.
If I change one of these options,
you can see it updates in the data.
That's all well and good.
We are updating our variant selection.
But what we need to do is convert that variant selection into an actual variant.
We've got our list of variants here.
What we need to do is calculate what variant is
currently selected by the selection that we have stored here.
This is something we would need to do inside any Shopify store,
whether we're using Vue or not.
I won't spend too long going through it.
What we're going to do is create our first method though.
This is something new that we haven't covered yet,
is to add a method.
On our instance, we've got our data object here.
But let's create a method which is basically a function on our Vue instance.
How we do that is make sure we put a comma there and we define a methods object.
Inside the methods object,
we create our first method.
I'm going to call it variant from options.
Inside I'm going to look up the variant based on the variant options.
Where I'm going do this is I'm going to copy and paste some code,
and then I'm just going to explain them.
What I'm doing here is using the find method on this variants array to find a match.
When the variant option 1 equals the variant selection option 1,
then that's a match on that particular one.
We'll start checking to see if it's blank.
Because if it's blank, then we shouldn't even look for a match by
default is going to be true unless we come up against a false.
Then at the very end,
we're going to be returned with a match.
That's going to return the find method here.
What we're going to do with that value,
if I create a new line,
is update the current variant id to be equal to
the variant that's selected in this find statement and take the ID of that.
Now that we've created this method,
we still need to hook it up to our element on the page.
We're going to use a another attribute here in Vue.js,
starting with the @ symbol and then writing the event that we're looking for.
This is basically saying onchange.
Then onchange, we're going to run variant from options.
We've got the binding,
and then when we change it,
not only are we changing it here in our variant selection,
we're going to recalculate the current variant id from
our variant selection here, or here rather.
Refreshing the page.
I want you to notice over here.
In our Vue instance,
if I change the selection,
you'll see that our current variant gets recalculated.
If I select Medium black and I click "Add to Cart."
We should now see a medium black t-shirt being added to the cart.
Just going to run that Fetch command again to get rid of the cart.
Let's go back to the shop Tee product page.
That's all well and good now we've got our variant selection working.
But what happens if each of our variants has a different price,
a different sold out status,
a different variant image.
We want that to update on the page.
Also, there's a thing in Shopify where the variant id gets stored in the URL.
If you share that URL or refresh the page,
the same variant is selected,
so we need to add that as well.
The three areas that we're going to do is the variant image,
the variant price, and the history state in our URL.
Let's head back to our Vue app.
If we're going to actually find what the current variant image is,
the current variant price and the current variant ID is,
well, we already have the ID updating here.
We're going to need to understand which variant is currently
selected and grab that as an object from this variants array.
If I go back to the data inside Vue,
the only thing we have on the current variant is its ID.
That allows us to look up the variant,
but it doesn't actually allow us to access data attributes on the variant.
What we're going to do is use this to look up
the relevant variant object inside this array.
The way we're going to do that is via something called a computed property.
Computed properties exist in Vue.js because we don't want to
put functions and logic inside our HTML structure.
We just add an extra object here with our computed properties.
Then we can treat the computed property as if it
is a data attribute here and place it in our HTML.
What we're going to do inside our computed property,
we're going to create our own property called current variant.
You'll see this reflected in our Vue DevTools in just a moment.
Computed properties are basically just functions that return a value.
We're going to do return and then we're going to look
up the variant using the find method.
Variant, and all we need to look for is the variant id equal to this current variant id.
That should give us the relevant variant object from this array.
Let's go back here, refresh the page.
You'll see under data we've got computed now.
If we look in current variant,
you can see that we've got an object with the variant id,
the options, the image, the price.
If I go in here and change this,
then this will update.
If the price is different, that will update.
See here, the image will update if it is supposed to be updated.
This is all happening without us having to trigger
a method because a computed property is reactive.
If any of this changes,
then all the computed properties will be recomputed.
If we put it into a method,
then we would have to recompute explicitly.
That's the beauty of computed methods.
We can tie together data and have that be reactive as well.
Now that we have our current variant computed property,
we now have access to our current variants image and price.
Let's make sure our UI updates in response to that.
I'm going to go back here,
and I'm going to go up to,
let's do the price first.
I'm going to get rid of this,
and I'm going to add an attribute on the element itself, code V-HTML.
Anytime you see v dash,
that is most likely a Vue attribute.
I'm going to add V-HTML.
Inside V-HTML, I can put in the attribute that we're looking for.
It's going to be current_variants.price.
Then up here for the image,
I'm going to replace this.
I'm going to make this dynamic by putting the colon in front and then I'm
going to put in the current variant image.
Now, if the current variant doesn't have an image,
we're going to need to use the fallback.
I'm going to use the double pipe syntax here.
If this comes as false,
null, or undefined, I believe the list is,
then we're going to default to the value that comes next,
which is going to be fallback product image.
That's going to be very important on products that don't have any variant images set.
Let's go back to our front end here,
and let's change this to black.
As you can see, the variant image updates it's not particularly
smooth right now we're going to add a bit of a transition on that but as you can see,
when we update the color,
the variant image changes as well, changing that color.
If we update the size,
you can see that the price is changing.
As always, you can use the Vue-devtools tools to
check whether this lines up with the data,
which of course it does.
The third thing I wanted to bind is the history state,
which we're not updating currently.
That's important if you share this link with somebody,
or you refresh the page.
If I refresh now,
you'll see it just defaults to the first selection.
Let's create a method for updating history state as well.
Inside methods object after this variant from options method,
I'm going to create an update history state method.
I'm going to put in the argument of a variant,
and then here some code,
"If history replace state".
This is code I copied from
a previous theme because it's going to be the same
regardless of whether you're using view or not.
I'm just loading it into a view instance on this occasion.
I'll just type out the rest of the code and we can
talk about what it's doing in just a sec.
It's not essential that you 100 percent understand exactly what's going on here,
obviously it helps if you do,
but basically what we're doing here,
if there is no "history replace state",
and there is no "variant",
then we're just going to return.
But if there is, we're going to create a new URL.
We're going to take the protocol,
which will probably be HTTPS,
then add these two slashes, then the host,
then the pathname, then we're going to add in
this query parameter of variant equals and then pass in the variant ID.
Then we're going to update our Window history to the new URL.
Feel free to copy and paste this code.
All it's doing is updating the URL in a browser using JavaScript.
Now of course, it's not going to trigger without
us cooling it somewhere so what I want to
do after the variant has been calculated from these options,
I want to update the history state.
In order to trigger a method from the same instance,
we just do this.updatehistorystate,
and then we've got that variant object so we can just place that in there.
That'll find the variant ID from this object
and place it after this query parameter in our browser.
if I refresh the page over here,
let's select a different variant and see what happens.
Here you can see that our variant ID gets added or updated in our browser.
If I refresh the page,
I'll get the same selection.
Those are the three areas that we want to be reactive.
We want the price to react,
we want the product image to react,
and we want the history state to react.
That's basically it for our Vue instance.
The one thing I'm going to do before we move on is,
this does look a little bit glitchy.
I mean, it could be a better user experience so I'm going to use something that
comes standard in Vue, which is transitions.
If I go back to where that image is,
and then I'm going to wrap the image in a Vue element called transition,
I'm going to call it fade,
which will give it the fade transition,
and then copy that back in there.
There are two things we need in order to make this work.
One is we need the CSS.
What this is going to do is add some classes to this element while it's changing.
We need to actually put into our CSS what we want it to do when those classes are added.
I'll just show you where that is in our theme.
CSS, right here.
It's going to add and remove these classes.
We just need to define them in our CSS.
You can find it on the examples of what to do though on the Vue documentation.
If we go into "Transitions" "Enter & Leave",
you can see this is basically the exact same code
from the documentation so here is the reference.
The other thing we're going to need is,
we need to add a key to this element,
because Vue is not going to know that it's changed even though this SRC has changed.
It needs to know that the element has changed.
One way we can force it to understand that is by giving the element a key.
We're going to do :key,
and then we're going to make the key equal to the exact same as here in the SRC.
Now if I refresh the page,
and let's change this attribute,
you can see we've got this nice little fade between the different colors.
How good is that?
There you have it. We've got our products page here.
If I select any variant,
the price, the variant image,
and the variant ID in the URL is going to update alongside it,
or within a few milliseconds,
and it's going to save the current variant ID based on the selection.
When I click add to cart,
if I have selected a large red t-shirt,
it's going to add a large red t-shirt to my cart.
As you can see here though, this has no interactivity,
if I up the quantity,
it's not going to work, if I click the trash, it's not going to work.
These upsells down here aren't linked up.
If you're ready to jump into the next lesson,
we're actually going to connect this page up to Vue,
and Vue is going to handle all of these interactions and sync all of that data.
The cart page, of course,
is a great candidate for Vue.js.
In the next lesson, let's actually hook up this cart page.