In the last lesson, we hooked up the functionality for
the variant selection on the product page.
Now if you change this is going to change all of
the elements on the page that are linked to that selection.
Let's up the ante now and work on the cart page.
As you can see here,
there's quite a few possible interactions.
One, we should be able to update the quantity,
so we can add more T-shirts to our order,
add less T-shirts to our order,
we should be able to remove a line item from the cart,
clicking this trash button.
We should also be able to add any of these up
sells to the cart and have the cart live update.
In this lesson, that's what we're going to build using Vue.
We just refresh the page,
make sure everything is in sync.
Let's move on from our product template here and open up our cart template.
In this lesson, we're going to have to refactor
some of these loops that had been created in JavaScript,
because we'll be updating these lists using Vue.
It's going to be a lot more dynamic even more so
than what we did in the previous product template.
As we've done before, let's open up a script tag at the bottom of template file here,
and using the same convention,
I'm going to call this Vue app CartPage.
Then I'm going to put that object into a create Vue app method,
so Vue.createApp CartPage.mount,
and I'm going to mount it to the element which has the ID of CartPage.
Now, one of the biggest differences between this Vue instance in this template compared
to the product template is we're not going to use Shopify Liquid to load in the data.
The reason why is we have an API called the cart Ajax API that allows us
to use Ajax request to gather cart information and update the cart.
We actually don't need to use Shopify Liquid at all.
I think it might be worth mentioning that we could actually
use the Ajax API in our product template as well.
Instead of this where we're creating
the data objects using different Shopify Liquid tags,
what we could have done instead,
and I'll just paste in some code right now,
is instead of this right here,
just comment this out,
so it's not distracting,
instead what we could have done is started with an empty product object
and then brought in the product information via the Ajax API as well.
I opted against that,
and the reason why is because we want the objects that populate on page load,
this can cause additional problems,
if this is empty on page load and that gets loaded,
just makes it a little bit harder.
But this is an option as well on your product page app,
if you wanted to avoid using Shopify Liquid.
I'll just put this code back to where it was before.
Much the same concept as on the product page to the cart page,
we could load in the cart information using Shopify Liquid.
But in order to update the cart on the fly,
we're going to need to use the Ajax API as well.
What we're going to do is only work with the cart object via the Ajax API.
In this particular app,
we're not going to have to use Shopify Liquid.
That's a big difference.
As mentioned earlier in the class,
I expect that you understand a little bit about the Ajax API.
If you don't, there is a lesson that I'll link up
in the description from a previous Skillshare class of mine.
The Ajax API is a way for us to gather especially cart information via JavaScript.
We don't have to actually use Shopify liquid.
This is perfect for creating front end cart interactions,
which we're going to be doing right here using Vue.
Let's actually load in some cart data from the Ajax API right now.
Like I showed you before with the product object,
we're going to have to start with an empty data object or an empty cart object here.
We know that inside the cart object they're going to be items.
We can define a basic structure here,
but until the Ajax request comes back,
we can't actually populate this data yet.
We're just going to start with cart items as an empty array.
But what we're going to do on
the created lifecycle hook is update this object right here.
I just mentioned a new concept here, lifecycle hooks.
It's basically different parts of
the creation process and mounting process of a Vue instance,
we can trigger certain things.
Just like you would when you're writing,
say, jQuery or any other JavaScript,
you would wait for the page to load,
for the DOM to load in order to execute some JavaScript.
With Vue, we can plug into different what's called lifecycle methods.
Just a quick look-up of what this is.
If there is a search here,
lifecycle hooks, we've got beforeCreate,
created, beforeMount, mounted, beforeUpdate, updated.
But basically the main common ones are mounted and created.
What I'm going to do is as soon as the Vue instance has been created,
I want to trigger that Ajax request and update our cart object.
Let's actually go over to our cart page and let's
add in that lifecycle hook right after the data method there.
It's just a method on the root of the Vue instance,
so we'll say when the instance is created,
we're going to create a get request,
and this is using jQuery.
You should be familiar with this syntax.
We're using jQuery to hit the cart.js endpoint,
then we're going to pipe a.then, treat the response.
We're going to JSON parse the response,
so that's going to become a JavaScript object then.
Then we're going to take that JavaScript object which is going to be
our cart and then here we're going to set
the cart object in the data of
that instance to the cart object that is returned from the API.
If I go over here,
refresh and open Vue DevTools.
You can see that the cart object from the Ajax API is populating our.data now.
You can see so much information all from the cart Ajax API,
we have all of that information now inside our Vue instance.
If you ever want to check on
the Ajax API request as always you can go into the Network tab,
refreshing the page, here you should see it.
It should be one of the first ones there, cart.js.
You can see we're making this GET request status code 200.
It's all good. This is what comes back.
Awesome. We've now got our cart.
What we want to do is use our card object inside
Vue to render this part now rather than Shopify Liquid,
because we're going to be updating the cart based on if
we delete a product or we add a new product to the cart.
There's going to be products added and removed from this list on the fly,
and we don't want to have to wait for
Shopify Liquid to do a page load in order to update this table.
What I'm going to do is introduce some new things we haven't seen
before in this class which is a loop,
and some conditionals as well inside Vue.
As you can see here,
we've got if the number of items in
the cart is greater than zero then we want to loop through them and show them.
We don't want to do that with Shopify Liquid anymore.
Let's refactor this to use Vue.
What I'm going to do is get rid of that and use what's called a template tag.
A template tag is basically a tag that's not going to be rendered in Vue,
but it's just used for logic and loops.
I could do a div here and wrap this all in a div and then do my v-if,
but I don't want to actually render a div.
I'm just going to div-template,
and you'll see in just a second it won't render an item,
but it will render what's in here if the if-statement is true.
To put a conditional inside of our Vue HTML here,
we can use v-if,
and what I want to do is similar to how we just did it in Shopify Liquid.
I'm going to look at cart.items.length and check if it's greater than zero.
If so, we're going to loop through,
else, what I'm going to do, end that template,
create a new one for else,
and all you do is v-else,
and put in your cart is currently empty.
I'll get rid of that.
End if-statement there and refresh the page over here,
it should look the same.
But one thing you should notice actually is that when we refresh the page,
there's a slight glitch before it appears because we're
calculating whether it should show or not based on JavaScript.
There is a split second where the cart object is actually empty.
This is actually false for a split second before the cart information is loaded in,
and then this becomes true.
It's a bit glitchy, but we'll fix it up later in this lesson.
Now we want to replace this Shopify Liquid for loop with a Vue for loop.
For this we can just put the for loop directly on this element itself.
I'm going to get rid of the beginning-for and end-for.
Let's change the indenting here.
We can do v-for and what we can do here is for item in cart.items.
Let's see if we go into the issues doing that.
As you can see, we've got one position,
but this has, of course,
broken all of these because with our previous code
we created this item object inside our loop so that we could grab these attributes.
We're going to have to refactor that as well.
Going into here, I don't want the Shopify Liquid version of item title.
What I'm going to do instead v-html like we did before, and do item.title.
Using the information inside Vue for the image src,
let's just look at our data object here,
see the title coming across now.
It's go into our items. Have a look.
We've got this image here so we can just go get rid of that.
Put a colon in because it's a dynamic value and we're inserting
a variable here, item.image.
Let's see if that worked correctly.
Yeah. Then down here for item final line price,
we'll format this value in just a second,
but for now, let's just put in the explicit value.
We'll do item, line, price.
Double-check that that works.
Yeah. Again, it's in sense and it's not formatted,
but we'll fix that in just a second.
Then here inside value,
we want to fix that to the actual item quantity.
As always, if we're putting in a variable here, dynamic value,
we need to make that field dynamic by putting in that colon.
I think that's it.
There's no more Shopify Liquid inside here.
Let's get rid of some of this white space and bring in this indenting.
There we go. Actually here in the sidebar, we've got one.
We're just going to remove that v-html and instead of going into a specific item,
we're just going to do cart total price.
Upsell we've still got a Shopify Liquid loop here,
but we'll fix that in just a second.
I'm going to refresh over here,
and as you can see,
all this information is now coming from our Vue instance rather than Shopify Liquid.
Here it is still generated by Shopify Liquid but
we'll get to that after we work on fixing this quantity,
formatting the prices, and enabling
a user to remove a product from the cart using this icon.
First thing we're going to hook up this quantity selector so that it
actually updates the quantity of the line item in the cart.
For that, we're going to create a method,
it's similar to how we did on the product page when the select is changed,
we need to actually trigger a method on that event,
and in this case,
we're going to be submitting a Ajax request to the cart
Ajax API to update the card on the back-end.
Let's actually go after our created life-cycle hook here and create a method's object,
and inside let's create this update cart method.
Now the methods that I've created in this Vue instance,
or I'm going to create in this Vue instance based
of the different functions within the cart Ajax API.
We've got the main ones is get the cart,
add an item to the cart,
update quantities, and then here is change.
You can update quantities and properties as well.
You've also got Clear,
if you want to clear the cart,
we're not going to have a button for clearing the whole cart,
but we are going to trigger this API endpoint in order
to enable removing a line item from the cart or reducing its quantity.
Both are going to use the same end point and therefore the same method.
Going back to the code,
the two attributes that I'm going to be putting in here,
variant id and quantity.
That's based, of course of what we put through here.
We've got a variant id and the quantity,
and then we send that through in a update's object.
What I'm going to do id and quantity,
and then inside this method,
I'm going to start the post request using jQuery and
it's going to the cart update.js end point.
Next we'll put in the body of the request,
and for this, we can do it like this,
or we can do it as a string.
I think this is a little easier,
so I'm going to do it this way.
Essentially all we need to do is have updates in the square brackets,
put the variant id, and then equals followed by the quantity.
I'm just going to do that,
updates, and by the way,
these back ticks, if you're not familiar,
allow us to put these variables within
the string without having to exit and enter into the string over and over again.
With the back ticks set,
I'm going to put id with this syntax in there,
and then after the equals put the quantity.
Then we're going to chain a.then,
just like we've done with get cart,
take the response, JSON parse the response,
and then we're going to be returned to the cart object to which
we are going to set our own cart object equal to.
Now, note that not every AJAX request will return the cart object.
Some of them do return a single-line item,
but in this case,
the update.js endpoint does return the cart.
Same thing, obviously, for get cart,
with add to cart.
I believe it just returns the item.
We'll see that in just a sec when we build that into our upsells.
But for now, we can rely that the update.js cart
endpoint is going to give us back the cart.
Obviously, this is not going to run,
unless we attach it to our select.
So let's go on to that change method.
Just like we did with the product template,
I'm going to put inside this @change, update cut.
For the variant ID, we've got it set on the item.
There we go, variant ID.
Then the second argument,
the quantity is also sets on the item, it's just quantity.
Now, if we leave this like it is and then we go back here and we put this up,
you'll see it goes back to one,
and that's because we haven't set V-model here.
So just like we did on the Products page,
we need to change this to V-model to get that two-way data binding.
Now let's refresh the page and let's see if this works.
As you can see, when we put up the quantity,
we see the line price and the total price update.
Let's check all the individual parts are working.
It should be if it's getting that result,
but let me refresh our Network tab over here,
clear the Network tab, click this,
and you'll see that we are hitting that update.js endpoint.
It is coming back green.
There you can see what we're sending to it,
and here you can see what we get back.
It's a whole new cart object.
That, as we have set in our view,
is going to update this.
If I go into my items and I scroll down to where it has quantity.
Where is quantity? There it is.
If I click on this,
it'll take a second,
but then once it comes back from the API,
it'll update it on our view instance as well.
Shopify by default output prices like this, in cents,
with no formatting, so we're going to have to format it ourselves in JavaScript.
But if you remember, we included this shopify-money.js file,
and inside that shopify.money.js file,
we have this format money method on the Shopify object.
We're going to use that now.
What I'm going to do is create a new method so we can
use this at different points in our application.
Here is the methods object.
I'm going to carefully check where that ends,
and then before it ends,
I'm going to add in another method here called format prices.
Inside this method, there's two prices I want to update.
I want to update the line price and I want to update the total price.
Those are the two ones we can see in our UI here.
But I'm not actually going to update the values themselves,
I'm going to create a new value called formatted line price and formatted total price.
That way, we retain those old ones.
You can do it any way you want,
you can override them,
but I'm going to leave the original in place and just create a new one.
I'm going to create a loop here,
looping through the different items in our cart.
For each item, I'm going to create a new attribute, formatted line price,
which is going to be equal to the item line price,
but with a difference that we're running it through the Shopify format money method.
I'm going to wrap that in format money.
That's for the line item line price.
Then for the cart overall,
I'm going to create a new attribute, formatted total price,
and that's going to be equal, again,
to the result of Shopify format money (this.cart.total price).
Now, of course, we're not running this anywhere,
so let's run this after we set the cart.
There's two places where we do that.
I'm going to run it here after we update the cart,
and run it here when we first load the cart.
Now, refreshing the page,
you'll see that we've still got the same values here.
But if we go into our object here,
you can see that we've got a formatted line price,
and on the cart,
we should have a formatted total price.
What we have to do is go into our HTML and update those.
So instead of line price,
formatted line price, and instead of total price, formatted total price.
Then it'll use the formatted version rather than
the other version that comes directly from Shopify. There you go.
Now we've got our quantity selectors working,
and it is updating our line prices and total price.
Now, you may have noticed here that we're not really writing DRY code when we've got
this.cart equals cart and this.format prices two times duplicated.
What I'm going to do is move both of these
into a new method that I'm going to call set cart.
It's going to take a cart object and then it's going
to put that cart object into the cart and then format prices.
Instead of this, what I'm going to do is put this set cart,
and then we can do the same for update cart.
That just makes our code a little bit more DRY so we can recycle code.
There you go, it still works.
Now that we've got that update cart function
working and we're hitting the API successfully,
it should be pretty easy to enable this button to work.
All I'm going to do is create another method after format prices called remove from cart.
All this is going to take is a variant ID.
It doesn't need to know the quantity because the quantity is implied.
The quantity, of course, is going to be zero if we're removing it from the cart.
What I can do is just do this, update cart,
put in the ID, and then for the second argument,
the quantity, just put in zero.
Now we're going to link this up on the onclick event for this button.
I'm going to use that @ symbol syntax,
and write here, "Remove from cart item.variant ID.
Now let's check if that works.
Perfect. We have just removed an item from our cart.
If I go back to the T-shirt,
let's add in a small red T-shirt.
You'll see it's there. We can update the quantity,
we can remove it from the cart,
and it's all working.
That is our main functions within the cart table.
Let's take a short break,
and let's actually code up these upsells here.
We're going to add in another function here to add to cart,
as well as to update and remove items that are already in the cart.