Welcome to this bonus video on Vuex.
I wanted to cover this as a bonus in
this class as it's a concept in Vue that I've previously
utilized using Vue in
Shopify theme development and something that might be valuable for you to learn as well.
In this class so far, we've created two apps in our Shopify theme,
one for the product page and one for the cart page.
Currently, these are very separate.
They each carry their own data, properties,
and methods, and these are exclusive to each instance.
To share data between multiple instances and components in our Shopify theme,
we can utilize a library called Vuex.
If I look up Vuex online,
the first link is what is Vuex.
As it states here, Vuex is
a state management pattern and library for Vue.js applications.
It serves as a centralized store for all of the components in an application.
We've rules ensuring that the state can only be mutated in a predictable fashion.
Essentially, Vuex allows us to create a centralized store of
data that all Vue Instances and components can access.
Now, why would we need this specifically in Shopify theme development?
Well, there's one clear example and that is if we were to allow for
front-end cart interactions outside of this cart page.
For instance, one feature you might have noticed on a Shopify site before is a side cart.
Like on this store,
for instance, if we add a product to the cart here,
you'll see that we have a little interaction here.
We have some cart information here,
but we can also go to the actual cart page and see that same information.
If I was to add one of these upsells to the cart,
that is reflected in this side cart as well.
That means that data is shared between the side cart and the cart page.
It's basically coming from the same place,
it's coming from the cart object.
All of this needs to be in sync.
So how we can do this is via a Vuex store.
Now note whenever I refer to a Vuex store,
I'm referring to a centralized store of data,
not the Shopify store itself.
Sometimes it can get a little confusing talking about Vuex stores on Shopify stores.
Therefore, I'll make sure to refer to the Vuex store as the Vuex store or Vuex for short.
All right, so in this video, we're going to move the cart data and
methods into a new Vuex store.
Update our cart page,
and then I'll show you how we can use this new source of
truth to update other areas of our theme.
Sound good? Let's get started.
All right, so first thing we're going to do is include the script for Vuex.
All right, so I'm going to go back to this documentation at
vuex.vuejs.org, click on installation,
and what we're going to have to do is make sure that the version that we're
using is compatible with the version that we're using of Vue.
So in this class, we used Vue 3.
So if you are following along the same as this class and using Vue 3,
then you're going to have to use version four of Vuex.
So click on V4 right here,
switch over to that documentation,
go to installation, and I'm going to grab this CDN link of Vuex 4.
Copy that, head into our code.
In our theme.liquid after our Vue script tag,
I'm going to add in Vuex.
So just making sure that we're using Vuex version 4 if we're using Vue version 3.
So now that we've included the library for Vuex,
we can now create our Vuex store.
What I like to do is put it inside a snippet.
As you can see, this theme has no snippets right now.
So I'm going to actually create the snippets folder.
Inside the snippets folder,
I'm going to create a file called store.js.liquid.
We're not actually going to use liquid variables in here.
So an alternative could be to put it in theme.js,
or create a js file and assets and include it.
But this allows us to include it on specific pages using the include keyword,
which I'll show you in just a second.
So what we're going to do is let's do that straight away.
We're going to use it on the cart page.
So I'm going to make some room up here and let's include that snippet.
Include store.js.
We don't need the.liquid part because that's implied when we use include statements.
All right. So two parts to getting this all hooked up.
One, we're going to have to create a store here.
Then we're going to have to link up that store to the instances that are going to use it.
So I'm just going to use the standard convention here.
Let's not forget to open up our script tags because we are in a.liquid file.
The standard syntax and standard naming convention is to just call our store, store.
We can then use the create store method of the Vuex object like this.
Inside here we will create our Vuex store.
All of our options for the store will go right in here.
Before I do that, I just want to link it up in our Vue instance here.
What I'm going to do is change this to
a more appropriate name because it is the options object.
I'm going to rename this to cart page options,
cart page options, and then I'm going to store this in a variable.
So we're going to call this cart page.
So this will store the actual app now rather than the options.
Then what I'm going to do is mount
the cart page and add another step here for using our new Vuex store.
So what we do is do use and then we put in the variable name of our Vuex store,
which we just called store.
Ideally, we should only have one store for the whole website.
So it makes sense to call it store and then we can just include it like this.
I'm going to go back to the store here and just in my code editor,
change the language detection to HTML.
That'll get rid of those squiggly lines.
Actually, there's one more step and that's to go into our options
here and just make sure we add in store to the options.
Okay, this is the equivalent of store: store.
So we can just save some space and just put it in as store.
Then that now enables us to reference the store within this instance.
Okay, so what we're going to do is we're going to move
our cart data into our newly created store.
So I'm going to cut this.
I'm going to leave the upsells in there.
Inside our store, I'm going to create a state function.
Then just like we do when we're returning data inside a Vue instance,
I'm going to copy and paste this into our state here.
I think we can bring back some indenting here.
Yeah. All right.
Now, a little bit of Vuex theory.
We have some core concepts here.
State, which is basically data getters,
which allow us to access that data that we've just set on the store state.
Mutations, which are the only way to change data in a Vuex store.
So mutations mean anytime we change data.
Actions which we dispatch to commit mutations,
and then modules which we're not using in this lesson.
But essentially what we're going to do is we're going to use getters to get the data.
Then we're going to use actions and mutations to set the data.
Okay? Now, if you want to get in-depth about why we use
mutations and actions in order to change data and not just one or the other,
you can read about it here on the documentation.
I'm not going to go into the theory of actions and mutations in this particular video,
but all the information is there if you want to look into it.
All right, so let's go back to our store right here, our Vuex store.
Let's think about what mutations we might need to do.
Basically, the only mutation we need to do on here is to update the cart.
Remember every time we are changing the cart,
we're just getting a fresh cart object from the Ajax API and setting that new data.
Okay? So we only need one mutation.
You can choose whether to do this or not.
But I like to use the capital's convention when naming mutations.
So I'm going to open up a mutations object.
In here, I'm going to create a set cart mutation.
The first argument is going to be state.
This is standard when running mutations.
Then the next thing is going to be the payload,
which is going to be the cart.
So that's what we're going to pass in.
Then all we're going to do is do state cart equals cart.
Again, this might look a little bit redundant,
but there's some method to the madness with Vuex.
It's following a specific pattern.
Again, if you want to read more about this,
you can do so on the documentation.
But after we've created that mutation,
what I'm going to do is create some actions.
This is where we start to transfer some of
these asynchronous functions over from our cart page into our Vuex store.
But before that, I want to create
some working code and show you this is actually working.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to close down this and open this up in a split tab.
Let's get rid of all the other tabs here.
What we're going to do is refactor this,
move, some of this code over to here.
Now, the first thing that happens when we load the page,
of course, is we get the cart.
So let's recreate that using this Vuex store.
Okay? So what I'm going to do is before actions actually,
I'm going to open up a getters object here.
Here we can put our getters.
Again, this is going to look a little redundant.
Why can't we just access the state directly?
Again, there's theory behind it that you can look up on the documentation.
But how this works is in order to get to the cart object,
we need to write a function just like this,
and it's just going to return state.cart.
So in order to get that data from our Vuex store,
remember we already included the store up here,
we just need to create a new computed property
which just pulls that data from the Vuex store.
So all I'm going to do is replace
that cart object that we just removed with the computed property.
Here we go, I'm just going to call it cart and this is where
we bring in our Vuex store data,
I'm going to first reference store.state.cart.
Now of course, when you first load the page,
we're going to have this data.
So that's why on created,
we run get_cart, but now we're going to be doing it through Vuex.
What we're going to do is put this into an action.
So down here, I'm going to create an action called get_cart,
and from the first argument,
I'm going to pull off the commit method.
This is standard practice with actions,
and we don't have a payload here,
so that's all I need and then what I'm going to do is mimic the get_cart action here.
I'm going to grab all of this, bring it in,
and instead of running this set cart method,
I'm actually going to run
the set cart mutation and the term for that is called committing.
What we do here is instead of this we do store.commit,
then we put the name of the mutation set_cart,
and then as the second argument,
we put the payload in there,
which is what we get returned from the API.
Then that's going to set the value of the cart to what we get from the API.
Again, this is just pretty much exactly what we have over here.
We're just putting it into Vuex.
So on created instead of this.get_cart,
we're going to instead dispatch the action we have here.
So what I'm going to do is to store.dispatch get_cart.
Now, if we run this code now,
let's go back to our shopping cart,
open up our DevTools,
refresh the page; you'll see that when we go and look in here,
our cart table is there,
but it's currently set to display none.
You can see your cart is empty,
but it's not displaying as you can see here.
The reason why is because we've now lost that part of
the code here where we set cart and changed the loading to false.
So what we're going to have to do is get
this action to return a promise and then when that promise resolves,
then we're going to set loading back to false.
So what we need to do for this is here,
where the get requests start,
we need to just put return in front of it.
Then now we can put a dot then over here.
So when the get_cart action has finished dispatching,
finishes running, then we're going to set loading to false.
All right, now let's refresh the page,
and you can see now we've got that value coming up.
Now if we go to shop the T and we add,
let's say a small black t-shirt to the cart,
you'll see it shows up not from our cart data that's stored on the view instance,
but from a computed property of cart that is pulling from our store.
So we've got the beginnings of our refactor here,
and we can see that that's now pulling from our Vuex store.
Let's go back to the code and continue working on this.
So moving down in our filtered upsells,
I can see this.cart.
We're now using cart as a computed property, pulling this value,
so I'm going to replace this.cart with store.state.cart.
That's the first change,
and then as we go down,
we don't need get_cart anymore because that's now a Vuex action.
We are just going to check where we refer to that.
As you can see, we're using it in add to cart as well.
Let's just remove that and then we'll refactor add to cart when we get to it.
In set_cart, we're doing that through the mutation now,
so I can remove that,
but what I'm going to have to do is there's this extra step in here for format prices.
So let's move this logic out of here,
and let's put it into the actual mutation.
I'm going to remove format prices and inside this mutation here,
let's take the cart object that is submitted as the payload,
and let's update that before we put it into our state.
For that, all we have to do is just remove this dot
because we're now using the cart that's passed in, in this payload.
So this is going to create those new formatted line price,
and formatted total price,
and then insert it into state.cart.
All right, so back to the actions here.
Let's go further down.
We can get rid of set_cart now,
and we're going to have to create a new method
or a new action for this one right here, the update cart.
For this one, I'm going to assume that the only time we're updating cart we're
just doing it for one line item so we're going to keep this syntax.
So what I'm going to do is grab this asynchronous code here
and let's create a update cart method here and of course,
the first argument is going to be commit,
and then the second argument is going to be an object with
those same two arguments; ID and quantity.
Then inside we can do that post request and so that we can make it return a promise,
we put return in front of the Ajax request.
That of course allows us to chain a dot then on the dispatch like we've done over here.
Let's get rid of this code and of course,
this.set_cart needs to be replaced with store.commit set_cart,
and then in our update card method here,
all we have to do is trigger
this action or to use the Vuex terminology, dispatch the action.
So we do that from the store object, dispatch, update cart,
and then an object with the two parameters,
ID and quantity, and that's all we need to do.
Because in our update cart method we're just using that to
update quantity as you can see over here,
we don't need to update loading states therefore,
we don't need to chain a dot then on the end.
But for add_to_cart, we are going to definitely have to use promises.
In fact, we're going to have to chain some promises together.
I'll show you how we do that right now.
So after update_cart, we're going to put in add_to_cart,
and let's use the same syntax as before.
The first argument we're going to pull off
the commit method and then the payload is going to be ID.
Let's pull off this ajax request
into here as I did before so that we can
deal with the promise as it comes back from the action,
put a return in front of it,
and unfortunately the indenting is all wack here,
so let me just fix this quickly.
All right, that'll do.
Now to refactor this code,
we have to replace this method with another dispatch.
Then this we're going to deal with once the promise
comes back from Vuex into our instance.
Let's just remove that and we'll do that inside the instance a little later.
What I'm going to have to do to dispatch an action from within another action is
just to pull off the dispatch method right here on this object,
and so instead of this.get_cart,
I'm going to run dispatch get_cart,
and then that's all we need to do.
Because we're going to handle the promise inside our instance,
we don't need to do anything else after that in the Vuex store.
So let's do that right now.
Let's go into here, into add_to_cart,
and let's do our dispatch, store,
dispatch, add_to_cart with our payload of ID,
and then we can handle the promise like this and first update the loading state to false,
and then upsell, adding upsell, false.
It makes sense to update these loading states because this relates to
the UI that we're dealing with on the page itself,
so inside this particular instance,
but everything to do with the cart data should be centralized within this Vuex store.
Hopefully, that explains why we're handling some promises within
Vuex and some promises within the Vuex instance.
All these loading attributes had to do with the UI on the cart page itself,
not the cart data.
Finally, we've got this remove from cart method,
which is triggering this.update cart.
What I'm going to do here is replace
this update cart method with the update cart action on our Vuex store.
As we've seen before,
store_dispatch, same payload as before.
We just need to put it in an object form, ID and zero,
then we're going to set this dot loading to false after it comes back.
Let's see if that'll work.
I'm not sure whether the explicit value here is going to error.
Yeah.
As you can see, it doesn't like the zero there.
What I'm going to do is just do const quantity equals zero,
and then replace that with quantity.
Hit "Save" on that.
Refresh the page over here.
As you can see, we've got an error,
"Cannot read property total_price of undefined".
If I scroll up here,
you can see I've got a reference to this here.
Just need to remove that,
because we don't have access to this.
This of course, was referring to the Vue instance, the Vue app,
but now we're inside our cart,
so we just need to look at what we've passed in,
and the store object.
I'm going to fix that up,
refresh over here, and now we can see our black shirt coming through.
If I am to update the quantity here,
you can see despite the errors in our JavaScript console,
this is now working.
If I hit the trash can here,
it'll remove that product from the cart,
refreshing to show that this is legit.
If I hit "Add to cart" on one of these, it now works.
Now, all of this data is coming from our Vuex store.
If I go into here, unfortunately,
with this latest version of Vue DevTools,
I don't think we can actually look at the store itself,
there's is not a Vuex tab like there was
in the previous versions of you Vue DevTools but what we
can see is that we're getting the cart objects from computed rather than data here,
and that makes it clear to us that we're pulling
that cart object from somewhere else other than the instance.
If I remove that,
you'll see that that cart object is
updating in accordance with what is in the Vuex store.
Now, of course, what you see here is exactly the same as what we had before.
It might not be clear to you why this is any different or any better,
so I thought I might show you how we could use this new centralized point of
truth to interact with the cart on any other page on our Shopify website.
What I'm going to do is actually put the item count in our cart up here,
and have this live update when we add a new product to the cart,
currently we can only do it from the product page here.
Of course, we can do it on the cart page,
but we're already on the cart page,
so it doesn't really make a lot of sense to do so but perhaps we want
to add to the cart and there's to be feedback straight away without reloading the page.
Now, we can use that cart data to update something in our header to
indicate that we have added a product to the cart without having to go to the cart page.
I'll show you a little example of that right now.
What I'm going to do is create a Vue instance for the header,
and unfortunately, we don't have a section file for the header.
We could go and create that right now,
it wouldn't be too hard but let's just keep the code in our theme.liquid.
I'm going to close down this cart page here.
What I'm going to do is include the same snippet over here,
just above our header.
We're going to do include store.js,
and so now we're including that Vuex store in our theme layout file as well.
I'm also going to add an ID of header to
this element here so that we can clearly identify it in our Vue instance.
Then like we've done throughout this class,
I'm going to create a Vue instance underneath this HTML code here.
First, we're going to create a options objects, header options.
Let's just open up an empty object for now,
and then I'm going to create another variable that's
going to hold our app header, Vue.createApp,
insert those header options,
and then I'm going to mount that using the ID that we just added to the header,
and then I'm going to get that Vue instance to use the Vuex store.
Now, if I refresh the page over here,
we should see under here that we've got two apps.
You'll see that the information that we had here has now gone,
because it's sitting under App 1 over here.
Let me just see if I can zoom out and show you. Here we go.
As you can see, App 1 and App 2,
we haven't actually named them,
so it's a bit confusing.
Let's go in and actually do that right now.
I'm going to give this instance a name of "Header",
and let's go in and name our other instances in the cart page.
I'm going to put in a name into the "Options",
"Cart", and then "Product Page", "Name", "Products".
That's just going to give it a name in the Vue DevTools so we can easily identify it.
Let's go back, refresh, look at the DevTools,
and you can see we can switch between the Header app and the Product app here.
We're running two apps on the one page.
Of course, if we go to the cart page,
you'll see that we have Header and Cart on there as well.
Let's go back to the product page.
We can now switch between the different apps.
Let's add that cart data to the header.
So what I'm going to do is bring in that store,
and then like we've done for the Cart page,
I'm going to create a computed property that pulls the cart from the Vuex store.
This is going to be cart,
exactly like we've done in the Cart page, store.state.cart.
Then in order to populate that cart on page load,
what I'm going to do is tap into the lifecycle hook we've created,
and then in this lifecycle hook,
dispatch the get_cart action.
Let's refresh the page now with our DevTools open.
It looks like we've got an error, "Unexpected identifier, store".
That's because I forgot the comma here.
Let's "Save", "Refresh".
Go back to our Vue DevTools.
Yeah, we've got header and product.
If we click into the header,
we can see we've got our cart object coming from the Vuex store now.
How we can use this is we can now go into here,
let's create a span,
and inside here in the v-html,
we can add in the item count from our cart.
I'm going to do cart.item_count.
This is, of course an attribute on the cart object,
you can see here.
If I "Save", "Refresh" the page over here,
you can see that we've got one item in the cart.
Of course, we could have achieved the same result using
shopify.liquid but what we're going to do now is update the product page to
submit the variant ID through Vue rather than through the standard Shopify
means which ends up processing the "Add to cart" and moving you to the cart page.
As you can see here,
we've already got that interaction happening between the header and the cart page.
Just to complete this,
let's go back to the product page.
Let's go to the product page code, right here.
What we're going to do is right here,
add in an event handler,
we could actually remove this form completely
and just have a button that does this as well,
but let's just stick with the form for now and make it easier.
We're going to attach this to the submit event,
and as an extra modifier,
we can put in here called prevent,
and that's going to prevent the default submit functionality,
which is, of course, what we want.
In here, we can put a method that's going to handle the Add to Cart.
I'm just going to create that now.
Let's go down after the final method and create a handle_atc function.
All it's going to do is take the ID of the variant that needs to be added to the cart,
and we're just going to dispatch the "Add to cart" action with the payload of that ID.
Then we're going to go up here.
Where was it? Right here.
To handle_atc, and as the argument in that method,
we're going to put the current variant ID.
This makes the hidden fields a little bit redundant,
but it should still work.
Let's go over here,
refresh the page, and let's see what happens when we click "Add to cart".
You can now see that the page doesn't refresh,
but something did change.
The number in the cart updated.
We could add in other interactions like we could have
it pop up here saying, "Recently added",
we could still redirect to the cart,
we could have a side cart pop out like we saw earlier.
We could do all sorts of things but the point is,
we have now got synchronization of data between our header and our cart page.
As you can see, the number in our header is
updating when we update the items on our cart page,
even though they're in separate apps,
and the reason why is we're sharing data between them using Vuex.
That's a little bonus on Vuex for you guys.
If you are building a fully featured side cart while having a fully featured cart page,
then you're going to want to share data between them,
and Vuex is the go-to solution for doing this work in Vue.
I hope you learned something from this lesson.
If you want to incorporate a side cart and use Vuex in your class project,
I encourage you to do so.
I'll give you more details about
your class project in the final video that's coming up next.
Thanks for watching. I'll see you in that one.