Now let's talk about the second issue what happens when we add a liquid to miners mine a block almost
at the center of all this say at the same time.
Right.
Like that.
So now all of a sudden we've got we've got a conflict in the chain.
How is this conflict going to resolve.
So let's have a look.
This is this is really where the consensus protocol is like is it at its best.
This is very similar to the buys in time for Tolan's and we talked about before.
So by Byzantine Generals problem this is the bicentennial it's.
But this is very similar to the general's problem.
OK.
So what happens.
Well this this Noad this block is since it's correct we're going to assume that it's correct there's
no malicious intent or anything it's going to be propagated through a network.
So they're propagated or relayed through the network.
So there we go.
It got relayed to these nodes.
They checked the checks and they accepted this one could relate there.
And like when you got to come up with like our own example scenarios in our example scenario maybe the
connectivity here is faster.
So these got propagated first and then this one is maybe this like longer connection or something.
So by the time this one got there it is there is some stuff happening here and then this one got here.
So basically the connection was here was faster here and like the information spread here faster than
on this site so that just for the purposes for argument's sake of course in real locations this is much
much bigger it is like you know dozens like tens and hundreds of thousands of nodes and then you know
like when they far away by the time they like the conflict happens it's not like two versus four it's
it's a much bigger number.
But this still conveys the point will help us understand better.
So now what happens is this node and these nodes are trying to like tell the snow that they had this
orange walk.
But this note is saying to these guys no you add the purple Block.
And now here is the orange block at the orange block and he's saying no add the purple find it the connections
are gone through it so you can see we've got an issue and this is here you should.
You can probably tell that it's very similar to that Byzantine Generals problem where you got conflicting
messages going across the network.
So that's why we need bicentennial tolerance.
OK.
And so what happens what's the consensus protocol in blushes.
We remember with the generals their consensus protocol was to look at the average of what you were getting
the average of the messages that you're getting and then do that.
Right.
So you know like somebody saying attack somebody saying retreat and then and then decide from there
you know take not the average take like take the majority.
And look there is a majority.
Look at the majority of the messages that you're getting and then do the will change the concerns protocol
is different and brought in block chain what the nodes do is they're like OK that's fine.
So you've got a purple walk.
I've got an orange walk.
You know like OK we've got two versions of the chain right now so we've got competing chains.
What are we going to do is we're going to wait and we're going to wait until another block is added.
And once that block is added then we'll see which of the two chains is longer.
And so which change basically as a block for you guys or us and then whoever has a block first That's
chain wins.
So looks Shane's the term they're saying is the longest chain is king whichever chain has the most blocks
will eventually win and replace the chain.
And the key here is that the key here is that's the part of the network that has the highest hashing
power will eventually generate the longest chain and it's very easy to see in this example we can see
that here we've got four computers and you really have to.
And assuming they have the same hash and power for each computer.
So how has your power is basically how many hash it hashes can you check per second.
You know how many hashes can he check and how can they how many hashes can it check and check them you
know together they have a hash in power.
And how many hashes can each one of these check that hash are assuming they have the same hash power.
These guys have double the hash and power than these guys.
So the orange chain is double the hash and power that then the purple chain which means that statistically
speaking these guys have a twice as high chance of finding the next to of solving the cryptographic
puzzle first.
So solve solving their cryptographic puzzle because all her graphic puzzles are equal.
You just need to find the hash for block.
So these ones have a.
So each one is working on their own.
But if you add up the probabilities all together over all that even if they're you know trying to add
different blocks and so on.
You know like this one might have central actions or the search was actually that doesn't matter.
Overall statistically speaking this group of nodes has a high much higher or double chance of finding
a next block or finding the next block in their chain.
Whatever it is what is it like coming up with a block to add to their chain.
Because there's more hand-car.
These guys have a lesser chance.
And so what will happen statistically probabilistically is one of the computers in the the computers
in the orange chain.
Maybe just click here.
There we go.
One of the computers in the orange chain will come up with a block and then this block will be spread
across the network so bam bam bam.
I guess they're part of the network.
And then now is when this conflict will get resolved is now we can see that this these nodes Center
has a longer chain it's got two extra nodes this one only has one Laux this only has one extra block.
And so what will happen is these blocks will go to the side and the purple network will now adopt the
Orange network.
So the longest network is key.
And so right away the most important conclusion here is that in a block chain the consensus protocol
means that 50 of those who have 51 percent of the power or we just more than 50 percent of the power
that watch that chain will win.
So in watching I like the Byzantine Generals problem where Remember we talked about like you they cannot
come to a consensus even if this 30 percent malicious or like traitors here they will.
So in that case in that case they cannot come to a consensus.
They have to have like 70 plus on on the right on 70 plus non traders or 70 plus agreeing generals to
come to consensus you know block chain.
Its its better in a block chain.
You only need 51 percent and thats from what we just discussed that it basically goes down to probabilities
and hash and power.
So as long as you have more than 50 percent of the hashing power on one side agreeing more and more
than 50 percent of the power coming to a consensus the block chain will come to a consensus.
So as you can see the consensus protocol in a block chain is more powerful than the consensus per call
in the Byzantine Generals problem thats important to note that there you need 70 percent in blotching
you need 50 just over 50 percent in order to come to a consensus.
That's very that's a very important feature very important powerful thing of watches.
So where would we stop.
So yeah so this conflict gets resolved.
These blokes go to the side and these blocks you know are actually now called orphan blocks orphaned
blocks.
So to that there we go.
These are often orphan blocks.
And so unfortunately the the miner that mind this block in the first place there what happens is their
transaction Their them their reward is actually contained in that block it's in there it's not like
they got they got paid in cash all the transactions.
And we'll talk about this more in module two.
They're actually in the blotching So basically the reward won't be valid anymore.
Only this reward will be valid.
That and mine are gone.
And also the transactions that were in this block there are no longer valid.
So that's why it's important to block change to actually wait until a couple of blocks are added to
make sure that your transactions are have been accepted and then you know they're not going to be they're
not going to be they're not part of a competing chain that's going to lose.
So again we'll talk more about those things in module 2 of course.
But for now this is what happens this is how the consensus protocol works and that's it.
So of course after that the book chain goes to normal.
It is already a normal and you know new blocks are going to be mined.
It's going to continue growing.
So we've come to a consensus based.
And so there we go.
That sums it up.
Our saga across the different realms of block chain and we've discussed immutable Ledger distributed
P2P networks hash group chugger free mining and finally consensus protocol.
I really hope that now you have a good foundation you can see you can feel that you have a good foundation
of blog chains and you feel confident in going into don't know and debated a heated debate with where
people are talking about actions and you can maybe bring in the clarity and explain how things actually
work and also that you're confident in about going into the practical tutorials that are coming up very
very soon.
And to finish off today's tutorial additional reading this is really fun.
You can actually read Satoshi Okamoto as emails to people like how Phinny Charles Jackson read Dillinger
and James Donald and a couple of others so if you go to this website again this will be in the link
will be in the notes for the course.
If you go there you'll you'll be able to just go to the e-mails and click through and see what they
said and then the specific e-mail.
Which.
Yeah.
Which if you go to this link you'll go straight to this e-mail.
You'll see him talking about the Byzantine Generals problem.
He puts in a funny way through like hacking a wildfire.
But basically in the term in the term of boxing interesting short read and as promised the article about
block chain consensus Pericles is a short one and just gives a high level overview of what other consensus
Pericles exist out there for actions which can be also useful on that note thank you so much for being
here and going through these tutorials on a one block chain.
I look forward to see you back here next time.
And until then enjoy.