Well welcome back to the course on blockade.
And today we have an extra tutorial that I originally wanted to include in the mining difficulties of.
But then it became just too long and I didn't see it quite necessary So this is like a kind of bonus
topic if you will about how you can derive the current target how it's actually stored in the blocks
so you don't have to take this to trial.
There will be some calculations.
Not complex math but some tedious calculations and you might find interesting.
On the other hand you might find it not useful so feel free to skip this to trial.
But nevertheless I personally found this concept interesting and that's why I decided to record this.
All right so let's have a look.
We talked about this in the difficulty tutorial how difficult is related to Target to do that.
Is the current target divided by the max target.
And so here we can see oops we can see that the current target is.
Has that been adding zeros and or has that number over there.
And then the next target has that number there.
And that building is.
And so interestingly enough we're going to find out as well today why there's so many leadings or why
something like a proper number why that there's only like six digits here or you know four digits here
it's actually six zeros.
But yeah.
So why is there a proper number why is it like a truncated type of number.
So maybe it would be kind of like an extra piece of knowledge that we get from the.
It's going to be like a side conclusion.
The main thing that we're after the main thing we're after is where where is this target stored right
where is that store remember last time how we did it we just went through the blockade and examples
of the blocks to find the car.
So we just looked at the number of zeros in the blocks and we decided OK.
So it's 18 zeros.
But how do you get the exact value of the target.
So that's what we have today.
So whereas the current target is stored.
Well if we look at an example of a block you will see here it has a field called B it's it's called
that's all that's part of the information that store in the block.
And so there is no field called Target.
There's no actual hash target here but they do have this field called bits and that's nauts.
It's not the size or anything like megabits or kilobits is just it's just that is it's a code.
It's a code that store here and today we're going to learn how to read that code and how to from this
code get this number.
It's all legal to look completely different Yeah but at the same time that's exactly where it's stored.
So let's have a look how we're going to do this.
All right.
The first step is to take this value bits and turn it into a hexadecimal number.
So I was going to have to remember what it is here so is 3:9 to double 0 9 6 9 2.
All right so we're going to go to a hex calculator and we're going to go 3 9 2 0 6 9 2 3 9 2 0 9 6 9
2 0 9 6 9 to convert.
There is a hex number.
OK.
Copy it.
And well we don't really need to because this is a slide.
So there there's bits and there is are there there's a hex number.
So you can see exactly the same number as I got here.
So this is basically our bids and number in decimals in the decimal system.
This is in hex.
All right so you can see we're already getting close so you see the suspiciously similar thing here
5 9 9 7 9 0 5 D 9 7 DC 5 d and DC.
So we can already see that that's that's a component.
What about this first thing.
What do we do with that.
And that's all we have to find out here.
I saw this YouTube video on somebody explaining how to do this and it was so complex I got scared at
the start but it's actually not that hard.
So here we've got 17 what we need to do is that's in hexadecimal now we need to convert that those first
two teachers back to the desert is the answer because it's funny because we just got this number from
the decimal system we can read to the hexadecimal.
Now we need to convert this back into the decimal system.
All right so you do that.
How do you do that.
Well there are seven states the as a seven right.
Or.
Well basically it's you know if it was like an A or A B or C or so you just need to convert to what.
What that means.
Like in like a like a would be like it 10 B would be 11 and so on.
And and then and then here you gotta multiply whatever you see here by 16.
Right.
So again that's that's just the way this system works.
You is a hexadecimal system so that's a conversion conversion rate if you will into back into the normal
system.
That's what we get.
Sixteen times the number here plus just the number here itself.
But don't forget to convert them into decimals if they're like letters and so you get 23 so 17 or you
could just use another calculator 17 in the hexadecimal system is equal to 23 in the decimal system
and that makes sense right.
If you think about it like 10 in the hexadecimal is actually 16 in the decimal because that means this
digit was like 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15.
Then it went over to a 1 here which means it's got to 16 and then 0 1 2 0 0 7.
And so that means 16 that's 16 plus the 7 23.
And so then what that means is that will this number.
This is a code.
This is basically not just a number it's a code.
The first two digits represent the length of the resulting in the resulting number that we want in and
what is it in invites.
So that means our final number here that we're after is actually 20.
Or that means like that means our final number that we're going to be building is 23 bytes long.
Right.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to draw it 23 times to poor and to multiply by two.
So 46 hex digits.
Why are we drawing forty six so that's the length of our numbers.
So 23 bytes is actually 46 stitches.
Was that is because if we look at it like it and Hegge X hexadecimal digit takes up four takes of four
bits always because you know it's two to the power or power for 60.
So here you have two options times two times two times to two times two is four times two is eight times
to 16.
So a hexadecimal number takes up four bits.
And then if you take 23 bytes there's actually 23 times by 8 bits because a byte is 8 bits and that
means 23 times two times four bits.
And that is twenty three times two times a hex digit So four bits is a heggs digit.
So that means 23 times to 46 heggs dishes.
I know this is crazy amount of like annoying bits and bytes calculations but that's what it is that's
the justification while we're about multiplying by 2 to take this you convert from Hex to decimal multiply
by 2.
That's how long your number is going to be.
And then this is the most significant component of the number.
Meaning that this part needs to be put in there VAM put it in there that's it.
And so that's the number you can see that's exactly our number.
And what else we do is is going to add these leading zeros to make it to make it look like a 64 digit
hex number to make it look like a proper sixty four to five six hash boom add missing zeros which they
are 64 minus 46 of why 46 because we know that this is 46 long so 64 minus four to six 18 put the leading
zeros in.
Voila there we go that's our current target.
So again not compulsory this knowledge or to but if ever you need to derive the target or if you want
to do like some development work with blocks Shanes and develop applications and so on then you'll need
to like dig in and find out how the target store.
Like with Bitcoin you'll need to somehow get that number.
This will hopefully save you some time because the explanations I found on line there was just only
a few that got to the point quickly and yet.
So hopefully this makes sense.
And don't don't get don't get worried if this is like too much to handle these bits and bytes and so
on.
Just remember that the target is actually stored inside every single block but it's stored as this value
of this field called bits and it's actually stored like that because it's a code.
It saves space.
So instead of storing this whole number like that where you know every digit is actually four bits.
So as you can imagine that's you know that's quite a big number to store where as in you can just store
it as a code.
You can encode the length of the number of the first two digits and then you can call just the most
significant digits like that.
So the length of the number is encoded in bytes and everything else is derived from it.
OK.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed this Tauriel.
I look forward to seeing you back here on the next one.
And until then inject Lachance.