Hi everyone and welcome back.
For those of you who are not familiar with the stellar cryptocurrency we're going to be taking a look
at how stellar got started.
Some information related to how it works and the benefits of steller and the organization behind it.
So let's take a look at these stellar cryptocurrency stellar was released in 2014 as a de-centralized
payment network and protocol with its currency steller can also be referred to as Lumines or Emsellem
you will more than likely see it referred to as Lumines.
In 2014 the first Brazilian Bitcoin exchange Mercato Bitcoin announced it would be using the steller
network sometimes with steller.
You can get a little confusing so let's make this clear that in this area of the cryptocurrency steller
is the network made up of a distributed block chain ledger and database wherein refer to the coins as
Lumines or SLM since steller was released by the nonprofit stellar dark.
It seems to have that extra and added level of transparency so it's a nice benefit.
Stoller's goal is to expand access to the low cost financial services to fight poverty and maximise
individual potential and we can see from the steller or web site that they have made the following permanently
and publicly available.
This is related to transparency.
These include the details and mechanism of the various Looman distribution programs.
The aggregate number of individuals who have participated in the direct sign of program and number of
Lumines distributed details and progress of the partnerships program and steller Bill challenge details
and progress of the Bitcoin program and total Lumines held by the foundation.
This is just a awesome transparency list when we're working with crypto currencies.
You know does de-centralized applications.
The more information that we have either as developers or investors or just someone looking to get into
crypto currencies this information can be very useful if you're trying to predict or build models that
look at investments of these currencies.
Just think about the uses of this information and publicly available details related to Lumines.
So what are the key main points.
Of course we have to start and state that it's open source and as we have mentioned that steller is
hosted the stellar core.
It's hosted on get help and we can actually pull it up here and we can see the stellar core information
and documentation on get hub.
So if you get the chance scroll through take a look at the stellar core and the information related
to it is very useful if you want to understand more of the technical aspects and side of steller at
least the backbone of this steller network but jumping back in with its currency Lumines they have a
very low fee and the network actually has transactions that rival rebel since we mentioned Ripl.
We can see some similarities such as the fast transaction speed and they both aim to handle cross platform
transactions and micro-transactions and an interesting fact and why we probably see these similarities
is that steller was originally based on ripples protocol and more.
But with steller it's more open source and more decentralized and we can also see that the government
over the creation of Lumines is determined by a fixed protocol level rules.
The number of Lumines created agenesis was 100 billion and every year there is a 1 percent inflation
rate Neumann's cannot be generated arbitrarily by anyone and we can also see that since it is so open
source and de-centralized someone could actually theoretically push a proposal but it's very unlikely
to succeed or very unlikely that the validators on the network are unlikely to accept and ratify it.
So the chance of more of them is being created is very minimal.
If you want to explore that further you can visit the link here and we get take a quick look on how
it works this is put together by the stellar dot org.
And if you get the chance you can scroll through this further.
Let's take a quick look at it.
Does it provide some useful information for how stellar works.
So we can see this information.
It's very practical.
We could see that sending the transactions.
Remember it's aiming to handle those micro-transactions.
It's also targeting those financial services and sectors.
We can scroll through and see that is similar to other crypto currencies and centralized applications
and block chain algorithms that it's made up of a network of servers containing our data.
The steller network decentralise and spread throughout many locations that power the distributed Ledger
recording every transaction in the system and any entity can run our server.
Remember this is very open source.
And if you scroll through it just has some other remaining useful information related to the ledgers
and transferring money issuing credit.
Acting like a virtual wallet.
And we can see steller since it's distributed exchange the Lumines you can actually send euro credits
to your friend using your U.S. dollar credit balance.
This is that area similar to ripple where it's facilitating the ease of currency changes.
I think that's something to pay attention to in the near future.
All right.
To wrap it up Lumines ateliers currents are in competition with other currencies such as Ripl for becoming
partners with banks and other financial institutions due to this.
It makes loon's a necessary cryptocurrency to keep an eye on for the near future.
And we could see that the prominence of it and that financial institutions are taking on Lumines and
utilizing this network within their services.
Because recently IBM announced that they were launching a block chain banking across multiple countries
with Stoler.
So keep that in mind if you're looking to get into crypto currencies if you're looking to invest or
are looking to build or contribute to the network trying to work with steller that the financial sector
is definitely one of the main targets again similar to ripple ripple and steller with their currencies
are very prominent within these financial institutions because it still States the ease of use of transfer
and currencies of these transactions along with this beat.
All right I hope that you're more familiar with stellar as always if you have any questions please feel
free to share them in the Q&amp;A.
Keep this cryptocurrency on your radar for the next few years.
Let's see how it's performing how it's moving and what changes are made if any changes are made to the
network.
Always visit the cellar dot or the nonprofit Web site that released the stellar network and enjoy cryptocurrency.