Hello and welcome back to the course on blotching.
And today we've got another exciting tutorial ahead.
We're talking about how minors pick their transactions.
All right let's get straight into it.
OK so here we've got a minor.
As usual we're just used to illustrating minors with laptops.
This has got to be minor.
And so how does a minor get the list of transactions that actually goes into Here goes into this field.
All right so we we kind of know all the rest.
And we've been using that transaction that those fake transactions that I made up of the other coins
but in reality where do these transactions come from.
So that's what we're going to be sorting out today.
Well the transactions they come from something called a meme pool or a memory pool which is attached
to every node every miner.
And basically these are all the Aankhen from transactions that they get stored here before they get
included in a ball inside a block.
So blocks are added about every 10 minutes.
But transactions happen all the time.
So you know I can send some bitcoins now I can receive some bitcoins we're going to we don't have to
wait until every 10 minutes to do that we can do that all the time so all those transactions get put
into a meme pool.
In the meantime it's like a staging area for transactions.
We'll talk more about the meme pool in an upcoming tutorial further down the track and we'll understand
how it works exactly in more detail.
But for now that's sufficient information for us or a minor or every node has a memory attached to them
where there is a list of transactions that are still pending.
Like a staging area.
And so the miner will need to include some of these transactions in the block and let's say a miner
has a maximum for you know for argument's sake that there's a maximum of five transaction that they
can include in the real blotching world.
There's a different limit.
The limit is one megabyte and then Hoven transactions fit in there and that's about two thousand transactions
superball.
But for our purposes we'll just say that a minor can include max five transactions.
OK.
So how is the Myer going to pick these transactions.
Well if we look at them we can see like there's a transaction ID which is much longer in real life but
and then there's some more information usually.
But here you can see that there's the fees the fees that the miner will get for including each one of
these transactions and fees.
Well again that's another topic will cover further down the course.
But for now we need to know that fees are non-compulsory and they're specified by the users themselves
whoever sends the Bitcoins like for instance I send them because I can say I'm going to I'm going to
send this I'm on.
But and this is the fee I'm going to pay.
And then say you it's absolutely arbitrary absolutely up to you can put a 0 if you can put a high if
you can put any type of fee.
But the miners they actually get these fees so if the miners are successful in creating this block then
he's going to get the fees that are attached.
So he's obviously going to pick the highest fees so this one is you can see it's the highest part of
all of them than this one.
This one this one and this one.
So there you go.
There we go.
Those are the five to actually the highest fees.
That's the first choice or the minor like all else all other things equal which they are.
Why would the miners use anything else if you can change five transactions.
So you're going to put them in said look OK.
And so that's how these two are where the subjects and the cover.
And now as promised previously we're going to return to our Non's problem.
Our non-SS challenge which we or issue which we identified in the previous to Turo.
Let's let's have a quick reminder of what that challenge was.
So we established that the nonces a number between 0 and 4 billion.
It's an integer and that's the range where we can pick the nods from.
And so we have a times then we identify in the first term then we also have a timestamp in our block.
And so now if we're going to set off the timer and if in one second the minor doesn't get to the end
of the non-SS then everything is great everything is totally fine because he's gone through a lot of
different numbers.
A lot of different integers have all generated their own hashes and he's checked them you know probably
he's most likely not found a a valid hash that would make this block valid.
He hasn't found the goal.
A golden loans and therefore one second has passed.
What happens next is the time stamp gets updated by one second and he can go through these dances again.
Right.
So let's see how he does that goes again bam another second and again.
So basically that's the reusability of the loans because of the time stamps.
Simply because the minor is not fast enough to go through four billion nonces within one second.
And that's that's a that's a good up.
If you're one minor but if you're a pool of minors or if you are a minor who's got a lot of processing
power that you can go through so much more than four billion hashes in one second.
Right.
So as we saw previously the total hashing rate a total hash rate of the natural combined right now is
22 million trillion hashes per second million trillion.
You know and this is only 4 billion.
So they're definitely going to go through and you know obviously that's a whole network so a pool that
says let's say has 10 percent of the network would be 2 million.
Still that is way more than 4 billion.
And so they would go through the nose like it's like nothing like very quickly no time.
And so the challenge or the issue that we identified how what architecture in the network allows such
big players to not have idle capacity.
Right because if if they go through the non-SS.
Right so let's have a look at an example right.
So let's say they're extremely fast and bam they went through the non-SS whole thing in less than a
second like that.
So what do they do now.
They still have they still out and are much like more than half a second left of time or like 0.7 or
0.6 of a second six tenths of a second left.
What are they going to do with this capacity.
Do they really have to wait until this number of dates.
Because there's no point of them going through the non-SS again if they go through the notes again.
What happens is we're remember because nothing else has changed in this block because of that we know
that the shot 256 Hadash or for that matter any hash has this cryptographic property that it is deterministic
that you put in and if you put it this way if you have the same inputs you will always get the same
outputs and there's no point in going through this again.
Well the solution or the architectural design from this slide will be that that begs the question what
can we do.
What is architectural build solution in the protocol of bitcoin that allows us to overcome the challenge
and for even minors we have a lot of power to participate.
Are mining pools to work properly.
So the solution from this slide we kind of started with this solution.
So the solution is to change the block configuration because remember at the very start of this Toral
we were picking the transactions based on the highest fees.
So we put the transactions in here the miner gets to choose the transactions they put and they put the
highest fees.
But if you put the high transactions with the highest fees and you went through the whole Montse in
less than a second and you haven't found that yet valid a valid hash.
Then what.
What else have you got to do but to change the configuration of the block.
That's exactly what the miner will do.
So let's have a look at that.
So the mirror will say let's look at the transaction of the lowest fee out of the ones I've picked which
is the one that has the lowest fee.
This one it's only 0.0 as are zero for less than that all other transactions and the ones that are fake.
So I'm going to take it out of my choice.
I'm going to remove it and now I'm going to pick the next transaction with the next highest fee which
is this one and I'm going to put it into my blog configuration.
There we go.
And so now because a bloke I figure she has changed the data inside the block has changed and we noticed
that the time stamp hasn't changed but the data has changed in said look.
And so the the.
So that means that we can now reuse the high reaches the lawns and every single month's number.
Overall this will be different and therefore will have a different hash.
Right.
So there we go.
Now we can just watch this whole thing again.
Bam as you can see he the miner again went through the whole lawns and again the whole time here.
We look at the total time is this in a second.
And again he still hasn't found the cash.
So what happens now.
Same thing change what configuration.
All right let's identify transaction of the lowest fees.
This one which we just included like throw it away and find the one with the next highest fees.
OK this one.
All right.
Good.
Put it in put it into the block.
Wonderful.
And now the minor of goes off again.
And as you can see now is now we've reached one second.
All of that.
Well we've been talking for like five minutes and all of that was actually one second in the world of
mining and the miner hasn't finished this non-SS wasn't able to even finish his dance again.
Hasn't found the cash.
But now what happens.
Finally a relief the second time stamp gets updated to announce a new a new second and that means everything
here has changed and that means we can start all over again.
And what does that mean.
Means this timer gets reset.
Can you start from zero and as well.
Let's not forget we can now get rid of this transaction of this fee and put in that high value transaction
again back in.
OK.
And there we go.
There's our new transaction back in the block and there we go.
So basically now we're starting the whole thing afresh.
So that's how Minder's big transactions and that's how mining pools or large miners there's just any
minor saw algorithmically solves the problem.
So they Bourne's those here.
Number one is all of this happens algorithmically all of the minor doesn't sit there because transaction
out would be impossible because you only have one second for that to happen and you're doing like two
or the pool is doing like two trillion million trillion transactions.
So all of this is encoded in the algorithms that govern how people are mining.
And that's that's part of the service.
So like if it's let's say if it's an independent minor that is not part of a pool then for some reason
doing it or like somebody with a very powerful computer then that's they need to come up with that algorithm.
Is if you join a pool then that's part of the service that the pool provides.
So when you redirect your hashing power into a pool you don't need to think about this.
Remember this is one of the things we talked about the advantages of a pool that they get rid of the
headache the miners don't you know they take away the headache from the miners.
So you'd lose your day you're bound to minute pool.
They will allocate you the right transactions that you need to be working.
And so a pool knows that they have a cup of water I don't know thousand ten thousands hundred thousand
miners in there and they know that.
OK.
The algorithm already knows how to allocate the transaction there.
And remember there's not only like whatever we have here five 11 transactions in the whole pool.
Is usually like 7000 transactions so they know the algorithm automatically combines the transactions
in the best possible way in order to get the maximize the fees.
But also in order for the miners not to duplicate their work for different miners in the pool or to
do good work it's a very smart algorithm.
And so it allocates the work to the miners it allocates the transaction fees allocates the nuances and
so on.
And the miners then just like the churn away and churn away turn away and eventually somebody finds
that golden lawns or the finds of Allagash.
And so that's point number two.
And point number three is as you can see from here and this is something we'll be talking about further
and of course if you specify very low seeing your transaction like a zero something it is likely to
get stuck in the pool like no miner will ever use it.
Maybe by accident sometime not X and like through this process of distribution by the algorithm it might
use utilization might need to like switch over but because it has such a variety it has like 7000 transaction
to choose from.
They usually start like you know from the high seas they have like a threshold they don't even look
at transactions below a certain threshold for their allocation.
And then what happens is your action will be released back to you.
I think the new standard right now is within 72 hours if it's not picked up by any minor then it'll
be released back to you.
So it's also like your wallet will usually help you identify what the current fees average current average
fees are and what you need to import in order for a transaction not to get stuck in them.
So that's just another thing to know.
OK.
So that's how this is big transactions.
Now we know there's actually a couple of things that change in the blog.
So the timestamp changes the non-SS is something we can control and the actual fees.
Finally we've uncovered the really how we can control the fees that transactions how we can control
the transactions inside the block in order to all of these things influence a hash.
OK.
And so that's that.
Let's have a look at some charts again.