Highs and welcome to the demo of module 3 create a smart contract in this demo we're going to be an
investor who wants to buy some coins to do so.
We're going to set up a Mithraeum wallet on my wallet the website that I showed you in the first story
of this module and also on this get her page where we got our my Isa wallet folder.
So we're going to set up this will that we also have opened to interact with the block chain because
you know each time we sign the transaction Well the transaction will be added to a block and we will
see that happening in real time in cash.
So we'll do all this.
And so now the first step that we're going to do is open again.
And therefore I prepared everything here and especially I prepared my list of programs to find cash.
So open first is opening right now.
And here we go.
Welcome to get us some green too and watch this so that we can all see very well.
And there we go.
So we're going to do in cash is pretty simple.
We'll choose one of these addresses you know each row here corresponds to an address to which you can
connect and you have a virtual balance of 100 ether and you'll see that each time we sign a transaction
or a block we'll spend very little amount of ether.
This is all virtual Of course.
Right now we are on current like zero meaning that we have in mind any block.
But first important information that we must see is this one the address of the server where she is
found.
So you recognize the local host here.
One hundred twenty seven point zero point zero upon one exactly like the one we used in Postman.
But then we have a different port.
It's no longer five thousand five thousand one.
We're going to use the port seven thousand five hundred forty five.
OK so remember this because we will enter it in my wallet and then I can just walk you through the important
stuff like here we have all the plugs you'll see.
So far we have the Genesis block but then each time we sign a transaction the transaction will be added
to a new block and we'll see the new blocks appear here and then we have the transactions here we'll
be able to have all the details of the transactions we sign right here in this page.
And also you have the lugs but we won't be needing this waiting for requests.
Yes the requests are coming.
All right.
So let's go back to our clowns.
Let's use an account.
We're going to choose.
Well anyone you want.
I'm going to choose the first one.
That is the account of index zero.
All right.
So that's your first step and ganache and now we're going to move on to my wallet and go to my wallet.
Well we can either you know go back to Google because in the first Soyo this module Well we opened my
wallet from our local computer using you know remember if you go to your chain it is that folder and
then Mudgal 3 create a smart contract.
Well remember we went inside this folder and we double clicked on this index HVM L and that redirected
us to my word.
So you can do that again.
If you closed this page and there we are in my wallet remember we had all the warnings that were useful
to check out.
And now we're ready to start.
And so the first step is right in the center of this page.
We're going to create a new wallet a new eatery and wallet and to do this well we're going to create
a brand new one and to create a brand new one you go to this dropdown this year and you're going to
add a custom network node at the bottom of this dropdown.
So just click on this add custom network node.
Let's do this.
And here we go.
So set up your custom notes.
Basically we're just setting up a virtual custom node.
And as you can already guess here we are going to enter the U R L at the local host which is this 127
point 0.0 upon one and here of course we're going to enter the port of Ganesh which remember is seven
thousand five hundred forty five.
OK.
So let's do this first.
We're going to enter a node name.
So what can we call this.
Well whatever you want you can call this by your name you can call it by at coin ICAO wherever you want.
Well in fact that's a pretty good idea.
Let's call this ad Quoin.
I see you.
All right.
CONAN So then the u r l is.
So we can if you won't go back to gannets then copy this without the port because the port is entered
separately.
So let's go back to my wallet and let's face that right here and there you are.
All right.
That's right you are well and now the port.
We can go back to Ghana to make sure we have the right one.
Seven thousand five hundred and forty five.
Let's go back to my wallet and let's face the port here.
All right.
And then you don't need to see like this an ether of course.
That's the theory that if you read classic we're going to use ECM.
That's one of the best blocking technologies.
Let's go for it and let's save and use our network note plug chain note.
All right you are successfully connected.
Great start so far.
OK so we are getting close to the ICU now.
We are going to go here to contract up contracts.
Let's click on this.
And there we go.
We have the choice between interacting with our contracts or deploy our contract.
So according to you what do we need to start with.
Well of course we need to deploy the contract first because so far we have just simply implemented the
contract insipidity.
But we haven't deployed anything yet.
So we're going to deploy it now and to do this well we need to enter the byte code here which we will
get in solidity and then you'll see this the gas limit the gas by the way is a unit of some money you
spend.
You'll see when we sign a transaction or complete some actions like buying some coins basically an action
that is in the small contract.
So this will automatically be populated and then we'll select a private key.
But first let's start with the byte code and to get the bite code well we need to go back to our program
remix solidity.
That's our program and to get the bytecode of this program we need to go here to details.
All right.
And here we have all the details of our solidity implementation.
And as you can see the bytecode is right here.
So that's about code basically But we can copy it.
The efficient way by clicking on this is the copy value to clipboard.
So just click on this copy.
Perfect.
And now let's go back to my wallet and let's paste the bytecode right here.
But in this bytecode we're only going to include the number inside the object you know from here excluding
the double quote down to the very end of this very large string which is the byte code.
So here and pressing shift and I'm clicking to select all this and that's exactly what we want so I
can just copy it then select everything and then delete everything and then pasting it again.
So that's exactly what you want.
That's the bytecode we need here and there you go you have to guess limit automatically populated.
Okay perfect.
Next up how would you like to access your wallet.
Well of course it's going to be with a private key.
By the way you can see you can use adjacent fell to access your wallet.
So if you're interested in doing that you will have no problem understanding how it works.
Since you now know what a file looks like but here we're going to use a private key and there we go.
That's where we enter the private key.
And now of course the question is Where are we going to get our private key.
Well according to you where is it going to be exactly is it going to be in my wallet.
Is it going to be in solidity or is it going to be.
Well I'm going to tell you now it's going to be in gas.
That's where we're going to get our key and that's where we have to choose one of these addresses.
So as I told you I'm choosing this address.
But feel free to choose any other one and to get the key.
Well I think it's pretty obvious now.
The key is right here on the key so click on Shoki is here and there we go.
Welcome to our private key.
That's our private key.
So let's keep this let's get a copy done.
And now let's go back to my wallet to paste the private key.
All right.
Now next step is just to click on unlock because we now have everything we have to bytecode we have
the private key.
So we're ready to unlock the wallet that is now successfully decrypted and not only we were ready to
unlock this but now we are ready to sign the transaction.
Congratulations guys you're about to sign your very first transaction through my contract.
Let's do this let's click on some transaction and there we go.
Now we are ready to deploy the contract.
However depending on the version of Guinness you're using you might have a little issue here.
If we go to Ghana.
There we go.
That's the issue I'm talking about cash encountered in there.
Help us fixing it by raising good habitue.
So no worries about this.
The trick to solve this is just to relaunch Nashe.
So just click on this relaunch button and Ghana will be relaunching and expanding it again.
OK.
And right now the only thing that you have to do is go back to my wallet and since actually the transaction
is already signed as we can see here with the bytecode.
Well we are ready to deploy the contract and once we do this you will see the transaction will appear
on the finish.
All right let's do this let's deploy the contract warning you we're about to deploy a contract well
they will have warnings but they're right.
But yes we are sure we want to make the transaction happen.
And there we go your transaction has been broadcast to the network.
And now if we go back to Ken Nash Well what do we see what are the two things interesting to see here.
Well first the tax count here was incremental to 1.
That's our transaction.
And second we spent 2 cents of ether to make this transaction happen.
That is to sign this transaction and to deploy the contract.
So that was quite cheap when either at the time I'm speaking is around $1000 I think and therefore 2
cents of ether is like $20.
Okay.
So that's the price for deploying a contract that's very cheap because indeed it's much cheaper than
the classic contracted you and a classic deal and saving all these costs is one of the pillars of this
theory and Blache and revolution.
And now by the way there is another interesting thing to see.
It's the current block that you can see was incremented to one.
And so now what we can check out is delux here.
We see our new blocks.
That was just the block number zero which we already had.
And now we have the black one which contains our recent transaction that we signed right before deploying
the contract.
And if we click on this block Well we have some more details.
We have to get used to guest limit.
We have the time stamp when it was mine so exactly like what we implemented on bison and Mudgal 1 and
2.
We have to plug hash also.
And if we click on this well we have even more data on the transaction.
We have the sender address to created contract address which we'll use very soon you'll see and we see
that this transaction was integrated in block number one that was mind to receive this transaction.
And that's the bytecode of the transaction.
As you can see here transaction data this can also be accessed by clicking on transactions that search
and the action that we just signed.
And again if we click on this we obtain the same data.
All right.
Perfect.
So pretty user friendly.
And so now what we're going to do is since our contract you know you know we have to realize that now
our smart contract is integrated to the block chain.
Well it is time to interact with it.
You know we deployed it and remember in my wallet we also have the option to interact with the contract.
But we can only do that of course after deployment and now we can do this.
And it's actually right now that the fun starts.
So speaking of the contract address which I just mentioned you know in cash.
This one right here created a contract address.
Well that's the first thing we were asked to put in my wallet when we want to interact with the contract.
So in Ghana let's just copy this address here.
The created contract address.
Copy this contract address.
And now let's go back to my wallet and paste it right here.
All right good.
We have the contract address and now we need to enter the FBI or Jason interface.
So where are we going to get this.
Well this time it's not going to be in cash.
It can be of course in solidity remakes because if you remember just below the byte codes we got to
deploy the contract now to interact with the contract.
We need the API which we can also copy by just clicking on this button.
So that's what I just did.
Now let's go back to my wallet and let's paste the API right here and now we have nothing to select
specifically in this API.
We're ready to click on access.
But before we do this let me tell you a few words about this.
AB What is it exactly.
Well that's just basically the code that will explain to my wallet which actions can be run and how
we can run them.
So by actions I mean you know to buy some at coins to sell some coins to have a look at the equity in
dollars or at coins all this is coded in this FBI.
And basically thanks to it we'll be able to run these actions.
OK.
So no need to go through this and for the details.
Now we're going to access this.
So I just clicked on it.
And now breaking news.
We are ready to buy some odd coins.
As you can see I have to select a function dropdown.
And what do we see.
We see all our functions.
Not only our functions but also the variables you know that can be updated like the equity in USD or
this one which gives us the equity in at coins and we have these other actions that just run some actions
like buying some ad coins or selling some coins.
All right so now we can just play.
Do whatever you want.
Let's start maybe by making sure that the maximum number of coins is 1 million.
You know we are the very first investor to buy the coins but let's check that out.
I'm selecting this next at coin.
And there we go we have indeed the one million ad coins available for us.
So that's awesome.
And now since we know they're here let's buy some odd coins.
So I'm going to select the buy at coin's function.
Well action now let's input remember the two arguments of our function.
Let's have a look again of our function so just closing the details here.
Remember the buy at Queen's function had two arguments.
First the address of the investor and second the amount of money you want to spend to buy whatever amount
of coins we want.
So that's the first two arguments and that's exactly what we have to import here.
So let's start with investor dress how to get this address.
Well of course to get it we need to go back to get Nash.
And here is the address sender address That's our address.
Let's copy this.
Or by the way this address is also the same in the accounts we chose which is this one.
You know this row of index 0.
Well here indeed you can find the exact same address.
All right so again it's the same any way.
And now let's go back to my wallet.
Let's put our address here the investor address.
And now let's choose which amount of coins you want to buy.
Well I want to buy.
Let's say let's see ten dollars of at coins.
That's not much.
But that will give me ten thousand at coins because remember the rate USD coin is 1000 and therefore
$10 of that coin is worth ten thousand at coins.
So that's pretty cool.
Let's get these coins now and to get them we need to click on right here.
Warning again.
There we go.
They really love warnings.
Yes limit.
We're all good that's way below the maximum limit.
And now let's generate the transaction by just clicking on general transaction.
All right.
The transaction is signed.
And to really make this happen well we need to click on.
Yes I am sure.
Make transaction.
And there we go.
The transaction has been broadcasting the network.
Let's check this out on cash.
And here it is transaction count was again incremented by one and we can see either in the blocks it
was integrated to block to a new transaction here one transaction we can click on the block if you want.
And here is the transaction we can click on this again to have even more details.
Here we go.
That's our dressed investor dress.
That's the contract address which we entered before and there we go that's the transaction data.
And if we go back to accounts well the balance hasn't changed.
Okay.
And again you can use this shortcut by clicking directly on transactions to see the transaction.
That's this one.
The ones on the top are the most recent ones.
All right.
So there we go.
That's our first transaction now let's go back to my wallet and let's see what our equity has become
and to check that out.
We need to click on the job done that here and well first let's check out the equity in USD.
All right.
So again we need to put the investor address because indeed in our equity in us the function well there
is one argument which is exactly this investor dress.
So let's get it back in cash.
That's exactly this one.
Let's copy this and now let's go back to my wallet here it is let's put the investor address and let's
read to check out how much does we have in the platform while this interface where we invest the money
to buy some at coins.
And indeed since we just invested $10 to buy 10000 at coins well here that's our equity in dollars.
We have $10 invested but now this check out that the equity in at coin's is indeed 10000 at Goines because
$10 is 10000 at coins.
So here I am inputting again our address the address of the investor.
And when we click on read well indeed we have 10000 Atco it's perfect.
Our actions or functions seem to be working very well.
Now let's check out the other tools.
So just for fun let's just check out the tool at coin's but and indeed since I'm the only investor playing
with this I see so well of course only 10000 cons were but.
And that's the exact same coins I just bought.
So that's all good.
And now let's just for fun buy some more coins.
Let's imagine that coins is becoming hype and therefore now instead of investing $10 we want to invest
$100.
Let's see what happens.
So you click on right and warning again generate transaction.
Yes I'm sure make transaction transaction broadcast we can check very quickly in accounts.
Yes incremental is three.
And we have three blocks.
All good.
And when we go back to here now let's check our equity in let's say at coin's read and there we go we
have one hundred and ten thousand at coin's congratulations.
We are now starting to have a lot of Atuona.
And we can check also our equity in dollars read $110 and now just for fun that say that you know the
coins actually turn out to not be that good or just you know we want to get some money back.
Well let's try to sell some coins.
That's the action we haven't tried yet.
So sell at coins now we need to input the investor address again.
So there was already copied.
And now let's see what number of at Cone's you want to sell back.
So let's see.
Remember we have one hundred and ten thousand at coin's let's say we want to sell 50 thousand at coin's
right 50000.
Let's see what happens.
I'm clicking on right now.
Let's generate the transaction.
Yes we are sure make transaction and there we go the transaction has been broadcasting network.
All good.
We can check that again.
Well here it is in black for just mind and can actually check the balance.
All good for transactions now.
Congratulations.
And now let's check out the equity and at coin's to see if it was well updated.
So let's click on equity at coin's Let's read this.
And there we go 110000 minus the 50000 at constat which is sold is indeed equal to sixty thousand at
Cone's.
Perfect.
Everything seems to be working very well.
Let's just finish by getting the equity in USD which should be equal to 60000 divided by 1000.
That is $60 and indeed $60.
So guys congratulations.
We made this happen.
We have a successful smart contract so there we go.
I think that's the end of the journey.
I was so happy to say this course.
I had a lot of fun.
I hope you liked it too.
So I guess I'll see you for our next course as we have a very exciting year ahead of us in 2018 and
we're truly excited to provide some great content about these new techs.
You know a black chain.
We even want to combine the two.
We'll do this for you.
Thank you so much again for your support and I'll see you very soon in some new course.
Until then and Joe bludgeons.