Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will install JWT and configure it, first of all, let's talk about
a little bit of JWT, JWT.
So, Jason, the token is used for authorization, not authentication.
JWT starts after authentication.
When I say authentication, you have a username and password and you are logging in with these credentials.
But authorization is actually making sure that the user that sent the request to your server is the
same user that actually logged in during the authentication process.
We use JWT instead of, say, ID in default sipping security user session ID for authorization.
After login authentication, the client uses a some that token to reach and to access the servers.
Then the server identifies and validates it with a token menu, then operations on like that.
Now we will start to implement it to implement it.
First of all, we will add the dependency of JWT to build cradle.
We can find dependencies from the Melbourne one repository prior to the J.
W.T. version tab.
Both the API and the implementation were packaged as a single Artec, but version nine will be enough
for us so we can go on with it.
And we refreshed, ready to receive dependencies.
OK, now our JWT dependencies are ready, now we will configure JWT properties first property of it,
Beilby, Jason, their token Segretti.
This property is arbitrary field.
This will be used token encryption.
We can describe it like app JWT, that sekret, and for now we can give a random things for it.
Our other property will be expiration time, this time means expiration time of the JWT token, our
token will be valid for Monday.
After that, we should refresh it.
Of course, here we can give the value as milliseconds.
OK, that's all about Jason Tokens installation.
Thank you.