Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will configures environmental variables for the production, so from
now on we will start to prepare our application for production.
We can create environmental variables in England with different profiles.
But these variables are hard coded variables.
With Anglet, we can store those information in an environment that testifies, but we need to commit
them in the repository.
And again, this is not what we want because if there are variables are sensitive data, we could not
push them to the repository or these items can be changeable items over time.
So we need to supply them with custom environmental variables.
On Hiroku A.W. s or other platforms, we can describe custom environmental variables easily.
These custom variables are generally sensitive variables or volatile variables.
So I mean, we couldn't push them in hardcoded format on our repositories.
At this point.
We can access these environmental variables with process, start and prefix.
What does that mean if we are using clode systems like Hiroku, A.W., etc. to build our application,
we can usually set those environments information directly in the system settings.
We can access the system variables from that end config files.
So process that env is used to reach the system variables.
Engelhard is built with Engler's Cianni, which is a node application, but we are not able to access
process that n directly from within the application during that delts process as it is not processed
as a node application.
We won't have access to process environment at compile time of the angular code.
So to do it, we should treat that end file somehow and we should override our environment variables
on the of time to do it.
We have two important ANTM packets.
One is the dart and the library.
It is used to create environmental variables.
The other one is F.
S.
It has used to write the five.
Our steps will go on like that.
First of all, we will read the system and environment variables.
Then we will set them according to our profile, development or production.
Finally, we will write them to our angular environment files.
Now we can implement it.
First of all, I'll install the dart and library because I'll read environmental variables from the
dart end file or system variables with dots and package.
Then I hit enter and my parents will be installed.
Then I'll carry the fire to set the environment variables from system variables, I can create a fire
like set the ash and not just under the project.
This will be your.
First of all, I'll import the file system, plus I'll use it to write my environmental variables to
angular environment that specifies.
Secondly, I'd import the dust and glass, I'll use it to rate environment variables from the dust and
fly or system variables with that end to read environments variables I should call the conflict methods
of the dot and class.
From now on, I can reach environmental variables.
Now I'll check the node environment, whether it is production or not.
I assume that the not environment will be served as a system variable.
Then if the not environment is in production mode, I'll change the environment, that product under
the environment's focus.
Otherwise, I'll update the environment, satisfied to describe the pad and use the relative pat.
And we will access our environment variables in the process, that environment object thanks to that
and and we will all the content of the environment, that tesfai here we have only two variables.
One is production.
Other one is bais.
You are production variable will be a billion radio and we have already found it.
Secondly, we will get the base water from the system variables so we can reach it with the process
that an object.
Finally, we will overwrite the environment, that tesfai to write it, we have right file function
that comes from filesystem class, right file function expects three arguments.
One is Target Patts, the other one is Cantante of the file.
The last one is the callback function.
If we get an error, we can throw the exception and we can write it to the council.
OK, now our script is ready, now we can create a script comment for it to call it effectively in real
time to create a script comment, we can use the package that Jason Suntai here.
We have scripts.
These scripts are predefined commands for the NPM package, for example.
Then the Cold and TPIMs third comment, it will trigger the end user comment.
Or when we call the NPM Beeld comment, it will trigger the MGB comment.
For example, let's see the AMPM start comment.
First of all, I stop my application, then I'll call it.
When I call it and comment will be called and we can access the application from the Bronx.
So we can describe AMPM comments on package that Jason like this now I'll create a comment for setting
the environmental variables.
For example, we can create a comment like Quantic in context comment.
I'll call my comment, but not just so our comment will be not set.
That environment that Jess.
OK, now our comment is really I can call it like ampm config, but first of all, I should create some
system variables.
I can create it from the console like export, not environment equals production.
So value cheapish.
So I can describe it like export variable name ECLSS variable value.
Or I can create that environment file under the project.
Then I can create my variables line by line.
For example, we need a variable like base urate so I can describe it in that environment.
FYI, if I have other variable like that, I can describe it also.
OK, now I can call the AMPM config comment, this comment.
All right.
The environment that brought that tesfai with system variables because I set the not environment as
production.
OK, it looks perfect.
That's all for this lesson in next lessons I included into the build process.
That's all.
Thank you.