Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will talk about Cypriote request porra simply provides a request invitation
for rest Abia.
We can use recurse para to extract created parameters, form parameters and even Hye's from the requests.
Let's check it for an example.
For example, if we have an example and XPoint like API example that takes a query parameter called
Idy, we can send a request like API example.
IDG equals Idemitsu.
These requests invoke our example methods with the extract that I'd really like one, two or three,
four.
In spring we can also specify the query variable name query default value and declared a state of good
in default.
The query variable uses the same name with the parameter name, but we can customize it with the request
per name.
Property in spring methods, parameters annotated with request param are required by default, but request
permission optional.
Also, we can set the required property of request parameter to force to make it optional.
Finally, we can give a default value for a request.
If we don't send it as per the default value, it will be used by method.
We will see the details of it on our project.
That's all for the beginning.
Thank you.