Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement the authentication service in lessons we prepared our
authentication backbone.
From now on, we will use this backbone and we will use it for our signing operations.
Actually, in this lesson, we will implement this in method to sign in.
We will have that username and password.
Then using these credentials, we will carry that JWT token.
Let's implement it.
First of all, we will create an identification service interface class and authentication service implementation
class under the service package.
Authentication service will implement the authentication service interface class.
Authentication service will be a sibling service class, so it will be a business logic class.
Then we have this sign in Madrid, it will take the user as a parameter and they turn JWT token as a
response here is important.
We want to convert from user info to the authentication object also then the automated ID Sebring security
should also be avail of it to handle it.
We will use the authentication manager.
Authentication manager is the bridge between user and sibling security.
Now we can implement it, first of all, we will inject authentication, Manege We can use Ultralight
to inject it.
Then we have this sign in Madrid, it will take the user as a parameter and they turn JWT token as a
response.
Then we will authenticate the user with username and password.
Here is important.
We want to convert from user info to the authentication object also then be accommodated.
Sibling security should also be avail of its sibling.
Security has a specific provider class for credentials.
That is username password authentication token here.
When we authenticate it, we will handle an automatically object.
Actually, the authentication manager will call the load by username method from user data service.
If you remember it, we implemented it on custom user data service.
So our authentication object will contain the user principle object.
To reach this user principle object, we can use the authentication principle method.
Finally, we will return JWT from the use of principle object.
Actually, we already have this method on JWT provider, so we can call it easily.
Firstly, we will inject it.
Then we will call the General Tolkan Matt.
OK, now JWT token is really we will serve it with the user object to do it, we can add a field to
the user class, then we can serve it from the user.
Let's open the user class and let's add a token field.
Token field should be transient so it won't be a persistent field.
So it won't be stored on the database.
It will be used only as on the floor instances.
Now we can call it from authentication service as a result.
Like I said before, we describe the user instance on user principle, not to call it twice from the
database.
So now it still makes sense.
Then they will set the token venue for the user and we will return it.
OK, that's OK, thank you.