Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create Hiroku configuration on our project, we need three different
configurations on Anglet.
These are EBP Jason Profile and build script on APJ so we can describe the Herock at properties like
name of app resources of app, Beeld Package, etc..
Actually, we can describe how our app will be built in the profile.
We can declare process types.
We can have multiple modules like work or web, etc..
In the Beeld script, we should describe how Hiroku will build our application.
OK, now let's start with the app.
AJ Sandfire.
It has some basic configuration settings like name, deal, type environments, variables, etc. We
can describe them under app that JSON on our project.
First of all, let's create an app JSON file under the project at a JSON will be adjacent object.
Our first property will be the name.
And then we will describe the attack we will use not Aegeus as a built back.
OK, these properties will be enough for beginning here.
We can give more details about it, but we can handle all properties from the Hiroku interface easily.
Awesome.
Now we will create the profile for Hiroku.
Hiroku apps include a profile that specifies the comments that are executed by the app on Startup.
Actually, in this file we can describe how our application will run and will serve.
If you remember it, we already describe it in the previous listen.
So we describe an express server and we describe it as a NPM script and our script name is Start Now.
We will create a profile and we will call this comment from that in the Heroku.
We can work with different resources if we have different modules.
But this is not for English or not English application.
We will have a single web server and we will serve our application as a resource.
Then we will call the AMPM Start comment.
Finally, we will describe the heroic build secret, we will describe it under the package that Jason
gets here, we will create a build script and the script will show how Hiroku will build our application.
Actually, he expects a specific comment for it.
And this comment is Hiroku Post built.
When we commit our quote to Heroku Hiroku, we'll search for this comment and we'll use it as Beeld
comment.
We need two things to build our application.
First of all, we should set environments from system variables.
Then we can build our application with the angular saola.
We already described both of them in the previous lessons.
Our first comment is config to call it in AMPM.
We can write a comment like ampm rom config.
And the second comment is built prot to call it in the AMPM, we can write a comment like AMPM Ron built
Prot, OK, now our configurations are ready.
When we commit our courts to Hiroku Hiroku, we'll compile and deploy our courts in this order.
First of all, Hiroku will install all AMPM peckerwoods with NPM install, so not modules will be ready
before the built operation.
Secondly, Hiroku will set system variables and custom environment variables.
One of the system variables is not an environment.
It will set it to the production.
Then if we have other custom environment variables, Hiroku will also serve them as environment variables.
Thirdly, Hiroku will call the Hiroku Velt comment and build the application.
Finally, Heroku will serve our application with the AMPM Ronstadt like we described in the profi.
That's all.
Thank you.