Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement an authentication route guard class, route guards help
us to prevent users from accessing a certain part of the application without proper authorization.
In addition, route cards are used to secure the routes.
We can think of it on an easy example.
For example, if we want to show some pates for some users that has some specific rules.
For example, we have an admin page.
We want to show this page for only admin users to provide it, we will benefit from angular guard.
There are several types of cards so we can implement it in different ways, can activate checks to see
if a user can visit a route, which means, for example, we have an admin page, we can add admin role
restrictions on this path with can activate.
And only if the user has admin role, these path can be activated.
Second guard type is canActivateChild,  canActivateChild checks if the user can access the route's children
a pad can have multiple segments.
For example, we can think of a path like user's idea of user details.
For this example, we can create access restriction for main path.
So I mean, for our example, it is users also.
We can create access restriction for us children.
So I mean, for our example, it can users select idea of users or users, select idea of users details
to restrict these routes.
Children we can use can activate child guard.
So if we need to run a guard, then only the child round changes we need to use can activate child. Third gurad
type is canLoad.
It is directly related with lazy loading, so actually the name of it comes from there.
So we can protect a lot of components with the can load ga type canLoad protects the route completely.
If you are going on with lazy load you can use it.
Another guard type is canDeactivate.
It is related to the activity of the page so canDeactivate.
Makes sure that I use it is really sure that he is exiting the route.
For example, I assume that we have a page like EDIT and the user made some changes on the page that
he tried to leave from the page or he tried to get away from the lot.
In this case, we can stop or warn the user with an alert and prompt thanks to can deactivate guard.
And we can say that, hey, are you sure you want to leave this particular out so I can deactivate provides
this kind of guard for us.
OK, now we can implement it and let's see an example of it.
In our case, we can create cards with the end comment to create a card component.
We will use ng generate guard and guard-name.
Our guard name can be authentication.
And we can create it under the guards folder when we try to create it, ng presents guard types, which
interfaces would you like to implement here?
We can implement, can activate.
We don't have a child, right.
So we don't need it.
We don't have editing or similar pages, so we don't need constructor.
It also can load is related to laser loading.
We don't have it lazy loading guard also.
Then I'll hit.
enter the authentication guard is an angular route guard that's used to prevent unauthorized users from accessing
restricted routes.
In our case, we will implement one type of it.
It is can activate to implement it, we will use the authentication card, plus when we look at the
credit card class, we will see an important decorator's that is injectable.
The injectable decorator specifies that angular can use this glass in the dependency injection system.
The metadata provided in the root means that the authentication guuard is visible throughout the application.
First of all, we need the current user object because I want to restrict paths according to user rules.
So we need to reach the role of user.
Then we can inject our services on the constructor.
First of all, we will use authentication service to get the current user.
Secondly, we need ratas service because according to restriction, we will need to navigate to not
phonte or unauthorized or login page.
In this constructor, we will set the current user from the authentication service and we should get
current user from the authentication service as observable, because whenever it's really a change on
the old guard, we want to catch it.
It is observable.
So to get it, we should listen to it with the subscribe function.
And this subscribe function will be triggered when there is a change on the current user inside it,
we will set the common data to our current user variable, then we will overwrite the ten activate method.
But first of all, let's talk about how we can implement it.
First of all, can activate card will work for users that are signed in.
So if the result has can activate restriction and not sign in, then he will be redirected.
Login page.
Secondly, the user can be signed in, but the result is special to some rules and the user might not
have this specific role.
In that case, we will display the unauthorized page because the user tries to access the unauthorized
page.
So the architecture will be like that.
Each year old will have a role attribute that describes which rules can access the road and can activate
it, will work under the hood and catch tense, then checks the access rights of the route and checks
the current user role with the route role.
If the rules match for current user and role, this may not otherwise show the unauthorized page.
OK, now we can implement it.
First of all, let's check current user.
If the user is available, there are ten to activate it, otherwise it cannot be displayed.
So if the road has connectivity restriction and not signed in, then he will be redirected to the login
page.
Then I'll check the roll restriction.
But first of all, I should add rule restrictions on routes.
So first of all, we need to know which page can be seen by each role.
So first of all, we should describe them on the approaching module for each brought.
Let's open the app routing module, then we can describe roles for each relative login register and
home rotters will be public so everybody can reach them.
So we don't need the guard.
Then the provider can be accessible by authenticated users that have admin or user roles.
So to describe it, we should add, can activate property as authentication.
guard also we should describe rules with data rules property.
By the way, the rules field will be an error like we see in our case.
The admin roles should be accessible by authenticated users that have the admin role, so to describe
it, we should add, can activate property as authentication guard.
Also, we should describe rules with data rules, property here, we describe the data format like this,
then we will reach it from the authentication guard glass.
Also like this error, our public pates so everybody can reach them so we don't need to guard that them.
OK, now we can return to authentication, but then we can hook up with these routes.
In the can activate method.
We will check the role of the current user according to route roles, if the user is not authorized
to display the route, then redirect it to unauthorized for hundreds.
One page.
And return as unauthorized force, which means this user has no access to see this page, otherwise
return to the.
OK, that's all about what you've got now let's reload the changes on the browser, then we can test
it.
First of all, when we try to access the admin or profile page with the not signing user, we shall
see the login page.
Secondly, if they log in the application with the user at all, then then accessed the admin that we
should get an unauthorized error.
Thirdly, we can check it for the admin role, it can access all rot's.
OK, everything looks perfect.
That's all.
Thank you.