Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will talk about HTTP and observables in angular.
You know that we have a server side or backend code and it provides the data with API and points.
So somehow we should reach these Web server API and we should fetch these API data.
Now we will try to figure it out so we have our application that runs on the browser.
In our application, we display some content like product lists or booklist to find and fill these lists.
We need an extra layer.
This extra layer is services.
Services are injectable components in angular.
So Angular can use these glasses in the dependency injection system under the hood as service is basically
a class which can be used by multiple components.
We can use a service for multiple purposes, for example, to outsource some court which you want to
use in multiple components.
Or we will do here to manage our data in one global place where than multiple pieces or spots in our
application have access to it.
So this is how we can use such a service.
But here we want to use it to fetch data from server.
We can do it with HTTP calls.
First of all, to use HTTP in angular, angular provides http client module with using this module.
We can use HTTP methods, headers, contents programs so we can use HTTP requests to fetch data from the
server and we can use the different methods to fetch data.
For example, we can use post to get requests, put requests, delete requests, etc. We can write our
HTTP requests and these requests hit the Web server API and points on the server side when I say end
point.
Of course we will have an API, URL and API method to reach the Web server API.
Then these requests will be processed on the server server can fetch the data from the database or it
can provide it as hardcode and send it back as an HTTP response.
The response we get back from the HTTP call is observable and these observable objects are listened to
by the service injectors.
And this process goes on like that.
The important thing here is observable.
Let's see what the observable is.
Observable is a wrapper around some data source and data source typically means a stream of values because
observable are a concept that we use for asynchronous data observables.
We have asynchronized data and these data is processed over time.
Observables can be listened to by the observers.
These observers can be one or multiple.
These observers subscribe to the observables.
Observers can catch three states of the observables.
These are next, errors and complete functions.
Next function is fired whenever we receive any value error event is triggered.
If an error occurs in observable and if the observer reports that it is done, then we can catch the
complete state.
If we think about the API and points, it will take a while to complete the data and there can be errors
while fetching the data from the server side.
But at the end of it, we need that done state because for example, we can show a loading part while
fetching, then the down state we can dismiss it.
So observables going like that, that's all for the beginning.
Thank you.