Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will start to implement the spring security late spring.
Security is a framework used for securing spring applications.
It stands between client and application and gives the possibility of configuring what data and functionalities
are exposed to which users.
Also, it handles common vulnerabilities.
It's a huge topic.
And in this lesson we are going to explain the process of basic authentication in sibling security.
Sibling security works with HTP filters.
These filters catch the coming requests and extract the credentials from HTTP headers.
We we can say the authentication filter for these HTP filters authentication filter creates an ID object
that contains credentials from request.
Then it sends that object to the authentication manager to choose the appropriate authentication provider.
There are different authentication strategies and for each strategy there is an appropriate authentication
provider.
Each provider needs to get user from the system and to check its credentials like as it expired or is
password, Carex, etc..
We can use different types of authentication providers in separate security or we can combine them.
Only part that is different between providers is how it finds users.
That part is extracted in class user details, service in load by username, load by username method
which returns to user details.
Object user details.
Object contains data about user and account.
Abboud's like is account expired, logged or enabled, are credentials nonexperts, etc..
It takes like these methods the account which authentication provider needs for authentication.
If authentication is successful, the authentication object with the principle is returned to the authentication
filter, which will set principle to security context.
Security context is associated with the current threat, and it provides principle for further authorization
of requests in the case that authentication fails, court rules and authentication exception, which
goes back to the filter so it can be caj or shown to the users.
One of the previous lessons we described the password encoded in this lesson.
We will describe user details service to LAUT Users by username in spring security default.
User service is user data service.
These user service, these users details.
Service is an obstacle class so we can override it to do it.
First of all, let's create a new package like security.
Then we will create a new class under the security package.
Our class name will be Custom User Details Service.
Custom user details service will implement user details, service and custom user details service will
be a spring service.
We have an override method for user data service.
This matter is law, the user by user name in this method, we will find our user according to the user
name from our user service.
So we will need the user service injection in the service later.
We will authorize these user according to user role in the method.
First of all, we will call the find by username method from our user service.
If the user is no return user username, not found exception or otherwise authorized user according
to user or.
Sibling security provides specific clauses to describe authority, these are granted authority and simple
granted authority clauses.
Granted, authority is an abstract class, so it's an interface and simple.
Granted authority is an implementation class for granted authority.
Now we will create our authority according to the user at all, but we will use this conversion in different
methods also so we can create it as a util method to do it.
Let's create a new package as it will.
Under the new tool package, we will create a class like security utils.
In this class, we will create util methods to use on security classes and methods.
Now we will create a method to convert from use user role to authority, but there is an important thing
here.
Role religion should be the start role prefix for sibling security.
So we should add the role prefix to authority if it does not exist to do it.
First of all, let's create and role constant, then we will create our formatted role.
Finally, we will Creedon authority object from the pharmacist's wrath.
OK, now we can call it from custom user details, service users can have multiple roles, so supreme
security is designed for that.
So here we will have a set of authorities.
Then they will return it bit security, user encapsulation with username, password and authorities
here, user details, service, it turns the user details object user details object contains details
of the user like username password, but that is also an abstract class.
Separate also provides a security user object to handle this problem.
Or they can create custom user details object.
Let's create a custom user.
Details object to the Girardet.
Clearly our class name can be user principal.
User principle will implement user details.
Let's implement all of the methods that come from the user details class.
Then we want to store the idea of user username, transend username and password on user class, but
the user and password should be transient.
When they set it as transient, it doesn't show up on centralized places.
Here to start the user object is not the best practice, but I want to show some example practices,
what kind of data we can keep on, we can store on user details.
Also, we will use these user object on login operation so we don't want to call the user find method
device.
So we will figure out that more clearly in the next listener's.
Then we can complete our missing methods with our fields in the user details class.
We can also set the expired state or lock state of the user, but we will use JWT to handle them.
So for now, we can set them as thoroughly by default.
Then we need geter methods and constructors for our class.
We can provide it with Lomborg Library.
The loan book library provides greater annotation to provide better methods of fields automatically.
If we describe it on class level, get methods of all fields will be created.
If we describe it on field level, just that field will be affected.
The loan book library also provides constructor's to create with no arguments and all arguments.
And the Lombok Library also provides builder incitation, lone local builder annotation, produces the
quote, automatically using the builder pattern.
OK, now our user class for security is ready.
Finally, we can call it from user details service.
We can return as a result because it's all, say, user details, implementation class.
Let's use the builder method of user principle to return the user object.
So our method format will be user principle, that builder plus user principal fields plus built.
So this is a typical builder pattern.
OK, that's all about user details, service in the next listen, we will configure it with Web security.
Thank you.