Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will install Posman and we will talk about the functionalities of it.
First of all, let's dowland it.
We can find that the won't link from Google searching easily.
We can search it like no Lond Postma, or we can search it according to our operating system, for example,
Dowland Postman for Mac or Windows.
Then from the postman page, we can easily Dowland and install it.
Actually, no extra configuration on installation steps, so we will install it with default settings.
Then it will be accessible from our computer postman is an API application programming interface development
tool which helps to build, test and modify APIs.
Almost any functionality that could be needed by any developer is encapsulated in this tool.
It is used by over five million developers every month to make their API development easy and simple.
It has the ability to make various types of HTTP requests, such as get requests, post requests, put
request, page request, option request, delete requests, etc. But they will we need about the HTTP
request and HTTP response.
Postman provides it.
Also, Postman provides saving APIs and converting the API to court for various languages like JavaScript,
Python, JOA, etc..
Let's use it with example API calls, we can use the JSON placeholder to illustrate it.
For example, we can choose our HTP method type from the left menu just to the left of it, it's a drop
down button which has all the various HTP methods as options.
If we want to post to the Europe that we have specified, we will select post.
For example, let's call the Jason Placeholder Posts API.
Our HDTV methods will be passed and our year end will be Jason Placeholder that composts.
Now click on the send button.
That's all, for example, if you want to send the post request with a form data, we can send it from
the body tap.
Here, Postman provides multiple options, we can send it as key value pairs or we can send it as rawData
or we can send it as greyscale format, etc. In most cases, we send it in JSON format to handle it.
We will choose rather tab than from a drop down menu.
We will select JSON format.
Then we can send our body in JSON format.
To illustrate it, we can write some random things.
Also, we can send request headers easily in postmen from the headers tap, we can describe our header
with a key value page.
For example, we can describe a user agent, authorization, host connection, content type cetera.
Also, Postman provides many authorization types, for example, brutalisation, basic authorization,
Apte authorization, etc. For example, if we choose basic authorization, we need a username and password
and postman reps.
These credentials with base64 encryption then sends them as authorization.
Hej.
The other cool feature of Posman is we can convert our API calls to other languages to do it from the
right code section.
We can choose our desired language.
At this point, Postman serves tons of options like Joa C, Sharp JavaScript, not JS, etc..
Like you see Posman, is it really cool so we can talk about it deeply, but this will be enough for
the beginning.
That's all.
Thank you.