Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will start to implement the admin page component and VIF on this page.
First of all, we will list all books with tables.
Secondly, we can add new books.
Thirdly, we can edit these books and finally we can delete these books.
So we will implement the current page.
Let's start with listing all books.
First of all, I'll open the admin component.
We will display the books in the table so we should create a book list at a as a eight able and type
of it will be an array of books.
Then we can inject our services on the constructor's.
We need a single service, we will use Booke service to call the get all books and point.
Then we can implement the engie on in its methods, engy on any method is a callback method that is
invoked immediately after the default change detector has checked the directive's data Bond's properties
for the first time and before any of the verb or content children having checked it is invoked only
once when the directive is instantiated.
In this matter, we will set the booklist I will call the book service method, then I will set the
results to vocalist's.
OK, now our admin component is ready, now we will implement our admin.
Let's open the admin estimate.
First of all, let's clear the contents.
Then I start to write HTML content using it and met plugin.
We generally use the container to wrap the whole content and I want to add some heading to the top of
the contents.
Then I'll carry the card to present to the table because our context looks like a card.
So it has a title on the header and body of it will be table.
So I will start with a class card inside it, I'll create an element that has a card headed class next
to these card headers on the card, buddy, that is in other class and inside these card, buddy on
that table.
And this table will have two classes that are table and tables throughout.
So it will be stripe format.
Then I hit the tap and the inmates bill again, we'll complete the demo contents for me.
OK, here is our Marco.
Inside the court, Heather, I showed the table heads to show it, I can edit growth.
So I will start with a glass glassblower inside it, I'll create an element that has a whole six glass.
This whole six or call to Earth comes from great pieces.
Whole pieces are 12.
So you can think it like you separate the 16 to equal pieces and you choose the six pieces of it.
Then on the head there are three elements inside the cup.
Then I hit the top.
Our title can be all books.
Now we can implement the content of the table.
We will have a header and body in the table to do it.
I create each team and elements.
So I will start with the hat.
Inside it, all across the table, raw elements.
Inside it, I create p h elements and these t h schult have an attribute called Skop Call.
I multiply with six because we will need six different cells.
Next to the table had oil at the table, but in amounts inside it, I could see that table, raw element
inside it on the key h element.
And these t h should have an attribute called skop roll because I use it to show index values next to
the edge.
I'll add it to the element I multiply with five, then I'll hit the top.
OK, now let's steal the headers one by one, first one will be used for indexing.
Second one will be used to show the title of the book.
31 will be used to show the price of the book of them will be used to show the author of The Book Thief
will be used to show the date of the book.
And the last one will be used for actions like delete or edit buttons and hook up later.
Then we will use the energy for DirecTV.
It is a structural directive that renders a template for each time in a collection.
So our collection is Booklist.
We will render each book item in the book list with the energy for detective.
They can also get the index value from list with energy for DirecTV.
OK, now let's fill the headers one by one, first one will be used for indexing here to start from
one we can add plus one to the index.
Second one will be the title of the book item.
One will be the price of the book item here we can use Courant's Pipe to transform the price of the
book.
They can use pipes to transform strings, currency elements, dates and other data for display types
are simple functions we can use in template expressions to accept an input value and return a transformed
value.
Pipes are useful because we can use them throughout our application while only declaration each pipe
wants.
For example, we would use a pipe to show a price as ten dollars rather than the real price format.
Or we can sell it for that also.
So in our example, we want price with a dollar symbol to do it, we will add a pipe that pipe.
So I feel the currency and property of currency, it will be USD.
Ford Field will be the author of the book Eitam.
Chief Dunn will be the lead time of the book item.
Here we can use that pipe to form up the creek time of the book, that pipe provides many predefined
formats or we can create a custom format here.
We can use one of them to transform the date.
For example, we can use media formats or short format.
And the last cell will be used for election buttons like delete or edit buttons, for now, let's create
the templates of the buttons in the next.
Listen, I hook up so I will create a button.
This button has classes like DTN and B10 primary and margin ads for space with the next button.
Then I hit the tap.
First button text will be added.
Next to it, I'll add another button.
This button has Colossus like DTN, b10 danger.
This button will be used for delete, then I hit the top second button text will be delete, we will
implement the contents of them in the next lesson.
OK, now our HTML page is ready.
Let's check the result on the browser.
OK, it looks perfect.
That's all for this lesson.
See you and the next lesson.
Thank you.