Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will configure our project for class production deployment in.
We can work with different provice.
For example, we can create profiles for development, testing and production.
Then we can go on.
One of the profiles allow us to describe different property sets for different environments.
For example, with the development profile, we can work from localised.
On the other hand, with a production profile, we can work from the but also to change or to enable
a profile is so easy we can use Ziprin that profile, start up the future to change the active profile
in spring.
Now let's implement it.
To do it, we will create our application properties according to production and development.
You know that if we're going with the same configuration, we could not use different settings for both
of them in development mode.
We want to use default settings to do it.
We will change the name of our application properties to the application default properties.
And for the production profile, we want to use production settings to do it.
We will create new application properties like application product properties.
Actually, property keys will be the same with the allotment, but values will be changed according
to production settings here, we will use placeholders to display properties when we deploy it to the
cloud.
We will set these placeholders on the alert for the database.
We will create a Hiroku PostgreSQL database.
Then according to its credentials, we will field these placeholders on the lot.
Then we will create placeholders for JWT, secret and internal APIC, these fields are secret fields,
so we will specified them on the clade one by one.
Finally, we will describe the properties path according to the active spring profile.
To do it, we can use property source annotation on our main class.
In here, we will get the application properties from the class pet.
According to active profile.
If we don't have active spring profile, we can set it as default.
Actually, this invitation is not necessary because spring will catch the property source according
to the profile name automatically.
But to do it like that, we make sure of the process and we figure out how the process will go.
OK, default profile will be default if we don't specify inactive profile on environmental variables.
The default profile of Sprink is default.
OK, that's all.
Thank you.