Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will complete the internal field, we have described our internal filter,
but we should also consider two more things for it.
First one is ordering and the second one is filtering.
That's when I say ordering sweeping security has a filter in.
So we should include our internal filter in this filter chain and we should specify the order for it.
Let's think about it.
We have a username password authentication filter that comes from spring security default filters.
Also, we have described JWT authorization filter.
Now we have an internal filters here.
Our filters should be handled before our username and password authentication filter because skippering
security expects username and password or authentication on this filter.
If they use the username and password authentication filter before our filter, our filter won't trigger.
So we should maintain our ordering in this order and our internal filter should be handled before JWT
authorization filter because we don't have a JWT token.
So our security filter or the link will be firstly internal filter, then JWT authorization filters
and finally username and password authentication filter.
Let us implement it.
HDTV security already has a method for filter ordering and filter addition.
We can directly use the filter be formatted here.
We will add internal filters before JWT filters than username and password authentication filters.
Okay, now filter change ordering is done.
Now we should specify the filter pads for filters.
We have two custom filters.
They are JWT authorization filters and internal filters.
If in this case we send the request to our application, these boards filters will catch the request
and they will try to authenticate the request.
But this is not the right way.
The right way is internal filter should work for only internal API parts and JWT authorization filter
should work for other parts to do it.
We will specify the filtering parts of filters.
Let's implement it.
First of all, our internal API parts.
We'll start with API internal.
We can describe it from now.
Then we will specify it on HTP security and these PETS' can only be accessible by sys managers.
No, we will specify this part from fielders
once per request, filter provides a method like should not filter method.
With this method, we can restrict filter pads on our filter classes for our internal filter.
We will only work with internal API pads, so it shouldn't filter if the request pads start with API
internal.
For our gwg authorisation filter, we will work with except internal API parts, so it should not filter
if the request pads start with API internal.
OK, that's all about filters.
Thank you.