Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'll talk about what we do on the client side and how we will go.
First of all, on the client side, we will create an angular project to create it.
We will use angular CLI command line interface.
Of course, this angular CLI will work over nodeJS so our application will be basically and
nodejs project with this application, we will create a user interface for a bookselling system,
bookstore system.
So we will present books in the application and users can purchase them.
Of course it will.
have many details.
First of all, we will have an admin dashboard and from the admin dashboard we can create books or we
can edit books or we can delete books so we can manage books from the admin dashboard.
Secondly, users can purchase books from the home page.
Thirdly, we will have different roles like user and admin, so we will see an example application for
a role based system fourthly.
We will implement authorization and authentication.
For example, some page will be displayed by only admins if the default users try to access these admin
pages.
We will restrict these pages with authorization mechanisms for authentication.
We will have a login and register pages.
Then we will see the model will control the implementation on angular.
So we will implement the best practices on the angular. To illustrate it,
We will create different models, services and components and we will see the dependency relationship
among them.
Last but not least, we will use JWT as authorization.
So we will see example cases with JWT implementation like we see from the beginning.
At the end of the course, we will learn lots of features of angular and we will see them in example
cases one by one and step by step.
That's all for the beginning.
Thank you.