Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our model class for book class, actually, world class
will be a basic class that has the title Altor Prize Description and eight fields.
Actually, it will be similar to the backend model class.
Now I'll read the book model class under the models folder.
So it will be a TypeScript Phi.
I'll export it as a book class, and here I simply want to define how it should look like I do this
by adding book fields first field is idy and type of it should be no, it can be undefined also if it
is not descript, the second one is the title and the type of it should be Citilink.
I can initialize it like the third one is the alter and the type of it should be Citilink.
I can initialize it blank.
The other one is the price and the type of it should be and no I can initialize it.
Zero.
The other one is the description and the type of it should be sitrick.
I can initialize it blank lost fields will be crit time and the type of it should be date.
I can initialize it as a new date.
Then I'll add a constructor where I am able to initialize them collectively.
Here, I'll get my idea as a parameter, which is of type no.
Of course, it can be undefined also.
So the meaning of the question mark is that it can be undefined.
Secondly, I can get the title as a parameter, which is of TIV string.
Its initial value will be blank and lost.
Parameter is price, which is of type no.
Its initial value will be zero.
And here in the constructor, the assembly hook my properties with these parameters.
Like, you see, I have created that construct that includes some fields, so it is not necessary to
describe all properties in the constructor because I have already initialized other fields in field
description.
So what I did here is basically create a typescript clause with six properties and a constructor where
I initialize these properties.
OK, that's all about the book.
Middle class.
Thank you.