Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create a configuration on our project, Hiroku needs three different
configuration files for a Supreme Court project.
These are F.J., some profiles and system properties on APJ Sun.
We can describe the Hiroku properties like name of app resources, of AB Delt package, etc..
Actually, we describe how our app will be built in the profile.
We declare process types.
We can have multiple processes, multiple modules like Worker WAP, etc. in the system properties.
We declared the basic system settings like our Java version.
Okay, now let's start with the APJ.
Sonthi Hiroku has some basic configuration settings like name BEEL type environmental variables, etc.
We can describe them under the JSON on our project.
First of all, let's create an adjacent file under the project APJ, some will be JSON object and here
we can customize properties.
We can find all properties from the heroic page easily.
We can find it like a page on schema on the Google.
We can see all properties in here and the example format for it.
Now we can describe our properties, our first property will be the name.
Then we will describe the attack, we will use Gradle as it built back.
OK, these properties will be enough for beginning here.
We can give more details about it, but we can handle all properties from the Heroku interface is the
author.
Now we will create a profile for Hiroku Hiroku.
Apps include a profile that specifies the comments that are executed by the app on Stata.
We can use that profile to declare a very of process types.
We can describe our apps web service.
We can create only a single web server for our project.
For example, if our project has a multi module and we want to create a web server for all modules,
we could do it.
We're here because Hiroku provides a single Web server for a project.
Of course we can scale them with load balancers.
Secondly, we can describe multiple types of work, reprocesses.
Also, we can set environment variables.
We are tasks now.
We can create it under the project.
We will have only a web resource here.
We will call Java exec comments.
Our first environment will be Cypriote, that Actifed, that profile.
It will be for production mode.
So we will use production configuration properties.
Secondly, we will use the port number generated by Hiroko.
He has a specific environment key for ports, so we can use it directly.
Thirdly, we will specify the build your pet to find it.
We can assemble the project.
We can assemble the project from the gradle top.
When we assemble the project in spring two point five or later, we will see two fires.
One of them is plain George and the other one is an executables GFI plane.
Zha is a the legal standard file that contains only the modules, classes and resources executable.
Jafarzadeh is a springboard for Hadija that contains all of the modules, dependencies as well as its
classes and resources.
So we don't need that plane jash so we can disable it from the build Credle.
Then we can refresh the greater.
Then we can clean and assemble the project again.
Finally, we should describe the job aversion for Hiroko to describe it.
We will use system properties.
First of all, let's create it.
Then we will specify our original version as Jawa 11.
OK.
Our Hiroku configuration is red, that's all.
Thank you.