Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our guitar people story and we will send our code to these
GitHub repository to do it.
First of all, we will open our GitHub dashboard.
Then we will click to the newly posted bottom.
Then we will specify our repost.
Only our reporter name will be English bookseller's.
Then we can set access rights here.
We will set it as public.
But of course you can go on with private mod, then we can create it, actually get access.
What we do to import our code here.
First of all, we will initialised get on our project, then we will add all items to it.
Then we will relate our remote repository with the project.
Then we will commit our courts with the commit message.
Finally, we will push it to a branch in intelligibly.
We can do it via comment or we can do it via user interface here.
Our comments are ready so we can use these comments from the terminal easily.
When we try to initialize git on our project, we will get a warning like initialized existant git repository.
This is so normal because Angerer Seelie on default initializes gets for us.
Then I'll add all files to the git stage.
Then I'll create the relation between GitHub and my local repository.
Then I'll come into my office with a message, my cosmic message can be initial.
Finally, I'll push my comments to get up here, I should send it in upstream, not because we want
to use our local branch name on the remote with the same name also.
So when the push the local branch with the new option, that local branch is linked with the remote
branch automatically.
OK, now our quote is reachable from GitHub as public, that's all.
Thank you.