Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will talk about authorization, architecture in spring, security authorization
is the process which makes sure that the authenticated user has the necessary approvals and access rights
to access our secured resource.
To implement it, cybering security uses, interceptors, interceptors, work with configured UARS,
these Urias, these Eurorail configuration can be in different types.
First one is we can define them as perimeter permit.
All means these yards can be reached by everybody without authentication.
Secondly, we can define them as deny or deny all means.
These Urus cannot be reached by anybody.
Third one is we can define them according to their rule or multiple rules.
So in that case, these bets can be reached by just users that have provided Roeg are the ones we can
define them as authenticators.
So in that case, these bets can be reached by authenticated.
So not anonymous users are the ones we can define them as fully authenticated.
So not anonymous or not.
Remember me user after Eurail definition skippering security maps to us as pets and permission, then
ciprian security users access the seasoned managers to check these config attributes.
How access rights or not?
The Access Decision manager is called by the Abstract Security Interceptor, and it is responsible for
making final access control decisions to decide end access.
Decision managers can use access decision waters.
These borders are all water that checks it according to roll permission.
The other one is authenticated water that checks it according to fully automatic users, alternate Ketut
or remember me authenticated, etc..
The other one is G.S. and Water.
That checks it according to deny all or permit all, etc..
All waters can give Warth as access granted, access denied or access steam.
So there is no information about what they can decide as access abstain as a result of voters access
decision manager makes a decision to do it.
Access decision manager can use three different strategies.
First one is default.
One affirmative base in affirmative based access decision manager if at least one or to what Grant is
access to the secured resource.
Second one is consensus basis in consensus based if a consensus of voters votes.
So granted, what are more then denied grant is access to the secured resource.
The last one is anonymous, based in anonymised based access decision measures if all the configured
waters, wards and granted access is granted to the secure resource.
OK, that's all about authorization, thank you.