Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create the Jason laptop and provider class in this class, we will
create JWT util methods like Tolkan Generator or creating authentication from HTTP requests to do it.
We will create a new package as JWT under the security package.
Then we will create a JWT provider interface class and a JWT provider implementation class under the
JWT package.
JWT provider will be a Sprink component, then we will call JWT report from application properties with
value annotation.
Exploration and JWT secret.
No, we need three important util methods, first of all, we need a method to generate a token.
We will have a user name for like username, password, etc. We will use this information and we will
create a JWT token from this information.
Secondly, we need a method to authenticate that requests after Loganathan petition.
Each request should send authorization.
Haddish and this header should be generate generated token for the user.
In this method we will pass JWT and we will create an authentication object.
Finally, we need a method to validate a token like me described before.
Each JWT token should have expiration time.
So with this method, we will check whether the token is expired or not.
Now we can create our methods.
Our first method will be generate token.
In this method we will expect user principal objects as a parameter.
If you remember, user principle is created after logging operation.
Authentication clause keeps the credentials and rules of authenticate users in our JWT object, we can
store everything related with user and session.
JWT has a builder method and we can build it using these methods.
In this method, we will create a JSON token that contains first.
One is the user name of authentication.
We can get it from authentication directly.
Username will be the main identifier of the JWT object, so it will be a subject.
Secondly, it will contain rules of authentication.
We can get them from authentication.
Also, we can add extra parameters to JWT with the claim method.
Thirdly, we can add user ID.
Then it will contain the expiration time of the token, we don't find it from the current time plus
default expiration time.
Finally, we will sign it with an Alberta Jason Babytalk concerns different signature algorithms, the
will we can use one of the longest and safest harsh match algorithms here.
We will encoded with this secret key and our algorithm will be hashmark.
Sha five montre.
Our second smattered Beilby yet authentication in this matter.
First of all, we will get the authorization from the HTP Haddish.
Actually, this extracting header from the authorization will be a generic and common method.
So we can describe it as Utne method.
Let's create created under the security.
You don't call us.
We will reach it from the authorization haddish with the beer token.
So first of all, let's get it done as constant variables.
We can create with a public access modifier because this is a YouTube class, so these videos can be
also reachable by other causes than we can create the authentication token prefix variable.
Actually, it will be concatenation of tokens plus space.
Now we can create are you still mad?
Are you still mad at Beilby extract authentication token from the guest.
So we will expect the HTTP request as a parameter and we will return the BEERA token value as strict
authorization will be provided as a HTTP request header.
And we will expect it as a beer token, so it will start with a beta key word so we can reach our token
after the beta key.
So it is after seven letters later.
If it is not provided, we can return now as a result.
OK, now we can return the JWT provided class again.
Now we can extract token value with the security util method.
If the token is not, we can return null as authentication.
We can pass the talk on using the secret key.
JWT provides Pospisil that we can use it easily and we can pass it easily after passing it.
We can reach fields of it with claims Odjick, then we will pass the token value and we will get users
details from the talk here.
We can reach data like we sent it on JWT generates.
So we will have a user name as subject and we will have roles and user idy as extra parameters.
There is an important thing here, role where you should be the start role prefix for spring security
and Jason Token, so we should add the role prefix to authentication if it does not exist.
Actually, we will implement this logic before on security first class so we can directly call it.
Finally, we will create a security user details object from user info to create it, we can use the
build it and we will provide an authentication object here.
We already have a user principle class to create user details object.
To create an authentication object, we can use username, password authentication, token sibling security
provides it also to implement an authentication object username.
Password authentication token is a provider to describe authentication object in separate security.
Our last methods will be validated in this method.
We will check the expiration date of the token if the expiration date of the token is before then.
Now we will return false.
Otherwise, we will return to actually we can use similar processes to create authentication object
so we can copy and past partial code from the previous method.
Then we will check the expiration date.
Then we will check the expiration date if the expiration date of the token is before then.
Now we will return false.
Otherwise we will return to.
OK, that's all about the JWT provider.
Thank you.