Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement the request based service, we will use JWT for authorization
and we need to send this authorization for most of the requests that need authorization.
OK, we didn't use it for login and register endpoints because they are public end points, but Facebook
and points and purchase at points.
We should send JWT authorization with the HTTP request, so we're sending authorization in.
The request will be a common case so we can create a base class and we can describe such kinds of common
methods in this class.
Then I can extend it from the other classes.
I say that extension and base class because in Angler we can use abstract classes and inheritance.
Actually we will benefit from these concepts and we will implement our classes.
Now let's implement our basic request class.
We can create a service class with the and generate comment.
Our comments will be engy generate service and service need.
Our service name will be request based, but I'll create it under the services folder so I'll specify
it like services request base and it will create our service class.
Now I'll open it.
First of all, it will be an abstract class so I don't create instances from it.
I just use it as a base class.
Then we need a current user object because we need the JWT token value of the user and we can reach
it from the user object.
By the way, we can use protected as access modified because this object can be accessible from other
extended classes, then we can inject our services on the constructor.
First of all, we will use authentication service to get the current user.
Secondly, we will need HDB Clines because we will use it to send Gests.
In this constructor, we will set the current user from the authentication service and we should get
the current user from the authentication service as an observable because whenever it's value chains
on the request based service, we want to catch it.
It is Auxerre also to get it, we should listen to it with the subscribe function.
And this function will be triggered when there is a change on the current user inside it.
We will set the common data to our current user variable.
Then we will create our HTP header.
It has a get modified and it will be a HTP Hadass instance.
So as a return value we will create an HDD beheaders object in the HDD beheaders object.
We can send different properties in T value format.
Here we need two basic properties.
Our first property will be authorization and we will send it with the beta prefix.
We will send the token very of the user in the authorization header.
It is a JWT token here.
We can also add another check before getting the token value from current users.
Our second property will be content type.
We will send it as Jayton.
OK, that's all.
Thank you.