Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our model class for purchase history.
Actually, the purchase historic class will be a basic class that has the user I.D., boogity and create
time fields.
Actually, it will be similar to the back and mother class.
Now I'll carry the purchase model class under the models folder, so it will be a typescript file.
I'll export it as a purchase class.
And here I simply want to define how it should look like I did this by adding purchase field's first
field is idy and type of it should be.
No, it can be undefined also if it is not described.
The second one is the user ID and the type of it should be a no.
It can be undefined also if it is not described.
The third one is the book idea and the type of it should be a number.
It can be undefined also.
It is not described.
The other one is the price and the type of it should be a no, it can be undefined also, if it is not
described last, feel it will be purchased time.
And the type of it should be date.
I can initialize it as a new date.
Then I'll add a constructive where I am able to initialize them collectively here, I'll get my user
ID as a parameter, which is of type no.
Of course, it can be undefined also.
So the meaning of the question mark is that it can be undefined.
Secondly, I can get the book idea as a parameter, which is of type no.
Its initial willy will be undefined and last parameter is price, which is of type no, its initial
where you will be undefined and here in the constructor by the assembly hall.
My properties are the parameters.
So what I did hear is basically create a type of class with five properties and a constructor where
I initialize some of these properties.
OK, that's all about the purchase model class.
Thank you.