Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will talk about basic escort queries, Asgeir is structured clear language
for relational database with using Eskil.
We can do every database operations to use Asgeir.
First of all, we need a database to create a database with Eskild.
We can use Chiri database if not exists.
Database name.
This query means if the database is not created before, the database will be created as the name.
Relational databases are constructed from tables to create table with Esguerra, we can use kiddie table,
table name and columns with data types.
In relational database tables, primary is used for unique identifier for table Ross.
We can also delete tables, which is get to do it, we can use the round table table name.
After table is created, we can insert any rules to table with insert query in Ezekial, insert query
works like that, insert into table name columns and various.
Like insertion, we can also delete laws in here to do it.
We can use the lead from table name and work on.
Or to delete all rules of table we can use to navigate table plus table NE.
After insertion, we can write silly queries in asking to do it, we can use SELEK plus columnists or
staff from table name and work on this.
Of course, there are other many things in Eskild, but for beginning this will be enough.
That's all.
Thank you.