Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will deploy our guitar project to the Crocombe on HINAKO.
We can create three deployments.
We are heat up easily.
Our HILCO process will go on like that.
First of all, we will create a template.
Then we will set an environment.
Variables, if you remember it, we describe them on the environment.
That's fine.
Then we will assign our guitar project to Heroku and we will deploy it.
Finally, we will reach our application with the Euro.
Now let's implement it.
First of all, from the dashboard, we will collect the new app.
He expects a unique app name, our app name will be Shah Bookseller's UI application is important for
performance, so you should consider it according to your customer locations and your other services
locations.
For now, we can go on with the United States.
OK, now we can create our application.
Now our app template is ready.
Then we will set the placeholders for our environment.
That's for production.
Actually, we have only a single placeholder and that is basically where these videos should be the
order of the server.
We can find it from Hiroku applications because we also created our project in the previous lessons.
Now, our app is ready, now we will import our code from it up to do it.
We will integrate our GitHub account.
We can access to the GitHub account easily, and then we will search our repository via name.
Then we will choose it.
OK, our deployment is ready now.
Now we can deploy it from the master branch, of course, here if we have different brands.
These all brands will be listed.
We can see the details from the deployment part or from the right top of the page.
OK, this will take a couple of minutes.
OK, now our deployment is ready after deployment, we can see the current processes from the resources
tap.
If we don't find them, we can refresh their social stuff, then we can see them.
To reach our application, we can't find the application varied from those settings to.
OK, now our application is ready, we can test it with different scenarios, but let's test it on the
next lesson, OK, that's all for this lesson.
Thank you.