Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will Dowland PostgreSQL server and we will install it, you can download
PostgreSQL server according to your computer operating system, we will search it in Google and we can
reach it easily.
Then from the launch page, we will download it.
Installs, taps are so easy, we will just click next button and we will use default configurations.
The default route user of PostgreSQL is Puskar, so we will give a password for it and we should not
forget it.
We will give a password like one to three four.
Then we will complete insolation.
With PostgreSQL solar installation, PJI admin will be also installed, PJI admin is a management council
of crispier we can reach it from.
Let me open PJI Admin Council.
PostgreSQL localhost server will be presented automatically.
And we can change PostgreSQL preferences from council easily.
OK, that's all for beginning, thank you.