Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our digital repository and we will send our code to this
GitHub repository in local.
We can create some files and we can implement some developments.
These local developments can be presented by a couple of files.
These files are committed with it.
Then we can deliver and store these repositories on GitHub as clot.
So did is a version control system that we can store it on local or remote getup is an alternative.
Get remote cost to create and tostada.
Guedes repository on the guitar.
We can follow these steps.
First of all, to create a good project.
We need to initialize it on our project.
Secondly, we can create some developments on our project.
But we should add these developments to the gate repository because the git repository should be aware
of that.
By the way, Gaede adds files to only the lead stage area or get index.
If they want to store them in Geita repository, we should commit them.
So the difference between AD and commit comment is did add comment stores, the flies in the Gaete stage
or did index did commit towards the fires in the Guidi poster.
Finally, we will create a guitar repository and we will relate our local repository with it.
Then we will push the files to the get up.
We can push them to a branch with obsolete remote.
So in that case, our brains will be reachable with git pull comments.
Now let's implement it to do it.
First of all, we will open our GitHub dashboard, then we will connect to the repository button.
Then we will specify our reporter name, our reporter name will be Sprink Board book sellers, then
we can set access rights here.
We will set it as public.
But of course, you can go on with private, not then we can create it actually get is what we do to
import our code here.
First of all, we will initialised get on our project, then we will add all items to it.
Then we will relate our remote repository with the project.
Then we will commit our course with a comet message.
Finally, we will push it to branch in Indonesia.
We can do it.
We are comment or we can do it.
We are user interface here.
Our guide comments are ready so we can use these comments from the terminal easily.
First of all, we will initialize our project in intelligent after the initialization in the intelligence,
we can see the git tap on the.
So from the GitHub we can see the user interface for the iGate.
From the user interface, we can add or commit or we can create some message for these comments, then
we can commit and push from the user interface in intelligent easily anyway.
We can go on with terminal, then I'll add all files to the get stage.
Then I'll create the relation between GitHub and my local repository.
Then I'll commit my files with a comedy message, my economic message can be initial.
Finally, I push my comets to get up here, I should send it in upstream, not because we want to use
our local branch name on the remote with the same name also.
So when we push the local branch with the upstream option, that local branch is linked with the remote
branch automatically.
OK, now our quote is reachable from GitHub as public, that's all.
Thank you.