Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement the book service, we will use the book service to fetch
book and points that we created on the server side we created and points like the same book to the lead
book and list all books on the server side.
In this lesson, we will create functions to fetch these and points with the Engler's HDTV client.
Let's implement them one by one.
We can create a service class with the engine generate comment.
Our comments will be engy generate service and service name.
Our service name will be book, but I'll create it under the services folder.
So I specified like services slash book and it will create our service class.
I open it, first of all, I need to describe Bay Zero for book and points, we can find the server.
You are from the environment.
Then I'll read the book Postfix because each exists for the book and points start with a book API book.
We can check it also from the server side.
Then I'll extend it with the request based service class, because I used the base methods that were
described at.
Then we can inject our services on the constructor's first of all, we will use authentication service
to get the current user.
Secondly, we need HTP client because we will use it to send requests.
Actually, both of them will be used by the superclass.
Also, the class which implements and obstruct class must call super in the constructor.
So we will call the function here with the parameters.
OK, now we can create our HTP requests.
Our first method is save book.
We will take a book object as a parameter and of course the result of it will be observable because
the result of the HTP request is observable.
Our method will be post our Posterized API Pettys API book and we will send the book object as a form
data.
Finally, we will send the HTP headers in the options below with the Options blog.
We can send a lot of different properties like HDTV header, HTP content, HTP parameters, etc..
Our second method is BILLETT book.
We can take a book object or book idea as a parameter.
The result of it will be observable.
Our method will be delete our deletes rest API Pattie's API book plus book idee.
Finally, we will send the headers as property of the options.
Our last method, will we get all books, to get all books, we will send a get request to the server
side to get all books.
Rest API is API book.
Here, we don't need to send headers because it is a public transport.
OK, that's all about work service implementation.
Thank you.