Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement HD Melkert of the Register page, we will use bootstrap
frameworks type classes and we will create a register for these registered fonville, have three input
fields for username, password and full name, and we will have a submit button with click on the submit
button.
The registered function will be called and the user registration operation will be completed.
Let's implement it.
I'll open the HDMI form, then I'll start to write HDMI content using the Emett plugin.
First of all, let's clear the content and create the content.
We generally use the container to wrap the whole content and I want to add some margin to the top of
the content.
By the way, we don't need to know all bootstrap functions or the meaning of that.
We can easily understand them from the name of them, for example, and T means margin top.
Then I'll carry the cart to present the form because our form looks like a cart and this cart will be
in the center of the page so we can set it with margin horizontal auto.
I can handle it with setting of margins start and margin and then I can add some padding for it, then
I can add some shadow for it.
Now let's check it.
Let's reload the register page and check it.
OK, it looks big now, let's make it a little bit smaller, we can create custom siestas glasses on
Craster component that cyesis, for example, we need a smaller register box so we can specify it with
the Veith property, like we can set it like three hundred and fifty pixels.
Then we can set the max rate for responsive style because for small screens, 350 pixels might be big.
So we can restrict it using Max with property, then we can set the background of the register box like
we can set it as light gray.
OK, now we can call our siss function from FEMA.
Now, let's check it, let's reload the register page and check it.
OK, it looks nice now then we will have a user icon to describe it, we will use the font awesome eye
contact font awesome provides the FAA eye contact to describe icons in angular HDMI form.
Then we can describe the icon with icon DirecTV in this tech.
For example, here we describe the user icon so we can use it like this.
After describing it, we need some style on it.
For example, we need to centralize it so we use margin orta for the left and right side.
Then we need to shrink it with with font size and we need to colorize it so we can do them with a custom
style function.
Let's create a custom style on register.com component that suggests, for example, we can create it
as user icon.
Then the font size of it can be a hundred pixels and the color of it might be a little green.
Then we can customize the color a little bit.
OK, now we can call our Cyesis function from HDMI for.
Now, let's check it.
Let's reload the registered page and check it.
OK, it looks nice, no.