Hi, guys, in this listen, we will talk about basic things, about your secret, in your secret,
there is no specific type like in Zhihua.
If you want to go with specific types, you can use type secret in your script that are generic types.
These types are much less and cost.
All of them can be used for very evil, but the differences among them are scoping.
And I.
Scope essentially means where these variables are available for use via declarations are global escort
or functional Scott, if they use it outside of function, we can reach it globally.
If they use it inside of function, we can reach it functionality.
And we can override it after this initialization.
Our second genetic type is let's let declarations are globally scoffed or blocked, Scott, actually
this is the main difference between VA and let, for example, when we write a for each blog reads what
then?
We can reach what incremental value in function.
But when we ride into it, let me reveal we could not reach the incremental value in function because
let can be used in this crime block only.
The other difference between two of them is we can declare the war tide, but we could not politically
let very.
Our last type is cost CONSED maintains constant values.
Consecrations shares some similarities with land declarations, cost cannot be updated or declared,
so if these setted one time.
Then we cannot change the video of it.
Other thing about Egypt is we can create constructor in JavaScript and we can reach it with creating
neat instances, but to reach it, we don't need to describe all parameters.
One by one, we should describe constructor parameters according to order of parameters.
But if we don't define parameters, JavaScript will set them to null.
Will you automatically?
Other thing about JavaScript is the structure in JavaScript, instead of accessing elements in an array
with their index numbers or instead of accessing elements in an object with their key video, we can
use the structuring in JavaScript.
For example, we can reach the first element of array with normal weight or with the structure like
that.
Or we can reach the field of an object with normal way or with the structure way like that.
Last thing about your secret is it co-operators enjoy a secret, we can compare various with double
equal size or triple equal sounds.
When we compare with double equals signs, we can just compare the in all fields when we compare with
triple equal size.
We can also compare the types of fields.
Of course, there are other many things in your script, but for beginning for our course, this will
be enough.
That's all.
Thank you.