Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our backhands project and we will import it to Intelligent
to create a spring project, the best way is using Cypriote initializes.
First of all, we shall choose our project type.
Our project type will be greater, but if you want to go on with one, you can choose it.
Also, we will use Garito because Gradle has eesa configuration and better performance than most.
Gradle awards work by taking input and output of tasks and only running what is necessary and only processing
fires that changed when possible.
Secondly, our language will be Zhuo.
Our Springwood version will be the latest stable version.
Our group name will be.
Com that shot.
Our artifact name will be Cyprien.
Would bookseller's lasting about project metadata is to choose the Zhuo version.
We will go on with Jawa 11.
OK, that's all about metadata.
Let us choose our dependencies.
First one is that because we will use model, we have control or structure on our service.
Second one is security, because we will implement secure endpoints, the other one is Zhawar Persistance
API, because we will use object relational mapping.
The other one is PostgreSQL, because we will use it for database operations.
Last one is Lombok, because we will use it for clean cut.
OK, that's all about dependencies.
Now we can generate it.
We are almost ready to start programming now.
We will import it to intelligence in the schools.
We will go on with intelligence.
But if you want, you can go on with Eclipse or other framework's.
After importing a third the intelligence to enable Lumberg operations on intelligence, we should enable
incitation processing from setting Sprong preferences.
OK, now we are ready to start coding.
By the way, if we run our project on this step, we will get errors about database configuration.
This is so normal because we don't consider it yet.
We will handle it in the next lessons.
That's all for the beginning.
Thank you.