Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create the connection between the book components and Edman component
and we will share the data between two of them.
Let's implement it.
First of all, we need to call the book component from the admin component.
This is so easy.
We can directly call it with the book component selector.
The selector for the book component is EBP book, so to call it.
We will use this text in the admin HDMI.
OK, let's check the results from the browser.
Yes, now we can see the content of the book component in the Edvin Page.
So our first mission is completed.
Our second mission is to call the child function from the parent.
So I create a crit button on the admin component.
Then when I click this button, I want to open the module in the book component.
How can we implement it?
First of all, I need a crede button in the admin HDMI.
Secondly, I need a module in the book component.
Thirdly, I need the function in the book component to open the model dialog.
Finally, I need a function in the admin component which cost book component function.
Let's start with the first one.
I could either create button on the admin estimate, let's open the admin estimate.
I'd add a column next to the header off the table on the division that has two classes.
One is column which takes the other half of the row and other class is the text and.
It will show the bottom at the end of the row inside it, I'll carry the button that has two classes.
One is N and the other one is B10 primary.
Then I hit the top text of the bottom can Creed book.
Now, I can check the results from the browser.
OK, it looks good.
Secondly, I could see the model in the book Estima to do it, I'd open the book HDMI and I'll carry
that book model.
First of all, I'll clear the content of the page.
Then I'll create a component template with the Emmet's plugin.
So I will start with the Golos model and fate.
They are basically step model container Steiglitz.
Then this model will have two basic attributes.
One is idy.
The value of it can be book model.
The other one is TEPP Index.
The TEPP index attribute explicitly defines the navigation order for flexible elements.
So here we are setting it for minus one.
We remove the element from the default navigation flow so a user cannot tap to it.
Inside it.
I create an element that has a model dialog class.
Inside it, I'll create an element that has a model content class inside it.
I create that form element that separate it from here.
I'll hit the tab and Emmott's plugin will complete that HDMI content for me.
Here, I don't need form action so I can remove it inside the form, I need three module parts.
First one is the Model Haddish.
I carry the model head of glass inside it, I'll carry the Heather element that has a model title class
next to the title, that close button, this button will have a button, close glass and I'll and then
attribute for display to the attributes will be data.
Yes, this means it will be used to close the model.
I hit the top and the EMTs plug in will complete the HDMI contents for me.
I can set the model title as book details.
Then I'll add model buddy, I hit the tab, I'll handle the content of my money later.
Finally, I'll create the model for that part inside it, I'll carry that close button.
These button will have beaten and beat and secondary classes.
I'll add an attribute for this pattern, the attribute will be data.
Yes, this means it will be used to close the model.
Next to these close button, I'll add a submit button, this button will have beaten and beat and primary
classes and I'll add an attribute for this button attribute of it will be type and value of attribute
will be submit.
Then I'll hit the tab and the math plugin will complete the HDMI content for me.
Here is our markup.
First button text will be close.
And the second button text will be, say, Chanes.
OK, now our model template is ready now in the book components, I create the function to open the
model dialog.
I'll open the book component, I can access the model from the angle of component by model.
But to show or highlight the model, I need to query declaration.
So first of all, I'll add the query declaration in the book component.
Then I create the method to show the book model J creating element.
That model will be used to show or highlight the model we can send to show parameters to show it, or
we can send the height parameter to hide it.
Finally, we will call the book component function from the head component.
Now, I open the admin component to access the child component in English, we can use the the child
declaration.
The U.S. declaration gets a component as a parameter, so our parameter will be muk components when
we set it with the VHI declaration, we can access all the functions of book component from the admin
component.
Now I'll create a function to call the child function here.
We want to create a method to create a book.
Then I'll call the show book model function from the book component.
OK, our function is ready.
Now I'll assign it to the button in the admin HDMI page.
The click event of the create button will be three book requests.
OK, now we have completed our mission.
Now we can see the results from the browser.
When me collected the book, we will see the book model that comes from the book component.
OK, that's all for this lesson.
Thank you.