Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will start to implement a profile page component and we're on this page,
we will list all books that were purchased by the user and we will show it with a table so it will look
like this.
Let's start to implement it.
First of all, I'll open the profile component.
We will display the purchased items in the table so we should create a purchase item list.
Array is a variable and type of it will be an array of purchase item.
Then we can inject our services on the constructor.
We need a single service, we will use purchased service to call the get all purchased items and then
we can implement the energy on in.
It mattered in this method.
We will set the purchase item list.
I will call the purchase service method, then I will set the results to purchase item list.
OK, now our profile component is ready.
Now we will implement our profile of let's open the profile that HDMI.
First of all, let's clear the content.
Then I start to write HDMI content using the Emet plugin.
We generally use the container to read the whole content and I want to add some heading to the top of
the content.
Then I'll carry the card to present to the table because our context looks like a card.
So it has a title on the header and part of it will be a table.
So I will start with a class card inside it.
I'll create an element that has a card header class next to this card header.
I'll add a card by the that is another bootstrap class.
And inside this card buddy, I'll edit table and this table will have two classes that are table and
table striped.
So it will be striped format.
Then I'll hit the top and the mat plugin will complete the HDMI content for me.
OK, here is our markup inside the card header.
I'll show the table header to show it in their head.
There are three element inside the column.
Then I'll hit the tab.
Our title can be all purchased items.
OK, now our title is ready.
Let's check the result on the browser to see it.
We should sign in.
Let me check their profile page.
It looks good now we can implement the content of the table.
We will have a header and body in the table to do it.
I'll create excitement, different elements.
So I will start with the hat inside it.
I'll create a table row element inside it.
I'll create p h element.
And these t h should have an attribute called skop call.
I multiply with four because we will need four different cells next to the table.
Had I'll add a table by the element inside it.
I create a table row element inside it.
I'll carry the p h element and these t h schult have an attribute called Scarbro because I use it to
show index values next to the t h.
I'll add it to the element I multiply with three, then I'll hit the top.
OK, now let's fill the headers one by one, first one will be used for indexing.
Second one will be used to show the title of the book.
Third one will be used to show the price of the book.
41 will be used to show the date of the purchase.
Then we will use the energy for DirecTV.
It is a structural DirecTV that renders a template for each item in a collection.
So our collection is purchase item list.
We will render each purchase item in the purchase item list with the energy for DirecTV.
We can also get the indexed video from the list with energy for DirecTV.
OK, now let's fill the headers one by one.
First one will be used for indexing here to start from one we can add plus one to the index.
Second one will be the title of the book item.
Third one will be the price of the book item.
Here we can use currency pipe to transform the price of the book, so in our case, we want to price
with the dollar symbol.
To do it, we will add a pipe.
That pipe type will be currency and a property of currency, a field.
The US, the last one will be the purchase time of the item.
Here we can use that pipe to format the purchase time of the book.
That pipe provides many predefined formats or we can create custom format here.
We can use one of them to transform the date.
OK, now our e-mail page is ready.
Let's check the result on the browser then be look at the table.
We can see the books that were purchased by the U.S..
OK, everything looks perfect, that's all.
Thank you.