Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will learn basic things about book library, we will use a book library
for clean code.
Normally we should create getter and setter methods in Java for encapsulation principle.
But all time to create these methods are not effective for coders.
For escape it, we can use more, get it or certain methods.
These methods can be used on class level or field level.
If they use it on class level, all fields will have getset and settle methods.
The other annotation of Lundbeck is data with this.
In addition, we can handle Gitter Setar equals and Hedgcock methods automatically.
The other important annotation of Bloomberg is venue with this innovation.
We can create final imitable classes.
Venue is similar to the data innovation, but it creates imitable classes.
The other thing about Bloomberg is creating default, empty constructors and full argument constructed
to create empty constructors, we can use no ARC's constructed annotation to create full argument constructed.
We can use all concepts annotation.
OK, that's OK.
Thank you.