Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will examine the project structure that is created by Angler Kelley
and we will see how Engler's first application, we will try to understand these steps in the steps
in this project.
We can see a couple of folders and files were created that might look intimidating at the beginning,
but most of the files you see under the main folder are only required for configuring the project.
And the default configuration should be absolutely fine and in the source folder.
That is where you create your project.
Now, here we are.
Find even more files, but we don't really need to touch all these files here.
The most important file is index that estimate our application will have a single page and everything
goes on with this page.
We don't need to change anything here.
We are going to write all are caught in the Web folder.
Here we also have an assets folder, asset folder could be used for some static assets in our application,
like emotes, etc. And we also have an environment folder environments folder can be used for environment
variables if they need different profiles and we need different variables for these profiles.
For example, we can have two different profiles like development and production on production.
We can go in with Clojure, but on development we can go on with localhost so we can customize these
kinds of things with environments.
OK, we saw the file and folder structure of English.
Now we will examine how browsers or how servers host our application.
First of all, let's serve our application with Engy serve.
The important thing here, we should serve it from the project folder.
We can run the server comment and this comment will compile and serve our application from for thousands
to hundreds powered by default.
Of course we can change the port number with some customization.
Is it then we can reach it from our browser.
When we run it, we can see some dummy content that was created by Angela Saili by default.
The important question is, what is this dummy data and where is this dummy data on your application?
Engelhardt is a single page application and our pages indexed that estimate.
When we check index that HDMI, this is a normal e-mail side that has a title and the body of the fight
on body index, that e-mail doesn't have any content, but it includes and other components.
It is at root.
Then we dive into the app route, it redirects to app that component that, yes, here we can see the
app component decorator's.
This seems to be important, but more important right now, you see that we have this Selecter property,
which assigns Citilink as a value and this stream calls app route.
This is clearly the same text as in the index that HDMI, and this actually is the information that
Angerer needed to be able to replace this part here in the index, that e-mail file with the template
of the component.
And this actually is the information that Angela needed to be able to replace this part here in the
next e-mail file with the template of these companies.
Now we understand where the dummer data comes from.
But we need one more thing, how angler serves these components, actually, how Angular compiles these
F components on index that estimate.
Let's dive deeper into how to create components and how to configure that.
We try to figure out how angular is triggered, how is it kicked off to actually run over our body in
the index that HTML5?
The answer is in the final index that ASML file getting served in the browser and we can verify this
by inspecting the source code here.
We get a couple of split imports at the end.
These are injected by Engler's Clie automatically, so that is why we don't see it here in the raw index
that they might find here, we don't have any script imports, but whenever it is NDR, a process rebuilds
our project.
It will create bundles of strip secret bundles and automatically add imports in the index that HDMI
fine.
So in the final five, these secret imports here are present and these secret imports will contain our
own code to sew.
These secret plants are therefore executed.
Our second missing point is here, we don't have any scarified on index that estimate, but somehow
Engelhard generates these secrets.
But we know that to generate this kind of scripts we need, that means cryptid.
Engelhard handles it.
We are may that tesfai.
Let's have a closer look at it here.
You can see that we get a couple of imports that we check if we are in production mode or not.
You basically turn off some warning message.
I can tell you that.
But most importantly, here is D-line.
These boot straps starts our angular application by passing an app module.
Let's look at it.
If we look at it, we can see some services and some components.
But most importantly, for now here we get these bootstrap array, which basically lists all the components
which should be known to ANGULAR at the point of time.
It analyzes our index that HDMI light and hear the circle us because here we reference our app component.
So angular get started.
These men, that tesfai just started that the bootstrap and angular application and we passed this module
as an argument.
In this module, we tell Angerer there is these app component, which you should know when you try to
start your S and angular now analysers the app component and reach the set up we pass here.
And now Engelhard is able to handle Applewood in the index that HDMI Alfi.
Actually this is how the angular application starts.
It is.
Summarize it.
We have two main components in our project.
These are men that Tierce and indexed that HDMI angular configuration works with that index.
That estimate is responsible for serving the application and main Tierce is responsible for generating
the bundles and assigning the components, etc..
Main that T.
S configures, components, services providers, pipes, cetera.
With the app module ID module bootstraps.
The app component and app component serves the content from the index that estimate.
OK, now let's edit our app component and see the change on the browser.
First of all, let's clear the content except the angular icon.
And corrida, Hallowell text.
By the way, this is a typical e-mail form, so we can use basic HDMI components easily.
When we created Andy Serwer will detect the change and automatically deploy chains for us.
There is also one more important thing here, when we check the source code, we can see changes on
the source code because angular compliance code on runtime with scripts.
So it doesn't affect the source code.
OK, that's all for today.
Thank you.