Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will talk about English and English basic operations, English works
with English command line interface with using this interface, we can create projects and we can test
them easily to create a project in command line interface we can use and Geneve plus project name.
This will create the project with not module dependencies, not module is a library folder for English.
These libraries come from and repository.
For example, for JOA we can use Mavin repository to pool Gire libraries.
Similarly for English, we can use NPM repository to pull JavaScript libraries in here.
You can think that for sure.
We use pome and or build griddled place to configure libraries.
So how can we provide it on English to do it in Angerer we can use Pykrete Jason Thig.
In addition, we can generate components from angular command line interface in English.
There are a lot of component types.
First of them is component.
You can think like it.
Basic paste for English.
Second one is directive directives are used for creating widgets or rethink existing things.
For example, we can create like an indirect directive and then we add to each demo email components,
background of components.
We'll be read.
Third one is service services are mainly a way to communicate between controllers.
Services are often used as a way to get to your data stores.
We will generally use them for API requests, our responses.
The other one is Klus.
This is exactly the same mission like Java classes.
So you just create OJEA components with class component.
The other one is, you know, you can create constant variable list with enum components.
The other one is got you tancred router authentication components with got.
The other one is pipe.
We can think pipe s transformation components or feltl components for example.
We have a text then we want to display it with lowercase.
To do it we can use lowercase pipe.
And components go on like that.
Generally, we will use these components and they will be enough for us.
Others things we can do it from angle of command line interface is to add Neve NPM Library.
We can do it easily with using NPM, install a library name and save parameter.
We should use save parameter from library installation because save parameter a process to save dependancy
to pick Jason thig so we could do this.
If the loose are not module folders we can regenerate it using it npm install commands.
You can think it like refreshing gradle or updating Meryem file.
Additionally, in England, there is just one main HTML page, this is indexed estimate, the other
components are related with these H.T. Amplify in ANGULAR to provide its air.
Brute tech is used in index estimate with this tech angular component estimate is included.
And the other components are called from EV components like that.
Each component has a controller typescript by.
HTML5 and accessible, so you can write every component as different parts, different page in English.
There are two main configuration files.
These are app module typescript.
And the other one is in Jason.
With a module type secret, we can describe libraries, we should describe modules of external libraries
to use in English.
The other one is English, Jason, we can describe JavaScript and CSS plug ins here, for example,
we can describe bootstrap or query from here.
In English, the life cycle of component goes on with these steps.
These methods, first one is engie on chain's methods, it is called when an input or output binding
value chains.
Second one is Engy on in its methods.
It is called After Engy on Chanes was called the first time, but only once.
Third one is engie after live in it.
It is called after the components leave and it is children's lives are created.
The other one is Engy on destroy.
It is called just before the component is destroyed.
There are also life cycle methods in English, but these will be enough for us for beginning.
OK, now we will talk about important directives and components in English.
First one is we can show components, video in HDMI like this, double paresis.
Second one is we can add in expression with NGF tech.
Third one is we can add four look in each team and with end 40.
The other one is Wythenshawe form component with engie model tech.
And the other components goes on like that.
That's all for beginning.
Thank you.