Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will deploy our guitar project to Hiroku on Hiroku.
We can create three deployments.
We are yet up easily.
All Hiroku process will go on like that.
First of all, we will carry that Hiroku up template.
Then we will create our PostgreSQL database with Hiroku Posterous, Hiroku Postgres, is it Plugin or
Eddo.
So we will just assign it to the Oracle.
Then we will set environment variables.
If you remember it, we describe them on application properties.
Then we will assign our GitHub project to Heroku and we will deploy it.
Finally, we will reach our local resources.
Now let's implement it.
First of all, from this we will click to the new app.
He expects a unique Apne, our name will be Shah bookseller's if location is important for performance.
So you should consider it according to your customer locations and your other services locations.
For now, we can go on with the United States.
OK, now we can create our app.
Now our app template is ready.
Now we can assign our database.
Also, we will use PostgreSQL and Hiroku also provides Boskell as good as Edem.
We can edit for free.
After adding it, Hiroku provides database Eurail for us on settings we can also find username and password
from Hiroko PostgreSQL page, then we should set them one by one.
Then we will set the placeholders on our application properties for production.
These placeholders are JWT secret key and internal APHC.
Now, our app and database are ready, now we will import our quote from GitHub to do it, we will integrate
our GitHub account.
We can give you access to the GitHub account easily.
Then we will search our repository via name.
Then we will choose it, OK?
Our deployment is ready now.
Now we can deploy it from the master branch, of course, here.
If we have different brands, these all brands will be.
We can see the details from the deployment part or from the right top of the page.
OK, now our deployment is ready after the deployment, we don't see the current processes from the
resources that if we don't see it, we can refresh the page.
To reach our education, we can find the application referral from the setting step.
OK, now our application is ready.
We can test it with different scenarios, but let's test it on the next lesson.
OK, that's all for this lesson.
Thank you.