Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'll complete the book's model for I'll open the book HDMI, first of all,
for the fourth element, I can export DirecTV into a local template variable using engy form as the
key.
For example, here I can export it with the F key.
Now I can access the form controls and form validations with using these F key.
Then I submit this form with the energy submit property before we submit it, we can validate the form
after validation.
We can call the save book method from that component.
By the way, the submit button at the bottom of the form does nothing on its own, but it does trigger
a form submit event because of its type.
So we should describe the submit method on the form element.
Secondly, in the model body, I need an editor blog to display error message.
You know that they describe the error message variable on the component.
We can use it to display errors if there is error on the server connection.
To show it, we will use a division element, this element will have two classes.
One is alert and the other is alert danger, which puts the message in a red box and evenly split only
if there is an error message so we can handle it with the end.
If, Detective.
Finally, we will display the error message, by the way, to display content in England, we use double
Brace's.
Then I create the form items I have for different for items, these are title price after and description.
We already know how we can create form items.
We saw it on the register and in indeed.
Now we will create them with the same.
First of all, I create a form item for the title, so I will start with a class form group.
Inside it I create a label and this label should have an attribute called for title.
Next to this label, I'll add an input with an idea, a tribute set the title.
And these inputs should also have a class called Form Control next to this input.
I'll add the validation error division to show this validation block.
I should also have a class called Alert Danger, which puts the content in a red box.
Then I'll hit the top and the Emmott's plugin will complete the HDMI content for me.
OK, it is Armonica.
I have created this form group element for title, so the label name should be title.
And I want to describe it as required, so input should have the required attribute if the input is
not valid, I show an error message like title is required.
Now we will buy the input fields with the form control.
Like I said before, we will use template driven approach.
We apply a directive to our input field and Engler will create a control object associated with that
input field under the foot.
This directive is engy model.
We use it for Toovey data binding so we can read the value from the object or we can edit it.
Our first input is the title input.
I'm going to apply the Engie Model Directive.
We can use it like Engy Model Directive and bombed a property or a field in our component.
We will binded the title field of the book object.
They already describe it on the component.
If we use the engine model directer, we should set the name, attribute or input field.
So I should set the name attribute.
I'm going to use the same venue with Idy final.
Think about this input.
I should give reference to these engine model directive because I want to validate this input field
and I can handle it with this reference for that, we are going to create a template variable.
So the hash tag, let's call it template variable is title and is the video.
I'm going to use Engie Model.
So when Engler's sees this, it is going to set these templates.
We're able to the engine model directive that is applied on this input field.
OK, now we can use this variable on the editing block to validate this input field.
We don't want to display error and block at all times.
We want to display this only if the input field is not valid and form is submitted.
So we use the NGF directive, which is used for condition check on English.
OK, our first form item is ready now.
I'll create the order filled with the same so I can copy and paste the title field, then I can edit
it.
First of all, I'd apply the engine model directive on the after input.
Then I'll add a reference for engine model and I'll change the error message.
Now I'll create the price filled with the same way so I can copy and paste the title field, then I
can edit it.
I'll apply the NJ model detective on the price input, then I'll add a reference for Engie Model, Crisfield
will be the number, so I should change the type of input
and I'll change the error message.
Error message also should include the value of the price.
So it should be a price is required and should be greater than zero.
Now, I'll create the description filled with the same me so I can copy and paste the title field,
then I can edit it.
I'll change the label and label idea of it, by the way.
It will be a tax area because it can be taxed.
Then I'll change the energy model assignment and I finally I'll change the error message as description
is required.
OK, now our form is ready.
Finally, I'll check the saved book function in the book component.
I remember that I should add something that in the save book function, if the save operation is successfully
completed, I close the book model.
I can do it with elements that model.
It will get height as a parameter.
OK, now let's check the book component from the browser.
When I click the book button, I should see the book model.
Book model should include book form.
We have a problem with Save Button.
Most probably.
We forgot a CSI style about it.
Let's fix it from the book HDMI.
OK, we should at the BTM class to show it properly, then we can check it again from the browser.
OK, now it looks nice, then I can test it with example later, I can type something for title after
price and description feels.
Then when I click the same change button, the book should be created and the model should be closed.
OK, everything looks good except the last update after the book creation.
When I refresh the page, of course, I can see the great book, but it is not enough.
We will handle it in the next lesson.
That's all for this lesson.
Thank you.