Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will test our API and points with Hiroku, you at it?
Actually, we have completed our server side application.
Now we will test application and points one by one.
First of all, let's open the postman then.
Firstly, we can test, sign up and sign in and points for sign up.
We will send users some data with username, name and full name to the authentication and sign up endpoint
and it will be a post request.
This is a public outpoint so everyone can access it here.
We can create different users like user and admin.
When we sign up, our role will be user by default.
Of course, we have different roles like admin, then we can sign in with the creator to use it.
We will send a post request with username and password to authentication, sign in and point.
We can create two different users for different roles because we will have two basic roles.
These are user and admin after sign.
In operation we will have a JWT token and these token will be used by the requests.
Now we can test internal API and points, actually, we will have a single endpoint for internal API
that is make atme.
We will send a put request with user name and authorization value authorization.
Video can be found from the Hiroku settings.
Now our test users are ready, we have two different users, one of them is users and the other one
is admin.
Now we can test the book and points for book and points.
Save and delete operations can only be performed by admins.
So if we call them with the user role, they won't be triggered.
We will get forbidden letters.
We should send the form data in some format, we can create random content, like we write some random
things in here because our purpose is to test the end points.
Getting all books and point is accessible by everyone, so we don't need to send an authorization header
for it.
Now we can test purchase history and points our first and point Valby say purchase history, we will
send a post request and the API that Filby API purchase history.
Then we will send form data as JSON content.
We can find the user idy and boogity venues from the premise and points because we have created books
and users.
Then we will test getting all purchases of the user and points, this will be a get request here, the
result will be changed according to the authorized user.
OK, our all end points are working like we want.
That's all.
Thank you.