Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will notify the admin component after book creation, so we need the
same data or events from child to parent or parent component is admin component and our child component
is book component.
Angler provides it with the output decorator's output decorator.
Mark's property in each component is a doorway through which data control from the child to the parent
output decorator events manually from child to parent thanks to event Amatus.
Actually the important thing is here event amateurishly so let's check the event amateurishly and event
šemeta is an object that listens for something to happen and then publish an event when triggered.
This is the other form of observers.
For example, when we create an event ammeter on our child component like notify, in this case our
child component's has become a publisher and our child component will send the data up to its parent.
Using the Emmet's matters, the parent component will subscribe to this notify event at the end of it.
Then we send the data from child to parent.
Parents will catch it with these subscription.
OK, let's see an example of it.
In our case, I'll open the book component.
After the book Creation Successfully, I sent an event to parents with event imitation.
First of all, I carry the same events with the output decorators output, is it the creative function?
Marking the property is a way for data to go from the child to the parent.
And output has a type of event amosite, which means it's an event.
Now, I sent the data in the same book function with Emet methods and the data will be the response
of Save book.
Now, we'll catch this event from the parents.
So our parent is Edman component.
I'll catch this event from that coming from child component in the Stearman.
First of all, I need to add an event watcher in the parent compound event named Shilpi, same did the
child event.
So our event name is saved.
Then I'll catch this event in the parents and send it to a parent function.
For example, we can create a method like Save Book Watch.
And to get the parameters that come from the child component, we can use events parameter.
OK, now I should describe this function on the admin compartment, my function name will be saved,
Khwaja and as parameter, I'll expect the book item from the child component because I am the response
of Sambrook method from the child component, and it is the book object in this method.
I let the book object to Booklist.
OK, now we shared the data from child to parent.
Let's check it on the browser.
When I clicked the concrete book button, I see the book model, then I'll type something on the title
Alter Price and Description Fields and I'll carry the dummy data at the end of it.
When I click the save button, I'll see the book item in the table immediately.
OK, everything looks good and the next lesson we will implement, edit and delete actions, that's
all.
Thank you.