Now we can create our form, first of all, we should add forms module because template, the rival
forms rely on directive's defined in the forms module.
We should add it to that module that, yes, it is a module, so we should describe it under the imports
block.
Then I can go on with the register HDMI.
Here, I'll add for.
We don't need these ction attribute inside this forum.
We need three different inputs.
We should wrap our form inputs with form the Suguru because it is a requirement for bootstrap.
So I will start with a class for Kurup inside it.
I'll create a label and these label should have an attribute called for name or fullName.
Next to this label, I'll need an input with an idea attribute set to name.
And this input should also have a clause called form control next to this input and validation error
division to show these validation blook, I should also have a class called Alert Danger, which puts
the content in a red box.
Then I'll hit to the tab and the Emmott's plugin will complete HDMI content for me.
OK, here is our markup.
Here is our division.
We have a label input and editable block inside it.
I have created this form group Elements for fullName, so the label name should be full name and I want
to describe it as required.
So input should have the required attribute.
If the input is not valid.
I show an error message like full name is required.
I do the same thing for username and password so I can copy and paste the name field and then I can
edit it for other fields.
Label attribute Phoenixville, the user name and the label name will be the user name also.
Idea of input will be username also I'll edit the error message.
I'll do the same thing for Pettiford also lable, attribute and value will be password e-mail provides
password input for sekret display.
So I should use it as input time.
Idea of input will be password.
Also, I'll edit the error message.
Finally, we need a button to submit the form, this button should have three classes, one is Betty
and the other is between success and the last one is W a hundredth, which is the style for which Hanlon's
percent.
And we will use this button for our sign up so we can call it as sign up.
Now, let's check it, let's reload the register page and check it.
OK, it looks nice.
I'll register form template is ready now we will bind this form with the angular object.
First of all, for the form element, I can export the directive into a local template variable using
energy for as the key.
For example, here I can export it with the F.T..
Now I can access the phone controls and foreign relations with using these F key, for example, we
can submit this and submit property before we submit it.
We can validate the form after validation.
We can call the register method from register.com point.
That is, by the way, the submit button at the bottom of the form does nothing on its own, but it
does trigger a form submit event because of its type.
So we should describe the submit method on the form element.
No, we will bind the input fields with the form control.
Like I said before, we will use template driven approach.
We apply a directive to our input field and ANGULAR will create a control object associated with that
input field under the hood.
This directive is engine model.
We use it for Toovey data binding so we can read the value from the object or we can edit it.
Our first input is the name input.
I'm going to apply the engine model directive.
We can use it like Engy Model Directive and bonte it to a property or a field in our component level.
Bind it to name fields of the user object.
We already describe it on the component.
If we use the engine model directive, we should set the name attribute of input field, so I should
set the name attribute.
I am going to use the same value with the ID.
Final thing about this input.
I should give reference to these Engy Noddle directive because I want to validate this input field and
I can handle it with this reference for that.
We are going to create a template variable so hectic, let's call it template variable as name and as
the video I am going to use Engie Model.
So when Engler's sees this, it is going to set this template variable to the engine model directive.
It is applied on this input field.
OK, now we can use this variable on the editable to validate this input field.
We don't want to display error block at all times.
We wanna display this only if the input field is not valid.
So we use the NGF directive, which is used for condition check on English.
But how can we know the valid state of the input field?
It is so easy because we have a reference for the input field and this reference provides foreign control
validation methods so we can use varied state title, state, dot, state, etc. with this reference.
So we will render this error block only the name field is not valid.
Now, let's check the results, let's reload the register page and check it.
When I type something to the name field, the error is gone, when I delete it, the error is back.
So the validation is working, but in the initial case, it looks like it has a problem.
We don't fix it.
Like if there is no submission on the phone, don't show any message.
We have a reference for the form and this reference provides the information whether the form is submitted
or not, so we can directly use it on the ED block.
Now, let's check the result, let's reload the register page and check it.
OK, it looks nice.
OK, now I do the same things in other fields, first of all, I play the energy model directive on
the user name input, then I add a reference for energy model and I'll render this error.
Look, only the username field is not valid and the form is submitted.
And finally, I do the same thing on the passport field, I'll apply the engine model directive on the
password field, then I'll add a reference for Engy model and I'll render this error block.
Only the passport field is not valid and the form is submitted.
Now, let's check the result, let's reload the register page and check it.
OK, it looks nice.