Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement edit book action, I clicked the edit button from the
book list and I'll see the book model with the selected item.
Then I can make some changes on the farm and I can save it here.
We can do it in many ways, but I want to do it by passing the selected book item to book model.
To do it, we need to share data from parent to child.
We can provide it with input decorator's in English.
The input decorator in a child component or directive signifies that the property can receive its value
from its parent component.
Now we can implement it.
First of all, let's open the book component.
Here we have a book object, if they get it from the parent, we can provide the crate and update operations
together because when we sent it as a new object, it will be a discrete operation.
If they sent it as an existing item, it will be the update operation.
So we need to add only an input decorator to the book object.
OK, now we will sent the book object from the admin compartment.
Let's open the admin compartment.
First of all, I need then object to describe that book object we can initialize as a neat book object.
On the credit request, I said it is a new book object.
And for the edit operation, I need the need function, I can create a function like edit book request
in this function, I'll expect the book object as a parameter.
In this function, I set the selected book object as the select item, but I can use the Neeve copy
of that because if I changed some fields of book object and if I don't save it, the item on the book
list will be dirty.
So to prevent it I can use object assign in JavaScript, then I can show the book model.
OK, now I'll call it from the admin estimate by edit button, I'll open the administration and I'll
assign it to the edit button with the click event.
Then I'll pass the selected book object from the admin component to book component.
And I'll assign it to the edit button with the click event.
When I make some changes on the farm and then I save it, I showed the the book item because I should
update the Sambrook Wotcher method also for the edit operation.
I open the admin contract and I'll edit the same book.
What's your method inside this code?
First of all, I checked the edited book item.
I can check it from the ID field.
Because the field is unique for the book, if the book item exists, then it is edited operation.
In this case, I should update the lists, otherwise it is a crude operation.
I should add the new item to Booklist.
OK, now we can test it on the browser when I click to the edit button, I see the book model with the
selected book item when I make some changes on the form and then I say it I the edited item properly.
OK, that's all.
Thank you.