Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will implement application properties for our server side, you know
that spring has default configurations.
So in this lesson we will customize these configurations.
We will use PostgreSQL DJed in our projec.
You know, that Postgres kid works with Database's, so Supreme Court shoot, no database name and credentials
so we can easily set it with using Sprink, that datasource Datura.
Your own format will be JDBC, PostgreSQL Hostname Port name, plus Deveny.
Also, we should describe octaves schema Omura because the default schema of PostgreSQL is public,
so we don't specify the schema.
PostgreSQL try to use these public schema.
Our active schema will be schema product like we described in the previous list.
In the data source, you're dead.
We can customize all the properties of PostgreSQL connection, for example.
We can permit to connect with them, as I said, connection, or we can enable Bache operations, etc..
Our other property is Ciprian.
That datasource.
That username will be admin and Sprink that datasource.
That password will be one, two, three, four.
You know that we described in the previous lesson on the database user roll part.
Then we will describe the driver, class, name and dialect for PostgreSQL, because Supreme Court should
know which database drivers will be processed.
In our project, we won't use a database migration tool or we won't implement database changes manually,
so we will use hibernate the AL set auto configuration to set it simply that JPA that hibernate, that
the dell'orto properties will be used, the dell'orto property can be created, update, validate or
not create means delete and create a database from beginning for each day.
Update means just implement changes coming from hibernate entities.
Validate means just to validate data base according to the hibernate entities.
So we can use update mode here.
Then, especially in the development mode, we want to see the logs of asking to set it.
We can use sibling that JPA dot show Escala will be true.
OK, this configuration will be enough for us for the beginning.
Thank you.