Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our page templates in English, we can create a component
service, pipe, guard, etc. from the command line to create a component.
We can use energy, generate component type and component name.
When I say component, we can think of it as a page or reusable component.
When I say service, we can think of it as a business component or a helper for components.
When I say directive, it is used to extend the power of the estimate by giving it new Centex, for
example.
We can carry that directive like color converter, etc..
When I say pipe, it is a simple way to transform values in an angular template.
For example, they pipe currency, pipe it, transform they to formating string or it transforms decimal
number to formatted currency.
When I say God, it is specific to rotters and the rod gods are interfaces provided by ANGULAR, which
when implemented, allow us to control the accessibility of hérault based on condition provided in class
implementation of that interface and goes on like that.
In this lesson, we will consider only components.
First of all, let's look at our system and our requirements in our application.
We need three kinds of pets.
These are guest pates, user page and admin pates.
Yes, pets are simple.
Yes, can visit our application and can see the books to buy them.
So our first page should be the home page.
This page will include a list of books.
Guests can see the books, but to purchase them, they should sign in the application.
So we also need to register and login page.
OK, those pages will be enough for guests.
Our second page type will be for users after users visit the home page and sign into the application
user page will be reachable anymore.
Users also see all guests.
Page and user also can have a profile page to see the previous purchases.
So our order page will be a profile page.
Our other page type will be for admins.
User role can be the default user or admin.
If the user role is admin, the user can have the ability to add or delete the books so specific to
admins we should create an admin dashboard.
So our other page will be an admin page.
OK, these pages will be our main components, but we should also have typical error updates for not
fonts and unauthorized.
If they get an unknown page request, we will redirect to the not font page.
If they get an unauthorized user request, we will redirect to the unauthorized page.
OK, now our page requirements are ready.
Now let's create them one by one with engy comment.
We can directly use and generate components plus component name or we can use it with a short format
like Engie G, C plus component NE.
Both of them will produce the same result.
We can create our components in the folder structure.
I mean, we can create a guest page under the guest folder, user page under the user pates admin page,
under the admin folder and error page under the edit folder.
This will provide a better structure and readability.
We have a home login and registered components for the guest.
We can specify their component name with the folder.
These comments will create folders and components for us under the source.
We have a profile page for the users, we can specify the folder name as the user.
We have an admin page for the admins, we can specify the folder name as the admin.
This will be an admin page under the admin folder.
No problem.
Our file structure will be the same it others.
Finally, we will accrete error page four, not font exceptions and authorized exceptions.
We can use the error folder for the.
OK, now our page templates are ready.
Now let's check what happens after the component creation.
For example, we can check the log in page angular command line interface created for different types
of files for the login page.
These are successful HTML5 spec file and typescript five cases file for the components style e-mail
file for the component rendering specified for the component unit testing and typescript file for the
business logic.
But somehow all these items should be connected to each other.
We can find it from the component typescript when we look at it and go and provide set component declaration.
This declaration provides the connection with other items so we can say that these components is a controller
for the other FEIS.
FirstLine is The Selecter, this means that we can reach this component with this tack so we can say
that it is a string identifier for this component.
This means that we can reach these component with this tag so we can say that it is a string identifier
for this component.
For example, if we want to reach the logging component from the app component, we can use these selecter
when we implement it, we can directly see it on dobros.
Second line is template you.
It is CircuLite, this means these components will render this template here.
We can specify the HDMI page or content of the estimated page.
So if these specify the e-mail content like Hello World, it will also work.
When we implement it, we can directly see it on liberalisers.
Last line is Steinglass, this means this component will use these tile clauses for styling here.
We can also specify the style, class or content of the style class like template.
OK, components work like that.
But there is one missing point here.
How Angular knows these NEE components.
So I mean that angular somehow shoot no logging component is the main component for Logan items.
So if someone or some page tries to reach Logan component, they should use the Logan component.
Yes.
Answer is that Angular handles it with the module.
If they check the module, we can see the Logan component.
Is it decoration?
Angular Cianni generation's handle it automatically also on behalf of us.
OK, if we summarize it angular Saili generates components and informs the angular we are at module
to access the component.
It provides the main typescript and creates spirits with other items like cost, estimate, etc. All
other components will have the same direction and logic.
So this will be enough for us for the beginning.
OK, that's all about component templates in the next lessons, we will see the details about that.
Thank you.