Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'll implement the lead operation in the booklist, I'll open the admin
compartment.
First of all, I'll Creedon error message, we're able to show the errors, it will be a sitrick.
Then on Crete, the bullet function as a parameter, I expect the selected book Object and index of
the selected book object.
Then I call the delete book method from the book service, I will send the book object as a parameter
to the book service, then I will subscribe to the delete book function because the delete book function
is an observable item.
If the delete book operation is completed successfully, I remove the selected index from the book list.
Then I will implement the Ed block if there is an error.
We should set the error message.
We can set it like unexpected error occured to the bucket.
We can also write the error on the console.
Finally, I'll sign it to the delete button on the admin HDMI.
I opened the admin HDMI and I'll carry that click events on the delete button and I'll call the delete
function with the parameters.
OK, now we can test it from the browser.
When I click to the delete button on the booklist, we can see the selected item as removed, that's
all.
Thank you.