Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will examine our model and diagram in our project, we will implement
an online book shopping based on users and books to implement the system.
We will use three main classes.
These are users, book and purchase.
Our user table will be a typical user table, so it will store user name, password, name and roll
here.
We will store the roll field as in on video and in our application, we will have different roles.
These are users, admin and system manager users role will be our default role.
So when someone comes to our application and signing the roll of it will be user.
Admin minerals will be used to create books, update books and delete books, so for admin, operation,
admin, dashboard operations system manager role will be used for internal operations, for example,
to change the role of the user, etc..
Our second table will be book in the stable.
We will store the book metadata like title after price description, etc. We will store the some basic
properties of book.
Our last table will be purchase or purchase history.
This table will be a transaction table, or we can say that it will be a long table, it will store
the purchase locks.
It will store information like this.
User purchased that book with X price on that date.
So we will start this information in the stable hour and these will be these items and we will create
them one by one and we will see the details about them on the next lessons.
OK, that's all about class and diagram.
Thank you.