Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will improve the navigation bar and complement.
Currently we have an aviation bar, but it doesn't support role based templates and it doesn't support
the logout event.
I mean, that it displays sign in and sign up links everything.
But I want to show a laggard and profile page links after the successful logging operation.
Now let's implement them one by one.
First of all, we need a current user object because I want to show the user name on the navigation
after the logging operation, and I need to know the role of the user.
If it is admin, I need to display different links on the navigation bar.
Then we can inject our services on the constructor, first of all, we will use authentication service
to call the logout method and to get the current user.
Secondly, we need rotor service because after the logout operation, the login page should be displayed.
In this construct, we will set the current user from the authentication service and we should get current
user from the authentication service as an observable because we know it's really chains on the app
component.
We want to touch it.
It is observable.
So to get it, we should listen to it with the subscribe function and to subscribe function will be
triggered when there is a change on the current user inside it.
We will set the common data to our current user with able.
Then we need a function to understand the role of the user.
Actually, we need a method to get whether the user is admin or not because we want to display the admin
page link.
If the user has admin, we can find out easily from user or.
Finally, we need to create a logout function, it will call the logout method from the authentication
service and it will never get to the login page.
Now we can edit the navigation bar on the app component estimate.
First of all, I'll show the admin link if the user has admin role so I can handle it with the NGF directive
and my condition is, is admin.
Secondly, I shoulda registered and login links if the current user is not available so I can handle
it with the NGF directive and my condition is current user or current user I.D. is undefined.
I use the question mark to check on object rates.
Then I'll copy and paste this block and I'll edit it for if current user is available.
If current user is available, I'll replace the register link with the profile link and is a text I
ensure the current user username.
Then I replace the Logan linked with the logout function and as text, I shall sign out.
By the way, logout will be a function so I cannot use to link.
Instead of it, I should use Callick event.
OK, that's all.
Now we can check the result from the browser to test all cases, I shall test it for guest default user
and admin for guests.
I'll see the register and login links for session users.
So if I sign in user is available, I should see the profile and log to links for admins.
I should also see the admin link on the navigation bar for admin users.
I can use the user that I created on the server side or I can create it from the beginning.
OK, everything looks perfect, that's all.
Thank you.