Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our model class for user user class, we will be a typical
basic user class.
It will store the user name, password, name and role of the user.
We will use it for sign in and sign up operations to do it.
First of all, let's create a new package under our main package or package.
Name will be model.
Under the model package, we will create the user class, user class.
We'll have a database table relation and the user will be an to the class table name will be users.
By the way, it cannot be user because user is a reserved that isn't covered by the PostgreSQL configuration
tables.
So we cannot use it in here when we say entity.
This class will be a Zhuo persistance API entity.
So Hibernate or JPA, we all know that this class is an entity here.
Then we say table.
This class is related to a database table and the name of the table is name property on the table annotation,
for example.
And the annotation also has name property.
If we don't describe it, it will be the class name here.
My point is we can represent our class with these entered name on JPA queries.
On the other hand, in the database native queries, we represent it using table name.
Actually, the difference between Arnst and table annotation is exactly this.
OK, now we can return to the our class again.
We will have an idea.
Fields and idee will be the primary key and it will be an auto incremented generated value.
The GPA specification supports for different primary key generation strategies which generate the primary
key values programmatically, or use data base features like auto incremented columns or sequences.
The generation type auto is the default generation type.
It selects a generation strategy based on the database specific dialect.
For example, my Eskil choose a second strategy, but if we use another database, it can be an identity
strategy.
So it totally depends on the database.
Our second idea generator is identity.
It relies on an auto incremented database column and lets the database generate a new value with each
insert operation from a database point of view.
This is very effective because the auto increment columns are highly optimized and it doesn't require
any additional statements.
Our third idea generator is second.
It uses a database sequence to generate the primary key.
It requires additional select statements to get the next venue from a database sitcom's.
But this has no performance impact for most applications.
Our last idea generator is table.
It simulates a sequence by storing and updating its current video in a database table, which requires
the use of pessimistic locks which put all transactions into sequential order.
The slows down our application so it is not a preferrable generates.
We need to implement it with you so we can use identity here.
We will have a username, Velt, we can also relate this feel to be at the table column directly using
Collomb annotation, for example, username should be unique so we can directly say that we are Collum
annotation.
Also, we can set the nullable feature and length of the column.
We will have a password fields, password fields will be not nullable fields, and also we can set the
length of that.
We will have a name field and name fields will be not nullable field, and also we can set the length
of it.
We will have a great time, fields, actually, we will store this field for logging purposes.
It will also be not nullable field.
Finally, we will have a role field, but the role field will be an immigration.
So first of all, let's create it as an enumeration class under the model package.
We will have three basic rules.
These are user admin and system manager.
User will be a basic default role, admin will be used for card operations, so if a user has admin
role, the user can access the management of the book operations.
And finally, we will have a system manager role.
This role will be used for internal API operations.
For example, if we want to change the user at all, we can do it with this role.
Now we can call it from the user class.
We will store the information on the database as a string, we can store the enumeration value on the
database in two ways.
One way is to store it.
We are ordinal numbers or to store it, we are string value.
The default type is Ordnung.
Now our fields are ready, but they are private to access them.
We shall describe the getter and setter for all of them.
At this point, we will use Lumberg data annotation together, Setar equals and Hedgcock methods.
We will use Lumberg data annotation, linework, data annotation.
We'll handle Geter Setar equals and Hedgcock methods automatically.
OK, we have just created our user model class.
Thank you.