Hey, guys, in this lesson, we will see how we can generate simple ideas with using JPA and hibernate,
you know that we use I.D. to identify our table records and this allows us to reach the records effectively.
The GPA specification supports for different primary key generation strategies would generate the primary
key values programmatically or use database features like other incremented columns or sequencers.
Now we will see all of these strategies with examples.
Let's start with the default strategy.
Could do it.
First of all, we will create an example model class.
First of all, it will have zero persistence, table annotation, because we describe it as a database
table.
Then we should add and the invitation to describe it as an art class,
then we will add Lumberg in addition to generate getter and setter methods of our class fields'.
Our first field will be Idy could describe it as an idea.
We will add the annotation.
To generate ID field automatically, we will add generated value annotation in here or generate a strategy
will be default.
The generated type auto is the pull generation type.
It selects a generation strategy based on the database specific dialect.
For example, in our example, we will use my skill and my skill will choose second strategy.
But if we use another database, it can be an identity strategy or second strategy.
OK, let's Creadon and other fields for it, like main stream name.
Now to say that we will carry the JPA riposted Occulus.
JP Repository is an abstract class implemented by sweeping G.P.A. repository,
which with G.P.A. repository Ciprian will handle basic croute database operations automatically like,
say, update, find by Idy, etc..
JP Repository has two genetic parameters.
First parameter is for the middle class.
The second parameter is for the idea class of the model class.
So our model class will be default one and our idea class will be long.
OK, now we can test it, could test it.
We can create unit tests for each case.
Of course we will use superimposed book test under the test source.
We can create our package and our test scores.
Then we will inject our reporter class, we can inject it with using autobahns innovation in spring,
then we can carry the test methods.
Our test methods will be so save and to with test name.
Now we can run it.
After running it, we can see the Esker looks on the council to show it, our property is Ciprian JPA
show ESCA will be thorough when we check out our strategy uses Hibernates second table to generate it.
They can also check database.
OK, let's check our second idea generator to check it.
We will create another and the glass like the Volkman.
Actually, we can take a copy and paste it from default, but then we can change the table name and
last name.
Our second idea, generator is identity, it relies on an auto increment database color and lets the
database generate new value with each user operation.
This is very efficient because the auto incremented columns are highly optimized and it doesn't require
any additional statements.
Now we can create a repository for it to test it.
JP sort has to generate Parramatta's first parameterize for the model class, and the second parameter
is that for the idea of model class.
Now, let's test it, first of all, we will inject our repository class with OTTAVI,
then we can create a test methods like the false alarm or test method we'll be to save and with test
name.
Now we can run it.
After running it, we can see the Esker locks on the console when we check the locks, we couldn't see
the I.T. field on insert query because it will be provided as default video on database table.
We can see it on the table and also we can check the check it from database.
When we checked the database, we will see the ID field as auto insurance.
OK, let's check our third generator to check it.
We will create another and the glass like defaults on.
Actually, we can take the copy and paste it from Prairie's default one class, then we can edit it,
we can change the table name and last name of it.
Our third idea generator is second.
It uses databased seconds to generate primary key.
It requires additional select statement to get the next value from its database sequence.
But this has no performance effect for most applications, so it is optimized.
Then we don't specify the generator name, however, he uses default sequence generator, or we can
use specific signals generated with using sitcom's generator annotation.
The second generator annotation lets us define the name of the generator.
The name of the database seconds and the location size of the seconds.
In here, default allocation size is 50.
We can think it like Sation increments value if we use badge in certain that can be meaningful, but
I suggest to use it as long.
By the way, my Israel does not have a second strike, it behaves like a cable generator.
Now we can create a repository.
JPA repository has to generate parameters first the is there for the IE, the first parameter is the
model class and second parameter is the idea plus of course.
Now let's test its.
First of all, we will inject it with using autobio.
Then we can create it, then we can create that premise.
OK, that's my that's really the same entity with test name.
Norwegian runit.
After running it, we can see the locks on the console.
When we check the looks, we can see that our second table update created to get next value.
Like I said before, my scan does not have a second type.
It creates a table star sequence values.
Of course, it is not effective because sitcom's like is optimized for the generation.
We can check it also from database.
OK, let's check our last idee generator to check it.
We will create another end of the glass like the full time.
Actually, we can directly copy and paste it from default form, then we can change the table name.
Our last idea generator is cable, it simulates a second space storing and updating its current value
in a database table, which requires the use of pessimistic locks which put all transactions into a
sequential order.
This slows down our application, so it is not preferable to generate such.
Then we don't specify the generator name Hibernate uses before cable generator, or we can use specific
cable generator.
The table generator, in addition, lets us define the name of the generator.
The name of the database table and the location size of the table.
Now we can create a proposal for it, but test it.
J.P. Adipocere has two genetic parameters, first, parliamentary as part of the middle class, and
the second parameter is for the idea of the middle class.
Now, let's test it
with using the generator test glass, we can copy and paste that from previous test methods
we will save and they will test name for God to inject the to us.
That's injected with using Altovise.
Then we'll save it with a test name.
OK, now we can run it.
After running and we can see the locks on the console,
let me check the looks, we can see that our table generator updates credit cards next value.
We can check it from the database also, of course.
OK, now we learned idea generator types, you can ask me which strategy is best for me.
I definitely say that if your data base support systems generator directly use its second generator
because it's very efficient and it supports battery research and updates.
Otherwise you can use identity generator.
That's all from me.
Thank you.