Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our model class for book actually book class will be a basic
class that has the title order prize description and create eight fields.
You know that if the check and a commerce website, we can see these fields for a book.
Of course we can add other fields like STUC can't reveal, etc. but these skills will be enough for
us for that.
We can now make and implement it to do it under the model package, we will create the book class BOOKLESS,
we'll have a database table relation and book class will be an entity in here.
When we say enter this class will be our persons API entity.
So Hibernators GPA will note that this class is an answer to class here.
When we say table, this class is related to database table and the name of table is named property
on the table.
In addition, we will have an idea.
Field and idea will be the primary key and it will be auto increment.
It generated value.
If you remember from the previous lesson, we can handle it.
We are generations tradition.
Our generator will be identity.
It relies on an auto incremented database column and lets the database generate a nivola with each insert
operation.
We will have a title field, we can also relate this field with the table column directly using color.
Magnetation column annotation provides every feature of database column properties.
We will have a description fields in the description fields.
We can give more detail about the books.
These fields will also be not nullable fields.
We will have an altar filled, these fields will also be not nullable filled also.
We can set the length of it.
We are the column length feature.
We will have a price killed, these fields will be a double so we can give them similar values for its.
Finally, we will have a great time field, we will use it for logic.
Now our fields are ready, but they are private to access them, we should describe the getter and setter
for all of them.
At this point we will use Lumberg data in addition to getter setter equals and what methods we will
use.
Lomborg data on addition.
Lomborg data annotation will handle getter setter equals and hedgcock methods automatically.
OK, we have just created our model class.
Thank you.