Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our model class for purchase history.
Actually, the purchase historic class will be a basic class that has the user I.D. book idea and Kree
Time Fields because we want to store the relation between the user and the book.
We can think of it as a log table.
So this table will keep the transaction like this user purchased that book on this date with this price.
So we will implement these transaction look on our table to do it under the model because we will create
the purchase history class, purchase history class, we'll have a database table relation and purchase
history will be an entity.
In here, when we say into this glass will be usual persistance API entity, so hibernate or G.P.A.,
we'll know that this glass isn't into the glass here.
When we say table, this glass is related to a database table and the name of a table is named property
on the table.
In addition to our table name will be a purchase.
Underscore history.
We will have an idea.
Fields and Idy will be the primary key and it will be auto increment generated value.
We can use identity as a generation strategy.
It relies on an auto incremented database column and lets the database generate any video.
With each insert operation, we will have a user ID field.
We can also relate this field with the table column directly using column annotation here.
We won't use hibernates mappings because we don't want to struggle with hibernate performance issues.
Of course we can associate it with the user class to handle it.
We can use Minetta one and join relations in hibernate.
But when we use them, Hibernate generates extra select queries.
So for now we can use pure user idea instead of user model class.
We will have a book Idea Fields.
It will be a not nullable field.
We will have a price field, these fields will start a price that the book has the price on a special
purchase date, you know that price can be changed by time.
So we should set for the specific date.
Finally, we'll have a great time field.
These will be used for logging.
Now our fields are ready, but they are in private mode to access them, we should describe the getter
and setter for all of them.
At this point, we will use Lomborg data annotation together.
Setar equals and what methods we will use Lumberg Data Annotation Ltd..
In addition, we'll handle getter setter equals and has got methods automatically.
OK, we have just created our model class.
Thank you.