Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create our reporter class for book to do it under the repository
package, we will carry the book repository interface.
Berkeley, he will extend GPA, riposted, GPA replacer is an obstacle course implemented by spring
GPA repository with GPA repository, Cypriote will handle basic database operations automatically like
say, update, find by the delete, bidi, etc..
J-P repository has two genetic parameters.
First parameter is for the model class.
The second parameter is for the idea class of the middle class.
So our middle class will be book and our idea class will be long here.
We can write the example method queries like fine by title or find by price greater then etc. or we
can write some queries with query, annotation, etc. but the basic operations that are provided by
the AP reports are in default will be enough for us because we need typical save update for the lead
book or find book methods.
OK, that's all about book repository implementation.
Thank you.