Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create user service in spring, there is a cycle in model service
controller structure.
First of all, this great model can assess these model classes.
Are entities later create repositories for these classes?
These replacer classes are persistance classes later called these repositories from services.
These services will be our business logic finally called services from controllers and these controllers
will be our access point.
So in the previous lesson, we described our user repository in this lesson.
We will call it from Serb's.
Our service class will include basic krot methods about user like save user delete, user finta, user
change, user roll, etc. Let's implement them one by one to do it.
First of all, we will create a service class.
First of all, let's create a new package under our main package.
Our name will be service.
Under the service package, we will create a user service interface and under the service package we
will create a user service implementation class.
And these user service implementation will implement user service to define user service as a service
class, we will add service.
In addition to it, the Martine's with their service in addition to indicate that it's holding the business
logic or service layer.
So user service will keep business logic operations for the user later.
We will call user repository for dependency injection.
We can use autopilot insipient.
OK, now we can create our methods.
Our first method will be save users to save users.
We can call user repository dot save method.
But here, first of all, let's describe the default properties of the user.
Then we can save the users.
First of all, we should encode passwords to store passwords with clear text anyway.
That is not a secure way.
So how can we handle it?
We can store it with harshing sibling security presence.
A lot of encoding or hashing algorithms here.
We can use any encoding algorithm that we want.
For example, here we can use decrypt password encoded it uses to decrypt strong caching function.
It also uses salt video to generate encoding passwords and it produces passwords that are hard to crack.
In Sprink, we can describe Beanz under the configuration classes.
For now we have the main class as a configuration class so we can describe it under the main class.
Done from the user service, we can inject it with autosite annotation and we can encode the user password.
Later, we will set our password with password encoder, that anchored user that get passwords as a
parameter.
Then we will set the default roll of the users, default roll will be users.
Then we can set Crede state of the user data and we can call the user repository save Matt.
OK, that's all about the same at our second method.
We'll be fine, too, user by username.
We can directly call it from user repository because we describe it before.
Our last method will be to change the default user role, to admit we will expect a user I.D. as a parameter.
Then we can directly call it from the repository.
Here, we will update the U.S. role as admin.
In Sprink, transaction is required when executing an update or delete query, so here we should add
transactional annotation also on method level.
OK, that's all about user service implementation.
Thank you.