Hi, guys, in this lesson, we will create the purchase history serves in this lesson, we will also
continue to implement model service control structure.
In the previous lesson, we described our purchase history poster in this lesson, we will call it from
service.
And these service class will be our business logic.
Our service class will include basic krod methods about purchase history, like save purchase history,
Fynes purchase history, etc..
Let's implement it.
First of all, under the service package, we will carry their purchase history service interface.
And under the service package, we will carry their purchase history service, implementation class,
and these purchases, straight service implementation will implement purchase history service interface
to define purchase history service as a service class.
We will add service.
In addition to it, we mark beings with service in addition to indicate that it's sold the business
logic or seriously or purchases or service will key business logic operations for the purchase.
Sorry.
Later we will call purchase history repository for dependency injection.
We can use Ottowa in spring.
We can use auto wiring on property satyrs or constructor's.
We can in here.
We can use constructor's also of course.
OK, now we can create our methods.
Our first method will be save purchase history.
To save purchase history, we can call purchases the repository that same made here.
First of all, let's describe the default properties of the purchase history.
Then we can save their purchase history.
OK, that's all about the same method, our second method will be to find purchase items of the user.
We can directly call it from purchases the repository because we describe it before in repository class.
OK, that's all about purchase history, service implementation.
Thank you.