In this module,
we're going to build a set of integration tests for the three
projects that we built in the previous modules.
We'll begin by looking at the integration testing strategy that
we'll use for all of our integration tests,
and then we'll review how to build integration tests for the product service,
the review service, and finally, the inventory service.
Before we start building integration tests,
let's define integration testing and look at why we might want to use it.
Martin Fowler described integration testing as follows: Integration tests
determine if independently developed units of software work correctly
together when they're connected to each other.
Thus far,
we have written unit tests to validate that our controller
works properly against a mock service,
that our service works properly against a mock repository,
and that our repository accurately persists data to
and from a back-end database.
But how can we be confident that when we put them all together,
that the collective unit will work properly?
The answer is that we need to build a set of integration
tests that exercise each service end to end.
We want to test that a request to a controller resolves to the correct
call to a service that resolves to the correct call to a repository
that accurately interacts with the database.
Integration testing helps us in two ways: First,
it allows us to validate that our application configuration is correct,
that the right database connection is wired into the repository,
that the right repository is wired into the service,
and the right service is wired into the controller.
And then, once the application is correctly wired together,
it allows us to exercise the complete functionality end to end.
There are many ways to write integration tests,
including setting up and connecting to a full production-like environment,
or more recently,
leveraging Docker to set us a production-like environment locally,
and then executing HTTP requests against that environment,
but a simpler approach that obtains our objective of testing a
Spring application end to end with JUnit is to load the full Spring
application context and test using MockMvc.
MockMvc allows us to execute HTTP requests against our
controllers and validate the responses.
And loading the full Spring application context without mocks
creates and wires the full application together.
The only thing that we'll be doing differently from a full production-like
environment test is to leverage the techniques we reviewed in the previous
modules to manage the back-end resources.
Specifically, we'll use DbUnit to pre-populate our back-end SQL database,
we'll use our Spring Mongo extension and the Spring
MongoTemplate to pre-populate our MongoDB instance,
and we'll use WireMock to stub our third-party API.
In the next section, we'll begin by writing integration tests for the product service.