Now let's take a look at the source code for the InventoryControllerTest.
The InventoryControllerTest class is annotated with the
ExtendWith SpringExtension annotation, the SpringBootTest annotation,
and the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation.
The corresponding MockMvc instance is autowired into the class,
and we create a mock InventoryService using the MockBean annotation.
There are three test cases: TestGetInventoryByIdSuccess,
testGetInventoryByIdNotFound, and testCreatePurchaseRecord.
The testGetInventoryByIdSuccess method creates a mock InventoryRecord,
and configures the mock service's getInventoryRecord method to
return it when it's invoked for productId 1.
It uses mockMvc to perform a GET request to /inventory/1,
and then verifies that it returns a 200 OK HTTP response code,
the correct LOCATION header, and the correct values in the JSON payload.
The testGetInventoryByIdNotFound method does the same thing,
but configures the mocked service to return Optional.empty when its
getInventoryRecord method is called for productId 2.
It uses MockMvc to perform a GET request against /inventory/2,
and validates that returns a 404 Not Found HTTP response.
Finally,
the testCreatePurchase method creates a mock InventoryRecord object and
configures the mock inventory service to return it when its purchaseProduct
method is invoked on productid 1 with a quantity of 5.
It uses MockMvc to perform a post request to /inventory/purchaseRecord with a
JSON content type and a body that is the JSON representation of a new
PurchaseRecord for product ID 1 with a quantity of 5.
Finally, it validates that the post returns a 200 OK HTTP response,
verifies the LOCATION header, and the values in the JSON payload.
This is our third time through a controller test, so at this point, you should feel pretty comfortable with this test code.