Let's review what we've learned.
The inventory web service is a Spring Boot microservice that
retrieves and updates product inventory information by connecting to
a third party through a RESTful interface.
To facilitate this connection,
the inventory service uses Spring's RestTemplate to make HTTP calls and
translate requests and response bodies to Java objects.
We reviewed how to test our controller using MockMvc,
which followed the same pattern as in the previous two modules.
Our service test is where things got interesting in this module.
The inventory service retrieves and updates product
information by connecting to a third-party API,
so we learned how to use WireMock to control the responses
that are returned for various HTTP requests.
And then, through a test.properties file,
we configured the inventory service to connect to WireMock.
We reviewed how to configure requests and responses manually in code,
and we looked at WireMock's support for mapping files to
externalize requests and responses using JSON files.
At this point,
you should feel confident writing unit tests against components that connect to a third-party API using WireMock.