Now let's turn our attention to the core functionality of this module,
namely, testing a MongoDB repository.
Recall that our goal, when testing the review repository,
is to pre-populate data in the review database with a known set of data
and then validate both that our review and reviewEntry classes are mapped
properly to MongoDB and that our persistence operations and custom query
method are generated correctly.
Let's review what a MongoDB test case looks like.
First, we annotate our test class with the DataMongoTest annotation,
which creates an embedded MongoDB instance and loads the subset of
our Spring configuration that supports MongoDB.
This means that we'll have an embedded MongoDB instance to test with,
as well as our repository, but it won't load our controller or service.
Then we autowire into our test class a Mongo template,
which is a Spring Data class that implements the template design
pattern and makes interacting with MongoDB easy.
Finally, we autowire the repository that we want to test.
So at this point, we have an embedded MongoDB instance,
a Mongo template that's connected to that embedded MongoDB instance,
and our review repository that will persist documents to and
from that same embedded MongoDB instance.
Getting back to our goal of pre-populating our embedded MongoDB instance
so that we can write tests against a known set of data,
we're going to hook into the JUnit 5 lifecycle methods.
First, we're going to define a BeforeEach method,
which is called before each test executes to
pre-populate our MongoDB data collection.
Then each test method will run against a known set of good data,
and finally we're going to define an AfterEach method,
which is called after each test invocation to drop the MongoDB
collection and delete all of our pre-populated data.
We'll create a JSON file that contains our test data as an array of reviews,
store that JSON file in the src/test/resources/data directory,
and then we'll handle both of the BeforeEach and
AfterEach lifecycle notifications.
Importing data that is stored in a JSON file into MongoDB is a simple process.
We're going to use the Jackson JSON library's ObjectMapper to load the
contents of a JSON file into a list of review objects,
and then we're going to use the MongoDB template's save method to
persist each review into our embedded MongoDB instance.
So it's quite a bit of design for what amounts to three lines of code.
The code to accomplish this is pretty simple.
In our BeforeEach method,
we use a Jackson ObjectMapper to read the contents of a
file into an array of review instances,
and then we iterate over each of those review instances and
pass it to mongoTemplate's save method, which inserts the review into MongoDB.
In our AfterEach method,
we invoke mongoTemplate's dropCollection method to
delete all the pre-populated data.
The end result is that when each test runs,
it can be certain that its database contains the contents of our sample JSON
file and implement its test functionality accordingly.
Now let's look at the source code for the
ReviewRepositoryTest and see how it all fits together.
The ReviewRepositoryTest class is annotated with the DataMongoTest annotation,
which creates an embedded MongoDB instance,
and loads the subset of your Spring configuration that pertains to Mongo,
namely your repository.
It has a MongoTemplate wired into it, which makes Mongo operations easy,
and it has the ReviewRepository that we want to test wired into it.
We create a Jackson ObjectMapper, which converts objects to and from JSON.
We'll use it to load the contents of our sample JSON
file into an array of review objects.
Next,
we use the Java NIO Path class to create a
platform-independent path to our sample JSON file,
which is located in the src/test/resources/data folder,
and then it calls the path's toFile method to build
a file object from that path.
Just as we talked about earlier,
the beforeEach method is annotated with the JUnit 5 BeforeEach annotation,
which means that it will be called before each test method runs.
We used the Jackson ObjectMapper to load the contents of our
sample JSON file into an array of review instances.
There are a couple ways to specify the type of object that
Jackson should create from the file, but Review array .class is the simplest.
In the next example, we'll see how to specify it a little bit more generically.
Once we have an array of review objects,
then we we'll use the Array's class to stream over the array,
and then pass each review to the MongoTemplate's save method.
This effectively loads the contents of the sample JSON
file into our embedded MongoDB instance.
The AfterEach method is annotated with the JUnit5 AfterEach annotation,
which means that it will be called after each test method runs.
In this case, we invoke the mongoTemplate's dropCollection method,
which deletes all the documents in the reviews collection.
Recall that when we created the review class,
we specified that it should map to the reviews collection.
At this point,
each of our tests can be sure that the embedded MongoDB instance
contains the documents in our sample JSON file.
But before we get into the test methods,
let's quickly look at the sample JSON file so that you can know what to expect.
The sample JSON file contains JSON representations of two reviews.
One for productId 1 and one for productId 2.
The first review contains a single review entry,
and the second review contains three review entries.
With our database populated, let's review out test methods.
The testFindAll method invokes the review repository's findAll method,
and then validates that two reviews are returned.
The testFindByIdSucess method invokes the review repository's findById method,
specifying the document ID 1, which is in our sample JSON file.
It validates that the review is found, and then it checks the ID,
productId, and version values,
and finally validates that it contains a single review entry.
The testFindByIdFailure method attempts to retrieve a review with a
document ID that does not exist in our sample data.
It calls the review repository's findById method,
passing the document ID 99, and then validates that the review is not present.
FindById and findAll are standard methods generated by Spring Data.
The next two tests validate the custom query method we defined, findByProductId.
The productId is an integer, so in the testFindByProductIdSuccess method,
we pass the findByProductId, the value 1,
and validate that the review is present.
The testFindByProductIdFailure method passes the product ID 99,
which is not in our sample data, so it verifies that the review is not present.
The testSave method creates a new review object with a single
review entry and saves it to the repository by calling the
review repository.save method.
The save method returns the savedReview,
which is now populated with the MongoDB generated ID,
so we validate that when we execute a findById method call,
we receive the same sample object back from Mongo.
The testUpdate method tests that we can update an existing review in Mongo.
We first retrieve the review with Id 2, which has 3 review entries,
we add a fourth entry to it, and then save it back to MongoDB.
We then retrieve the object again and validate that it now has 4 review entries.
Finally, the testDelete method deletes the review with the document ID of 2,
and validates that when we attempt to retrieve the review with ID 2,
it's now not present.
This test harness should allow you to test the other standard
methods that Spring Data generates for you,
as well as any other more advanced custom query methods that you define.
You can add more reviews to your sample JSON file and write your tests knowing that those reviews will be in your embedded MongoDB instance.