Welcome back to the second part
of this quick crash course to Flexbox.
So this is where we left off in the last video,
and we already have the hero part and the price part ready
so now we're gonna worry about the content.
And just as a reminder,
this is what it's gonna look like in the end.
Okay, so this is a reference.
And let's now recreate this using the power of Flexbox.
Giving us some more space here.
And I will start with the markup for the first part.
So in the content,
I'm gonna create a pizza title element.
And in there,
we will have the title
and the two tags that I showed you before.
So let's actually take a look at that again.
So this entire element here,
this will be the pizza title.
And so this will be the heading.
This part will be the heading.
And then these two tags here.
Okay, so we have an h1.
And this one is called pizza vegetale.
And let me add a small emoji here.
And if you're on a Mac,
to get this emoji window here,
you just have to type control+command+space
and then...
Where is that?
So that's the one I'm looking for.
On Windows,
I'm not really sure how to do it.
Actually, if you don't like these emojis,
you can just skip them altogether.
Okay, I find them fun here in this user interface.
Instead of using real icons,
I just use these ones.
So that is the h1
and let's get these tags.
So pizza tag.
And if you remember,
there were two of them and they had different colors.
So now I'm gonna use that modifier
as I was telling you before.
So we have pizza tag to style both of them.
And then I'm gonna add a more specific class
to each of them.
So this is gonna be the pizza tag and then dash dash one.
And then the other one,
as you can guess,
will be the number two.
So you wanna say that it's a vegetarian
and also that it's Italian.
Okay, so that's it for the title.
So let's go ahead and actually style them.
So pizza heading.
And actually, I'm missing the pizza title.
Let's go ahead and copy this.
Title and the tag.
And also tag one and two.
And these will only have one line of code, so...
Alright, first of all,
we wanna have these three elements here side by side.
Okay, so by now, you already know how to do that.
So all we have to do
is decide what the flex container will be
and that is, of course, the pizza title.
Alright, so that is the element that contains these three.
So pizza title will be display flex.
And just like this,
they should be now side by side.
They don't really fit because this text is super large.
So let me actually go ahead
and decrease that in the heading.
So font size, 20 pixels.
And now, as for these tags,
let's also just style them.
And we're gonna take care of the alignment
and all that stuff a bit later.
So for these,
we want a font size of 10 pixels.
So kinda small.
We want them to be uppercase.
So uppercase.
Their color should be white
because each of them should have a background color.
And so for now,
they will kind of disappear.
So let's go ahead
and actually give each of them a background color.
The first one is green.
The second one is blue.
Where are we?
Background color is this one
and here we have the blue one.
Alright.
Let's just give them some padding.
Two pixels on top, seven on the sides.
And some border radius.
Something really large.
It doesn't really matter.
All we want is this exact look here.
And now finally some spacing between them.
So I'm gonna give them both margin left of seven pixels.
Alright, so that looks great already.
So now what we want is these two on the right side
and, of course, they shouldn't stretch like this.
And that's the easiest part, right?
Because remember that the default value
of the align items property is stretch.
And that's why along the cross axis
they're now stretched like this.
So we need to go to the flex container
and say, align items,
and in this case we want them centered.
So watch what happens.
Yeah, now they're really nicely vertically aligned
with this title here.
So without Flexbox,
you would now have to go ahead
and add some margin to the top
and really guess how you'd want this to look.
But like this, it's so much easier.
We don't have to guess anything
in order to make them vertically aligned.
All we have to do is write one line of code
and that's it.
Really straightforward
with really just a small amount of code.
And before we move on,
let's give this entire container here some padding.
So, its the pizza content.
So 35 top, bottom.
30 left and right.
And now all we have to do
is actually make these two,
basically push them to the right side
all the way that they can.
There are two ways of doing this.
So let's think about it.
Well, first we could make it so this title here,
this heading,
occupies all the empty space.
Right, that would automatically push these two
to the right side.
Okay, so let me show that to you.
We could say flex one.
And then, just like this,
you saw that these two were pushed to the right.
Now let's actually take a look at that in the inspector.
In the Chrome dev tools.
So you see,
it now occupies this entire space here.
Whether, when we remove it, then it only has this space.
Now this is not ideal
because actually the element should really end here.
This h1 should kinda end here where it does end actually
and not expand like that all the way to the right side.
Okay, instead what we can do...
Let me bring that down here a bit.
What we can do instead
is to give it a margin right
and set that one to auto
and that will visually have the same effect.
But now you see that the extra space is actually a margin.
And that margin will always automatically
take all the empty space and occupy it.
Let's say that this entire element here
was a lot larger, like 900 pixels.
Well, now you see that we have a lot more space here
and that space is automatically occupied
by that margin right set to auto.
Let's get rid of that here.
Of course, we want 800.
Okay, that was just to demonstrate it to you.
So nice, again we used Flexbox and a couple of techniques
to very easily achieve this great looking part here
of this component.
Okay, so I hope you start seeing
how handy this actually is.
So next up,
we just have this small text.
Let's go ahead and copy it.
And then finally we will have
these icons here with this data.
So right after the pizza content,
we have a paragraph with a class of pizza description.
Then the text.
And close it.
So pizza description.
And I think there's something wrong here.
Oh yeah, so I put this paragraph
outside of the pizza content
and so now we basically have four flex items
in this pizza container.
But that's not where I want this to be obviously.
It should still be inside of the pizza content.
So right after this one actually.
So let's see.
Yeah, that looks a lot better.
So let's just give this a font size of 14 pixels.
And then give some margin to the pizza heading,
actually the pizza title.
Margin bottom and let's say 20 pixels.
And so finally, let's create an element
which will then contain these three elements here.
So these three data about this pizza.
So that is gonna be called the pizza details.
Alright, in there we have three pizza detail.
So without the S.
So three paragraphs basically.
So one pizza detail.
And I will have a small span here
for the emoji
so I can give it some margin to the right.
So span class, actually just gonna call it emoji.
And the first one is the pizza emoji.
And here it is.
Close that one
and now we say it has 850 kilocalories.
And let's just close it and copy this.
Two times.
So now let's use the clock and here it is.
Say that it's gonna take 30 minutes.
And then finally we have the star
basically for the rating.
So we have 4.7 out of five.
Alright, so pizza details and pizza detail.
And also one class for the emoji.
So first of all,
put all the three side by side.
And nothing could be easier than that, right?
Display flex and bam, here we go.
Now let's style the text in there.
We have font size of 15 pixels.
Have a text transform of uppercase
to give them this modern look.
And a margin to the right of 20 pixels.
We can also make them bold
by saying font weight 700
and that should be enough for now.
And we want these icons here
actually a bit bigger than the text.
So let's say font size 20 pixels.
And I'm doing this so we can use some more Flexbox.
Margin right just three pixels.
But now you'll see
that they aren't really aligned vertically, right?
This is not really fine.
So in here, in pizza details, we should fix that.
And again, it's very easy.
All we have to do is say, display flex.
And, of course, they are already side by side.
And now just say align items center.
And here we go.
And this already looks good.
We could now experiment some more here with Flexbox.
For example,
let's say that we actually want to center
all of these flex items inside its container.
The container is pizza details, right?
Let's say we wanna center them along the main axis.
So in this direction.
We could do this and say, justify content center.
And that will look like this.
But there are actually more properties
that I haven't talked about yet.
So let me show them to you.
Another thing that we can do
is to basically divide the empty space that is left
between basically the gaps of these items.
Let me show that to you.
Justify content and it's called space between.
And you can see that this element
goes all the way to the right, or actually to the left.
This one here goes all the way to the right.
And then a space here in between them is the same.
So this one is centered
and we have now the space all around is all the same.
So that is space between.
There is also space around and space evenly.
But I don't think these are really useful.
Let me just show them to you very quick.
And what it does is each flex item
will have the exact same space
on its left and its right side.
So space between I believe is the most useful of them.
And actually you will use them from time to time.
Okay, so now in this case we don't want any of this.
We just want them to be in the beginning
and that is basically the default.
So flex start will put them exactly where they were.
Of course, there's also flex end
to push them all the way to the right side.
But that's also not really what we want.
So we can just get rid of this
because the start is, as you know,
the default anyway.
Now we're almost done.
All there is to do is to push this entire element here
so the pizza details,
all the way to the bottom as much as we can.
So how could we achieve that?
Well, it would be really nice to use Flexbox for that.
Now the default behavior for Flexbox
is to put elements side by side.
So we can push, as we did here,
these elements all the way to the right side.
Remember we did the margin right and set it to auto here
on this element,
which then pushed these two all the way to the right.
But up until this point,
we only did this in the horizontal direction
which is the default.
But we can change that.
So we can actually make Flexbox not go from left to right.
So put all the elements side by side
so the elements go one after the other
and so the main axis,
which was originally in this way,
will then be from top to bottom like this.
Okay, so let me show that to you again.
And in order to do that,
I will now set pizza content
which is the entire wide element,
and we'll set it to Flexbox.
And so, where do we have that?
It is the flex content.
So I will say display flex.
And watch what happens now by default
if I put all of these side by side.
Just what we expected.
Because that's default behavior of Flexbox.
But let's now actually change that.
We do that by using the flex direction property.
And the default for flex direction is row.
So that's why we get all of these elements here in one row.
But we can also change it to column.
And then it's gonna look like this.
Basically, it's gonna look exactly like it did before.
Okay, but these are now actually flex items
we can now manipulate.
We could now say,
align items, which is along the cross axis remember, center.
So what do you think will happen?
So it centered these along the cross axis.
And since our main axis is now this way here,
the cross axis is this way.
Alright, makes sense?
So that's why align items
works in this direction here as well.
Okay, we could also do justify content.
And set that one to center.
And try to guess what's gonna happen.
Yep, it's gonna put all of these elements
in the center along the main axis
which now is, remember, from top to bottom.
Alright, so that's one very important aspect
of Flexbox as well
that we can change the flex direction.
We can also do column reverse, for example.
And what that's gonna do
is reverse the order of the elements.
So we had this at the top and this at the bottom.
And so now it's inverted.
Alright, but we simply want it to be a column.
Now what we wanted originally to do
is to push the pizza details here
all the way to the bottom.
And so let's do that.
So pizza details.
And can you guess how we're gonna do that?
It's actually very similar to what we did up here
in this pizza...
Oh, what's that?
So as I was saying,
it's gonna be in a very similar way
to what we did up here.
All we have to do is to say margin to the top should be auto
and just like this it should actually work.
Well, it is in the wrong place.
So of course it's not in pizza detail but in pizza details
because that is the flex item, right?
So margin top and there we go.
This margin here is now automatically calculated by Flexbox
in order to occupy this empty space.
Let's actually check that out here using the dev tools again
and you will see we have all this margin
as you see here in this orange color.
So that is the margin that is defined by margin auto.
And that was the whole reason
why we actually used Flexbox here on that pizza content
because without Flexbox
this margin auto doesn't even work like this.
So if I would simply remove it from here,
so if this was no longer a Flexbox item,
well then it will simply look like this again.
And so, I think with that we're actually done.
And what we have here looks exactly the same
as it does in here.
So let's count how many times
we actually used Flexbox in this kind of small component.
One, two, three Flexbox containers.
Four and five and actually six.
So we actually find six flex containers
just in this small component.
And that is enough to show you
how powerful and useful actually Flexbox is
to lay out the elements on a page like this.
And as your websites grow,
you'll see yourself using it all over the place
and all the time.
As an exercise,
you could try to recreate the exact same thing
but without using Flexbox
and instead using margins and floats.
And you will then see how much more code you will write
and how much longer it's gonna take you
and how much more difficult it'll probably be.
So if you have the time,
that will probably be a great exercise.
Now as I said in the beginning,
in this small project,
of course we barely just scratched the surface of Flexbox.
There is so much more to learn.
Many more techniques
and all the properties that it includes.
But in this small video I, of course,
couldn't do all that
because that requires an entire new course.
And that brings me actually
to the other new course that I have here on Udemy
which is called Advanced CSS and Sass.
And it teaches you all these new properties
that I talked about in the beginning of the video,
or actually in the last video,
and so much more.
So it has three different projects
where you will learn to use all these advanced techniques.
You will have one project that is only just for Flexbox
where you're gonna code a huge design using Flexbox.
And also a project using just CSS grid
to learn the most cutting edge layout technology
that we have right now in CSS.
Okay, so give it a try
and if it sounds interesting,
then of course I am more than happy
to welcome you into that course as well.
That's all I have to tell you for now.
I hope you like this video and see you next time.