Now it's time to talk about inspiration.
Inspiration is absolutely essential,
especially for a beginner like you.
Believe me, without inspiration you'll have a hard time
to even start anything.
Of course, you don't have to reinvent website layouts
and user interface elements such as buttons or navigations.
Instead of that, you should use other websites
as inspiration in order to see what other leading designers
are doing right.
So, here are some steps that you may follow.
First, collect a bunch of designs that you like
and that you think are well-designed.
Then, understand everything about them
by answering those questions.
Why do they look good?
What do these sites have in common?
And how were they built in HTML and CSS?
Now, in order to analyze the HTML and CSS code,
you can use a Google Chrome Developer tools
if you are familiar with them.
You can actually learn a lot by just doing this.
Believe me, this is a very effective method.
And next thing I wanna tell you about inspiration
is steal like an artist.
Yes, you heard that right.
So, basically, I want you to make your design similar
to webpages you like, at least at first.
When you're starting out, don't worry so much
about being original.
Once you're getting better and better, then originality
will come automatically.
Of course, you should not literally copy anything,
but you get the idea, right?
So, where should you actually get inspiration?
Don't worry, you will find some great websites in the Ebook,
where you can find inspiration.
For instance, Dribble is a show-and-tell for designers
and it's invite-only, so the quality you'll find there
is quite high.
Basically, all great designers are there,
and you can learn a lot from them.
We already saw some inspiration in many
of the other lectures, so you can just go back
and take a deeper look at those if you want.