Welcome to Section 12 of the complete web developer course I hope you enjoyed the previous app making
section and are already thinking of an app that you can build and put into Google Play and the App Store.
In this section we'll be looking at the latest versions of HVM L and C S S that is HDMI 5 and CSSA 3.
Both of them are big updates to their respective language and allow us to do a lot more powerful things
and we could before.
With HD in 0 5 we'll be seeing how we can integrate audio and video into our apps as well as make our
forms a lot more powerful and user friendly.
We'll even see how the canvas tag works and how we can use it to start drawing directly onto our HD
M-L page and even create real HMO based games.
With CSSA three We'll see how to do things like introduce gradients and make our webapps interactive
using animation.
There's a lot of powerful stuff here.
So I hope you're looking forward to it and I'll see you as always at the beginning of the next section.