Welcome to Chapter 11 of the complete web developer course you've now covered eight TMLC SS and javascript
on the client side and HP miscue and API is on the server side as well as seeing how you can use bootstrap
and wordpress to put together great looking Web sites very quickly in this section we're going to be
taking a slightly different tack and we're going to see how we can use the skills that we've learned
so far to build real apps that we can put on Google Play and the App Store using web technologies is
a great way to build simple apps because we only need to code the app once and then we can just package
it to the various different app stores.
It's the only way to do that.
And I'm going to show you exactly how to do it in this section.
Once again I hope you have a number of ideas for different apps.
And you start putting them together using the techniques we're about to learn.
Tweet me if you date and I'll forward your tweet to the world.
Enjoy learning how to make mobile apps and I'll see you at the beginning of Section 12.