Congratulations on making it to Section 9 of the complete web developer of course I hope you enjoyed
working with HP.
I managed to get the weather scraper projects a good guy at the end of the previous section.
Now BHP is a very powerful language but it's limited in what it can do without connecting it to a database.
And that's what we're going to be doing in this section.
So we'll be learning the Maya skew wealth database language and seeing how it integrates with THP.
My school is extremely widely used and a very standard database language so it's a great first one to
learn it will allow you to store things like your users usernames and passwords as well as actual content
for your website.
So there's a lot to learn here.
But once you've got to the end of the section a combination of PH P and my s u l on the server side
and HCM L C Ss and javascript on the client side will actually allow you to build any web site in existence.
So you really should be looking at Web sites that you can build for friends and family or be looking
for work that you can get on freelance Web sites if you want to go that way.
As always I'm really keen to see what you're making.
So please do tweet me a link to whatever you've built and I'll send it on to the world.
Enjoy learning about my school and I'll see you at the beginning of Section 10.