All right we're now going to take our javascript's to the next level by seeing how we can not only just
change the content of an element but we can also append content to it which means take whatever's there
and then add some extra text to it and we can make a whole element appear out of nothing.
So let's get cracking.
Let's add a second paragraph and I'm going to put in the words.
Javascript is.
And then dot dot dot
and we'll give this an ID of a second.
Paragraph and here's a little challenge can you add some code.
And a second button so that when that second button is clicked the content of this paragraph changes
too.
Hello Rob.
So exactly like the first button behaves.
So add a new button so that when you press that button content of this paragraph changes to hello.
Well go for it.
I managed it.
It's just a bit of code copy and paste really is all we need.
So let's copy the button code
I'm going to change
change text to append text so append means adding something to the end of it and we'll call this second
button.
And it's just have a look.
OK.
Yes.
That all looks fine.
Obviously a pen text at the moment doesn't do anything.
So we need to set up some javascript to connect that to some code.
So again I'm going to copy and paste
and all we need to do is change the necessary bits so that it does what we want.
So we want it so that when the second button is clicked it updates the content of second paragraph too.
Hello Rob.
So a second button of course has the ID of a second button.
So we want to make this function happen when second button is clicked.
I would do that using Document or get element by id second button on click equals and then function.
So a very quick question.
What would happen if I ran this code now and then click the second button.
What will happen.
You got it right.
It should update hello world too.
Hello Rob.
Every It does because it's just doing the same thing as what the first button did.
Updating the elements with ID text which is this one too.
Hello Rob.
So we wanted to make it so that it updated javascript is and the ID for that paragraph is second paragraph
and that's it.
So that's going to update second paragraph too.
Hello Rob.
With any luck.
Fantastic.
OK.
So that was the mini challenge and how I expected you to do it.
Let's see how we achieve what we originally wanted which was how to append some content to this.
So first off the content that I want to append is going to be awesome.
So we end up with javascript is awesome the way I'm going to do it and it's going to take quite a long
line of text.
I'm just going to extend this out so we can do it all in one line is by copying and pasting all of this
and then popping it in there and adding a plus symbol.
And before I explain how that works just take a moment to have a look at that and see if you can work
out why that will append awesome to the content of second paragraph.
I hope you got it.
What we're essentially doing here is we're taking the HD M-L of second paragraph which is javascript
is dot dot dot and then we're setting that equal to the end of second paragraph which is javascript
is and then we're adding that to awesome or we're adding awesome to that.
So we're setting the enraged him out of the second paragraph to whatever it is.
Plus the word awesome.
So we're essentially adding the word awesome to the end or in programming terms were appending the word
awesome to whatever the content was before.
So let's take a look see if that does what we want.
So I refresh a pen text pen text and there we go.
Javascript is awesome so another teeny challenge then could you append something else to this line and
make it so that it becomes I think javascript is awesome.
Go for it.
All right.
I hope you manage that.
All we need to do is before we get the contents of the second paragraph we're going to add I think in
double quotes with a space at the end.
Otherwise it's going to be all one word and then plus again.
And this means I think.
And then whatever the content is and then the word awesome.
So let's have a look
javascript is.
And I think javascript is awesome.
I agree.
All right.
So finally then how could we make some content appear out of thin air out of nowhere.
I'm actually going to set this as a challenge.
See if you can figure it out.
So how can we have no content here just a button.
And then when you click that button you get some text whatever you want that to be go for it.
Did you manage it.
OK.
It was a pretty tough challenge but well done if you got there.
Well I'm going to do it is have a paragraph with an ID of empty paragraph and then that is of course
just an empty paragraph.
It's just blank.
Nothing will display on the screen.
And then I'm going to have a button with an ID of create
paragraph
and then I'll have the words create text on it.
And rather than copying and pasting this time I'll create the code from scratch just gives us an opportunity
to see it and talk it through once again.
So we want something to happen when the person with ID create a paragraph is clicked.
So that means we need to get that button first off and we do that using document to say that we want
something within this document and then we say we want to get the element by its ID then in brackets
and quites we give the ID.
So that create paragraph and then we set on click to be a function and then we have curly brackets in
which we're going to put the code for our function.
So that means whatever I write in here will happen when that button is clicked.
And then all we need to do is make it so that we select the paragraph with ID empty paragraph and put
some content in it.
So it's exactly the same as what we had up here when we changed the content just in this case we're
changing it from blank to some text.
So let's say that an action document or get element by ID.
And the idea this time is empty paragraph and then we want to set in each L to say hi there.
And that's it.
Let's take a look.
So refresh that said create text.
Nothing's happening.
Let's have a look.
Find out what's going wrong.
It must be an error in my code somewhere.
Maybe you can see what it is but let's have a look at the console document or get an ID.
Each is not a function.
Aha of course a line 42 this line here.
What I've done of course as you probably noticed was I tried to pass the string high there to enrich
DML and as it says enriched him is not a function it's a value it's the content of empty paragraph.
So what I should have done is set it equal to and then.
Hi there.
All right no worries.
Good use of the console.
Let's have another look.
Create text now.
And there it is.
Brilliant.
So we've created something from nothing there which is particularly useful if you've got an error message
or something you want to display to the user.
Once they've done something a very quick thing to say is that this can be any age.
Tim L we've only used tech so far but you can bet HCM L right in here.
As well.
So let's have a look now.
We've created a heading so you can put lipstick and performs in there you can put whole chunks of text
if you want to any HD M-L will do.
All right.
I hope you enjoy those challenges.
We're going to have an even bigger challenge in the next video where we're going to create the first
part of our reaction game that will make at the end of this section.
And this first part is called disappearing circles.