So for in the Jaker section we've seen have Jay query is a little bit easier to read and write than
javascript.
And it's a bit more flexible as well in that we can easily select classes or a range of element types
using exactly the same syntax.
But there's also a number of functions that are very easy to do with Jay equerry.
That would be very difficult to do with plain Javascript.
And one of those is fading content.
So let's see how easy that is to achieve with Jay query.
So let's try and find out whatever item is clicked when we click it.
Rather than making it disappear.
So again to select the item we use this and then it's as simple as
applying the function fade out to it.
Don't forget the parentheses.
Let's take a look.
There we go.
So a lovely face animation just by using a single key word there.
We can also use hige just to show you which is effectively the same as setting the display to none.
As we saw in the previous section that just does the fade but without any kind of gradual fighting as
with pretty much all j queery functions we can apply a lot of parameters and settings to those functions
if we want.
And the easy way to find out what those are is to do a quick search.
So if I start with something like Jay queery fade out likely the top result will be the Jay queery dot
com Web site itself which I thoroughly recommend has some really good documentation and examples on
it.
So if you want to find out for example you might want to make it fade out more slowly or more quickly
or in a number of different ways.
Then you'll get all of the options here.
Let's just look at a couple of the examples.
So this shows you roughly what's going on there.
But we can also look at some direct examples like that one that you can see that that's a slow fade
out.
So we could try that ourselves if we want.
And there's some more complicated content here that looks like it's going to fade out when it's clicked
and say if I try that.
There you go.
So the click is doing the fade out and then it's adding some text as well.
So that's the next thing we're going to see.
I'll just show you that again.
When we clicked on really that it did the fade out.
And then when the fadeout completed it did something else and that can be really useful not just with
fighting but with any function that might take a certain amount of time.
You often want to do something else just when it's completed.
So let's see how we do that using our fade here.
So first off let's change it to a nice slow fade out so that we can see that we get to see it happening
a little more slowly.
So how would we add a callback function i.e. a function that happens when the fadeout is complete.
Well we add it as a parameter in the function call itself.
So just after we add the slow parameter we're going to add a function and then this will be defined
in just the same way that we set up a function on the click.
So whatever I write here will now happen as soon as the fight is completed.
So for now let's just do a night to let fade out has finished.
All right let's take a look.
Fade out and there we go.
Feda has finished.
So one of the particularly useful situations for callbacks is when you're getting data from another
web site or another bit of your Web site which will see how to do it and a couple of videos time.
And that could take a while.
If you've got a large bit of data and use an internet connection it's quite slow for example.
So you want to wait until you've got that data and then process it and do something with it and callback
functions are the perfect way to do that.
All right let's have a few challenges then I'm going to get rid of all of this.
And the first challenge is going to be can you create a paragraph with some text and a button such that
when the button is pressed the paragraph fades out.
Bedford
OK I read that one well I'm going to get rid of my style's
because I don't need them any more.
So in my paragraph
this is some text from them and they don't.
And then my button I'll give it an ID of fadeout
and then we'll call it fade out text.
All right.
And then I just need to select my button
like that and then I want this to have a click function attached to it just like that.
And I want to find out the text when that button is clicked.
So I'm going to select the text or I'll just do it using P because it's a paragraph and then fadeout
simple as that.
Let's take a look.
Fadeout text.
I've made a mistake.
Anyone see what it is.
I forgot the parentheses.
It's a function.
So you always have parentheses after it.
Even if you're not going to have any options like slow or callback function.
I notice as well once it's faded out it's gone.
So the display property of the paragraph is made equal to none.
Just as we saw before and it's effectively not there anymore.
OK so challenge 2 is going to be.
Can you have some text in a different paragraph which is initially hidden and then when you press another
button it fades that text in different
writes.
Have you managed to do that.
So this text will be hidden initially and now we're going to need some ideas.
Differentiate between our two paragraphs
so we'll have text and hidden text and I'll change this to text so they're not confusing each other.
And then I need to make hidden text hidden initially so I'll bring some styles back in.
I would get that I only need to style hidden text
and the only style I need to give it is display.
None that will make it hidden initially.
And then I'm going to have a button.
The ID is going to be fade in.
Which is a little clue as to what the function is that I'm going to use and that fade in text.
Let's just check that that's all I care.
Yep obviously fade in text at the moment doesn't do anything for that.
My semi-colon there.
So to make the fade in button do something I need to select it in the usual way.
Fade in and I'm adding a click function to it in the same way as usual and then as I hope you figure
it out to make something Faden you just select it.
So this is hidden text and we want to make it fade in and don't forget your parentheses.
Let's have a look.
Didn't Text fantastic.
There it is.
All right now there's one more challenge for you and this one is a bit of a tricky one but I have given
you a clue to it earlier in the video.
So what I now want you to do is to go back to having just a single paragraph but instead of having just
a fade out button we're going to have a toggle button on what that toggle button is going to do is if
the text is there it will make it disappear.
And if the text is not there it will make it appear.
So that's a pretty big challenge.
There's a number of different ways you could do it but give it a shot.
Good luck
OK.
Did you manage him.
I'm going to show you a couple of different ways starting with what I think is the best method ending
with a method that allows us to use callbacks which is quite nice.
So let's do everything with a single function.
And now we're working on the toggle button.
So as I change quite a lot there let's just check at the moment if I click toggle text it should fade
out great of course but it doesn't say yet is faith back in.
So what I need is some way to know whether the text has faded out or not depending on what stage we
are on our page.
There's no way I can know just with the code here.
I need to look at some property of the page and what I can do as I hope some of you spot it is I can
use the display CSSA property to find out whether or not the text has been faded out.
So if the
text
element has got a display
property of none then we're going to want to fight it in
reps.
We want to take the text and fade it in.
So that that's what I was hoping you would think of doing.
Don't worry if you didn't but this is quite a neat way of doing it.
So we're looking at the display property of the s of the text element if that's equal to none.
That means it's not displayed.
So we want to fight it in if it's not equal to none.
That means it is displayed.
So we want to fight it out.
That's that's look.
So toggling it fades out suddenly again fighting are so very well done.
If you did it that way I'll just show you another way that might be better in certain situations and
that is to have a variable which keeps track of the state of the paragraph text.
So we might call it something like text showing text displaying or something like that and will initially
set it to true because when we first read the page the text is going to show.
And then instead of looking at the CSSA property we can just look at if text showing is true.
And in fact we can do a bit of a shortcut and we can just look at if text showing because remember the
if statement is looking for something which is true or false.
And one advantage of using Brillion variables is that they are either true or false so you don't need
to write is equal to.
You can do if you want it'll work but you can leave it like just text showing.
So let's have a quick look at that.
But of course if Tex is sharing I want it to fade out rather than fade in.
So let's just make sure that's working for the fade out.
It is.
Yes.
It's not going to work for the fade in yet because we haven't updated text showing.
So this is a little bit unnecessary but I like to use callback from actions whenever we can.
So I'm going to add a callback function to our fade out
such that when the fade out is complete we'll set text showing to fourths.
So now it's no longer showing.
So if we click it again it will fade it back in.
And of course we'll need a callback function for that as well which resets text text showing back to
true.
OK let's check it out.
So it fades out fades back in fade out fades back in.
Fantastic.
So as I say in this case I prefer the previous method just because it's a bit neater.
But you might have situations where you can't just grab the information you need from a CSSA property.
And in those situations you're probably going to want some kind of variable which keeps track of the
state of the various items on your page.
Well then if you manage to do that challenge don't worry too much if you didn't it was a toughie.
So now we know how to feed content in and out.
We realized that fighting is actually a specific example of the more general animating content which
we can do with Jay queery.
So let's find out how we do that.
We'll have our elements changing size shrinking growing moving all over the place.
It's going to be a lot of fun and we'll do it in the next video.