All right.
So we've seen how we can use bootstrap to customize our forms and tables to make them look beautiful
and make them a lot more fun to use.
We're now going to whiz through a few of the components that bootstrap provides.
You'll want to use in your web sites because they look great and add a lot of functionality as well.
So back on the bootstrap Web site click on components and then we've already got two buttons.
We know how they work.
So I'm going to move on to the excellently named Jumbotron which is essentially a big rectangle that
is designed to go at the top of the home page of your site and be a real attention grabbing thing.
So you've probably seen this before.
If you go to almost any big news startup web site such as you but up come you'll see that very commonly
use some kind of big image bit of text and then a big call to action.
So the idea of that really is that it funnels the user where they want them to go.
So what is it you but want you to do when you go to their Web site.
They want you to sign up.
That's the big thing.
So there's a nice big image there.
Simple bit of text.
And then the call to action.
And that's what the JumboTron is for.
So let's again copy the code and take a look at it.
On our own page I'm going to get rid of the container for the moment because JumboTron is one of those
things you probably want to stretch right to the edge of the screen and there it is.
So we've got no background image there but that's pretty easy to add.
But what we do have is a readymade element to catch the user's attention and get them to do something
with the button.
The code is pretty simple.
All we've got is a div with a class of Jumbotron just indent it nicely.
We've got a custom class for the one which we don't really need.
It just makes it a bigger thinner text as you can see them so we can leave that in if you like.
And then we've got a little bit of text paragraph with a class of lead So it's a bigger more spaced
out text than usual and we've got a horizontal rule and normal paragraph.
And then our call to action button.
So nice and simple but very useful.
Just the same.
We've known from the Jumbotron like she alerts which I've used in a number of sites.
There are a great way of getting simple messages displayed to the user.
And they look like this.
So essentially if the users just filled in a form to send you an e-mail or something like that you might
want to have this green one to show them a success or a warning they didn't fill out one of the boxes
for example or read in your message if something actually went wrong.
So let's copy the warning one over and you can see that this is pretty straightforward.
We've got our Dave with a class of alert and an alert warning to clarify that this is going to be the
red one.
We've got a semantic role is equal to alert.
Again if we remove that it wouldn't make any difference but it makes each day mail clearer.
And then we've just got some content which could be anything we like is in there.
So there we go.
There's a warning.
We've also got a special alert link color which just makes the link if there is going to be one in your
alert fit in better the background and text color.
And I really like this feature.
You can just add an alert dismissable class to your alert and you just need to add a button which again
will copy the code for and then see what's going on.
And you add that inside your alert and then you've got a button here with a type of button.
A class is equal to close which means that it will have some javascript attached to it so it will close
the alert that it's in when it's clicked.
The thing that is going to dismiss the data dismiss is the alert.
And then you've got this thing called an aria label.
Now a RIAA stands for accessible rich Internet applications which is another one of these things that
makes your Web site easier to use.
For those with disabilities which is yet another reason for using bootstrap because these things are
built in.
So if a user was using a screen reader for example or had accessibility options switched on in their
browser they may see a message called close there.
And then we've got our present times semi-colon which is our way of getting that X symbol and an area
hidden is equal to true means that the X won't be displayed if the user is on a screen reader because
they will see clothes instead.
OK so let's just see that in action.
There we go.
So you can see the X now and if I click that it disappears.
Wonderful alerts which are really useful.
You can also work with the javascript if you want to make them do something fancy but we're not going
to look at that right now.
OK.
So there are two more components that I want to show you in this video.
And the first is the progress component which is a really handy way of showing the user's progress in
something.
So it's pretty straightforward.
We use the progress HDMI 5 Element give it a class give it a value a maximum and then some text if you
want that will display.
So let's have a look.
So let's just change the value to say 35 percent.
We might as well change this one as well.
And we're going to go to a very simple progress bar which you can update using javascript if you want
but it might just be a static way of showing how far before through your sign up process for example
something like that.
And we can add nice colors.
So let's do that let's give our
progress a class of progress success.
And why not give it a Strypes effect as well.
Which of course we are using progress striped OK let's take a look.
There we go.
Very nice.
The last one then is a new component for bootstrap 4 which is very flexible and has replaced a number
of other components.
And that is the card.
So it will be pretty clear what it is when you see it.
Something like this.
So it's kind of an image and then a title and then some information and the call to action.
So let's have a little look to see how that looks in our site.
It's just indent everything nicely.
There we go.
So we've got I thought with one there of course we don't actually have an image so let's pop in a quick
image from Wikipedia just so we've got something to work with.
We've had Homer and Marge say let's have one of Simpson.
So I will click on him
and then I'm just going to control click and copy image address and then paste that straight into the
SIRC for our image and then we just want a standard SIRC as we're used to here source so ill only use
data as I see if you're doing something quite fancy with images.
We're just loading one up.
So it's just SIRC that we use.
OK.
So that looks pretty good but it's obviously stretched out right to the edge of the screen.
Often what you're going to want to use this for is if for example you want to show three features of
your brilliant app then you might want to have an image and then some information about that feature
and then a call to action to do with that feature.
And that's what these are generally designed for.
So let's have a quick look see how we do that as obviously some other content types that we can add
to them.
You can play around with those if you like but I'm going to focus on layout here.
So to change the layout we need to do is add some columns as we've seen before.
So we just add a class of row and then a class of call.
And then however many many columns we want the width of that object to be.
So here's a challenge for you.
Can you make it so that there are four cards each with the same content going from left to right on
the screen.
Go for it.
OK.
I hope you manage that.
All you needed was a div with a class of rho to contain all of our lives.
And then we can contain each of the cards in a div with a class of call for column S-M because we want
to stack when it gets onto a phone screen.
And then we want four of them 12 divided by four is three.
So they're going to be three columns each.
And you can see that there's an extra class of card block here as well which provides some nice styles
it will work without it but it just had some nice spacing for the cards as they go from left to right.
Can I just get indenting all nice.
So that's one two three four and then have a look.
Wonderful.
So are four cards going along and they will remain as they are until we hit the phone screen size and
then they will stack.
So as always cards I've got a bunch of different options which you might want to check out if you're
going to be using them in your site various layouts headers footers etc. but that's as far as we're
going to go in this video in the next video we're going to look at bootstrap modals which is a more
interactive feature of bootstrap and we'll use that as an opportunity to see how we can interact with
the javascript bootstrap as well.
See that.