In this final video in the HVM L5 section we'll be looking at just a small number of remaining cool
features of HDMI 5 and why we might want to use them to start off one of the biggest philosophical changes
behind HVM L5 is that we're now aiming to make our HDMI out more human readable than it was before and
this has led to a number of changes on the styling front.
For example changing be too strong but it's also led to some new elements some of which we've actually
seen in the bootstrap section of the course and in wordpress as well.
So one of them is the article which is essentially just a div that's used for article content so it
would be the main content section of a blog post for example.
But then we can style it directly
using article without using any classes or IDs say something like that.
Let's take a look there again.
There are a number of other elements which are essentially just divs but renamed to make your HMO more
readable and they are header footer Article Section nav and menu.
Again some of which we've seen before.
But all of these are essentially divs but we just use these names to make our HMO more standardized
and readable.
One small note is that Internet Explorer at the time of recording will by default give these elements
a display of in line which means they'll appear to the right of previous elements rather than a display
of block which means that they will stretch to the whole width of that container and go into a new line.
And that's normally what we want for these div like elements.
So if you're going to be using them it's recommended to put display as blog to make sure that they're
displayed correctly in Internet Explorer.
We can even create our own elements which is pretty if I'm using javascript so we can use something
like document don't create elements let's say we wanted to call an element a container.
And then we could use container in each DML as well.
Which is quite different.
What we're talking about new elements is also a new image containing elements called figer
and this is designed to help us put captions and connects those with images.
So let's say we've got an image
let's just go and find one quickly
let's have Maggie Simpson
so we'll just feed that image.
Every gay copy you are al great.
Just make sure that is displaying properly that we get.
And while we're out in an image it's worth stating that in HCM L5 for an image to be direct HTL it has
to have an old tag so all images should have all tags in H.A. five.
And then if you want to have our caption we use fake caption
and then just put something like Mike Simpson and then if we have a look and see that the caption is
nicely aligned to the image obviously we probably want to style that to make it display how we want.
But again the aim is really to make each DML readable and to see that this is definitely supposed to
be a caption related to this particular image.
While we're talking about new tags This one's not exactly new.
That has been redefined and we can now use small to display some small text
if I wanted to quote the location of this image source then I could do that easily using small.
And the last new one I'll show you is Mark which essentially highlights your text.
Take a look that we get.
We've seen this next one before particularly in the mobile app section but we can now add data attributes
with anything we like.
So I might want to add data description and then use baby or something like that.
This would be perfectly valid.
Tim L..
I can put whatever word I like in there and then if I want to access that and get the value of that
tag at some point I can do that easily with javascript
which I remember I don't need the type variable and they enabled him at 5.
I'll just get this an ID
so to access the data description.
I use document to get element by id and then get the element by its ID and then get attribute and attribute
that I want to get is data description and then for now I could just let that
should I let you be.
Everything or just comment that out find out.
And now there's just two more things left.
I'd like to show you.
The first is a new type of input called range
which is very simply a slider.
You can see it on the bottom there and we can slide from left to right to choose value.
We can specify some options as well.
So we could specify what the minimum value is.
So we if from zero there what the maximum value is.
So maybe 100 and we can also specify the step value.
So we might want it to go up in tens or ones depending on our form and then that doesn't change the
look of the slider.
But it does if we change the step to something high you'll notice that we can any of them pick particular
values.
So it jumps up and down and then we can get a result of that either through javascript's using Vau or
through our form when it's submitted via page pate.
Excellent.
So one more thing and I've saved one of the best features to last and this one is the content editable
feature which essentially makes any content on your Web site editable by the user.
So if I just add some code here or just some straightforward text and we then refresh the page as the
user.
I can now go in and edit that text directly.
So you could use that to create a diary or interactive coding application.
And one advantage over say text areas is that we can use this on any element type so if we wanted to
create a to do list app for example we could make the UL content editable or just put an example list
element in there.
And then if we take a look.
So we can now edit
the options that are there but we can also add options of our own and the formatting is maintained.
So we're getting a new list item as we add a new item on our to do list.
So that takes us to the end of what we're going to look at from HDMI 5.
Now it's time to look at one of the major new specifications that goes along with it and that's CSSA
3.