Having looks at HVM L5 in some detail we're now going to examine the new features in CSSA three CSSA
three is the latest version of the cascading style sheets language and it brings a lot of new and cool
features that we're going to be examining in the next few videos.
We're going to start by looking at advanced selectors and pseudo classes which allow us to access particular
elements very easily then we're going to look at how we can do calculations within CSSA.
So for example we could change the width of one column of a page relative to the screen size without
using javascript.
Then we'll look at the more graphical sites including gradients shadows transformations and animations.
And finally we'll look at some of the new layout features specific to CSSA three to get you a little
bit excited though I thought I'd show you a few of the cool things that we can do.
So we can do all sorts of fading effects and transitions using C-s three we can do cool tech shadowing
like bats and even make it interactive as the user can move the light source around we can make a cube
which has text on all sides and we can rotate around with the arrow keys.
And we got this nice cool parallax effect as well where we can effectively have depth to our images
and then animate them completely using CSSA.
So there are a lot of cool stuff we can do.
We'll start in the next video.
Looking at selectors.