So alongside the for loop we have the while loop which has hopefully you remember from the javascript
section of the Course is just really another way to achieve the same thing but because of the different
way that it's set up might be more useful in different circumstances.
So let's take a look with the While loop will set up an initial variable outside of the loop and then
we do a loop while something is true.
So if we were going to do the same thing that we did before we would keep going as long as I is less
than 10 then we have our brackets to denote what we can do as long as it is less than 10.
And very importantly we have to remember to increment each time if we don't do that it will just go
on forever and ever.
And then we just put our code that we want to happen here.
We get let's have a look.
So that does exactly the same thing as we did before.
So here's a quick while the challenge for you.
Can you use a while loop to display the first 10 items the first 10 numbers in the five times table
OK.
Did you manage it.
So the first item in the five times table is five.
And we want to keep going as long as I is less than or equal to the tenth item which is 50 and instead
of adding 1 to each time we're going to add I going to set.
I'd say I plus five we get let's have a look that should do it.
Fantastic.
You may have done it another way as well.
If we actually just use Undo to go back to what we had before we could actually use that code but set
the initial value to 1.
We want the first 10 items in the times table.
But then if we don't display I instead we calculate say a J.
Which is I multiplied by 5 and then we just display that and that should give us the exact same thing
that we got.
So well done if you solved it that way as well.
That's a good solution.
All right.
Second challenge then can you create an array any four items you like.
You know what I'm going to choose and then use a while loop to display each of the values in that array.
If you can figure out how to do it.
Good luck.
OK.
How do you manage that.
We show you how I would have done it.
So let's have our good out family right.
It's going to be an array with for all our favorite characters Kirsten Tommy and Ralph and then we're
going to set up our counter again.
We're going to start at zero because we'll start with the zero item in the array.
And we want to keep going as long as I is less than the number of items in the array.
We know how to get that size of.
And then there right
whenever I'm doing a while loop.
I always do the plus plus before I do anything else.
Otherwise I forget it.
And then I try and run my code and then it crashes or does something horrendous.
So then all we need to do is to display each item which we get from family string.
I let's put a line break in as well.
There we go.
So that's how we use a while loop loop through an array.
You can see though I think that the foreach loop is the simplest way to do that and that's it.
So that's all we need to know about while loops.
For now we're now heading toward the two big challenges for this section and for those we'll need a
way of interacting with the user.
So you notice so far all of the people have written it's not been interactive use couldn't do anything
to change the output of this.
So to make interactive scripts using HP we need a way to pass information from the Web site to the server
and we're going to see two different ways to do that in the next two videos.
The first of which is using GET variables.