All right so now that we've figured out how to log in using both sessions and cookies there's one more
thing that we need to understand before we make our first web site using a log in system our secret
diary project and that is how to store uses passwords securely.
Now this is quite a complex topic and what I'm going to tell you it is definitely not everything there
is to know about web site security but it's everything you need to get your users passwords as secure
as they can be.
So let's first off see how we're doing things at the moment and realize why that's such a bad idea.
So at the moment in our system our password is just stored as plain.
So that's perfectly fine from a user's point of view.
We can just lock them in test their password against the one that they've entered and we'll get them
in.
But if someone gets access to our database then obviously they can just access all of our user accounts.
That's pretty bad.
But it's even worse that most people use the same password for a number of different Web sites.
So not only could access your users account on your Web site but they might well be able to access their
Pay-Pal that Twitter account and many worse Web sites sites.
So we need to encrypt the password in some way.
But that encryption has to work in such a way that when the user enters that password we can still test
what they've entered against the encryption that we have stored.
So there is a process designed specifically for this and this is known as creating a hash for a particular
string.
And there's one well-established type of hash that we normally use Impey HP and that is M.D 5 and the
M.D five function essentially takes a string.
So let's say our user has a very bad password and does a one way encryption on it.
So it essentially turns it into a long alphanumeric string that is very hard to reverse encrypt.
But given the initial string it's the same output every time.
So if we store this in our database then when the user tried to log in we could M.D 5:8 and then check
that against our database and we would then know that the user had the password correct.
So this is not as one way encryption because it's easy to go one way and this result is unique for that
word.
But it's hard to go the other way.
So you might think we're done right.
We can just store the empty five hash of our users passwords in our database and no one can go the other
way.
Unfortunately not because the empty five string is unique to each original string.
Hackers can quite easily create long lists of empty fives for commonly used passwords and you can actually
check this for yourself online using a web site such as Krock station dot net.
So if we take our long string here and paste it into crack station dot net
put in the capture of
then it will check that hash against its known hashes and you can see it's got a password straight away.
So that's the problem because this is a unique one way hash common passwords will be detectable by your
hackers.
And we don't want that.
Note that if we do have a properly complex password something like that and save that and apply M.D
5 to that then this will be secure.
So anyone who has a good password in your database so anyone who has a good password in your database
will still be secured with this method because it won't be on a pre created list.
But that's not good enough for us.
We want even the people who have weak passwords to be able to feel secure with our system.
So how are we going to achieve that.
Well you could think of this as level 2 decryption.
It's definitely better than not encrypting at all but it's not the best we can do.
So how might we get to a level three level three encryption add something known as a socket and that
is essentially a long string of easily numbers and letters.
But it could contain anything which then we put in front of the password each time.
And what we're effectively doing that is turning a weak password into a strong one and then if we see
what the empty five result of that is and we attempts
to crack that it should fail.
DAVID So so this is pretty good and definitely better than level 2.
But we're not quite there yet because especially if you've got a large number of users then it's possible
for the hacker to get hold of that sold somehow and then work out the M.D 5s for that salt and commonly
used passwords.
And that would still enable them to decrypt the commonly used passwords.
So what's our final top level for encryption.
Well what we do is we have a different salt for every item in the database and that's actually quite
easy to create.
We can use something like the ID for that particular right.
So imagine that we've got a right ID of 73.
We can then
D5 the row ID and use that as a solved.
And then because we've got a different slot for every user in our database it's still not 100 percent
impossible for the hacker to get hold of one of the solids.
But if they do that doesn't give them access to any of the other passwords and they have to start from
scratch with each user.
So essentially it will be such a long and complicated process that it's probably not worth it for the
hacker to try and decode even commonly used passwords.
If you do it this way.
The other advantage of doing it this way is that you don't even need to store your hash anywhere because
it's just calculated from something in your database.
One extra point to bear in mind is that you should make sure that you use something absolutely static
for your variable sold here that is static per user.
So don't use the user's e-mail address for example because they might change their email address.
And if they do then you're hashing system will break or at least you'll have to update the password
with the new hash with a new e-mail address.
So better to use something absolutely fixed like the ID number.
So there we go.
This is our secure as we can possibly manage way of storing passwords and we're now ready to build our
complete logging system for our secret diary Web site.
We'll do that in the next video.