All right so now we've looked at modals popovers and tool tips.
I'm going to challenge you to complete the set up of a reasonably complicated bootstrap component and
that is scroll spy.
So the object of this challenge is for you to put together everything that we've learned in the last
few videos and find the information on the component work out first of what it does and then recreate
that in your own HVM l page.
As always if you have any problems I'll go through the process after the pause.
So good luck.
Just got to find the information about scroll spy on the bootstrap Web site and set it up in your bootstrap
toward HCM help web page.
Good luck.
All right.
Did you manage it.
I hope so.
I'm going to get the information from here.
So let's.
First off try and figure out what on earth skirl spy does.
Generally speaking an example is the best thing for it.
There's calls for a operation is automatically updating Naftogaz based on the scroll position.
OK.
So if we scroll down this window you can see that it's moving along the nav bar at the top.
Great.
OK so hopefully that's something that you can see would be quite useful.
One of the reasons that I chose the scroll spy plug in for you to attempt is that at the time of writing
there's no copy and paste code on the bootstrap site.
That may well be different for you.
And if you are able to copy and paste it and get it working absolutely fine.
But we're going to try and figure it out how it works without just copying pasting an example.
Obviously worth mentioning that we could view the page source and find the code and probably copy and
paste that but attempt to do it another way just to show you how we could do it.
So trying to figure out how on earth this plugin works so we can see we're going to need a Nav. at the
top and then we're going to need some content and some Wow we need a way of connecting up the nav and
the content.
So let's start by putting a nav in to go to link that to the boot strap nav component.
Here we go.
I think this inline one will do fine for us.
So let's get rid of this script code because we don't need any of that.
And also we don't need tether anymore either.
And get rid of all of our code there.
So let's put the novel first off and just check that that's displaying correctly.
There we go.
And then let's go back and see how we going to connect this up.
So first off we need to apply relative positioning to our body tag.
So let's do that.
So I'll do that with I in line style or internal Zari style
command every game.
And then we apply the data spy and data target elements to our body tag.
So that makes sense we're setting up the body tag to be the thing that is spied on as we're scrolling
and we're setting up the nav bar example div to be the thing that gets updated when the user is scrolling.
So let's add an ID here to our NAV.
We might as well use the same one and it looks to me like we'll need a UL
with those classes Nav. and laptops with a roll of tab list.
So let's set up our links as Elyse
OK and just close those allies off to the links
right we'll just have a look.
Make sure it still looks like an ass.
Yep great.
We've lost our in line but that's OK.
And I think I'll get rid of the disabled one as well.
OK.
So the question I'm wondering is how we connect up each of these links to its respective point on the
page.
Ah.
Now this is looking like the answer now if Pollocks must have a resolvable ID targets so we need a link
that goes to an ID on the page and then we need a div that ID on the page.
OK.
So that makes sense I'll just put the names of the sections in.
So I'll just go for one two three and four.
And then we'll have an NHT with an ID of one
which will contain Section 1 and then we'll have a div and we'll get some good old Lorem Epson text
in there.
To fill out our page
lovely and then we'll do the same for sections 2 3 and 4.
And then just go back and rename those
Section 3
to
ones already there.
And one thing to note is that we will need the nav to be fixed.
So I'm going to just change that to a nav bar.
With a different styling and
we'll make it fixed to the top.
All right fingers crossed.
Let's have a look.
All right so it doesn't look great but that's ok.
Scroll down and see if we get the effect.
There it is say it is indeed updating our scroll spy is working.
We could definitely do with a little bit of tidying up here though.
So first off let's give this a background.
So it's not transparent which is a bit confusing.
And let's add the never item class to our list which should make everything go horizontal rather than
vertical.
Not that it really matters but it's a little bit nicer as an example to work with the great so you can
see what our NAV bar tabs is doing there.
It's styling it like tabs.
All right.
So we're pretty much done.
I do want to just add a bit of a margin there to my section 1.
So that's
it's not hidden behind the navigation so let's just add a margin up of let's try 70 pixels that we get
that looks a lot better.
And there is one final issue.
If you see where it updates in fact to make it slightly clearer don't just change these to the correct
numbers.
So one the three and four
so Section 2 is coming along and it only changes when Section 2 gets right to the top of the page which
is not necessarily what you want it also for us because there's a problem here because it never quite
gets to Section 4 because Section 4 is almost at the top of the page but not quite.
But there's a nice easy way round that.
And we can actually see it on the scrolls by bootstrap page.
We have this data offset attribute that we can add which is pixels to offset from the top.
When calculating position of scroll.
So as we just added a margin top of 70.
Let's add a data offset value of 70 as well.
And we should find this will give us a more sensible point of switching from one to the other.
So let's have a look.
So now switching to Section 2 just there which is great that's when Section 2 is at the top of the visible
part of the screen and then Section 3 and Section 4 as well.
And of course we can click on the links to jump to the respective parts of the page as well.
All right.
So I hope you manage that in the next and final video of the section then we'll be using everything
that we've learned in the bootstrap section of this course to put together a beautiful and functional
app landing page.