So carrying on our investigation of how we can position our elements ever we want them on the page we're
going to move away from floating and look at positioning.
So floating has the advantage of being pretty flexible.
It will float to the edge of the page however wide the user's screen is which can often be very useful.
Sometimes you need a bit more precision and you want to know exactly where your elements are and that's
where positioning comes in.
So first off I'm going to get rid of all our floating
so that we know where everything is to start with and so we don't need our clear float anymore.
And let's just check that that brings us back to where we were before.
Wonderful.
So maybe I want to take this green box and move it a little bit to the right when it quite after the
page for some reason I want to indent it a little bit.
So there are several ways to do that but we're going to do that now with positioning.
So I remember the first box is our first section here.
So first off we tell the Browns are we going to be positioning this Dave.
And we do that by setting the position to relative relative positioning means that we're going to be
positioning it relative to where it would otherwise be.
So at the moment if we just take a look at that that doesn't change anything at all because it is where
it was.
If you know what I mean.
But if we wanted to move it relative to where it currently is we would then add something like left
and then say 200 pixels and let's have a look and see what effect that has.
So that now moves it 200 pixels in the horizontal direction.
You might be slightly surprised that we've said left 200 and it's actually moved it to the right.
But you could think of it as having almost a 200 pixel margin on the left there.
And that's why we move to the right.
If we wanted to move it to the left we just do the same thing but with a negative number of pixels.
So let's try moving it to the left.
Fix 50 pixels and there you go.
You can see we've even moved it off the screen and we can move off the screen completely if we want
five hundred pixels you might wonder why we might want to do that.
It can actually be quite useful because we we might want to slide it in in some sort of fancy animation
later on which will see how to do in the Jay Querrey chapter.
But for now the main thing is we can move it left and right by having positive or negative numbers that
we can also move it up and down by adding a top property.
Again you can think of this a bit of a bit like having a margin at the top.
So if we have a 100 pixel margin then that will mean that 100 pixels down and that we get.
So let's just
in fact we'll have a hundred pixels there.
So it's now 100 pixels to the right and 100 pixels down of where it would otherwise be.
So this is what this relative positioning is all about with positioning relative to where it was so
quick challenge for you.
Can you move the blue box.
So it's 100 pixels to the right and 100 pixels up of where it is now under pixels to the right 100 pixels
up it.
All right.
How do you manage that.
Well we needed to do was set the position to relative again and then 100 pixels right means left 100
pixels and then for 100 pixels up we're going to use a top of minus one hundred pixels.
If we use 100 pixels there that would of course move it 100 pixels down.
Let's just check.
Wonderful.
It's now going 100 pixels right and 100 pixels up and we can use this relative positioning on any element
doesn't have to be a box.
It doesn't have to be a div we could do it on the paragraph or a table or an image or anything that
we wanted to be moved around in some way.
Great.
So I'm going to show you a different type of positioning in a moment but first I just want to move the
second section back and just show you how when you've got two elements overlapping like this you might
want to change which one appears in front of the other.
So by default the green box is in front of the blue one.
But if we wanted it to be the other way round we could change that with Zed index to that index works
in this way can set the Zed index of any element we like.
So whether it be a div or a paragraph or whatever.
And then the one with the highest Zed index will appear at the front.
So if I give this one that say a zed index of 1 and this one is an index of two.
The second one is the blue one should appear in front of the green one that won't quite work as it is
though because 0 said Index require a position of relative or there are a couple of other position types
that will work.
But we've only seen relative to so far.
So it will stick with that to work.
Let's have a look.
Now there we go.
So now the blue one is in front of the green one.
So Zed indexes are really handy if you won't have overlapping elements and you want to be very clear
as to which is going to be in the front and you can set the set index whatever you like so you could
have 100 different values if you had 100 different things overlapping each other which I probably wouldn't
recommend but you could do it if you wanted.
One other little cheeky thing I'm going to show you is really to do with positioning.
But while we're talking about layering it's quite nice.
You might want to have an element in the front which is a little bit C-3.
So you can actually see the element behind it and that's pretty easy to achieve.
So at the moment second section is in the front.
So if we set the opacity which is how opaque The object is a and opacity of one means that it will be
completely solid as it is now a curve and opacity of zero means that it will be completely invisible
and it's there but we can't see it and then opacity of say nought point five means that it will be there
but see through.
So you can choose whatever passes you like on a scale of zero to one.
And the bigger the number the less see through it is so that can be really nice especially if you're
working with images of a sort of slightly faded image behind your text or something like that however
you wanted to do it all right.
So we've had a lot of fun with relative positioning.
I'm now going to show you a couple of other types of positioning which can be really useful as well.
So if we go back to our default with no positioning at all I'm going to start with a position of absolute.
So instead of relative we're now talking absolute and this is now quite different to how we were working
before with relative positioning and let's just see how that affects the page.
Ha.
The second section is now completely disappeared.
While it hasn't actually disappeared what's happened it's gone behind the first section.
So if we change the width of that one to 400 You can see it's actually still there as is the paragraph
underneath but they're behind it and that's because absolute positioning then takes the object that
you're positioning out of the flow of the page.
So basically all the other elements Dishan themselves as if this green box isn't there at all.
So that can be really useful if you want something to be on top of everything else and for everything
else to ignore that and here then the positioning is relative to the top left of the page.
So
we can do similar things that we did before we could move it 500 pixels to the right and we could move
it say 200 pixels down and that would move it around in exactly the same way as we had before.
But the main point of absolute positioning is it takes the element out of the flow of the page.
So if you want something to position itself over the top of everything else that's the way to do it.
All right.
So that's absolute positioning.
Take it back to them now.
So the last one I want to show you is a position of fixed.
Now how could this be different to the others you wonder.
Well let's find out if we have a look at how that looks.
By itself it's exactly the same as absolutes so fixed is out of the flow of the page.
Just like absolute and we can move it around.
Just like absolute.
So how is it different.
Absolute Well we can see this very clearly.
If for example I changed the height of my second section which is the blue div here and made it really
big say something like 5000 pixels.
And we've now got a really long page and watch what happens if I start to scroll down here we get the
green box stays in position.
So that's how fixed is different to absolute absolute will move when the page is scrolled fixed will
not.
So a typical example for a fixed position Dave might be if you want to have a menu at the top of your
page and you want that to appear even as the user scrolls down the page.
Then you might use a fixed position for that.
And there we go.
So there's several different types of positioning then.
I'll give you a quick summary member relative positioning means we can move the element relative to
where it would otherwise be in the page.
Absolute positioning takes the element out of the flow of the page and allows us to move it around relative
to the top left of the page and fixed positioning does the same thing but it keeps the element fixed
even when we scroll down the page.
And for all three of those types we can use left and top to move it left and right and up and down get
exactly where we wanted.
We also saw how to use opacity to change a see through an object is.
And Zed index to help make clear which object goes in front when you've got two overlapping ones.
Great.
So lots of new information there.
As always do you have a play around and see what you can make happen with these different positions.
We're going to move on to something slightly different.
And that is margin's.