Get them.
So I'm going to begin by just adding my e-mail input and e-mail label and styling those so that everything
looks like I want it to.
So I did mention that there are things that we can use labels which attach themselves to inputs.
So let's do a quick google for something like labels for inputs HTL.
OK the label tag that looks like what we might want
OK.
And there we go.
So looks like I can use a label to just attach myself or touch my label specifically to an input.
All right so we've pasted that in.
Let's update things.
So the label is connected to the input itself virus ID those other things that are matching them.
So I'm going to change my label to e-mail.
And All right e-mail is the name for the label itself as well.
This is going to be a radio.
This is going to be a text input will have the name being e-mail as well.
The idea being e-mail and I don't want an initial Valley so I'm going to get rid of that.
But I will have a placeholder because I think they usually look nice e.g. your name at gmail dot com
something like that.
All right let's take a look.
OK.
Not a bad start.
We definitely want to do a fair bit of styling on this day.
First off let's change our phones.
For everything to a nice sunset font
I'll go for Helvetica and then sans serif.
If that fails I've forgotten to put my style tagging them
Enrique and
and then.
So that should change the fun for everything to help get to.
But only if I put a comma in between those two.
Great.
Next I want to make everything a fair bit bigger.
So let's try a font size of 300 percent.
Little bit too large
200 percent.
That'll do.
Next I want to style my inputs so let's add in some input styling.
We'll start off with a height of let's try 40 pixels.
See how that looks.
I think that's about right.
Not quite aligned correctly but maybe a little bit taller.
But actually I also want some padding so I'm going to put 5 pixels of padding in and that should make
it a little different.
And I also want a larger font size.
So let's go for a font size of has a height of 40 pixels 30 pixels.
Sounds about right.
Yeah a little large I think.
Maybe 25.
OK that looks more reasonable.
I would like some rounded corners in that say I'm going to add a border radius of let's try 5 pixels
OK.
That's nice but I don't quite like this sort of phony 3D effects them so I'm going to set the border
to the one VX solid gray.
OK that's a bit neater.
I don't like the centering in the vertical centering of the text so I'm going to get rid of that height
and adjust the padding so I like the amount of padding on the top.
I won't have the same amount on the bottom and it's not quite centering that for me.
So I'm going to go for 5 x 5 x and then let's try 15 x on the bottom to give it a bit more padding there.
OK that's good but I think I've got a little bit too much so let's try 10 K.
Just a touch more.
There we go.
OK I'm liking that we do need a bit more with Thome So let's try 300 pixels for hour with maybe even
a touch more
try 3.
20.
OK now I think my
label is a little bit large so I'll actually make that much smaller.
And I also want to shift it down a little bit.
It's not quite centered vertically with the input that are going to style my labels you should indent
everything else a little bit.
So I will do this with relative positioning and give it a top of maybe 7 pixels.
See how that looks.
But too much
for pixels.
There we get great.
I'd like to censor everything in the page so you may remember how we do that from
big CSSA project we have some kind of container or wrapper div
doesn't matter too much what you call it.
Important Thing other styles that you give it
say let's
give it a fixed width
try 500 pixels initially and then a margin as you may remember zero for top and bottom and auto left
and right and that will then center everything in the middle of the page OK.
We adjust our styling a little bit as we go.
But let's start off with that and see how it works.
OK so now we've got our e-mail label.
Let's add our telephone
label.
So we'll call it telephone and it's still going to be text and we'll give it a name of an ideal of an
idea of phone and an EEG of one two three four five six seven eight nine.
Important thing is there's no spaces in there.
So let's have a look.
OK.
That looks good but you can see that these labels have different widths.
So let's try and fix that.
We should come across an interesting little issue.
So if I try and set the width of the wrapper of the label 250 pixels nothing happens that's a bit of
a mystery and that's one of those things you could spend quite a while messing around trying to fix.
So let's have a little look change label with HDMI or something like that and see if we can find an
answer.
OK.
How can I control the width of a label tag.
It looks promising.
Ah ha.
So here we go.
Label is an inline element.
It can have a with the value in order to that you need to change the display type to display block or
float left.
So we'll use float left because we want it to appear to the left of our input that we get.
That looks a lot better had we use display is block I would still would have worked but it would have
been above the input which is not what we wanted.
So let's go for floating left.
And these are a bit too close I think now so let's add a bit of a margin.
I think it's probably worth putting them in a div with a class of
something like form element
rather than applying the margins to the labels and the inputs directly.
It doesn't seem right somehow.
So another one that form elements so that also gives us a nice container for our labels and inputs as
well.
Which feels right.
Okay.
And then we can take our form elements device and I'm just going to go for a margin bottom of say 10
pixels.
Get that.
Excellent.
Much more nicely spaced out OK.
Now let's add our password fields.
So I'm going to copy the whole day of there
for password
and we'll call it password as well.
So this is going to have a type of text but we can actually use a type of password which will work in
exactly the same way as text but it won't display the text when the user types it.
It's more secure if someone's looking over their shoulder.
So that type of password name or password and I.D. be password and we won't have a place hold at this
time.
OK.
Let's get.
And then we might have a bit of an issue with space here.
But that's
see what pops up.
OK we could do it like that but that doesn't look particularly neat.
So let's change our sizes a little bit or just call this password.
Confirm
Hoopes the type is still the same only the name and ID that change.
And then that's still a bit of restyling.
So let's look at 150 percent and maybe increase the width of our wrapper a little that's too much.
And that will allow us to have a wider
label.
There we go.
Just a touch too close there I think.
Let's make it
130 percent on the size it's great.
I would just need to adjust the label positioning.
So we'll go for
about 15 a little too much
to I-12.
Okay that looks good.
All right.
All that remains then for our AGM L is our submit button.
So it's a form element let's put it inside one of those divs.
It doesn't need a label.
We could use an input or a button here.
It doesn't really matter.
But if we're going to have an impact we need a type of submit and then I'll give it an ID of Submit
button and a valley of
Sign-Up
OK.
So already quite like the styling of it but we need to adjust it a little bit.
So let's give it some custom styles.
I call it submit button
so first off it's a bit too wide.
So let's give it its own width of say 100 pixels or an hour
130 that looks about right.
So I'd like it to be lined up with these inputs here.
So I'm going to give it a margin left of two hundred pixels should work there.
Put them.
So there's our form.
It's not exactly a work of art but it's pretty neat.
And it does the job.
Now for the interesting bit let's start doing some validation.
So we want validation to happen when the sign up button is clicked.
So let's add that in.
First off for our Javascript.
So the sign up button is submit button select selected in the usual way with a hash and then its name
submit button and we want to do something when the submit button is clicked
and that something is going to be a function
as always.
I'd like to know that everything's
connected nicely.
So let's do a quick check on it.
Something's gone horribly wrong.
I've got too many parentheses that.
Let's try that again.
Sign up that we can.
Great.
So we'll work our way down from top to bottom for our validation.
So we'll start with the e-mail which is the most complicated but as I mentioned I wouldn't recommend
you come up with your own e-mail validating function.
Internet's already done it for you.
So let's have a look at.
Well we could use javascript but why not go for Jay query.
E-mail validation function.
E-mail validation using Jey query that looks promising.
Here we go.
So we've got a very very complicated regular expression that I'm not going to go into the precise meanings
of all of this but you can probably just about work out that we're looking for a string of small letters
or big letters or numbers or these punctuation marks and then an at symbol and then some more small
letters or big letters or numbers or a dash and then a range of potential Dotcom's or de-code it ukase
etc..
If you're really into projects you can go into that and a lot more detail and figure out exactly what's
going on.
But for our purposes that will be enough.
So this is a nice function that we can use to validate an email address.
So that's the beginning of our code here and we'll just spread it out a little.
Alex nice
that we get.
So you can see this is going to return rejects.
Test.
Now test is a javascript function that we haven't seen yet so we're not certain exactly whether that's
going to give us true or false or the e-mail address or what.
So let's find out.
So we need to run this test against the contents of this HDMI input which I remember has an ID of email
so let's select it.
Now we need to get its value which we could google and try and find out.
But I think we could just guess maybe with Jay query we need to do it and then that will that looks
promising.
So let's get its value.
And remember if we send no parameters that that implies that we want to get the value rather than set
the value.
So that will give us the value and what we want is to run the function is email
on that.
And let's then alert the outcome of that to see what it looks like.
All right let's take a look.
If I click that so far so looks like we're getting true or false here that's just put in.
I yes that's false.
If we put in ICF at asd you have to come.
It becomes truly excellent.
So this is looking like exactly what we need.
If it's a valid email address then it will be true.
If not it's false.
Brilliant.
So we can actually put that straight in see an if statement.
And remember this is going to be true or false so don't even need to put is equal to true.
But what I do need is to test whether this is false because I'm what I'm interested in is getting an
error here.
So I'm actually against it is not equal to or.
So I'm actually going to put is equally false because that's what I'm particularly interested in.
And if it is we want to show an error message of some sort.
So let's think for a moment how are we going to do that.
That could well be more than one arrow with this form.
So what we don't want to do is let each one or anything like that but we do want to display every error
so that the user doesn't fix one and then submit again and then realize there's another one.
So the way I'm going to deal with that is to have a variable called error message which is initially
empty.
And then if we get any of these errors I'm going to add some text to the error message and then the
end will display the whole error message.
That's quite a nice way round when you've got potentially lots of different things to say to your users
but also potentially none.
Start off with an empty string and then had the issues in as you go.
So let's append to error message which Remember we do using plus equals and we'll say your email address
is not valid.
And for now just to check will alert error message OK let's take a look.
Your e-mail address is not valid.
Fantastic.
In fact I'm going to put a paragraph tags around that.
However a message will appear on separate lines.
All right.
So now to the telephone number.
So the validation here is we want to check if the phone number is numeric or not.
And I did give you a clue at the beginning that there is a J queery function to do exactly that.
So let's see if we can discover what it is.
So now we're looking at
string phone with an ID phone and we want to check whether that is numeric or not and that is indeed
a query function that we can access.
Remember using string dots to get all the J.A.G. functions is numeric.
So if we pop dot vowel again on to the end of that that will test to see if the phone number that they've
entered is a number we could use a regular expression for that as well.
But as Jay query has a built in function we might as well use that.
So we actually want to check if that is false cause we're interested in when it's not numeric
IP your phone number is not numeric.
These may not be the most useful error messages by the way.
They will serve our purposes but you probably want something a bit more friendly.
Let's have a look.
Yep.
So we've got e-mail addresses not valid phone number is not numeric.
But if we do put a number in there then we just get e-mail address is not valid.
Wonderful.
Now for our passwords the main thing we want to check here is that they're the same.
So that's fairly straightforward if there are two IDs our password confirm and password
say if password dot vowel is equal say
password.
Confirm thought Vau
in fact once again we're not interested in whether they're equal to each other we're interested if they're
not equal to each other.
Error message plus equals p your passwords don't match
say let's have a look if I just put two different passwords in we gets the email address but not this
one.
I think that's because I've got to put a hash in there.
It's like again
that's your passwords don't match.
And in the closing paragraph tag as well.
All right.
So that's most of the validation done.
The final step I want to do is introduce check just to make sure that they filled something in.
In each of these fields and again that's something that we don't really want to give them a separate
message.
The email is missing the telephone is missing the password is missing.
The confirmation is missing.
I want to do that all in one error message if I can.
So where I'm going to deal with that is similar to how I dealt with error message up here.
I'm going to have
fields missing which is initially empty.
And then if the e-mail Valley
is empty
then fields missing a pen so that's I'm going to give it a line breaks or it's going to be on a new
line and then email
then I'm going to add something very similar for the rest
if the phone number is missing and the fields missing.
Gets telephoned to it again with the Be off of the line break.
If passed what is missing.
Then we add password to it.
And if
password confirm is missing
then confirm password gets added to fields missing.
Then we check if
fields missing is not an empty string.
Then we add two error message
the following
fields missing and then we happened to that Fields missing.
If you wanted to you could add a little bit of code that works out whether one or more fields are missing.
So you get the correct singular or plural but I'll just leave it like that for now.
OK so let's have a look.
What if we leave all of these blank then.
Yep we're getting the following fields are missing.
Fantastic.
So we should now be checking for a numeric telephone for a valid email address for matching passwords
and for all of these fields to be filled in.
So we don't want to alert the message in that way we want to be a bit more stylish than that.
So what we'll do is inside our wrapper at the beginning we'll have a div with an ID
of error message.
So that's where our error messages are going to go.
And then once we've run through this whole post process.
If the variable error message is not an empty string then will display the error to the user.
So will do that using
error message to select the error message div will set the h t m l of that 2 error message.
All right let's take a look.
Fantastic.
That looks great.
That's exactly the errors that I would expect if we just add in some numbers and a couple of random
passwords to mess things up a little bit.
So it is still missing the email address but the email address is also not valid and the passwords don't
match.
Fantastic.
So just a couple of things to finish things off.
I'm going to add a little bit of styling to the error message
I'm going to make the text color red and I'm going to make the font size a little bit smaller.
So it looks a bit need to say font size is 130 so let's try 110.
See how that works.
We have to make sure that it's obeying this one.
And remember we've seen that if we put exclamation mark important then that one will override any other
CSSA instructions.
So let's have a look at.
That's better but still a bit large I think that's go for 90 percent.
OK.
I think that looks better.
All right.
So the final thing I want to add on is a nice friendly message if the user has finally been successful
in this form.
So that will happen when error message is empty.
So we can just use an else here and then let's give ourselves
ice excessive
say a success message which is going to be pretty similar to error message
except it's going to be green
and white I'm going to use Access Menchie's because any one success message is I'm going to start it
off.
Hidden
and I'm going to put the content of the success message in here which I'm happy with.
I prefer to have the content in the team l if possible.
So you did it.
Congratulations
of course.
Normally we'd be redirecting someone to the log in page and getting them to use the app or whatever
service they're signing up for.
But for now we'll just say them a nice friendly message.
So here am will take success message.
Don't forget the hash and all we need to do is show it.
We could use VSS here to display it.
Show is easy enough.
And actually I also want to hide error message because we don't want those error messages still displaying.
Once the user has got it right.
Wonderful.
So let's take a final look.
So I'm going to put in hopefully correct answers to each of these.
Sign up and there we go.
You did it.
Congratulations.
Maybe a touch of padding on the bottom then
or margin would do as well.
That would get
better.
Brilliant So I hope you had fun with that.
And as always I hope you managed to do at least some of it on your own.
We're now going to shift gears slightly and look at the J queery UI plugin and how we can use that to
create some fancy user interface elements really easily and will be working towards our big J queery
project at the end of this section which is code player.
I'll tell you more about that later on.