It because HP is a server side language it can do anything.
A server can do and that is quite a bit more than what you can do with say javascript or Jey query.
And one of the really useful features of BHP is allows you to send email.
So this is very useful for something like a contact form because you can code up the form to send you
an email when someone posts a contact request.
So I'm going to show you the simplest way to do it and then give you a number of reasons why you might
not want to do it completely that way and give you a few more complicated slightly better alternatives.
So the simplest way to send mail with HP is using the mail function and all we have to do is pass the
e-mail address the subject the body and any other information for the e-mail to that function and the
email will get set.
So let's set up all those variables.
You might want to start with email too.
So that could be Rob code dot com
subjects something like I hope this works
then the body of the email
something friendly.
I think you're great.
And then the most complicated bit is we set the headers which is a way of setting the kind of options
for the email.
And the only really important one there is the From.
Header.
So we enter it as from and then a colon and then whoever the sender email address we want to be.
So we might have if I'm sending it to myself.
Rob Percival took current UK.
All right.
So that's all the information that we need.
Then we just use mail and then we pass the various variables to it.
So we start with email to then subject then the body and then head is
and that's it.
It's as simple as that.
It's often very useful for us to know whether this has been successful though and this in itself actually
returns either a 1 or 0 depending on whether or not it's been successful.
So we can actually put an if statement around it directly like that.
And then if it's successful this statement will return true because it will be a 1.
And if it's not then it'll be a 0.
So the if statement will return false so we could do something like if it was successful the e-mail
was sent
successfully
and otherwise we'll say the e-mail could not be sent.
All right.
So let's just try that out and see what we get.
We don't need to resubmit that form we can just reload the page
great.
The e-mail was sent successfully.
And if we did something like forgot to include the e-mail to then we'd see the e-mail could not be sent.
Great.
So that's the basic way of sending a mail using THP.
What are the downsides of using this method then.
Well the main one is spam.
So because I can choose any e-mail address I like as my from e-mail address you can imagine spammers
are very excited about this.
So they like to send emails from various banks or from Twitter asking you to reset your password or
something like that and they can in theory and with a script to do that very simply because of that
they email clients or providers like Gmail and Yahoo.
Have become very sophisticated about what they will consider spam.
So even though this email was supposedly sent successfully that doesn't mean that it will be received
by the user.
So if you really want to get into this you might want to start with something like send HP e-mail without
it going to spam and you'll send you'll see a huge amount of advice here.
So if we have a quick look at this one avoiding spam filters.
So that's your basic mail.
So one way of doing it is to put more detail in the headers.
MKP MIME types and all sorts of more information then.
Another thing is to not try and send email from anywhere other than the domain that you're running the
script on.
So this would probably fail because I'm running the script uncomplete web developer course dot com but
I'm saying that the email is from Roback reposeful Tucker.
OK.
So if I change that to Rob at complete web developer call Stockham that's more likely to get through
because it's being run on the same server that it's claiming to be from.
And there's a few other options there as well that you can do to attempt to get past the spam filters
one completely different option which I actually use quite a lot is to use a service like Mandrell
and what that allows you to do is send email through mandrels servers and because Mandrell know what
they're doing.
They set up their servers very well so that they are much less likely than your servers to be marked
as spam.
So they charge a very small amount per e-mail but those emails are much more likely to get through.
And if you use this method and you can see from there what's their website is all about.
So it's all about deliverability if you're sending mass e-mail.
I would recommend using something like mandrill or MailChimp.
Having said that if we want to do something with a contact form we're actually relatively safe because
we're only sending e-mail to ourselves.
So you could even set up a rule in your email client to say anything that comes from Rob has complete
web develop because dot com.
Don't send it to spam even if you think it is spam.
So this method is perfectly reasonable for a contact form.
All right so now we've learned that a contact form is exactly what we're going to make and this will
give us an opportunity to use our Jey query validation as well and our HP server side skills with post
variables and e-mail sending and we'll do that in the next video.