Now that you have all the FRONT-END DEVELOPER skills for building web sites in HD and CSSA with javascript
NJ Querrey and also the backend developer skills coding server side scripts in HP and communicating
with databases via my Eskew Well all that really remains to add power and functionality to your apps
is to be able to connect to existing web services like Google Maps Facebook and Twitter and do something
cool with those services for your users and the web standard for doing that is an application programming
interface or API.
And it might sound a bit scary but it's actually pretty simple and I've got a nice easy diagram to get
the idea of how it works.
Essentially we've got your app or website running on your web server.
That makes a request to another provider's web server via an API which then returns some data to your
app for you to do something with it.
So for example if you knew the location of your user and you wanted to find some local businesses or
restaurants near to them you could send the location of the user to the Google Maps API.
And that would then return some local businesses in a format that you could then process and display
for your users.
So it's a really powerful easy and at the lower end for a way of getting access to the Web services
provided by the world's biggest companies.
So API are pretty cool.
And we're going to be looking at a few of them in this section to give you an idea about how they work
and how you can integrate them into your websites.
And we'll be starting using open weather maps to talk to rewrite out what the weather web app that we
made in the HP chapter in a much better and more efficient way and we'll do that in the next video.