In this section we're going to be looking at a platform called WordPress.
Wordpress is what's known as a content management system or CMOS and it's essentially a way of managing
your site which in theory avoids the need for code entirely.
It was originally developed for blogging and allowed people very easily to add new blog posts.
Change the style of their blog without any knowledge of HCM Eliseus as a tool it's developed since then
there are a whole web site management tool and now powers an astonishing 25 percent of all Web sites.
I'm going to recommend that you get to grips with it because it's free.
It's easy to use.
There's a huge amount of support online and you can make great looking sites that your clients will
be able to update and manage themselves.
Excited.
I hope so.
Let's get cracking.
To use Wordpress you need a web server.
And of course you're very lucky.
That's with the complete web developer of course.
Get a years.
Web hosting for free.
So if you haven't set up your first hosting package yet then go to the hosting section of this course.
Follow the instructions then if you've done that go to eco web hosting Dockerty UK slash C.P slash managed
hosting and that should list the domain names that you've set up.
The one that I'm going to be working with today is one called a WordPress test domain dot com and if
I click on that it'll open up the control panel for this test domain and I'll be able to install WordPress
directly from there.
Most web hosts do have this functionality so if you're already set up with a different web host I'm
sure you'll be able to do the same thing with them.
With the correct though.
Scroll down will be installing the full version of Wordpress which we can use for blogs or any other
web site.
So the only option we need to put in is where we want to install WordPress so you may have already uploaded
some files to your hosting package.
So if you have I'd recommend installing WordPress in a subdomain so that can be anything you like it
could be a blog or web site or whatever but I'm going to call it WordPress.
So just put web person that the slash at the end is optional but then click Install now and what that
actually does is creates a database and some P-H piece scripts which will be looking at in the next
section to allow WordPress to run on your site so that you can complete the install process.
Now the first link will only work if you've purchased the domain.
If you haven't purchased the domain name you'll need to use the temporary u r l.
That is the second link.
And that will work regardless of whether or not you've purchased the domain name right.
So if everything is going well you should see this WordPress installation page.
It's fairly straightforward.
You just put your site title.
So I'm going to put.
Example.
WordPress site.
But you can put whatever you like then use a name for replaceable.
Again you can put whatever you like and then password.
So I've caught one automatically generated for me here.
I'll leave that as it is.
And then your email address.
Rob Percival Tokarev UK.
If for some reason you want to switch off search engines then you can do that but probably you're going
to want people to find your site.
I would leave that text and then you just press install WordPress.
If you got last past caring it might remember your password.
So I will just do that
and then you log in.
Hopefully you remember the password.
I've got last boss here so I'm going to pop that in.
It's got the user name wrong.
I will just put his name and password that you entered.
Remember me if you want to be remembered on this machine and then log in and this will take you to the
Wordpress dashboard.
And this is where we're going to start looking through the functionality of Wordpress in the next video.
See you there.