So we're finally ready to write.
How first ever web page if you follow the instructions in the previous videos you should have a big
white page in front of you ready to accept your code.
Just before we write any code we're going to make sure that we're editing the right file.
So in your text editor just get a file and then save as.
And I'm just going to expand everything here by clicking that down.
You probably need to do that and I'd recommend working on your desktop.
This is where we're going to be storing all your files.
So if you want to put them in your documents or somewhere else then feel free.
But if you're not sure then just put them right here on the desktop.
Now I'm going to create a new folder for them to be nice and organized and I'm going to call it complete
web developer course
create and then I'm going to create another folder within that called Chapter 1 and then DML.
Now it is amusing no spaces and all small letters here as is normal in web addresses and file names
that are going to go onto the Internet.
So I'd recommend you do the same there and then we'll change the title of our document to Hello World
dot h DML the dot h t m l extension tells us it's a web page.
We're going to be looking at that in a little more detail in the next video.
But for now just leave it has Hello world.
H T i m l and safe.
And now just to check where that file is.
We can move our text editor and our browser out the way.
And there it is.
There's my lovely complete web developer Corps folder on my desktop and if I double click on there I
can see the one HDMI folder and then the hello world h will file in there.
So let's add a quick bit of content to our Hello world file and it's can be a very simple hello world.
This is the standard first thing to write whenever you are learning to program.
So I'd recommend doing that but if you want to change it to anything else then that's fine.
And then we get to use command or control as to save where you can go to File Save if you prefer.
And now finally we get to go to our Hello world on HVM L and I'm going to control click or right click
on windows open with and then Google Chrome and that will then open our Hello World Team HMO file in
our browser and Verity's.
Wonderful.
Congratulations.
Might not look like much but that's your first ever web page which is quite an achievement.
I think now we're just going to set ourselves up for the rest of the course in which we're going to
be using a split screen set up.
So you just need to resize your windows so that we've got the browser on the left and the code editor
on the right.
You can do this automatically I think but I quite like doing it manually to make sure everything is
set up exactly as I want it.
And then the great thing about having two programs like this side by side is that we can change how
text editor and change our code to something like.
Hello Rob.
We can use command or control as to say that.
And then we can just reload this page by clicking the error that or command our own Mac or F5 on a PC
and then updates straight away.
So this is how we're going to be working with code pretty much for the rest of the course.
We're going to be coding something over here on the right.
And we're then going to see the results straight away.
On the left which is really exciting and dynamic way of coding.
So congratulations on making your very first web page in the next video we'll be finding out what exactly
this TNL that I've been talking about is and how we can start writing some.