So moving on from fun animations and transformations in this final video on CSSA 3 we're going to see
how we can use CSI as three to improve our website layouts.
And the first of these that we're going to look at is a multi-column layout Now this is actually pretty
easy to set up.
But before yesterday there was no easy way to get multiple columns in your pages you had to resort to
quite complex DSS or even javascript solutions.
So see how easy it is today in CSSA 3.
So first of get a reasonably chunky amount of text
in our div just put a couple of line breaks in between each paragraph.
And then we'll start it in the usual way.
So multi column and then all we need to use is column count and then however many columns you want.
So I call it three Let's take a look.
And sadly it hasn't worked.
That's because this is one of the DSS three properties that's not fully supported by crime yet.
So to get it working in crime you need to add a Web Kit column count as well.
And then we have a look then that works really well.
And this is just a reminder you should always check the support of these CSSA 3 and Jim L5 methods that
you're using and put in any work around that you'll need to make sure that they work on your user's
browsers.
The usual one is Web Kit for anything that's web based.
So that's chrome Safari and opera.
And then if you need anything custom for Firefox that's usually molls short for Mozilla
so to be sure that this is going to work in all browsers you would add those three instructions.
You can customize this further if you like by deciding what the column gap should be.
So there's a default that around 10 pixels.
But if you want to customize that you just use column gap and then whatever you want it to be.
So maybe 40 pixels.
And sadly I'm going to have to use
these as well.
To make sure it works in all browsers.
Specifically the Web Kit one for crime here.
So that's increased the Kulim gap.
We can even add and style a rule between the column sight line.
It's a bit laborious I'm afraid especially because we have to do it three times but we use Cullom rule
style
and then one of those.
So go for solid
and then we need to do the same thing but with Web Kit
and Mole's in front in fact I leave those that we're going to be doing a few of these now.
So we then need column rule with.
So I'll just have one X and he might be able to anticipate column rule color I'll use grey and then
let's add these two in to maximize our compatibility and then we just prefix the official rule with
those two
that we get it's a bit of a hassle.
But we do get a nice rule down the middle so if you're making some kind of newspaper type web site then
this will be a great way to do it.
Sometimes you might want an element to span certain columns so say you've got a header
news finance or something like that.
So to make that had a span multiple columns we use column span and we can either put all or none or
a number if we wanted to span a certain number of columns okay for all and for this one we only need
a Web Kit alternative molls is fine for columns span so take a look.
There we go.
So now spanning all the way across even though it doesn't actually need to.
And that's about it.
Notice that this is different to the media queries.
Oh that's unfortunate.
That's better.
So crime is not supporting these columns particularly well here.
So these will not be responsive as such so they'll change their width but they won't flow one underneath
the other like how bootstrap columns do it if that's the bag that you want then column count.
It is.
All right so that's enough about columns.
I mentioned earlier that we can use CSSA 3 to calculate values for us and doing that is actually pretty
straightforward.
You may remember that when we built the code player way back in the queries section we wanted to have
a heading so we could even use the new head of tag and then a div underneath that
which was the height of the screen minus the height of the heading.
And we had to use and Jacquier to do that but we could have done it using CSSA three.
So let's see how that would work.
We'll start off by styling the head.
So this is just going to be a
100 percent height 50 pixels and will add a background color of gray
that we get so that's where our heading might be.
And while we're here I'll just set the margin to zero.
So that that goes all the way to the edge that we get.
Now then if I want my container Dave to be the whole height of the page minus the 50 pixels from the
top I could do that really easily.
So we use container.
And again we'll set the width to 100 percent we'll give it a background color of yellow and then we
would set the height to count.
And then 100 percent minus 50 pixels.
And that will do exactly what you might think.
It'll set it to 100 percent of the height of the screen.
Minus 50 pixels.
Now that's the basics of it.
What we do need a couple more options to make it work.
First off to get this 100 percent to work we need to set the position to absolute.
And we also need to add a Web Kit prefix to the height as well so that everything works in a crime.
Take a look.
There we go.
So now the height of the screen is the height of our page.
But we haven't had to use any javascript to work out what that is.
And you can use any kind of calculation here.
So you can multiply plus subtract divide et cetera.
That definitely makes your life much easier when you find yourself using javascript for styling.
All right so just a couple more things left.
First I would like to show you the flex box which is a great way of aligning things while avoiding flights
which can get quite nasty at times.
So the normal way to create a flex books would be something like create a class of flex box container
and then within your flex box container
you might have some more device with a class of flex box item or something like that.
I'm just going to put a few items in there.
And then with stylize
most importantly with a display of flex
and also display of rape kit flex.
We don't need a one here.
And then you might want to set a width
and a height
and I'll just set a background color here as well so we can see what's going on.
It's Aqua.
So as it is that doesn't change much compared to just a normal flex box.
We can use the settings we saw earlier to center things horizontally vertically which is a nice extra
feature vertical centering in particular can be tricky without a flex box but more importantly we can
use Flecha box item and we might want to give that a background color.
Of bisque Why not.
And let's give it a with of 100 pixels and a height of 100 pixels as well.
And you can see that these are already floating to the left of each other.
Make it a little bit clearer if we give them a margin so say 10 pixels and then if we added more of
those
then they actually start to behave like columns and they get thinner and thinner without going on to
the next line.
So compared to floating where we're not necessarily sure whether one element is going to go into the
next line or not because we don't know the screen size.
The Flex box is much more predictable for us.
So if we change the width here to 100 percent then it will stretch them out to a maximum size of their
full size but it will compress them if the page is an hour as well.
Now within that we can do some pretty fancy things.
So let's just add some numbers to these
so we can see which ones which.
And then you know flex box container if we want to we can set the flex direction to be road reverse
and we need to do the same thing as well with a Web Kit
in front of it and that will essentially lay them out from right to left.
We can also use a flex direction of colon
like that and that will lay them out in a column fashion and it will try and squeeze them in vertically
if it can.
If I change the container height to say 500 then it will stretch them out a bit more.
And we can use Collamer of us if we want to as well to go upwards.
So the whole idea here is to get a consistent lay out.
Now that might not be what you're after if you're after a responsive web site you might want a different
layout for different screen sizes.
But if you want to be pretty sure that your layout is going to be the same then Fluxbox is a great way
to do it.
If you really want your flex box items to wrap we can achieve that as well.
Using flex wrap and we've got wrap no wrap and wrap reverse.
I'm going to get a wrap and we'll add a Web Kit flex up as well.
And then if I haven't got enough room that will wrap around more like floated items.
All right.
So enough about flex box on onto our final of CSX three.
And this is a small but very welcome introduction and this is box sizing.
And to remind you about the issue with box sizing I'm going to give item to a cheeky bit of inline styling
where I'm going to give it a border of five picks solid grey and that will then as well as giving it
the border it will make it bigger than the rest because you'll remember from the CSSA section that this
width doesn't include the width of the border which in my experience is not normally the behavior that
you want but we can fix that with one line of series three.
And that's using Box sizing.
And then we can specify Borda box content box or padding box and I'm going to go for border box and
that will then include the border in the total size which will mean that item 2 is now the same size
as everything else.
Even though it's got a border and that even includes any padding.
So if I put padding of 10 pixels in there it doesn't increase the size of the box because the size of
the box is inclusive of both the border and the padding.
And I when I discovered that I breathe a big sigh of relief because it does make things a lot easier.
And you're styling things that have varying borders and paddings.
So that takes us to the end of our journey through HCM L5 and CSSA 3.
I hope you've enjoyed it and I hope you've had a lot of ideas about how you could use some of these
features in your websites.
A reminder again to make sure to check the availability of the various fancy new features that you are
using in the user's browsers and when necessary to include the Web Kit and Mole's prefixes to make sure
that you get the desired effect in every browser in which it's available.
It's now time to introduce our final language of the course.
It's one of my favorite programming languages and a great one for new code is to learn and that's Python.