Just before we start with a scraper I want to show you two ways we can get the contents of other scripts
inside our script.
And that's a very useful thing to be able to do for two quite different reasons.
On the one hand we might want to organize our B complex scripts into lots of mini scripts to help keep
them organized.
You might have a database connection script for example that you don't want to have every time but you
want to just save it once and then include it in your scripts.
On the other hand we might have content on different Web sites or servers that we want to access from
our site and we'll be able to do both of those by the end of this video.
So first off I'm going to show you how to include one ph P file in another do that we'll need to create
a second HP file.
So I'm going to go back over to five FTB and create another page file
call it included file page and then I'm just going to use command to open that in brackets and then
I'm just going to put
some simple BHP I'm included file
lovely.
That's what we need for that.
So these command w o control will be on Windows to shut that down and then all we need to do to include
that in our main page file is we use the include command and then we just give the name of the file
included.
I forget what I call it now included filed up HP
and then it will run the PH peacoat from that file.
So let's see it in action.
Now we don't want to resubmit the form that we gave.
So that might not look like much in terms of what we've done here but it's actually very powerful.
And if for example you want to have a site with say 10 pages but all of those pages have got the same
header and footer then you might want to have the header and footer as separate page files and then
just include those at the top and the bottom of each of your individual pages.
It's quite an efficient way to do it.
So you're not replicating code for every page.
All right.
So that's how to include APHC file from your own server but we can also get the contents of a completely
different site.
So for example we wanted to get the contents of everyone's favorite web hosting Web site we can use
file get contents like that with underscore between the word names and then the full you are Elser.
Yes.
And I will slash the read every w dot web hosting Tokarev UK you can try any Web site there you like
and it'll take a little while because it has to download it to the server and then display it to us
but it will get the HDMI contents and display them to us.
And this is actually something that we're going to be using in the weather scraper to get the weather
we're going to use an existing weather Web site and get the contents of it using file contents.
And there we go.
So it doesn't look great because the links work because we're not running it on eco with Hastings server
but we have got all the HDMI content there.
So those are two really powerful techniques.
When you're working with PKP and we're now ready to take on the final project in the HP section of the
complete web developer of course and that is the weather scraper.