So continuing our tour around the query UI so far we've set up a div with some text in it and we've
made it trackable by applying the Dragonball function to it.
And now we can drag it wherever we like.
So what if we wanted to customize the way in which this was trackable For example we might want to only
be able to drag it up and down not left and right.
Let's see if there's a way to do that.
So they drag a whole page on Jake where you come if we have a look down at the examples on the right
we've got constrain movement.
And this first example only allows you to be dragged up and down and this one on the left and right.
So a quick challenge can you see the code work out how to apply that.
In our case to make our text only draggle vertically Giffard
OK.
Did you do it.
Let's have a look.
View Source.
There we go.
So your eyes should shift past all of this really because we're not that interested in the styles.
What we really want is this here.
So it looks like if we add an option of access and set it equal to y that will only allow it to be scrolled
in the y axis i.e. the vertical axis.
So let's have a look at.
So now we can drag only up and down.
And of course if I wanted to change that to horizontal then that would apply as well.
So I'm going to leave that
there.
So you can see it in action.
Let's have a little look at some of the other trackable options.
So this one can be dragged about but only within a certain area.
And that one can indeed be dragged about within its small box as well.
So can you figure out how to do that.
In our case
did you manage it.
Once again it looks like it's quite straightforward.
We can just set the containment parameter to a particular ID or indeed just the parent which looks like
the simplest option for us.
So let's check that out.
Let's see if we can make that happen.
So it will need a div which will be our box.
So we're going to be naughty and put some inline styles in there.
We'll just have with 400 pixels height 300 pixels and background color
yellow.
So I have a little look.
There we go great.
And then inside that Dave will have a little paragraph that says I'm stuck in that box.
And then because that's our only paragraph we can select it using a P and then we want to apply trackable
to it and we want to set the containment parameter to parent.
All right let's give it a go.
And indeed we can only drag it in the box which is great.
Interestingly we can only drag it up and down as well.
Can you think about why that might be the case.
I hope you figured that out.
It's because we used a paragraph tag here and a paragraph tagged by default stretches across the whole
width of its container.
So I can't drag the paragraph left and right because it is already at the whole width of the box.
So if I change the paragraph to a span which doesn't span the whole width then that should fix the issue.
And now I can drag it up and down and also the left and right but I'm still stuck in the box.
All right.
So there's obviously a lot more options we can see.
But the last thing I want to show you about Dragon Balls is the API documentation.
So we've been working from examples here which is all well and good but sometimes you need a bit more
than examples to work out exactly what's going on.
And that's what the API documentation is for.
And here you can see all the details of all the different things that we can do.
So I'm not going to go into this in great detail but for example one of the options we can apply is
to choose whether or not a certain class is applied
whether or not the Dragonball helper is added et cetera et cetera.
And we've already seen the access option.
So that's where you get a lot more detail and usually some nice examples as well that you can see exactly
how it works.
All right.
So let's jump back over and look at another jay Querrey interaction resizable.
So this one looks pretty straightforward.
We can just resize an object using a little handle in the corner then so can you create a resizable
div in our carried.
Go for it.
All right.
Have you managed it.
It's pretty straightforward.
Again we just apply the resizable function to our div.
So let's create a div
just as they've done we'll give it an ID of resizable and then we'll select it with javascript.
In fact we can just paste that straight in so we're selecting the resizable div by its ID and we're
applying the resizable function to it.
I'm just going to have
Kwik-Fit of style them.
For my resizable Dave
and we'll have with 100 pixels height 100 pixels and background color really
OK.
There you go so you can see we've got the handle right there for us and we can of course drag this about
Great.
Let's have a quick look at a couple of the options here.
I think snap to Griots could be very useful in some situations.
So obviously there you overstraining the possible set of sizes.
And then we can do that just by setting the grid property to 50.
Let's do that here in gray it is 50.
So that's 50 pixels for the great width every game.
We could also
resize another element at the same time
every game go just like that.
Let's see how we do that.
So we just add an option of also resize along with the select set for the element that we want to also
resize and we set the other element to be resizable as well.
So let's try that.
So I will have to live with an idea of also just to save time and that's going to be quite similar in
style.
My initial one but we'll make it read and then we just need to add
the property here.
I'm going to put them on separate lines as we've seen before with commas separating them and then we
want to also resize
and we want to also resize the.
Also Dave the one with the also ID.
And then remember we just need to apply
the resizable command to all say as well.
All right let's have a look.
Fantastic.
So notice that grid only actually applies to the first one but the second one does resize smoothly.
OK so one final thing.
What if you wanted something to happen when the width hit a certain size you might be resizing this
rectangle.
And when the user goes above a certain way you might want to change the page layout in some way where
a word should be coming into your mind when you're thinking of doing things like that.
And that is a callback function as we've seen before.
So we're going to need to see how to find a callback function on our resize.
Let's have a look again at the API documentation and you can see we've got a bunch of options which
is what we've looked at so far.
We've got methods which are like functions that we can apply to our resizable so we can destroy it.
We can disable it enable it et cetera.
And we've got events and these are things that happen usually during the resize.
So this is when it's created this is when it's been resized and when the resizing is started or stops.
So what we're interested in is doing something when it hits a certain size.
So that's going to happen when it's been resized.
So this is a javascript or Jay queery event you want to do something when that event happens.
So you can see we've got various options again.
I'm going to look for a code example and this is then the crucial bit that we need here.
So we've seen this before when we've done callback functions.
This looks for a resize event and when the Resize event happens we run a certain function.
So that's what we're interested in here.
So let's jump back over and see if we can apply that to our original resize them or resizable.
So for now let's just
alert hello when the element has been resized.
Let's see what that does to get the right one that we get alerted hello when we've completed a resize.
We said that we wanted to do something if it reaches a certain width so we'd have to get the width
of our resizable.
We know how to do that.
We just select it in the usual way.
Resizable and we get the
this is particularly useful for us because it returns a number rather than if we use CSX with then that
will return the number plus peaks which we're not particularly interested in here.
We'd have to remove the ax.
So this is just a number so we can then check to see if the width is greater than for example 300
and for now what we'll do is just alert
big enough or something like that.
So let's have a look once we get to a bigger than 300 we get to big enough and that's just I didn't
stop the resizing.
I'm still resizing and we still get this pop up here.
So this is how we add a callback function to our resizable to do something when it's been resized.
All right now we're going to move on and look at an element that was designed with a callback function
in mind and that is the drop of all interaction.