All right so having looked at probables we're going to look at two of the career you I widgets before
we make our code play player project.
So the first one is accordion.
Let's have a quick look.
First off and see what that means.
And then I'll challenge you to make one yourself.
So accordions are pretty simple.
They look like this they're a way of condensing a large amount of information into a relatively small
space.
And then the user can select which bit they're interested in reading at any one time so they're quite
useful.
Our challenge then is just to recreate this more or less but do it ourselves without even text.
So I'm going to give that to you.
Go for it.
All right let's have a look then see how they've done it.
So the jey query looks pretty straightforward.
We just apply the accordion to the accordion div..
The div then contains obviously an ID of accordion and then an H 3 and then a div within it.
And it looks like that's what we need.
So let's try and recreate that structure.
See if we can make it work.
So we have a div ID of whatever we like but accordion makes sense.
And then within the accordion we have an H-3
which I just call title.
And then we have a div with some content in it.
I'm going to have some Lorem Ipsum which you may remember is some Latin that we can use to generate
some random text which just makes our sample websites look good before a client has given us their website
copy.
All right let's copy and paste that then.
So we've got a few more times and let's have a look.
Oh that's very good.
Of course I've forgotten my bit of Javascript here
should be pretty simple.
We just want to take the accordion element and apply the accordion function to it.
And just before I run that you might have noticed that I've managed to spell accordion wrong and each
of those
easily done and would result in absolutely nothing happening because you have to spell the accordion
function correctly.
Let's take a look.
All right.
There we go.
So it was indeed as simple as that.
And with just one line of inquiry we've got a really nice accordion effect then it's worth speaking
briefly about these styles.
These are the default Jacquier UI styles but you can apply different styles using the Jacquier UI themes
so you can see here for example they've applied the smooth smoothness theme and if you do a quick search
for Jake where UI themes there are a number of them out there that you can use or you could actually
start with something like this and create your own if you wanted something completely custom.
Your final challenge then before we move on to our code our project is to create a sortable list using
Jacquier UI.
Simple as that.
Go for it.
All right.
How you manage it.
Let's see how we do it up here where it says sortable
and very simply we can just sort out elements into a certain order.
I've actually used this in a few web sites.
It's a nice user interaction model.
So let's have a quick look at the source
so we've got two instructions here.
The first one makes sense with setting it to be sortable using the sortable function and then we're
doing the slightly strange disable selection.
So let's Firstly do things without that see how it works and then see why disable selection might be
important.
OK.
And then we've got a unordered list and a bunch of allies with a bunch of span's and classes which I
don't think we need.
So I'm going to try it without them.
So let's do it under my accordion.
We'll have a well again with an idea of
sortable.
And let's just put in some list items.
I use my usual list items for upcast and
Salmi
and Ralphy.
All right.
And then we just run our javascript's Rajai query.
We're going to apply to the sortable Dave.
The function sortable.
All right let's refresh and take a look.
So you've got a very normal looking list there but we can indeed sort it
wonderful and I trust then that you can also extend that and if you wanted something to happen when
the user has resorted then you could do that with a callback function which you would find in the API
documentation.
OK so that's as far as we're going to go looking into the various different interactions from widgets.
But there really are a bunch of very very useful widgets here.
The data pick picker for example.
It's something that's you've probably seen on several Web sites and is really useful autocomplete.
That's something I mentioned again at the beginning of this chapter that's a really useful thing to
be able to do and you can do it just straight away with Jake where you live and feel free to have a
click around and see how you might use some of these in the sites that you're working on.
So that takes us to the end of our J query UI too.
And indeed to the Jay queery section.
So all that remains is to make what will probably be the biggest project so far and that is code player.
Let's find out what it is and how you're going to make it in the next video.