OK so nearly at the end of the age DML section where we're going to be doing our big H D M L project.
But before we do that there's one thing I want to show you that is including content from other sites
in yours using eye frames and it's actually really easy.
So first off let's say for example we wanted to include the Google home page for some reason in our
web page.
All we do is create an I-frame and then we set the SIRC.
So just the same as with an image to whatever we want to use.
And this time I'll use everyone's favorite web hosting sites.
He care saying don't go to UK.
I'm actually using that because Google blocks I-frame usage of Google and it won't work.
But if we do it with web hosting it should work fine.
And there we go.
You can see we've got the page in there it's obviously in a small box at the moment but we could change
the size of that with CSSA later on.
And you can interact with that Web site just in the normal way just clicking on legs etc..
All right so that's a basic I-frame.
We can also if we want perts content from our own Web site in there.
So you remember this is an absolute link because it's got the HGT pay at the front but we had a relative
link as well.
So if we go back to our halo world that HDMI L
then you can see we get the content from that page as well.
So this might not look like something you want to deregulate put a whole home page or different page
in your site but it actually can be really useful if you want to use a translation service for example
to translate words on your site could use an I-frame to get the data from that site and display it on
your web page.
One other very common use for eye frames is including videos and embedding other media in your web site.
And that is why you might have noticed I've got this great song from Brian Adams up on YouTube.
It's not because I've been listening to it.
In between making videos it's because when we get to any video on YouTube and click the share button
the Owerri then the second option along is in bed and then that gives you some code which you'll notice
is an I-frame code.
So I'm going to select all of that using command or control on a PC.
Copy it to the clipboard using Komansky or Control-C and then paste it in right underneath the code
that we've got there so that some I-frame code in the wild you can see we've got some extra attributes
that we've got a width and height setting so that the number of pixels wide and number of pixels high
and with also got a framed border equals zero setting which you're welcome to try out on these ones.
In fact let's just pop it on there.
To have a look.
And as you can imagine that we'll get rid of the frame border and now we have a YouTube video right
there in our page and we can even listen to it right there if we want to.
Very exciting stuff.
All right.
So congratulations you've made it to the end of the first section of the complete web developer because
you've learned how web pages are put together with DML with headers and body tags.
You've learned about paragraphs formatting text lists images forms tables links HTL entities.
And then finally I frames that for a lot of new information.
And as I said at the beginning of the section the best way to keep this new information in your head
is practice it as often as you possibly can.
So we're going to start that in the next video by giving you a challenge to put all of this together
and make a fantastic first ever complete web page.