So we're almost at the point where we can do our big CSSA project.
But before we do that I just want to show you a little bit of styling links because they're very important
and there are some quite useful things that we can do with them.
So first off if you can remember this from a couple of videos ago.
Can you create a link to say Google dot com which is not underlined but then underlines when you hover
over it with your mouse over it.
All right.
Have you managed to do that to create a link.
Of course we use an I and then I Tref to refer to where we want it to go.
I wonder if any of you put Google dot com
like that in your link and then clicked and then got an error.
Can you think why that would be.
Because you need the TTP at the top to tell your browser that this is not a relative link.
So without that your browser will actually go to Google dot com on your website which in this case of
course doesn't exist.
So you need to put HTP at the front and then colon slash slash and then probably UWW is a good idea.
Even though Google Chrome will work without it.
So there's our link.
Just go back and now make sure that that works.
Yes.
Wonderful.
This is of course underlined those so let's change our styles
so that the standard link is not underlined.
And we do that with text decoration.
None.
But then if we wanted to be underlined on hover we use the pseudo class hover and then text decoration
underline as we've seen before.
So as not underline bear underlined when you hover over.
Fantastic.
So a couple of new things I want to show you.
The first is that you can get a link to open a new tab.
Which is particularly useful if you want a link to something which is off your web site but leave your
web site open.
So let's copy our Google link to see how we do that.
What we do is we set the target attribute of the link to link and that will then open a new tab Google
in I knew.
Just so we know which ones which open the link in it.
Let's have a look.
There we go.
Fantastic.
I think I'm just going to put those in paragraph tags.
So that they look a little bit more separated that we get.
And then I just want to show you a couple more of these pseudo classes so we can use Hulver to decide
what it looks like when someone hovers over it so at the moment it's underlined.
We can also use visited to change what it looks like when the user has been there.
So if I change this link to a Web site that I've not been to before.
Pretty sure I haven't been to Google or SE for example.
And you can see it's blue.
So Blue is the standard color for inks that I haven't been to before.
And purple is the color for links that I have been to before.
But we can change that and we can make that whatever we like.
So for example we might want visited links to be great but green for some reason.
And then you can see that one becomes green.
This one is still blue.
But if I click on it and then go back you can see now it's green because my browser knows that I've
been there.
So there's a couple more pseudo classes that you can use if you like find them.
Just search for pseudo classes links or something like that should get you there.
There you go.
Good old three schools again shows you what they are.
So these are the examples we've seen visited and Hulver.
There's also just a normal link so if you want to just style a link hasn't been visited and is not being
hovered over them.
We can do that.
And an active link i.e. the link of the page that we're on at the moment.
Then we can use a current active to dial that specifically if we'd wanted to do that.
There we go.
So congratulations you've made it to the end of the core part of the CSSA section of the complete web
developer because it's quite an achievement and you've learned a huge amount.
The best way to keep that all in your head is to practices.
And one of the best ways that I've learned to do this is by attempting to copy existing web sites.
And that's what we'll be doing in the next few years.