So this is the Wordpress dashboard and this is where you're going to be spending most of your time when
you're working with wordpress.
In this video I'll give you a quick tour of the main parts of the dashboard and show you how to manage
and set up your site.
You might be wondering at this point what your site actually looks like and we can see it by hovering
over example WordPress site and I'm just going to command click or control click on Windows visit site
to open it up in a new tab.
So this is it.
So you can see we've got the site title there example WordPress site and we've got just another WordPress
site will see how to change that in a moment.
And then our basic set up is quite bloke like.
So we've got our first blog post here which has been generated for us and then we've got a search button
and some recent posts down here on the site as well as look out side admen et cetera.
So it doesn't look like much but don't worry we can change it into something beautiful very easily.
But before we worry about beauty Let's get the site working as we'd like.
So first off you can see this update option at the top there.
You may or may not see that depending on what version you have got installed but it's definitely well
worth keeping your Wordpress up to date.
If you let it get out of date it'll get very vulnerable to hackers because Wordpress is so popular.
Hackers target WordPress sites especially out-of-date ones.
Fortunately though you can update within WordPress you don't need to download the files and upload them
or anything like that.
It all happens within the system so you just have to click the button and then let the update happen.
There we go.
OK so back to the dashboard.
I'm going to work our way down the menu on the left there.
So actually this home page you probably won't use a great deal with it does have some handy quick links
but I'm going to start by looking at posts so you'll only really be interested in posts if you are actually
making a blog.
But if you are.
This is where you'll write to your or your blog posts.
So if we click on the example one then that will take us to the edit screen where we can change the
post title and we can change the permalink as well we'll talk about that in a moment and we've got the
main content of our blog post here so we can just start typing something like that and we can use formatting
as well but because we're coders we're probably going to prefer the text version which allows us to
use DML to make our posts slick.
However we want from here while you're writing your post you can preview the changes and that will then
load up your changes without actually posting them on the site.
But when you're ready you can then update that post and then it will be live on your actual Web site.
Once you've done that one really handy feature of Wordpress is that you can go back to if you click
Browse next to revisions you can actually revert to a previous version if you want to get rid of those
changes.
You just go back and you can see the changes and restore the autosave and then update again and then
your changes will be undone.
So that's really handy if you want to go back and revert to an older version.
We can then choose a bunch of formatting options so we can have it as an image a video quite link a
gallery even audio and chat as well.
So you can experiment with very different post types but normally we're going to stick with the standard.
Next up is categories.
These are really useful ways to categorize your blog posts so you might have a funny category for example.
Or I don't know a world news category if you are doing a news website or something like that.
And then your users can view those specific categories very easily and search them as well.
I've used categories on several occasions when I'm not actually doing a blogsite.
For example if you were building a quiz website could use a WordPress plugin and then each post would
represent a quiz.
So don't be fooled into thinking that posts are exclusively for blogs.
You can use them to display any kind of content and then further down here we've got tags which are
much like category's but we can assign them more arbitrarily So if we're writing an article about coding
we might have page DML
javascript and fun as being Outbacks something like that and then once again the users can search within
the tax just like they can with categories.
But it's a bit less formal and we can assign them wherever we like.
Again you could use tag to have ways of categorize quid's questions your worksheets.
Whatever it was you wanted to share on your site.
Not necessarily just log posts.
And finally we can set a featured image there which is as simple as just uploading a file and then extracting
it from the media library.
Now I mentioned the permalink earlier.
So by default the pages look like this.
With a not particularly friendly looking you are well at the end there.
So if you click Change permalink then you can set them up to have a date or a month or have a numeric
look like that.
I normally go for the very simple post name and then that will just give you our help that looks like
that which is a bit friendlier and more sharable.
So let's save our permalink settings.
And then how just get back and refresh the page here and let's see what this link has changed you can
see it's a much nicer now.
Slash Hello world.
I could change that if I wanted if I didn't want the hyphen in there then I could just change that and
click OK and then update and that's all saved.
So that's how posts work.
We've looked at categories and tags as well although you can edit them directly on those pages.
You don't have to edit them within a post page.
Now media is much what we saw just now.
Normally I don't look at the media library specifically but when I want to add an item to a post I just
use the option right there.
So if we added again so if I want to add some media here I would just click Add media and that takes
me to the media library.
But if you want to specifically manage your media then you might want to do it
pages then are slightly different to posts.
They look very similar.
So we've got a sample page here.
And if we edit that you can see we've got some nice Stiefel content there.
And let's have a little look at our sample page as well.
So I just command clicks that I open it up in a new tab and you can see it looks like this pages are
different to posts because they're intended to store more permanent content.
So here is my quizz website example again you might use your pages to have a contact form and about
page or a list of all the quizzes that are available and then you might store the quizzes themselves
on posts.
So they are different in function without informe they're pretty similar.
And we can edit them in the same way set up a featured image although we don't generally assign them
to categories because they're more standalone.
All right then we've got comments which again may be useful for you if you're running a blog of some
sort but if you're not you may want to disable comments I'll show you how to do that in a moment but
here we've got our sample comments which we can either unapproved Reply-To or send to spam now the appearance
tap is where things get really interesting.
So I'm going to save themes for the next video but this is where we would add a new theme where we can
completely change the look of our site and also where we would customize what appears in various places.
That's a pretty meaty topic in itself though.
So we're going to do that separately in the next video.
Plugins we'll have a quick look at what plugins are installed by default.
Most of these you won't be using directly but they are working in the background but WordPress has a
huge community that are building plugins.
And if we do a quick search for Wordpress plugins find 43000 plugins are available.
So we've got beby press forum software caching software that speeds up your site but the press turns
your site into a social network themed check to make sure your theme is working correctly.
And there's a lot more in there.
Almost anything you could want to do with a Web site.
You can probably find a WordPress plugin that does it.
The plugin ecosystem is one of the best reasons to develop with Wordpress and really can save a huge
amount of time when creating things like contact forms logging systems or social features.
Speaking of which we can add users to our sites as well.
So most sites you probably won't want to have users but you might want to have for example a single
admin who maybe you was able to manage the site and then your client might want to be a member of the
site as well.
Just put an example usernames
in there and then they can be a number of different roles so they can be a subscriber a contributor
author editor or administrator.
With most clients you'd probably want to make them an editor which means that they could edit the site
themselves without having access to advanced features with which they might break the site.
Again one of the best features of Wordpress is that clients are able to update the content without actually
having to know any code at all.
So that's generally how you use users.
But as I say you can you WordPress to create log in web sites as well which means that breaches like
password resets and secure logging systems are set up for you by default moving swiftly on tools.
We're going to jump over because there's nothing particularly useful for us there.
But settings it is worth whenever you set up a new WordPress site to just quickly go through the settings.
It will start at Gen..
This is where the tagline just another WordPress site is put.
So you'll probably want to change that to something which explains what your web site does a little
bit.
This is out WordPress you are el and the moment registration is switched off.
We might want to switch that up to allow people to register and comment.
But we could also allow people to even be an editor or an administrator when they sign up chinked the
time zone date format and a bunch of other stuff that we're probably not that interested in the writing
settings.
I don't normally go in and edit these very much but you can actually post via email if you want to but
we'll jump over that and go to read.
Well there's one important setting and that's what you want your front page to display.
So by default it displays your latest posts but you might well want to have a static front page and
then we can set that to our sample page if you want.
And then that will mean that your home page is no longer a list of posts but some content instead.
So if you're not creating a blog then that's going to be likely the way that you want to set things
up.
OK.
So that's pretty much all you need to know about WordPress as a web developer though most of your work
is going to be in changing the appearance of the site.
So you want to set up firstly a good looking site but also one that has the functionality that you or
your client want and has all the links and the options in the right places.
So we do most of that with working with themes and that'll be the topic of our next video.