Congratulations on making it to the end of the javascript's section of this course you've covered a
huge amount.
You've gone from pretty much zero knowledge of javascript to understanding how to make your javascript
interact with your age DML how to make your pages behave as you want them.
And then how to create complex code structures using variables arrays loops and if statements.
In this video we're going to put all of that together to make a great fun reaction tester.
And this is how it's going to work.
So I've got nice instructions at the top there and all it's going to do is measure how long it takes
for you to click on the box after it appears.
So once I click there that took me quite a long time.
That was quite a bit quicker.
And now with keeping the speed pretty high.
So you can see we've got a lot of randomness here.
It's randomly positioned it's randomly sized.
It's randomly colored and it's randomly a square or a circle.
So there's a lot of randomness built in there.
And there are a couple of new things that we haven't seen so we haven't used timers before with using
time as both to measure the length of time and to have a bit of random delay before the next square
or circle appears.
So those two things are new.
And we haven't used random colors before either.
But all three of those are pretty accessible with a quick Google.
So I definitely recommend you have a good go at making this one yourself.
As always though if you have any problems you can just watch me do it and see if you would have done
it a different way.
So I'll give you a minute now to pause the video and give it a shot.
Best of luck.
So I'm going to start off by keeping things fairly simple and I'm just going to have a simple red square
which will then click on to make disappear.
So much like our disappearing circles program from a few years ago.
So this should be pretty straightforward.
I'm going to call it shape because I know that it's going to be a circle later on as well.
And then in the head we'll have a bit of style with a type of text slash CSSA and then we'll select
our shape ID and we'll go for a width of 200 pixels and a height of 200 pixels and a background color
of red.
Ok lovely that we got next then is the challenge to make it so that when we click on it it disappears.
Shouldn't be too bad.
So the documents don't get on by ID as we're used to.
The ID is shaped and we want to add an on click and set it equal to a function.
We want that function to do is to make the shape disappear.
And we do that using again document get element by the shape and hopefully you'll remember from an earlier
video that we do style dots display and we will see nothing.
OK let's take a look.
That didn't work I suspect because we need the known to be in quotes.
We get the world and if you didn't make that mistake.
All right.
Now the main new thing as I mentioned here is the idea of a timer which we haven't introduced.
Let's see if we can have a Google and figure something out.
I'll go for something like javascript timer javascript timing events and it's premising and it's good
O.W. W3 schools as well.
So we want to work out how long it takes before the user has tapped on the square now set time out excusive
function.
After waiting a specified number of milliseconds we will need that actually later on when we want to
make the square appear after a random period of time.
But that's not what we need it at the moment we need a time to measure
how long it takes.
And I don't think this page is going to give me that.
OK maybe I need to be a bit more detailed in my googling.
I'm going to leave that live there because we'll need it later on.
As Dr javascript's measure time something like that
measuring time taken for a function to execute OK.
We don't quite want to measure how long it takes to function but we do want to measure how much time
has passed and this is now looking very promising.
So it looks like we can use the Date Time function to get the current time and then we can use it again
later on to work out the difference.
Fantastic.
Okay.
So let's try that out.
And I'll carry it so I'll make it so that the time is first measured when the page is loaded and then
when we click we want to see get a new time so we'll call this and
then according to this case we just subtract the T and then that should give us the time that's passed
in milliseconds.
So we'll call this time taken.
And that is and minus start
and then let's just do an alert for now Alert time taken.
All right let's have a look.
And actually we want to make it disappear straight away so we'll do that before we do any alerting or
anything else OK.
See if we click on there 1 9 7 6 that sounds about right.
So that's just under 2 seconds.
If I do it quicker we get a smaller number.
So first off Bear in mind that this is in milliseconds.
So let's divide it by a thousand to get the time in seconds.
And let's also add a paragraph which is going to contain the time.
We don't want to alerting every time and the way we do that is with a span
I'll call it time taken.
There we go.
And it doesn't need to have any content.
Initially we're just going to fill it in here.
So instead of alerting time taken we're going to find the time taken by its id get element by id and
time taken so that we'll get the span and then we want to set the interface DML of that span to be time
taken.
And then we want to have an s to make it clear that this is seconds we're talking about.
All right let's take a look.
So now instead of alerting his shit display my time there Birnam OK.
So now we've got our basic functionality in place.
Our next challenge is to get our shape to appear after a certain number of seconds.
So as it happens the first google link that I clicked on showed us how to do that.
So this is the set timeout method.
I always prefer looking at the examples rather than the kind of definition I think that make it a bit
clearer.
And here so we can use set time outs to run my function after three seconds or three thousand milliseconds.
Fantastic that's exactly what we want today.
And we know all about functions because we learned about them in the previous video.
So let's set up our function first off
the way I copied that really I didn't need see we could have typed that out ourselves but we've got
it now.
So my function is a little bit vague.
We wanted to make shipe
say we do this using document to get element by ID.
And once again it's shape and we set that display again this time not to none but to a different option
which will make it appear now.
We haven't done that before.
So we should just check.
I think something like this ok that one looks promising hide and reveal text and graphics we already
know how to hide it.
We just need to make it display and there we go.
So style display is none.
We've already used so style display is block.
That's what we need to make it display so that essentially brings it back into the flow of the page
again by giving it a display property of block.
OK so that will make the shape appear.
We also want to start the timer at that point.
So what I'm going to do is all the fine my start up there and then I'll update it when the shape appears.
So this will run as soon as the page runs.
And because the start variable is defined out here and then the function is defined within that we'll
be able to use the start variable inside that function.
So again this is about scope.
Anything that's defined inside the function can't be used outside the function but things that are defined
outside the function can be used inside the function.
That makes sense and then we just need a command to make the shape appear after.
Let's say one second for the moment and it looks like the command that we need for that is set time
out and then the name of the function and then the number of milliseconds.
So let's do that here.
So I don't want to run my function.
I want to run make shape appear and let's do it after 1000 milliseconds.
All right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
If not just go back and forth the last few seconds again because we did quite a lot of new stuff.
One thing I will need to change is I need to actually hide the square before we start otherwise making
it appear won't make any difference.
All right let's take a look see if fingers crossed.
The shape will now appear after one second that we get and it will then counter-counter from when it
appears this is the first time that the reaction time actually works let's see how quick I can get there.
No point two seconds.
Not bad.
See if you can do better than that.
All right.
So I'm happy with things how things are going at the moment.
Next I'm going to make it so the amount of time that it takes for the square to appear is not fixed.
So we've got a thousand here so let's make it a random number instead.
So I think we can put that straight in here.
We know how to create a random number so this will create a random number between 0 and 1.
We need to decide the maximum length of time that we want for this to appear so we don't want it to
be 10 minutes.
Otherwise the user is going to get very bored.
So let's say two seconds from now.
So this will give a random number between 0 and 2000 so up to two seconds.
Just check that that works.
Yes.
Looks promising.
I think that was different to before.
We'll have to wait and see.
All right.
So we're moving along pretty quickly here.
We've got our random time.
The main issue of course is that it only happens once and then the game is over.
Which isn't great but that's actually really easy to fix because of the way that we've set up this function.
So now all we need to do is when the user clicks on the shape is to run the function make shape appear
again.
And then this will make the shape appear.
One problem though is that that's going to do it immediately.
So soon as I click on it it's going to reappear immediately.
So there's two solutions to that either.
I could bring in the set timeout method here as well.
Or I could bring the set timeout method into the function.
And hopefully if you've been listening carefully to what I've been saying about functions you'll want
to do the second one because we avoid having the same code twice in our script if we possibly can.
So it makes more sense I think to set up a function
with a small f which I'll call say appear after delay
and then that's where we'll put
our instruction to make the shape appear.
And then instead of calling that directly we'll have a pair after delay there and also appear after
a delay.
Inside our Click code as well.
So hopefully that makes more sense if you can imagine an immediate benefit of that is that if we didn't
do it that way we'd have to have the set timeout method twice.
So if we wanted to change the maximum from two seconds to five seconds for example then we'd have to
change that in two places which isn't a nice thing to have to do.
So I think it makes more sense to keep it as it is.
All right them let's have a look.
So we should get a bit of a delay.
All right.
Bit too much of a delay there because I've forgotten the parentheses always a parentheses when you've
got a function that you are using.
Let's try that again.
OK.
Fantastic.
That's working really well.
Brilliant.
So now we're going to make the game a little trickier by moving the square around.
And as always there's a few ways that you could do this.
I'm going to do it with positioning.
So you'll remember hopefully that we if we set our position to relative and we can do things like setting
the top to 100 pixels which will shift it down 100 pixels and we can also have the left to say 200 pixels
which will shift it right or give it a left margin of 200 pixels.
So what we want to do is to introduce a element of randomness
with the top and left so we'll do that and they make shape appear
and you should be able to guess really how we do that with javascript.
We get the shape in the usual way and then we're affecting its style here.
And we're affecting the top.
I'm going to set that up just before we introduce any randomness.
Let's just set the top 50 pixels and then we'll just check it should be down 50 pixels.
There we go.
So we have moved it down a certain number of pixels using javascript.
We want that to be a random number.
So let's get rid of our 50 and let's bring in a variable I call it top.
And this is going to be the number of pixels and we want that to be a random number.
So math random and that's 50 pixels that say up to a maximum of 400
pixels.
And then we just use top plus and then peaks on the end to be clear it is pixels that we want to move
it.
So now it should be in a random position vertically each time we get
excellent.
So now sit just the same thing with left.
So let's have a left which is math Matho random times let's go for 400 again.
And then we want to do exactly the same thing
get the shape element by its ID.
And this time will set the style dot left and that's going to be left and then pixels on the end to
give out units.
So now it should be randomly positioned both vertically and horizontally
Brenham.
We're really getting that OK.
Well we're really into our randomness I want to give it a random size as well.
So let's give it a random width of let's go up to
400 pixels.
That's going to potentially let it be really small but let's see how that works out.
And then once again get the elements
and set its width to width plus X and I'll set the height to the same thing.
Because I don't think we want sort of strange shaped boxes I want to keep them all at squares.
So let's see what effect that has
Yeah I quite like that.
I think that makes it interesting
OK.
400 maybe a little bit large scale for 300.
All right.
So really it's now just a matter of refining the game a little bit.
And one thing I definitely want is a random color generator.
So this is again something we haven't done before.
So let's see what we can get from a google random color generator in javascript that looks pretty good.
Let's have a look.
OK.
Then test it.
So this looks like it does what we want.
Let's just run through it and make sure that we understand what's going on.
OK.
Right.
So what this is doing is taking the letters and numbers that make up our DML Colaco and splitting them
into an array.
So this dot split splits a string into an array.
So what we've got here is letters being an array of 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 and a b c d e f.
Then we've got our color string which starts off with a hash.
As I told him all colors always do.
And then we got a for loop which starts with Isaac with zero goes on as long as I is less than six and
increments.
I buy one each time and then we haven't seen this before.
This is a way of appending to a string.
So color plus equals means we take color as it is and we add to it letters.
So that's this array up here.
And this is now familiar to us as well.
So getting a random number up to 16 and we're using math floor to effectively get a random integer or
whole number between 0 and 15.
So essentially this is creating a random h g l color code brilliant.
So we learned a couple of new tricks there as well as got some code that will be useful for us.
So let's add this function definition to our code
and some nice automatic indenting for us.
Lovely.
So now we've got our code in them let's change our background color a document get element by id shape
and then style and.
Whereas background color just see it all on one line.
So we're going to want to get random color
empty pair of parentheses because it doesn't need any variables passed to it and that's it.
So that should give us a random color each time as well.
Gang Green purple the gray probably pink fantastic little bit agree.
OK.
This is looking great.
So there's actually only one more feature I want to add on the shape itself and that is I want to occasionally
to appear as a circle.
So let's say we wanted to be a circle 50 percent of the time.
We can do that with an if statement and we'll take once again.
Good old math taught random.
And so if that's bigger than no point five
then we'll make it a circle.
We could have less than there as well.
It doesn't make any difference.
But this will happen on average half the time.
So to make it a circle hopefully you remember we get the element by its ID as before and style.
And we want to do is set the border radius to be 50 percent.
So that means it should be a circle.
We get 50 percent of the time two circles three circles four circles.
And it's vanished.
I think that's a problem with our code.
I think it's there somewhere but it's so small I can't see it.
So I think we're going to need a minimum size.
It does appear to be a circle.
Every time
which is unlikely.
Let's have a look and see if something's gone wrong.
Ah yes.
Can you see what the issue is.
It's quite a good one.
What it is is because it was a circle the first time we set the border radius to 50 percent and then
the border radius was set to 50 percent full stop.
So even if it wasn't greater than 0.5 the second time it was still a circle.
So we need to had an instruction to say if that's not the case then set the border radius back to zero
or
well-done if you spotted that as before.
Border radius
zero.
OK let's have a look.
So now we've got a square and a circle
and something very small.
There it is
a square
and something very small again.
OK we definitely want to have a minimum size here.
So let's change the width to be a random number from 0 to 200 and then we'll add 100 to that.
And that effectively gives us a random number between 100 and 300.
So it shouldn't get too small every day.
Pretty So we're nearly done.
All I'm going to do is wrap it up a little bit give it a nice font and a bit of a title at the top so
it looks like more of a finished article.
So that's pretty trivial in the scheme of things.
But still makes all the difference.
So it will cool it reaction time them and then we'll have an H1 which says test your reactions
and a little bit of instruction.
So let's say click on the boxes and circles as quickly as you can.
And I'm going to use a neat sensor font and we'll do that for everything.
So I'll use body and then we'll set the phone family too.
I'll keep it simple and just choose sans serif see how that looks.
OK.
Nice.
I'd like a little bit more emphasis of your time down here in say let's make that bold
and we'll do that with a class of bold so funny white is old and then we go so let's have a look that's
working great.
Fantastic.
Hope you enjoyed that one.
See if you can get a better time than me.
And as always there's a lot of ways you could extend this so you might want to save the as quickest
time for example.
So it displays that constantly and then that gives them a challenge to beat it.
You might want to show their average time or you might want to change the way the box display is completely
up to you.
But I hope you enjoy that.
And as always I hope you manage to do a fair bit of it yourself or if not that you realized after we
completed it.
Yeah maybe I could have done more of that.
Congratulations once again forgetting pretty much to the end of this chapter we've just got one small
video left and that's going to show you just like with CSX how we can store our javascript in a separate
file using external javascript.