So congratulations once again on making it to the end of the CSSA section of this course.
You've gone from almost no knowledge of CSI as to exactly how to implement it into your pages and then
some really quite advanced CSSA techniques involving pseudo classes layouts selectors like classes and
ideas and a lot more.
So now's your chance to use all of those skills and create something real.
The challenge I'm about to set will definitely be the toughest challenge that you've had so far in this
course
but I hope that you'll learn the most from it as well.
So what we're going to be doing is cloning this page.
The BBC News website and I've chosen the tech page not because I don't like Asda but as a upcoming web
developer you should definitely be keeping up with the latest tech developments.
So creating something like this is definitely not going to be easy.
But the more effort you put into figuring stuff out yourself the more you'll learn from it.
So one option is to follow along with me as I recreate this page which is perfectly fine but I would
certainly recommend at least attempting recreating parts of it on your own.
You've got all the skill and techniques that you need and if you've forgotten any or want to try something
else there's always Google to figure out something more advanced.
So if you possibly can have a go at it yourself before you watch the videos and follow along with me
one word of warning don't necessarily be too fussy.
We're not going to use the exact same font and some of our layouts might not be exactly the same as
this site but it'll be close enough that the layman probably couldn't tell the difference.
Least a first glance.
One final thing before we begin.
Of course the news on whatever day you are doing this is going to be different to what I'm seeing here.
I think that's a plus and it will give you the opportunity to do something slightly different to what
I've done.
But if you want the exact same page that I'm going to be working with then you can jump to complete
web developer course com slash clone and we're going to be doing it without the cookie message at the
top.
So this is the exact page and this is not going to change.
I'm going to go as far as about this line here so where that gray line is all the way along because
I don't think you don't necessarily want to watch me for hours and hours recreating the whole page will
just do that top up there.
If you want to be super creative Feel free to choose another Web site to clone or do this one and then
do a different one.
But I think the BBC site is a great looking site.
You'll learn a huge amount by attempting to copy it as well.
One final word of warning don't attempt to try and recreate the responsiveness of the site so the BBC
website is responsive which means that it looks different and lays out nicely regardless of the screen
with.
We're not going to try and recreate that at this stage we don't have the techniques but we will be covering
them later on in the course.
So all you're aiming to do is create something that looks like this.
I also wouldn't worry too much about making it look exactly right in every browser because I'm getting
it right.
In Crime and your cross-browser development skills will come along as the course goes on.
All right then so good luck.
I hope you enjoy the challenge and when you've done it do come back and watch me give it a shot.
OK here we go them.
So I'm going to start by creating a new page
so I'm going to do that within brackets so I will get a file save as a leader in your text editor and
then just call it BBC HMO save it then and then get rid of the style from the previous video and will
change the title so that that match is technology dash BBC News.
I've just copied that from up there.
And then
and then let's jump over and change this so that we're looking at the right page
in a browser.
OK and a quick check is always good.
There we go.
And we've got the rights Web site title as well.
All right then here we go.
Deep breath.
I'm going to essentially start from the top left and work my way along.
And that bar at the top definitely looks to me like a good place to start with a div definitely.
That's a section of the page which is different to everything else.
So let's start there and we'll create our div
and I'm going to give it an ID of top bar because it's the bar at the top of the page.
Now it's got a white background or at least it looks white to me.
I'm going to use the color picker just to check that it is.
Yes it is.
So all those F's in the middle are a complete white so I don't need to give it a particular background.
What I do need to do is center it so you can see that it could have fixed width but it is centered in
the page so as far as my clone is concerned I could forget that sintered bit but I would quite like
to do it.
So let's have a quick google to see if we can work out how to center a div within the page.
Well there again Center div in page that looks good that takes us to Stack Overflow Dockum.
If you haven't discovered stack overflow don't come yet.
Then you haven't been Googling enough to work out how to do things because it comes up all the time.
It's a great site so it looks to me that we can send to outlive by giving it a fixed width and then
setting the margin to zero and auto.
So that's going to be a zero margin at the top and the bottom and an auto margin on the left and right
so that should Senza it for us.
Great.
So let's do that
so for our top bar.
Can you use hash and then
top bar and will experiment a bit with the width.
I think about 1000 pixels is likely to be about right and then as we saw we want margin 0 and then auto
and I'm actually just going to give it a temporary background color.
So that I can see how wide it is and I think we'll need to give it a height as well.
So I will experiment with that.
My guess would be around 40 pixels.
OK let's take a look.
So there we go.
Excellent.
So I think that looks good.
It's about the right width and height but we do have this bar at the top there which I want to get rid
of.
We did see how that town to do that
a few videos ago.
I wonder if you can remember it's just a matter of setting the body margin and padding to zero.
So that should now align it to the very top left that we get to the very top anyway left only if it
happens to be smaller than a hundred pixels.
OK.
So now we can get rid of background color and the first thing we're going to want is this BBC logo.
So I'm just going to steal it directly from the page by right clicking or control clicking and then
save image as then I'm actually going to create a new folder called images.
You don't have to do this but it's quite a neat way of keeping all your images separate from your HMO
files.
And I'm going to call this BBC logo
OK.
So now we've got BBC logo dot PNB.
So let's pop it in and see what it looks like.
So we add an image using EMG and then we went to SLC and it's going to be an image is slash and I even
get that nice auto predicts that brilliant.
Let's take a look.
Fantastic sir.
I'm very happy with that.
But it is at the top of the page and we want it down slightly so I'm going to give it a margin at the
top.
So let's give it an ID of Logo Stephanie and ID because there's only one logo.
And then with the logo I want to set a margin top of let's say five pixels.
Let's have a look at that.
OK.
I think we could make it a little bit more than that.
Maybe eight number we're going to bring about purely pixel perfect hair but that looks about right.
It is a bit smaller by default as well.
So I'm going to stretch it out a bit let's try giving it a width of maybe 120 pixels.
OK.
A little too big.
That's true.
100 pixels.
OK.
That looks about right to me.
All right.
So now we've got our logo the bit to the right of here.
We want a nice vertical border there and we've actually got those to separate out each of these.
So I'm going to create a class for those with a border on the left so we'll need to float the logo to
the left because we're going to want to put other things to the right of it.
And then let's create this sign in Dave so we're still inside the talk by hand.
And we'll call it seinen.
Dave
we going.
Now we want it floated left and we want it with a border to the left and we're going to want that for
all of the top bar sections here.
So I'm going to create a class of top bar section and then
I'm going to assign those styles to that.
So we don't want them all to float left and we want this border left and let's try one pick's Gray.
Solve it.
See how that looks.
And there's nothing there that's interesting.
I suspect that's because we don't have a height yet.
So let's make it a height of 100 percent so it will completely fill the top bar.
And there we go.
So now we can see it.
It needs a bit of work.
So I think I'm going to add a margin to the right of my BBC image.
So that logo here just to spread that out and let's have a look how why do we want this to be
about the same as the distance from the top.
So let's try a margin right of eight pixels.
OK.
That looks pretty good.
We haven't got the color right.
So let's use our color picker to pick a color from the page and then try and isolate the color that
we want.
It's pretty tricky to do at this scale so I'm going to zoom in as much as I can and we can see that
it's one pixel here.
It's tricky to get it just right.
But I think it's that CCCC see that looks like the right sort of gray to me.
So let's jump back and change the border color from gray to hash.
C c c c c c it's Take a look.
OK that looks much better.
Great.
I'm going to fix the height later on because I want to put some content in first.
So let's zoom out again so we've got two things here.
We've got this image and then we've got the sign in text.
So let's zoom in and if we right click on this image you'll see that we can actually download it directly.
So I'm actually going to use the screen grab tool on the Mac which has command shift 4.
And that will allow me to select the image and save it to my desktop.
If you're on Windows you can use the snipping tool to do the same thing or if you have problems with
that.
You can always download it from the zip at the end of this section which gives you the whole of my version
of the BBC page.
So I'm going to go back over to find out.
And there's the file size screen shot and then the date and time I'm going to change that to sign an
image and then I'm going to copy it to the clipboard and pop it in my images folder.
So now let's jump back here either and add that in.
So we're going to put this in the sign in Dave and it's an image with an S or C of images and then
sign
sign an image tompion G.
And we go OK let's have a look.
All right.
So we've got it.
It's a little larger than we need.
So let's give it an ID of sign an image and then use a bit of CSSA to customize that.
So I will create a sign an image selector and then will set the width.
Let's try 10 pixels.
Little bit small.
Forty pixels but too big.
Thirty pixels.
Zoom out again.
I think that looks about right.
We want the same kind of height as the BBC logo.
Sir I like that.
And we'll need some margin for it as well.
We want a top margin and a left margin.
So let's see if we can imagine all the way around.
Let's try 8 pixels.
OK that looks pretty good.
I think that is about right although the left margin is actually a little bit more.
So I'm going to change that.
So 8 pixels at the top and maybe 15 pixels on the left
let's just have a look at that.
There we go.
I think that looks a little better.
It's maybe a bit large.
So let's make it slightly smaller.
And give it more of a margin at the top.
OK that looks better a touch more margin at the top I think.
Bring it down a little bit.
OK.
So next bit is the sign in text.
So we're going to need to change the font and make it bold.
So let's add in
that's just make sure I get the capitalization right set sign in with a small I
every game.
OK so we definitely want to float this image to the left so that it's to the left of our sign in text.
So let's just add that in
that sped up and now let's get this fund right.
Now I'm going to show you a little trick.
Think we'll use the same font throughout.
So if we select a certain bit of text right click or control click in Chrome and then inspect.
This will give us a bit of information about that particular text and the computed section is particularly
useful because it gives you a bit of information about that text so that can be really handy.
We're going to particularly focus focus on the font family.
There we go so the font family is something called helmet.
I think I'm going to go for just this last bit here.
So Helvetica Aeriel and sans serif.
I suspect these ones are custom fonts for the BBC site.
So let's see if we can change the font and we're going to want to change the font for pretty much everything.
So let's do that within our body tag.
And we want to set the font family to Helvetica Aeriel and then San Sarath if we can't get either of
those so let's have a look.
That should change the font of our sign in.
Fantastic.
So I think this can be a span
because it's not quite a paragraph on its own.
So we'll call it sign in text and we don't need to do a lot with it.
We need to make it bold maybe change the size and then move it down a touch.
I'm actually looking at the sign in image that I think should be slightly higher if that looks better.
So let's take a sign in
text selector and we want font weight.
Bold.
I'm going to make it a touch smaller font size.
That's try 90 percent and then
try moving it down around 11 pixels
OK.
I'm liking the size and weight.
It's not liking my Margene top 5.
So I suspect that's because it doesn't want to apply a margin to a span.
So let's try doing it with positioning instead.
So we'll give it a relative positioning with a top of 11 percent 11 pixels sorry that we get that looks
good it's moving down I think we need to make it a bit further 15 pixels slightly to fall 14.
Ok I'm liking that
OK.
That looks pretty similar.
You'll notice that there is this nice color that appears on mouseover here.
We're not going to be recreating that.
We didn't have the skills for that yet I'm afraid.
If you want to check out how to do that with javascript's then feel free.
It's not too tricky but it's definitely beyond our abilities right now.
Next time we've got this slightly strange wiggly line then I'm going to use command shift 4 again to
take a screenshot of that.
I'll try and get it accurately as I can.
And I recommend doing the same thing with the snipping to down to the bottom.
And while I'm here I'll do the same thing for the bell
we get.
So let's find though is that so.
So rename this one.
Bell
and I'll call this one wiggly line.
Now you can see I've copied some of the top of the screen there.
If you're on a Mac there's an easy way to fix that.
You can just double click on your image and then zoom in and select the bit that you want to keep and
then use command OK to crop and then you're left with just the bit that you want.
So that's really useful.
You'll need to use an image editor if you're on a PC to do the same thing.
Or you could just use the images in the zip file at the end of this section if you'd rather say let's
select wiggly line and bell and then copy them back into our images folder.
All right.
So our wiggly line is going to go somewhat to the right of sign and then
so I think it deserves it.
I mean Dave
which is going to be here so we're still inside top bar but we're not in sign in at the moment.
I'll call this one bell Dave.
OK.
And then first thing that we're going to want in hour belive is our image which is going to be our wiggly
line top PMG.
So I'll just have a little look about that.
OK that's fine but it's obviously a little bit large.
I suspect we'll need to mess around with that later.
But let's just give it a height for the moment.
I'll give it an idea of wiggly line which is probably not the sort of professional sounding ID that
you'd want to use.
And a final page but it will do for our purposes.
So wiggly line we're going to want to float it left and let's give it a height of for now we can put
40 pixels which is the same height that we gave the top bar originally.
So that will do for now we might need to perfect it when we've got everything in place.
Obviously it's pretty close to signing that.
So what I'm going to do to fix that is give my sign and text span.
I write padding all of let's say 50 pixels.
See how that works.
OK.
I'm happy with that.
I think that's about the right sort of distance.
Along right now we're going to bring in our bell.
So that's just going to go next to our wiggly line
so image
we'll call it Bell SIRC his images and then I'll
have a look.
I'm
happy with that but obviously we need to make it a little bit smaller.
So let's try a height of 15 pixels.
See how that looks cool a little bit too small maybe 25 pixels.
Yep I like that.
And then let's give it high margin.
So let's try a top margin of around 12 pixels and I left and right margin that's about the same 12 pixels
as well.
OK that's definitely a little bit too much
maybe 10 maybe nine
OK.
I will tell you this a little bit far from the weekly line as well so let's make that 10
maybe still too far.
Try it.
OK.
We can play with that and see how it looks.
Now we're going to have our relatively easy bits hopefully Newspoll whether I play or et cetera.
So let's bring in
a new class for those after the bell Dave I did float the bell.
They've left did I know I didn't see that
day that means everything will be to the left of it.
Now these ones I think don't need a specific idea because they're all the same but they will need a
specific class that they might need two classes.
They all have a margin left and they're all going to be floated left.
So we can use the Tabar section class for all of them.
Okay.
And then that first one that is just news.
Let's see how that looks.
OK.
So it looks fine but I think we're going to need to make it bold maybe a touch smaller and we're going
to need to add some margins to it.
So that's cool this top bar menu as well.
So go to classes and then specifically to top our menu.
We all have a font weight of both and I font size of let's try 90 percent.
We might not need it.
And then we'll have a margin of what we have before.
Actually what worked for the sign in text
14 pixels.
Let's try that's And we'll try 15 left and right as well.
OK.
Yes.
I didn't mean margin.
I definitely meant padding.
OK.
So yeah we're getting there.
We've got much too much left margin there and I think we need to move it up maybe just a touch to try
13 pixels there.
15 because let's have zero padding at the bottom but then keep out 15 pixels on the right.
See how that looks.
OK.
That hasn't helped our problem with our lines so let's try specifying a particular height.
Remember the height is going to be Plus the padding.
So if we want the whole height of this thing to be 40 pixels then we need to take away the padding at
the top which is 13 pixels.
So that leaves us with 27 pixels.
So let's have a look.
OK.
That looks a lot better.
Great.
We might have to fiddle around with that a little bit later on.
But that looks good enough for now.
All right so now we got some easy bits.
We just need to add sport whether I play a TV and more.
So let's do that by copying these divs so see if I can remember them sport.
I can't support whether I play a
TV and more
go.
Let's have a look.
All right.
I think for the first time it's starting to take shape.
I'm liking that we do need a little down hour there.
We're not going to bring in this fancy menu there but I will put down our I suspect we'll need to do
a little screen shot of it should be fine.
OK.
So same as before.
If you can't get that for whatever reason
then just grab it from the zip at the end of the section.
So there's the more let's bring that into
images that we get and then that's just going to go after more.
So let's bring that in.
Image with a source and then image is more.
There it is.
So we want it moved along a little bit.
And of course
the right size.
So I'm liking the position actually that works quite well.
So I give it a more hour ID.
And then I think we need to change the size First of all.
So let's try a width of six pixels and we definitely want this high margin left of let's say 15 pixels
and a little bit small 16 pixels.
OK.
Yeah that looks better.
And
maybe 20 pixels there space it out a little bit.
Great.
All right so that was looking good.
Let's jump back over and see what we need to make next.
So we've actually got left.
So we've actually got left in this top bar is the search box here which is going to be a text input
with a little bit of styling to get that image in the background.
All right so let's see if we can pull that off.
We definitely need a new section.
So let's create a new Dave with a class of top section
and then we'll start off just by putting in input with a type of text
and seeing how that looks in itself.
OK so we've got the input but that's not quite what we're after.
So let's do a little bit of work to try and make it look like that.
So we're going to need to make it why don't we get I need to set the background to that gray color.
And it's and we're going to need the magnifying glass image.
So while I'm here I'm going to use command shift 4 again.
You can use a snippet tool if you're on Windows and I'm just going to copy that to the desktop and there
it is.
So I call it magnifying glass and then I've just copied it again to Komansky Control-C and I'm going
to paste it into the images folder.
With all our other images I would get
so lets start by thinking about the right shape and size and that background.
I think I've just lost the background color again.
I guess I grab it again to the clipboard.
So let's give this.
And Heidi all such books
and then create some styles to make it look how we want.
So we'll start off with a background color that's in the Clipboard.
And that's going to be
number that looks about right.
We don't want any border here.
So I'm just going to put in border none.
OK.
We definitely wanted a little bit taller than it currently is but we might achieve that with padding.
Let's have a look.
Just putting some text in them.
So we definitely want to style that text a little bit
try bold font white.
First of all and I think a little bit bigger.
Yes.
So let's try a fun size of.
Start off with 14 pixels.
I think that looks about right.
And then we'll have a little bit of padding try out five pixels.
OK.
I'm liking that.
I think that's about close enough.
We then definitely want a bit of margin OK.
That looks pretty good.
I think that's about right.
You can obviously play with those depending on how much of a perfectionist you are.
All right.
So just before we add that image in.
Let's have another quick look at how it actually works.
If we take a look at this search box here and drag the mouse over it we can actually see that the image
is separate to the search box itself.
So what we actually want to do is get our image to appear on the right of the search box and it will
be nice to do it in such a way that clicking on the magnifying glass does the actual search for us.
Obviously we're not going to create a functional search engine here.
We can do that last bit quite easily.
So let's see how we achieve that IDF away if we just had an image would be just after the impetus to
have an image with an SLC of images and then magnifying glass
we'll give that an idea of magnifying glass
that we gave and we're going to need to add a flight left to the search box to make that flight nicely.
And then
find out let's just leave that blank and see how that looks.
OK so we've overlapped our 800 or so pixels.
I think that's fine.
Let's make it a little bit smaller.
And we're also going to want to remove the margin from the right of the search box as well.
So let's change our margin to 5 pixels and then zero and then five pixels five pixels and that should
remove that margin.
So the nice thing to get up now I'm not happy with the coloring.
It doesn't seem to match up.
So let's try that again just grabbing the right color.
Doesn't seem to be working too well for me here.
OK let's try that's for evil
OK.
That's a lot better.
Excellent.
So let's get this hyped right sort of at around 15 pixels.
OK that's handy.
We're now in the right range
but we need to make it a little bit bigger.
So let's go for 25 and let's add a margin top of five pixels as well.
OK.
Now we're looking good.
So I think we need a couple more pixels in the Heights.
Let's go for 27.
There we go.
OK.
That looks great.
Now what we can do at the moment is what I mentioned earlier which is click on that image but I'm going
to show you a nice and easy way that we can do that.
We need to do is change our image to an input with a type of image and then that will make it clickable.
And if we had a proper form that would actually submit the form as well.
So you can see that that's now clickable and effectively does the same thing as a submit button because
we don't have a form here.
When actually submit.
But if it did we would say that's as far as we're going to go on this video.
Our top law is now more or less complete in the next video we're going to create the news section there
in red and then the menu underneath.
I hope you are staying with me and that you're learning a lot at the same time.
I'll see you in the next video.