So if you can tell yourself away from our addictive reaction time for just a few moments I'd like to
show you how we can separate our javascript from our HDL in just the same way that we did with Stiles.
So let's first separate our styles to remind ourselves how we did that at the end of the previous section.
We're going to create a new file and I'm going to call this style dot C Ss in the same folder as the
javascript to HVM l file and then I'm just going to open up the javascript to alleged here Melgen to
get the styles and cut so command X or control X and then here in brackets I can actually bring out
a menu on the left there so that I can see several different files at once.
If you're in a different text editor then you can just switch back and forth between the different files
using Windows.
So once I've taken those styles I can put them into style.
Dot CSSA to get our indenting right and then back in the HTL file.
Hopefully you'll remember that we create a link with a rel relation of style sheet a type of text slash
C S S and an H ref with a hyperlink reference of style C S S and that's it.
So if we just check that and run it it should look exactly the same.
Fantastic.
Finally then we're going to do the same thing with the javascript's.
So ignoring the script tags for the moment just copy all of the JavaScript out and I'm going to cut
that.
So command X or control X on Windows and then I'm going to create a new file I'm going to paste all
of my javascript right in there.
OK.
And then I'm going to save that as script dot.
J.S.
said the J.S. is of course the javascript extension just like Dotsie SS But javascript and then it's
just a matter of getting rid of those script tax completely and replacing them with our javascript.
Now in most cases you can put javascript at the head or at the end of an AGM document.
I generally recommend doing it at the end partly because all of your HMO elements will be in place by
then but also because it gives the chance for the browser to load the page before the javascript kicks
in which usually allows the user to start reading the instructions or at least looking at something
before the Javascript has to finish.
But there are a lot of other considerations as to where you put your javascript which are beyond.
We need to discuss right now.
So I'm going to pop it at the end and we do this using scripts as before and as before we give it a
type of text slash Javascript.
And this time instead of NH ref we give it an S or C short for source.
Just like an image.
And then we select our file.
Script.
J.S. and for script tags we need to manually close them like that and like Link tags.
So lets have a look.
That should work in exactly the same way as before and it does indeed.
So hopefully you can see that especially if you're working with a big Web site.
We've now got everything really nice and neat.
And I've got all my javascript together in one file.
I've got my styles together in another file and I've got my HMO in a third file.
So it's nice and neat.
Fission for browsers.
If they're downloading a number of different pages on your site and pretty straightforward to maintain
as well.
So once again congratulations on making it to the end of the JavaScript section of the complete web
developer course.
Go grab a cup of tea and a biscuit but don't take too long because we've got some jay equerry to look
at and you'll be amazed at what we can achieve.
Just a few lines of Jake rary.
See you in the next section.