So in this video we're going to see how to set up FTB on a Mac and we're going to be using the same
software as in Windows.
So that is Firefox and Faia FTB.
So first off in Chrome if you haven't already got it then Google download Firefox and just click on
the top result there and click the big free download button and I'm just going to download it here to
my desktop.
It shouldn't take too long.
But while we're waiting I'll just tell you that if you haven't used it before Firefox is an alternative
browser.
It's quite highly used so it's worth having on your system to be able to check to make sure your web
sites look good in Firefox as well as chrome.
But one of the best things about it is it has a huge add on and a plugin ecosystem and one of my favorite
plugins is fire FTB which allows you to connect to your web sites using FDCPA.
So that's now downloaded.
So click on the DMD file that's downloaded and that will open up the Firefox installer and you'll be
able to go through the installation process and then you'll get something like this and you just need
to drag Firefox over into your applications.
Now I'm not actually going to do that because I already have Firefox installed but it's a very straightforward
process from there.
Just click next.
And then when it finishes installing I open up Firefox and you'll be presented with something like this.
So it looks like many other browsers that we've seen before and it obviously works in the same way but
we're going to jump straight to downloading fire FTB.
So I would give that a quick google and then click on the top result.
I don't stalk muzzleloader at all.
And then click on the green add to Firefox button.
Now once again I've already got five T.P. installed on my system so I can't go through the installation
process.
But again it's just a matter of clicking next.
You may have to restart Firefox to finish the installation.
All right.
We're almost there.
So now that you've installed fire FTB we can add it to our menu bar up here.
So you need to control click on the toolbar area not on any one of the actual icons and then click customize.
And this gives you the option to customize the icons that appear up here.
And I'm going to take five pay and drag it up to the top that then click exit customize at the bottom
and you should be back in Firefox but with the five T.P. icons showing.
So now we're going to click on fire FTB and you should see something like this.
So on the left here we've got a directory on your computer.
For me it's my desktop and on the right is where we'll see the files on our server when we connect to
it.
So how do we connect.
Well you've got create an account selected in the dropdown menu then.
So just click connect and you should see the account manager pop up and this is where we put the details
of our FGP connection in and we can get those from our control panel so on the right underneath unlock
pay go down and look at the T-P details.
So the user name is just the domain name.
So in my case we're Percival's test hosting package dot com.
So back over half of that as the log in the password you click on the link there and then select the
password.
Paste that in and the host is FDCPA dot stack C.P. dot com.
We'll type that in there.
And I would actually put the domain name in as the account name as well so that you can refer to it
later on.
And that's it.
So then click OK.
There is one more thing we need to do before we can connect and that is unlock FCPA.
Now eco web hosting have a security feature that FCP is locked automatically after a certain time to
prevent anyone else getting access to your files.
So we either have to unlock FTB by time and obviously the longer you choose here the more risky it is
in terms of someone else getting hold of your FTB log in details and being able to access your files.
Or we can unlock by IP address which you can use if you know you have a fixed IP address on your computer.
You can check with your internet provider whether that's the case.
But for now I'm just going to unlock for one hour there we go.
And now we go back over to fire and click connect.
And here we go.
So now you can see the files that we saw in the file manager in the previous video.
And if we look at public page DML we can see we've got our index file in there.
Now one thing you may have noticed about our Hello World page is that the image didn't display.
Now that's because we didn't upload the image file to our web hosting so let's do that now using FGP
so I'm going to go into the complete web develop a course folder and then number one HVM L and there's
my earth dot J pedofile so I'm going to click the right way to upload it and then it's now on the server.
So if I go back over and refresh the page using command.
I can now with any luck see the image there it is.
So we're almost done but there's one more thing I'd like to show you and that's the real reason that
I recommend using fire FTB over the other available FGP clients out there.
So the FTC allows you to edit files directly on the server which means you can click Save in your text
that is and it will save directly on the server which makes creating an editing websites much easier.
There is a very small risk involved with that that if you have a flaky connection occasionally Icesave
won't be registered and you'll actually lose the content of the page.
But that's only happened to me very rarely and I find it doesn't outweigh the convenience of being able
to add it this way.
Having said that you should always have a backup of your website files so that if you do lose something
you can just upload without losing all your work.
So how do we open a file.
Now text that is from fire FTB.
Well it's very easy.
But before we do so we have to make sure that the file extension.
So in this case dark HVM L is associated with text that is on our computer.
So that means if we double clicked on the page T.M. l file in the Finder would it open it up in our
text editor and to make sure that that's the case go over to Finder and find any HMO page doesn't matter
which one it is.
It doesn't matter which.
So I'm going to take my web page mail and then control click on that web page and click get info.
And then in the open with section you manage to click on the hierarchy to open it up.
You can select the programs that you want to open it up with and if you haven't added to your system
before it's probably going to be Chrome Firefox or Safari.
So you need to make sure that you've selected brackets.
Or if you've chosen a different text then you've chosen that text added to that and then you just click
change all of that will then change all files with an extension of HVM else open in your text as a right.
So now that we've done that we can go back to Firefox and click command you to open the file and control
click and open or we can also use command and O to open the file in our text editor and there it is.
So now if we want to edit this file live on the Web for example if I want to put a full stop at the
end of that H-2 then we just use command s to save and you can see it's updating live on the Web site
itself.
And if we go back over to crime and refresh the page you can see that that change has happened live
on the web.
So that's how I do most of my website editing.
And I recommend that's how you do it too.
Bear in mind that when you start using other file extensions such as Dot CSSA or dot HP you'll need
to go through the same process in Finder and make sure that you've controlled collect get info and then
make sure that they're all opening with brackets.
Otherwise when you use control click and open they won't necessarily open in the right editor and that's
it.
So now if you like you can actually work for the whole course live on the web.
And use this set up to edit your page live on the web on the right and view the output on the left.
I'm going to carry on working on the desktop just because it's a little bit faster but you've got the
power to work life.
Now if you want to.
Great.
So I hope you're clear on how FCP works and how we can use fire FGP to upload and update files on our
web space immediately and without further ado.
Let's get back to the code and learn some CSX.