Getting started with Python is very very slightly more complicated than with HP but will still only
take a couple of minutes.
So I'm going to go back over to fire after you pay to connect to my web server and when I'm connected
I'm going to be in the root of the web server which we saw right back at the beginning of the course.
And then you remember that we normally put our web based files in public HTL but our Python scripts
actually go in this folder called cgi bin.
CGI is short for common Gateway Interface but essentially these cgi bin is a place to put scripts that's
all going to be called by a client computer or a browser and then communicate with your web server.
And of course then likely send something back as well.
So this is where we're going to put all of our Python scripts.
So I'm going to start by control clicking and create file and I'm going to start with Hello World dot
and then the python extension is dot p.
Y.
And then I'm going to open that up by clicking command in brackets.
Remember you need to associate the dot p y extension with your text editor to be able to do that.
If you can't remember how to do it then go back to that how do I set up FTB section and watch that video
for your operating system.
All right but now you're here.
You'll remember that BHP had a symbol like that that said Right we're going to start doing ph Peeno
Python doesn't quite have that.
Because if we're in a python file everything we write is going to be python but it does have what's
known as a sheer bank line which is essentially a line that tells the python script where the Python
interpreter is on the server and the Python interpreter is essentially a bit of software that will process
the Python and then do what it says.
And on a web hosting service we use the standard shebang line which is a hash and then an exclamation
mark and then the location is slash use the US all slash bin slash Python.
So don't worry too much about that.
Essentially what that saying is that this is the location of the Python processing scripts on this particular
server.
And that's a pretty standard location.
All right.
Once we set that up we want to tell Python to do something.
So the thing that I obviously wanted to do is to print hello world and doing that is pretty straightforward.
We use print rather than Ekho as we did in THP And then as before we just put the string that we want
to print in quites like with javascript I can use semi-colons on the end but it's usually discouraged
in Python.
So we just use line breaks to our commands.
So this is a valid command but it won't actually work as a Python script on a web server because we
need to tell it first that we want to output some TNL and we do that with another print command which
is print and then content type text slash HLL.
And this essentially tells the Python interpreter that we want to output some text or channel and then
we just need to print a line break or a blank line essentially.
So we just use print and then an empty string.
All right we're almost there.
I'm just going to say that and then I'll show you what happens if we try and run this script as it is.
Now we access that script using complete web developer caused dot com slash cgi bin.
And then the file name which is hello world dot p y.
So if we access it now we get a file permissions error so permissions is not something we've looked
at yet but it's a good opportunity to do that.
You may have noticed when you've been using fire FGP that when you control click or right click on a
file there's an option to select Properties and properties is another word for permissions.
In this case and you can see here that we've got a number of different permissions which essentially
control what can be done with this script.
And we've got three that we should be interested in here.
Read write and execute.
So we set it up so that anyone can read this script which is good that's what we want.
Only the owner of the script can write to it.
That's again what we want.
But at the moment no one can execute the script but we want anyone to be able to go to the U R L and
execute the script.
So we just need to select those three boxes.
And that gives us a permission number of 7 5 5.
You can play with the selecting and selecting these options to see what effect it has on the number
that the number is just essentially a shortcut to get to the box takings.
So 7 5 5 is what you want for your Python scripts on a web server.
And now if we go back to crime and refresh the page we should finally get our Python Hello world.
Fantastics and now we're up and running with our Python script.
We're going to start running through the basics of Python programming and we're going to do that starting
with variables and arrays.