All right.
So you've now written your first bit of Javascript and this is as I've mentioned in line javascript
which is a very easy way to get it up and running but not generally the way I'd recommend doing it for
exactly the same reasons we avoided inline ss.
It's just very messy.
Just in the same way that we want to keep our style and our content different.
We want to keep our logic or our code or our javascript different from our content as well.
So the way we do that is very similar to how we put in our style.
We just use script and we get any javascript that we put in here will then be executed as soon as the
page loads.
Now that will work in itself but it's considered correct to put the correct type just to make it really
clear that this is javascript that we want the browser to execute.
So a very quick challenge for you then can you write a little bit of Javascript here to pop up the pages
loaded or something similar.
Once you reload the page go for it.
Did you manage it.
The challenge with possibly you might have included the on click command and if you did.
No worries.
But the javascript itself is actually just the alert part and then
whatever text you want inside the quotes then so that's it.
That's you need it let's just save that and refresh the page so you can see I just did a refresh there.
I didn't click the button but that javascript was executed.
A quick note about single and double quotes.
I used single quotes here because we had double quotes around the edge of the unclick attribute.
So if I'd used double quotes in there that would get very confused because the system would have thought
that this double quote was supposed to end this bit of text rather than start a new one.
So if you want to have quotes within quotes as we've got here then you need to use double and single.
But here we don't have quotes within quotes so you can use double or single and double.
Is slightly more conventionally correct these days even though both will work exactly the same.
Single is only rarely used when we have to use it.
If we're just using some quotes double quotes is the standard.
While we're here as well.
Just like C Ss Javascript has an optional semi-colon at the end.
You don't need it but you can put it there and that will enable you to put several different commands
on one line if you want to.
So I'd recommend getting into the habit of putting semicolons at the end of your lines.
But it's up to you.
One more thing I want to show you while we're here is the chrome console which is really handy for debugging
your javascript.
So let's get back to just right click or control click on the page and click inspect.
Like you may have done a few times if you followed along.
The BBC CSSA project with me and then we go over and click console.
So the console gives you two powerful tools.
First off you can actually write javascript straight into it.
So alert Hello.
One bit of Javascript that we know and then that then is actually run on that page itself so that can
be really handy if you want to check a particular command but probably more usefully is.
It will show you if you've got errors in your javascript.
So if I make a mistake and instead of alert I type or then.
First off if I run the page.
Let's just get rid of the console.
If I run the page no just nothing happens.
I don't get an error message or anything.
Just nothing happens and that's what will happen if there's an error in your script you won't get an
error message on the page itself.
It just won't do anything and that can be really frustrating but if we have a look in the console you
can see we've got a lovely error message there.
It is not defined so we're trying to use a command that doesn't exist.
So I have no doubt that while your pages in practicing with javascript you'll make mistakes and you'll
have errors in your code and the chrome console is a really good way to see what they are.
It even tells you what line your error is at so line 15 takes you straight there and then she bad C
straight away.
Yes of course I've just got that wrong and then you run it again.
Your error disappears and your code works.
So I'd recommend using that and I'll definitely refer to it throughout the course as well.
Notice that you can put your script code up in the head and in some situations that's a good idea.
I will see some of those later on in this section but generally for the first section at least we're
going to be primarily putting our code at the end of the page like that.
And that means that it will get executed as soon as the page is run which for most of these examples
that's what we want.
All right so enough introduction.
Let's get started and start writing some real javascript.