Rights and other with set up with Jay queery we're going to use it to detect a click much in the same
way that we did with javascript but we'll see Thursley how the syntax.
That is the code itself is a lot simpler but also how we can be a lot more flexible with the sort of
thing that we can click on.
So first off very quick mini CSSA challenge for you.
Can you create a green circle and two red squares using divs and see.
Go for it.
All right I hope you managed it.
I'm going to create a div with an ID of circle because there's only one circle and then I'm going to
create a div with a class of square because there are going to be two squares
that we get.
And then let's pop in some style
and then to make a circle.
We use hash and then circle to select it.
And we want a with of let's say 150 pixels a height of 150 pixels and border radius of 50 percent.
That's what makes it secular.
And then the background color of green.
All right let's just check that.
Excellent.
Oh indeed.
Jay query is still installed successfully.
That's great.
We don't need that carrot anymore.
All right.
And now let's get the squares.
So don't.
Because with selecting a class this time and will have the width and height the same
and this time the there's no radius and the background color is red.
Have a look.
OK.
That's great.
The two squares have kind of gone together.
So let's give everything a margin of 10 pixels.
To separate out everything.
Lovely.
OK.
So now we're going to write some jay Querrey which we'll just alert something when we tap on some combination
of these squares and circles.
So remember with javascript there was only one way that we sought to select an object and that was by
its ID.
There are other ways to select objects in javascript but we only looked at the get element by id command
NJ query.
This looks very different.
So we start off with a string character and that is just shift 4 for me and probably for years well
but it may be somewhere else on your keyboard and pretty much every j where instruction starts with
a string so the string here kind of says Right we're doing something with J query and then we put parentheses.
And as you can see here on my text editor saying we need a string of selector.
So inside these parentheses we enter a string and that's the thing that we want to select.
So if we want to select this first circle we want to select it by its ID.
So that's a hash just as it is in CSSA.
And then the ID circle.
So what this does essentially means select the circle and then we want to do something when that circle
is clicked.
So we use dot and then click.
So pretty similar to the unclick command but slightly different.
We're just looking at Click here and then we want to do something when the circle is clicked and just
like with javascript previously we create a function.
So you'll notice that there are bits of javascript that remain unchanged in Jay query and creating a
function is one of them.
As before a function pair of parentheses and then curly brackets to contain our function code.
So this is the equivalent of document don't get element by id circle dot on click equals and then function.
So it's a lot shorter.
And as you'll see in a minute a lot more flexible as well.
So if we just let that circle was clicked something like that.
Let's see that in action.
So the circle was clicked.
And obviously that doesn't work for squares.
Here's a challenge for you that can you change this code so that instead of selecting the circle it
selects the two squares.
So when either a square is clicked we get an alert.
How do you think we might see that.
I hope you got it.
It's just like in C S S instead of hash circle.
We use dot square and then this selects both the squares and applies this function to both of them.
So let's see that in action.
Let's change the alert to make it make sense first a square was clicked.
That's how I look.
So now we click that square.
We get the alerts we click the other square we get the alert as well.
We collect the circle nothing happens.
So this is the second big advantage of using Jey query as well as the code being bit shorter neater
is more flexible so I can just replace whatever goes in here with a class or an ID to select things.
I can also select things by that type so I could select all of the divs for example just like that.
So if it doesn't start with a hash or a dot then we will select all the elements with that name.
So we are elements that are called a div.
So now we change the code to a div was clicked then it will now respond when any one of those three
is clicked.
And if I click anywhere else nothing happens because there's no divs over there.
So this is an early taste of the power ease and flexibility of Jake Weary.
We can change our code by just a little bit and we can select both class ID and the type of element
that we want to select.
All right so now we've seen how to use a query to respond to a click.
Let's use it to change and adjust our website content.