During the course you'll probably have a few problems with your code.
It won't work as you expect it to.
You'll get bugs and you'll probably be pretty frustrated.
So I'd like to take a couple of minutes right now to show you how best to deal with those situations
when they arise and how to get answers super quickly.
So step one is debug your code.
Usual thing is to check for error messages.
So I would have a look in the compiler in the browser wherever it is that you're working to see exactly
what's causing the problem.
You can normally get the line number as well and then you can just use that to hopefully work out where
the error messages had in that bracket or the semi-colon or whatever it is that's missing and move on
with the course.
Failing that my usual advice is to remove all the code that you just added until it works again and
then add it in gradually one line by line then you should find that at some point it will stop working.
If it doesn't and you're problem solved.
But if it does at least then you know exactly where the problem is and you can start to find solutions
to it.
Finally if that doesn't help compile your code against my demo code all the lectures have code built
in to them so that you can download and then you can see what is different in your code and hopefully
see if that is causing the problem.
All right so what if you've done all this debugging and you still can't get it working.
Well step two and this is what makes you a real programmer is learning how to find solutions online.
So it's pretty straightforward really it is just googling my general approach is to google the specific
error message that you've got.
And if you don't have an error message then get one either from the compiler from the browser from X
code whatever it is and then Google that along with the name of the programming language almost certainly
at least one person if not several people have had that exact same problem.
And there's probably a solution right there on Stack Overflow for you.
So that's issue number one.
If that doesn't help then you can always google how do I do.
And then whatever it is they are trying to do.
Again put the name of the programming language in there as well and that will probably get you a few
lines of code which will achieve exactly what you want.
You can either paste those in and move on or you can see what was different about those to the code
that you were using.
And then hopefully work out where you are going wrong.
And then once again move on with the course right.
Occasionally of course you will have to ask them questions.
And that's absolutely fine.
I love that we've got 200000 people in the forums for these courses and people are extremely helpful
and I want to get answers to your questions as quickly as possible.
So the main thing here is to ask good questions.
I've answered thousands of simple questions now over these courses and I know what makes a good question.
So first off Be positive.
I know you're feeling frustrated and often that can leak out into when you're asking a question.
But if you keep things positive you're much more likely to get an answer.
So ask very nicely for help.
So you'd be very grateful for anyone that can help you out.
And you're much more likely to get a quick and helpful response.
Secondly be specific.
So don't just paste in a massive load of code and say this doesn't work what's wrong but once you've
done all the error checking and the debugging you should know exactly where your problem is.
So I send a screenshot of that code or send the few lines of code that are not working along with the
error message so that we know exactly where you're going wrong.
And then once again you should get a nice quick and accurate response to your question if you can give
a link to your code in action.
So this is particularly useful for the web course but maybe for other courses as well.
Either give a link on your web hosting or to just been dot com or another site where your code is actually
running.
Then we can make changes and test it out and we should be able to get back to you even quicker with
a solution.
Finally once you've got your solution thank someone if they've helped you.
I've looked back over the forms and the vast majority of helpful comments are not thanked at all.
Which doesn't encourage people to help people again.
So please do just go back and say thanks that was really helpful.
So that they know that they've helped you.
And last but not least while you're there.
Why not see if you can answer someone else's question.
If you've had help from me or from other people during the course then it's great to give back a little
to the cause and then help a few other people as well.
So while you've asked your question just answer a couple of other peoples and then that will keep the
love flowing and keep everyone happy and progressing in that coding Korea's so enjoy the course and
I'll see you in the forums.