So in the previous video we created some stylings using in line CSSA.
There are a couple of problems with this then burst is our styling is all mixed up inside our content
which makes it not very nice to read and difficult to maintain.
Also our stylings are linked to a specific paragraph tag.
So if I wanted to change all of my paragraph tags to a certain font or color or size I'd have to add
the style attribute to all of them which is messy.
So for that reason I wouldn't recommend using inline C as s except in very specific circumstances.
So the solution then is internal CSSA.
This is what we saw in the example dot com HVM L.
So we create some internal CSSA by creating a style tag inside the head.
We can actually put it anywhere in the DML but inside the head section is the traditional place to put
it.
We then set up a type for our style and the type is text slash CSSA.
So that then tells the browser that this is some style commands that then be applied to the rest of
the document.
So let's get rid of all the styles that we have and see how we can apply some styles from here to our
code in the body.
So just to reset everything we're now at the start with no style.
So if I want to apply say the color red to this paragraph tag then what I would do is I would start
with a P to say that I wanted to lie this style to all the tags in the document and then some curly
brackets add a bit of spacing and then whatever style I wanted.
So I want to color.
And then you can say we've got a nice selection of colors here.
Beautiful.
I'm going to keep it simple and go for red
so have a look.
There we go.
So that's how I applied the color red to that paragraph.
So a very quick challenge for you.
Can you double this paragraph text in size as well as keeping it red.
So make it twice as big.
Using internal stylesheets.
Go for it.
I hope you managed it.
All we needed was something like font size and then 200 percent.
Let's have a look.
I don't know something's going wrong.
I wonder if you did that.
If you did and you realized that you lost all of your stylings it was probably because you didn't put
a semi-colon at the end there.
And so just like when we were having our inline C S S We need to separate different styles with the
semi-colon in internal CSSA as well.
So now we have a look.
We've got it read and twice as big.
Notice you don't need to put a semi-colon on the end of the last one.
You can do if you like.
I kind of like to because it makes everything uniform and the same def. doesn't cause any problems.
So the nice thing about this is that if we then create another paragraph tag.
Wow I love internals.
SS something like that.
Then of course this styling will be applied to that one as well.
If you want to set all of your text to the same font for example you could do that very easily with
a single instruction in your internal CSSA at the top there.
So final quick challenge for you can you change the CSSA is cool header to being pink.
Go for it.
All right I hope you managed it very easy.
So just H-1 to tell our browser that we want to apply these stylings to all the H-1 tags and then color
and pink and an optional semi-colon at the end there.
Let's have a look.
There it is.
Fabulous.
So this is internal CSSA and this is how we're going to be applying pretty much all of the assets that
we learn in this section.
There is one more way to do it that is to have all your styles in a separate file which can be very
useful.
And I'm going to show you how to do that.
At the end of this section what you might be wondering is how you might apply styles in this way to
some paragraph tags but not others.
And that's what we're going to look at in the next video.