In this video we'll be looking at how variables and arrays work in Python.
But we won't be spending a long time on the basics because you already know that the real work with
javascript and HP.
So here we'll be really focusing on the specific aspects of python and variables.
So first off we can define a number in a very simple way something like that.
So if we wanted to define an integer or whole number we just use the name of the variable without any
dollar signs or anything else or even a vowel.
We just use the variable name equals and then the.
In this case integer value and then if we wanted to display that we'd use print and then the variable
name obviously without any quites.
So let's remove our Hello world and just see the action that we get 35.
Similarly we can create floating point numbers like if I wanted to create very bookoo Pi which might
be equal to three point 1 4.
And I can print that.
And they would get a decimal for me and we can work with strings.
Using either single quotes like we did up here or double quotes and we can print those as well.
So that's all pretty straightforward.
We can obviously do math with our numbers.
So if I wanted for some reason to divide my age by pi I could print that
just in the usual way.
But give me some horrendous number.
There it is what's important about Python though compared to both javascript and THP is that Python
is a typed language.
Now this means if you have a variable called number which is confusingly set equal to say five.
But as a string then that you would not be able to multiply by the actual numbers.
So if I tried to print something like number multiplied by age
bizarrely enough I actually get a big string of fives.
And what that's doing there is multiplying the string 35 times.
So that's actually exactly the same as multiplying name by age.
And that would just give me 35 lots of rope.
So Jim really multiplying a string by a number is not something we want to do.
And definitely if we try and multiply our circle number by a floating point number like pi that simply
won't work at all.
So in order to make these things work you need to do a process called casting and this is where you
take a variable of one type and cast it to another.
And that's actually fairly straightforward.
So if you want to cast our string called Number two an integer all we do is take the variable type that
we want our string to be.
So in this case an int and then essentially apply the method or function to the string and then that
will convert it if it can to a number.
So now we should get a result of five times three point 1 4 which is indeed fifteen point seven.
So you might use this for example if a users entered some data into your app quite often that will return
as a string.
But if you know that it's a number then you can use this to convert it.
You can also use float if you wanted to convert to a floating point number.
But that won't make any difference here.
All right so now that we've looked at numbers let's have a quick look at strings and let's set up a
string.
My name is Rob and see what cool things we can do with that really easily in Python.
So first off if we want a particular character from the string we can use SDR say zero to get the first
character.
And that actually works in ph P as well that we get.
But we can do a lot more than that.
We can do things like print s t r and then 0 to 5 to get the first how many characters to get that right.
One two three four five characters.
If we wanted to get the M What would we use.
Did you get it start at 0 6 0 1 2 3 4 5
so note it's slightly oddly printing from 0 to 5 here doesn't actually include the number 5.
So this is actually the first character to the fifth character and this one is actually the sixth character
because the 0 represents the first character
and we can all say
combine strings in the way that we used to say something like s t plus name is going to give us My name
is Rob or writes motoring on beekeeping with me arrays in Python are actually known as lists and that's
the case in a number of other languages as well.
So you should get used to the word list.
It just is another word for Array.
And to define one we might call it my list and then it's a very similar definition as in javascript.
Say I have my usual list of upcast and told me and Ralphy notice that lists can have variables of more
than one type in them.
So you could even put a number or something at the end if you wanted to.
And then we can access that list in the usual way.
So we can actually just print out the whole lot if we want to.
There we go.
And if we want to access Keston what would we type do you think.
Because that is just print my list.
And then one because I would be 0 1 2 3
that we get we can use a similar formulation as with strings if we wanted to print Tommy and Ralphy
together we can use my list from Tommy to.
But then again slightly or late we'd have to go up to 4 to print Tommy and Ralphy together if we just
did two to three.
Even though that looks like it should print to me and Ralphy.
That just gives us Tommy essentially think of this last one as being exclusive.
So we have to put four in there to get the base.
There's also a variable type in Python called a tuple which is essentially a read only list.
So we might define it like that and then to define a tuple we use exactly the same set up.
But we use parentheses rather than square brackets.
So if I just have one two three four for example in my table then if I printed
it will appear perfectly fine.
Indeed I can pick particular values so much people to what value would that print hopefully you got
three.
But if I try and take my tuple to and set it to five and then
print my cuple after that then nothing will happen.
It won't work because I can't update it but if I can if I try to update my list
then that works fine because lists are updatable so don't be confused by the word tuple.
It's just exactly the same list but as read only the final type of variable.
I'm going to show you within Python is the dictionary.
And this is essentially a two dimensional array and we've used them both in HP and Javascript before
but we haven't called them dictionaries before.
So to set up a dictionary we use curly brackets like that and then
we would define each member of our dictionary separately.
So we might have something like dictionary dad
is equal to rob
dictionary.
Mom is equal to the question and we didn't have to have strings everywhere.
We could have child number one.
Perhaps it's Tommy
and child and I'm pretty is Rafi.
And then as usual we can print the dictionary as we go and we can get any of the particular values.
And the usual way quite usefully if we want to we can print all of the keys
in the dictionary so that's dad mom two and one and we can print all the values as well.
There we go.
So I very much rush through that process because I don't want you to feel like you're learning all the
same stuff over again.
The main thing you should be focusing on is the differences between Python and what we've learned so
far.
So the primary thing is to remember that Python is a typed language if you want to multiply two things
together.
You have to make sure their numbers or at least you have to convert them from strings to numbers.
Next is to bear in mind that arrays are now known as lists but they work in a very similar way to what
we used to in Javascript in particular.
Then we had a new variable called a tuple which is exactly like a list but Read-Only.
And finally we've got our dictionary which is another word for a two dimensional array where instead
of just having a 0 1 2 and 3 items in the array we can choose the keys ourselves.
All right.
So now we're going to move straight on to looking at our first fundamental programming structure in
Python.
And that is loops.