All right so moving on from variables to array's you may remember from the javascript and Jay Querrey
sections that arrays are ways of storing a number of different values in the same object.
That sounds weird until you see it in action.
So let's create one straight away.
We use exactly the same structure as with variables so dollar sign and then whatever you want to call
the array and then we're going to set this equal to an array and then we just add the values that we
want to put in the array.
So we'll do the classic example for me at least over upcast and Tommy and
Ralphy.
Then we want to see what this variable actually looks like.
If we try and echo it
see what happens we get a notice.
So it's not quite an error but it's a bit of a warning telling us that we're trying to essentially treat
an array like a string because we're trying to echo it.
But then it does it anyway but all it does is tell us that it's an array.
So echoing an array doesn't do anything particularly useful but there is another command to print underscore
are the are there.
Is short for readable.
And print is a great way of showing you what the contents of an array or any kind of object are.
So let's have a look at we go.
And now we get a much more useful array.
And then the zeroth item in the arrays robe the number one item is cast and then to is Tommy 3 is Ralphy
etc..
And if you've got a big array it's worth noting that if you look at the page source then it's actually
really nicely laid out for you.
You don't get the line breaks in the HGL but you do on the page source.
So that can be a handy way of working your way through a big array if you need to.
All right.
So that's how we create an array in order to get some of the items we can do something like Ecko because
we're displaying a string this time we're just going to get one of the items.
And then my array and then just like in javascript square brackets and then the number that you want
within the array.
So a quick challenge for you which of the four family members is going to display
I hope you got it.
It is of course Keston.
Some of you may have said well it's going to just buy the first one.
And that's Rob.
But remember rates always start at the zero index.
So to display Rob I need to do my array zero.
And then at 0 1 2 3.
Of course if I attempted my right for then I wouldn't get any output.
I'd also get another notice saying that I'm trying to display an array index which doesn't exist.
So let's go back to three.
There we go.
Another way to define an array is to just create the values manually.
So I could have another array and I could set the zeroth item in that to be say pizza.
If we're doing an array of fruits and then I could set one today.
You'll get to for example and then
let's have a look.
If we display all of that we get a normal array that I think I'm just going to put in a couple of line
breaks.
To separate all that out.
So it's a bit clearer what's going on.
Notice that we didn't actually need to have 0 and 1 and then two and then three there we could put whatever
we liked.
If I wanted to jump for some reason to number five which might be coffee
then that works absolutely fine.
And that's because the arrays are associative meaning that you can put anything you like in the index
column.
So I could even go crazy and put a string in there.
My favorite food set.
That equals the ice cream for example.
And that sets the index has my favorite food.
So that can be pretty useful if you've got some information about a user for example and you want to
store that as an array.
You can have name username password whatever right there if you want to create an associative array
like this using indexes like favorite food and you want to do that straight away like we have here.
Then you can do that in a similar way as we defined my up top.
Let's create a third array and we set it up in the same way.
It's going to be an array but we first put the index.
So let's say we want a collection of languages here.
That index might be France and then we use equals and greater than to create a sort of Arrow and then
the language.
So that would mean that the index of France would give us French and similarly for USA
is English and Germany
German.
Let's get the quites
again.
Let's just have a look at that.
Poppin a couple of line breaks as well.
Keep everything separate.
There we go.
Sort of set up an IRA in a similar way that we did here but all in one go if you're going to do something
like that I would recommend having it nice and tidy.
Say something like that.
Would be a nice way to have it on your carrier rather than all in one line.
Just a couple of things then before we move on.
We can get the length of an hour.
That is the number of items in the array using size of search just like that.
And then whatever the name is so I'm going to echo that.
What should it be.
Should of course be three because there are three items in the array.
What if you want to add an item to the end of an array created like this.
So a non associative array with just 0 1 2 3 etc. has the indices.
That's easy enough.
So we just have my array and then empty square brackets and then whatever we want the new one to be.
So without giving anything away for example we might have Katie there and then that would add Katy onto
the end of our right.
Finally what if we wanted to remove an item from an array.
We can do that using the unset command.
So if we wanted to get rid of fronts for example from this array we would just use unset and then the
name of the right that are right and then the name of the item that we wanted to get rid of.
If we have a look at that then that will be the same but without France we can also use that on variable.
So if you create a variable and you want to delete it for some reason then you would use unset to do
that.
Correct.
That's all you need to know about arrays at this point in the next video we're going to move on from
variables and arrays and look at things which affect the flow of our code.
Specifically if statements and loops.