All right.
So hopefully you're getting the idea of how Jay quivery works in this video.
We're going to move on from seeing how we can change content with Jake rary to how we can change styles.
So let's go back to just having our circle.
So I'll get rid of my I-frame and as a quick challenge can you from scratch write a little bit of code
that will alert halo when you click on the circle using Jay queery of Coop's effort.
I hope you remember that.
We start with string.
And then in parentheses and double quotes we use hash and circle to select the object with idea of circle.
You could use Dave there I guess as well as we've only got one Dave and then we want to set up a click
function.
Parentheses after function and then curly brackets and a closing parenthesis then there to contain our
code and then it's just a lot like in good old fashioned javascript like.
Let's have a look.
Click on there.
Hello.
Fantastic.
So hopefully that reminded you the basic syntax for setting up a correct function.
What we're going to do now is change some styles of our circle when it is clicked and this is super
easy today with Jake Weary as you might guess the first thing we need to do is select the thing that
we want to change the style of.
So again it's hash circle and then we use don't see SS to change the process.
And then we just give the name of the property that we want to change and the value that we want to
change it to.
So if we want to change with for example we use width and then we set the width to whatever we want
it to be.
So I'd say 400 pixels Let's have a look.
There you go.
It stretches out.
So could you for example change the background color to red.
When it's clicked Durford
you got it.
It's just a matter of changing background color to red.
Simple as that.
There we go.
It's super simple and you can experiment as much as you like with changing different properties to different
values.
We can also get the values of particular properties using exactly the same function.
So if we wanted to know what the background color of a particular object was we could find that out
by just getting rid of the value of the property there.
So just like we did with HTL if we have a property and the value then that will change the value of
the property to whatever you state if we just have the property that will return the value of that property.
So if we take a look we could alert that whole thing and get the background color that we get.
So it's in the form Oggi 0 1 2 8 0 which is another way of saying green So a quick challenge for you
then can you get the width of the body of the page so the width of the body of this web page for
you got to remember to select elements we don't use a hash or a dot.
We just use the word or the name of the element that we want to select so body.
And then if we want the width we just change the CSSA property to width.
Let's take a look at 591 pixels.
And interestingly that will change if we make the page wider on our.
So now we're up to about 21 pixels.
So that can actually be quite useful if you want to change your website layout depending on the width
of the page.
You can use J query to get that with for you and then do something with it if you want it.
All right there's one more thing I want to show you in this video.
And for that only my squares back.
So I'm going to bring in my divs with a class of squared and then I'll just recreate the CSSA for them.
So we'll just change that to square and get rid of the border radius and set the background color to
red.
Take a look.
There they are.
Wonderful.
So what if we wanted to set up a function which made each of these disappear when they're clicked.
Why don't you have a quick go at attempting to do that.
Best of luck.
OK I hope you found a little bit of a problem there because what I hope you are tempted to do rather
than have a separate function for each div and give these two an idea or something like that which is
a bit messy.
We want to do it in a single function.
We might have tried something like Dave click function so that will action a function that will happen
when any of those is clicked.
And then you may have tried something like Dave and then to make it disappear.
We could use VSS and then you may have remembered setting display equal to none.
Is there a way of making things disappear so that looks reasonably promising but let's have a look and
see how it behaves.
I click on the circle.
It makes all of them disappear which of course we should do because we're saying select everything that's
cool the div and make it disappear.
So how do we create a single function which somehow knows which element has been clicked.
Well that's actually really easy.
And there's a very powerful javascript NJ query idea that I'm going to show you to do this and it is
the very simple keyword this.
So on the surface of it this seems quite simple.
In practice this can be a little bit of a nightmare to figure out what it's actually referring to.
But in this context all it is is in our case this is going to be the element that has been clicked.
So it's the element that we're dealing with at the moment.
So let's take a look and see what happens.
Now if I click on the green circle that disappears if I click on one of the red squares that disappears.
And obviously the final one does as well.
So this is a really useful keyword if you want to have a single function that applies to a number of
different elements.
But then but then it does something depending on which element is clicked or hovered or selected or
whatever.
Then this is a great way to do that.
So I'll give you another quick example.
If we wanted to just alert whether the user had clicked on a circle or a square we could use this to
do that.
And there's a number of ways that we could do that but I'll show you something like this.
So if we weren't alert and then you clicked on.
And then we wanted the name of the shape then we could give the idea of the shape if it was a circle
and we'd get that from
this dot attributes and then Id say let's have a quick look about that in action.
There we go.
You clicked on the circle.
So we've got the ID.
Obviously that's not going to work for this one because they don't have an ID.
You clicked on a undefined.
That's not what we want.
So to get the square in we need to add in an IF statement so we can look to see if
the ID is equal to a circle.
Then
alert that and it probably makes sense to change that out to just be plain text.
We could then change it to green circle or something if we wanted to.
And Else
let you clicked
on a square
Let's have a look.
We got fantastic.
Obviously we could check for classes or other ways to distinguish between different elements if we wanted
to here as well if we wanted to search for more than two different types of elements.
It's worth noting that this is a javascript keyword as well as everyone.
So you can use it in plain javascript if you want to.
OK so now we've seen the this keyword and also how to affect styles and to return the styles of particular
elements.
We're going to start looking at some jay Querrey Pacific features now and the first one I'll show you
is fading content.