So moving on from Naftogaz forms and tables are two things that with plain HTL now it can take a lot
of efforts to make them look good.
If we have a look at a basic form it's going to get rid of all my nav bar code.
I might have something like email and then an input I'm going to be very minimal code here and then
a submit button
something like that.
And I'm just going to take out bootstrapped for the moment.
It doesn't look great.
It does the job and the user knows what to do hopefully.
But it looks pretty 90s.
Similarly with tables.
If we put in a very quick table
then in fact I'll be very lazy and just put loads of rubbish in this time
it gets the alignment right.
But other than that it doesn't look like something you'd want to put on your web page.
There are also two elements that are pretty difficult.
Make it look nice responsively that is on a number of different screen sizes from your huge desktop
to your small user's phone.
Fortunately the bootstrap has us covered.
So let's see how we use bootstrapped to make nice pretty forms and tables.
So we'll go back and see the bootstrap Web site in and under components here.
I'm going to click on forms and let's scroll down pretty quickly to get something that looks like a
form.
And there we go.
You can see it looks a lot nicer than your standard form.
And of course because this is bootstrap it's responsive as well.
So it will change behavior and look nice on a range of different screen sizes.
So as before rather than writing all the code out from scratch I'm going to copy the bootstrap code
and we'll have a look.
Three
once up and running on our site see how it works.
So there we go.
There's a lovely form we should probably put it in a container.
Because we don't want it spread out right to the end of the screen like that that we get.
So then you get those nice borders and that responsive effect as well
so you can see the spacing is really nice.
We've got a good bit of padding in the inputs there and all the different elements are styled nicely
and we've got those nice pretty buttons that we saw earlier as well at the bottom.
So let's have a look see how we code it because it is slightly different.
Obviously this is still HDMI.
So we still have the form element at the beginning.
We then have a field set which is an element that we haven't seen before.
But essentially it's a way of grouping together a number of form elements but often it's only one.
But you can't put more than one in there if you want.
You can see here most of the elements are inside a field set.
So we've got our input there and then our password input and then our select etc..
So this has a class of form group which gives those styles and then bootstrap uses labels which we have
seen before but we haven't used a great deal.
They are a standard HDMI element and the advantage is that the label is then linked to the input itself.
So you can style it relatively to that impers. and you can see it's linked via the ID that sort of got
or label them have got our input.
We're used to seeing the type and ID and placeholder.
But we've got a class of form control form control is just a way of referring to any form element so
input input there as well.
Select would be a form control text area et cetera.
So that's again what gives it the stylings and worth noting as well.
We've got a type of e-mail here which I don't think we've seen before.
It's one of the HVM five foot types and it's very well supported by bootstrap.
So if you try and submit a form with an invalid email address automatically a warning if the e-mail
address is not correct.
And that's something that we don't need to program in at all but it's something that bootstrapped US
force which is the aim here makes our life a lot easier.
Then we've got some text with a element of small which again we haven't seen before.
But essentially it's just a paragraph tag.
But with small text and this has got the text muted class that we saw in the previous day which makes
it slightly faded as well.
OK.
So that's our e-mail address.
We then closed the field set element and opened up a new one for our password.
And from here on out everything is more or less the same.
So the two classes that are critical here are the form group class and the form control class.
So they they give all the styles and the layouts and the rest just follow a very similar structure.
And we're used to seeing radio inputs text areas et cetera.
All right.
So a quick bit of practice then to get this into your head.
So remember those two special classes that we needed.
Can you create a simple form that asks for an email address and a password and has a submit button at
the bottom.
Go for it.
OK.
I managed it.
This is what I would do.
I'll start with my container div.
I didn't specifically say you needed a container div.
So don't worry if you didn't but want.
But with bootstrap unless you want something to specifically go right to the edge of the screen then
I'd recommend putting in a container div every time.
Then we create our form.
No special classes then you get in my tapster line up all day.
Then we create a field set with a class of form group that's important class number one.
And then I'm going to create a label for my e-mail address.
I just call it email address and I need to specify that this is for and it's for the input that I'm
just about to create which will have an ID of email and then
we'll create an input with an idea of email is going to have a type of email as well and it needs to
have a class and it needs to have a class of form control.
I'm not going to get a placeholder or anything here will keep it as simple as possible.
That's how Alec we get.
So we're looking good already then for our password.
We'll create another field set with another class of phone great
and then just as before label for and this is going to have an ID of password
and will have an input with a type of password and an ID of password.
And of course class of form control.
And finally we'll have another field set with a class of perform group
and we'll have a button with a type of summit and a class of button and we want a blue one button dash
primary
and I'll just have the text of submit.
All right let's take a look.
There we go.
Fantastic.
So I hope you managed to produce something similar.
It is a good idea when you're learning these things to type it out for yourself at least once.
So you've got it fairly clear in your head what the classes are and how it all fits together.
Once you've done that there's no shame in going back to the bootstrap site and copying and pasting direct
from there OK.
Just before we move on to tables Let's have a little look at some of the alternative layouts and features
of bootstrap forms.
So the standard layout is what we've seen here.
The label above the inputs but quite often you might want the label to the left of the input and you
can do that very simply just by adding the class form dash in line to the form itself.
So let's have a look and see how that changes things.
So what we're doing is adding a single class of form in line and now the form looks like that.
Essentially it's all in a single line.
So that's great for say a small loggin form or maybe a search form at the top of your website but quite
often you won't want the whole thing to be in a line but you will want the labels just to be to the
left of the inputs themselves.
So we just scroll down a little as an option to do that.
There we go.
So this is my favorite lay out because it's using the screen space well for a wide screen.
But then if we get narrow enough then it uses the vertical layout again.
So a very quick challenge again then can you apply this lay out to the form that we've got here.
Go for it.
Hint there's the H M L you're going to need.
All right.
Have you managed to do that.
Notice we're going to remove the inline form class from form and the way this whole thing works is we're
putting columns around our labels and inputs just like we saw in the grid section previously in the
grid's video previously.
We've got a two column class on the label and then a 10 column class on the div which contains the input
say I'm going to add a row class to my field set.
You may experiment a little bit here.
It should work fine with field.
Even though they're using div here field that is essentially a div Anyway anyway it just semantically
clear that we're working with form fields rather than just generic content.
So I'm going to add a class to my label of zero for column small because we want this to switch into
the stack layout when we hit the phone screen size which is s.m and then we'll give that one two columns
and then we want a div with a class of again columns small and then 10 columns.
This one
that we get.
So let's just have a quick look.
Looks very good.
So if we expand that.
Yep that looks nice.
And then when we get a narrow enough point it reverts to how it was before.
Great.
So very quickly let's apply that to password as well.
So I'm just going to copy and paste.
Keep things speedy
you've got that class.
So the label we can add a row class to the field set and then we can add our div
to surround the password impot
excellent of big screen it's going to look great like that with a smaller screen.
It compresses it a little and then very small screen it goes stacked
correct.
So that's more or less what I'm going to show you with forms.
Feel free to have a look.
The more layout options here.
They're all pretty useful.
And if you're making complex forms especially then you'll be very grateful for things like inline checkboxes
or radio buttons removing labels.
Adding disabled States to inputs read only inputs and one more I'll just show you which is quite nice
is adding some info to the end of an input like here.
I really like this layout.
And you do that with the class input group add on.
If you put that before the input then it will add some content before the actual interactive part of
the input.
And then you can add some at the end as well.
So that's bootstrap forms.
They're pretty functional and they're easy to use.
Let's have a look now at bootstrap tables which are all of that and more tables will go back to bootstrap
and content and then tables.
Remember the lap of your bootstraps type may be slightly different to mine but you should be able to
find tables quite easily.
So we'll go through these a little bit quicker than we did the forms because you've got the idea now
but mostly you can see that these are a lot prettier than normal tables.
So let's copy the code
and we'll see that there's not a great deal
to change that.
So I'll put it just above the form so we can have both at once.
And then let's have a look.
There it is.
So there's a nice pretty table.
How are we doing that.
It's actually very simple We've got a table with a class of table.
Pretty much all the work.
If we remove that class then the table just reverts back to a normal table albeit with a prettier than
usual.
You can see we've also got a scope attribute here.
This is not actually a bootstrap thing it's a general HLL way of saying that this th which member of
a table header is the header for this row.
So you could also have a T-H with a scope of code for column for example.
But that is kind of considered the default.
So essentially this doesn't make any difference at all.
If we get rid of it then everything will still look exactly the same.
It just makes it clear that we're using th but it's not a column header it's a row header.
The rest of the syntax there is exactly the same as the tables that we've looked at before.
So let's jump straight to the more fancy things we can do with tables and bootstrap so we can make a
nice inverse table simply enough by using the table inverse class.
Let's have a little look.
Notice that pattern again of having an initial class and then other classes which customise that first
class type.
Then again so there's inverse table
we can buy classes to the table head against I head Inv. and the default to show different backgrounds
there.
And we can apply those to table rows as well.
One of my favorites is the table striped.
So let's have a look at that one.
There we go.
So that just makes a long table especially a lot more readable than if every writer is the same color.
And then there are various other ones so you can make it completely boarded overbold like that all with
a single class.
All of these things will be a lot of work to code if you're doing it separate from Twitter and a small
table.
And we can apply our usual colorings to the rows and the cells as well using active success.
Info warning danger etc..
And of course we can make our tables responsive as well.
All right so now that we've fixed two of the very commonly used HDMI elements tables and forms we're
going to have a run through some of the coolest and most useful bootstrap components in the next video.