Now that we've built our fantastic HMO based app our next challenge is to get it onto the app stores.
And as always there's a number of ways to do this.
But the simplest and quickest is to use service called phone gap build and we can find this app build
dot phone gap dot com now phone gap was a system to package HDMI all based apps in a format that could
be submitted to the major app stores.
It was then purchased by Adobe and rebranded Cordova and as well as allowing your app to go on the app
stores.
It also allows you to use plugins to access deeper aspects of the devices functionality like the accelerometer
or the G.P.S. or the microphone.
So if you want to do things like that then have a Google for cord over plugins and see what else there
is available.
We're gonna be focused here though on getting our app in the app stores as quickly as possible so quickly
scrolling down here again feel free to pause and have a read if you want to know more about phone get
built.
But we're going to be focusing on the free plan here that allows you to have one app with a maximum
size of 50 megabytes and you can use all the major Cordova plug in.
Not that we're going to be actively using any of those today.
So click the completely free button and then you'll need an Adobe I.D..
So I'll pretend that I didn't have one and sign up for 1 0 years up to code stuff dot com and then I'll
just put in a random password
and then agree to the terms of use
and that will then sign us up and take us through to the apps page and you can see we've got the option
to import from github or upload a zip file and we're going to do the latter.
So here are my files.
I've just got one index file and then I've got a CSX and J.S. and zapped a DOJ s as well so I'm going
to right click on those and compress for items and I'll just rename that Abdullah zip okay.
And then let's click upload is it and then we should be able to find it in mobile apps and there it
is.
So that will then upload the file for you and prepare it.
And I'll call it Rob's email client
pretty simple and then click ready to build it will then start producing the various files to deploy
for different platforms.
So here you can see the Windows Phone version has already completed so I can actually download that
straight away and run it on my windows phone.
Now I can do the same with Android as well so that will download an android file that I will be able
to run on my android phone.
It's an AP Okay so if you've used those before they're actually pretty easy to install on your phone.
IOW however is a little bit more complicated.
You don't just get a nice simple download for Iowa you need to do a little bit of work and in fact for
each of these you will need to do something called signing.
If you want to submit them to an app store and signing is essentially the process of proving ownership
of your app so that you can submit updates and generally control the app later on.
That process is not trivial for either of the two major app stores.
So I'm gonna show you how to do it in the next two videos.
We'll start with Android and then I'll show you how to set up your keys and signature files for ISIS.
And at the end of that you'll have something that you could completely admit to Google Play or the appstore.