First of all, a huge congratulations.
You have made it all the way through this app
without giving up and that's really, really amazing.
I'm really happy for you right now
and I really hope that you enjoyed this project
as much as I enjoyed coding it with you.
So, let's now look at the final structure of our app.
So, this is what we built throughout all these lectures
all these methods and functions
sitting in different modules and calling one another.
So, please take some time now to look at the entire code
that we wrote and then compare it with this diagram
to see that this is really exactly what we did
because, you know, just looking at the code
can be really confusing, right?
But after having something like this,
it all starts to make sense.
So yeah, you should do that.
And then, after that is done, I want you to think
of ways in which you could extend this app
and add even more features to it,
and then, of course, I want you to implement
these features as well.
So, not just thinking about them but really coding them,
and that will be a great way build up
your knowledge even more
and to start getting some practice in a project
that you're already familiar with.
So, that makes it a lot easier.
So, good luck with that and make sure
to share your progress with the community.
I can't wait to see the features that you come up with.