Welcome back.
So, in this lecture, we're gonna get
a quick overview of
what's new in ES6 or ES2017,
which is actually the official name.
But everyone just calls it ES6,
simply because it came right after ES5.
And, so that's what I'm gonna
do for the rest of the course.
So, before we start, just a quick
recap of what we already talked
about right in the first section.
So right now we have all these modern
javascript versions that we can use
in production, as long as we transpile
and polyfill the codes back to ES5, right?
And I'm going to show you how to do exactly that
in one of the next sections, okay?
So we're actually going to use ES7 and ES8
also in the next sections, but for now I want to
start by really focusing on ES6 in this
section, because remember, that's the
version that brought us a ton of updates
and new features to a language.
And so here is what we're going
to cover in this section.
So we'll start with the two new
ways of declaring variables in
javascript and that's let and const,
and then move on to blocks and IIFEs,
use string methods, and then arrow
functions which is a ute and amazing topic.
After that we're gonna talk about
destructuring, new array methods,
the spread operator,
and rest and default parameters
before we finally move on to the
big and important topics of
maps, classes, and subclasses.
Now there are two other extremely
important ES6 features that we're gonna
talk about a bit later because they
need some more background knowledge
and that is promises for dealing
with asynchronous javascript and
native javascript modules to a
separate or code into different files, okay?
Alright, and so that's it for the intro.
Let's now move on to the real coding.