Hi would you like to make an online multiplayer game using real engine.
My name's Ben tristam one of your team's top instructors and I've teamed up with Sam and I say the University
of Cambridge I studied computer science and I'm also an experienced developer so I'm real is insanely
powerful.
However if you've ever tried to make a multiplayer game with it you'll find it pretty difficult to even
get started.
Lots of technical challenges to solve.
Not very good documentation.
That's where we step in.
We're going to take it step by step and make it very easy for you.
But are you ready for the course.
So this course isn't for beginners like a lot of our courses it actually requires that you have experience
making a couple of games with unreel and C plus plus.
Now that said you don't have to be an expert at all by any means just a couple of games to know your
way around the engine and know a little bit of C++ will be sufficient and then you're ready you can
dive in and take this course.
And if that sounds like you were going to take you step by step through the entire process through the
course we're going to teach you the fundamentals of multiplayer gaming and how the whole the whole gamut
works from state synchronization and lagon latency.
All that stuff would be in there.
But we're going to build this syllabus through a series of projects the first project is going to be
a simple landing game we're going to use a land locally and it work via a VPN virtual private network
so you can connect to somebody over the other side of the world but without any of the complexities
involved that you will see later from there.
What do we do then.
Next up we are going to be building a pretty looking you like this that will help you in the future
multiplayer games to get your players connected and you can give it to your grandma basically and she
can play with you across across the network.
And then we're going to go and use services like steam to allow us to very easily again for your grandma
connect with each other and your friends over a network without having to use a VPN and then we'll go
onto the advanced topics of understanding state synchronization unreel wonderful social happy grandma
and the ability to make online multiplayer games with unreel.
And please take this course now.