Welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be talking a little bit about what the types of multiplayer game are
outearning that journey that we're going to take in this course through the multiplayer space and sharing
our personal ambitions for what types of game we would like to make.
All this is going to give us a really good grounding.
Let me just take a second to say well done for getting this far already and having actually dived right
into the course.
Now keep that up and keep making steps forward a bit of time so that you don't stall and find yourself
in a very dissatisfying place of having given up and if you have given up then just jump right back
in and maybe take a few of the previous lectures case of warmed up and build up that momentum again.
But basically what I'm saying is keep that great momentum that you've got and keep it going.
So you've been introduced to the community and you are itching to go and get building some stuff but
you don't quite know what kind of game should you build.
Multiplayer is a huge space and we've got to break it down.
And in this course we are going to break it down into bite sized chunks for you to digest.
And I'm going to go over in this lecture.
What types of games we can make with multi players in what is the map of this space and also how we
are going to traverse it.
What is our journey.
Can I be.
So let's start off with the overview of multiplayer game types.
The first were the three main types of game that we are going to be bucketing out.
Obviously it's going to be very broad and very hard going to be loads of games that don't fit into these
buckets exactly but have some elements of all of that.
But I'm going to start off with talking about turn based games.
That is the kind of thing like a like a card game or a chess game.
In fact many board games are turn based and they have some properties which we'll be seeing about in
the second.
Then there are real time in session based games real time session based games.
These are things like your classic first person shooter where you would go in and join a game and you
would boom headshot your friends and things like that and have a lot of laughs.
Now the m0 and persistent world they I bracketed them together is kind of persistent world an enemy
as a subtype of that.
And the idea there is that there is not a game that you join.
There is a world that you join that world is there whether you're playing or not it's not has not come
into existence for your benefit.
So let's have a look at these.
On the idea of synchronicity is that coming from the Greek of course.
Soon kronos which soon means together and Chronos means time.
So when we say something synchronous we mean that they happen at the same time.
And in games typically synchronicity as it is known is that the quality of a game meaning that you have
to both be sitting at the computer at the same time in order to benefit.
So we can say that a turn based game is not synchronous also known as a synchronous.
And what we mean by that is that I could play one move in chess and then you could.
Reply a day later and it would still be okay.
In fact these games could often be played via email or by letter correspondence back in the bad old
days.
So that is the idea of a term based synchronicity.
Now real time and m0 are both a synchronous if you want to shoot someone's head off.
You have to know they're there.
They need to give them the opportunity to duck.
So you need to be pretty much there in exactly the same time.
Now the session length is another important factor and it can identify the differences between these
games.
So the session length for a turn based game can be variable.
It really depends on how long you want to be playing chess for or how long you want to be playing cards
or whatever whether the game is.
It might depend very largely on the game play real time sessions tend to be much shorter because they
require people to come in sit down and all be there together.
Again that synchronous aspect for a limited time game that has just been created for those people sitting
down together.
So typically your butt starts to get numb around the one hour mark.
Some of you may have better padded chairs than me and may be able to sit down for much longer.
But then you're typically playing multiple games rather than just one very long game because not everyone
has a comfortable chair and then the NATO and persistent world we've got potentially infinite session
length because people can pop in and pop out and the world can carry on without them being there because
they're so large and because they just continue to persist.
When you're not there.
Then this metric is a bit of an interesting one the in the suitability I have kind of hacked together
here.
The idea being how good from a business point of view would it be for you as an indie developer to create
one of these games now for turn based It's excellent because you don't have to have a very large user
base to start having a fun game to play with other people.
You can have just a couple of users and it would already be great because they can be in different time
zones.
They can be not very hard core players but you can still have an enjoyable game.
Now real time session based is okay.
It's a bit harder.
So here you've got to have people there at the same time but you don't have the server costs necessarily
because you can have.
Players hosting the servers for each other they can be friends so you need a little bit more.
A critical mass of people in order to have multiple people online at the same time unless of course
you have a single player aspect to your game as well.
Because obviously if they're going out a fire up your game find that nobody's online they're going to
instantly close it back down again and not have had any fun.
And so he'll never open up your game again.
And that just means that your users are going to never take off because you never reached that network
effect.
But enough about network effect.
What about persistent world Emma.
Moe Well this is poor for a different reason.
Again for the same reason of the synchronicity being a little bit tough you need to reach a critical
mass to have some fun in the world with other characters but harder still is the technical aspect where
persistent world typically requires large teams of engineers.
In an indie studio you don't have that budget.
You also don't have the money to pay for all the servers that it takes.
So this can be quite poor suitability for indes.
And then unreal support now here unreal really has the best support for the real time session based
games.
He's just built in as we have seen.
We were able to just ramp up the two players with very little effort and obviously that is session based
because we are hitting play it last for a certain amount time until we hit escape and it ends and everything
we do own real tends to be a variation on the Real Time session.
Now that doesn't mean that you can't build turn based and you can't build persistent world games in
unreal.
It just means that you're going to have to build all of our logic yourself.
And so we are going to be starting off with using real time session based as this is what unreel really
supports and it also puts us in a very good technical grounding for understanding how we might make
turn based games as well as a persistent world games.
So we're going to be using that as a vehicle of knowledge to teach us about everything in the networking
a multiplayer space.
Okay.
So next up I want to give a brief outline of the journey we're going to cover.
So in session based games we have typically three stages that we go through in order to make a connection.
The first one is discovery finding who else is online who's hosting some games and finding a session
that we can join and play with.
The second one is connection.
That is where we are joining the session hooking up from a client sue a server will talk a bit more
about clients and servers in the next video.
And we are playing in the same space very much as we've already seen done in unreal.
That was the connection aspect.
Then we've got synchronization which is after the connection we need to make sure that what player one
sees is the same as what player to sees even though they are running over separate network connections
and we don't want player to if he's not the one running the server to be seeing a really laggy horrible
version of the game he still needs to have a good experience so we're going to talk more about synchronization
as well.
Now we're going to be roughly covering these in the order 2 1 3 so we to start off with connection.
That's what this section is all about getting connected and using and Real's builtin tools to make a
fun game already.
Then in the following section we're going to be talking about discovery was going to be a little interim
for you guys but we're going to be talking about discovery and using steam to find your friends online
and how to play em all that sort of thing and getting a self hosted servers up and running.
And then in three if I can keep on the same slide we are going to be looking at synchronization all
the gory details of how to make your game look smooth even though they're not running on the same computer
and trying to keep things in sync.
Okay so next up we have share in your ambitions that is going to be channelled which I have gone to
a few too many times already.
What will you build that is the idea here we're going to ask you to review the outline of games types
that I've just given you so it should be fairly fresh in your mind then what background are you coming
from.
Are you looking to be part of a big team.
Are you looking to be an indie developer.
Are you maybe already an indie developer or are you just a hobbyist doing this for fun.
Tell us a little bit about that and then tell us what you want to make in the multiplayer space.
Is it turn based.
Is it against my better judgment is it hammer M.O. or is it a real time session based game.
And what kind of aspect or a mere mishmash both.
Tell us what you're interested in and what kind of designs you've got in mind and what difficulties
do you foresee in this type of game obviously in a memo.
No I am foreseeing many difficulties but tell us a little bit about what you think they will be.
So pause the video and go and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
So hopefully you've gone over to the community website using the map from the previous lecture and I
hope that you have shared and also gone and responded to some other people remembering to give as well
as get.
Now the idea here is to just get thinking about the types of game 4 going to be making.
So here in this particular section we are going to be making a third person puzzle based game.
The idea being that you have to together solve the puzzle and we're going to be using this to get ourselves
connected over a network and understand what connecting over a network really means so that further
ado let's dive further deeper in the next lecture.