Welcome in this lecture we're going to be getting into the details of how our platform is working and
how it's not working so that we can make it go backwards and forwards between the target and the start
location were going to be creating a target and start location were going to be swapping them round
when certain conditions are met such as having gone past our end location at target location.
So we're going to get an effect that looks roughly like this.
We've got the platform going up from a start location up to a target location which is up there and
then back down to the start location and vice versa.
And it keeps going backwards and forwards ad infinitum.
So we are going to be implementing that.
Let's dive right in.
Okay so at the moment our target our target our platform isn't moving to the target and back.
In fact you'll notice that it is simply just moving off and let's see whether it stops at our target
location or not.
I would expect it to stop Let's go and have a look.
Why.
Because if we go to my visual studio then you'll see that we are doing.
The direction is the global target location minus the location get safe normal.
So I would expect that this target location my location gets smaller and smaller as we approach our
target and eventually the get safe normal won't be safe anymore and it will return zero for the direction
meaning that we will update our location by zero as well.
So let's see if that's what's happening that jump into unreel.
And you can follow along with this.
I'm just going to increase the speed of my moving platform to 1000 centimetres a second.
Go ahead hit play go shooting up towards the target.
And well it's definitely gone well beyond the target hasn't it.
Because if we click on it you can see the target location was just here.
Not very far up at all.
So why has that happened why is it gone shooting up and gone well past the target location.
Contrary to what I was expecting.
The reason for this is that the global target location is being recalculated every frame and it's being
recalculated from the target location which as we said before is in local space.
So we've updated the location of the actor and then have recalculated the target location which has
moved with the actor Meaning that basically we can never reach this target So this is seeming to indicate
that if we want to be able to reach the target now that we've reached it and turn back we're going to
need to make a note of where that target was initially as well as where we want to move back to let's
have a look at this in a little bit more detail.
We've got Target A and B which we have already said we want to take a note of right at the beginning
of our platforms lifetime and then we want to start moving towards it which will give us a current location
of C and then we want to say what happens when we reach B and turn back towards C..
So let's put this in in action.
Let's create a starting point and a finishing point to do that I'm going to go to my moving platform.
Dot H.
And we are going to we've got a target location and we're going to have a start location as well.
In fact we're going to make a we've got a target location which tells us the offset.
So the kind of local target location I want to also have some private variables.
Which are going to be the global target location and the global start location.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'm going to make them just fxi as they don't need to be you properties don't need to edit them anywhere.
So an EF vector global target.
Location.
And an F vector.
Global start location.
Like so I'll go over in to the C plus plus file and one going to do is on begin play.
I'm going to set the target and the start location fairly simple.
So first let's do the start location that's going to be global start location equal to get actor location.
You'll be following along here if you like.
And then again in begin play we're going to set up our global target location.
Equal to.
Now I am going to take that from our tick.
We're currently setting the global target location to we're going to set it to get transform transform
position of the target location so it's going to do that.
Transforming into a global coordinance only once and let's remove that global target location local
variable from tick my line.
Thirty three.
So now it's going to be using the global target location.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and save and hit build for this.
Now you'll notice I haven't replaced the use of location in our calculation of the direction vector.
So what I would expect at this point is that it goes up to our target n then stops.
Let's see if that is the case.
Okay.
That is a build success.
Let's go over into one and real and hit play.
Okay.
As expected it stopped at the target location but it is glitching out somewhat.
So what I would like it to do is to continue past that target location let me explain a little bit why
because here we've got see which is and midpoint it or it's a position along the way it's the location
and it's going towards be is going toward It's going towards B and then at some point it's becoming
zero and stopping but that's not a very clear thing.
It hasn't gone past be it's just nearly and B and that's not very exact will be much better if it carried
on shooting past B and we could detect that now it's gone past B.
So we need to head back.
So I would like it to shoot on past the target to do that.
What we're going to have to do.
Because that's looking rather weird and I don't like the look of that one bit is if we go over to visual
studio is if we replace the location with the global start location then what we're going to get is
a vector.
There is always going to be the same intake.
It's still going to be the right direction and it's going to shoot past our target location.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Global start location.
And just have a little think about why that must be true.
Because now we're not calculating the difference between C and B which is what we were doing before.
So as C got very close to B we ended up with a very small vector and it was hard to normalize that and
turn it into a direction because it was so small and the errors start to accumulate in our machines.
But instead we're just taking this much longer vector from a to b which stays constant no matter where
c is.
And so it's always easy to find a direction from it and we don't get this weird jittering effect.
So let's go back into one real now with it compile and let's hit play.
Right.
Shooting off into the distance and going well past the target point exactly as I expect.
No glitching and I understand why it's doing it this time whereas at the beginning of the lecture lecture
I didn't really understand why it was shooting off past so much better.
Much cleaner way of doing the direction in my opinion and it allows us now to do something very cool
which is where we want to go back in the other direction.
We can just swap around the start location and target location very very simple.
So that's the main reason that I wanted to do this and I kind of did it led you on there a little bit
but there's also other good reasons such as the fact that we want to shoot past in order to know better
whether we are got we've got to head back rather than just putting some arbitrary limit on how close
to the target location we end up getting.
So it is time for us to start swapping the start and target around based on some conditions and I'm
going to leave that up to you as a challenge a little bit of a tricky challenge but a challenge I'm
sure and confident you can do.
So swapping the start and target what condition will you use.
Have a little bit of a think about how you might be able to tell that you've gone past be gone past
the target and need to turn back.
Have a little research in the vector API and see well what you could use if you're stuck that could
help you out see what the better api has to offer.
Then I'd like you to implement the condition and implement swapping that variable around.
Now remember that when you swap two variables around you sometimes need to have a temporary variable
to store one of the variables into.
Because otherwise you're going to overwrite a value that was stored in one of the variables.
So go and have a go at this little challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So first things first.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to make sure that the let's have a look at our vector diagram just
to elucidate.
Just to make it clearer.
When C has gone beyond be one thing that I know is that the length from C to the start location is now
longer than the length from a to b.
So that's what I'm going to use as my condition.
So let's create a variable to hold that length from a to b which I'm going to call the journey length.
It's going to be a float.
Journey length.
And it is just this vector again.
The global target location minus the start location.
But then we want to get the length of that vector and to do that we need to have a little look at the
vector documentation.
So here are the docs that I've handly got in a background window and let's go over to it.
We've got an F vector and I want to find out.
It's either called the size or the magnitude.
And you could scan through the documentation's to find that and I think in our case it is actually called
the size so the size or the length the magnitude of this vector.
Let's go back into visual studio and just do a dot size which should get as a float of the size of that
vector of the journey length as we said and then we are going to have another float called Journey travel.
So float journey.
Travelled.
And that is going to be equal to rather than the target location.
It's going to be from the start to the current location.
So let's just copy and paste what was above but we will replace the global target location with as simply
our location.
Okay.
And now the condition to turn back is going to be.
But the journey travelled is longer than the journey length.
So if that happens then on the next line after I've created my two floats I'm going to have an if statement
saying if journey travelled.
My auto complete Give me a little bit of grief there and also completely the wrong thing.
Joint journey travelled is greater than the journey length Valis make this greater than or equal to
it shouldn't really matter too much with floats.
But just in case.
So it's great and are equal to the journey length.
Well then in that case let me put my.
Curly brackets on separate lines to keep in with unveils coding convention.
Well in that case we want to swap our global target location and our global star location now as I mentioned
we're gonna need a temporary variable for doing the swap so I'm going to create an F vector called swap.
And I'm going to put the in global start location in there.
And then I am going to fill the global start location.
With the target location.
I'm just going to copy and paste because there long names and I can't be bothered to type them all out
and the altar completes not helping very much so.
Just to recall this is quite a common paradigm.
When you wanting to swap variables we are putting the global target location into start location which
overwrites what's in the start.
Okay.
But that's fine because we've got that saved in our swap variable and then we can overwrite our global
target location because now it's safely in the start location.
So I global target location is going to be written overwritten with our swap temporary variable so that
swapped the global and target around.
That's fantastic.
And we then can carry on and do our getting the direction and updating the location as we were doing
before.
Let's build that and see if it has the desired effect.
Kate build success.
Let's go over into the unreel editor and hit play.
Excellent.
It's ping pong back and forth between the start and that target.
That's fantastic.
And I don't want it to go quite so fast.
Let's say let's just turn it speed down to 20.
Going into the details pane phone in speed and going to 20 hit play and watch it go in maybe a little
bit monumentally slow so let's up that again to 100 rather than 1000 this time.
Let's hit play.
Okay.
That's looking much better.
100 centimetres a second about one meter per second.
It's going to the target and then it's bouncing right back to the start and back to the target again.
Exactly how we want our moving platforms to work.
So I'm going to save my mat and that's a job well done and a challenge well completed and I'll see you
in the next lecture.