Welcome.
What's this lecture all about.
I hear you ask.
Well it's about implementing the core of my project my puzzle logic which is this trigger the trigger
that when you step on it will activate.
So let me show you the idea here is that I go and step on the platform and it moved.
But as soon as I get on the platform off the pressure pad so I can't activate any more.
However if I go over to my second player he can step on the pressure pad for me and watch me go across
to the new destination and then when I arrive over at the new destination.
I'm going to step on that pressure pad like so.
So that it can carry on being active for player number two player number two will be able to step on
it and go across as well.
So a collaborative puzzle solving element with our pressure pads they go I'm on the platform and I'm
going over to location number two.
Got to find these locations.
A better name don't we.
Okay.
Let's dive in and see how we can implement the activation and deactivation of these trigger pads.
So we've had little mention of what the desired behaviour for these triggers already is.
But let me just recap.
The idea is if I go and swarm myself near the first trigger and I go and step on that trigger what I'm
expecting is that the platform starts to move.
Now obviously the platform is moving in the first place so we need to have a way to make sure that platform
is disabled from moving until someone is standing on one or more of the triggers.
That's the idea that standing on a trigger will activate the platform coming off the trigger will deactivate
the platform as long as both of you are off the trigger.
That sounds like a counting set up to me.
Sounds like the platform needs to know how many active triggers there are and when it goes down to zero
it d activates and we can start off with a default of having one active and we can set up a platform
so that it has no active triggers by default so that it doesn't move by default without somebody standing
on the pressure pad.
That's the outline of the general behaviour that we're looking for.
So let's start off by creating an interface to our platform that the trigger can talk to to activate
and deactivate it.
When we stand on it.
So there's going to be two parts we will need the trigger to point to a platform and we need to have
the platform keep track of how many active triggers it has got.
So let's hop on over in two visual studio and start off with just the platform portion of that puzzle.
So I am going into source possible platforms and it's the moving platform the sound is going to look
at implementing the interface first and I'm going leave the details to you as a challenge.
So first off I'm going to create a private variable that's going to store the activated platform.
This isn't technically part of the interface though of course.
So we are going to make it a new property.
Because I want to be able to change the default in the editor so it's going to have to be at it anywhere.
And then it's going to be an integer because it's going to be a count of how many active platforms there
are.
And it's going to be active.
Platforms equals one by default which means that basically it is active.
No this is not active platforms are it's active triggers because we are platform.
So we've got one active triggers that makes sense.
That's why we are able to move.
By default if we set that answer zero then we will not be able to move then let's create a public interface
to this class.
It's going to have an active and active trigger and remove active trigger I think is the sensible thing
to do.
So let's do a void.
Add active trigger.
And voids remove active trigger like so.
And I think that's good enough.
They're public so we'll be able to call them from the other side of the trigger site.
So let's have a look at the next step.
It's going to be hooking up the platform the platform to the trigger or the trigger point at a platform
to do that.
We are going to use a T array.
So one the reason I'm using a T array rather than just a pointer to a platform is because I want to
give the game design a leeway to use one trigger to activate more than one platform at the same time.
So that's fairly straightforward or we've got to go and do is go over to our platell triggered on H
and then create a private variable.
I'm going to put it above my on Begin overlaps.
And it's going to be a property again because we want to edit it and give access to it to add designer
edit anywhere.
Because you want to be able to edit it in a map for example.
And then what it's going to be a pointer to a moving platform but particularly is going to be a tier
race so let's go ahead and look for documentation on this.
Handly I have the window open in the background here.
Let's go ahead to the first one that TI array documentation.
And let's see let's have a look at how we are going to construct a T array.
So I seem to recall that arrays have their element types as part of the generics in the in the angle
brackets and then we've got lots of adding inserting and stuff which is going to be useful.
And the question is whether we're going to have to include anything in order to use a-t array.
I don't think so.
I think it's kind of included by default by some of the other headers so we can go ahead and try and
see where that auto completes is often a good way.
If you don't have auto complete such as on X code then you can go ahead and try it and then see if you
get a compile error instead.
But if we do get it a compile error then we just need this containers arraycom h included.
So it's going to be a t array and it's going to be a t array of type here.
The in element type and you can see that construct on the documentation page near the top.
There's quite a few constructors so I understand you might be a little bit confused but it's not actually
a constructor at all because here we're just defining a type using t array.
So if we go to the top of our page we can see that the type declaration here has a template so to read
this you say well basically it's looking for a type in first and the second argument you can often ignore
if it's something like an allocator you can often not pass that in and it will automatically be defined.
So it's going to be a t array and then the in element type.
So let me just show you.
This is revision obviously you've used ti arrays before.
Now we want it to be a class.
Moving a moving platform.
Now in actual fact I have mis typed here but that will be fixed later on in the video.
It does need to be a pointer not just a forward declaration of the type.
And then we are going to just call this the platforms to trigger.
And so on.
That should do it.
So we've got gone ahead and created the interface on both sides on the platform trigger and on the moving
platform.
Dot H.
So it's time to implement the logic and that is going to be your challenge.
So let's have a look at the definition of that challenge.
I'd like you to first off fill out the interface.
That's kind of the whole idea of this whole challenge.
Let's go into more detail activate from the call-backs So that is the call-backs we've already got for
overlap and end overlap.
You need to be using those to basically call the activating platforms to make sure that they activate
and deactivate conditionally activate the platforms so make it so that they don't move when the number
of activated triggers is not high enough and then go and test that out in the world.
So pause video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive in to implementing this.
So first things first I'm going to go to my platform triggers dotsie P P in a visual studio that controls.
K. Oh I think moves over to the seapass plus file.
Yep that is right.
And the first thing I want to do is MY on overlap begin.
Instead of calling a log message what I want to do there is do a full loop over that t array.
Now you can have a little search for four loops over teh array.
And see what the syntax looks like as it's often quite easy range based loops I think is what we're
looking for.
That's one way of doing it is first and so with an index is quite straightforward and easy but the easier
and nicer syntax is.
This one from the second answer which is for a actor star an actor Ray block a block.
So let's go ahead and do that version.
So for and it's a moving platform star.
And I'm just going to call that variable platform.
Because it's one platform of many of the.
And let's go to the head of file to see what I call that variable platforms to trigger.
So and then my curly braces on a new line for the body of the for loop.
Now why is it complaining about platforms to trigger.
Well apparently it's because it can't find a conversion from a moving platform to a moving platform
star.
Okay so it looks like I was wrong in defining my t irena.
Hopefully you found that out in the challenge because we do need to have class a moving platform star
because it is an array of pointers.
And I was wrong.
It doesn't take pointers by default because you could for example have a t array of integers and it
wouldn't be an array of integer pointers.
So let's go over to the C++ again and now it's not complaining about that a more thank goodness.
So what we can do is platform.
Arrow and knows there's no members of our available reason for that is that I have not included the
head of file I've just done a forward declaration in my dot file.
So at the top we are going to go ahead and include that Im going to include local stuff underneath the
global stuff and leave a space between it so that we can clearly see what is being included from the
engine and what is being included from our own project.
So its going to be include and then it's just going to be the moving platform.
H.
Now hopefully that should mean that auto completes going to allow me to do the error operator to get
hold of the public methods to add active trigger Perfect's I've added the active trigger on Begin overlap
and I've got to do a very similar thing on end overlap I need to remove the active trigger song and
copy and paste the code from bit over overlap begin to overlap end and remove active trigger instead.
Okay.
That's looking hunky dory.
Now let's go and implement over in moving platform to h again.
I'm going to control k o in X code that short cut is a control command.
Up and down I believe.
Tell me whether you have any luck with that.
Okay so the thing we are going to do here is implement what was in the head of files.
I'm going to have a copy signatures from there.
Let's go ahead and copy both lines and we can do the various manipulations we need to do going to stick
them at the bomb at the file for now and copy the moving platform.
How long calon from take and add it to the beginning of both of these methods.
Remove the semicolon and add curly braces instead.
And that should be enough to convert them in two.
Declarations declarations the word I'm using.
I always get confused between declarations and definitions.
I think in this case we are defining them.
Yes because we.
A declaration is saying that I'm going to make it.
I declare that I will make this thing and a definition is here.
This is how it is made.
So that's how I like to remember the difference between declaration and definition.
In case you were asking you probably weren't asking.
So I'm going to move on now.
We're going to implement the add active trigger so this is basically just going to be incrementing that
variable that we created in the head of file.
Let me move the moving platform closer to its C++ file in my tab pane.
So we've got active triggers equal to one moment but it might be equal to something else if the designer
decides to change it in the property so we can simply use it's going to be a very easy one to implement
it's to be active triggers plus plus.
Simple.
Now removing active triggers is going to be slightly harder because we don't want to go negative.
In this case so we might say for example if active triggers.
Is Greater Than Zero.
Then will do.
Active triggers minus minus.
So we'll basically never go below zero which makes sense.
We have an absorbing barrier at the bottom is what you might be able to say.
If you are like me and like to use silly fancy words to describe things which are very simple like the
fact that it doesn't go below zero.
Okay so next up we have implemented that.
The only thing that's missing is making sure that the platform doesn't move when it is below zero.
That's fairly simple because all that logic goes on in tick and basically all of this logic we want
to activate.
So all I'm going to do is after we've called super tech I'm going to just deactivate this logic.
I'm just going to return early out of the tech.
So we're going to say if.
Actually.
Um had a second thought because we might add further things into tic and it would be really confusing
if we wanted to only deactivate this part of the logic and not some other part of the logic.
So I'm actually going to embed it all in the if statement so I'm going to say if active triggers is
greater than zero.
That's when we know that it is indeed active.
Then on a new line.
Stick my curly braces and I'm going to move everything including this has authority.
If statement inside that if statement.
So this will mean that only if we have active triggers.
Do we move.
Okay it's the moment of truth.
The final countdown.
Time to build and see whether the behaviour we want is the one that we are getting out in the game world.
And this is the perfect moment to sip your coffee.
I'm just having a nice aero press espresso that I made myself very velvety smooth.
K time for the moment of truth the build has finished.
Let's go ahead and see whether these platforms are still moving.
They are still moving.
That is at least one good sign.
Let's see if we can go and deactivate a platform by changing its default number of active platforms
of click on one of the platforms.
In fact this last platform that goes between the two high up locations.
That's the one that I don't want to be active by default so I'm going to go to its details pane and
find its active triggers and set its active triggers down to zero.
Now let's go ahead and hit play.
Sure enough that platform is no longer moving.
Which is exactly the behaviour I would expect.
So next up let's hook up the triggers to said platform and see one at a time whether they will make
it move first trigger.
Let's go ahead select the nearest one the first one that the characters are going to encounter and go
through his details pane looking for the relevant you property.
Here we go we've got a t array.
I can add to my T array and I can use the pick actor from scene button it's the one that looks like
a colour picker if you ever use colour.
Picking and editing programs they use this colour picone you can pick the platform from the scene it's
moving platform 6.
That's when it's going to activate.
So it's go ahead and play it from here near to the trigger.
It's not moving.
If I stand on the platform it starts moving.
I step off the platform it stops moving on off on off on off.
Now my mother would say I'm going to break that light switch if I keep stepping on and off it so I'm
going to stop.
Okay now let's try out the other trigga.
At present it should not work so I'm going to go and play from here from the other side.
Step on my platform and nothing happens.
Exactly what I would expect.
Let's click on that trigger.
Go to the details.
Pain.
Add a platform to trigger elements.
Select from scene and select that platform.
Go ahead and hit play.
I actually want to play from near that trigger.
Otherwise I'm gonna have a hard time getting that play from here.
Step on my trigger asar it's working.
It definitely working now.
Okay an on off on off seems to be working too.
Let's just check this.
Two things active.
Hypothesis of mine that I wanted to make sure that the trigger could activate multiple things.
Let's go over to the first trigger I set up and add another element.
And a pic from the scene and I'm going to pick just the second platform this time move platform 5 for
whatever reason I'm not sure why they're numbered like that.
Then I'm going to play from here.
That's active by default so it's not we're not going to see the results that's click on the platform
platform 5 for me and go to its details and try and find the property related to active triggers.
Zero.
Play.
Play from the right place near the trigger.
And neither of them are active.
I step on and they both activate on off on off on off.
Excellent.
So we've got Ad trigger working exactly as we'd like.
I just want to stick a platform fight back because that kind of breaks my puzzle at the moment.
So I'm going to go and set his default number of active triggers tell one and go to my trigger my pressure
pad and remove him from the T a race platform five.
I can remove the way I can do this is I think it's this dropped down here and it says delete next to
the platform five in the platform platform to trigger a.
Delete.
Let's go ahead and see whether this is actually playable.
Give it a little short.
Playtest and hopefully you've got somebody waiting to play Test with you soon so you can show them your
cool behaving triggers.
And the interesting puzzles that you can do with your triggers.
Okay so I'm now my second platform are coming over to the unseen area I hop across.
And I think ah ha I step on my pressure pad is moving.
It's moving on so I get on the block and I can't move anymore which is why you're going to need a second
player to play test this level with to get on with getting to your goal.
That's the whole idea here.
Now obviously I can play test this with increasing the number of players to go ahead and hit play.
Now there's two of us.
We can go ahead and get on our moving platforms both get up to that space which is what we try and do
with play a number to go and get on that moving platform again.
Will there be room for the two of us in a room in this world for the two of us.
K so plan number one it's going to go and try and get on to the second platform now.
Okay.
He's on the second platform making room for player number two who is here and is going to try and hop
onto the second platform and he's made it.
And now he's going to hop on to the other unseen area number one and unseen.
And both of them are now they're fantastic.
Now let's get on that platform gets on the platform.
But number two quickly quickly drives the jump and or just fell off.
But you can see how this is going to work.
It's moving player.
No one will get on the platform he's going to get on over to the other side and then get on the trigger.
So player number two can get across as well.
Okay.
That's the gist of the puzzle.
We've implemented the logic to make it happen.
Pat yourselves on the back.
Really well done.
And it's really time to make sure you have got someone to play test this with.
Go to your post spruce it up a little bit boast about it on discord and say yes I really have got a
cool level now got triggers.
You really want to come and play with me and hop on and play with other people get their feedback tweak
the level make it really cool.
That's the whole point of multiplayer.
It's collaborative experience and I'll see you in the next lecture where we're going to be talking about
making this more ready to share with your friends and family.
I will see you there.