Malcolm in this lecture we are going to be learning about the game instance class how we can create
our own custom subclasses and how we can basically have one class basically a singleton that goes between
all of our levels when we switch levels it's still there and it can create an overarching logic between
our levels.
Perfect for hosting servers and hosting clients right from within our game.
So let's dive in and see how that's done.
At this point we want to create an experience that we can share with our friends and family.
And unfortunately when you got to use the command line a lot of people are afraid of that.
So we need to build a system into our game to actually be able to join servers and to host servers.
Now the way we're going to do this in this section is via the console.
So let me just show you quickly what I mean by this.
When you hit play you've got the option with the key underneath the escape key it's often tilled on
a U.S. keyboard but on other keyboards can be different.
It is always the one underneath the escape key.
You get access to a console within the game.
And in this console you can type various commands and let's just see I just start typing some random
keys and it's got to play console key.
No idea what these commands are.
But we can create our own such commands to for example host a server and join a server.
So we're going to be doing that to make it just a little bit easier for you to share your game with
other people.
Create a executable share on the service like it or I know get people to download it play with you and
you can get very simple instructions on how to host and join a server.
So that's great.
We can see how this is going to pan out.
But first off where are we going to create and handle those commands.
Well to do that I'm going to tell you a little bit about a cool type of class which you probably not
come across before called a game instance.
Now a game instance as the name suggests is the core thing to your game.
It is always there when your game is active.
There aren't multiple games and says there's only one game instance and there is.
Basically one between all levels so it's perfect when your logic involves switching between levels such
as for example hosting a server or joining a server you're going to start off in a level such as maybe
an empty menu level or or not.
Or inside this game and you want to join in with somebody else that's perfect.
Perfect material for a game instance because it doesn't depend on a single level.
And that's what we're going to do we're going to create our own custom game instance because if you
go to our blueprint menu here I think you can see that there is.
Now these are game game modes but there are again instances running in the background it's kind of hard
to see there somewhere hidden away in the settings.
But let's have a look at how we can create a custom one of those game instances for your project.
It's quite simple.
Go over to the content browser go to add new and add new C++ classic only making a C plus plus game
instance here.
Now you can scroll through and see that we don't actually have any game instance classes here in these
default classes so we're gonna go ahead and show all and search for game instance and we want the first
one not the platform game instance.
Go ahead hit next and give it a sensible name.
I dont like the name my game instance I'm going to call it the puzzle platforms.
Game instance.
Like so.
And go ahead and create that class again I'm just going to leave it in the default.
Folder for now will find any structure if we need to find that structure.
So go ahead and compiling.
But there's nothing that's telling my game and telling unreel at the moment that this game instance
is the one that I want to use.
Now I have to let it compile to show you how we can change that in the settings.
But it's basically a project wide setting.
So that compiles completed I can go in to the settings go to the project settings here.
And I'm not going to go and try and find it.
I think I'm just going to go to this search and search for game instance and you see here we've got
a game instance property called The Game instance class.
So we can go to the drop down there and we can select our puzzle platforms game instance there and make
sure that we go ahead and save.
After that I think it's saved anyway.
But what we're going to see over in our project changes which I have over on my other screen I may drag
it across here.
Here we go.
So in my projects changes let's just have a look at this bit here.
You can see I've got changed to the read me.
That's right it's just telling me what we're seeing down here and some other changes we've got these
puzzle platform C++ and h file which is the game instance we just created chain minor changes to the
map.
Maybe but the default game engine.
Any has been changed.
As you can see to save the property that the game instance class is pointing to this particular script
of the puzzle platforms.
Interesting.
But that's how it works that's all these site settings are basically saved in these any files in your
project.
Okay.
So we can get rid of that window now.
So let's go ahead and open up that puzzle platforms game instance in Visual Studio which it has done
over here.
You can see it's pretty empty.
Nothing much going on in here let's go and have a look at the C++ file again nothing much going on.
So for starters I want us to see that we can indeed create or that this game instance is indeed being
used in our project to do that.
We can set off some log messages in that the constructor.
And that's something called the initialization function as well.
So let's have a look at the documentation for the game.
Kindly I have it here in the background.
The game you game instance and what we will see is we've got a constructor obviously but furthermore
not lots of other functions as well and you can take a little bit of time to go reading those.
But the function we're in interested in is called in it and this is the function here as it says virtual
function to allow custom game instances an opportunity to set up what it needs.
Okay so you might be wondering what's the difference between in it and a constructor.
At this point.
Well that's what you're going to find out in this chat.
In it or construct that is the question as Shakespeare once said I'm sure implement both methods the
init and construct methods using the documentation as your guide and remember the documentation is linked
from the resources.
Go and log out of both of them.
I don't mean log out in the sense of log out of your user but put log messages in both them so you can
distinguish which one is being called.
Then try starting the game in different ways by doing a play in editor window doing just a normal standalone
window doing a standalone game maybe launching the game without the editor.
And perhaps try restarting the editor as well and see what happens in all of these cases what log messages
get printed out and see what you notice and go and share what you notice and have a little bit of a
theory on a tising about the in it and construct methods.
Pause the video and have a go at that challenge.
Okay.
Welcome back.
I hope a chance gave you some time to get acquainted with the ins and outs of the game instance.
Now I'm going to go through and implement this change myself.
First let's go to the constructor and use this constructor from the documentation as a base for us to
use.
I'm going to go ahead and put it in the puzzle platforms game instance dot H at the top here.
And I think this is giving me a little warning about my ampersand here.
I wonder why.
I think probably because the game instance is the wrong name it should be the same name as my class.
So let's play pace that one instead.
That seems to have a better effect.
And I think I might just want to make sure that.
Don't think I need to put a virtual in front of constructor's.
I think it's just fight like that put a semicolon at the end and we aag it go.
Just going to make this a.
Wrong Sievert or public I think public.
What other classes to be able to construct us.
And then we want to implement it as well.
So let's go and find that in it in the documentation.
Here it is and find it signature.
It's a virtual void in it.
So I will implement it as such.
Virtual void in it.
We're the semakula at the end.
Now let's take those two signatures and go over into our C++ file and paste them in there.
Now we are going to do the implementation step so that you.
You puzzle platform game instance.
Come on come along at the beginning of both remove the virtual key word.
We don't need that in C++ files and then stick some curly braces after instead of a semicolon.
You know the drill by now.
So it's not complaining that is always a good sign.
Now I can't be bothered to type out my log message so I'm just going to see if any of my other files
have got logged messages left in.
Looks like I'm going to have to be bothered.
So it's eui underscore.
Log log temp at this point you probably getting quite used to this warning.
Text.
And then in the text we can put the lets see game instance construct.
If I can spell it correctly.
Put some can't be underlining that it doesn't need it and put it another one in be in it.
And call it in it.
And I just noticed that I'm missing my colon colon in the in it.
Doesn't the spying with confidence that the compiler is doing the right job things and put the Squidbillies
on that one.
That's right they and it's got constructer we've got log messages from both Let's go ahead and build
and see whether I did indeed use the documentation correctly.
Okay build complete.
Let's go over in to unreel and check out our output log height.
You'll notice that we have a game instance constructor has already been called but no in it I go and
look for in it in the logs you notice that there is no warning type but is in it.
In fact let's make this easier for us all by clicking on the filters of the output log and disabling
messages so that we just have errors and warnings and you can see now we've got the game instance construct
that has indeed been called if you dont get the game isn't constructer at this point then you may need
to restart your editor.
OK.
Let's go ahead and do a normal play.
So a play with this active level editor viewport and we can see that the constructor has been called
again and it has been called Hang on it's been done twice.
Why is that.
Because you get one for every game instance.
Hey look at this.
But we've got the player too.
And the player one and both of them get the game instance constructed and then initialised.
That's that's quite cool.
So we always get a construct of when we hit play but we also get a construct inside the editor just
when we are using the editor whereas in it only happens when we hit play that is the difference between
the two.
We can go ahead and see with a new editor window whether that same thing happens go back into our logs
and sure enough we've got two more constructs and in it.
So I'm pretty happy that that is what's going on.
Contri a standalone game as well but you might struggle to get the logs out of this one.
So the same effect as a standalone game would be to do it with the logs from the terminal.
So let's go ahead and open up a command prompt.
And let's see if we can get this working.
So I've just quit the standalone game and instead what I'm going do is go and copy the executable as
we've done many times before into the command prompt.
So those these I'm clearly not copying the right thing and select the executable again copy path and
go back and command prompt.
Paste it then select project you project copy path back into command prompt and paste it.
Now I'm going to do a dash game and dash log and we'll see whether in the log we are going to get the
game instance initializer.
See here comes the game.
Black screen signalling that something is happening here we are we're in the game.
Let's go over to our log and sure enough constructer and in it both called in the standalone game as
well.
So basically it always gets called but only when we're playing the game constructor called all times
even in the editor that is the summary.
So go ahead and put game instances in your game.
Are we seeing why they're useful in the following lectures.