Hey guys congratulations on getting to the end of the first section.
Great momentum and we hope you keep it up.
So what can they do with this first section now.
They've completed it.
Well one thing you need to bear in mind is that you've been using the unreal third person character
and that's got a whole load of magic in there that's doing things that you're going to learn about in
section 4 and beyond for you.
But what you could do in the bigger picture if you want a real revision of this game you have this material
other you create a whole new game.
I'd suggest using the third person and controller but you gain from scratch.
That's one possibility and go in show off to the community.
If you're going to make a game from scratch and you want to do a little bit of extra work well what
could they do.
Yeah a great way to just cement all this knowledge is to create some extensions to the game and we've
got students who are already doing that.
You can find the link in the resources to the student showcase over on the forum.
Go and have a look at that and see what other students are doing see if that inspires you to do something
new or to copy anything that they're doing.
It's no shame in copying.
Absolutely.
So basically it's up to you if you feel really comfortable with what you've learned.
Crack on to the next section if you want some revision you've got a couple of options modify the existing
game and make a whole new game but probably stick with the third person characters.
Otherwise you might come unstuck.
Exactly.
So great work well done for getting this far.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next section.