Hey guys and welcome to section two.
So firstly as the designer of this cause I wanted to explain why we're doing a whole section on you
why in a multiplayer court a couple of good reasons firstly we want to show you the very latest practices
for you why.
And secondly it's really important to have a strong foundation in UI before you move into the next section
where you going to be trying to connect to people over the Internet where you may not have a Skype chat
or a live chat going with you.
You need a lot of good quality real time feedback so you can be foundational to lobbying and connecting
in multiplayer games.
That's why this section is all about you.
So Sam what are we going to learn precisely so precisely you're going to be learning about how you can
create a C++ underpinning to your blueprint your eyes and how we can use C++ logic to drive things such
as submenus put text into your menus and trigger events from buttons and that's it.
By the end of it you'll have some nice looking simple but very functional UI and a great foundation
to move forward with.
So see you at the end of the section.