Welcome this lecture is all about getting hold of nuns C++ classes from within C++ entirely.
The whole premise of this is to be able to create a main menu which we're going to be doing in later
lectures.
But first of all to do that we need to get hold of a reference to the blueprint class from within C++
and what you can see here in this log method it doesn't look particularly exciting but this log message
comes entirely from C++ and it's telling us the name of the class that is found the w.p. main menu underscored.
Now that is quite cool.
And we're going to find out how we can do that and are was going to learn about the UMG module and how
to include extra modules in C++.
So let's dive in and dig into some of this exciting stuff.
So ideally we'd be able to create and launch our menu entirely from within C++ so we don't have to rely
on blueprints in order to do this and create most of our logic in C++ which is what we do.
However the first step to this will be to actually be able to get hold of that blueprint class so that
we can create an instance of it.
Now to get hold of a blueprint class isn't as easy as a C++ class with a C plus plus class it's quite
easy you just do an include and then you've got the class but with a blueprint What do we have to do.
Well we have to actually use string reference it and get hold of the class a different way using something
called an F Class.
A find is a helper class that allows you to find the blueprint class by a string reference to it.
Now you've probably seen some of these before.
You can go and have a look at the documentation I dont find the documentation particularly useful for
this class not off the bat like this it's quite hard to reason about.
So often when you find documentation that's a bit terse and a bit hard to use I like to resort to looking
through the engine code for examples of its use.
So let's start off with that.
Im going to I mean my project Im going to just search through the project actually first before I look
through the entire solution and just look for instances or uses of the S class finder class.
So let's go ahead and find that and sure enough there is an example in the puzzle platform game modot
Copy.
So let's take a look at that.
Okay.
So that's quite a lot going on in one line.
Let's break it down and kind of read it from the middle out as you do with these C++ declarations so
we can see that it is a player pawn BP class variable that we're creating here and we can see that it
is type F Class finder.
With the parameter or the template parameter a pawn.
So it's an F Class finder of a pawn.
And then we are constructing it using this text macros just basically just the way of creating an F
string.
And we are passing it an F string of the.
The location of the third person character.
So in summary and finally just one more thing is it that it's static which means that this variable
exists only once in the program not once.
For every instance of the game mode but just once full stop every game mode will share the same F Class
finder because it doesn't matter.
We're always going to say find the same class every single time because there is only one third person
character asset.
That's just a bit of an obscene zation it's not to my zation which I don't particularly care about so
we're not going to be using that one I think it complicates reading this line.
So basically what we've done is we've constructed and play a BP play a pawn BP Classic which is a variable
that helps us find a blueprint class or a class that is a subclass of a pawn in our asset folder.
Then with this variable we can go ahead and access it's class property which is actually the pointer
to that class object that we can then later use to instantiate and so on and we can do things like get
its name get its name.
So let's see if we can try and apply the use of the F Class finder to a class of our own.
Let's go over to the unreel editor and hop into our content browser and go up to the top of content
and then navigate down into puzzle platforms and we'll notice that there is a BP straight away called
BP platform trigger which we have created in the last section.
So I'd like to go ahead and get a reference to that class and log out it's name so let's see how that
would be done how to find the BP platform trigger.
So let's go ahead and copy everything from the game mode C P P from after static until the end of that
first line.
Or semicolon.
And I'm going to go in to my game instance because this is I think is the logical place to be spawning
and creating new eyes so that's where we're going to start and the F Class Finder has to be done inside
the constructor you can tell because well it's a subclass it's in the name space construct help helpers
so that's kind of an indication that it has to be done within the construct.
And if you do elsewhere it will give you errors.
So I'm going to replace that log that we have in our construct in fact no longer a just the X. I'm going
to want to use the log later so Im going to paste in what I just copied and youll see there are a couple
of errors off the bat.
First off squiggly under construct to help us.
The reason for that is I dont have the right include.
Lets go back into the s.p. Files simple and find the right include.
Can you see the right include.
Well online 5 there is the e.u. object construct to help us that's the one.
Everything else there is from the project so it wouldn't make sense to go back to the game and see people
and I'm going to paste it underneath my engine.
I'm keeping the engine in close together vs. the project includes which are on a site separated by a
blank line.
So I've got my construct to help.
Now there's no squiggly.
It's finding an a pawn.
So what time do I want to find.
Not a pawn.
What I want to find is a platform trigger.
Now obviously that's not included yet so let's go ahead and include B.
Platform.
Trigger.
Dot H like so.
And that means that now I have access to an a platform trigger.
So we're saying that we're trying to find a class that is a subclass of the a platform trigger.
Now let's rename the class finder.
I'm going to call it platform trigger BP class.
Okay.
And then we're going to want to put in the right text reference to this BP class.
Let's go back over and with our content browser in the B class selected let's write quick and copy reference.
Back into visual studio.
We can paste that reference in place of this text but we will need to remove a few bits.
Basically everything from the blueprint to the single quote is going to be removed and everything from
the dot at the end to the single quote is going to be removed so that we just end up with a forward
slash game forwards that puzzle platform towards that BP platform trigger fairly straightforward.
Okay so we've got hold of our BP platform trigger class hopefully all we need to do is do a null check
of the class in case we didn't actually find the class at all.
We can do this with.
I've got my no read macro which will fill out so Im going to do a platform.
Trigga BP class.
Daughter class.
Because its the dot class property which returns us the actual class that it found.
And so that's going to return early if and trigger an error.
If we've got null in that class which means that now it's safe to use that class to get hold of the
name which is why I wanted to in the log message so I'm going to say found class in this log message.
Percent s.
And then at the end we give an extra argument for the class which is going to be platform trigger BP
class declasse class which I copied.
Arrow.
Operator because it's a pointer that we get returned and we can do get name which is getting the name
of the class.
Basically it's a pointer to a class object which we can later use to instantiate other objects create
some object and things like that.
But we can also do some things on that class object itself such as get the name of the class that we've
found.
And finally we're gonna have to put a star in front of all of that argument because we want to get the
in a string as we always do with log messages.
Let's go ahead and build and see whether we've successfully got hold of the class by seeing whether
it prints out the right class name.
So my builder has succeeded.
Let's go over into one real and just take a look at the logs straight away because it's in the construct.
So it's running straight away in without even having to play.
You'll notice that we found a class and it's the BP platform trigger.
See.
Fantastic.
So it's found the right class and it's found its name and we've done all of that entirely in C++ So
that's great great news.
Now there is going to be one more hurdle in the road when trying to access the widget we go and have
a look at our widget go up to the content browser to the root of content down to the menu system and
select the WP main menu and hover over it.
You'll see that it has a native parent class of you mge you don't use a widget.
Now the problem is the UMG module isn't by default accessible in C++.
Now going to give you a challenge in a minute to try getting hold of the UMG use a widget without actually
doing these following steps.
But first of all we're going to have to do is include the UMG module.
So let's go into visual studio and we're going to open a very special file in our project which will
probably haven't touched before you haven't touched before which is the puzzle platforms stop builder.
So yes this is the build configuration for a project that's fairly straightforward here.
But one of the key things here is online 11 for me the public dependency module names and this is a
list of modules in the unreal engine that our product depends on.
You can see it depends on core depends on core you object.
It depends on engine.
It depends on input core and head mounted display.
Now a head mounted display is there because the default third person project is VR enabled.
We're not going to remove any of that code just yet so let's leave the head mounted display as it is
but an extra module we have to add in here at the end so comma open quote is it you.
M G.
The unreel graphics library so we're going to close quotes there and that should update our build configuration.
Now to properly update our build configuration and get the right auto complete.
We closed down our project.
We need to go over to Explorer or find a right click on a new project and regenerate the visual studio
project file which is under services for Mac users.
Once we regenerate the project files then auto complete and Visual Studio will be able to work a lot
better.
So let's open up the solution once more.
And the final step once we have opened up visual studio is going to be having to include the user widget
class.
Now this has a bit of an interesting includes.
Let's go to the game instance key.
Some reason it's asking me about line endings.
I'm just going to say yes and then we are going to include the following class.
In fact let's have a little look through the documentation for you with it.
If you google for user widget you'll find that the unreal documentation that the class actually called
you use a widget So that's what we've found here.
And if I go ahead and scroll down to the bottom and then we will see that we're actually looking for
this header runtime you injury public blueprint.
Use a widget and we can just go ahead and select blueprint use a widget.
H That is the Include that we need.
Let's go back into visual studio.
You can try doing it without the include unfortunately visual studio auto complete will mislead you
and think that you use a widget is a class that's available.
It's not unless you do include this include and you'll get some errors later down the line.
But that's okay you can always try via error first and see whether that works out.
So let's go back in to the Include and include our blueprint.
Use a widget.
This now means that our class finder could take for example a user widget and it wouldn't complain and
it wouldn't give us build errors at the end.
But that is for you to do.
In your upcoming challenge to save our menu class.
So to say the menu class what is the challenge going to be to create a menu menu class field a private
variable on the class called menu class.
You are going to have to find out how to use their class finder to save to it to get the string reference
to add W. BP blueprint class and save the class that we find into the menu class field.
You have to find out what type the menu class field should be.
You can use the F Class find a documentation to do that.
And I want you to log out the name that you found into it and as a bonus I would like you to try building
without the u m g module included.
Just so you can get a sense of what sort of error you get when you don't have the module dependencies
because it's quite different to an include error.
And I'd like you to see what that actually looks like so pause a video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive right in with the challenge so I'm going to be searching for the user widget class as we
have intimated already.
We don't change the class find a name to be Instead the menu menu BP clas and I am going to save that
to a private variable which I am about to create.
So let's go to the game.
Instance does H create a private section in the head a file.
And it's going to be a menu class variable but what's its type going to be.
Well you can find that out by looking at the documentation for F Class finder.
As I already said and in F Class finder we have a variable called class which is what we've been using
up till now.
You click on that and you can see that the type of this is actually t subclass of and then t being the
type that we have given as the parameter to an F Class so in our case if you use a widget so we can
use that in game instance dot H we can do a T subclass of.
And then have that.
Brackets there and it's going to be a user widget but beware.
We'll probably get some bill there as if we try and build it like this because we haven't gone.
Include for user which at this point I'm going to forward declare it by putting class in front of its
own class you use a widget will go back in to Game instance.
Got to be PE menu class I'm going to copy that in to the null check going to remove the logging.
At this stage because we don't want to do it there want to do it in in it.
And then what I want to save to my menu class so it's going to be menu class.
He calls it's going to be menu BP class Doc class to get hold of that t subclass object.
In fact subclass is just something like a function.
But four types.
So what it does is it takes that you use a widget and says that this can be a type anything that that
is a subclass of use a widget.
Okay so now we've got hold of our menu class we can go ahead and edit the log in in it.
I'm going to have it say something like found class.
Percent S.
And then give it the argument of star menu class.
Arrow operator.
And then it's going to be let's see.
Get a name.
Not get archetype get a name like autocomplete being overzealous there.
And let's go ahead and build and see whether that works out for us.
Hurray build success.
Let's go over in that one real editor have a look at the logs.
So it here will notice that there is an error.
It's saying I failed to find the class because you're asking for basically something else you asking
for a subclass that is not a subclass of you use a widget or you've given me a class that is not a subclass
of you use Widget.
Indeed that's because we forgot to update text reference so if we right click on the user widget in
the content browser and then copy its reference then go back in to puzzle platforms and update this
text reference to our platform trigger.
Many of you probably spotted that I was going to make that mistake remove the Gump around it to make
it look just like it was before so it's.
GAME was left many system forwards lashed w.p. main menu and let's go ahead and build that slight change
shouldn't take very long.
Just a string the change.
Now.
Okay and let's go ahead and try that out.
Go back into an output log and hopefully this time we shan't have any errors.
So I think those errors were from before so I've gone ahead and cleared the logs.
So let's go ahead and hit play.
And sure enough we've got found class w w b main menu dasch underscores c so that as successfully found
the correct class and kept it all the way from constructer until in it so we've shown that we can then
use it later on to actually construct and create and set up this main menu so I'm really excited about
that.
That's quite cool though we've done all that within C++ without having to expose anything within blue
print at all.
In fact so very very cool.
Now I'm going to leave the last bit of the challenge.
The part about trying to build without you energy up to you because we're running out of time and we
don't want to make this lecture too long.
But you can definitely try taking out your energy from the module list and try rebuilding.
See what error you get and just remember that error because if you ever need to use something that is
in a different module and you forgot to include the module it's important to recognize what that error
looks like.
Okay patch cells on the back.
We've managed to find the menu class from entirely within C plus plus using the class binders.
Great stuff and I'll see you in the next lecture.