Welcome.
This lecture is all about getting our first to bottom to work the host button.
Now when I click on it you'll be able to see that I have been able to host my game and I'm now there
in my game having hosted it.
Now we're not just going to do this the simple way we're going to actually make it so that our menu
system stays as a completely separate plugin to do this we're going to learn about subjects such as
dependency injection dependency inversion and interfaces.
So stay tuned for that and let's find out how this works.
So we've got ourselves a lovely menu system but totally non functional at the moment the buttons don't
do the host unjoin functions that we have written into our command line in the game instance.
So to do this we would need to be able to make a call from our main menu to the game instance which
is simple enough except that we had said that we wanted our main menu to be a plugin that we could use
in later gettings if we made a call to that game instance and then we are going to ruin that because
the game instance in different games might be different.
It might be a different class entirely and so we would have to change our plug in the menu system every
single time.
Not ideal So let's have a little bit of talk about our dependencies in this setup.
So I want to be talking a little bit about something called inverting dependencies but let's do the
pre framing to that first so we've got our game on the left in yellow.
Our menu system on the right in green and at the moment what we want to achieve is to have all our dependencies
go in this direction from left to right from the game to the menu system.
This means that if we want to take our menu system and place it in a different game then all we've got
to do is change the game to integrate an new menu system.
We don't have to rewrite the menu system or change any code in that menu system it stands alone as a
plugin.
So it just slots in to the space pointed at by this arrow and the game has to integrate around it.
Now this is called a compile time dependency.
That's because without changing any code we can do a recompilation and it'll all work.
Now there is another type of dependency the runtime dependency and this does go both ways.
The reason for that is the menu system has got buttons that we want to activate some gameplay functionality
in the game and vice versa we want the game to be able to launch our menu system so at runtime the dependencies
and the calls go both ways.
And that is important to remember.
You can have a compile time dependency that goes one way and the runtime dependency goes the other.
And we're going to talk about how that's done through a method called in in inversion of dependencies.
So let's see how it currently stands or how we would naively think about implementing this dependency
between game instance and Main Menu for our bottom call-backs.
We would start off by saying okay well let's include the game instance that is a compile time dependency
because it then gets compiled in and then we've got a cause dependency which is at runtime so at runtime
the main menu needs the game is then so be there and at compile time the main menu needs the game instance
to be there.
We want to do is remove that second one where we're saying that the comp at compile time the game insys
needs to be there because it might not be if we move it into a different game.
It might be a different game instance and we don't want to have to change our code.
So let's do something that does make it so that we can invert that dependency so that it looks like
the dependency in the first diagram where the compile time dependency only goes from game to menu system.
To do that we are going to introduce a new concept called an interface.
Now the interface is very much like a class except that you dont actually make any objects out of that
interface you just use it for inheritance.
Now what you do is you say to the main menu okay.
Im going to include and use this interface.
The interface being part of the menu system not part of the game so it's all within that green block.
So it includes and uses methods on the interface the interface has various methods that we're allowed
to call and the game instance includes But implements rather than uses the interface.
So it inherits from it and says okay if there's a host method on the interface then I'm going to have
a host method too and I'm going to implement that host method.
Then what happens at run time is that the main menu is told that the thing implementing its interface
is the game instance and it can make its calls through the interface that was defined at compile time
to the thing that was defined at runtime which is the actual game instance.
So that's how it works.
That's the idea of in it dependency inversion that we've got.
Often a dotted line that is the implements line the solid white line which is the user's line and then
the call actually goes forward along the solid line backwards along the dotted line at inversion of
dependency.
Fair enough.
Let's see how that actually all hangs together in unreel.
The first concept we need to be able to use is an interface in unreel how do we create such an interface
that real.
Let's go to the content browser.
Go to add new new C++ class as that is what were going to be creating it as.
And were going to go and look for the C++ class down at the bottom of the list called Unreal interface.
That's a special type of interfaces you'll see from the generator code very soon.
Let's go ahead to next and we can cause anything we like.
But the important thing is I want to put it in our menu system subfolder so that it is part of that
green box and if we want to rip it out we can rip it out very easily.
So here we are.
It's the menu system some poulder and I'm going to call it the menu interface very straightforwardly
and go ahead and create that class and wait for it to compile.
Okay that's a compile complete and we can now see our menu interface is in the menu system subfolder
And if we go over to a visual studio we should be able to see our see Plus pass and head a file for
the menu interface.
So if we go to the menu interface dot H then you'll see something rather odd.
Let me make a bit of room on the screen so that you can see what Im see here we've actually got two
classes.
Okay so we've just gone and create it one place and it's given us two for the price of one.
What's actually going on here.
That first class is called You menu interface and it inherits from you interface.
Now the second class is not inheriting from anything and it's called menu interface.
Now if you read the comments you can see that it's saying that the first class does not need to be modified
then that the second one is where we add the interface functions.
Now why is there that first class of we're not meant to modify it.
The whole idea here is that um real cant know about an interface unless it inherits from something that
is a you object.
And unfortunately we dont want to inherit multiple multiple you object.
So what would happen is if we inherited from our game instance at the you menu interface then it would
both be a you game instance and a you menu interface which is just a bit weird in terms of an Real's
inheritance system.
So what we do instead is we would inherit the inherit from a menu interface and the menu interface has
no parents.
So we dont end up with this tricky so called Diamond inheritance problem where multiple things could
end up having the same parent class and that can end up with all sorts of tricky reasons if you want
to know more about it go and look up what Diamond inheritance is.
So how do we actually use this interface.
Well you go ahead and add virtual functions into the public section of the menu interface that you want
to be able to call from the menu and to have implemented on the game instance.
So its very straightforward.
We want a method like host.
So I would go for it host and then no arguments and semicolon at the end because I want it to be implemented
by the game instance.
Im going to make sure that it is virtual.
Like so let's go ahead and build and see how that looks.
Hopefully like me you have got some errors here lets go and have a look at the proper output log rather
than the error list to see what those errors are actually talking about.
So here among lots of gunfire you can see that there is some errors about unresolved external symbols
for the menu interface.
HOST Okay well that makes sense.
What were what its saying is that theres no implementation for this virtual host function.
Usually we go into the C++ file and we'd implement host but not here because we don't actually want
our interface to have the implementation the intimate implementation should be the implementation on
game instance.
So what's going wrong here why is it expecting one.
Well because by default C++ always expects to find an implementation for a function despite even a virtual
function it expects there to be an implementation.
Now if you don't want it to be having an intimate implementation then you need something called a pure
virtual function.
That means that it doesn't have an implementation and expect the class below it.
The class that inherits from it to implement that function.
That's what we want.
We want to expect our game instance to implement that function to do that.
We are going to have it equal 0.
So use a virtual void host equals zero and you can think of that as saying this has an empty implementation.
Okay so thats what were going to do on this side now.
How are we going to make use of our on a menu interface.
Well lets go on over to our menu C++.
Votes should be in here somewhere in a game puzzle platforms source and puzzle platforms again and the
menu system we've got our main menu.
Dot H and or c p p.
So what I want to do is have our main menu have a pointer to an interface and that can just be in the
private So I am going to include at the top.
But before generated because generated always wants to be the last thing we're going to do and include
for our menu interface.
H.
Which means that now we can use the eye menu interface.
Star.
For the Basically we call this the menu interface.
Early straightforward.
This is a point that we're going to fill in later that points to our menu interface something we don't
know what yet.
It could be a puzzle platform game instance it could be a testing ground game instance it could be any
game instance for the game of your choice.
And then we're going to go into it Main Menu dot s.p. and we're going to make use of that.
So currently we've got our host server function which is just returning a log message instead of that
we should check that it's not null first of all because we might not set up menu interface.
I'm going to check if menu interface.
Is not now.
Well not equal to null pointer.
Then that is when we are going to be able to use it and say that the menu interface.
Our show host so call host on that menu interface.
Now what are my errors about so many interfaces undefined.
Let's go back to the head of file doesn't seem undefined from here.
So let's just go ahead and build it might just not have caught up yet.
Sure enough it compiles successfully so we know that the issue is just an auto complete one for that
we know that a good solution is to go and regenerate the visual studio pretty fast.
I'm going to right click on the new project and generate visual studio project files that should help
me out with the autocomplete.
Okay.
Well let's head back in.
So that's how we use the interface now.
Oh yeah.
Let's reload the solution hopefully now it's going to give us less grief.
Yeah sure enough.
Now it's not giving us anything about our.
Giving us no errors and hopefully the auto complete would work as well as check that out.
Menu interface error host.
Maybe it's just not caught up yet.
It's not doing a little squiggles yet so that's what it should be anyway.
We don't need to do anything with the P file just yet so we're going to leave that closed.
The final piece of the puzzle is to make sure that the puzzle platforms game instance does indeed implement
our online menu interface so that we can set an instance of the puzzle platform game instance to the
pointer menu interface.
This point here in our main menu DCP the way we do this is really simple you just go over to puzzle
platform game instance and we include at the top of the head of file our menu system so it's going to
be in hash include.
Men use this term.
Forward slash menu interface.
H.
And then what we can do is where we are currently inheriting from you game instance so public you game
instance on public you game instance.
We can also inherit from that interface by putting a comma and then public again.
And then I menu interface should also complete for me.
Okay.
And what that's saying is I have all the methods in the menu interface and you can rely on me to implement
them which then means that we can use it as a pointer of type you platform game instance.
We could use it as a pointer of type you game instance but we can now also use that as a pointer of
a menu interface which means that we can use it in our main menu dotsie P P.
So it's time to try and inject the dependency.
By that I mean at run time making sure that our main menu DCP is getting an instance of the you puzzle
game you puzzle platform game instance.
Now that's going to be your challenge to inject the menu interface pointer.
You're going to set the menu interface.
Remember about best practices around setting and whether you should be setting pointers and properties
directly on classes.
Then ask yourself what happens if the interface isn't fully implemented.
And finally test that hosting works when you've got everything set up including the end dependency injection
pause video and have a go.
So because this video is already going on for 15 minutes long we're going to put the challenge into
the next video to give you a bit of a breather.
If you wanted to see the solution afterwards but no pausing required here.
Just go on to the next video when you're ready.