Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be doing some stuff with the many that makes it look nicer.
As you can see here we've added some darkness to the background which just makes a lot little bit easier
to read in a centre.
The buttons a bit but beyond this beyond adding some styling hints what we've done is actually add in
something called a menu switcher which is going to allow us to switch between a main menu this one house
and join buttons and this join game menu which when clicking the join button will allow you to enter
an IP address and then join a game which will basically allow us to do this second command that we had
implemented in the last section of joining a remote IP address game.
So let's dive in and see how we can do this.
So the next part the stop on our journey of the quest of the main menu isn't to get and join.
Ben button working now and join button isn't good and easy like the host button because it actually
required a parameter.
Remember that join requires the address that we want to actually be joining.
So to actually achieve that we need a more menu we need a sub menu here.
Now to do this we could create a whole new widget and pull it out and replace it from the game instance
that would be quite heavy weight however and would mean that then the game instance is too involved
in the UI.
We want to remember keep this all inside our UI module and one way that we can easily do this is with
a clever little widget called a widget switcher.
Now lets have a look at what widgets which is are and how they work.
You can go and look for a widgets which are in your pallet so it will be called widget switches so you
can just look for.
Things i already puts it up as the first element in there anyway.
And what we can do is we can use it to wrap any of the things in our hierarchy and replace them with
another widget So lets have a look at our hierarchy.
I personally would want to keep my background and I wont wont probably want to keep my vertical box
so the vertical box and the size box I want that to be specifier ball in my submenus for example.
So one cannot do them going to right click on my top level vertical box underneath the overlay and right
click and go to replace with an Im going to replace it with a widget switcher.
And there we go.
Weve got the widgets which are set up obviously at the moment it is taking up all the space in the overlay.
But the and rather the size boxes.
But if I click on my size box and stick it to be horizontally aligned to the centre and vertically aligned
to the centre then we're back where we started with our widgets whicher.
And the size box actually that has kind of replaced out the vertical box.
That's okay as well.
Okay.
So we've got our size box and our widgets which are out now let's illustrate how these actually work
by trying to replace our main menu with some text.
So I'm going to look in the palette for a text item the text widget.
I'm going to bring the text widget in and dump it on the widget switcher.
Now what you'll notice is if I select the text block then the size box and everything underneath it.
The main menu disappear by select the size box then vice versa happens.
But that's not very helpful because if I go and hit play then we're still going to be seeing our main
menu at least.
We will be if I am in the right map so let's make sure I open up the right main menu map.
There's many maps.
Now if I go and play.
And then let's have a look.
Let's open this up in a separate window.
Then we still got our main menu as the central components.
So it hasn't changed anything so what's actually going on.
Well if you go ahead and select the widgets which you'll notice that in the details there is a property
under switcher called active widget index.
And if I change this from zero to 1 then it's going to select my text block instead as the active widget.
And if we go ahead and hit play then indeed the only thing visible is the text block so we can use this
to create ourselves a special join menu.
And let's go ahead and do that right now.
Let's go ahead and create a join menu so I can remove my text block as a starting point.
And how do I want my Join menu to work.
Well I am going to have a text field and I'm going to have a join button so I'm going to need at least
a vertical box to hold all that in.
So let's start off with that vertical box.
I like building things from the bottom up rather than from the top down.
So we've got a vertical box in my vertical box.
I am going to throw a text box which is the text input thing.
The editable text box that goes in my vertical box.
Then what else goes my vertical box.
I'm going to have a button now for buttons.
I'm going to go ahead and copy the buttons from our main menu to keep that whole thing consistent.
So let's grab that.
Copy it and go in to my vertical box and paste it in there.
Now obviously this is looking super ugly.
So let's start off with our button.
We want the button to not be trying to fill the horizontal line but rather be using its own width for
that.
So that helps.
Next up we want add a civil text box to whom.
Maybe use feel size no auto size was just fine but we do want it to have some height of its own.
I'll try to add in some hint text see if that helps.
So I want to say IP address.
For the hint text of the editable text box and I'm going to go ahead and increase the font size that
might be the other issue.
So you go to style and then font and then size and we can scroll the font up.
Yep sure enough it was the font size that was causing as an issue.
Now go ahead and play.
We can see that we've got our IP address we've got our host button and it's all looking fabulously ugly
at the moment but it is sort of functional and we're going to make it pretty and that's going to be
the challenge to make it pretty.
But the important thing is that this has now is entirely controlled.
Which one is active by the widgets which I change the index in the widgets which are I can switch over
to my Join menu even though it's not very obvious that the join menu just yet.
So I'm going go and be really lazy and leave the whole job of styling up to you.
Well I'm not being lazy because I'm going to be doing it myself in the chosen solution.
So here is your challenge outline the menus with style.
We are going to style the text box that is one ugly looking text box at the moment if we go back to
our vertical box for that menu and you can see that the IP address menu looks absolutely awful.
So you're going to do something about that then you are going to improve the layouts again.
The got very awful boring lay out at the moment ensure everything is legible and I would like to add
a heading so that we know where we are when we're inside a menu now because the solution again requires
quite a lot clicking.
It's about 10 minutes long so I'm going to be putting that in the next video.
So when you're done with the challenge go ahead and watch the solution video.
Coming up next.