Hello and welcome to another exciting episode.
So here we are with our Big Game.
And if we bring up our in-game menu now what happens is I can cancel that menu and I can also use it
to quit.
Back to the main menu.
And if we're in a multiplayer scenario and you are joining a server that will make you leave the server.
So we are going to be doing this in fact you're going to be doing this again.
Another challenge lecture.
So let's dive in and see how it goes.
So let's take a look at the problem.
We're going to go to our first of all get our map in the third person cvp Maps third person example
map load that one up and hit play so that we can get an in game menu.
I'm going to hit em get my in-game menu.
And obviously the problem here is the cancell and quick but buttons are not working at all well.
Easily enough.
You guys know how to actually fix this.
So I'm going to make this whole challenge this whole lecture challenge.
And this was to create cancell and quit to create the behaviours for both of these.
So it's quite simple.
You're going to create a function in the game instance that will handle what is need.
What needs to be handled.
Your update the interface to talk to that you'll then implement cancel which may not need a function
in the game instance at all.
Think about that and implement the quit to main menu so I'm using quick to mean go up to the main menu
where you can then choose a quick option that'll be the subject the next lecture.
But in this one just going back to the main menu will do so.
Pause the video and have a go at this.
Okay welcome back.
So we've had to quiz challenge videos back to back.
I hope that's okay.
Let me know what you think of that.
And we're going to dive right in and start implementing this.
First of all with hooking up that cancel button So let's dive in to visual studio as a first port of
call.
And what we're going to be doing is going to be adding in a button to the in-game menu.
H.
So as a starting point I'm going to be using the menu that we already have which is our menu widget
dot H and in the menu widget actually sorry not the menu widget but the main menu or agent or s.p. we're
the ones who want to use not the menu widgets are going to close down the many widget to avoid confusion.
And in the head a file we have a bunch of private properties which are binding to you buttons.
So I'm going to take one of those including the private label and put it in our header file for the
in-game menu.
H Okay.
And we're going to has changed the name because our button is called something else let's go and see
what our bundes call go to us real go into our menu system folder.
The main the.
You what's it called w.p. in game any.
That's the one I open up that widget and take a look in the hierarchy and see what I cancel buttons
called Funnily enough it's called cancel button you'd never have guessed it.
So we're going to change the name of the property to cancel button so binds properly and we can actually
go ahead and compile that right away so that it we've got a head start on getting that comp. and checking
that all works out.
The next thing we have to do is bind that cancel button.
So for that we need an initialised method.
If we go into our many do h.
We have got a protected method that we called initialised because we might want to override it in subclasses
but we definitely do not want it being called from the outside.
So that's why I'm going to put in my ingame many are age as well.
And let's have a look at the see hoopy for how that was implemented.
I remember it being a little bit tricky for how it was implemented.
It's obviously not compiling now that I've added in that initialise signature.
So we have something a little bit interesting going on here.
It's calling the super initialised but it's super initialised can return success or not.
So were returning early if super fail to initialize.
Fair enough.
I'm going to copy all of that into in-game menu.
Scott C. P. P..
Like so.
And I'm going to change my name spacing so the namespace should be you in-game menu.
Let's change that out.
Now Super will work just fine I'm going to close off the brackets and I'm going to make sure that the
end of our method we have a return equals true because otherwise we won't be returning after having
successfully set it up.
So next up we want to do the binding again binding we've done before in Maine many CPS hunger.
Take those as templates.
Take one of these lines that does our insurer of the button and then doesn't click had dynamic take
one of those lines paste it into the ingame NAACP and change out the button name.
So I'm going to take cancel button as the name and replace it both in the insurer statement and the
on click statement like so.
And now we just have to point it at a function that we want to call.
Now what is it that we want the cancel button to do.
Essentially we want it to tear down the menu.
For that we don't have to call out to the game instance we've got a tear down method implemented in
the superclass here so you might be tempted to go ahead and just put it in something like you in-game
menu.
Ted how.
And that seems sensible at first glance but it isn't going to work and the reason it's not going to
work is that tear down is not a you function.
So in order to fix this we can even make 10 hour you function then particularly fancy that shouldn't
really be a function.
However the other thing we can do is create a function here on the ingame many that then cause a tear
down.
So I'm going to do the latter option.
Going to go ahead and create a new function.
With a void return type called cancel.
Or cancel pressed and it's going to take no arguments.
And that should do it for the signature.
Let's take that signature and implement it in C++.
Put namespace.
But a body.
And then Amy here we can call.
Tear down to our hearts content.
Okay.
And that means that now we want to use this cancell pressed as our call-back for the cancel button.
Hopefully that will work.
Let's go ahead and I see squiggly line actually before I compile that says the cancel button isn't working.
That's because an incomplete type because we need to include the head a file for the button the head
file for the button is in our main menu see if pupae which is include components for Flash button or
H that bring that over as well.
And there we go.
Hopefully that will bring get rid of all our warnings.
Let's go and Bill and see whether that's making our cancel button work now.
Okay so our field has succeeded.
Let's go back in to unreal.
Let's hit play in our game get our menu up.
Hit cancel.
And sure enough it turns itself down we get to carry on playing.
Here I am again I kept cancel and I can just pause.
This is not pausing the many of the game.
The game keeps running while the menu is up but I am able to cancel that menu and carry on from where
I was before which is much much better.
Okay so next up we wanted to do something for that quick button as well.
So let's head back into visual studio.
We what we want to do is now add in a click a quick button which would be very easy.
We can now just copy the.
Not that you function but our cancel button.
Binding.
And I really wish something could be done about this visual studio indent stuff.
It really is very annoying.
Okay so we're going to bind a quick button and then with this quick button we're going to need to call
out to something.
So I'm going to create a new function right away.
For quick pressed Boyd quit Prest.
Mike so and then with quick press we are gonna need to obviously implement it too.
So we're going to take that over and see.
Plus plast and paste in our name space.
And put in a body.
Okay.
So it will worry about how to implement it in just a second.
First off I'm going to add the binding to the quick button.
So take a quick Button's name so I don't miss type it and replace it in the Ensure and in the binding
line itself and change the method that we're binding to.
To be quick Prest.
Okay.
Now that's pretty much good except now we actually need to call something.
So what are we going to need to call.
Well is going to have to be our game instance because the game instances the thing that knows how to
travel to a different level it knows how to go back to the main menu.
So what we're going to need is something in the interface in a menu interface or h.
Let's open that up.
That allows us to go back to Main Menu.
So I'm going to create it as a virtual void load main menu.
Mike so it's not going to take anything and it's going to be pure virtual with a zero.
Now hopefully this means that when we go over to our game instance which implements our menu interface
we should be getting some errors from the game.
Essence in fact let's go ahead and build and see whether we get pay.
Again error.
So sure enough if I now get to my output log and have a look at the error that is showing up here it
says that it cannot instantiate the abstract class game instance which is abstract due to load main
menu being abstract basically meaning that we haven't implemented lone main menu so we can go ahead
and do that fairly easily.
I'm just going to copy the signature again from our menu interface dot H and we're going go over to
puzzle platforms game in Sterns and we're going to stick it in there.
So where am I going to put it.
It's not going to be public I think.
And it is an is it going to be private.
Yes I think it's got to be private.
Because now let's think about this.
Why is it private.
Because what I don't want to happen is for someone to grab hold of a game instance and use the lomo
menu or do I maybe I do maybe that's okay actually.
So let's put it in public.
And we will implement a load main menu.
It's okay for it to be virtual.
It's okay for it to be void it's not okay for it to be abstract.
And I want to make sure that I am correctly overriding song and put the override key word there as well.
Now that's something that could be said for some of the other functions in the menu interface door as
well in both host and join I want to make sure that they are being overridden.
So let's have a look at where we've done that we've got a void host and a voice join both of which could
do with having an override key word after them.
So let's do that to make sure that they are indeed being overwritten over ridden rather.
Now our load main menu is without an implementation so if we go into the C++ for the game instance and
find an appropriate place somewhere to join I believe would be a good place.
Then we can implement our load main menu we'd need to remove virtual We need to remove override we need
to add a namespace.
And after we've added the namespace we need to put in a body.
For the method.
Okay so I'm pretty happy that that's good.
Now we actually have to make load maimon you do something.
Fortunately we basically know how to do this.
We've got our server travel or client travel both of which would be helpful in this case.
I think Server travels what we want.
We just want to take ourselves all the way back to to our main menu.
Actually on second thoughts I think about this so we've got our server travel which would basically
take all of the players with it to the main menu.
If we are the server so that's not exactly ideal.
And if we're not the server it might not work at all we might not be able to use a truck travel so we're
better off using a client travel which will disconnect us from the current server which is what we want
if we're on a server and want to leave the server then we do a quit action.
So let's do that instead let's do a client travel for that.
We can use our join.
Add join menu.
Basically what we've done in join.
So how we're going to do this where we've got our play a controller get our player control win sure
it's there and then we do a client travel as do the same thing in our load main menu.
Except this time instead of an address we are going to give the string very similar to what we had in
server trowels.
I'm going to copy that.
And use it as the address and instead of game third person maps we are going to be going to our main
menu screen which we know to be content main menu system main menu.
So it's going to be menu system main menu and we don't have to put any Listen after it because we're
not trying to host a server here.
Okay travel absolute.
We'll keep that as it is and pretty much we've got an implementation there for load main menu.
Okay so now if we go in to our in-game P copy we just need to ensure that interface is there.
So again to say if menu interface is not not not not pointer.
Then we can go ahead.
And we can use the menu interface to call that function.
So let's do that.
It's going to be load main menu but not forgetting that before we load than a menu actually wants to
tear down the current menu.
So that's what we're going do.
We're going to call tear down as a first port of call.
Okay.
And let's go ahead and build that and see whether we have got something working let's just overview
what and while that's building what we have done we have created a binding to the quit button in ingame
many die each We have bound in ingame many docs keen that Quit button to quit Prest then quit Prest
We are checking whether we have a menu interface remember the menu interface is set by our superclass.
It's a variable on our superclass.
If that is set then we tear down our menu and we use the menu interface to load ourselves a main menu
that load main menu is implemented over in our game instance dot s.p. with load menu which gets our
first player controller and does a client travel back to the main menu.
Fantastic.
So I think that's all good.
Let's.
It's compiled successfully.
Let's go over in two and real and test it out so I'm going to go ahead hit play.
Get the menu hit quit.
And here we are back at our main menu.
I'm going to leave it up to you folk to test this out in a multiplayer scenario and check that the disconnection
happens as intended.