Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be learning how to reliably quit our games from right within our game.
So we're going to able to do this both in standalone games and in the ED without crashing the editor.
So you can see here I've got a new button and my top right.
You see I've even added a little tooltip to it and it's a nice little icon denotes exit.
So if I go and click that exit button boom the game's gone.
So that allows us to complete that cycle of being able to get all the way from within the game back
out of the main menu and back exiting out of the game entirely.
So let's dive in and see how that's accomplished.
So with the game as it currently stands we can go into our main menu we can host the game we can go
to our in-game menu and cancel it.
We can go into our in game menu again and quit back to the main menu but what we can't do is exit the
game.
Any of these points.
Now what I want to show you is that actually it's really easy to exit the game from any of these points.
But we have to do it using a console command and that's very very straightforward.
You just go ahead and hit your console key which the one under escape in case you've forgotten.
And then you just quit.
And that's it.
That will both quit in the editor and do it in a sensible way.
There are some commands in C++ that do in a very non sensible way that actually bring the whole editor
crashing while not crashing but stops the whole editor or you can do it using this quick man which just
exists.
The play in Ed set up if you do it in a standalone game like fact let's go ahead and do it in a standalone
game.
It's not just talk about it get a launch up a standalone game and doing it in the console here in the
standalone game will also work just as well.
So let's try it out.
Here's the game loading up.
And here we are at the main menu.
And if I open up my console and type in wit.
Then close by request it's done it's gone ahead and closed it down so that's what we want to be able
to achieve.
But from our C++ so that we can do it on and pressing a button in the main menu we don't want to have
our users have to open up a console just in order to quit the game.
That's a little bit too much maybe a little bit too aggressive with your game saying that you will not
leave this game until you've learned how to use the console is not in the best way to treat your users.
At least I don't think so.
So let's figure out how we can run this from C++ console commitments or how can we run console commands
from within C++.
Now that might sound like a bit of a hack to you might be thinking Well can't we do this through a actual
C++ method.
Well yes you can but sometimes it's actually easier to do it this way.
And the console command is one example where it's easier to run the console command from within C++.
That's why it's just probably legacy.
Obviously you can ask why.
I'm just saying that you might not find a very satisfactory answer.
So here we have the documentation for the player controller.
And I want to show you that the player controller has a command for or hell's a function for running
commands.
So he was going to search for Command.
And sure enough they find it.
We've got console command as one such example.
So I'm going to leave the rest to you basically in trying to create that quick button.
So the instructions are fairly straightforward to quit the game you need to add a menu button to the
main menu bind that button and somehow implement quits.
Now you get to choose whether you want to do then the main menu you want to do it in the game instance
tiley up to you where that happens.
But the main thing is to quit.
So pause a video and have a go.
Okay.
Let's dive right into this so I am going to go ahead and open up the blueprint first of all so the WP
main menu blueprint and we are going to be adding in a new button now because our menu looks quite nice
as it is.
I don't want to go sticking another button at the same level as host unjoin I'd like to take it off
somewhere to the side I'm going to stick it down here in the bottom right corner for me now the way
that fat may be at the top right corner is where exits usually go.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and in a menu switch we've got our main menu and under
the main menu we've got an overlay.
And if I want something to be here on the main menu to be here I am going to have to do this with a
canvas.
So I'm going to right click my overlay and I'm going to go to wrap with canvas where the canvas panel.
There we go.
Now obviously it's messed up a few things so let's go to our overlay first and foremost and use size
to content on there so that we are not squishing down our size based on the canvas.
Next up I want my alignment to be point five and point five.
And I want my anchors to be at the Centre for the menu and reset the X and the y position so that it's
basically back where it was.
But now we can get a button from our palette and stick it under that canvas panel and hopefully that
button should now be positionable to wherever we want it.
Except we've got a slight issue here.
Let's have a look at our canvas panel.
Yes sure enough our canvas panel is a bit small.
Now why is it a bit small.
Let's get up and have a look at our main menu.
Our main menu seemed okay a menu switcher seems okay so why is our main menu acting all small.
Maybe we need to stretch it to fill horizontally and vertically.
Okay so that's helped them a canvas takes up the whole space and now button can be positioned.
I'm going to select the anchor to be the top right corner and I'm going to move my button somewhere
somewhat over in that direction and resize a little bit and it's looking a bit ugly.
So we're going to need some images so I'm going to do a google image search for eggs it icon.
And we're going to do a tools and usage rights and label for reuse.
Now is a nice one to hear from pics obey my second icon I think I'll be using that one has an exit hi
can and let's save that and say image.
Save it in there.
And then this icon I can go ahead and bring into my content browser.
Let's bring up the content browser.
Navigate to our images folder and then I can go ahead and drag my image in to.
Content browser.
Least I should be able to.
There we go.
Let's rename it to something sensible like exact icon and squat icon.
And let's open it up because it's black on a black background that's not going to be very helpful.
I just want to show you a quick little trick that you can do with these images.
Obviously not something that's necessarily I expected to do by yourself but if you go to the adjustments
in the details pane once you've got the image open you can go to the curve and brightness and set the
curve brightness to minus 1 and you'll see that what that does is it makes it white on basically a transparent
background and that means that now with my button I can go in two or back in the main menu and select
a button again and we go to a parents open up style.
Go to normal open up normal.
Change the image to be the exact icon and looks a bit weird.
The reason it looks weird is because we're drawing as a box by draw it as an image instead and rescale
it to the right sort of scale for that images ratio.
Then there we go.
We've got ourselves a nice tool or exit icon that can position it to look just right relative to that
corner.
Let's go ahead and play and see how it looks.
Looks good.
Obviously when a hover over it something goes wrong because it's using a different button for the background
but it looks like an exit button I'm happy with that.
Now one trick we can use is when that button selected I can copy right click on normal and copy and
right click on hovered and paste right click on Prest and paste.
And that means that now when I hover over it it's still the exact icon.
I do want to have a hover effect on going click on the hover effect and the effect I'm going to go for
is changing the tint to red just a kind of warning sign that if you click this you are exiting.
So if I now play and hover over it you can see its wishes to read.
I click it it goes white and finally I just want to make it absolutely crystal clear what's going to
happen if you click that button and for that I'm going to add in a tooltip so you can go down to behaviour.
There's a tooltip text and I'm going to put in quits the game.
As my tooltip doesn't need capitalization.
And let's go ahead and play that.
So if I hover over it says quit the game so if I am in any doubt what that bunn's supposed to do.
The tooltip isn't going to tell me.
OK so I'm happy with that.
Let's go ahead and make sure that's bound.
So first things first I'm going to rename the button to quit button.
Like.
Oh.
I didn't read it properly.
Select the button again and rename and we'll go and call it quit button.
Okay quit but button it is.
Let's go over into visual studio.
Here it is.
And in visual studio we're going to go to our main menu dot H and create a new button binding.
It's going to be near the host button and join button.
I'm going to put one underneath that called Quick button.
And we're going to have to have a quote function.
As well.
So how do you function.
Void.
Pressed.
And we are going to implement that over in the C plus plus.
Go to our C plus plus create our quit quick press function had the namespace and the body.
And let's bind it so it will go and copy the join button binding code in it and we will rename that
to join to quit.
So it's quick button and quick button and we're going to bind to our quick pressed function instead
of join open join menu.
Great.
So that is going to more or less work.
The only thing we need to do now is actually go ahead and quit.
So the thing to do here is to get hold of our player controller in order to quit.
Now we've done this before from within a menu we've done this in now our parent class which is the menu
interface DCP.
So it's open.
No not the menu interface cbp the menu widget cbp That's what I meant.
We have got the tear down which gets a hold of our player controller from the world so let's get that
whole world ensure player and sure player control the Ensure and bring that in to our main menu key.
Now the reason I'm doing it here rather than setting up an interface is because the way that you quit
is not going to change very much depending on the game.
Obviously if we want to do that later on and has some weird quitting behaviour that is game specific
then you might want to put it through an interface but I don't predict that being a problem.
So I'm going to be doing it right here in the main menu key.
So let's get hold of our player controller which we've got here or copy that and with the player controller
we are going to arrow to that console.
Command.
Which is what we want to run.
And we can give it a string which we know is going to be quit.
And then that should pretty much do the trick.
We've got a play controller we have executed the console command.
We've done that from button which we have found.
Let's go ahead and build this and see if it works.
Okay that build successfully completed Let's go back in to visual studio visual studio.
I mean unreal.
And let's go on and hit play and see we've got our exit menu exit button if I hit that.
Sure enough it exists.
That's fantastic.
Let's go over in to our file system and try it in the standalone game.
So right click on the project launch game and let's see when that loads up what happens.
Okay the game has launched up if I hit my quick button.
It closes down of perfect that's working exactly as we want it to.
So pat yourselves on the back for pretty much implementing that yourselves.
All you needed to know was that the console quit command worked and how to call it so excellent work
and I will see you in the next lecture.