Welcome to a brand new section and in this section we are going to be talking about Steam multiplayer
probably long awaited for some of you who are very excited to get in to using steam as a proper multiplayer
backend.
So this actually is going to be all about connecting it to your friends over the Internet.
We are going to be talking about how to use the steelworks back and see how that integrates into one
real and we are going to fundamentally take the project that weve been working on in previous sections
and make it really easy for you to spruce it up and play it with your friends is going to get to the
point where its ready for you to say hey guys go and download this on my HBO account for example and
you'll just be able to play with anybody who's online at the moment.
That means that you'll be able to share this game with your Facebook friends in groups and forums to
get some actual feedback.
That's going to be great.
Great stuff so I can't wait to get started on this content.
Let's dive into it.