Welcome to another exciting new instalment of unreal multiplayer in this exciting instalment of an real
marketplace.
We are actually going to be getting the steam works example working over the network with another member
of the course.
So we're gonna be learning about a little thing called steam lobby.
So let me exit to the main menu where you can go ahead and find lobby's to join other people's lobbies
and you can play games with other people either on the course with you or just on the web.
So let's go ahead and dive in and see how that all works.
So before we even begin we're gonna need to find a test partner in order to test out the servers and
the lobbies.
In this example projects that's going to be the first part the straightaway.
The first thing you need to be doing is this challenge to find a test partner as very much similar to
how you've done it in previous sections.
2 you can first of all check in with your previous partner if you think that they might be in the same
stage of the course then you can see if they're available again if you got on well then you might want
to use them again as a sounding board for this example project then you.
If that fails you can write a post on the forum.
Now go to the post link from this lecture and create a new post there.
Again with the title of the availability times or including your availability times in the title in
the utc time zone so that everyone can compare.
No matter what time zone they're in and then the important thing is to respond to other people's posts
because obviously if you just write a post then and everybody did that then nobody is going to get any
responses so make sure you respond as well as writing your own post.
Okay so pause video and go and get that first and then we'll show you what you going to be doing with
your test partner.
Okay welcome back I hope you have gone and at least start the search for a test partner.
Don't forget that discord is a good place.
This channel is a good place to go and find people who might be available right now to be testing partners.
Do try and be available for people even if you're not at this stage in the course as you get later on
in the course.
Do try and stay available for others to help them out and testing as they get to this stage in the course.
It all is very very helpful if you do that.
So let's see what we're going to be doing well the first step is going to be testing service.
I'll show you what I mean in just a second.
So let's launch up our steam game.
The steam works example Spacewar.
We're going to launch it up and you can see here right away that we have got a couple of things.
Quite a few menu items really we've got the start server find LAN servers find Internet servers and
create a lot of it so for this first part I'm interested in having a look at these first three entries
the start new server find land serves and find Internet site.
So if I go to start new server let me just show you what that does.
And basically what I want you to be doing with your partner is testing out that all of this works as
it does here in my lecture.
So here I am I am starting a new server but obviously nobody is there to join me so I'm going to show
you what happens if on my other computer I start the service I'm going to exit back to the main menu
scape.
Go back to the main menu and on another computer.
I'm going to launch up a server.
Okay so I have a server running on my other computer.
And here we've got find LAN servers.
Let's see that first of all they go you can see Sam's game and if I go and join it then I get to connect
into that server and let's just see if this works out.
They waited for the round to finish on the other computer and.
And now I've got Echo.
So let's see if I can get a little less erico.
So as you can see here I am playing against the server.
There's actually some voice chat going on.
In this example application as well.
That should help you communicate with the person you are testing with.
That should be quite good as long as you've both got microphones.
Yes I'm going to exit back to the menu at this stage.
The service still running on the other computer I can demonstrate that to you.
By going to find land servers then you can see that the server is still there.
So going to return to the main menu as click.
Find Internet servers.
Is this server going to be an Internet server.
Well no it's not.
And I think you'll find that you also struggle for it to be an Internet server or you'll struggle to
find it with your partner.
Now I'm not entirely sure what the reason for this is but it seems like Internet servers are a different
thing and probably not available to the free tier on Steam work now.
The thing is you are using the free tier because there is a special case for Spacewar for the Spacewar
app.
If there is a special case in steam and it allows you to use it for free as long as you are not using
things like achievements and leaderboards you can just use it to connect with.
I think up to five players for free over their network so that's quite cool.
But you can't use anything like Internet servers and other other things that I mentioned like leaderboards
and so on.
So that's enough said about servers.
I think we also haven't yet managed to connect it to our friendly peer over the Internet.
You've so far could have done this all on your land so if you want to in the meantime while you're waiting
for somebody to pass a test with you then you can try this out on a LAN if you've got more than one
computer if not then you're going to have to use a VPN with the peer that you want to test with.
You can use amati like we did in the first section you can revise that by going back to the section
to the lectures on her marji in those in that section.
Okay so let's return back to the main menu because the next thing we want to test here is the lobby
system.
Okay so lobbies are a way that you are going to be able to connect over the Internet and hopefully this
will actually work.
So lets go and create a lobby here.
Go created Sam patooties lobby and I can do things like set myself as ready as some.
Lobby state and as the lobby creator I am able to start the game wherever I like.
Probably when enough people are in the game.
So let's go ahead and on the other computer.
Im going to go and join this lobby.
But I am having problems finding it.
Lets try it the other way round.
So I am going to go and start a lobby on the other computer.
Just doing exact same thing create lobby.
Then I am returning to the main menu here and we are going to find a lobby and I actually it seems like
a long list.
But even if you were to scroll down all the way you wouldn't find anything.
Typically the lobbies that you just started will appear near the top you shouldn't have too many issues
with that so we cant find the lobby.
Whats going on here.
You might run into the same issue well a little.
One word of warning word of caution is that in steam you're going to have to be in the same download
region and you can easily do this by deciding on a down road load reading between you and changing your
settings or one of you change the settings in esteem for them to match.
Let me show you what I mean.
If I go to my steam settings it's in a slightly different place on the Mac.
But I'm sure you'll be able to find it then in the steam settings.
There is a download section and there we have a download region as you can see I have deliberately set
mine to Ukraine so that we can see this issue.
But if I switch it to UK London which is the region that my other computer is on my other STEAM account
is on remember you'll need to steam accounts to be able to do this if you're doing this on two computers
yourself.
Then we can go ahead and click okay it's going to ask me to restart steam.
Going to ask me to shut down Spacewar which I think we already did and that steam is going to launch
and back up again and once it has launched back up again we can start our visual studio and it wait
for it to finish loading and I believe it has just finished loading because it's telling me how many
items I've got in my mentary.
So let's go ahead and debug.
Start with debugging start up the game and now we're going to go and find lobbies.
Once it has finished loading I'm going to go find lobby's and hopefully find my other computer.
There it is right at the top of the list so that's where you should be expecting that the other person's
lobby is going to be very near the top of the list such as mine is.
I go to Sam's lobby now.
Both of us are called Sam I can set myself as ready.
He can set himself as ready as well and it comes up on my list and because he's the host.
You can go ahead and start the game whenever he likes and I just have to wait around and then when he
starts the game will be connecting to server like so and then boom we are in the same room he started
side before me so gets the first round on his own for some reason and he should be able to voice chat
like before.
So this is fantastic.
We have got lobbies lobbies are going to be the way forward with steam.
That's what we're going to be using in our unreal game.
I just want to make sure that you've got this all working across the Internet with steam works before
we dive into one real one.
Eke out any problems that might be around your network.
That might be around the download regions as we just saw and make sure those are all cleared out the
way before we add another layer on top with the open source.
In the online subsystem that's the one I'm looking for.
The online search subsystem in real.
Then we will add in some other complexities that will deal with so we're going to be looking at that
in the next few videos.
I'll see you there.