Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be importing puzzle platforms as a starting point for getting online with our multiplayer
so we're going to be doing this via the online subsystems which we've already talked about a little
bit in this.
Next we're going to be talking more about the capabilities of the online system subsystem and how we
can include it as part of our project and how we can get hold of a pointer to it.
That's what it is it has a pointer to the subsystem So we're going to find out how to get that pointer
in this lecture.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So before we dive into the online subsystem and its intricacies we want to have something to convert
over to a web functioning at a working over Internet multiplayer.
That's what I mean.
And the way we're going to be doing that is just taking our puzzle platform product which is already
pretty fully formed and figuring out how we can get that connection to work over the Internet without
having to use a VPN and how we can integrate that with the work of the menu system from last letter
to actually pull together a cohesive bit of lobbying you why that allows us to connect over Steve.
Now the first thing we're going to do for the answer is go ahead and import our puzzle platforms project.
Now you can carry on with the repository that you are currently using.
If you were using just one repository that's fine.
I'm going to split these all up into separate repositories just to make it really easy for people picking
it up without having gone through that whole thing.
So I'm going to go to clone and download on my menu system project on get.
The link is in your resources and I'm going to go ahead and download the zip.
And actually I've done this already so here's one I prepared earlier in my downloads folder here I have
the menu system zip massed and I'm going to go ahead and grab that the puzzle platforms directory from
that.
Folder and Im going to put it in to the pre prepared folder in my current stream multiplayer repository
which is called Unreal project so let's open up that and real product folder.
It has a gift ignore in here already which is the standard.
Unreal guitar ignore and Im going to go ahead and paste the patch folder in and then what we can do
is get it doing its thing of building and generate and portable studio project files so lets go and
right click on the you project and generate the visual studio or X code project file from here.
That didn't quite work let's click on it again.
I believe I'm in the wrong.
No I'm not in the wrong repository.
Let's try this one more time.
I click on the project.
There we go.
Generate visual studio project files.
That's the first thing we're going to do.
And once we've generated a bit of stick pretty far we can open it up so it starts indexing the problem.
The whole project and it will be ready for hours to have all the auto complete in there so I'm going
to open up the solution and simultaneously I am going to go back to the folder structure and open up
the new project which is going to trigger a compile which will also allow So we're just getting all
of that compilation process started while I tell you about the next bit.
Feel free to be doing the same thing waiting for it to compile and so on.
While I am going to be telling you about the online subsystems.
Okay so everything is compiling right now.
Let's talk a little bit about online subsystems and what they are and what their capabilities are.
Previously we talked about the online subsystem we talked about it as a wrapper around the steam works
API and in fact it's a wrapper around many other API such as the X Box API and the Playstation API the.
IOW Android and Facebook.
All these things have online systems and the online subsystem basically provides a neutral wrapper around
that.
But you might be saying all these services are so varied they have a little bit of overlap in certain
places but they're very very varied and the online subsystem takes this into account it knows that they're
not all exactly the same.
And if you have a look at the online subsystem overview documentation here then you will see that there
is an interfaces section.
That's because the online subsystem is not just a one monolithic blob.
It is composed of many interfaces all of which are optional.
So not all services will implement every single interface our can have unreal jump over the top of this
window in a second.
Please excuse that.
So we've got the interfaces and they are things like a profile so as a user you may have a profile on
these online services.
You can access that through the online subsystem.
You've got friends so you can figure out whether your friends are playing the game and what your friends
are doing invite them and so on so forth.
SESSIONS That is the bit about connecting multiplayer games creating Sessions joining sessions finding
sessions and matchmaking and all that sort of stuff is included in the sessions interface.
Then there's some stuff called Shared cloud and user cloud not something I'm particularly particularly
know about so we'll be not worrying too much about that's not very important.
And then there's the leaderboards voice achievements fairly self-explanatory what those are about voice
is for having connecting with VoIP kind of essentially in your game as we saw in the steelworks example.
And there's external you why which is useful for things like x box and P.S. PlayStation and things like
that but not so much for the steam side of things.
So this is great.
This allows us to break down some of the things that are possible in the online subsystem into different
interfaces.
We've seen interfaces with our menu system we've had a menu interface there and we are seeing interfaces
again here in the online subsystem.
So let's go ahead and see if we can include the online subsystem module in our project because it is
a separate module very much like our UMG module so let's go ahead in to our visual studio project and
we're going to navigate to games puzzle platform we are going to find the source puzzle platform and
then puzzle platform build dot C S and in the build up cebes we are going to have this UMG module after
the UMG module we want to add a new one which is going to be the online subsystem module.
So it's online with a capital O and subsystem with one capital S not two not subsystem it's just subsystem
and we are going to put quotes around the whole thing.
We are going to go ahead and say that and we are going to go ahead and build that as well.
So what this is doing is as we already know its including a new module into our project the online subsystem
and that will allow us to get access to new head of files and new auto completes around that whole online
subsystem.
So while we're waiting for that to compile Let's go ahead back over to the documentation that I had
open and in particular I'm interested in the documentation for the online subsystem the online subsystem
interface.
That's what this is about.
One thing we're going to want to know straight off the bat is what its head file is so if we go head
to the bottom we might find out.
And it's not particularly helpful as it was just saying online module online subsystem.
So we may have to have a little intuitive guess of what its head afar's going to be.
We'll do that in a minute.
And then there's lots of other things here which include having interfaces to get the friend interface
get the external interface so that you can see are ways of getting hold of each of the individual individual
interface components such as the special interface the identity interface and so on.
So that is how it's implemented having multiple interfaces as part of this larger interface.
BI get us now if you want to get hold of the actual online subsystem it's an interface not an object
so you want to get a pointer to something with this interface type.
We can actually use a special method they've got here which is called get.
And so if you do online subsystem get it a static method meaning that it doesn't have to be called on
a particular object just on the class on the class namespace it will get as a pointer to the online
subsystem of our choice.
We don't have to worry about constructing it or anything like that.
We can just get it a single turn.
For those of you who know about singletons it's a singleton so we're going to be using that in just
a minute.
OK.
So first things first let's go back to Visual Studio which has just built successfully.
We're going to actually go and regenerate the project.
Far So if I go back to puzzle platforms in my Explorer and get a right click on the you project generate
the visual studio project files so that we can get the auto complete that we need to get hold of the
various head of files that we want.
Let's go back into the visual studio solution and a reload.
Which will reload all of the various project files.
So with that reloaded of what we can go ahead and do is we going to want to get hold of this session
interface.
I think a good place to do that rather the online subsystem interface would be to do it in the game
instance class so I'm going to go to the game instance s.p. file and in there I'm going to go in to
the init method gets called fairly late in the construction of the game instance I'm fairly sure that
at that point we will have a online subsystem to get hold of and we want to use that method so let's
go back in to our class and see that we're going to need to get hold of this online subsystem first
of all we're going to need a header.
So let's think about what that header is going to be.
So I'm going to just include an.
I'm going to do as above our local includes.
I'm going to do it in the section where I am including engine related things and I am going to include.
And I believe all will need to be called is the online subsystem.
Get online subsystem.
Dot H.
That is the one that we're looking for.
I'm going to go ahead and save that and just compile.
Make sure that everything's going to work out for us like that.
And actually it hasn't worked at all.
So what's going on here.
Why have we gone error.
It's been a completely random place here in this load menu functions complaining about if I go and have
a look at the output.
The error message the top error message is saying that it cannot find that load menu double W is not
a member of a puzzle platform game instance load many W I haven't written a load menu w what is going
on here this is super strange now actually whats going on here.
If I hover over my load menu you will see that it is got a hash.
Define for load menu to load menu w what's going on here.
Right click that and go to the definition and you'll see that I end up in a win that use dot H head
a file so it's something in the windows API is on Mac you may be fortunate enough not to get this error
but the win user API is has a define which renames any instance of a load menu to load menu W and it's
clear that this one user dot age has been included as part of our online subsystem.
Dot H.
Which is fine but I didn't expect it to go and rename things like load menu but we can fix this by changing
our load menu name to something else so let's go over to our head of file and think about what a better
name for load menu might be.
In this case I think we can call it a load menu widget So let's just add it to the end and that should
hopefully make the Windows API header file a little bit happier.
Obviously if this isn't happening for you on Mac or on different versions of Windows then don't worry
about the rename.
That's just something that we have to do to work around whatever this header file is trying to do.
Okay this time we had a successful build So the next step is going to be getting hold of the pointer
to the subsystem interface.
Now this is actually going to be a challenge that I leave up to you to get the OSX pointer you're going
to do this through that gets static that I showed you in the documentation.
Go and read up on the documentation and see if you can figure out how to use it.
Id like is check for NULL.
In that point up because it can come back and forth for example if there isn't a configured subsystem.
And I'd like you to print the result and tell me do you get now or do you not get null and if you dont
get an old what do you get.
So pause a video and have a go at this.
Okay welcome back.
So let's get stuck.
I've got the game instance cvp that I'm going to go ahead and open and at the top of it I am going to
be reusing this message because that's quite a handy one for printing out and I am going to go ahead
and get the interface from the online subsystem.
Colon colon.
Because it's name spaced it's static dot.
And so rather than doing a dot we do a colon colon get it's going to go ahead and return as an R..
I online subsystem pointer so let's go ahead and create a variable to store that in two of Type II on
line subsystem.
So much typing.
Okay.
And this is going to be a pointer and I'm going to call the variable a subsystem like so.
Now I'm going to check for Noel because remember we have to be paranoid about null pointers at all times
in C++ otherwise you might end up with crashing engines.
So we're going to do an if subsystem not equals and null pointer and then in this case I am going to
log out a message which I'm going to for which I am going to use a copy of this log message down here
in as part of the unit and I'm going to say that I.
We found that class we found they in fact we're going to say we found the subsystem and the subsystem
that we found Let's go ahead and use the subsystem and dereference its pointers.
You can have a look at the documentation for what's included in the subsystem.
If your auto complete doesn't show you here but I am going to be getting the names so get named interface
like so.
Well see if that works out.
And then I am going to have an ELT's just in case to make sure that it is indeed running and in the
else statement I'm just going to say we got a null subsystem so found that no subsystem.
And it doesn't need any arguments to reference because otherwise that would be problematic would be
dereferencing a pointer and everything would come crashing down around our ears which is never a good
thing so we can get rid of this log message about found class now.
We don't need that one.
A log message is currently giving me some problems out because from the get named interface.
Facts it'll get named in face.
We want.
It is get.
See instance name or subsystem name I think is the one I want.
But anyway that's subsystem name returns an F name.
So if we do a dot two string then that should pacify our log message.
It's now being able to print a string or turning that into a teacher or whatever it's doing with our
star getting the internal representation of the F string.
And we are now printing out the long message as required.
Great.
So let's go ahead and build that and see what we get.
So that compile is now complete.
Let's go over in to.
Unreal Engine.
And hit play and see what happens.
If at this point you get an error talking about unresolved compile errors in the blueprint when you're
trying to play.
Then you may need to go in to the blueprint and question and reattach a couple of nodes.
For me this error comes up in the next video.
Not in this one.
At about four minutes and 54 seconds so if you do want to see my solution it's very straightforward
but you can probably work it out for yourself.
There we go.
It's actually saying that it found no subsystem.
So that's interesting.
So there is no subsystem when we haven't configured one in the next.
We're going to be looking at how we can configure a subsystem.
In particular we're going to be configuring the noell subsystem the subsystem that does nothing.
Why does she do nothing.
It does some useful stuff but it doesn't actually talk to any back end such as steam.
So were going to be figuring out how we can use that to how we can use in testing as all can be very
exciting so I will see you in the next actual talk about the null subsystem.