Welcome.
I'm excited about this next lecture and you will know why.
Because we are going to be making it so that when we have a list of items in an join menu we can select
the items in that join menu and when we've selected them we will know which index we selected.
Now currently it's not showing me in the UI that it selected that we're going to do later but you can
see here in the logs it's telling me that my selected index is one of my selected index is not set or
that my selective index is zero going to find out how we can do that and how we can make it look good
like this so that we basically doesn't look like we're clicking on a button or a checkbox but rather
that we're just clicking on the server row and we're going a little to learn about a little type called
T optional.
It is a contained type like a T array or a t shared pointer and we will find out what it does and why
it's useful.
So let's dive in and do that.
So if we take a look at how our join menu is currently working at we have the side effect that if I
hit join it will populate it with a list of servers and it just got overwritten by the final session
but found none.
But if I hit join we do get a list of well simulated servers at the very least.
How do we want this menu to actually work because we've got this joined button it's not currently doing
the right thing.
We do want it to do the right thing or do something.
What is that going to be.
Well what I want to be able to do is hover over the items here get some affordance that when we're hovering
over there selectable and then I want to be able to click on one of the items then it should look like
it's selected.
And when I go over and hit join when that triggers a button call-back it should be able to see with
a variable basically which index was selected and we can send the index up to the game instance where
it can find the server information for that index.
So that's the idea is that I want to be able to set an index up at the new main menu level so that when
we hit join it will have that index and we will access that index to send up.
Okay.
So for now we're not going to worry about sending.
Up above you main menu level but we do want to get indexed to that you may many level and there is a
slight hitch here because that index is optional.
It's not necessarily going to be set for example when I've just arrived in this menu which indexes are
going to be set to.
Are we defaulting to the first or are we saying that it's not set to any.
So we're going to need to deal with that case and one way that we can deal with that case is with a
little something called a tea option or a tea option or is a special um real type that's going to have
a look at the documentation which is also linked against this lecture.
What it says here about a the he optional is that we have an optional value where is set returns true
that optional value can be got at using the get value function.
Otherwise get value is not meaningful basically meaning it's essentially like a nold pointer that when
it is valid we can get the contents right we can dereference that null pointer but when it's not valid
dereferencing is an error.
It's exactly the same here.
So why do we have a different concept.
Because with a pointer we're assigning memory on the heap now assigning memory on the heap is a expensive
and B we have to worry about allocating it.
If we use an optional type none of that is true because we can just allocate the memory right here on
the stack or wherever.
This value is being created it might be on the heap but it can be part of an object on the heap.
So t optional is a great option when you just want something that is essentially nullable but not necessarily
a pointer.
So were going to be using teh optional for our selected index.
Let's go ahead and implement that in Visual Studio.
So I'm going to set up a index in the main menu dot H and go to do it right at the bottom and we're
going to have a.
Optional.
And what types is it going to be it's going to be a u you int.
32.
I don't need more than a 32 bit integer and I don't need it to have sign doesn't need to be negative
so it's going to be a new int and I'm going to call it the selected index now.
Note here that I could use an integer with a negative value and not worry with the T.
Optional which I've misspelt because then I could use more negative numbers to say that the index is
not set but obviously there are more than one negative number and it doesn't really protect us because
there's no function like getting value.
That reminds us that this could be null.
The nice thing about t optional is that it really does remind you that the value you are getting might
be a null value might not be set and in which case would be invalid.
So I like using teh optional you can obviously not use it.
If you don't feel comfortable using it and you can use a negative number to represent something that
is unset.
But if you want to try to be optional go ahead and try it.
Next up we are going to set up a server row.
No we're not I beg your pardon we're going to have to set a set up for.
Selected index first because we want it to be set from the server row and then we're going to need to
get the server row to have pointers up so it can set it basically.
So first off let's create that public method for setting it so it's going to be void.
Select index.
And it is going to take a new int.
32 doesn't need to be optional here because we could have a reset index if we need that later on.
But for now is just going to give it the number it wants it to set to.
So that's going to be the index and that should do the trick.
I'm going to go over into the C plus bus and implement that I'm going to implement it between sets up
a list and join server because I think chronologically that's about where it's going to happen.
I'm going to namespace it and implement its body as we always do.
Nothing new here and I'm going to set these selected index.
Equal to index.
Now noticed that I can just set it like this very much.
Well no actually like a pointer in this case because we don't have to dereference it to set it.
That's because the T optional has overloads for the equal assignment operator so it's an overlive overloaded
assignment which is basically putting B you 32 in the box and saying that it is set.
So that's great.
We can just use it very simply.
Setting is very easy it's the getting that we have to be cautious about because it might be null.
Okay so we set it let's go ahead and print it.
What does it look like to print one of these T optionals.
I'm going to print it out in the join server call-back and what we have to be careful of as I have said
is whether it's set or not set.
I I'm going to do an if statement were going to say selected index.
Dot is set which you'll find on the documentation page and if it is set then I'm going to do a u e underscore
or log log temp.
Warning.
And with some text saying.
Selected index.
Percent D.
A digit.
For a decimal rather.
And then we're going to get the value of the selected index.
Which is going to be done with.
Get value.
So now obviously this doesn't work if it is not set.
But we are in an IF statement the just said that it was.
So we are fairly safe and we can do in ELT's and on the in the else we are going to do a ewy Log that
says selected index not set.
Now what would you expect to come back if we run this now or let's remove just that item from the log
message that we don't need go ahead build them all tested out the build succeeded Let's hop head on
into unreel and restart the game go to and join menu populate the join menu and you can see that it
says a selected index is indeed not set because we have not yet called set and set were set index select
select index that's the one select index.
We have called that we are going to want to call this from our server row when a button is pressed So
let's set up our server roads to be able to call up.
We are going to do that from the head of aren't going to add a public method called set up.
It's going to be void.
Set up.
And then we are going to have it's going to need a pointer basically to the main menu class so it's
going to be for declaration here.
You mean menu pointer and I'll call this parent because it's the owning menu essentially and then it's
also going to want to know which index it is so that's you in 32 which is going to be index because
it's going to need to call the parent don't need to call the method on the parent called select index
and it's going to tell it which index it currently is.
So we've got this set up I'm going to go into the key and implement this set up.
Create the body copy the namespace from the head of file you server row.
Count on colon.
And that is now implement it.
Okay.
So all we can do now is we would be able to call up to the parent from within this class at least we
have the information to do so.
Okay.
So we've got the information to do so what else do we need.
Well we need to remember to set it up in the main key So where we've done so far created our role in
set server list.
We are going to do the ROE arrow set up.
And it's going to pass a pointer to this.
And the current index which we're going to have to create a for loop that basically is a range based
for loop so it goes over the server names.
So if we want to get an index i can keep a story separate to you in thirty two which I'm going to initialised
to zero outside of the loop and then I'm going to use in our set up method and then after the set up
method I'm going to increment and I'm going to use a pre increment he can read all about the difference
between post increment and pre increment on the web.
I'm not going to basically elaborate on this pre increment is slightly more efficient but really only
slightly and it depends on your compiler.
Okay so I am going to go ahead and do that.
Great.
The set up and just go check that it all compiles it should do.
So let's move on to the next step which is actually setting up a new button and it's back on this server
row.
So I'm going to go over in to one real stop the game from playing.
Go to my content browser open up the server row widget in blueprint which opens up on another screen
for some reason with me.
And here we are.
I've got my server and I want to actually change it the screen size or sorry the desired size to custom
where I can restart Gaelic to something that resembles more of a row and in fact what I'm going to do
is I'm going to think it looks ugly without anything but the server names.
I'm going to add in some mock stuff over on the right.
Like the number of players on the server so I'm just going to do that by duplicate the text.
I'm going to copy the text.
I think the horizant box and paste the text in the horizontal box can change the text in the box to
something that just like one out of two to indicate how many players there I didn't intend to have the
hash there so I will remove the hash and then we can spaced this out with a widget.
Call a spacer you can put the space between things in a horizontal box to add some space.
You do need to select the spacer and select under the slot horizontal box slot you can select fill and
that will fill it out so that it'll put it on the other side.
If we go in hit play here and hit join you'll see this menu looks quite a lot better.
It looks like it's intentionally a row of servers so I am going to close that back down again.
And now I want to wrap this whole horizontal box inside a button so that you can click anywhere on this
row to select it so I'm going to right click to a wrap with and I'm going to wrap it with a button.
So I've got my button.
You can see it's looking a bit funky it's looking like a button is wrapping it so I'm going to click
on the horizontal box.
Look at the slot buttons lot and I'm going horizontally and vertically fill it.
So we are using all the space in the button and then I dont want it to look like a button song and select
the button go to appearance and style and on in the normal section.
I'm going to go into draw as and select draw as none.
And I'm going to have to copy the normal style and paste it onto hovered and pressed so that it's a
sensually eradicated any style from the button.
So if I compile get hit play join and join again to see our test servers you can see that there's no
hover and when I click there is no click other than it slightly moves the text which at least gives
us some affordance so that's okay.
Now in this lecture we aren't going to worry about making sure that the text is highlighted when we
click on it because that's going to add a bit more time and I really want to get back to doing more
multiplayer stuff.
We're going to polish that off don't worry.
In later in later lectures.
Okay so the next step is for you to set the selected index that we have already set up.
It's just hooking up the bits in between now basically the way you're going to do this is you're going
to handle the button call with created a button you're gonna need to bind it handle it's call back and
call the selected index on the main menu we've got the point and got the index so all the information
for it you just need to make that happen.
Then I want you to test that the printed value is actually set by hitting the join button.
So pause a video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back we're going to dive right in with this.
So the first thing to do is go into our server row and bind that button.
So I'm going to copy and paste the binding of the you text block and I am going to make that private
because we don't want it called from the outside we're going to be doing the binding in the Servat row
s.p it's going to be a new button.
In this case and I'm going to call it as such I'm going to call it the row button.
And this I'm going to copy and take over.
Well that's first that the build off.
Going to take it over in to the unreel editor and I'm going to rename the button to row button which
should allow it to bind correctly.
We'll see that when it is finished building.
Okay so we have a row button now in set up.
Well actually we're going need a function a u function to handle the On Click event of you button.
So I'm going to create a new function.
It does not need a return type.
I believe you can check that with the documentation of course on clicked.
Just like the handle for you button.
What I'm going to call it and I'm going to go ahead and implement this over in the C plus plus where
I will add a namespace.
And I will add a body.
Now we are going to want to hook up this call-back So I'm going to get a row button.
And arrow.
And I'm going to do on click it.
We don't have the header file for Button So I'm going to go and include.
The component components forward slash button.
Dot H like so now on click it should work will have on clicked add dynamic and then auto complete gets
my way so undo the auto complete.
Going to add dynamic to this.
And then I need to get the address of on clicked so I am going to do that.
With the address of operator and the fully qualified name of honour clicked some come at the end of
the line that should do the trick.
Okay so that's great.
I'm going to set that off building as well.
But even on clicked we need to call the parent with the index so we're going to need to store the parent
index as private variables are going to do that in the header.
I'm going to stick that under our ROE button and I am going to see put them on separate lines at least.
And I am going to make that parent the you main menu parent.
I am going to pay you property so that it is properly handled by the garbage collection system and we
won't get it won't go away when we don't want it to.
Okay so we've got the parent point we've got you in 32.
Now let's go into our server ocp where we're going to call the parent.
So parent our own.
Now you'll notice isn't completing and we get an error because we've got an incomplete class type so
we need to include our main menu so hash it out.
Well if I can hit hash go include main menu.
H.
And then we should be able to get access to that so I'm going to do a a what I want select.
Index.
And I'm going to pass it.
The index variable.
But it mustn't forget that these two variables have actually been set in set up so I'm going to set
them in set up parent he took equal to parent.
That's not going to work so I'm going have to rename parent too in parent.
So it's got to be parent equal to in parent.
And then we're going to do the same thing with index index equal to in index and then we're going to
copy and paste that variable name in to the class.
Enter the function parameter.
And I would say that pretty much does the should fit the bill.
So let's go ahead and build and test it out.
Build all good.
Let's go over to unreel and hit play.
Go join and hit join met method.
More than once.
And you can see we've got selected index not set so far.
Now if I click on one of the rows and hit join they go select it.
Next is zero.
If I hit two then the selected index is one.
So that's working just fine.
Were able to select an index and access it from joint which means that we should be able to pass that
back up to our game instance pat yourselves on the back.
LS quite intense we did quite a bit of stuff in there we had TI optional and did a few architectural
manoeuvres but well done Pat yourselves on the back and I'll see you in the next lecture a will actually
join that game.