Hello and welcome to this lecture where we are going to be sorting out and during menus you can see
here the join menu now has a header explaining what these fields are.
And it also makes sure that they don't overlap each other as you can see here the serving is rather
long but it doesn't go over the top of the hostname which is also rather long but doesn't go over the
name.
The number of players in the play a fraction and we're able to select it.
You can see now the players is 0 out of 2 instead of being 2 out of two.
Because there is no other player in there at that moment so I can go ahead hit join.
And here I am in the game.
So that's all working out really nicely.
Let's go and debug what was wrong with it in the first place.
So as mentioned in The Last Lecture.
Let's try and get that search menu working without bugs.
Now without the Those features I'm going to make them actually properly work.
The first one is going to be making sure that we can disable steam fully for testing so that we can
actually connect on a local machine.
We're going to get the available connections make sure that's working correctly and also caveat about
the null subsystem and then we're going to check out the padding text properly.
In fact I'm going to get you to do that.
So we're going to start off with disabling steam fully and the best way to achieve this is actually
really straightforward.
What we do is we can just go in two config and default engine or any go ahead and open that up and you
don't have to remove any of the stuff that you've done here.
All you've got to do is change the.
Be enabled property of the online subsystems steam from true to false.
And that does everything they won't need the no steam argument on the command line.
If we go and open up power shell we aren't going to open up to game instances here.
Then we should be able to see each other and see that it's not using the sub theme subsystem any more
it should be using null automatically.
Notice that with the command line option I gave it.
I didn't give it the no steam option there.
So it works entirely without that so on one of these games I'm going to be the host and all stand on
the cube in my usual presenting position and I'm going to go up to find the other menu and hit join.
And one thing we can do is verify in the logs that we aren't using steam by going and having a look
and seeing it so steam API disabled and all said that it found the subsystem null and sure enough here
in the menu we have got the line the line that we're expecting and go ahead and join it and there is
my character presenting himself on the cube to me so we're going to close down these two games and that
has successfully disabled seams.
I'm going to leave it like that.
Next up we need to look at the available connections and why they're always showing two out of two why
do we have two players out of two.
While the hint is actually in the way of saying It's called the available connections if we go to game
instance and have a proper look then we've got our current players is being set to search results session
no open public connections.
That means the number of connections that are available not the number of connections that are being
used or number of connections as I understood it to be.
How many players there are.
That's not actually the case.
It is the inverse of that.
It's the number of free slots.
So the way we can work this out is fairly straightforward if we go and change the order of max players
and current players we can actually use the max players and subtract the number of open connections.
So if we have two max players and two free sessions then that means that we've got zero players basically
because the players are the ones occupying the connections.
So that should give us the result we want.
I'm going to go ahead and build that make sure I've not got anything else running and that should give
us the result we want except it won't.
Not entirely because the nols subsystem has a bit of a weird issue where it will not properly update
the number of public connections so you're always going to get zero players.
That's okay while we're testing.
But you can verify for yourself that if you use this on Steam you will actually get the correct number
of players in a given.
Okay so the builder has been successful but I'm not going to go and check it out just yet.
Well actually I am.
I dont want to get you doing a challenge based on stuff that isn't working so let's open up to game
instances and will set one of them to hosting.
When I got control of her mounce Animals that the other one to join.
And hopefully if we can pass this line of text that comes back in just a second correctly it will now
say zero out of two.
Yes it does zero out of two.
Instead of saying two out of two so we've got the right sort of maths going on there but we've got a
bug in the subsystem which is preventing this from happening.
If you are interested in finding out what that bug is then you can go and search the null subsystem
implementation for the words register player and also for the just the number of open public connections
if you look for that then you can see that it's only happening and register for player which is a call
as far as I can tell isn't cold anywhere really relevant in the engine.
And so is basically not getting updated for us.
But on Steam this doesn't happen this number of public connections and gets updated using the workflow
that we're using.
So that's going to be fine.
Okay.
So with steam working correctly with no available connections working correctly we want to go and set
up at text properties to work correctly as well.
So it's going to be my challenge to you you should be perfectly capable of doing this stuff by now.
So we are going to lay out the text in that menu in the server list menu a little bit better.
We don't need to get equal spacing in each row so each row lines up nicely underneath the one below
it.
We going to have no overlapping.
So the problem that we've been having when I tried to do my fill spacing and we're going to add a row
header as well so that anybody looking at it can see that this is the name this is the username this
is the number of players and so on.
Case so pause video and have a go at the challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive right into this.
So I've already got the server row open in unreel.
So what we're going to do is we're going to select and serve and name.
And we're going to enable fill again and we're going to do that for the text block and this time for
the connection.
Fraction as well.
And then with our text block we're going to enter some text that is long.
I'm just going to add in some random characters and see the problem of overlapping and then what we
can do is with this text block selected we can scroll on down to a section called clipping an ink clipping.
We can select the option of clip to bounds and you can see that it has truncated that text for us automatically.
We're going to do the same thing for the server name in case we get really wrong server names.
They're going to be the same thing for the fraction although that shouldn't really be a problem just
in case we have really long.
Fraction numbers.
And one thing that I also want to do with the fraction is I want to go out to a parents and change the
justification to write justification so that it's on the right over here.
And we're pretty much there.
I just want to actually go for equal fill between my server name my house name and the text block.
Maybe less for the text.
So I'll put that to point five.
But the other two are equal.
And we get something that looks vaguely good.
And then the next thing I want to do is go and open up our main menu widget.
And with this main menu widget we want to go and find our server list so that we can see ad join menu.
I want to add in a header here.
So to add in the header is actually really straight forward or we're going to do is we're going to add
in an instance of our server wrote widget which has already got all the correct spacing and I'm going
to add that just above our server listing basically.
And then what I want to do is I want to change its default text to describe what those fields are.
So my server is going to be changed to server name.
And obviously we can do this because we're just going to overwrite these fields in a given row then
this text block is going to be just the host.
And then we've got the fraction which I'm just going to call play as well.
So I've got server name host and players he can save that we can go and have a look at our main menu
which now says something that makes sense.
And if we go and play we'll notice that there's a bit of an issue here which is when I hover over it
it basically has the yellow highlighting want to disable that.
So what we can do is quite simply make sure I've got the money saved.
I'm going to go over to the server row and into the graph and create a new variable called is header.
And that is going to default to false.
Let's compile and check it defaults to false.
Yes it does.
And then all we can do is in the event tick we can do a branch that basically only executes if it is
false.
I'm going to break the link from true and I'm going to hook it up to his head.
So what we're going to say is that when it is not the header then we do all the highlighting logic.
Otherwise we don't bother with the highlighting logic.
So you can go ahead hit play.
See if that works and enjoy many Nat.
Well still highlighting.
Let's check that out.
We need to compile our main menu.
Let's hit play again.
Join now.
That's still an issue.
Yes because we need to select the server row and then check the property is header to be true because
we want to override it for the server row and for the header rather we go and join and now we don't
get anything when we hover over it so that's great.
So finally let's put this all together and check that it's working out once we've got everything saved
and compiled that if we go over to a power channel and launch up a couple of game instances that they
can indeed see each other and they display it or nicely and well laid out.
Okay.
So hosting on one you know the procedure by now we go to join from the other.
Wait for the server list to populate that's looking nice with the head is definitely much more readable.
And there we go we've got a server name which is a bit long.
Then we've got detritus which is the name of my computer and then we've got the number of players showing
up nicely zero of two.
So I'm very happy with that we can click it.
We can go ahead and join it.
Everything still works as it should do.
So I'm very happy that that server list is working functionally you can test it yourself over steam.
Little challenge to your little extra challenge.
But the play number is actually updating it correctly and will look at putting a more meaningful server
name in in the next lecture.