Welcome.
In this lecture we are going to be looking at how we can add timeouts to our lobby so he can see or
increase my maximum number of players to five.
And there is one active as we have been able to do in the last lecture.
Well if I go into this lobby now you will notice that I am actually in the lobby with the other player.
But after 10 seconds has elapsed then we all get transferred over into the game.
So this allows a little bit of leeway in terms of how many players join in.
We could be up to five players if they're quick and if they all join in that 10 seconds or it could
just be the two players required to play the game and we're going to look at how to implement that session
timeout mechanic.
But we're also going to be looking at how we can make sure that once the session has started we aren't
going to get new players popping in late to the game.
Let's dive in.
So now that we have fixed the bug that was present in the last lecture we were able to get the number
of players that is required in our session.
You'll find that there's no way of moving on from the lobby because no more than two people can be in
the lobby at the same time because you won't find the game when it's at maximum capacity.
So the first thing we want to do is update the maximum number of players in our game.
This is very very easy to follow along with me.
Let's go to the puzzle platforms game instance and go and look for where we are creating our session.
So it's going to be here in create session.
We can see that the number of public connections is two.
Now what I want to do is add some leeway for more people to join than just the three that are required
to move on from the lobby and that is going to just be done by having five public connections.
And we will make it such that there is a time out when people hope for more than three people have joined
so three people have joined they can go on and play after five seconds but then we want to allow for
other people to be joining in that time span.
At the end of the timespan we want to close down the window for new people to join into the lobby and
everyone moves on who has who has joined the game already.
So that's the aim he says.
We're going to create a we've increased the number of connections so I'm going to go ahead build that
and just check that we can get what we want which is that we can get more work and get three people
into the game and we can move on from the lobby.
Okay so the compile as successfully completed Let's go and launch up a few game instances and get them
to connect.
Specifically on going to launch up a one of em to launch up to and I'm going to launch up fabbri game
instances.
So in the first game instance let's be the host typing in any old name that we want and I will start
there I am.
I am in the lobby.
OK.
Now what about arse second and third game instance.
I'm going to go ahead and hit join for both of those.
And here is the server.
Let's go ahead.
We can see that it's one of five players now because we've updated the number of players I'm going to
go and join in.
And I'm going to check that the other doods there yes he is sorry he's just hiding from me.
And then with the third game instance let's go ahead and join that server too.
It's now saying there's one of five players.
I think that's because I had not refreshed the menu if I go and hit join again.
Hopefully the menu will refresh.
Which it has done.
And now you can see that there are two of five players in the game which is perfect as the bug that
we solved.
Let's go ahead and join that game.
And they'll go.
Everybody has joined in to the main third person Matt.
We want to be able to do is have a bit of a five or 10 second delay where a fourth person could join
in there as well.
So let's go ahead and shut down these instances.
All three.
There we go.
They are all shut down.
That's my time tracking.
It's just a showing there in the background telling me that I am working on the right things.
Okay so let's carry on to actually getting that session time out working.
We can do this in C++ and it has to be in the game mode because that's what's currently starting our
third person session.
So let's go and find our lobby game mode which is game mode C++ at the root of vassie plus plus hierarchy.
And as you can see here we have got a we're doing a world server travel as you will probably remember
when we have more than three players.
What I want to do is that when we have more than three players we start a timer which will trigger the
world server travel.
Now if you haven't seen how this is done before let me just show you.
This piece of documentation on game play time is which is in your resources has everything you need
to manage your time as there is a class called F timer manager which you can get hold of with a global
call here which says Get world time a manager and then you can do things like set timers on it and it
takes in something call well an hour parameter here which is the timer handle which allows you to clear
the timer if you later need to and it takes in whether how long to wait and whether this is a repeating
timer.
So whether it should repeatedly call this function.
And the first delay and the subsequent intervals is basically what it's telling us but you can find
all that from the documentation for yourself and then it calls a delegate.
So that's all pretty straightforward you could easily set this up for yourself.
I'm going to ask you to do it as part of your choice.
Given that we're quite late on in the course this is going to be quite a sizable challenge.
Not huge though not huge at all.
You going to start the game on time.
The idea here is that you are going to use the time manager and try and figure out how you can use that.
It's fairly easy fairly well documented so you should have no problem whatsoever then wait for X players
to join X is totally up to you whether it's three in my case or two or four up to game play choice and
depends how many friends you have.
If you are very popular you might want 15 players who are less popular you might just want to and so
on.
Then get the games started after y second so again that depends how long you want to leave for other
people to join potentially and then you can go ahead and call start session on the session interface
which is going to have the side effect of making sure that others can't join.
Now you'll have to check that that is indeed the case that no one else can see your session any more
and can't be joined.
But that start session should do the trick so give it a shot.
Pause the video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive in and see if we can figure out how to use these timer managers shall we.
So the first things first we need to call this get time manager.
So that's what I'm going to do over in my C++ in place of.
So where we'd previously been calling this world thing before that I'm going to do a get to time a manager
and then I go and do get time and a dot.
Nothing is coming out here.
Now why is that.
Because we have an incomplete type.
So you folks probably know how to deal with these incomplete types.
By now we are talking about the timer Manager API.
So there's even a link from this page to the EFT type of manager.
AP I am going to go ahead and scroll right down to the bottom where hopefully sure enough there is a
header file for me to include I'm going to include the bit after Publicly though the whole thing would
work too and I'm going to put it in underneath my include lobby game mode.
So it's going to be include and then I'm just to paste in that head a file that should remove an incomplete
type errors.
Now what would we be doing next.
Well we can have a look at the API for each time a manager can't we.
We should be setting a timer.
That's the thing I'm looking for as a few options for set time that we can take in with basically all
of them take an F timer handle this out parameter thing in our parameter and what do we do with it.
So we basically all of them seem to take in different types of delegates but the other arguments seem
to stay the same.
And I think the one we want is that takes in a user class and then takes in a function of some sort
so that we can just patin this and the function.
I think that's the top one we can have a look at.
Not this one back.
We want the very top one.
Which takes in a pointer to an object which in our case is going to be this and then it takes this type
name f timer.
Delegate method type.
Basically And we can see in the example code here how it works and what the.
That the time basically doesn't take any arguments at all which makes sense because if we're responsible
for setting up the timer here we have all the data that we need.
We don't need to attach any more data to this timer and we wouldn't be getting any data back from the
system because we've set off the timer ourselves.
OK so enough talking about it.
Let's go in and get it done so I'm going to go ahead and create a thing for us to call that will allow
us to start the game so I'm going to go over to the head of file with that control K control o in Visual
Studio and I'm going to create a private method because we're only calling it from within here and it's
going to return void and it going to call it start game.
Like so.
And then start a game.
And we are going to go over into the C++ and implement this I'm and do it after log out because logout
could happen before we start again.
And then I'm going to implement them.
Body and the body were just going to take from.
Our post log in where we are getting hold of the world and then on the world we are doing a server travel
to the game.
So that's what we want to call.
After a certain time out so we get our timer manager and we need to do set timer.
And then what are we going to be passing it.
Let's go and have a look at the arguments.
The first thing is this timer handle which we know to be of.
Type f timer handle and it is a an out parameter so we kind of want this to live on the class because
it needs to exist between methods if we want to later try and cancel it.
Between.
Between it starting and finish we might want to cancel it when somebody logs out for example.
I'm not going to do that straight away but that is a possibility.
So we're going to want to implement this f timer handle.
As a member variable.
So let's go up to the head of file again in under privat and do it just above.
Start a game.
In fact on a dip below our game because we've got our other member variable in there but the number
of players and I think I'll do it even below that.
So it's going to be an F timer handle.
And we are going to just call this game start timer.
Like so.
And that means that I can just pass game start time as the first argument to my set timer.
Then I need to pass the pointer to this and then I need to pass the address of the start game function
to do with the address of operator.
And be fully qualified.
A start game then then we need to specify the first delay the amount of time in basically till the first
note first the in rate.
This is showing the wrong signature here in Visual Studio which can happen.
Let's try and find it.
Go for the one we want.
Is the in rate.
So we are going to pass.
How many seconds.
Basically until we execute this timer which in my case I'm going to go for 5 seconds and then whether
I want it to loop or not.
Well the default is false and there is a first delay already so I'm not going to pass any of those which
should automatically mean that after 5 seconds start game will be called from the call to this set.
Tyler I'm happy with that.
Let's go ahead and build it and see if it actually works.
Well least the build worked.
Let's go over and start up some instances.
In particular when I start up three instances so we can get three people joining in fact that reminds
me I actually want to change the number of people to not going to rebuild for this for this instance
but in future I want to have just two people so that I can test it out with fewer people and few instances
and less load on my system.
So here are the games.
Let's go ahead and host in and one of them and we're going to go over to the others and we are going
to join in those.
So first member who can see that there is one player currently there so let's join and or go over to
number two.
Jolene.
As you can see there are two players.
Here we are.
We've joined.
And he can actually see the lobby for a while hopefully for about five seconds and then boom we have
moved it on into the game which means that somebody else could have joined in that intervening time
does feel like a little bit of a short time for other people to join so I'm going to go ahead and close
this down and increase my timeout to about 10 seconds.
And I've got two players so we're going to be easier to test like that and the next thing we want to
do is actually start the session so that once the game is in progress no one else is going to be able
to see that there is a session there to join.
It's no longer available even though the maximum number of players was five.
If you've already started the session no more no more game for anybody else.
So the way we're going to do this is that the game instances where we're calling everything on the session
interface already.
So I'm going to expose a public method from the game instance and we are going to call it.
So let's get the game instance C++ file open and we're going to create a public method here which is
going to be something along the lines of start a session.
So I'm going to do this.
I've got hosed we've got join and then we can just have a void start.
Or start sessional star games start session.
I think I'll call it that need to take any arguments because we've only got one session that we could
possibly want to start.
It's copy that go back into the C++ file for the game instance and we find we've got create sesshin
we've got refresh server list.
I think I'm going to do it after all of this and probably just before load main menu.
So let's and a namespace to that.
And let's add a body to that method.
And a namespace wasn't quite a colon code on it was a bit bizarre.
So let's go ahead and add something into this body it should be fairly straightforward we just want
to do an if session interface.
Dot is valid.
Then we want to go ahead and we want to session interface arrow.
And you're found in the documentation for start session that it just takes the session name which is
handly in our constant at the top of the file so I'm going to copy it called session name and I am going
to paste that thing and it's really as simple as that that's all you need to do to go ahead and start
a session opes have started building.
I mean that's okay but it's not fully complete yet anyway.
So astarte session we are going to now try and call from the game instance.
So we need to get hold of it in our.
No sorry not the game instance in the game mode and the C++ So we need to get hold of it in here.
So once we've done our server travel or before we've done our server travel even we want to go ahead
and get hold of the current game instance and cast it to a puzzle platforms game instance and then call
the method on it.
So how do we do all of that.
Well fortunately the game mode actually has a method on it called Get game instance which is very easy
and convenient for us and that's going to get hold of a game instance of the generic game new game instance
type which is useful but not the best thing in the world.
Now the reason we've got these get game instance type is because our game mode actually inherits from
actor an actor has this get game is this type very convenient for us.
So what I'm going do is I'm going to include the head of file for our puzzle platforms game instance
dot H.
And that is going to allow us to use that type of puzzle platform game instance and also know what functions
are on there.
So it's not an incomplete type so that we can call things like We want to.
So now that we got a game instance what I want to do is cast that game instance which we've used before
to do something like to cast it to see see if I can get auto complete to do it for me.
So the main brackets I'm going to have the game instance in the angle brackets.
I'm going to look for a puzzle platform.
Not the game mode but should be the game.
Instance should be in here somewhere.
Yeah you puzzle platform game instance is a type we're trying to cast to now remember I said that we
use auto when there is going to be a lot of repetition here.
That's at least what I like to do and I'm going to call this the game instance.
And if I hover over auto It should tell me what the inferred type is it says classic you puzzle platform
game instance I'm fairly sure that's going to be a pointer.
It will have inferred that it's a pointer because what we gain back from get game instance is a pointer.
So that means that we need to check if it is not only going to an IF game instance.
Let's see equals null pointer.
Then I'm just going to return from here.
Mike so.
And otherwise we can go ahead and start the session so we can say game instance arrow.
Start.
Session.
Fantastic So that's past the start session up to the game instance where it then called it on its session
in object and now we can go ahead and build and we want to fire up some game instances after it's built
to test it.
So build succeeded.
Let's go ahead and launch up a three game instances because I want to go ahead and add in Freeplay is
simultaneously into this game.
That's one more than the time out.
Then I want to show you if we launch up a fourth game instance that once they've moved across they will
no longer be visible some simultaneously showing you that it is visible even when you've got more than
the two required players.
But that is not visible once we've called Start session.
So let's go ahead and host in one I will go into the other two and load up the join menu so I can make
them join in quick succession.
So before the 10 second time out and then in the first one I'm going to go ahead and join in the second
one.
I'm going to go ahead and join switches before the timeout so we're all in here time should have started
on the second player and then we are going to move across after the 10 second timeout while they are
doing that are they go.
They've all moved across in one go.
While we are doing that we can go over and launch another game instance and I want to show you that
its join menu its fine menu is actually going to be empty.
So lets go ahead and hit join and look at what comes up.
Now no matter how long I wait that session is not going to come up anymore because it has been marked
as in progress and so is no longer joinable.
That's true.
The Null subsystem but it's also true of steam you can test that out for yourself by re-enable ing steam
and that's definitely something I recommend you do because at this point this section of steam connection
is done you are able to connect to steam.
Your able to do all the lobbying mechanics you are able to mark the session as in progress as the end
of dealing with sessions.
Now we can really deal with the meat in the next section so there might be a few more lectures of tidying
up that get added later but for now this is the main subject of what we wanted to do.
Congratulations pat ourselves on the back.
Steam is now working and I'll see you in the next lectures.