Welcome to the end of the season multiplayer section and what a fun section it's been.
Right.
We've been able to go from only connecting overland and v.p Ends and messing around with UI.
And we've got it to the stage where we actually are connecting over the Internet with people you know
we can put it out there on Facebook.
We can put this game out there on it and let people play the game without having to have any funky coupland's
that we're amateur any command line stuff.
And it's a big step.
Big step to be able to connect that way.
So I'm really excited to see what you guys come up with with just the abilities that we've got so far
we've got a lot we can do with game play.
I want to see what games you design.
I want to see you playing them with each other and I want to see different lobbying mechanics maybe
different game mode mechanics and things like that and use your knowledge from this section just go
a little bit further and share in the community website share on Facebook group share in discord and
get playing with friends and see what the experiences get.
Game play testing.
Yeah basically that's my challenge to you.
Go out there and create something novel and play it with other people.