Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be looking at how we can create our own movement mechanics using a very rudimentary
physics engine where we're going to simulate some forces and some accelerations going to revise all
that Forces and acceleration stuff from scratch.
So don't worry if you're very rusty on your physics and I am going to end up with something that can
accelerate the car like so and can decelerate the car like so or very close to hitting the wall hand
and go on and decelerate back in the opposite direction as well.
Okay so let's dive in and see how we can achieve that kind of behaviour with the pseudo physics engine.
Let's dive in and find.
So our car is currently a little bit unrealistic as you can see going backwards and forwards.
It instantly accelerates and reaches its acceleration maximum and doesn't go anywhere from there.
We want to make this a little bit more realistic and make it more realistic.
We need to get a bit more of an understanding of physics and how physics would actually make this work.
So let's start off by a quick revision of forces in physics and how they work now.
For some of you this you may know very very well off by heart but doesn't hurt to do a bit revision.
So let's have a talk about how things move here.
We've got a nice little porsh and we're going to be attempting to make this port move by putting our
foot down on the accelerator.
So what will happen when we put our foot down on the accelerator is that the engine will create a force
and we denote forces by arrows just like vectors.
They are they have direction and they have magnitude.
So this is a vector going forwards and it has a certain magnitude indicated by the size of this arrow.
So this is a force but the force itself does not cause the movement.
The force is the first step in that chain.
The next thing is that the force will create an acceleration in the car and the acceleration will create
a velocity which it then moves the car.
So was the relationship between our force and which were gonna use call F and our acceleration which
we can call a while as a simple relationship.
It's called F equals M times a.
So F being the force M being the mass of the object moving and a being the acceleration that comes out
of it.
Obviously the acceleration coming out of it in this equation.
It kind of is a bit topsy turvy so we can rearrange the equation to say that acceleration is equal to
a force divided by the mass.
So the heavier your object is the smaller the acceleration will be from the same force.
It's harder to get something moving if it is very heavy.
That obviously makes sense.
You can easily push a feather very very hard to push a tank.
You need require more force to get the same acceleration which is basically what these two equations
say.
So how does then the acceleration translate into an actual movement of the car.
Well we've already said the following.
We said that delta x over Delta T equals V where X is the movement then the location in space v is the
velocity.
Now you may not recognize it in this particular form because if we rearrange the equation what we get
is that the Delta X..
Let's actually have a look at our code because we've got this written into our code.
We're saying that the translation also known as delta x is equal to the velocity multiplied by Delta
time.
So that's exactly what we've got here.
Got velocity.
And then we're adjusting for the units.
And we've got a delta time.
So this is exactly the same equation as the definition of velocity definition of velocity being that
the small change in x So the translation divided by the time it took for that translation to happen
is equal to the velocity.
Now acceleration is defined in exactly the same way over velocity.
So we're saying that the change in the velocity divided by the time it took for that change to happen
is that the acceleration.
So Delta V.
Divide by Delta T equals acceleration and so the way we get an acceleration is exactly the same as we
got our bill out.
Our Delta sorry the way we get our delta v is exactly the same as we got our Delta X. We do Delta B
is equal to the acceleration multiplied by Delta time.
Okay so that all seems to make sense.
But how does actually work when we start to translate things into code.
Let's have a go at translating these into code.
I'm going to assume that in tic we start off with a force so it's going to be an F vector force that
obviously set to 0 by default but we are going to be.
That's gonna be your challenge to make sure that is set to something meaningful and in the meantime
will talk about this calculation that we need to do.
So the first thing is from the force we want to get the acceleration.
So we're going to have an F vector acceleration.
And that's going to be equal to the force as we said divided by the mass of the object.
Now the mass here a is not defined.
How are we going to define it.
Well we're going to go over into the dot h file and we're going to create ourselves a new property to
define it so it's going to be your property.
I'm going to make it an edit anywhere so that we can edit it both in the blueprint and the inspector.
And it is going to be a float called mass.
Because it is a real number so it can't be caught using a float and were going to give it a default
value of one thousand.
Which if we take the units to be kilogrammes is going to be about a metric ton so we can add a comment
here just to make sure that it's clear what this mass property is.
I'm going to call it the mass of the car.
And I'm going to put in brackets that the unit is kg so that it's obvious to anybody who is using this.
What size of number they should be putting in here.
So this is a ton for a realistic car perhaps even quite a light car.
And then we'll go over to C++ and that all seems to make sense now.
Okay so we've got ourselves an acceleration but we have not got the velocity from that or we haven't
got the change in velocity from that acceleration.
So to get a change in velocity we need to do the acceleration.
Multiplied by the delta time.
Like so that's obviously a change in velocity what we've got here is velocity itself so to create a
change we just need to add to velocity.
So it's going to be velocity equals velocity.
Plus acceleration times delta time.
And that will work because if it's a negative acceleration then it's going to subtract from velocity
because the addition sign Plus a negative will be a subtraction.
OK.
So that has allowed us to calculate the moving for the moving translation all the way from starting
off with a force.
And that's all physically based.
So this should work pretty well once we have a realistic force coming in and that's going to be your
challenge to provide the driving force and figure out how that's done.
Let's have a look at that challenge definition.
So provide the driving force.
The main question here is where should it come from.
What is the lever that you're going to pull that makes the driving force happen.
What's the magnitude of that force going to be.
All these questions make sure that it's configurable so that the size of the force can be configured
in the editor and test it makes sure.
But it works as you would expect both video and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
So let's go about providing that driving force you may have guessed it the driving force is going to
come from move forward instead of setting the velocity directly.
What I'm going do is I'm going to introduce a throttle variable where we can store the value of move
forward this frame and we can then calculate the force in tick.
So I'm going to go to my head a file and I am going to create a float called throttle.
In here.
And then that throttle value I'm going to set in our move forward.
So it's going to be throttle equals value.
Like so.
And then what else do we need.
We need another you property in here that allows us to define the driving force or the maximum driving
force that when we've got the throttle fully down will be applied to the car.
So I'm going to call it Max driving force.
And it's going to be anywhere.
It's going to be.
Let me create a meaningful comment.
So the force applied to the car when the throttle is fully down.
Now what's the unit for this going to be.
Well you may remember that the unit for forces is the Newton.
So just like that in s are units standard units.
So it's max driving force.
Should it be a thousand let's ask ourselves that question.
Well a typical very fast acceleration.
In fact very very fast indeed is 10 meters per second per second.
Remember that it is the delta time delta time.
That's why we've got per second per second.
Whereas velocity was just meters per second.
So anyway the very fast acceleration is 10 meters per second in fact gravity's not even that fast but
in games we typically are don't mind being a little unrealistic.
So 10 meters per second per second is a good acceleration.
If we want to achieve that with a metric ton which is a thousand kilograms we are going to have to have
10000 Newtons because it is going to be.
Ten thousand.
Divided by 1000 gives us an acceleration of 10 Okay.
So that's what I'm going to start off with a default driving force of let's go ahead and make sure that
builds and go over into my C++ and I want to set our force to basically being that driving force.
So it's going to be the driving force and that's the maximum driving force multiplied by the throttle
value.
Remember if your throttle is off it's going to be zero which means that we're going to have zero force
which is perfectly fine and we're going to have a max force which is going to be as we said is going
to be that thousand Newtons and then what we've got to do is have a direction to this Quand seekers
at the moment it's got only a magnitude it's just two floats multiplied together.
We need to add in some vector amount and to do that we do a Get active forward or actor forward vector
because the driving force is going to be applied in the direction of the forward of the car or in the
backwards if the throttle is negative.
But using forward multiplied by a negative numbers is going to give you backwards that's why there is
no get asked a backward vector.
Okay.
So that has built successfully I'm not sure whether incorporated my most recent changes are going to
build one more time.
So that was successful.
Let's go over into the unreel editor and hit play and see if this is working.
So now if I am holding down the accelerator you can see that it's going faster and faster and faster
and faster.
I'm passing through objects but that's okay.
And if I hold down the back button so that as in the wac keys then I should be slowing down and going
in the other direction I can't quite tell yet and probably see when I go shooting through the torain
in the opposite direction.
Let's let's see if I d possessor's f 8.
I do appear to have just gone shooting through it right now.
Let's go play again.
So I'm accelerating forward if I take my hand off.
It carries on going at the velocity that was previously set.
If I hit the back button then you see it slows down and then starts going backwards and it can accelerate
just as fast and just as much in the opposite direction.
Obviously there's nothing limiting how fast we can go.
That is for later lectures but for now you can see that we are able to accelerate by the use of a force
and we've implemented all of that in our own code without using any physics engine.
What so ever.
So I'll see you in the next lecture where we are going to be extending this further to stop us from
being able to go through walls like we currently are.