Welcome to this lecture on simulating air resistance here.
We're going to get rid of the infinites top speed of the car.
Now you can see that as I'm accelerating I've actually reached a top speed here.
I'm not accelerating any further.
I'm not going at those crazy speeds that were completely unmanageable and believing I still got the
throttle held down.
I just can't go any faster.
And the way we're going to do this is by simulating air resistance in the world so that when we basically
try and accelerate too fast the air resistance will be slowing us down.
Let's dive in and see how that actually works.
So as I mentioned in the last video we currently have a rather unrealistic situation that we can carry
on accelerating until the cows come home.
Basically there is no top speed.
We just keep going until we hit something which is fun in itself maybe but a more simple way to accelerate
and get used to it is to actually be able to have a top speed.
Now this does beg the question why do cars have a top speed why they not carry on accelerating for ever.
And if you've been paying attention in physics you may have heard of such a thing as air resistance
or drag as it's also known.
So let's have a look at how air is distance and drag stop us from being able to reach an infinite top
speed.
Let's take a look at the car we were looking at from before.
We've got a porch with a driving force on it.
Now the driving force isn't the only force that we have on our porsh.
In reality we also have a force due to drag or air resistance which I'm going to denote with this purple
arrow here which is pointing backwards.
Now unlike the driving force it doesn't depend on our input at least not directly.
It doesn't depend on me putting the throttle down and so we provide more driving force through the engine.
No.
This depends on how fast we are going.
So you can start to see why this might imply a top speed.
In fact this is the way that it depends on how fast we're going so if we're going at zero speed there
is no drag force there's no resistance to our movement by the air that's hitting the car.
That's why we get drag because air hits the car and slows us down.
Now if we're going at one then we're going to get a force roughly proportional to one.
So we're going to get one unit of force we're going at a speed of two then we're actually going to get
a force of a four.
So you can see how this is rapidly growing much faster than our speed.
When we go at three we get a force of roughly nine and only go for we going at 16.
So you can see that what we're doing here is we're squaring the speed in order to get to the force and
that is how air resistance works is what's known as a square law which means that the more you increase
your speed the faster and the more and more force you're going to have to put in to counteract the drag
that you getting from that speed that's why cars have a top speed because they have a top force that
they can produce.
They have a search engine horsepower.
And once you reach a certain speed the drag equals the amount of force that your engine can create to
maintain that speed.
And you get stuck and can't accelerate anymore because you've got a negative force plus a positive force
which equals zero when they're equal.
So that's why we have drag.
That's why there is a top speed and this is how they're related.
Now let's have a look at the exact formula for that.
The formula is that the air resistance is equal to the negative of the speed squared multiplied by some
drag coefficient.
The drag coefficient is a constant number which we just use to help us convert between the speed and
the air resistance.
And the reason we have a drag coefficient.
It's because certain cars are more aerodynamic than others.
So if you had a rather large drag coefficient then that means that you have a very poor aerodynamic
car because your air resistance is going to be greater for the same amount of speed.
But still we are squaring the speed and that is the main relationship here.
So this is what we are going to go ahead and implement in just a second.
But before that I want to tell you a little bit about the difference between speed and velocity in case
you haven't picked up on it yet.
The loss of T is a vector whereas speed is a float.
That's basically the difference.
Speed tells us about the dinner not about the direction it tells you about the magnitude of the velocity
vector whereas velocity tells you both the direction and the magnitude so when you're talking about
speed with saying this is the air resistance that goes in the opposite direction to the direction of
ass beat.
That's where a direction comes into things.
How we get hold of speed in unreel Let's go in to Visual Studio and have a look in attic.
So currently we've got a velocity.
How do we get speed from velocity.
Well it's actually super super simple.
You do a velocity dot size because that gives you the magnitude or size of the vector the length of
that arrow and that will tell you the speed it doesn't tell you the direction of the speed but it does
tell you the speed.
So when we're using a negative sign here we mean that the resistance goes in the opposite direction
to that speed.
So it's time for you to have a go at implementing this in a challenge to calculate the force due to
air resistance.
So add the air resistance to the force that we already have.
You can see we've got a force here that we're calculating in our acceleration.
Well if we equal this out with a negative force going in the opposite direction due to air resistance
we want our acceleration to be nil.
For it to stop accelerating.
So you're going to have to add to this force.
Going to start off with this force from the driving force and then you can add some resistance forces
on top of that.
So create a function to calculate the resistance and that will make it nice and factored out.
Use the formula from the last slide to calculate the resistance and obviously your unreel know how an
F maths in all your knowledge about vectors to do that.
Which direction should it be in.
Remember that the resultant force has to be a vector but the formula I gave you on the last line is
to do with forces.
So you're going to have to add the direction component back in.
And then some of the forces on the cart so that you get a resultant force and a resultant acceleration
pause a video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive in and give this a shot.
So I'm going to remove this velocity size that I was using to show you how we'd get the speed and we're
going to go ahead and create ourselves a new function over in the head of file.
We've got our plie rotation and update location from velocity above that I want to create a function
which returns an F vector.
Because that is our force.
And I'm going to call this get resistance.
Which basically says it all don't need to take any arguments because the velocity is the only thing
we need and that is on the class so we can go ahead and implement get resistance over in our C++ file.
I'm going to implement right under tick get resistance and I am going to namespace that.
And then I am going to implement the body.
Now obviously it's going to have to return something because it is of return type f vector.
That's fairly simple so we're just going to do the returns straightaway.
And remember what our formula was let's go back and have a look at what the formula was its air resistance
equals negative speed squared multiplied by the drag coefficient.
We're going to need a drag coefficient that's going to be something that we can edit.
So I'm going to create a new you property for this are after the degrees per second.
I am going to create a new property which says drag coefficient and 90 is not going to be what we want.
We'll have a think about what we want in just a second.
But let's think of a description.
Just going to start with higher means more drag.
That's the basic description.
But what are going to be the units on this let's have a look.
We've got an C++.
We haven't written out yet but we've got a speed squared multiplied by the drag coefficient ends up
creating Newtons.
So that's a bit strange.
It doesn't actually lend itself to any particular units at all.
The drag coefficient is units less as they say.
Actually it does have units thanks to Bill Westlake for pointing this out.
The units are kg's per meter and I will link to the forum post where Bill actually explains why that
is.
So let's go over to our head of fire and think of what a sensible value for this drag coefficient would
be.
Well let's think about the maximum speed and the maximum force.
We've got a maximum driving force of 10000 and we want to have say a maximum speed similar to the 60
miles per hour range which is about 25 meters per second which is the unit we are using remember so
we can work out what at sensible drag coefficient is going to be um going to do this in Rome for us.
In fact let's bring up everybody's favourite computational knowledge engine.
The Wolfram Alpha website and calculate this so we've got our.
Maximum force which is going to be air resistance.
And then we've got our speed which is 25 meters per second and we're going to try and rearrange this.
So we've got a drag her fission equal to the following.
So let's take a look at this slide which will rearrange things for us.
So we've got air resistance equal to minus their speed squared multiplied by the drag coefficient we
can rearrange.
This is a little bit of algebra to be air resistance divided by speed squared equals the drag efficient.
So add drag coefficient is going to be equal to 10000 divided by 25 squared.
Let's calculate that in Wolfram Alpha 10000 divided by 25 squared which you can just do with this Carrott
notation and we'll go ahead and look at what the result is and the result is 16.
So add drag coefficient as a good starting point should be 16.
So I'm going to put 16 into Add drag coefficient there so now equipped with that drag coefficient we
can go back into the C plus plus and actually calculate that resistance so we're saying that first we
want to get the speed.
So that's velocity dot size as shown.
And we can go ahead and square this we can square it with F maths.
So do an F maths curl on coelen Square like so.
But I want to show you that there is another trick that you can use here because actually during the
calculation of size we have to actually calculate the size square so unreal provides you with a little
efficiency function here where instead of getting a square and size square squaring the size after it's
just been square rooted you can do the square size squared like that so you can actually get the size
squared directly so we're going to just make use of that.
That's quite helpful I think.
Okay so that's size squared.
We're going to multiply by our.
Drag coefficient like so and it's almost right except we're not returning a vector because we haven't
added in some direction.
That direction is just going to be the negative of the velocity direction.
So we're going to go for velocity dot and then we need to get the direction of the hand so we're going
to get the normal.
So I'm going to do a get safe normal in unreel to do that and we can multiply it by the.
Floats on our right to increase the magnitude of that vector.
And remember we need to make it negative because this force goes counter to the velocity.
Okay.
So we've got ourselves a resistance force all that needs to be done now is we to add it to the driving
force that's going to be fairly straightforward isn't it we can't do a force plus equals get resistance.
And that should do the trick.
Let's go ahead and build and see if we've got a sensible resistance and a sensible coefficient of drag.
So the build at least were success of all.
Let's go ahead and try it out see if it now works.
So I'm accelerating accelerating accelerating and as you can see I do appear to have stopped accelerating
or not going any faster than this which is quite manageable speed.
So I do think that we are now experiencing air resistance that has counted out the speed that I was
going at.
I can see I'm not going any faster.
That seems like a successful air resistance to me.
One thing I would like to see is that if I take my hand off the accelerator we start to slow down.
But you'll notice that we aren't actually slowing down to a stop not very easily it's going to take
a very very long time to slow all the way down to a stop.
Now the reason for that is imagine that you are playing this game here.
Air hockey you will remember if you ever played this game that the park in question that your batting
between the between you and your opponent trying to get it into their goal basically never stops.
And the reason it never stops is because it's only subject to air resistance very much like a car it's
hovering on a bed of air.
And so it isn't getting any resistance from the ground.
This means that when you're lost he's starting to get very close to zero your force is your drag force
is also getting very close to zero so it's not slowing you down any quicker.
In fact we're going to look at our car you can see that it's still inching its way across the ground
very slowly getting slower and slower but it's never gonna stop because that force is never going to
be large enough to stop it.
I mean eventually will not be able to tell that it's moving but we basically can't ever stop it moving
with a force that changes with the velocity.
So we're going to look in the next lecture and a different type of force that doesn't change with velocity.
In fact it's constant and that's called rolling resistance so we'll have a look about the next letter
and how it will bring our car to a stop.
I'll see you there.