And know and welcome to this last lecture on physics.
Here we are going to be learning about turning circles and why vehicles steer.
And we're going to use it to implement a turning circle for our very own vehicles.
You can see here I am now rotating in a circle no matter how fast I go so maybe I'll make it clearer
by going really slowly you can see that my steering also goes really slowly when I go slowly.
And also when I stop I can no longer stay on the spot like I used to be able to.
And when I reverse I am now reversing in the direction that I'm holding down so I've got the right key
held down now left key held down now and it is steering exactly as I expect so that when I go forward
and backwards while holding down the left key I am steering within my turning circle.
Great stuff.
Let's see how it's implemented.
So it's quite clear at this point that our steering feels pretty Noddy.
If we go ahead and play it you can see that we can rotate on the spot.
And also when we reverse the rotation is reversed to what we would actually expect in a real car you'd
expect in a real car.
If we're turning this way when we're going forward and we start to reverse that we would be turning
in the other direction but that's not happening.
It keeps turning around in the same way.
Now the reason for this is because we hadn't really done a proper model of how a car actually steers.
So to do that we have to understand steering and why we get the notion of a turning circle.
You may have heard of cars having a certain size turning circle.
Well we're going to understand what makes that the case.
This is the whole reason that cars stay on this diagram here.
It's very concise.
So will pick it apart bit by bit.
But it is exactly why a cast is as you can see with a tyre it's you have a rotation around a central
axis and that's the only way you can move you can only move in line with these tyres.
You can't very easily slip the tyre and make it move against its axle.
It's meant to be moving always along the tyre.
So what we've done here in this diagram is we've drawn parallel lines through the axles of all the tyres
on the diagram.
As you can see they meet in a point here.
Over on the left.
That's because we're steering.
Now what this tells us is that all these tyres will move in a circle around this point because that
is the only way in which they will all not be slipping along any of their axes.
So this is actually to be precise this diagram comes from the Wikipedia article on ackerman's steering
and you can see that there's some interesting linkage going in here because these two tyres can't have
the same the same angle and you'll actually find this in real cars you'll find some degree of ackmann
linking.
And the reason for that is because one axle is closer to the centre of the circle than the other.
So they need to create a different angle in order for them to meet at the centre of the circle.
They didn't meet at the centre of the circle.
Then one of them would have to be slipping slightly on its axle.
Anyway that is why we get a turning circle.
And as you can see it doesn't matter what speed these tyres are going at.
They're going to go round in the same size circle.
That's why we always define a turning circle for a car not a range of turning circles we don't say oh
if you're going really slowly it will be able to turn in one meter and if you go any faster we'll be
able to turn in 10.
No it's always one circle.
And if we go and have a look at our car currently when we're going at zero at turning circle is infinitely
small So something is clearly wrong here.
And also when we're going really fast the turning circle becomes really massive and we can't really
turn around in nearly the same space.
In fact becomes twenty's of meters perhaps.
So we want to have it so that the turning circle always stays the same in our car just like in a real
car due to how the wheels and the axles work in a real car.
How do we achieve that.
Well here is a diagram on the turning circle.
Let's.
It's a bit dense.
Let's break it down in bits so we'll just start off with the car and it's turning circle.
This is the turning circle.
It will turn in no matter how fast you're going going.
At no point no not one meters per second you'll just very slowly make your way round this turning circle.
Bear in mind that this is at full steering lock.
That's what we're assuming with the full steering turned on.
That's what the previous diagram showed this was full steering.
Obviously you can have different degrees of steering and these angles will point further out which means
that your turning circle will simply be larger.
But we're not going to be dealing with that right now.
What we want to be dealing with is the full lock case the smallest turning circle that you can possibly
get.
Okay so how do we do this.
Well let's consider how far this car would move in one given second.
So we take essentially the velocity out of the equation and say how far will this move in one given
second.
What is the d x in this equation.
OK so we calculate that we've got the D X and you can see that this gives us a certain fraction of the
circle which is this angle in the middle which we're going to call devita.
We often use that Greek letter meter to denote angles.
So this is the change in foetor.
This is the change in rotation of our car.
Also the amount we go round this circle.
Okay so we've got D X and Deth Peter.
How are these two quantities related to one another.
How can we work out the angle we need to rotate the velocity and the car by in order to move the X around.
Turning circle.
Well it's actually quite easy when you're using radians like we are using in the equations in our code.
Let's go and have a look at where it is in the code.
In actual fact in our supply rotation you can see that we're taking this f quat Delta rotation and we're
having to convert our degrees to radians.
Well this is very helpful in this given situation because then the equation becomes really really simple.
It's simply that the x is equal to defeat but multiplied by it are where are is the radius of the turning
circle.
So it's really really that simple.
Now what we've got to do is actually calculate our rotation geometry we need to calculate the defeater
here to put in to this rotation Delta.
And we need to do that from our rotor.
Our turning circle.
Radius.
So that's going to be the configurable thing not this degrees per second.
That was a bit bogus.
We actually want to have the turning circle radius use the speed to calculate the.
Angle that we need to rotate in this given frame.
And you can do this all with this formula but I'm going to leave it as an exercise up to you to add
the turning circle so make the circle radius configurable as a you property calculate the angle from
the speed and the radius.
And what should happen when you are moving.
See if we can get the right behaviour when you're not moving anywhere when you're moving slowly when
you moving quickly.
See how it behaves and also see about reversing.
Can you make reversing behave in the correct way to.
Okay pause a video and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
Let's get this turning circle moving.
So first things first this Max degrees per second.
Don't need it.
Let's go and get rid of it.
In fact Max degrees per second you're gone.
We're going to copy it and paste it because we're going to be using something like it but we are getting
rid of Max degrees per second.
And what we are going to use is I could have just left it can I.
Anyway so we are going to be using something else which is going to be the minimum turning radius.
That's what we're going to need.
Now what is a sensible minimum turning radius.
Well a lot of cars have a turning radius of about 10 meters.
So that's where I'm going to start at.
And I'm going to.
Change our comment here so I'll call it the minimum the radius of the car turning circle at full lock.
Very descriptive.
And I put in brackets that there units are meeteetse Okay.
So we've got a configuration for Eminem turning circle Let's go to the C++ and see if we can actually
calculate our rotation angle.
So the first thing we're going to need is to calculate x adx as we know by now is the speed multiplied
by Delta time so speed is not velocity.
Remember the loss he is a vector we're trying to get a float out here so this isn't going to work.
As you can see there's no suitable conversion to float.
So we got to do a velocity dot size.
Like so multiplied by Delta time is going to give us the D X. So let's pull that out as a float Delta.
Location is equal to this like so.
And then we've got our Delta location which we are going to multiply by let's leave the steering throw
out of this for now Delta location multiplied by.
And what was it that it needs must be multiplied by let's have a look need to be multiplied by the radius
so it's going to be the turning minimum turning radius.
That's the one now it's the minimum turning radius because what can happen is we could have less than
the turning radius.
So we have to multiply by the throttle for that.
No not the throttle but the throw.
So it should be steering.
Throw.
There we go.
Okay.
So if you have less you might double the turning radius by having a smaller throw.
Hang on a second.
Does that work.
If I multiply my steering throw by a turning radius if I had 10 meters and I had half the row then I'm
going to have five meters so that doesn't quite work.
So if I go back and look at the equation again of course the problem is that I'm trying to get to Deth
Peter but I have multiplied by are in actual fact if I want to take R over to the other side of the
equation then it's going to be D X divided by.
Ah so we've got Delta location and we're going to have to divide through by R which is the main turning
radius and then we're multiply by at the stirrup and throw.
Which makes sense because now if we halve the steering fro it's essentially like doubling the radius.
I'll leave that one for you to have a little ponder about.
Okay so we've got our rotation angle.
Now we don't need to convert it from degrees to radians anymore because as we've said we are calculating
it in radians already using that equation.
So let's go ahead and build this and see how it works so that build a successful.
Let's go over and test it out.
Go and play.
Now if I try rotating on the spot you can see I can't just turn around randomly on the spot without
having any velocity.
Now if I had a small small velocity you can see that I'm moving in a turning circle.
And the faster I go that turning circle doesn't change.
So I now as I go faster and faster and faster I actually get really responsive steering just like in
reality when you are driving down a motorway you have got a very responsive steering and we only have
to try make a tiny change to the rotation of your steering wheel to actually send you flying off the
motorway so that is very good.
That is very much how we wanted it to be simulated But let's have a look at reverse by reverse.
I'm still getting the reversing in the wrong way if I turn right.
I am going off to the left if I turn left.
I'm going off to the right which is not what we want with our steering and the reason for this if we
go and have a look at our diagram is that we've been looking at d x in the positive direction round
this turning circle.
But what happens when we have velocity.
What size is there even when we were reversing in the opposite direction round this circle.
We've got a positive desex when really it should be negative.
How do we make it such that it will be positive when going forward and negative when we are going backward.
Well for that one there's a fairly easy fix.
Instead of taking our velocity size we can take the dot product of the velocity with the forward.
Vector.
Now what this does is essentially say what amount of the velocity is going forward.
And ideally it should be all of it because we're keeping our car rotated with our velocity vector.
But sometimes it will be negative because we're basically all against the forward direction.
Let me show you what I mean.
We can do an F vector colon colon dot product and then we take the dot product with the get.
Forward.
Get active forward vector.
And then we also give it the velocity and this will return a float.
It basically says what proportion of the velocity vector is in the forward direction.
And obviously if it's in the negative forward direction it gives a negative number.
So let's go ahead and build that and see if it gives us the effect we want.
For those of you not very comfortable with the dot product then I have linked in the resources to an
in-depth explanation of why we do the dot product and how it's useful particularly look at this section
on why.
Cause foetor because it will tell you why.
We basically are using it like this in order to get hold of the part of the vector that is a in a certain
direction.
You can see it very nicely with this torture analogy.
You can go and have a read of this as extra reading.
If you aren't entirely sure why we use the dot product here.
So let's go over to crazy carts and have a little play.
So now I want to test out my reverse.
I'm starting to reverse.
And sure enough when I go left I go left.
When I go right I go right and what I should be getting is that when I go forward and backwards I'm
staying in the same circle is not reversing the circle somehow.
I am going to stay in the same circle whether I am going forward or whether I am not going forward and
instead going backwards like I am here.
Okay fantastic.
You can obviously tweak your turning circles to your liking.
You may even want to put some non-linearity on the steering so that when we going faster the steering
is slightly lighter because often that's what cars do to allow you to tweak your steering on the motorway
a bit easier.
Obviously this will be much easier to steer with.
If you have got a joystick because it will give you non integer amounts of steering.
For me it's just kind of rapidly steering left and right and I'm having to just pulse the button to
get the right amount of steering but that is the problem with limited input controls through keyboards.
Okay so that's great.
We've got ourselves a fully simulated car that I'm pretty happy with that we can move forward from this
point and we can actually have a go at replicating it in the next lectures.
You have long been awaiting this.
And finally we're going to be looking at how to replicate it.