Hello and welcome.
In this lecture we have got a client on the left server on the right.
What I'm going to be doing is making it so that when I have my clients selected and I'm moving my arrow
keys that the movement will get propagated up to the server and change the state on the server as you
are seeing here the car that is in control that is moving around in the distance is actually the client
on the left.
Obviously there is a problem the client on the left is not being updated but we'll be dealing with that
later on.
For now we are interested in making sure that the movement gets propagated up to the state on the server.
Let's dive in and see how that's done.
Okay so it works great in single player.
How about in multiplayer if we go and select from the dropdown that we have a number of two players
and we go aimed at who are launching a new editor window.
So we get to game side by side and I'm going to have to bring them all onto the same screen.
So here's one.
And here comes a second I'll come on again and I'm going to put them side by side like so.
Okay.
So I believe the one on the left is at the server.
No it is yes it is the server.
Which one do I have selected.
No I have the one on the right selected.
Yes that's right.
And that one is the server because it's moving in both now and in fact it says off the top.
And if I go to the client and try and move.
You will notice that I'm moving on the client but I can't.
The car isn't showing up at all on the server.
If I switch back over to the server and try and rotate round to look at where the car is.
As far as the servers concerned it's still in the same place as it started.
Now the reason for this is the client is receiving input from me from my mouse and keyboard but it is
not its just changing its own state and that state does not get propagated up to the server.
The state from the server get its propagated down to the client but not the other way round.
So let's revise how this all works and how we might go about actually getting it so that we can change
state from the client.
So if you'll recall in a multiplayer game obviously we have multiple clients but we also have a server
in the middle that communicates between them all.
Now on this server it's authoritative which means that it has the canonical view of the state of the
game.
What it says goes and how does it communicate this state to all the clients.
Well it sends messages to the clients and the clients keep a copy of the state and when the state changes
the server sends out state change messages telling the clients what they should update what they should
change on their version of the state.
So this is how it works this is how state gets propagated through all of the different clients connected
and that's why on our clients we're seeing the server move because the server is updating its own version
of the car based on the user input and it is sending out to all the clients.
Now this only happens because we've got a client that's also the server.
But you'll also remember that when we had our puzzle platforms game there we were modifying the position
of the platform only on the server and the state was getting propagated out to all the clients.
What happens when we want to change the state on one of the clients from user input for example.
Well what we can do is we can actually send a message up to the server and ask the server could you
please change the state for me and then if the server agrees it will change the state and that state
will get propagated to all the clients.
So that's what we intend to do that's what we're trying to achieve.
And the way we achieve this in unreel is using something called arpey see.
So let's get an introduction to our Peacey server functions.
I've got this documentation page linked for you.
We're not going to be using all the different types of our Peacey but it does give you a quick overview
of what our policy is.
It says that our P C are functions that basically are called remote procedure calls and they do what
they say on the tin.
When you call them locally they get executed on a different machine.
That's why they're called remote procedure calls and the particular class that we're interested in is
mentioned here in using our species section and the one we're looking at is the u function server.
So a server Peacey function.
Now what happens with a server ipc function as you call it on a client and when you call it on a client
the body of that RBC function gets executed on the server.
So there's lots of other types of IP seen will be digging into those at a later date.
They do very similar things you could probably work it out for yourself.
But the most important one by far is the server arpey C function because it's the only way we can change
stay on the server from a client.
So how do we go ahead and implement one of these.
Well we'll go over in to our head of file first of all for the go cart and I'm just going to change
the MOVE FORWARD TO BE a message to be something that we call on a client and then gets executed on
the server.
To do this we turn it into a u function it doesn't have to become public to do this and we give it the
key word server.
That means that it's a server arpey function.
And what we also tend to do as a convention is we prefix with the word server underscore so we get server
underscore move forward.
This now means that when I'm calling it it's very clear to me as a programmer that this isn't going
to be executed here it's going to be executed on the server.
Okay so that's one thing.
We've got a server move forward now there is one caveat that by default these functions are what's known
as not reliable.
And if you go and scroll down the page you'll see there's a section on reliability.
And what this means is that when you call it there's no guarantee that it's actually going to execute
on the server.
Now obviously for our move forward function that's no good.
You don't want to be holding down the excelerate key and it's not accelerating you want it to always
get there.
So what you have to do is as well as the server key word you have to add the reliable keyword to.
Okay that's all fine.
I'm happy with that.
We need to add reliable it's a strange default but we can do it.
Let's go ahead and bill and see what the first errors we get are.
So as Quincy went.
Build fails.
The first error in our output log is that the server our P.S. is missing be with a validation keyword
in the you property.
Now this is a requirement for security and we'll talk about that in a little bit.
But for now we can just add that key word to get further into the build and see if it covers any höller
Errors.
So now we see some different errors in the output log.
Again look at our output log you will see that.
Okay.
Move forward is not a member of a go kart because it changed the name.
So let's go over and change the name in the C++.
And also in the bind axis changer in the bind axis two.
And this time we get a rather different error and a hopefully more informative one but also slightly
harder to read so bear with me.
Let's pick it apart a little bit at a time.
So the first thing it's saying is that we can't you define Servat move forward because it's already
defined.
Okay that's a bit strange.
Maybe the next errors will elucidate.
Then it's saying unresolved external symbol server move forward underscore validate.
So that's saying it can't find something called server move forward underscore validate and then again
we've got unresolved symbol server move forward implementation.
Now that's giving us some idea of what's going on here.
What server underscore move forward is is just a stub that we call on the clients in order to execute
something on the server.
So we can't actually implement that but we can implement server move forward underscore implementation.
So let's copy that and make sure we are implementing that.
But what about the second error.
What about this server move forward underscore validate.
You've also noticed that the return type for that server move forward unschool validate if you can read
through these rather terse looking logs is that it is a boolean.
So we'll have a little look into what validation actually means shall we because about time we've been
able to see that here this server move forward underscore implantation that's what gets called on the
server when we call on the client server move forward which we're doing in our bind access.
Okay.
So let's go over and have a little bit of a look at what this validation thing is anyway.
So validation is all about cheap protection it's about stopping the client from being able to cheat.
Why do we need to stop the client from being able to cheat because basically a client can be modded.
It can be hacked.
We can't trust anything that's coming from the client and we can only allow them to play to the best
of their ability.
So what we expose them as serve our policy needs to be really locked down and it needs to stop them
from being able to cheat so functions like set throttle are fine.
You can't cheat by setting the throttle.
That's just how you play the game.
You can't cheat by jumping you.
These are very high level actions which you are allowed to perform even in a cheating game and an attack
no matter how you mod this these actions are validated.
Well basically we'll update the server's state and they'll only update the service date in the correct
way so you can't cheat but functions that are a bad idea are things like set location say enemy health
and kill enemy.
This means that a modded client could try and move much faster than it would be allowed to it could
just teleport somewhere randomly in a level with that location completely circumventing any of the game
logic you could have it set the enemy health to zero because that again would circumvent any of the
damage that the player is actually allowed to do.
So these are bad ideas.
We need to be going for functions first of all that are like the ones on the left.
But beyond this we need to validate though the input to those functions so that the player cannot cheat
so that the input to these is a valid set of inputs.
That's what validation means.
So how do we create a validate function.
Well we can go ahead and copy as a starting point.
The move forward implementation we can change the word implementation over to validate.
And that's here in our logs output error logs I'm going to copy and paste that and rename it validate
and remember that the return value now is Boolean.
Basically whether or not the input to this is valid or not and then we need to return a boolean from
here.
So by default we'll just say that this is a fairly good level of abstraction.
This move forward won't allow us to cheat so we're going to validate to true and that's often the default
that you're going to be going for.
It's going to be saying well any valid any input to this function from the client is a valid input and
they can apply it to the game we can apply it to the game state.
So it will return true.
Okay.
So that is validation Let's go ahead and build and we'll see how it actually plays with and move forward
being replicated.
So I'm going to go over into one real going to go ahead and play with our client and server.
It does appear that one of the two hasn't spawned Let's try playing again sometimes they don't spawn
because they overlap with each other or they overlap with the ground or something like that.
Okay.
So we've got a client we've got a server let's go into our client put it over on the left and server
on the right and in the client.
That's how our clients select it.
I'm going to try and move.
You'll notice that my client is no longer moving but the car on the server is moving which means that
we have successfully updated the state on the server.
Don't worry that we aren't moving on the client we're going to deal with that in the next lecture.
Okay.
So we successfully updated slate on the server from input on the client.
What's next.
Well we want to make sure that we have validation of our input and that the player is unable to cheat.
And that's going to be your challenge to cheat protect the game you're going to need to implement steering
I've left as a challenge for you as well because I've only done moved forward.
I want you to implement.
Move left and right as well essentially.
And I then want you to think of how the client might cheat using these methods and what kind of validation
you can put in place to prevent it.
Implement the validation.
And what happens if the validation fails what happens if the client actually cheats.
Maybe you can test this by putting in an overly stringent validation condition pause a video and have
a go.
Okay welcome back.
So first things first let's implement that steering.
It's very very straightforward.
Pretty much done it already.
In fact I am going to go ahead and copy these two functions from our server move forward because all
I need to change actually is the word move forward to move.
Right.
So I'm just going to change that and I just need it also change the body hopes of over overstepped my
mark and removed the server.
So we've got server me right server move right implementations have move right validation yet that looks
fine and then we want to update the body of server move right implementation to change the steering
throw and we can get rid of the old server the old move.
Right.
And then we need to update the head of file.
We need to put the same new function server reliable with validation in front of move right and we need
to put the prefix of underscore or server underscore in front of me right then we can copy that and
make sure that that is what's being called by our bind axis function and we can go ahead and build that
should work just fine.
I'm pretty confident it's going to work okay.
So that is going to work.
And what we want to do now is make sure that we have validated the input coming in to move forward and
move right.
What could be invalid input have a little think about that if you haven't thought about it already.
What could we used to cheat.
Well for example if we had a value that was greater than 1 or less than minus 1 that would be cheating
because we would be able to basically have more throttle than is allowed.
Remember arthropod values are between minus 1 and positive what.
So one way that I can prevent this is by creating a expression that is only true when the values are
between minus 1 and positive 1 and the way I'm going to do this is with an F maths amps of the value
which makes just gets rid of the minus sign.
So if you got a minus one it will be 1.
He got positive 1 it will be 1 and then were going to check that this absolute value is less than or
equal to 1.
That's basically a short way of saying that it's less than one but greater than minus one.
So I'm going to take this and I'm going to do exactly the same thing for and move right validation.
Go ahead and build that as well.
But as I said this is going to work because we are only ever calling it where the values between minus
1 and 1.
So what happens if we call it with something that makes this expression false.
Well to do that very simply we do have an error here.
Let's find out what the error is.
I know double colon after f man.
You probably caught that.
Let's go ahead and build it again.
And now built correctly.
So what we want to do is change the expression just temporarily so that it will be false when we put
our full furrow on.
So we're going to do less than or equal to point five.
And we are going to build again.
And what should happen now is when we're moving forward everything will be valid when we move full lock
left and right.
Now that statement should fail and we'll be able to see what happens when our validation fails.
So let's hop over into one real with an newly built game.
Go ahead and play with these two side by side if I can get the two cars to spawn.
We have to do something about this collision error won't be.
Okay so let's get them side by side first of all.
So I'm going to have a server on the left and the clock on the right and the client on the left and
go into the client.
And we should see that he moves forward and backwards just fine.
But as soon as I try and steer I disappear and I end up on my own in the game and if we go and have
a look at the logs that happened at that time you can see that there was first of all a get last a fail
reason and server move right.
Validate and then it says closing the connection and you can see that basically the connection is has
been closed down by the server it said nope you're a cheating so and so I'm not going to play with you
and closed the connection.
So that's what happens when validation fails.
So before we go on let's make sure that validate is going to succeed so I'm going to change that over
to one again like so and build and we can be fairly certain that that is going to work.
Now obviously it's not replicating back to the kleiber we're going to deal with that in the next lecture.
And I'll see you there.