Welcome in this lecture we're going to be looking at how we can replicate position and location to the
autonomous proxy from the service over we overwrite its location remove that source of error coming
from the integration and be different time steps so you can see here that the output on the client is
definitely more juddering than it was before.
But this is just a stepping stone This isn't the final product.
We're just trying some approaches and seeing what the limitations of each of them are.
But you can see that for sure.
We're definitely ending up in the same location and position as we were on the server because that's
the location and position we're taking.
So let's dive in and see how we can use property replication to copy our position and location down
from the server.
So our first approach if you recall from last lecture is to attempt to overwrite the location and position
of our vehicles.
So we're going to have a go at just overwriting our autonomous proxy's location from the authority that
is the server now for doing this.
We are going to start off just by replicating the property so obviously location is already replicated
for us by the game engine except for it doesn't do that on the autonomous proxy.
So what we're going to do is we're going to set up our own replication of position and rotation which
will also help us to understand how things replicate in general in an e-mail.
So let's get an overview of that property replication.
So we've got a documentation page here that is also in the resources.
Do you have a read of that you can have a pause and have a read of that if you like to get basis for
this.
Then I'm just going to walk you through.
There are a few steps we need to go through to set up replication for a property.
Now the first one is fairly easy you just add the replicated property to the you property or attribute
whatever it's called to the you property that you want to replicate has to be you property on an actor
preferably and that an actor has to replicate.
So that's the third step first EP is the you property that third step is that the act of replicates.
And then there's this other step of this and get a lifetime replicated properties which you have to
implement and you have to implement exactly like this with this tea array of out lifetime properties
and you need to do this do rep lifetime on the thing that you want to replicate.
Both It's tight it needs to be passed in and the actual name itself.
Now the reason for this is that Ben unreal can cash what properties get replicated and it makes it really
efficient to actually do the replication process.
So let's go ahead and have a go at doing this for the replication of the actors position.
Now what we want to do is from the server set a variable that will be replicated down to the client.
Both autonomous and non autonomous.
And from there we want to overwrite the position on tick.
So that's what we're going to do let's go in to our source and our source code and we're going to create
a new property here specifically for this purpose which is going to be not the velocity but something
similar to that similar position.
Let's see where we should put this in the file and have a little think first before the moment seems
like best place might be just underneath for lost.
So I'm going to create a new F vector.
And I'm going to call this f vector.
Replicate it.
Location like so.
And then following that first step we are going to do a new property.
With the.
And tribute's replicate it.
Like so now we can go ahead and make sure that it gets built while we think about the next step.
So I'm going to go back to the documentation and the next step is to make sure our actor is replicating
So let's do that.
Go into an A go cart see BP and we've got can ever tick.
Let's see whether anything is telling it that it can replicate.
So I mean it should be replicating because so far we have been able to get our replicated locations.
So I'm just trying to find where we've done that.
It does look like we currently don't make it replicate so we should make it replicate so we can go ahead
and do that in the constructor for the a go cart.
MIKE So go ahead make sure it replicates and then we need to implement get lifetime replicated properties.
So let's go ahead and do this.
First of all just in the C++ file and we'll see whether we need to do it in the head file or not.
So let's do that or go over to the C++.
We will need to do it in the header far believe actually.
I've just checked and we don't need to do it in the head file just in the C++.
Why is that.
I hear you ask because when you have this new property replicated it automatically goes looking for
that get lifetime replicated properties in fact if we have built which we should done now I'll go to
night output log some We're not showing.
We are so rebuild showed the log and if we take a look at what we've got here you can see that it's
automatically saying unresolved external symbol get lifetime replicated props.
So basically by having put in a replicated property in there it's automatically expecting us to implement
fluency plus plus we don't have to declare it head.
It has been declared in fact it would be an error to redeclare it.
So I'm going to go ahead and put this replication stuff down underneath.
I actually kind of needs to go higher up in the hierarchy because it's closer to the set up methods
like the begin play and the constructor So I'm going to put it after begin play that we get this Lifetime
replicated propertys And then we've got this new lifetime rep he can see does not exist here.
So we're going to need a head of file for that.
So the thing to do is go over and search for it.
But if like me you do that and get some results there are a bit Incans inconsistent and you can't really
find this because this is a macro it's a little bit odd.
Then what you can do is just do a search across the entire solution to find all that can take a little
bit of time.
But once you have got yourself the results list which is just being found at the moment then what you'll
be able to do is find the place where that's declared.
So we're just going to go ahead and look for a place where it is being defined.
Here's one unreel network.
H seems to be where it's defined.
So let's go ahead and see whether we can just include unreal Network 8:00 am going to go to my C plus
plus five and I'm going to go up to the top of the C++ file and do an include four unreal network dot
H.
There we go.
Sure enough is showing up so we can do our do wrap thing there now.
And I believe the type that it wants here is not the type of the object but rather the type of a go
cart.
So we're going to put that in place like so.
And then notice this giving an error right now.
But remember that this might not give us an error when we compile this might just be the Intellisense
going wrong.
So I'm going to copy replicated location and paste it here.
So what this macro is actually doing is it's registering that this variable for replication.
And in fact this property here don't change the name of that property if you change the name of the
property you will find that the macro gives an error because it actually uses that inside here it's
expanding out to some C++ code which is using the out lifetime props.
So don't go change your name.
Basically that's the name it's expecting or change the name and see how it fails.
Just so that you know and feel a bit more comfortable with the code that we're using.
And with the auto generation that's going on.
So now hopefully that should be replicating replicated locations so whenever replicated location is
set on the server all the clients will see that value trickle down to their value of replicated location.
That's the idea of replicating a property and that's what I want you to use to go ahead and set and
read the property.
So how are we going to do that.
Here's your challenge to say and get the position.
I'd like you to.
On the server set the replicated position then on the client get a get it on all the clients and make
sure the position of your car the actual Get active location is updated from that replicated position.
Test it.
See that is getting replicated obviously the rotation won't be getting replicated all look a little
bit funny.
But then you can go ahead and repeat for rotation so pause the video and have a go at the challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So let's dive in and do this quickly.
So we're going to go in at two.
Tick tick is where our location is getting changed all the time so we're updating location from velocity
here.
And then what I want to do is at the end of this if we have the authority to do so I want to update
the position.
So this what we're going to do I'm going to say if in fact I'm going to wrap this whole thing up in
the IF because there's no point at the moment.
Let's think about this.
There's no point at the moment doing this simulation.
If we're just going to overwrite it on the client so I'm going to do it in the if.
Just like this for now but then I'll show you what I mean.
If has authority.
So we are the server basically.
Then we are going to want to set the position.
So we do this with the proper bracketing the one that visual studio doesn't want me to do.
We are going to want to go for the replicated location equals get actor.
Location.
Like so that should be enough to trigger the replication process that unreal is doing for us in the
background and now otherwise.
So if we don't have the replicated authority.
So in a ELT's that means were either a autonomous proxy or a simulated proxy.
Then we want to take this replicated location and set it.
So were going to go ahead and do a set actor low if I can type akhira.
Like so set out the location replicated.
Location So that's the one that will have trickled down from the server because if we were the server
we'd have got the first hand of the if and if if not then we're going to get this setting side of the.
So we are going to go ahead and build that and see whether that does the trick.
And you can see here what I mean is that here we're always every tick.
We're not the server setting the at a location from our replicator location so it doesn't make sense
that we're simulating at the top here but we're going to leave it like that for now.
Um I'm undecided whether to leave it or not to leave it because very soon we are going to be wanting
to just overwrite it when we get an update from the server and I'm going to show you how we can do things
on updated replication in the next lecture case so the build succeeded.
Let's go over into unreel and test it out so I'm going to go in here and I'm going to go ahead and be.
Hopefully not a simulated proxy I'm not sure why it's saying that I'm a simulated proxy but you can
see that as I am accelerating a round the rotation I am setting myself but the position is being set
from the server which is why you can see it's a little bit jolting but it's definitely concurring with
the server now so if I go all the way around you can see that I am still in the same place.
When I come back to the server.
Like so.
So let's escape from the game and do the next bit.
But just before we do that we did notice that we were getting the wrong name on our vehicle.
Now the reason for this is it's a bit strange because the documentation doesn't tell you you need to
do this but this get lifetime replicate propertys has a parent in the actors that we're driving from.
And we're not calling that super prop..
If you don't call that super property then what we see is that the wrong name comes out.
So you want to go ahead and make sure you are doing that you are calling up to Super.
So let's go to the right place.
Here it is in the gets a lifetime replicate propertys.
We are going to call super colon colon get lifetime replicated propertys.
If I can paste them in the right place and then we are going to do that out lifetime props.
And we are going to go ahead and build that and just check that we got the right name.
So build successful we'll go back into one real and play.
And we didn't spawn Let's hit play again some reason we're having a bit of difficulty spawning at the
moment.
Let's do it until we got her car and they can see that.
Now the autonomous proxy indeed and we've got a bit of juddering gobbing juddering So that's definitely
something we're going to want to fix and we're gonna want to figure out what that is and that rotation
is currently working.
But it could be liable to going wrong.
So let's just see whether it is actually going to go wrong.
I'm just gonna go and play around for a little bit and then hopefully with a lot of rotation and meandering
back and forth and we'll see whether we're still on the same rotation on the client and on the server.
So you can see we're kind of actually floating off slightly at an angle so that's already telling us
that the client here has got a different rotation to what is being seen on the server because we're
obviously travelling in a straight line on the server.
But on the client we are thinking we're in a different rotation.
So that's a good reason that we should go ahead and replicate the rotation as well.
So I'm going to go back into visual studio and make sure that happens.
So going to go up to the head of file and I'm going to actually just copy this.
I've got an F vector we're gonna have to change the vector to an F rotator or whatever comes out of
gets active rotation literally to make our lives easier.
So what does come out of.
Get asked a rotation Let's have a look.
Get.
Actor rotation on doing this in the attic.
And if I hover over we get an F rotator.
So that's what I'm going to use.
So we're going to have an F rotator.
Like so it's going to be a replicated rotation like so.
And we're going to copy that replicates rotation because we're going to need it in our method.
That sets up the lifetime replicated propertys.
Just copying and pasting it for now.
So I didn't lose it in my paste buffer.
And then once we've done that we are pretty much good to go.
We just need to set it in tic So it's going to be the rotation equals get active rotation.
And the set actor rotation is what we're going to need.
On the flip side on the clients.
Set out a rotation to replicate rotation and we can go ahead and build that.
They might be asking why we're not using a transform here.
Well really it's just so that you could have a go at practicing doing this twice.
You can definitely go ahead and replace these with a transformer if you prefer.
We don't really care about scale.
In this case so perhaps the transforms a little bit heavy weight.
We'll see about that in just a bit when we go more into this replication.
But for now it kind of works.
Mr. semicha off one of the lines.
Let's go ahead and build it one more time.
Yeah that works now.
So let's go back and see if we're able to play.
Well basically you should be able to tell me as you can see that the rotation is certainly gone a bit
more jugglery as well is not as smooth as it was because it's not really being replicated locally where
we're always copying that replicated property from the server on every tick which means that our local
simulation on the autonomous proxy doesn't really help very much.
And you can see that's having a bit of an overhead in terms of our performance is not really working
particularly fantastically but it is keeping things in sync for now which is the main thing.
So were going to be looking at how we can make sure that we only update with the advent of an update
from the server which should definitely help a lot.
Because the updates don't come all the time and we're going to look at how to do that in the next lecture.
So I'll see you there.