Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be dealing with the jerkiness of the authority.
We're going to be making it so that when it goes in front of the autonomous proxy as a simulated proxy
we have got more smoothness than we were going to have previously.
Bear in mind that this only getting an update once every second.
And it still seems like it's basically being controlled in the same game world as our autonomous proxy
with just a little bit of glitching.
So how are we going to achieve that.
Well we're going to be looking at what else we can replicate.
So let's dive in and find out.
So at the end of the last lecture I erroneously said that would be dealing with lag in this I got a
little bit ahead of myself.
In fact what were going to be dealing with is a slightly different plot problem.
If I go ahead and play hopefully with multiple players we have two players and I am going to play them
in stand alone windows and you get a two window and stick them side by side like so then what we are
going to see if I drive my old Thomas is exactly what we saw at the end of the last lecture.
That's all fine but what about.
And he may have tried this yourself.
If we drive the authority and have a look at it simulated proxy over on the client's site you can see
that this juddering around everywhere because it is only getting its transform updates once every second.
Every time there is a network update and we can't do anything in between because it doesn't know what
the velocity of the car is it doesn't know anything about this car.
So how are we going to go ahead and fix this.
Well it's pretty straightforward.
We're going to be replicating the velocity.
If you feel really really comfortable with this then just go ahead and try and get this car to look
as me as possible.
But if you're still not entirely comfortable follow along with me for the velocity and then I'm going
to say your challenge.
So let's go over in to Visual Studio and we're going to go in to the go cart dot h file and we are going
to locate our velocity and we're going to make it replicated how we're going to do that we're going
to copy the property with the replicated tag or what's it called annotation or something like that.
So it's going to be your property replicated close bracket.
And then what we're going to do.
Well we know that it's not enough just to mark things as replicated you also to go into the C++ find
the get lifetime replicated props and you need to copy and paste this and do rep macro with the first
argument as go a go.
We know this we've done this just two lectures ago and we are going to copy in velocity as the thing
that we were enabling replication form we go ahead and build that.
So what that's going to do basically it's going to say that when we update the velocity through the
server through calls to the server which may be directly if we are a server ourselves or if we are a
client and then when we get input player input we are going to call move forward move forward is going
to set our own throttle and then call the server move forward server move forward is going to set the
throttle value on the server the service going to calculate things and eventually it's going to set
the velocity and once it's sensed the velocity it's going to get replicated down to all the simulated
proxies.
So the simulated proxy's between their transform updates will be able to run this tick code but with
a velocity set rather than a velocity just being set to zero.
So this is very very helpful.
So we're going to see what the result is.
So the compile completed Let's dive in to the added turn.
Have a play that's hung on a stick.
My authority over on the left and my client on the right and drive the authority in front of the client
say go we've got something much much more smooth but you can see there's still some issues particularly
around rotation.
So what's going on here.
You can see that especially accelerating and speeding up.
There are some jolts.
And we can also see that when turning round especially turning round in a complete circle you can see
it's just going off and what's essentially a tangent to the circle is going off in a straight line at
all points has no idea how to make circular motion because we're just transferring that velocity and
between updates it keeps going in that direction that we last told it about seeing as I'd expect it's
going faster and faster here but the velocity is we're just going off in these directions like so.
So it's got better.
It's definitely not just jolting from one place the other there is some smooth update in between.
But I think we might be able to make it even better.
We might be able to do better than this sort of jerky motion.
So I'm actually going to ask you to solve this in your challenge to make it smooth.
So we are going to ask the question why is the motion still jerking in fact you're going to ask yourself
that question.
Why is this motion jerky.
What could I do that could possibly improve the jerkiness of the car.
Then think about what else you might be able to replicate to improve the motion of the car make it smooth.
And then finally ask yourself once you have made it smoother.
Can I do better.
Is there anything that we can do better or have we reached a fundamental limit on how smooth this car
can look without being the autonomous proxy.
Okay.
So pause the video and have a go at the challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So the trick here if you've asked yourself the question about why it's jerky is because we're just getting
the velocity which has already been calculated from the input throw and from the steering wheel throw
basically.
So we're going to have to replicate the input to the simulated proxy the autonomous proxy already has
the input but the simulated proxy does not.
And that is going to allow us to get as close as possible to the automate the autonomous proxy.
Obviously we can't ever be as good as the autonomous proxy because there will always be a delay in input.
So will always be some way behind and will only ever get the update from the autonomous proxy once every
second.
So we can't be as smooth as the autonomous proxy we never will be.
But that's okay.
We are just trying to get as close as we possibly can.
So with that said let's go ahead and implement this.
It's really very simple.
You could probably do it with your eyes closed by now.
You can put the property replicated in front of both the throttle and the steering throw.
Those were the words I was groping for before.
And we are going to go and look for again the Wherever they gone and hidden.
This particular method kantner were put at the top of the bomb.
Now go get lifetime replicated propertys and I'm going to copy and paste both of those.
We're going to have one setting the throttle to replicate the other setting the steering throat to replicate.
And with that done we can go ahead and build.
And just to reiterate.
Why are we doing this.
We're doing this because with the throttle and with the steering throw we're able to say okay the car
is currently going round the circle until I'm told otherwise by the server I am going to keep going
round in a circle.
Obviously it's not going to be right if at some point in the between the updates the autonomous player
had decided to stop going around the circle.
But for now it's going to be all we can do.
So let's go back into the unreal Ed and hit play.
And stick our authority on.
That left.
And our client on the right and drive the authority around in front of the client and you can see it's
definitely going round in circles.
It's looking a bit smoother.
Obviously doesn't know when I stopped going round the circle.
It does its best and then corrects for it.
So I can see when I'm just going round a circle continuously.
It's doing just fine.
When I leave the circle it sometimes goes on going in the circle a little bit longer but then corrects
for itself.
So with Gore as close as we can get right now to having the replicate controls for the simulated proxy
so pat yourself on the back and now in the next lecture we really will be dealing with lag.