While I'm in this lecture we're going to be taking a high level overview of the client side prediction
algorithm that was described with diagrams in the last lecture we're going to be looking at the pseudocode.
We're going to be looking at what data structures we need and they go ahead and create those data structures
but we aren't actually going to be making any changes to our code per say or how it works just yet that
will be for future lectures.
So let's dive in and see what our high level plan is going to be.
So in the last election we saw very much in detail how this architecture would work we got to understand
it using the graphs that we saw in the last lecture.
But we're very far away from being able to implement it.
So that's what we're going to be looking at in this letter is getting a high level plan for how we're
going to implement it.
Because when youre implementing very tricky things like this I often find it incredibly helpful to start
off with a plan and when we're talking about planning code one of the best tools to use is some pseudo
code especially when it's an algorithm.
So we're going to be writing some pseudo code for our client prediction.
Now you could have a go if you feel like you got a very good grasp of this you could have a go at writing
the pseudocode yourself and pause video and have a go.
But let's start off with a high level and you might want to write the pseudocode after that.
Okay.
So we are going to have a look at the high level there are basically three events that were going to
be dealing with the first one is the on tick event which we obviously know and love and what we are
going to do with the take spend is we're going to need to create a move and send that move to the server
so the move is something new and move is something that encapsulates essentially what we're doing in
this take and can be reassimilated by the server.
Then when the server receives that move well it's going to simulate it isn't it it's going to make sure
that the move is go here and turn it into some state and gersen that state back down to the Clydes then
it is going to go ahead and the clients are going to receive this service date including the autonomous
proxy and the autonomous proxy is going to have to replay its local moves on top of the server state
that has been sent.
And if that results in different state then its going to obviously be in a different place.
But if it isn't then it'll be in the same place.
So this is the high level and if you feel like going off and having a go at the pseudocode then do pause
the video and do that.
But there is going to be another challenge so don't worry if you feel like you'd be missing out on a
challenge by going on with me if you don't feel ready for it.
So let's talk about the on tick.
Let's go into a deep dive into that little bit of handling.
How is the pseudocode going to look for that.
Well step one we're going to need to create a new move.
Now this move is a new data type which we are going to define in this lecture for the challenge.
So the move is going to have to encapsulate everything you need in order to simulate on top of a given
set state.
So we've got a tick at the moment is responsible for doing simulation.
We're going to have to change that a little bit so that you can take a move and you can simulate that
move on the object.
Then we're going to have to save a list of unacknowledged moves going out to keep that move around because
that's Can need to be replayed later.
We're going to send the move up to the server so we can use our p.c to send the move up to the server
where the surf will obviously simulate it.
And then we're going to simulate the move locally so that we're not behind the serve we're not waiting
for the server update before we actually have this move and we can basically have quick reaction times
even with quite high lag to the server.
So that's what we're going to be doing locally on the autonomous proxy on tick.
How about on receive move on the server.
So when the server receives a move it's going to check first of all that the move is valid.
Obviously no cheating.
We don't want our clients to be able to cheat by sending a move that's bogus because there is going
to be more information in that move and there's going to have to be a little bit more trust.
Well not exactly more trusted but there is more ways in which that move could be invalid than we previously
had with our inputs.
Then we're going to have to simulate the move on the server.
Pretty much exactly the same way as we just did on the client.
And then we're going to send the canonical state to the clients again.
The state is now a new data type that is going to encapsulate all the state we need to send to the clients.
The reason for this rather than just putting replicate on all the different variables we want is because
I want to make sure that this state comes down in one single packet.
We don't want to have lots of different bits of state all coming at different times because we need
to be able to replay on top of it.
So we need a consistent packet of state that says yes at the end of a move this is where we were.
So that's why we're going to need that.
Okay.
So that's the server side.
Very straightforward really.
And then we're going to go back to the ords one proxy side where we're receiving that service state.
And remember this is where we previously jumped back.
So we were previously getting the service state and we would just reset ourselves to that server state.
So how we're going to deal with it this time well we remove all moves included in the state.
So remember we've been keeping those unacknowledged moves somewhere.
Well what we're going to do is we're gonna remove all the ones that are now gone stale because the state
includes them.
We'll figure out how to do that in fact it's going to be part of your challenge really is to figure
out what you need to include in the state to make sure that the moves can be included.
Then we are going to go ahead and reset to the server state so we're going take the solar state.
Apply it to our local object and then we're going to replay or simulate all the unacknowledged moves
the ones that haven't expired since that state all the ones that haven't reached the service yet or
the server hasn't told us about yet.
So that is the job of the client.
That's the high level that we're going to be doing.
That's what we're going to try to implement in the next few lectures.
So I have a little challenge for you to go ahead and create the structures from these last two three
sites so you're going to review the pseudocode from the slice make sure you understand it and why we
need to do that.
If you have any questions obviously ask them.
That's the point of being having a queue.
What data does the move and state include.
So what do you need to put in the move to be able to then simulate what do you need to put into the
state to simulate.
Is it like control things go in move.
Do you need any timing information you need to know how long that moves going to be.
Do you need to know when it started that sort of stuff.
How about State.
What does it need to include so that you can invalidate old moves.
What do they need to include so that you have the full state of the object to start simulating from.
Think about these kinds of questions and then create a struct for both and no need to use them just
yet with just creating the struct.
We'll be looking at integrating them into their code in the next few lectures.
Okay so pause a video and have a go this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So we're going to start off with implementing struts So we're going to go into the go cart dot H which
is where we're going to put these structures.
And I've linked this bit of documentation which talks about sorry.
This is the wrong bit of documentation.
The bit of documentation I want is actually in the background so it's close that one down and I've linked
to this one which just talks about struts and it's very simply has some nice copy and paste code right
here which is what I like to use for the struts because otherwise I totally forget all the paraphernalia
that you have to put around them for the auto generated code and introspection and all that sort of
stuff.
So here I've pasted in a code in a struct and obviously abstracts we start with an F usually And I'm
not just going to call it f move because that's a bit ambiguous I'm going to call it an F go cart.
Move.
MIKE So move rather than pluralizing it just keep it singler.
And we don't need any of these specifiers just yet.
We'll figure that out as we go along.
Okay.
But what do we actually want to include here.
Well two prime candidates are going to be the control.
We need to know what the control throw is in order to enact a move.
And if you go and have a look at the C++ and go into that tick function you can see that we are making
use of throttle.
We are making use of.
It's hard to see in here but actually in Apply rotation if we go into the definition of apply rotation
we have got the software here rotation angle the steering throat they go.
That's what's being used to calculate the rotation so that is the move.
That is what is coming uniquely from this autonomous proxy.
And there are some other things that we need to look at that are coming uniquely from this autonomous
proxy which you may not have caught or may not have thought of and that is the time or the delta time
of this tick because remember they're on the server.
This may be a different delta time in the simulation would then be different if it used its own delta
time in its own tick.
So what we're going to do is for simplicity's sake include our own delta time in the move so that when
the server simulator it knows how long to simulate it for and it gets the same result or as close as
possible the same result as we did.
So we will minimize the risk of us jumping around in the world.
So let's go over to our move and start building it up.
So the first thing to copy is actually these throw and the steering throw So the throttle and the steering
very sorry.
And we're going to be those with the new properties because we do want these to be you propertys inside
our go cart move so they are properly represented in the ED and all that sort of jazz.
So we'll be happy with that.
I'm going to remove replicated However as we do not need the individual parts of these to be replicated.
So we've got a throttle.
You've got a stearing throw.
We also want a delta time so going to go for a new property.
Of float again Delta time.
And there is one more thing that we're going to want to enable us to remove old moves.
But we're going to look at that in just a second.
So next up we're going to look at what's the state what comes down replicated from the server.
Well it should be fairly straightforward actually because we already got a bunch of things marked as
being replicated.
Okay we've got the throttle and the steering throw those are marked as replicated.
But their reputation in a slightly different way.
But there may be an argument for that maybe we actually need the move to be replicated back down in
order for the non or Thomas proxy to be able to simulate.
I think that does make sense.
So we're going to go ahead and make sure.
Let's create our state.
So I'm going to copy the paraphernalia above the struct and call it f go cart state instead of the move.
And I'm going to end with a semicolon because that's what classis instructs end with.
And in Him we are going to have an F go cart move.
Called the last move.
So that's going to be the last move that went into making this state and that's going to be helpful
because we all on the non autonomous simulated proxy's.
We're going to need that throttle to be able to interpolate.
Okay.
So that's one of the replicated properties.
What were the other replicated properties.
We've got velocity for example.
So we need velocity.
That's a very important part of the state when we are simulating.
So stick that in there.
And what else we've got for lost we don't need replicate is just you property and we can put you property
in over the F go can't move as well.
And what other than the lost how do we have we've got this replicated transform at the moment and we
can copy that and add that as well.
So we've got the transform we've got the velocity.
And we've got the last move.
I think we are pretty much there set that transform doesn't need to be called replicate a transform
anymore.
It would be sufficient just call it transform because it's not competing with any properties of the
actor like it was before.
Now let's just see whether we think this is going to be suitable for pseudocode.
Let's go and take a look at the pseudocode again.
So Antec create a move or yes we can create move save to a list of moves.
Yes we can do that and yes we can send it to the server.
We can simulate it locally can we simulate locally from this.
Yes I believe we can if we go over to tick we can see that we've got everything we need from the autonomous
proxy side.
We've got our throttle.
We've got our delta time and I believe we've got the steering throw as well which is hidden in here
at the moment.
So we've got everything we need for simulating what else.
On received move on the server side we check that the move is valid.
I think we've got enough information to check the movies now.
We can simulate the move Yes because we've added that Delta type if we hand out the DealTime we wouldn't
have been able to simulate that move then number three we send the canonical state to the client so
sending the canonical state to the client.
Yes we've got a velocity and a transforms so we can send the state to the client and the client can
simulate because were sending it the last move applied as well so it can keep interpolating in between.
If it's not the autonomous proxy the autonomous proxy does it differently autonomous proxy when it receives
the service state instead what it will do is remove all moves that aren't included in the state.
Okay how are we going to do that.
How are we going to remove all moves we've got the last move here so we could go round trying to check
for a quality.
But what if we had back to back by fluke two moves that were exactly the same delta time.
We need some other way to distinguish these.
And one really simple way to distinguish them you could add some sequence numbers to them if you really
wanted.
But the way I'm going to do it is simply by adding a timestamp.
So were going to have the delta time but were also going to have the time at which the move started
this way.
When we receive the last move from the server we can go through our list of unacknowledged moves and
we can check if they are before or equal to that last move.
And in that case we can remove them their old moves basically and the new moves are the ones that are
greater and they are the ones that are going to stay in that list and get replaced.
So do we have everything else for the rest of this pseudo code reset the service state yes we can do
that and we can simulate the moves.
Yes because we've been simulating moves just fine so far.
So and that is how it's going to work.
This is the data that we need to be sending back and forth between the client and server let's just
go and build and make sure that that's going to work okay.
So there is one area that I've forgotten to put this and generate new struct body at the beginning of
the state structure so I am going to go ahead and rebuild that now.
Yeah sure enough this time it compiles.
So if we want to get rid of our redd's quigley's what we have to do is go over into the UN real.
Ed. This is just another way to do it you can do it from the file system as well.
Refresh visual studio project is the one we want which was just go ahead and rebuild the visual studio
project.
Making sure that those struts are now included in the auto complete it will reload in Visual Studio
and then the Reds quigley's should hopefully disappear.
So that's it from me from this lecture and in the next one we're going to be looking at how we actually
start integrating these struts into our code base.