Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to fix that pesky bug that we had with a server going at a ridiculous speed he can see
the server is going at a normal speed.
And we're also going to fix the bug where the simulated proxy was coming across really jolting.
Here you can see it's moving nice and smoothly with the type of interpolation we've had before.
Sure there's a bit of jumping around but we've got it to the stage where it was before if you looked
at your simulated proxy before you'll have seen that it was jumping and it wasn't moving smoothly.
We're also going to have it so that the autonomous proxy is still working as it should be with no jumps.
Even if there is lag.
So let's jump right in and see how this is done so at the end of the last lecture we saw that our authority
when driving around was driving around a little bit.
Super quickly.
Now I'm going to go over the reason why this is so if you still wanted a chance to have a go at debugging
these are self-imposed video.
Now before I spoil it for you but the reason is that we need to ensure the server simulates only once.
What do I mean by this.
If we go into Visual Studio and read through the tick function as if we were the server we'll go through
this tick function and we'll say first of all is locally controlled.
Yes because we are in control of our own car.
Then we go ahead and create a move we'll say if not has authority where we do have authorities and not
has authority or be false so we don't execute the bit inside this if statement then we go on to do a
server send a move and then we simulate the move.
What actually happens in service and move.
Well we call the implementation even though there's no APC required in order to do this because we are
already on the server it would go ahead and call the implementation just so that it is behaving in the
same way as it would behave on any any of the other clients.
And what it does is it itself calls simulate move and updates the service date.
That's useful because we do need to update the service date in order for all the simulated proxies to
get the right state.
But the problem is in calling simulate move because we are doing this twice now we're also simulating
move in the tick.
So the simplest thing to do is to say let's take this simulate move that's happening in tick and just
move it to the place where we say not has authority which is equivalent to saying that it is the autonomous
proxy and in fact this is starting to get a little bit hard to read so we're going to do a little mini
refactor just after we've checked that this works.
So again the reason for doing this is that we want to make sure the simulate move only happens when
we're adding that unacknowledged me to the queue.
Only when we are an autonomous proxy because if we are the server is in control of their own porn then
we want to be careful about doing this.
So we're gonna go over check it out in the real Ed drive around our authority and sure enough now we're
going at a sensible speed.
So I'm happy with that.
Now I said that this was getting a bit hard to read.
Now one of the things that's telling me this is hard to read is the fact that we've got multiple indentation
levels.
So we've got this if is locally controlling and if not has authority.
Well I'd rather do is have a part of the tick that is responsible for when we are the authority and
have a part of the Take That is responsible for when we are a authoritative server or a pawn on the
authority.
So that's quite easy to do.
What we're going to do here is we'll do instead of if locally controlled.
Going to have two separate statements one is going to be if role equal equals.
And in this case we're just gonna go for the role authority like so and in here we can do all the things
that we do in authority.
Now I'm gonna duplicate code because at this point I don't think it's going to cause too much code duplication
and so I'm not too worried.
So what we're gonna do is we're going to create the move we're gonna simulate the move add it to the
unacknowledged move Q Which kind of makes sense and is easy to read and then we're going to send it
up to the server.
So that's what we do.
If we are sorry not the role authority but the role.
Autonomous proxy.
Fair enough.
What about if we are the server.
Well there's actually two cases if we're the server right.
Because in one case we might just be the authority but it's controlled elsewhere.
So if we do role authority then there are two cases.
And how do we distinguish between whether we are the one that is in control of the porn or whether there's
an autonomous proxy somewhere else.
Well that is using a property called the remote role you can get hold of the remote role with quite
simply get remote role like this and it works exactly the same as the other roles.
So what I'm going to say is that we want the case where the remote role is not autonomous proxy.
How you might be saying which remote because as an authority I've got some simulated proxies and simultaneous
proxies.
Well by default if there is an autonomous proxy the room the remote role will be autonomous proxy if
there are no autonomous proxies meaning that the server itself is the authority and controlling and
essentially the autonomous proxy for this thing then its role will be simulated proxy.
So what we're saying is that this local role has to be authority and the get remote role if I can type
it correctly has got to be roll and simulated proxy.
So this means that we are the ones in control and I'm going to put a little comment there to that effect.
We are the server and in control of the porn.
Hi Sam here from the future with a quick note for you about current versions of unreal it can be quite
unpredictable what the server will respond with.
Get remote roles sometimes it's simulated proxy sometimes it is autonomous proxy depending on whether
you're playing in the editor or standalone.
So I would recommend instead of using this expression remote role equals simulated proxy.
You just use the is locally controlled method from up above.
That's what I'm going to say in the comment.
That's what this thing means and that's a function get remote role.
So I will treat it as such.
Okay.
And if that's the case then we know that it's very simple.
What we've got to do is go ahead and create the move which we'll do and then we don't have to simulate
the move.
We don't have to acknowledge the move we just got to send that move to the server which we'll call the
implementation here locally and update all the simulated proxies.
That means that now I can remove this complicated if statement and replace it with a rather more hopefully
simple if statement here.
So we should build this and check that so the bill was successful let's go over into real just check
that we can still drive around.
Looks like we can.
How about the autonomous proxy.
Does he still work.
I drive around with him and go and drive in front of our server.
See does he still drive around.
Yes yes he does.
Excellent.
So that seems to have worked correctly.
Now one more problem.
Our local prediction on the client if we go ahead and play as the server and I drive my server around
you can see that on the autonomous proxy you put them side by side so it's really visible as the autonomous
proxy I'm seeing the simulated proxy jolting around.
So it's not doing that local client prediction like we used to have it do now what I want to do is for
you to have a go implementing that so here is that challenge definition to fix the client prediction.
So why is the client jumping around.
What could we do between updates to make sure it doesn't jump around and go ahead and implement your
solution.
So pause the video and have a go at this okay.
Welcome back.
Hopefully this is very simple.
Now what we've done in the past is we've been simulating locally however.
Currently you can see in our tick we have no if statement for these simulated proxy the simulated proxy
does nothing on tech.
The only time it gets its state updated is on rep server state.
You can see here the set at actor transform is what setting it.
It's also setting a velocity that because we do nothing on tick with that velocity it's not actually
moving because of it.
So we do need to start doing something on tick and what should that be.
Well we could easily just simulate but what move are we going to simulate.
Well we've got that in the server state as the last move.
So very simply I'm going to add in a new if statement it's gonna be if role is equal to role and then
it's going to be the simulated proxy.
So that currently role is simulated proxy up here we've got the remote role.
But if the role on this machine is simulated proxy then we can go ahead and do a simulate move with
the argument being the server state DOT last move.
So that is going to get us the last move executed on the server and we're going to just keep playing
that like we've done in the past when we've had replicated down the inputs.
So I'm gonna go ahead and build that and see if that's gonna give us a smoother local prediction on
the client.
Well it's built which is wonderful.
Let's go over to unreal hit play and get both actors in the world we've still got a glitch where they
don't always spawn.
Let's get our authority on the left the what's on his proxy on the right let's drive the authority around
in front of the autonomous proxy now you can see instantly it's going to be much much smoother we are
still seeing some little defects which we have seen before which is that it carries on turning for a
little while after we've turned and so it has to glitch back into place now that's as good as we've
got it too but can we do better.
Can we make smoother predictions than this.
Let's have a look.
So currently what we've got is this.
This is the path that happens on the server this white line.
You can see we're going a straight line and we decide start turning then we're going to straight line
for a bit then we turn a bit more.
So that's what's going on on the server.
Now these are the updates come through.
First we get this update and this update tells us that we should start simulating that's what we do
with this orange dotted line.
We simulate a head carrying on with that move.
There's no turning information but we do have the velocity so we carry on along that trajectory.
Then we get another update.
We carry on along that trajectory.
Now notice something we've departed from that white line on the server because we haven't had an update
yet that has told us that there is a turn when we finally get the update.
It's partway through the turn already.
So we have to jump back to be on that turn which is the thing that we're seeing in the game if you want
to convince yourself possibly and have a look when you turn on the server and see what happens from
the autonomous proxies point of view and then we carry on turning you see that we're turning a little
bit too far because we didn't get the information we didn't get the message that we've stopped turning
the carry on turning.
And so we had to be reset back in place and we carry on turning and so on.
So we end up with quite a lot of jolting resets which are very visible.
You know even if it hadn't made the right trajectory it would have been less visible than the fact that
we keep having to jump and correct.
So how could we do better than having to jump and correct.
Well we do something called interpolated the client's position.
Let's have a look at how that works.
So we get our first update but instead of simulating right away we hold off until we get another update
when we've got that other update we can start to interpolate meaning slowly move between the first position
and the second position using this orange line.
So far so good.
More or less the same as the first example when we get our third point back from the server instead
of trying to carry on with the move that was coming from the server last.
We are going to be interpolate in between the two.
Now notice we're always a step behind in this scenario but at least we're not jumping.
So again to be interpolated here in a straight line obviously it's not the move that happened on the
server and it's going to look slightly different on the clients but at least we're not jumping around.
Similarly when we get this other points we are going to go in a straight line between the two.
Now you can do some slightly smarter interpolation than doing this but as a starting point at least
this would stop us from jumping around.
That's what we gonna be working towards now.
At the moment our code is a little bit tricky if we go and have a look at visual studio and have a look
at our class you'll see that it is over 200 lines long and it's doing many things it is doing input
set up it is doing simulation of movement for a simulation of physics with all of the fields and properties
to do with the simulation of physics it's also doing on the replication code.
So that's at least three things that I can think of that it's doing and it makes it really hard for
us to keep expanding on this.
It's just got an X complexity that's growing out of control and that makes it very tricky.
So the next few lectures are gonna be about trying to manage that complexity and break this uber class
into a few parts and I'll see you at.