Now suppose we mess up with this file.
The sonnet here he's a a UTF‑8 file as seen here,
and I have the same file there, but not in the same file format.
Here it's Cp1252.
So I'm going to try to read this ISO file instead of the first
one. Let me run this code, and you see that this file is still
read properly. If I check this sonnet‑ISO,
I can see that, in fact, the text is correct and the file is read properly.
But if I add my name, for instance, at the end of it,
don't get me wrong, I don't pretend I have returned this text myself, this is
William Shakespeare's work, with this funny character here,
which is an e acute, and run this code again, now I have this weird
exception telling me that the charset is not the right one. And if
you check the lines that have been read,
you can see that, indeed, this is this letter that created the exception.
This is very important to understand that this code is not
correct because the file is not included properly.
But if it turns out that you don't have any special characters in your file,
you will not see the exception.
So this is very important when you consider testing your
application to pass those special characters in it.
How can I fix this problem?
Well, this newBufferedReader here can take a further argument,
which is a charset.
And the nice thing is that I have this StandardCharSet class with
the ISO_8859 one, which is going to fix my problem. Now if I run
this code, I can see that my file is read properly. So just be
careful with the charset.
Always a test your code very thoroughly,
especially with the special characters because you may end up with buggy code that is going to be very hard to fix.