Before we move on, who are you and what do you need to
know to be able to further this course. The prerequisites
of this course are very basic.
Basically,
this is a Java course so you need to have at least some basic
knowledge of the Java language and its basic API. I'm thinking of the
collection framework, for instance. You also need to be able to write
a simple Java program in your favorite IDE, whether it is Eclipse or
IntelliJ. And, of course, you also need to know what a file system is,
what a file is, what a directory is.
What does it mean to create symbolic links between elements and this
kind of thing. All this is very basic knowledge. So if you're okay with it, let us move on.