Let us try to analyze a CSV file using the pattern we saw.
So we have here very basic CSV file that we just saw in
the slides with several people in it, a name,
an age, and a city.
And we have a person being with three fields a name,
age, and city, and at the end of it,
a tostring method to display an instance of person,
and we're going to analyze this file.
So I've just returned this code here, opening of a path,
a try with resource to open a BufferedReader on this file,
and then we're going to look through all the lines of this file and
if a line does not start with this character,
it means that it should contain a person,
let me put this note here.
I'm going to split this line on this character, put the result in an array.
I'm going to put element, the name is the first element of this array,
the age is the second element of this array,
and the city is the last element of this array.
Now, if I want this code to compile,
I need to tell that this string of characters should be passed to an integer.
And now I can create an instance of Person, new Person, of name, age, and city.
And for the moment, I'm just going to display this person p = + person,
run this code, and indeed,
I have all my people that have been properly read from my file.
Now, this is not very nice.
And if I check this code, I can see that,
in fact,
I am looping through the elements of this file through the lines of this file.
I am just selecting a certain amount of lines,
I'm not taking all the lines into account.
The line that I'm starting with a sharp I'm not taking into account.
And then I am transforming each line to a person.
What I'm going to do is put this in the method and
call that method LineToPerson.
And in fact,
this is going to be a function because I'm just transforming a line to a
person so let me call that function Function from Java.util,
takes a line, returns a Person, I'm going to call it lineToPerson,
and I'm going to say that it takes a line and apply the
line to person method to it in that way.
So now I can just take this and say that this linetoPerson,
apply that to a line is going to return that person.
Let me get rid of this code and say that this person is the person here.
And here, what I can see is that I'm looping through the lines of this file.
I am filtering some of the lines, and I am mapping the rest to a line of person.
So this is exactly a job for the stream API introduced in Java 8.
The stream API is just about that implementing a map filter reduce approach.
And it turns out that on this reader object,
I have another method put lines that is just going to return
exactly what I need which is a Stream of String.
So this Stream of String here, I'm going to filter it,
just keeping the line, do not start with this, arrow this, and then
I'm going to map it with this lineToPerson function,
and for each of those elements, I'm just going to call System.out:: println.
Now I can just get rid of all this code, I don't need it anymore.
And if I run this code, I have roughly the same result as previously.
I can go one step further because, in fact,
on this Files factory class,
I directly have a lines factory method that takes a path as a
parameter and that is going to return the stream I need.
So in fact, this line of code is not needed.
All I need to do is this one.
So the problem is how is this BufferedReader going to be properly closed?
Well, to be able to open a resource in a try with resource pattern,
your resource needs to implement a special interface called AutoCloseable.
If we check BufferedReader,
it extends reader and we can see that indeed it does implement AutoCloseable.
It turns out that the stream interface that is an extension of
base stream also implements AutoCloseable.
So, in fact,
we can put this stream here directly in this try with resource pattern.
We do not need this reader anymore, and thus our reader created by the stream will be properly closed.