First we are going to see how this WalkFileTreePattern is working.
So, just for the sake of this example,
I created under this files folder are all the hierarchy of
folders and subfolders where the files are.
There are audio files, images, and videos.
They are all empty.
There is absolutely no content in those files.
They are just here so that we can see how this
WalkFileTreePattern is going to work.
So, we are going to explore this file hierarchy.
And for that, we have this factory method from the Files class,
which is called walkFileTree.
It takes the path that has to be visited as a parameter.
Hopefully this path is a directory.
And by the way, we could check that,
Files.isDirectory and pass this path as a parameter.
Print out the result.
Let me put this in a variable like this.
Print the result.
Indeed, this is a directory, so we can carry on.
So, walkFileTree takes a FileVisitor as a parameter.
So, we are going to create this FileVisitor.
It's a FileVisitor of Path.
And this walkFileTree throws an exception.
So let me just throw this exception from the main method.
This is really something you should never do, but here it's just
an example so there's nothing wrong with it.
And we are going to implement this FileVisitor.
This FileVisitor is an interface, so we need to implement it.
And you can see that there is a bunch of methods we implement.
Let me reformat stuff so that you can see everything.
We are not going to implement all of them because not all of them
are necessarily needed in all the applications.
For instance,
preVisitDirectory is just something that is called before
entering a directory and giving you the possibility to
visit that directory or not.
Since we want to visit everything we are going to return this constant,
CONTINUE, meaning that indeed this directory is going to be visited.
And we are going to do the same for the postVisitDirectory,
which is there, which is a callback that is called once you exit a directory.
This visitFileFailed,
we do not expect this method to fail so we are not
going to take it into account.
And FileVisitResult is going to be called every time we are visiting a file.
Let us, for instance, create a count inside this FileVisitor,
private long count = 0L, return FileVisitResult.CONTINUE.
So now our visitor is going to be called.
And once it is done visiting our hierarchy,
I would just like to display this visitor.count.
And this is not going to work because the FileVisitor interface,
of course, does not define this variable.
But if I say that this visitor is in fact a var,
tell the compiler that this is a FileVisitor of Path,
it is going to infer the type of this visitor and get
the visibility on this count variable.
So if I run this code,
indeed it will tell me that I have 16 files in my directory.
I could do something more because this count here is a count of the files, but I
could also add a count of the directories. And in the preVisitDirectory, just
increment that, Count files and this is the files, this is the directories. And
this is going to count the directories.
I have 12 directories under files. So, this is basically in a
nutshell how this FileVisitor is working,
which is at the core of this walkFileTree pattern.
All you have to do is implement your own visitor, pass it as an
argument to this walkFileTree, and this walkFileTree will go
through all the directories under a given directory and do whatever
you want using the visitor pattern.
We have a second pattern which is much simpler than this one and that we are going to see now.