All right, I think that we are done with this module.
Let us do a quick wrap‑up.
This module is mostly a use case study,
how to leverage the Stream API to analyze a CSV file. And you
can see that the JDK is not made of isolated modules that you
are going to use one by one.
We use the Java IO NIO stuff to read the file, and we could
connect it to the Stream API to make sense out of the data
that was held in this file.
And this is exactly what Java is about.
So we have one more point to cover in this course, how to move files
around the file system from one directory to another, and also how to see
the walk pattern that allows one to get information from within a set of
directory, the structure of directory.
So let us see that. I hope to meet you in the last module of this course in a second.