There is a second pattern to visit the content of a directory,
which is simpler, which is a walk pattern.
So I just need to call this walk factory method from the files and factory
class, pass the route path as a parameter, and it's going to return the stream
of path with all the path available in the directory.
So, for instance,
I could count all of the elements file on directories. So let me just
adjust this display, run this code, and indeed,
I have 28 elements, 16 files, and 12 directories.
If I want to separate out the files under directories,
I need to take this walk here and, for instance,
filter on the path checking if this path is a directory or not and count it.
I'm going to call this p because I have a clash in my local variable names.
This is the count of the directories. So let me just display the count of the
directories, run this code, and indeed, I have 12 directories.
If I want to count the number of files,
I just need to call isRegularFile, pass p as a parameter.
Let me just duplicate this and return the files, and you can see
that I have the same result as previously.
By the way,
those are method references, so I can just write those
down as using method references, which is going to be much more readable.
So here is the second pattern, the walk pattern that just creates a
stream of all the elements within a directory.
Now you need to be aware that this stream is lazily computed, meaning
that if you have a fine first shortcuts terminal operation on that
stream, it will not explore all the hierarchy, thus saving on performances.