And at last,
how can you get information on a file or directory using this path object?
Well,
you have this Files factory class that has all the methods that takes the
path as a parameter to give you the information you need.
You can check if this path exists or not, if the file or
directory you're looking for does exist or not. You can
check if this file is a hidden file.
You can see if it's a directory or a regular file. And at last, you
can check if it is readable, writeable, or if you can execute it. Let
us quickly see the patterns we may use.
All those functionalities are implemented using corresponding methods.
For instance, we have an exists method that takes a path as a parameter.
And by the way, this method can also take a further argument,
which is a constant called NOFOLLOW_LINKS.
That is going to tell the API whether you want to follow
symbolic links or not on the file system.
And at last, you have a method, isSameFile, that is going to
take two paths as parameters. Those two paths may be very
different in the structure, but, in fact,
pointing to the same element on the disk. And this is what this method is going to tell you.