All right.
So I think we are done with this module.
Let us make a quick wrap‑up of all you saw in it.
Basically what you saw is how to interact with files in directories.
First, you saw how to move files around with very simple patterns.
And second,
you saw how to look for information in a set of
directories with basically two patterns.
The first one is a find pattern and the second one is the
walk pattern with two flavors of it.
The first one uses a FileVisitor and the second one uses the Stream API.
And since this is the last module of this course,
let's also wrap up this course.
This course is both about text files and the patterns
introduced in Java NIO and NIO.2 in the JDK.
So, you saw how to deal with text files,
write and read content, text content in text files.
You saw how to deal with those weird errors
generated by using the wrong charsets.
We saw that.
You also saw how to analyze a CSV file using the Stream API.
And then you saw how to move files in a set of directory,
how to find files in those directories using a B predicate, and
also how to traverse a set of directories,
a hierarchy of directories, gathering information with two patterns,
a visitor and the map/filter/reduce pattern.
And I think we are done with this course,
so I would like to thank you for following it.
I just hope that you found it interesting.
If you want to know more about the Java space,
about Java technical aspects of everything what's going on
in Java, you can follow me on Twitter.
You can check my GitHub account.
I've got several open source projects that you may find interesting. And I
give many talks in many conferences all around the world.
If you're interested in that, you can also check my YouTube channel.
Thank you for watching this course, and I hope to see you next time here on Pluralsight.