Now that you have a client work project lined up it's time to start thinking about contracts.
Contracts can protect both you and the client and what you include or exclude from the contract can
make or break your client relationships.
First of all a quick disclaimer I am not a legal expert.
The information given out in this section of this course is for educational purposes only and not official
legal counsel.
Please seek legal counsel for any questions regarding the legal validity of your contract.
There also might be certain legal requirements for contracts in the country where you live or in the
industry you work in the following example contract and clauses are just a rough guide or outline and
may not include all necessary legal requirements for your particular client or project type when to
use a written contract.
It's nice to have a written contract for each client project but that's not always a reality.
There are some smaller projects where a verbal contract can suffice.
How do I know when that is.
This is very personal and up to you in your current relationship with your client.
A family member or a store owner you have known for years could enter into a verbal contract without
a written contract and be just fine.
Usually that price limit is a dollar amount or a projected total profit for that project.
This would be an amount I would not be willing to part with if the project fails a web design project
that exceeds two thousand dollars will almost certainly need a contract.
That's a lot of money to risk losing if something goes wrong with the client relationship.
One hundred dollar quick I can design someone needs that already knows you well that may not require
a contract.
It's up to you my personal limit has moved up over the years as client projects get bigger and bigger
and now rests at about 1000 dollars.
Anything below that price for the total project.
I try not to worry about contracts of course as your instructor.
I would encourage you to always have a written formal contract for every project you do but in reality
it's just not always necessary.
There is the exception when it comes to owning the copyright of certain graphics photos and illustrations.
You're creating an illustration.
It's nice to have that written in your contract.
Whether you still have the rights to use that graphic or resource or if the client will have 100 percent
rights to use it or if the client is allowed to let you use it in future projects are not.
Now let's dive into the details of the basic anatomy of a freelancers contract.
There are four main parts of a functioning client freelancer contract the contract needs to include
a service that the freelancer will perform.
This will be a full list of items or the description of services that will be provided or performed
there needs to be an exchange for that said service.
It could be cash or an exchange of services there needs to be set milestones.
If the project is longer and if and when payment will be distributed to the freelancer when certain
milestones are reached there also needs to be a stated timeline in which the written services will be
performed there needs to be a written agreement signed by both parties that binds the contract and where
both parties agree to all that's written in the contract agreeing to all terms and conditions your contracts
need to have clear sections that divide those four main items.
There are several other items that a freelancer should think about including in their contract and those
are contact information for both you and the client.
Perhaps a phone number and an address started in times for the project.
If there is a continuously hourly rate contract how long will that contract last.
Or when does the contract expire interest or any late fees do.
If the client does not pay on time breach of contract terms and those defined the actions that would
nullify or avoid the contract.
For example if the 50 percent deposit was returned upfront disclosure on any upfront deposit is required
to start work any other special situations that apply to just your project or your situation.
Contracts can protect freelancers of a client does not want to end up paying for client work or paying
for milestones that are reached in the court of law.
Written contracts hold up better than verbal ones.
I suggest keeping a record of email exchanges as well that mentions prices or agreements or the sending
of estimates or invoices just in case those need to be referenced along with a written contract in the
future.
Jessica Swartz is a blogger over at medium and has graciously shared her freelancing contract with the
world.
I'm providing you with that file for this section as a downloadable resource and writing a contract
from scratch that fully protects herself is almost impossible without a ton of legal knowledge.
So it's nice to have a basic template to customize to your needs.
Of course this does not include everything and is not customized for your project or your country and
needs quite yet.
We're going to work through this entire project and customize it to our sample quote we did in the previous
section and the previous section we landed a client to do a single illustration for a national campaign
for a big coffee chain.
Our quote was for twenty one hundred dollars for a single full color illustration.
Let's get started.