Are you ready to go freelance.
Are you wanting to learn everything about how to become a successful freelancer.
Are you interested in going from part time to full time.
Are wanting to explore this as a viable career option.
This course is a special focus on creative freelancers are anyone who uses their creative skill sets
in their craft.
This includes graphic designers illustrators photographers web designers you ex UI designers and more.
Although everyone get a ton of this class even if you do not use creative talents in your line of work
this extensive course reviews all aspects of the freelancing process including setting your business
goals creating your list of services and finding your target market.
We will craft our freelancing story together to write effective bios marketing copy and write a compelling
mission statement.
We will learn what goes into powerful personal freelance branding will work through the brainstorming
of a local design the creation of a letterhead and business card and learn how to create and use branded
assets to make yourself look incredibly professional and consistent.
We will learn the power of stellar portfolios and how to best present your work in several different
formats including a PDA portfolio and web based portfolio.
We'll even review had a post to work to third party Web sites finding clients is the hardest part of
freelancing and we'll spend plenty of time reviewing the many different ways to secure clients online
off line and on social media.
We learned to write fantastic bios and profile descriptions to present ourselves in the best way possible
to potential clients.
We've been spend time creating an upward profile and learn how to use freelancer websites to find work
efficiently pricing or work is essential to maximizing your earnings as a freelancer.
And we'll learn several different ways to price your work.
We'll go over the benefits and downsides to both hourly and fixed rate pricing.
We'll find ways to help us create accurate and profitable quotes and even work through several practice
quotes to get comfortable pricing our work after finding clients sometimes working with clients can
be just as challenging.
And we'll learn how to create contracts that properly protect us and talk about upfront deposits project's
scope and more.
We will work through a contract together and provide a basic contract as a downloadable resource we
work through several negative client situations and talk about best ways to navigate those common client
issues.
And finally we'll work through copyright issues as we review best practices for using fonts photos and
graphic resources for client work and projects.
Managing your income and cash flow is vital to your success.
We'll discuss when might be the right time for you to move from part time to full time freelance and
maybe even when to quit your job.
We also review cash flow basics and how to properly manage your income from month to month.
This causes dynamic and there'll be additional content added to the course.
And speaking of downloadable resources this course has more than all my prior classes combined with
over 100 pages of written content downloadable in a nice bite size resources that go along with each
section so you can work through the class with videos and resources.
Adding another level of engagement to this course.
Are you ready to start adding value to the world you never thought was possible before.
Are you ready to be your own boss or make your current freelancing side gig a bigger deal.
I am more than excited and proud to present this freelance masterclass to you today.
The best thing we can do as freelancers is stay in community with each other and that's why all students
of this course will have access to an exclusive student Facebook group where they could support each
other.
Ask questions and we'll thrive together.
So are you ready to open up your world to freelancing.
I'll see you in the first less.