So how do you price your work as a freelancer.
We have a lot to discuss and the section will review several different ways you can price your projects.
I hope this section will make you feel more confident not only in pricing your work but also helping
you maximize your profits by helping you find the highest price possible without that risk of losing
a client because you price too high.
And that's the biggest constraint on pricing.
I think that scares most freelancers.
Finding that balance between charging a reasonable profitable rate for yourself but also not being so
high it turns the clients toward other more affordable options once you have a pricing system in place.
You'll want to be able to easily find that just right middle pricing point as you start to price more
and more projects you will develop your own pricing model.
Some freelancers can think of the perfect quote right after hearing a project brief why some struggle
because of the complexity of it all.
Let's review several different ways you could price.
You can start to find out which pricing model or combination of pricing models may work best for you.
There are two main ways to price projects.
We can charge an hourly rate or a fixed project price and you can even use a mix of both fixed pricing
is simple and straightforward just like going to the store and buying items off the shelf.
Let's say I'm giving a client quote for a Web site design.
Once I find out the scope of the project I charge a fixed rate of let's say forty five hundred dollars.
If the project takes me 10 hours I still make forty five hundred dollars.
If it takes me 400 hours I still make four forty five hundred dollars.
You can see all this way of pricing could be beneficial if you're quick at completing your tasks and
detrimental if it takes longer than you expected.
You can even break fixed pricing quotes in a different line items to show the client exactly how we
added up that forty five hundred dollars in our quote.
For example this breakdown two for design and branding fifteen hundred for creating a custom war press
template and a thousand for coding and development with a forty five hundred dollar total so the big
benefits for fixed rate pricing.
Our number one you have total control over how much you receive for a given project.
Number two you can make more money if you move through your work quickly.
Number three the client has more certainty about total project costs before committing.
Of course there are also downsides to think about with fixed project quotes.
So number one if a project takes longer than anticipated you take the hit as you cannot go back and
increase your fixed quote unless it's built into the contract which we'll talk about a little bit later.
Number two it's not easy to have price fixed rates when you have not quoted for that project type before.
It's a little bit easier to price hourly but a little bit harder to learn how to price fixed rates.
On the other side there is that hourly pricing model where he can simply give the client an hourly rate
and maybe a projected time range for each line item for our same web design quote above.
This is what an hourly rate quote might look like.
Forty five dollar hourly rate.
And that's broken down by the following 20 to 25 hours for design and branding.
Notice the range.
It's not an exact number because we're not sure the exact amount of hours will need 10 to 15 hours for
creating a custom wordpress template and 10 to 12 hours for coding and development customizing a store
plug in total hours.
Of course all of this will be projected as a range from 40 to 50 to hours.
As you can see I included my example hourly rate but I also need to include projected hourly ranges
for each item or project as the next natural question a client has is how many hours might it take for
me to complete a project.
Hourly is an easier way to price for those freelancers who have yet to know how many hours it takes
to complete each project.
As you can include a wide range in your hours for that line item to protect yourself the benefits to
pricing hourly are hourly is an easier way to price for this freelancers who have yet to know how many
hours it takes to complete each project as include as wide ranges and hours for each line item.
Number two you're guaranteed to know how much you're going to make per hour you work and it's easier
to manage your income and cash flow projections number three clients have more clarity of how much you
make per hour which could make them feel more at ease.
Number four when pricing scopes get a little bit larger it is easier to adjust pricing for the additional
new work items by just adding more hours.
Of course there are some downsides to hourly pricing as well.
Number one this is the biggest downside.
If you complete a project in less hours than expected you will make less overall on the project and
some ways you're being punished for being quick and effective.
Not a great motivator to move fast and to do well number two clients may feel your quote is more speculative
and it could be higher project cost of the project goes longer than anticipated.
As we've discovered there are benefits and downsides to each way to price.
I usually recommend for those just starting out to start quoting hourly rates until you start feeling
more comfortable with how long it takes you to complete projects.
Once you've quoted several hourly projects you can try out fixed pricing so you can increase your overall
income.
Now that you know what problems may arise and you can price ahead of those issues it takes experience
to start coming up with solid fixed rate pricing.
But it does give you a chance to make more per hour if you move quickly and efficiently with projects.
There are times we can use both fixed and hourly rate in the same project especially those projects
with an undefined scope project scope is the total breath of the project.
Project scopes can change and become larger if a client decides to add a mobile app design for example
to our simple web design project.
If they add new items to the scope it changes and so can the pricing if you stuck with fixed pricing
model for the web design quote and they wanted to expand that scope and add another project later on
you can send them a new quote and start the process all over again with a new project or build it into
your contract clause.
When you do charge an hourly hourly rate for anything that exceeds the original project's scope.
This makes expanding and adding smaller projects easy without having to draw up another fixed rate quote
or contract or produce another proposal.
If the project scope is increased dramatically perhaps it might be smart to start over with another
fixed price quote for smaller scope creeps as they call it are small increases in scope.
Sometimes building in that hourly price pricing is smart and makes it easy for both you and the client
to have continuing work projects that are easy to add on but that comes to my next point about the benefit
to hourly pricing for long term clients sometimes they prefer to switch over to an hourly rate.
This helps them better project costs but also helps them continually give you steady stream of smaller
and larger projects.
If you did several projects per week imagine having to send them a fixed quote for each one of those
different projects being able to just keep a log of your hours and send them a monthly invoice might
be less hassle for the both of you finding out whether to price hourly or a fixed rate is never straightforward
but with time you'll learn what feels best for both you and your client the next few lessons will help
you figure out how to find your hourly rate as well as how to think about pricing fixed rate projects
with confidence.