Already for a student challenge your task is to create a portfolio or revamp a current portfolio.
Your portfolio can be one of several different types first of all you can try your hand at a traditional
PDA portfolio.
You could be more creative with how you lay out your projects and PDA portfolios are helpful in sending
proposals are featuring certain selected works.
You can also create a Web site based portfolio.
I find the best web portfolios.
Keep it simple and clean.
Featuring six or less total projects and a more detailed case study are two with it.
Portfolio Web sites exude personality.
Do not be afraid to show off your unique style.
Another option is you can create a portfolio on a Web site like bee Hanscom or another third party Web
site where you can post your projects.
Lastly we cannot forget Instagram.
Do you feel like turning your Instagram account into a portfolio display.
I'd love to review it.
Feel free to post it in the student Facebook group for feedback and I really look forward to seeing
your portfolio.