So what hourly rate do you charge when you're first starting out.
What if you already have intermediate or advanced skills and experience before going freelance.
This lesson will review ways to help you figure out that perfect pricing for hourly rates.
First of all you have to do the research.
Each one of you will be in a different industry and finding that rate will largely depend on the current
average rate for someone of your same skill level.
You can research what other freelancers charge in a variety of places.
First of all scouring websites like upward AECOM and finding profiles with similar work experience and
studying what they are charging.
I would look at more successful freelancers with higher earnings as those with lower earnings might
find out they are charging too much.
You can also ask other freelancers and Facebook freelancer groups communities and forms.
It's a hot topic question where you can really find open people just trying to gather some data to make
their own hourly rate determinations.
There are also Web sites like zip recruiter which gather data from people with your job title and location.
When researching hourly pricing and salary information online most of these Web sites will gather information
from salaried in-house workers and not from freelancers freelancers will almost always charge a higher
rate per hour than their salaried counterparts simply because salaried workers are most often offered
benefits like health insurance retirement.
That's also a part of compensation that's not in their hourly rate.
As a freelancer you're responsible for all of your benefits and that only comes from your hourly rate.
Hence why you notice freelancers charging 20 to 30 percent more than those salaried counterparts after
getting a good general range for what seems to be the going rate for other freelancers in your industry.
Let's start to get a little more personal.
The next step is to create a target annual income for yourself.
Make sure you download the worksheet for this lesson to work alongside me in these calculations let's
first define our goal annual salary by figuring out our monthly income requirements.
This would be what you'd like to make working full time in our field.
It's has to be based on realistic expectations.
Industry averages but also what you will need to make going freelance possible for you and your family.
For some of you only going part time this will be your goals for how much extra added income you'd like
to add now that we figured out our monthly income that we'd like or need.
Let's figure out what we need to make to equal the benefits from our old job or the amount of benefits
we'd like to have added to our salary.
Just like our full time job.
So let's say I need a thousand dollars for health insurance for my family of five.
This would be monthly.
I would then add that to my monthly income figures.
But I'd also like to start or match my current month retirement.
I get from my full time job so that would be five hundred dollars lastly we need to factor in taxes
into the calculations.
Every country will be different with taxes in the United States.
The salary would most likely fall in the 10 percent tax bracket.
So multiplying my salary not including benefits as they're sometimes not taxed.
If you set up a retirement account and I'm going to multiply that figure by point 0 1 I get something
close to about 400 dollars.
So in my case I round my number up just to be extra cautious and to make sure I'm factoring in enough
for taxes.
You always want to factor taxes in once we tally up our total benefits plus monthly salary we need we
subtract our taxes let's multiply that total figure by twelve to get our annual income goal will want
to find an hourly rate that can get us our annual income goals.
Let's Next figure out how many hours we'd like to work each month.
Let's say I want a typical 40 hour workweek in the world of freelance you can expect at least one hour
each day to be non paid activities.
So instead of your standard eight hours a day for the calculation let's use only seven hours a day to
make up for that one hour of anticipated unpaid work.
Accounting finding clients etc. we would expect in freelancing so seven hours daily and we want to work
five days a week.
That is 35 billable work hours per week and we want to multiply that by 52 weeks to find our total work
hours for the year.
But we want to factor in a few weeks of vacation and sick days since freelancing can take its toll.
We should give us more than what a standard job in our field would give.
If the standard in the United States for vacation is two weeks let's give ourselves three so instead
of multiplying our hours by that 52 week number let's multiply our thirty five hours per week by forty
nine weeks which equals one thousand seven hundred and fifteen hours.
That's how many billable work hours we have this year.
This is a fairly realistic figure.
Our number of hours we have worked to produce money.
We have our desired annual salary figured out as well.
So let's take our total desired annual salary of fifty five thousand and divide it by our total available
work hours for the year which is one thousand seven hundred fourteen.
Once again those seeking part time freelance will still do this but with less hours and a little bit
lower numbers.
But it all works out the same and the hourly rate we came up with is thirty two dollars.
This happens to line up with some research I was doing for beginner to intermediate level designers
and Lillian's local area.
This may not be the only rate we use when quoting clients but it gives us a general idea or range of
pricing that would help us reach our income goals instead of staying strict with a thirty two dollar
number.
We can create a save range we can move up and down on the scale depending on the client size scope of
the project.
Project exposure and project type later on will determine exactly what our hourly range will be based
on the scale and learn how to factor in everything to pick that exact hourly pricing.
So let's talk about our other pricing model first and figure out fixed project pricing.