There are many ways to present your projects and having the right photos can make or break your portfolio.
We'll be creating our PDL version of our portfolio using Adobe InDesign but you can use any program
where you can work with multiple page documents Believe it or not you can even build a strong portfolio
with Microsoft Word The first step in creating our PDA portfolio or any type of portfolio is organizing
and creating our project images and writing your project descriptions.
This may differ depending on what industry or type of freelance services you will offer.
We went super polished high resolution photos that can best represent our various projects to show off
to our potential clients.
If you're a photographer then making sure each photo is presented in its final edited format has the
right color correction in his cropped for high impact viewing let's say you're a UX UI designer.
Perhaps taking some great screenshots of your final Web site layouts or designs or mockups you can start
to think about best ways to display or tell your uniques our UI design process through a series of photos
that document your whole process.
You also want to think about writing your process in a short easy to digest paragraphs that pair well
with a particular photos you choose let's say you're a graphic designer.
You can apply your final designs onto polished mockups.
You can find plenty of great Photoshop mockups and graphic Burger dot com.
You can even create your own custom mockups using a program called Adobe dimensions using stock 3D models
or importing your own also.
Think about writing up brief statements about your projects who the client was so you can give client
proper credits and make sure you note which projects are personal projects if their personal projects
make sure you include a small line underneath the main project title that says personal work so clients
know it's not paid work.
We never want to mislead anyone illustrators.
You can start to take photos of your work if it's not currently in digital format.
You also apply your patterns to mockups as well to make simple pattern projects come to life.
You can include stills of your process at work.
You can even stage the creation of an illustration to take snapshots of your drawing process.
If you're a digital illustrator for example these little shots add a little value to your static projects.
They also add a little bit of character and makes the project feel more real relevant and professional.
All photos should be high resolution.
If they're not then try to obtain photos of your projects that are nothing should be blurry when printed
or viewed as a digital PDA.
On your final portfolio written copy should be written in your style somewhere in some of the things
you've developed in the goal section of the course.
Also get that bio you have written ready we'll be placing your bio in a bit about yourself in the first
three pages of the portfolio doesn't have to always be on the first page.
Lastly grab a great professional headshot of yourself.
We'll be needing this for our online Web site and when we build profiles on other freelancing Web sites
your headshot should be crisp clean with great lighting and also have nice background settings headshots
need to be properly cropped with your face being the main focal point.
Some profile photos can include computers or other equipment necessary for your craft.
This is a great way to add a little authenticity to your photos.
If you know of an affordable professional photographer it would not be a bad idea to have them do a
small photo shoot to gather some of these professional personal photos and headshots.
Now that we gathered everything together let's talk about strong PDA.
Portfolio building basics.
You can download this downloadable resource to read along as I go through this lesson.
Try to keep your portfolio short and manageable.
Keep it between three to 10 pages of possible.
You have to continue to capture the viewer as portfolios that are too long will cause viewer fatigue
create a cover page that wows feature your favorite project on the front cover along with your name
logo title contact information and create a highlight gallery to highlight multiple projects.
If you feel like that can tell a better story to the viewer.
CRAFT AND TELL YOUR STORY Well you want to show more than just static portfolio project photos.
You'll want to dedicate at least a half of a page to including a short bio photo if desired and maybe
a mission statement headline or sentence that explains your unique approach process style visions or
goals you can present this in the first three pages of your portfolio.
Or you can sprinkle a bit about yourself throughout the entire PDA and small snippets between projects
so do I do horizontal or vertical presentations.
Well either way works for PDX that are printed off by your clients or you portrait or vertical orientation
tends to work a little bit better do not overwhelm with too many photos or text.
This is easier said than done.
Sometimes the effectiveness of one to three well-chosen photos can outweigh the effect of a big gallery
page that may contain over 10 photos.
Remember to balance out your photos project descriptions and testimonials.
You will have several pages to display all this information.
Feel free to adopt that storytelling narrative approach and show bits and pieces and very planned ways.
Create a rough layout for your entire portfolio before adding final photos and text is really helps
if you create a plan for your portfolio.
Once you sketch this out you'll know how many photos you may need or need to create for each project.
You'll also know the amount of text base you're dedicating to a particular project or space and how
many client testimonials you may need to capture switch up your page layouts.
This leads to the next tip as the viewer moves through your pages.
Sometimes it's nice to switch up the layout to keep things interesting.
Try not to use the same presentation or layout for each one of your projects.
Doing this may start to make your portfolio look stale.
Each project will have its own layout that will work best for its style and the photos that you have
would do this all the time when building Web sites.
Why not have a layout plan for our PDA portfolios.
We're gonna do that right now.
Together in adobe in design and design is a great multiple page layout program perfect for magazine
layout design and of course creating that PDA portfolio you can use any multiple page layout project
or program you would like Adobe Illustrator has the arbor tool which allows you to create multiple pages
and export them as one PDA file.
If you feel more comfortable using Adobe Illustrator even Champa That online cloud based design tool
I've talked about prior has the ability to build documents with multiple pages including our online
or print PDA portfolio we're going to first focus on creating our rough page layouts.
There are many different layout options and ideas.
I included a handful in that downloadable resource for you to take a look.
As we start to sketch out our rough layout or our PDA portfolio I'm going to use this as a guide in
the next lesson to make some of these page layouts a reality with our chosen project photos for our
graphic designer.
Example Lillian Hernandez.