We're one step closer to creating our visual brand and logo inspiration boards or mood boards is another
name.
Our ways of gathering photos colors textures to put together a tapestry of what we think best represents
us as a creative freelancer.
These photos can make up ones you can download for free online like from pixels dot com.
These images can also be your own artwork.
If you're an artist or an illustrator or even a graphic designer they could be your favorite typefaces
or fonts.
They can even be textures or metallic colors you think best represents your style for the demonstration.
I'm going to happen to a program called canvas they currently offer a free basic account but a fine
canvas great way to put together quick inspiration boards.
But you can use about any photo editing program you choose.
This course will focus less on teaching the actual software and more on crafting the ideas behind creating
our personal brands so I'm here on pixels dot com and there's tons of free photo websites you can check
out.
An A-list set and the resource guides you can find out all sorts of places you can source your photos
for your brand board inspiration.
So I'm here right now in pixels and I'm just kind of flipping through the generic photos.
Of course I can always search and fine tune the kind of photos I'm looking for and what I'm trying to
do is I'm trying to find what I think would resonate with my own personal style my own personal brand
and my target audience.
So I'm thinking about a few things as I'm going through here and I'm looking at colors as well because
we're really going to derive our color palette and our brand color inspirations from some of these photos.
So I've got to think about that as well.
So I'm just going to scroll through here already have a couple downloaded that I wanted to check out
and we could also do textures as well textures colors people anything that you think would resonate
with your brand it doesn't just have to be a photo can be all sorts of different things.
I'm so going to scroll down here when I had downloaded that the white brick cutout that kind of resonated
with the style I wanted to kind of an urban style I wanted to go with and just kind of going round if
you like gold if you like.
You know this is really a personal journey for you figuring out what you think would resonate.
I also downloaded several leaf or dark nature photos because I really loved the Greens and I want to
see if I can pull out some of those greens in my brand and also purples just anything that I personally
like and this is different than branding for a company.
Because when you brand for a company you're thinking about the consumer.
And in this case we are thinking about our target market we are thinking about our client but we're
also thinking about our own personal style that we get to portray in our brand.
So I'm going to be over here in Canada dot com I'll see you there in a minute.
So the great thing about Canada is their ability to have all these premade photo templates you can make
a pretty good brand board quickly by kind of dragging those photos over and they have a free Canada.
It's not the Canada for work it's the paid monthly subscription to Canada which you get a lot of extra
things but there's also a free version of Canada that you can sign up for and do this step.
You don't have to use Canada just recommending this as a great tool for freelancers because it's free
and easy to use and it can also create social media graphics posters flyers.
There's a lot of great reasons to kind of have a Canada account so I recommend you check it out.
Well you can also use Photoshop Illustrator any old program to kind of put their put together your brand
board.
So I'm going to go ahead and find what I think would be enough photos to properly represent a brand
and pull some colors out.
I'm thinking anywhere from six to 10 photos.
Of course this is really personal to you if you have 50 photos you really want to pull from but I'd
like to simplify and make this choice a lot easier.
So I'm just going to flip through this and try to find what I think would be a really good layout for
my brand board so I found one I thought that would work really well.
And I went ahead and uploaded several the photos that I've found that I thought really resonated with
Lily and Hernandez's kind of personal brand that we're starting to build for her.
So she's trying to appeal to she's just getting started so she's trying to appeal to a broad audience.
So not really a specific target yet because she's still trying to develop that.
I know she really loves those tills and blue colors so that's something she really wanted to have in
her brand.
Got to go and drag a few of these I think would really work well and this is kind of she likes to brainstorm
and sketch out her logos and as a graphic designer so I thought this would really be helpful.
I'm going to go ahead and find a few others here really loves this kind of texture here I'm going to
go ahead and zoom in on this so you can really see that texture and she really really prefers this orange
color.
So we're gonna go ahead and focus that because that could be a chance for us to pull out some secondary
brand colors in that particular texture so you notice how he zoomed in on that because we have it zoomed
out it gets too detailed and you start to lose the essence of what you're really trying to focus on
and that's going to be the texture.
So let's go ahead focus on what's the most important because that's how we're deriving our inspiration
from our brand board.
And another thing was these dark green nature leaves.
That was something that really resonated well so we can kind of keep that as as is this Robin blue.
There's a lot of blues and steels that we want to maybe derive some colors off of.
So I'm going to zoom in on this egg so we can maybe get kind of some of that color out there also this
blue door was a huge inspiration especially because of the Teal.
And that really nice creamy color.
So that's something we can have in there as a part of the brand theme and also featuring previous artwork
or design work or illustrative work or web design work whatever freelance activity you do kind of putting
some previous client work in their personal work and also help your brand board because you have a particular
style or you have a style you want to have going forward with your clients.
So it's always nice to incorporate some of your prior work so that can be a part of your brand board.
If you already have some personal work or even some paid work you can go ahead incorporate that and
remember it could be textures it could be colors it could be anything that you find or derive a brand
inspiration from.
So in this case that little bit of silver could be something that we're inspired by.
Feel free to incorporate certain typography or font usage that you really appreciate if there's a certain
way that typography is done or a certain font choice.
You can also incorporate that into your brand board as well.
Are you catering to individuals or companies.
All these factors play a part and the colors we choose.
I'm including a color psychology chart to give you a rough idea of some of the emotions and reactions
we can evoke with color certain colors are stronger like reds and warm colors while other colors are
naturally more calming and relaxing.
And I go over a lot of this in detail in my logo design a mastery course so we have our little brand
board that we're going to get started with.
I'm going to go ahead and bring this into a color dot Adobe dot com which is another great resource
and also could include that into their resource list.
So feel free to check that out for all sorts of great resources.
This is great because I'm able to really pick the colors that I need and source that from the photos
I've done this and other classes if you take in some of my other design classes I do this a lot when
it comes to trying to find and derive colors from inspirational photos as opposed to trying to drive
and pick colors out of nowhere.
That really is kind of a helpful starting guide.
So I'm on color dot Adobe dot com.
I get to go to extract from image.
I believe this is free to use as long as you don't need to download anything.
But I don't think we need to do that
so once you load your photo in it will automatically populate with a color palette that they think are
the strongest colors but you can mainly manipulate these anyway you want to go and drag these around
and try to find and source the color that way.
So I find this a really helpful tool to kind of customizing your color palettes and let's say they focus
heavily on this image and you want to drag one over and focus on this door which was a really important
image for Lillian.
So going to drag that over to the door you'd also find off white subtle colors so if you want to have
some whites and creams you can also maybe drag this over and he could source a color that way so kind
of get a can like light gray can help you kind of choose those colors as well.
Just a really helpful tool.
There's kind of the color palette we have so far and of course you can extract using a color mood so
you can do colorful.
So this would be your colorful colors on your brights muted
darks and of course none.
You could do your own custom so you can go over to color will appear on that bore left.
They just recently redesigned this whole thing so it's a little bit different a little bit more efficient.
This is the standard color wheel so this is the color palette that we've brought in.
If you scroll down it will give you all the hex codes and different items that you'll need.
So these are hex codes hex goes will be important when you build your online portfolio.
These are the codes we need to do to do a digital representation on your website of that particular
color.
So anytime you see a hex code input this is where you can find those hex codes you can also do RG B
modes and also go ahead and click on some of these and you go ahead and give you all of the CNY K and
RG be colorful should be helpful if you're going to be really doing print and digital items and doing
more of the design work with a lot of your stuff so that's very helpful way to find colors.
So when I'm going to do is I going to go ahead and start with hex codes and bring in all my hats has
hex codes in the program of my choice which would be Adobe Illustrator and I'm just going to really
put together and finish up my brand board.
It looks a lot like this and it's kind of when I finally came up with the terms of color selection and
it's kind of has some circles there with put I input it in the hex code from colored out Adobe and I
was able to find the perfect shade and perfect match for these.
So now we have our brand board mood board which source some color ideas course.
Now these colors are final until we get a final brand together because as we test out some of these
colors we may need to go back and fine tune them and tweak them maybe we were a bit aggressive with
the orange.
All these little things need to be figured out when we actually start to put together our logo and practical
branded items.