So here we are we're an Adobe InDesign and we're gonna create our layout or our plan for our portfolio.
You can see I've already kind of started sketching this out a little bit.
You're going to want to have to figure out how many total projects you want to have in your portfolio.
I've decided to have three that Lillian Hernandez is going to feature and we're gonna do a little bit
more of a detailed overview of each project so that's why I'm only sticking to three.
I'm thinking overall I might commit three total pages to each project although not every project is
going to need all three and some may need four.
So as long as I keep it within 10 pages or less I'm going to feel pretty happy if I go over to 12 pages
to see to make sure this two extra pages I added are worth it.
Is it really needed to have those two pages.
If so you can go beyond 10 but only if you feel like it really really adds to the descriptions and extra
images you're able to have for your projects.
So first things first.
We can layout all these different things once we get an idea and we gather all of our project images
together.
I went ahead and did this.
I have all of our projects have the three projects and different folders for each one and I need to
figure out I have way more photos than I need to presented.
5 percent and all of these photos I think it would overwhelm the client.
So a lot of times you need to write your project descriptions to know what photos you need to incorporate
and how many you need to go corporate.
So we're going to do that we're going gonna write our project descriptions and once we have our project
descriptions we can do our basic layout and then start popping in those photos and really figuring out
the design and lay outside of things.
We're going to switch gears a little bit away from InDesign.
I'm just going to go to word and I'm creating a little bit of a plan and you can download this as a
downloadable resource so you can be able to read these bios and read the the project description so
you can get an idea of how I've written mine for Lilian but it can be very different depending on what
kind of work you do if you're an illustrator.
Your descriptions might be a lot shorter if you're a UX UI designer you might have very very long descriptions.
So for Lilian and she's a graphic designer so that's kind of the example I'm using.
So this is project one we have of course you need a title and you want to go ahead and just instead
of saying what the project name is.
Go ahead and be a little more descriptive.
So for this it's a branding projects.
So for this case it's elemental logo development brand creation and extension.
So I'm pretty much saying what the company name is and all the major things that I did for them.
And so the headline.
So the headline can be anything you feel I can further describe the project in this case I'm using a
client test demo testimonial is I feel like that's going to have a little bit of a higher impact when
viewed on that first page that we're going to develop.
So in this case it's working with win.
Lillian it's been a pure joy I thought that was a really great testimonial to use.
So you can see this is the total description.
It's not super long it's not super short either.
And so instead of putting the description all on the front page we are going to dole this out and little
small snippets throughout the three pages I'm dedicating to this project.
So I have to put the first couple of lines on maybe the first page as an introduction and then as I
describe the project I have different project images I'll go to another page and put a little bit of
explanation for each photo so you don't have one big block of text you're kind of slowly letting them
read the description as they move through your project.
So after you've spent some time writing your descriptions for each project go ahead do the first project
first so we can see what that looks like so we can start to work on the other projects.
So this is kind of the first page is obviously going to be your front cover.
It's going to be your splash page it's going to be your hero image.
It may be one image that is your favorite that you feel like really captures your skill set haven't
on the front to sell or could be a collage of just maybe a couple of hand selected images.
We're going to do that after we do the first project.
We're just going to kind of put some place holders are going to put that they are also gonna put a logo
as we start to develop our other project layouts going to be thinking of what that hero image is going
to be for the front what is going to be that big image that feel like it's going to capture the client's
attention to move on and so after we do a couple of pages I think we might start to get ideas for that.
So we're going to come and visit that front page but I have it already planned out already have the
first page dedicated to that already have the next three pages dedicated to our client project.
So right now I'm going to continually take a look at some of these layout ideas.
This is a downloadable resource from the last lesson.
There's lots of different ideas here for different ways you can present images.
And so I'm going to take a look at this and see if there's any I feel like we'd be really good for this
particular project.
I'm also going to take a look at my images to see kind of where I can get a little bit of inspiration.
So what I'm thinking for at first I don't I'm not going to put a huge long description in the front
so I don't need a lot of text but I do think kind of having one big hero image to kick off the project
might be good for this particular project because I have a lot of great images.
So perhaps this magazine feature layout might be really good or if I wanted to feature two I can do
this headline feature split or I can have a headline and it and I put our testimonial there but I can
also have two images so I can be able to have more control over cropping those images because they're
not taken up the whole page.
So let's take a look at that layout and see if it's going to work.
Go to our first one and I already have this layout right here I'm going to switch these pages right
in InDesign.
You can use whatever software you're using but I'm just switching those pages out.
I feel like this might be a really good headline.
So just going into word and just copying and pasting my title the headline and I'll be right back
so here's our first page of our first project I decided to feature the logo of the company or the project
instead of just having it in regular type just can add a little bit to the project presentation.
We're going to fine tune graphics and everything later we're just figuring out the basic layout.
So we have the ability to do different to different photos or one big photo.
Just depends on which photo we choose for this particular header cover.
So for project beginning pages I like to have this Wow photos that really capture the project in its
entirety.
You can have multiple photos if you feel like it works just try not to use too many.
We also have this quotation for a client testimonial that will want to also incorporate in there as
well.
So we need to figure out a place for that.
We can also start to work in some of our project description maybe the first couple of lines but let's
see how the front page looks as we start to put it together.
We still have two other pages or even a fourth one.
If we wanted to dedicate four pages to this project project.
So we need to create it the best way possible.
So we just need to be flexible with different layout options and ideas as we start to put this together.
So I'm going to go ahead and open up my project we have several different project images we can use
kind of as a well first page image and I already have a few in my mind that I want to kind of pick out.
This is kind of a branding project where the whole idea is to create a package design and a logo design.
So what best to feature an image that has both of those on here.
So that would be this one right here.
It's going to go and drag this in here of course you're gonna have a lot of different projects that
you're going to want to feature.
You may be a photographer web designer you're going to be presenting is a little bit differently but
the overall idea of creating a layout plan is the same no matter what type of work you do.
So this is when layouts need to be flexible not all the layouts I have in the downloadable resource
so the ones who come up with it first are going to work perfectly so feel free to manipulate and change
everything is needed so throughout this portfolio building process I'm looking at her branding standards
and the brand that she developed for her personal business or her personal freelance business trying
to find ways to incorporate the color palette the iconography the background the colors all this can
somehow be incorporated into the look of her portfolio so you can see I adapted some of that that blue
light blue greenish color to the portfolio as well.
So I'm just thinking about that as I develop these pages so continuing to figure out what looks best
for this first page in terms of our layout plan.
And I'm also realizing that I if I want have a description and a title in the name of the project it's
starting to get pretty heavy and there's a lot of things going on so there's some things we can do to
improve that.
I can shift this away and kind of start off with the logo design and kind of have that be a little bit
better of a complement.
We don't need the divider bar anymore.
I'm I can also do the quote so right now I'm starting with a description and so maybe since there's
a lot already going on I may decide to not do the description and wait till the second page can move
that off to the side also of work or working quote If this is a real project you could do quotes.
Obviously if it's a personal project you want to start off with a description or maybe a title and make
sure you have personal work somewhere on that first page so clients are not misled and thinking it was
a real client project.
You need to be upfront about that doesn't have to be really big it can be a little small text below
the first image that just lets them know it's a personal project.
But for this case we're going to make it a real project just kind of show that example.
So we have the quote and we'll just start a description on the next page.
You got three or four pages to do this.
Lots of room to slowly tell your story so don't feel you have to like it to cram everything on the front
page.
You're really just trying to grab their attention.
The product project and then you're ready for that second page.
So now we're onto the second page already and we need to figure out a layout plan for this one as well.
Once we have a couple more pages left.
And since we've already written our description we know exactly what images we're going to want to show.
And with the description as well.
So the first thing I talk about is kind of how I sit down and plan with them.
So if I have a great brainstorming sitting down at a meeting kind of images kind of like the examples
I'm showing where you kind of showing that process thinking preparing meeting discussing if you can
kind of have an image that really goes well with that description then great.
Let's go ahead find that.