Now that we have our inspiration board or brand board we can start to sketch out those concepts for
our global design which will be our main focal point for our personal branding project.
Since you already defined your target market and created your inspiration board sketching out ideas
for a logo and picking out our colors and fonts will go a lot quicker now that we have a bases of who
are designing for.
There are many directions we can go in with our logo design.
This class will focus more on the branding aspect and less on the technical steps we need to go through
using software.
I have many classes that focuses solely on local design and software like Adobe Illustrator and even
free cloud based programs like Canada.
If you wanted to get into the technical side of Do It Yourself logo design and branding.
First we want to sketch out our concepts and ideas on paper or digital sketching app before we make
it a reality.
There's many of you out there that may not have any graphic design background or experience and you
may prefer hiring a designer to turn your concept into a real vector usable logo design perhaps you're
an illustrator or a photographer or a web developer and design is not your strong suit.
Hiring another freelancer or designer can be an overwhelming task.
So I created this downloadable guide that gives you a lot of tips and tricks on places to start searching
for a designer or freelancer and also what to look out for when doing so.
For those who are graphic designers this can be helpful to look at too as it gives you some great insight
into what other small business owners are looking for and great designers if you decide to hire another
designer to create your logo or branded assets.
Make sure you send them some work we have done prior including your mission statement your target audience
sketches inspiration boards or brand boards.
Those will be very helpful to the designer that will be helping you craft your personal brand so Let's
sketch out some rough ideas on paper.
I'm going to be using a digital sketching app called procreate which you can use with your Apple iPad
and Apple pencil for this demonstration why you're sketching out ideas.
Think about your target audience along the way.
Are you targeting and high end clientele.
If so that might change the look and feel of your logo.
Would your target audience appreciate a detailed illustrative style also be thinking about the different
type of logo styles when you're sketching some of you may want to leave this up to a professional designer
or try a hand at this yourself.
If I have a few downloadable resources.
One is called the logo types and styles Cheat Sheet which goes over some of the basic logo design types
personal branding for freelancers as a bit different than branding for a company.
As I talked about before.
First of all personal branding as well.
It's very personal.
It's about you and your unique style and what you're going to bring to the market.
I find the best freelancer logos put the freelancers style on full display and you can echo similar
colors you use in your work.
Like we just arrived from our brand board in the lesson prior branding and logo design for companies
tend to focus on the product or service in a personal freelance branding we want to focus on yourself
and your personality.
Remember that being authentic and true to your own unique style sells yourself better to the right clients.
Remember how finding the right clients is kind of like dating.
We want to make sure we represent ourselves to the client in the most accurate way possible and the
style you choose for your logo design and the layout is a great way to show that style.
So what about names.
Freelancers can either stick to their personal name so in my case Lindsay marsh or they can create a
freelancer company name.
I recommend using your personal name if you plan on remaining independent with your client work or projects.
That means you work mostly with yourself and working collaboration with others but not really function
as a growing company or agency for example.
I would recommend using a company name or not your personal name.
For those who want to eventually grow into a multi employee company down the road look back at your
freelancing goals that you established earlier.
Maybe this could help you decide what might be best for you.
The great thing about sticking to your name at first is building up name recognition for our case with
Lillian.
We could be sticking with our personal name for now you can also include your official title as part
of your logo.
They can make sure you clearly communicate with surfaces you provide.
For example as a web designer making sure that is clearly communicated with text below it could be a
symbol an icon a tagline some way to tell the viewer what you do in your logo.
You may even provide multiple services like web design and photography and being able to communicate
through that in your logo through a type or a tagline is critical and showing the client right away
who you are and the kind of services you can provide for them.
It's not required but it's a nice inclusion and a strong logo design for freelancers when sketching
out your ideas find icons symbols illustrations that can represent what you do and help brainstorm concepts.
For example it could be the pen tool in Adobe Illustrator for a graphic designer for example and this
is a tool that she use everyday in her profession and so it makes a lot of sense and including in her
logo just for an example do not overdo it on brainstorming.
For those of you who are wanting to go as far as possible creating your own logo and branding.
Try coming up with three viable concepts you want to develop further using vector software every logo
needs to eventually be created in vector format.
There are many great vector programs like affinity design which is a cheaper version or if you have
the Adobe Creative Suite Adobe Illustrator you may also want to hire a graphic designer to take on your
rough sketches and create that vector format for you offended a designer is that cheaper solution and
only cost around 50 dollars just a one time fee for those wanting to give this a try on their own and
not hire a graphic designer.
You can even put together a logo using Kanda which is a cloud based free design tool that allows you
to put together simple logos although it is a little bit limited.
So now that we're able to sketch out three different ideas and concepts I'm going to go a step further
and make these are reality and vector format and Adobe Illustrator.