The higher and more advanced your skill level the more power you have with pushing for higher pricing.
But now we have another element we need to seriously take a look at.
That's your ability for your client to afford your pricing.
What good is a quote for a project if they may not afford or even worse you're under charging so much
that they do not take you seriously.
I signed clients into three main tiers the first tier is going to be your non-profits your small local
companies or startups.
This may be a small cleaning company a small coffeehouse with one or two locations or a local newspaper.
You're not going to have as much pricing power with his clients simply because they don't have the budget
to afford an expensive freelancer.
They're also not looking to spend a lot of money here and they're okay with the quality of the project
not being at agency level quality as long as it's done well and done on time.
A Tier 2 client is going to be a bit larger.
Perhaps they have around 10 to 100 employees maybe even up to 200 employees.
They have a couple thousand likes on their social media page and he may know them already from some
marketing they do regionally.
They're looking to grow and they've also looking to invest some more money so they have a little bit
of a larger budget to work with.
These guys also have a little bit more flexibility with pricing and they may even have a marketing person
that contacted you instead of a founder or CEO that would indicate a larger marketing budget.
I start to get a little bit more aggressive with my pricing when it comes to Tier 2 clients.
I'm also looking at my exposure which will get into the next lesson.
It could be that a social media graphic I'm designing for them may receive over 2000 likes and 50 shares.
They may even do a paid Facebook campaign and my work is out there getting even more exposure.
Remember when we mentioned how higher exposure of your project equals higher pricing on my part.
Tier 3 clients are dream clients.
Sometimes they're big ad agencies.
Sometimes they're smaller ad agencies that landed a large client and they need your help.
They may have a hundred plus employees work they've done that you'll be coding for may end up being
in national magazines or large ad campaigns.
A local design that you do may end up being printed on over 10000 different letterheads at some point
they may send out annual reports to 5000 plus donors.
They may even be a publicly traded company they may even have user impressions on content they post
and the tens of thousands if not hundreds of thousands and maybe even millions.
I have incredibly high flexibility when pricing for these clients of course they still me to afford
me and there's no point in pricing so sky high that they simply move on to the next person because they're
more on point with budget.
So even though this is the highest I would price it's still not unreasonable.
Remember when pricing for these sized clients you're most likely not the only one they're seeking a
quote from.
Sometimes it's required by the company policy to gather at least three quotes on any given contract
now that we're able to size up our client into one of these three tiers one two or three.
This is where does start to get a little complicated.
We're going to explore one other aspect of pricing which is project exposure and then we'll have our
three main ingredients to start formulating our perfect quote Let's do some examples.
Let's say I'm an intermediate level graphic designer.
I have about four years of experience and I'm starting to feel comfortable doing a wide variety of different
design projects and have a little pricing power based on an intermediate level experience.
I have a new potential client that approached me for a project quote They're a local nonprofit and they
just don't have a large budget.
I care a lot about their costs I'm going to be a little flexible with my pricing.
Plus they have a lot of donors that need design work and if I do a great job this may lead to more Tier
2 or even Tier 3 clients they're going to need some event design work including posters invites name
tags and advertising designed for the event since they're a tier one.
And even though I'm an intermediate level designer I'm going to still need to be careful with my pricing
and not price too high.
I've already established my hourly pricing according to my skill level and basis pricing line based
on research I've done with other designers and from up works com and other freelancing Web sites.
I fall right about here in this area for this example at least now I need to look at the client tier
they're Tier 1.
So that means I need to possibly price lower on my experience level range scale.
If I did not size up the client and assign them to a tier category I would not really know where on
that range I should price.
So gauging your skill and experience level with the client here helps to slowly narrow it down to a
proper and reasonable price on the scale same goes for fixed project quotes as opposes hourly quotes
for fixed project quotes.
I would come up with a scale for each type of project to create quotes for each one of my projects.
If there's multiple projects involved that would eventually end up being line items and my final quote
it does not deviate a drastic bout from my desired average but just enough to make me affordable to
this client let's do one more example a client approaches me about creating an ad campaign this ad campaign
will contain four full page magazine ads and a paid Instagram and Facebook at the campaign will have
the same theme throughout which I will also assist in creating the look and feel and the design of the
graphic.
How do I quote such a project.
First of all what is my experience level.
Let's say I fall right about here and this experience level two years as a freelancer and I've done
10 or so separate client projects paid.
There are three main skill or experience levels involved here but fortunately it exists on a scale I'd
fall right about here with what I describe so far.
So how do I come up with hourly or fixed project costs that exist on this experience scale.
I have source them from other freelancers with different experience levels and I've also done some research
to figure out the value range of a graphic designer in my country I have found top hourly prices and
I've also saw some lower prices too but I also have designed these to be in a range.
I feel most comfortable with personally.
So in this case anything under 20 dollars an hour does not even exist because I do not feel comfortable
charging less than this.
Also anything over 80 dollars is not included because I do not feel comfortable charging that at this
time.
This can be a very personal thing for you.
I also went over to help WorldCom to find graphic designers with these skill levels to find out what
they were charging.
I also know what ive charge clients in the past two years that helped me find out the sweet spot for
these rates.
What is great about the scale is I can use it over and over once I develop my scale I'm happy with I
can also tweak it later if I want to raise my lowest price to 30 dollars per hour for example.
Lastly I can switch this to a fixed project based scale instead of just an hourly one.
If I'm interested in a fixed project quote I simply do the same research but with fixed project costs
instead back to our example.
Now I know where I fall in the scale let's size up the client.
The client is a large regional mall.
They're well-known in the area and they people drive large distances to go to the small.
They've also included many high end stores and their current marketing is done by a local ad agency.
So based on my client tier system which year can be created custom to you I've put them solidly in Tier
2.
Let's look at the our clients tier level.
But let's factor in our skill and experience level because this is a client that may have a decent marketing
budget.
I can stretch my pricing power a little bit and quote on the higher end of my range maybe right about
here.
This is not an exact science but a guide for you to use to find a range that's most reasonable for you
and your client.
We now have two factors that we could use to help us narrow down our pricing.
There's another factor that we can use to help solidify our pricing and that's exposure.
The project will have and we'll do that in the next lesson.