Finding clients online is not for everyone but my personal freelance story started with a few clients
I found through networking offline.
Some of these suggested avenues for finding clients offline take a bit of entrepreneurial spirit and
perhaps a boost of confidence being around others and talking about your skill sets.
We've already crafted a business card a Web site or personal portfolio.
We defined our target audience and we've written our bios and stories and we have everything we need
to pursue clients and network off line making local connections at last.
My favorite and most recommended step in finding clients is connecting with local small or medium sized
business owners.
You could do this online by finding local Facebook business groups you can do this in person by connecting
with your Chamber of Commerce our local small business body group or gathering serving on the board
of directors and volunteering for a local nonprofit to make connections as well.
Asking to speak or teach at a local small business seminar or workshop etc. about marketing branding
design is another way to get your foot in the door it may sound a little old school but visiting local
businesses with a business card in hand can help land you those first few clients great clients tend
to refer you to other clients and local ones tend to do that a little bit more because of that personal
relationship.
You tend to build with them one thing you could do is volunteering your services.
Consider the list below for possible local entities that you could use your services at either a low
cost are free to get your foot in the door clearly communicate with them.
If you do volunteer your services what you may require in exchange for your free work or low cost work.
It could be either a testimonial a client referral or possibly to half future paid work.
This does not have to be free services sometimes contacting a local school for example and letting them
know you're giving them a nonprofit discount by cutting your rates by a third can help also motivate
them to contact you.
You can find phone numbers and emails to administrators of the following below by visiting their Web
sites preferably email someone who would be making those marketing decisions like a marketing coordinator
a principal or a manager in the finding clients guide.
I have a little sample of an email you can write to an administrator or a marketing coordinator of one
of those local groups.
It might help you get started in that course customize it to your needs.
Connecting with other freelancers so connecting with other freelancers is a great idea but not for the
reason you might think.
Being with other freelancers is a healthy thing to do to network and get out of the House and to share
your experiences.
But a big benefit to connecting with certain freelancers is to share and swap clients let's say you're
a visual designer who specializes in web design and graphic design.
You're not very comfortable coding but can turn any rough idea into something pretty good looking.
One thing you can do is seek out freelancers who have excellent coding and web development background
but they don't have a strong visual design background with the two of you now connected.
You can share client work and give the client not only the visual side but that back inside as well
and solid coding ideas.
Early on I was able to find through a client's connection a local programmer who sent me several clients
of his clients.
I did the web design and they did the back end coding and adapted it to a a or a content management
system like WordPress another example of this in action is if you're an illustrator.
How about finding and teaming up with the t shirt designer.
They're bound to need more custom hand drawn illustrations for their T-shirts.
And if you're a photographer teaming up with another event planner can help you land feature wedding
photography gigs if that's your style.
If you're a copywriter and editor there are many freelancers that need your skills like editorial designers
web designers and anyone who works with written type or copy you can find people off line or online.
The great thing about connecting with someone locally is finding and serving local clients together
and being able to meet face to face to discuss plans and start building that long term relationship
that leads to referrals.