So when looking at our project description I decided a story driven narrative might work better for
the next page as we have lots of little descriptions we can slowly work in and find the perfect photo
that pairs with the proper description on the right or the left.
So this is a layout that I found in the layout downloadable resource out that would be really helpful
so I'm just kind of applying it forced you can adjust it to how rethink would work best with your particular
photos.
But I want to really maximize the photos.
So this is when you may not have a particular photo for this so brainstorming.
Do I have a brainstorming photo of this project.
Maybe Lillian didn't have that when she created this project.
So that's where you need to maybe find one you can get a stock photo it's best to think about this when
you're doing your next project work to capture some of those beginning stages so that when you do your
portfolio you can show some of these more authentic brainstorming type actions where you're showing
sketches you can kind of think about that the next time you do a personal work or a paid client work.
Keep track of all those take photos of that process because it can really come in handy when putting
together your portfolio or your Web site to kind of have this really cool images.
So I found this one but I think it can work for what we have.
We can find something a little bit more fitting we can create our own if we have a little bit of time
so continuing to find photos that I think pair well with the descriptions you could do if you feel like
you need to put all three steps here.
That's great if you feel like you really want to make the images bigger and show more of the details
you can only do two per page or you can really focus on one per page.
If you don't have a lot of total projects in your portfolio can spend more time really focusing in on
detailed photos.
So we could do that for the next one.
This one's pretty description heavy so for the next page we're going to focus a lot on just one or two
photos to have more of a focus page where they can stop and see a lot more details especially when it
comes to the product or package design that we designed for them we really want to show that often a
nice big image they're going to do that for our next page so when thinking about the layout for this
one we're going to really display the product package design I really wanted to use this photo but we
already use that as our hero image in the first page introduction of the project and this is why it's
great to do a layout plan ahead of time you can figure out what photos are going to go where.
So what I decided to do is go back to the front page and use this one as kind of our hero image because
I feel like it has lots of different things going on.
We're using multiple images but it's really one well put together branded image that I think can really
capture the branding side of the project so that also leave us available for the the package design
page to have that image displayed.
This probably goes pairs better with a description here.
We want to make sure our descriptions pair well together.
You're probably noticing how each page is presented just a little bit differently.
Yet there's still a connecting theme.
I think this is nice to break it up.
So this one has quite a bit of photos it tells the story.
This one's more about showing off your design or your skill set so you kind of see kind of the different
arrangements I'm having on each page just to shake it up and to keep the viewer on their toes and to
kind of make a more rich experience.
So this is the next page kind of doing two photos that are trying not to compete with each other but
really highlight the logo and then going down to a another page.
We're already kind of going past what I planned.
That's OK sometimes you have to go past it if you have a pretty large project that you want to present.
And so here's the social media I thought I kind of maybe show one as a larger image and to a smaller
images because if you were to show all of them at the same time they can't really get a good idea what
it looks like.
So having kind of one that zoomed in a little bit bigger helps when you have the kind of projects that
have a lot of detail or you maybe have eight different versions or variations sometimes it's nice to
have a little hierarchy and have one be a little bit bigger so they can really see the details because
it was all small.
This is a PDA if they have to zoom in to really really look at the details you don't want them to have
to do any work.
You don't want them to have to zoom in to see anything.
They should be able to see everything right here at this.
This view super Project Number two we don't have a really big project which is good because our first
one took up a lot of pages so this going to only take up to pages only have a few images but I really
wanted to include it in the portfolio because I think it'd be a nice complement to the last project
it's a little bit different but it's still in the branding design side of things.
So this is a personal project for a school project that Lillian had.
So we want to make sure somewhere there's personal project labeled and we'll find it maybe a clever
way to do that in a very short description so we're going to be a little less wordy.
We're going to be a little bit more visual with our photos.
So let's go ahead and get started and get a happened in design.
Just kind of a basic layout I borrowed from our layout ideas guide that I have is the downloadable resource.
Let's look at our photos first and our project.
This will be project number two.
So we have several different photos not quite as many as the last one but we need to find one for kind
of our hero image that's going to grab people's attention this one already has kind of a label or designed
to it that we can go ahead and put in here.
Now we have to kind of fight myself when I have a couple of good photos to use to only choose the one
I think is the most effective because there's four or five I want to throw in there because I really
want to describe my project but there's always ways you could do that on the next page.
So less is more I always have to fight myself on that because when I put together my portfolio I feel
like every image is good.
But you really want to choose the images that are going to be the most effective at showing the details
so I'm really practicing the less is more approach with this project.
I found one image I think could really display both the products or package designs that I developed
for this project instead of showing lots of different ones I feel like showing the one worked a lot
better.
I also took a more editorial design layout approach to this.
And don't worry about being too matchy matchy so with our first theme we kind of had our branded colors
in this block of copy.
We're still using the same type or not changing our font or type style that's part of our brand but
it's OK to do maybe a white on black if I feel like it matches a little bit better with the project.
You don't have to keep the same white bar because it may not look as good with the next project as long
as you keep with the same fonts and type choices you could be a little bit more creative with how you
present another project so for this particular layout I had this little circle here why I wanted to
kind of zoom in and show little details of a project or illustration or a photo.
And so if you have a particular illustration where there's a lot of detailed work having a little circle
that zooms in on that really helps because as a PDA if it's only one size it's not like a Web site we
can download the photo and zoom in so kind of have that opportunity if you want to bring out details
of a particular project.
So there is our second project there's a lot quicker to put together and we have our first project done
as already.
I think we're going to be ready to create this cover photo.
This is going to be kind of the best page that we need to design we needed to really make this attention
grabbing as much as possible.
I'm going to go ahead drag in some of the elements that we're going to have to have on here like the
logo and maybe some of her branded colors.
And then we can figure out what photos will best represent our portfolio.
This is where we need to spend the most time.