Fort licensing is a complicated mess.
It can have huge consequences if you use a font requiring a purchase license for a commercial project
and you don't hold the proper license for it.
Let's start with the easy stuff the stuff that should not scare you.
I'm going to talk first about the open flight licensing which provides the user to free use of fonts
without attribution.
A great example of this in action is Google fonts.
Here's what they say about the Google font program which contains all open font licensing all of the
fonts in our catalog are free and open source making beautiful type accessible to anyone for any project.
This means you can share favorites and collaborate easily with friends and colleagues.
Google fonts takes care of all the licensing and hosting ensuring that the latest and greatest version
of any font is available to anyone.
That all sounds great.
So that means I can use these fonts without fear of needing a license.
Yep you betcha.
I'd love to find fonts on Google fonts knowing I do not need to purchase a license.
Makes me feel less worried when picking fonts for client projects.
I'm also free to share the fonts with clients if they needed to use them on the computer as well.
If you visit fonts stock Google dot com you'll be able to view their entire font library and download
the fonts you'd like to use open Sands and railway are fun to use all the time for my videos.
And you're seeing railway in use right now throughout this entire class.
When you visit the open Sands page on fonts that Google dot com you could see the font author and view
the specific type of open license each font uses please visit each font you plan to download and take
a look at their licensing just to make sure not all fonts are open source some fonts require the purchase
of a license or a EU L.A. an end user licensing agreement.
There are different type boundaries where you can find and purchase font licenses.
I'm on typography dot com which leads to the hoofer and company Web site.
There are type foundry that sells hundreds of different fault licenses for many different styles and
typefaces.
Take for example the archer font families.
I could purchase a license to use Archer on one computer or I can purchase it for use of up to a thousand
computers.
If I'm at a large company and I want this font to be used on every computer in the company but if I'm
a single freelancer I just need to purchase it for my 1 computer but if I have a laptop and a desktop
computer I want to be able to use Adobe Illustrator and have access to the Archer fonts on both my laptop
and my desktop.
So that doesn't mean I need to purchase a license for both computers who buys font licenses.
Me my client both of us fonts are essentially pieces of software used by other software like Photoshop
Illustrator or Microsoft Word For example when you buy a font license you buy it for that computer like
it's a piece of software.
For example if my client owns a license to use let's say Adobe Photoshop they can allow me to use it
if I'm an employee of said company and they purchase enough licenses for Photoshop for me to use on
that company computer.
If I'm a freelance designer for example I'm not part of said company just a contractor so I would need
to buy my own version of Photoshop to remain legal even though I'm doing work for said company.
That same basic concept can be applied to fonts as well.
Treat them just like a piece of software.
If my client purchased a font to use in their branding package that means if I'm going to maintain a
freelance design work for that client I also need to purchase a license for that font and charge the
client the amount for that license or the client may have an extended license that gives me the ability
to use it as well.
But it's good to find out that piece of information from the client first thought licenses come in a
few different forms.
This is where it gets a little complicated.
If I intended to use this font for print design for example a flyer I designed in Adobe Photoshop I
can purchase the desktop license for this font or if I'm going to use it for a Web site I need to have
the web font type of license.
Also if I wanted to use this font as a part of a web application there's a separate license for that
as well.
Fortunately most type foundries make it easy by buying all of them in a bundle so you can feel free
to use that font if any application in any form of course is bundles cost a little more this is where
having a font subscription pays off you can purchase a monthly subscription at type kit for example
and be able to have access to all the fonts in their library.
Adobe happens to own type kit.
And if you have a creative cloud subscription you automatically have access to the entire font library
and licenses that come with it.
Another good reason to be an Adobe Creative Cloud user
I noticed that died out as a font that needs a license to use.
I also notice that type Kit has a version of data that is free to use because of my creative cloud subscription.
If you want to subscribe to these fonts without the adobe cloud subscription you could still pay an
annual fee to have access to the spot library.
Remember when you have subscription to a font b any one of these spots subscription websites and you
pass your work on to another designer or to a client who wants to update or modify that work themselves.
They must also have a subscription to type kit for example to use the same font you used on type kit
for their system or they need to hold a license for that font you're passing along the anywhere any
one of their software programs or hold an individual license for that font so we have covered France
that you need to purchase fonts that come bundled into software subscription.
But what about those free fonts.
You can download all over the Internet.
They each come with a licensing agreement.
When you download the font read it carefully.
Some require an attribution to the author and some come with restrictions.
I'm on a Web site called Duff on dot com which is a common place to find these free fonts when browsing
fonts.
I looked over toward the licensing and then noticed a few different types.
Some are 100 percent free and these are the same as being open source.
No attribution is required but make sure you double check.
Another may say free for personal use only.
So if you're doing this for a personal project or zine you're free to use.
For a client or if you plan on using it for a for profit business you need to purchase a license on
the font Web site.
When you download a font it usually comes with a text document that lists the type of license it has
and outlines how you can use it and make sure you do this for every font you download online.
You can never be too careful.