Mean Adobe Illustrator right now and I'm going to vector rises asset and this is for those who are designers
who are already comfortable with Adobe Illustrator and you want to be able to vector rise your idea
or your rough sketch to go ahead and start to begin.
And I'm not going to get into too many details because then I'll start to be teaching a design class
I'm not a freelance class thing to show you a little time lapse of all the steps it took to kind of
make this a reality and make it our finished logo of course we haven't applied our color palette yet
we're gonna be doing that next a little trick when you vector ize your sketch or you make it kind of
a real vector logo object.
I'd like to bring in my rough sketch it could be a j peg PMG you can export it from anything you can
take a picture with your phone if you sketch it on a traditional paper or pen and paper and you can
bring it in and I'd like to put it on its own layer and I also like to reduce the transparency a little
bit so that when I do start to sketch with it or sketch on top of it it doesn't try to get in the way
when I sketch on top so I'm going to reduce the transparency to go and lock that layer so I don't accidentally
move it I'm creating a new layer to go ahead and victories everything so I get to recreate everything
you circles shapes the pen tool to draw and put the type on here as well
fonts are typefaces can make or break your logo for example notice these two logos using different typefaces
one is a boulder sans serif while the other one has lighter strokes and thinner lines and has syrups
there's little details at the ends of the letters it's amazing how just a small font change and a logo
changes its mood and style the serif typeface looks more high end and elegant why the boulder type choice
is more approachable and modern I have included a downloadable resource called the font styles guide
and I'll go over some great font type or font choices for certain styles you want to set for example
if you're looking for an approachable typeface that cater caters to a younger clientele perhaps a few
of these font choices my work just some small suggestions out there as there are thousands upon thousands
of fans to choose from Google fans is a great place to find free open source fonts.
We'll talk about photo and font licensing a little bit later in the course but just make sure you have
the proper license for font usage which will be for commercial use as you're using it for a personal
small business as another quick reminder.
All of the links software and external resources I mentioned in the class will be listed in the resource
guide that is accessible in the beginning of the Course as a downloadable Word doc and PD F so some
suggestions for you with the font styles guide.
But you'll know when you come across the right font for your personal brand.
Some personal brands with taglines will want or need to use two different types of fonts.
How do you know which two fonts pair well together.
I've included another resource called the font pairing guide which gives you some debt general direction
on pairing two different typefaces or fonts together in one logo and a few tips while you create your
personal brand and make sure that your font choice is very readable and it's very easy for small text
to get lost.
And remember your logo may have to be seen at small sizes on invoices.
So make sure everything is readable at those small sizes.
Try not to use too many font types.
Try to keep it to two to three font choices at a maximum.
Too many will overwhelm and it could look a little unprofessional in some cases.
Back when you're sketching out your logo make sure you plan out your logo layout.
Do you want to include an established date.
Do you have a tag line.
If so what's it going to be.
Do you want your title listed your full name including your middle name or just your first and last
name.
The more you include the more other logo types might work best for you.
For example a seal logo might work best for a freelancer for example whose including three different
phrases in your main logo.
Like our example of Lilian Hernandez you need to think about the logos flexibility can it be seen very
small but cannot look good and just one color.
How does it look printed out now that you have a good bases of your basic logo design.
Now we're to do some brand extension and take that logo design and put it on all sorts of items and
really create an amazing brand presentation.