We also need to see how much exposure we're going to have with our work.
The higher exposure impressions and views we have on the project report and for the more we need to
price that project higher.
I like to have this on the scale as well.
This one as complex as a video editor will put this project with a scale based on views perhaps possibly
YouTube views based on similar client videos.
Maybe you're a social media marketer and you put this on a scale of shares on Instagram or Instagram
likes.
Once again you would create this skill based on previous projects.
The clients have had or produced or another competitor has put out are even basis on similar projects
who have done that are similar in scope and exposure.
The higher on the scale of exposure the more pricing power you're most likely to have.
For example I am editing a video to promote a new product for a current client.
They have not done any videos so far to promote it.
So this will be the only one so I'm not sure about the amount of exposure the video will have.
I explore more with the client about where this video will be shown and they're going to invest five
thousand dollars to promote this video via paid Instagram and YouTube promotions because of this.
I would rate my potential exposure of the project to be on the high side once again none of this is
an exact science but a guide to help you with pricing.
Now we have a third layer to help us fine tune our pricing.
Let's say for this one we're putting our project based on a fixed rate to create this video as opposed
to trying to figure out how many hours it will take me because for an editing project especially video
that may prove difficult based on the exposure of the project.
Based on what I found other videos have cost companies to edit with a similar length.
I have come up with this basic pricing skill for myself and my experience.
Lastly the client tier is a Tier 2.
I know they're spending some ad money on this so they're flexible with budget based on the assumption
and willingness for them to invest money into this project.
A tier 2 client my intermediate level experience based on the scale I created from prior projects and
research on what others are charging.
And lastly the exposure level of the project.
I'm going to come up with this fixed costs for the project.
All three scales helped me feel more confident about pricing based on research.
I feel like my quota is reasonable industry standard and a strong contender to be accepted by the client.
Hopefully these lessons give you some insight on how to formulate a price or quote you do not have to
feel like you're quoting Klein at random.
There's a process you can go through and help guide you to the right price based on research.
Hopefully the next time you quote a client project you can send that quote with confidence.
I no longer feel nervous about your pricing decisions.