Licensing for graphic resources function in a similar way to photos.
There are several Web sites where you can download free vector resources for example.
Picard is one of those Web sites.
So for example I found the social media icon vector pack that are really need for a client project.
It was better than me having to find PND of each social media icon.
Plus these being in vector would be nice in terms of resolution for my project I look around the page
before I download any resource and I try to find the type of license this graphic has.
It looks like it's available for promotional use.
Great.
I can use this for my client.
It does look like I need to give a credit to the original author somehow.
There are two ways I can do this.
Be a Web site link if it's for online use or small print.
If it's for a printed project I could place the small line at the very bottom of my client's print project
would have my client or I do not like having the little line at the bottom of the project.
I can always purchase a premium graphic to use and I no longer have to credit the author or I can find
one that does not require an attribution by simply reading the license of that particular graphic it
just takes a little time noodling around to find the licensing and understand how they work and what
they are going to require me to do I'm on the creative market dot com.
A great place to find and purchase lots of premium assets for graphic designs.
I just happened to be on this Watercolor Collection.
I love these different images offered and I wanted to go ahead and purchase this for quite project.
And you'll notice that there's two different price points.
There's a standard license and an extended license just like for photography so if I want to figure
out what comes with the standard license I could scroll down on it a little bit and go down the license
offered.
I click on standard.
I can see if I can't satisfy what I need for my project because it is more affordable so for personal
use I have unlimited projects extended license and limited projects so great commercial use.
One project extend its license one project so if I'm using this for a client I need to purchase it again.
If I'm going to use it for another client and user product per sale I could do one project up to 500
sales but if I plan to have more than 500 sales on a particular graphic I'm going to want to buy the
extended license because of limited client budgets.
I've learned to use as many open source totally free resources as possible.
I've also learned to modify vector resources or graphics beyond recognition to make up my own artwork
that's unique.
And of course now usable for my clients my own personal work.
Of course I give credit to the original author and purchase any assets that I need.
This is where the lines really start to blur and get complicated.
Seek out the opinion of a legal professional for any serious inquiries.
You should always protect yourself.
If you have a serious legal question about licensing and copyrights of creative work but when does a
modified or derivative work start to become yours.
At no longer the original creators work this is always a hot topic up for debate.
Someone can easily take my design I made and modify it significantly beyond recognition and in some
cases I may no longer have protective rights on my work because that darn design was modified and changed
so much that I cannot retain any legal copyrights to it.
It becomes the new creator's work even though I created the basis for the design.
This is where it gets tricky.
If they stole my idea and that idea still shines through on their work even though they modified it
significantly I could still retain a legal case against them.
Does that mean you could take a vector graphic and modify it significantly and no longer need to give
credit to the original author.
That's a big fat.
Maybe it's up to you to cross that line.
This is once again a hot topic for discussion in the creative world and one that should we should continue
to talk about what is original art.
Can it combined with unoriginal works.
A big question you need to ask yourself before walking down that road.
Something I encourage you guys to do is to be as original as possible creating your own unique works
or to give credit to the artist work you use in your projects.
Looking for inspiration and other artist works that's a great idea.
Go remember their ideas theirs and your ideas are yours.