So now I need to apply the personal brand to a multitude of items in this class I'll walk through the
creation of two very important items a business card and a letterhead.
We'll talk about the paid an organic social media post design and other types of digital design a little
bit later in the marketing section of this course.
Business cards may seem outdated to some but when it comes to working and finding local clients having
a physical card to hand out really helps with remembering who you are and even jotting down quick notes
about your conversation when we start talking about finding clients.
I will emphasize heavily how important local networking is the business card is your golden ticket to
starting conversations but also providing something they can walk away with and remind them to follow
up with you your task is to create either a single side or double side business card for your personal
brand.
There is no requirement to what to include on a business card.
More commonly you'll find basic contact information like phone email or web site.
I'd like to include something interesting about my business.
Maybe my main headline or phrase that defines who I am what I do and how I do it better than the next
guy or gal business cards are small.
So this does not lend itself to big paragraphs of text.
So use this real estate wisely to say more with less.
There are all sorts of lovely effects you can apply to your business cards ever using an online printing
company like mu dot com.
You could apply a wonderful gold or silver foil stamping to give you a logo or another brand asset a
nice high end shine during the process of creating your first food marketing items you'll start to work
out certain layouts font sizes for particular things like I mentioned earlier.
For example working with this contact information I created a unique way of dividing the lines to display
the information.
This pairs well with the elements in my logo too.
There's a little bit of a theme there.
I could take this arrangement and use that on the letterhead layout or the business card layout displaying
the same information.
This is called brand consistency.
Using those similar layouts in different situations remember use your textures icons patterns or other
brand assets and find ways to incorporate those to continue that brand consistency.
In this example I'm using the repeat pattern I created from a few custom icons I created to create that
subtle background to complement the logo those who are illustrators or photographers may want to feature
your own work paintings photos illustrations to show that style whatever might capture the attention
of your target client or make them happy.
You could start to notice our theme throughout the items were creating.
We can easily apply this style to many different items.
T-shirts are a great way to start conversations with people while you're out and about networking or
just living your life.
I had a brand T-shirt with my logo and tagline on it and it landed several clients just by living my
normal life.
People are interested in what you are and what you do and what is on your T-shirt.
They're intrigued by it and so they ask you naturally some follow up questions.
So now that we developed our logo and some brand assets what file formats do I need to have these in
I'm going to be doing this yourself or hiring another person to do this part for you.
These are the formats I like to have my logos or brand assets and if possible the logos.
I'd like to have these in smaller J pegs larger PND pages can have transparent backgrounds as I like
to have these in vector format so as simple daddy I or illustrator file or a dot.
P.S. If using another program is great.
If you're getting your logo printed out and custom promo items a vector file is usually requested by
a printing company so it's nice to have one of those on hand we'll be uploading all of these exported
PMG and JPEG files that we have of our brand assets so we could start to put together a sample business
card front and back we're gonna be doing that in Adobe Illustrator.
But you could put this together in any program of your choice.
Once again these lessons focus less on using the software as many of you guys will be using different
software or some of you will be hiring someone to do these designs for you.
I'll focus more on how to extend your personal brand to other areas and less on graphic design as this
course is focused on freelancing and getting that personal brand ready to go if you're interested and
knowing how to use canvas in detail and how to create your entire brand in Canada.
I off offer a branding course for non designers.
Do it yourself non designers.
I also offer courses in all the Adobe software if you're interested in doing all this in Adobe software
OK we're ready.
We have all these brand assets we can pull from and are going to be doing that as you create all the
different assets you'll need.
You may not need a business card but you're going to need some kind of contact information whether it's
an email signature or some kind of way to display all your vital contact information.
So let's begin we have a two sided business card front and back.
I went ahead and pulled our headline.
This was kind of a little bit more generic than I'd like it to be this headline but there's several
more that I developed in that brainstorming process in the goal section of the class whereas coming
up with some kind of ways to talk about what I did and on one very simple statement I like to put this
in my business card because a lot of business cards will just have kind of your generic contact information
but they don't really tell you how you bring value like with my business cards.
I do elevate your business through design or something very similar to that.
They cut it tells them a little bit what you do more than just your title.
So I like to incorporate a little bit more of ideas and a little bit of text that way you never want
to overwhelm it too much if you can't say it in one sentence.
It's probably to be too long for a business card.
They're very very tiny.
You don't want to overwhelm a text.
Another great thing about having all of your branding standards manual developed.
I could start pulling all these assets that I need so I can go ahead and pull you know a logo over.
I can also have my type setup so I know what type of fonts I should use here for the headline and other
information.
So it's really just a matter of figuring out what I think would capture the imagination of a client.
What do I think would be a proper layout on the front in the back.
I like to have business cards that are front and back because they're really not that much more expensive
to get back these days.
And I'd like to put high quality upgrades and finishes to my business cards maybe a metallic ink foil
stamping and bossing go to move dot com if you want to get all those fancy effects but I like to do
that just because I don't mind spending a little bit more on my business card because I hand him out
very deliberately when I go meet people and I hand out a business card at somebody I've had a conversation
with someone I seriously want to pursue as a client.
I want to give them my best foot forward.
I'm going to give them a very high quality maybe even a little bit more expensive business card maybe
even you spend 50 cents even a dollar on a business card that's worth it a dollar if you're handing
that out to a high quality potential client or lead.
So let's continue to kind of fiddle around with the layout and we're just thinking about ideas we're
not thinking about graphic design I'm going to focus more on what what I'm including and why.
So we definitely want to have that headline over here.
So you to bring that headline we don't want to overwhelm people so it's going to make it a little bit
smaller.
I'm a big fan of putting the logo on both sides because you never know what side when they take it out
of their wallet or they take it out of their purse you don't know what side they're going to land on.
And I also like to do different contrasts on the side.
So instead of have two white sides I maybe have a darker background and then a lighter background or
the other way around.
I think it really helps to kind of add to the experience so you're just adding to the experience the
back of your card could even feature one of your works as long as maybe you have your logo or a watermark
mark somewhere on there so they can kind of see that work and see your name.
They want to connect your work in your name together.
So that's another great thing if you're illustrator especially a photographer or even a web designer
putting a little piece of your work a little snapshot on the back along with your logo really really
really helps.
So you need to make business cards fairly unique.
You know you kind of have the standard layout where you have the information over here and you kind
of have a typical layout but try to be creative even though you have to do contact information and clear
manner and you want to be consistent with your brand so continue to use the same typefaces throughout.
Find ways to get it to work or if you feel like your typeface or colors are not working please revisit
your branding inspiration and brand boards and all that stuff and branding standards and tweak it.
This is when you go back and forth in that creative process.
So some other things I'd like to include is I'd like to include obviously a Web site that's working
that they're going to drive them to the Web site.
That's the main focal point is not really the e-mail I'd like them to contact me but I'd like them to
contact me after they visited my Web site and portfolio because I want to get them sold before they
email me so that it would be a very soft sell for it to land that client they've already seen my work
I don't have to then send them to the Web site and keep going through that.
So the Web site Big bold beautiful.
That's what we want to have the Web site is going to be very prominent.
We could even bring in some of our colors I'm going to go ahead and copy and paste my color palette
so I have easy access to it.
So if we wanted to go ahead and switch things up we can so that'll be the main focal points is sometimes
putting your Web site away from the other contact information helps especially if you're doing its own
side because it really helps that user focus more on the Web site and not get lost among the other contact
information.
And also like to put a very obvious statement if my header making your small business ideas come to
life it's a little generic it doesn't actually say that I'm a graphic designer although we have a graphic
designer in her logo which is nice.
I wanted to have a very obvious statement almost like a title.
So if you want to say senior graphic designer or senior photographer or art director or illustrator
those are great to have titles.
Sometimes I'll put it in a phrase so offering full service graphic design or I can probably even rephrase
that a little bit to make it sound better but just kind of having something that's very very very obvious
what you do right when you look at it you're not playing in a games you're getting right to the point
so they can remember oh yeah she's the graphic designer I met in the elevator.
So that's exactly what you want to kind of do.
So I got to spend about 10 minutes rearranging everything and trying to find what I think is a suitable
layout already kind of did a couple of ideas here with an invoice and there's already some kind of brand
consistency I'm developing with kind of how I arrange everything so I'm going to do that and incorporate
that to have that brand consistency and I'll be right back.
So each one of these concepts are effective in their own ways.
That's why it's important to put together several different ideas and layouts to find out which one
you think would work in some cases even getting multiple different versions of your business card printed
for different situations.
The one here on the left really works well for high end clientele with this nice gold foil stamping
on the bottom and beautiful use of texture.
It's very clean and it reduces all the extra clutter.
I don't have the tag line and just focus on the offering full service graphic design as kind of the
main focal point on the front as well.
The Web site so it's very clean modern and really would do well at attracting a hiring clientele.
The one on the middle is very basic it's got the tagline on the top it's got my basic information as
everything it needs it even has a little sketching photo in the background using photo to kind of help
draw the user in and explain a little bit about what you do and how your process is different.
Of course we're a brainstorming design company so I put a little bit of that sketch pencil in the background
I thought that would be a fitting image for what we she does as a graphic designer on the bottom my
future her work on full display I would had an arranged a lot of her logos in a particular order and
was able to kind of put that on the back and of course with a big focal point on that Web site because
that's where they're going to be able to look at these in more detail and get case studies which we'll
be doing in the next section of the class creating our Web site portfolio in our PDA portfolio on the
right is kind of more of your everyday use I think it's kind of more flexible and adaptable to different
situations kind of your basic front and a very clean back not showing any work or photos but just kind
of showing what needs to be shown for the business card.
So three different layout ideas you know took about 20 minutes kind of brainstorm this you can of course
put this together in any program you like but it's kind of a little bit of my rough process of how I
think about business card and what needs to be on it not necessarily design but kind of the effectiveness
of the card.
So once again you're seeing a lot of two tone contrasts.
We have a bright front and kind of opposite darker back.
Not required but it is find that higher contrast nice as the user flips the card over they can definitely
tell the difference between the sides.