So let's take a look at another person here in this industry.
Let's take a look at Jack El.
He's also top rated so has a similar profile to the ones that we've written for Lillian.
And our first person that we studied so hi my name is Jack Larson.
I'm a web designer and front end developer based in Salt Lake City Utah.
So right away he's saying what he does.
I have been creating unique web sites for clients for over four years now.
I already know a lot about him.
He's has four years of experience creating Web sites.
Each of the Web sites I design and build are designed to capture a specific audience attention and keep
them engaged.
So he's talking about his unique style.
He designs Web sites that capture audiences attention and keeps them engaged.
So I already know so much about him in that first paragraph.
So this is what he can do I could build your Web site and custom HDR e-mails CSX and javascript if needed
I'm happy to build your web site using any content management system or web builder.
So he's really getting specific about certain technologies that clients might be looking for.
So that's it.
It's not super long.
And here's his kind of call to action let me know if you have any questions I'm happy to help.
So it's kind of a giving asking the person who's viewing it to contact them or reach out.
It's that natural call to action.
So they'd learn earn quite a bit on the platform.
So this profile has served them very well.
So let's study one more because I really want to make sure our profiles perfect since those are one
of the few things that can land us jobs at this point is our headshot our title and our profile we don't
have any prior work experience on the platform so we're going to have to have a really stellar profile
that impresses.
So one hundred and fifteen dollars now.
Wow.
That's the highest I've seen so far.
Let's see how she's done.
She's made over eighty thousand she's able to charge that rate and still get jobs so she must be a really
really successful really really talented.
So she has a little bit of a larger background since she charges so much per hour.
I think she has to go in a little bit more detail about why she charges so much per hour what makes
her so special.
So she's a web designer and front end web developer skilled in h t AML.
And she goes into everything that she does as well as template platforms including square space Shopify
and WordPress.
So in that first sentence I know what she does her title the software she has experience in and what
she can do all in the first line well done my extensive experience and background and graphic design
allow me to bridge the gap between design and development to create the most beautiful and highly functional
Web site.
So she's really talking about how she's unique her style and how she's able to take graphic design and
web design and make something that works well in the back end but also looks really good in the front
end so well well done well written profile so far.
So this is kind of where she talks about how she's different.
She draws inspiration from her background and 3d design principles and instills this awareness of physical
space and interactivity into all my.
So she's really saying kind of her unique perspective of how she works.
So she's worked with a free diverse clientele talking about her prior work experience.
So in addition to decaf digital I'm the owner and designer so continuing she's done a lot she's charging
one hundred fifteen dollars now or she has to go into a little bit more detail
so she doesn't necessarily have a call to action at the end of her.
Her last line is after studying architecture for two years.
I asked a little bit more of a resume major of an end what I would do to make this even better is have
kind of a I'd love to work with you to engage your customers some some kind of line that drives the
user to make a response to her.
So I think we've done a lot of steady work here.
I think I'm happy with our profile.
I think the length matches kind of more successful people.
I think kind of how we broke it down and to having we're explaining what we do or explaining the software
experience and work explaining our unique skill sets and how we're can apply our skill sets to what
we do and then we have the call to action at the end.
And I think I'm feeling pretty happy with this.
So let's go to employment.
So we're going to list past employment so they did work for a company before I'm going to list my company
so we're gonna go ahead and put the link that we were at this company.
So you guys may not have this experience to put yet it's not a big deal if you don't.
Do not worry about it.
Not everybody has prior work experience
so here we are we just finished our profile we go and get this published so we could start to get out
there for jobs would also start to submit proposals that we think we would connect and want to do.
We're just double checking our entire profile here.
We're going to go and click publish profile.
Congrats you're now part of the upward network.
Woo hoo.
So let's go ahead and look in our feed and kind of see it's go click on recommended kind of see what
we think would work really well.
So here's a creative designer monthly let's check it out.
I've got a reading write Arabic.
Don't think that's going to work out.
So you're not gonna be able to apply to every job you're going to be able to apply to a select few.
And people can also find you and search as well so they may ask you to submit a proposal.
And that's when we'll get into proposal writing.
And another note if you get your profile denied sometimes your profile can be denied.
I've had a couple students contact me and say Up work sent me this generic message saying they're not
accepting their skills sets at the time.
So sometimes up work will deny or profile for a couple of reasons.
And there's several tips on getting.
If your profile was not approved there's several kind of tips I got to supply several article linked
to articles that go into how to get your profile up and running and maybe resubmit for approval because
I've had some students change the profile five times and they finally got it approved.
So some of that's just based on the skill sets they put maybe that up work has too many freelancers
and those skill sets and you just have to adjust that a little bit.
I've known some students who change their skill sets and then change it back to the ones that they want
to do after they had their profile accepted.
There's all sorts of things you can do I'm going to post a couple of articles that I think would be
helpful in those kind of situations where you do find yourself where it didn't approve it like mine
was approved right away.
But hopefully if you went through the process like I did you write a really good profile and you're
in high demand skill sets you would.
You're not going to have any problem getting approved.
Here's a good one looking for a graphic designer ninja to work with the best team ever and it can be
full time or part time.
Let's kind of look at this a little bit more.
Let's look at a more detail.
So they're looking for three freelancers so this is we're having an amazing portfolio and profile are
really going to help you stand above the crowd.
You already have that we talked about how to build a killer portfolio that's clean and gets right to
the point with your projects.
We've already talked about how to write a really great profile or bio so we already have that already
given you a lot of things to hopefully get you above the stack on the top of the stack when you apply
to these types of jobs.
Let's go ahead and read through this.
See if we like it.
We're searching for talented designer to help us bring our next branding campaigns to life.
And hey I'm a logo design brand are Lillian as a logo design branding expert.
So our title will stand right out to them.
We're looking for someone to design a number of different categories food restaurant medical.
So we need to have advance knowledge of sketch and vision studio figure.
We already have the Adobe Creative Cloud other software says in your proposal and a lot of times people
will ask you for specific things in their proposal.
So make sure you read the entire item in your proposal please provide one or two paragraph summary of
your design experience and why you'd be a great fit for this work.
So we already have that also include two relevant samples that show your best design work and creativity.
So we already have that and have those first two projects.
Guess what I can probably even submit those pages of my PDA portfolio that we created as well or at
least take snapshots or get those images we used.
So we already did this.
We don't have to do any extra work we've already done this.
We have two projects that we can show and we already have some summary and a bio of what we have done
and experience in the past.
OK so when you find a project that you think will fit go ahead and submit a proposal course you might
have to do some verification of your I.D. and my I.D..
So I went through that process where I had to submit a driver's license to be able to apply to jobs
in the U.S..
So you'll be in a different country.
You may have different requirements so I did that and to be able to submit proposals I wanted to talk
about Connex for a little bit.
You'll have to have 20 connects.
So this is when you're able to spend those to be able to submit proposals or reach out to clients.
Course they can always reach out to you anytime.
This is for you applying and reaching out to jobs.
So you get 20 when you start and you can always buy additional ones or you get the plus plan which you
get 70 each month or the free after you spend the 20 they're going to cost a little bit.
And so that's kind of how up how up work makes money they make a little bit of money from the people
who are seeking out jobs and they like make a little money from freelancers like you.
This is how they stay in business.
This is part of the how it works.
But fourteen ninety nine is not bad if you start getting a lot of client work that can help pay for
that but you don't need to pay for anything right up front you still get 20 to use a guy to use and
very wisely you know really pick those ones that you want to to be able to send the proposals.
So let's say we want to submit a proposal on a project where we were last time that so this particular
one requires four of our connects and we have 20.
So we have to really make sure if it's a really high connect requirement.
So this case for a basically is the same as coins or currency if it's a very high.
So for it we got to really make sure we won it because then after that after we run out of 20 we have
to pay 15 cents for each one or get some kind of monthly subscription to be able to get 70 each month.
Was go ahead and submit a proposal so we need to figure out how we're going to be paid.
It could be paid by milestone.
So that's dividing the project in smaller segments called Milestones when you complete a milestone let's
say you develop a logo and you're done with that logo concept and it gets approved.
That's a milestone and you get a little bit of payment.
And then when you submit the final files you get the remainder of the payment or you could do it by
project get paid at the very end.
So I like to do by by Project is a little bit more simple.
But if you have longer projects I I would suggest the milestone.
So we're doing a web design project that's going to take a month or two definitely milestone because
you don't want to wait till the very end to get paid.
We're going to use the knowledge that we learned about pricing projects and to fill this out.
So bid how much do we want to bid for this.
We kind of read a little bit about the project this is a different project than the one I was on just
a few minutes ago.
So we're going to do two hundred and so this is going to be the up work service fee.
So these are kind of things that another way that up work makes money.
This is how these platforms work.
You've got to get paid to be able to connect to clients you've got to understand that's part of the
business.
So I'll end up receiving after fees one hundred and sixty dollars for this I think this is just a simple
logo needed in vector files needed.
So this is a really low low price this is lower than what Lillian or I would ever be happy with.
But I don't have any social proof on the platform I'm hoping if I do really good and I get this job
I get paid a little less than I would charge if I ran into a client or found a client locally I would
charge four hundred dollars but since I'm trying to build up my social proof and reviews this is part
of what I have to do.
So timeline so you need to be realistic with this.
If you could do it in a week do it in a week of it's going to take three to six months.
You just need to be very realistic here.
So going to second do this in a week is a very quick job cover letter.
We're going to kind of write adapt our bio a little bit to this or we're just going to put our bio in
here and we're going to attach it sometimes they required like that one job was requiring our two projects.
So this is where your PDA portfolio you may think that was old school or who needs a PDA portfolio we
need it all online.
This is where having the PDA portfolio really helps because you can attach that you can export only
certain pages or certain projects out of your PDA portfolio if you want to show off of certain certain
projects so let's utilize what we did already earlier in the class.
Let's go to go ahead and attach that PDA if all right.
We're going to submit our proposal yays.
We're gonna go ahead and submit it and kind of see what happens.
We're going to go apply for a couple more jobs so I can spend all of the connects that I have spent
all 20 and cannot hopefully maybe one of those will contact me.
And for the jobs that can be accepted for the job also with up work they can contact you by looking
at your profile and finding you on the search.
So there's ways that they can require you to submit a proposal without you having to submit one but
do a combination always use your connects if you have any for free use them all.
Go ahead to apply to the top jobs you think you have the best if you're the best candidate for don't
apply to jobs that are out of your skill range apply to ones that are maybe under your skill range.
So have a higher probability of getting those first couple jobs to get some social proof on the platform.
So we created an up work profile and we already applied to a couple of jobs.
So now we just wait and hope that we get connected.
But this is just one Web site.
There's so many other ones to explore.
So I created an excellent resource full of all sorts of great quality freelancer Web sites for you to
also create profiles on just so you can increase your chances of landing a job.