Online portfolios are a little more fun to create.
We now have the ability to glued video on our Web sites as well as ad motions animations and interactions.
So the biggest question I get is where do I build my Web site.
Do I need my own Web site or can I just host my portfolio and a third party Web site like Be hands.
Dot com.
The downside to hosting your portfolio on a third party Web site is you lose control over your portfolio.
That Web site can close down at any time.
Taking your portfolio with it another great benefit of having your own Web site is having a professional
domain name.
You can purchase a domain name on Web sites like GoDaddy dot com for a fairly cheap price depending
on what you want your domain name to be.
I can look up Lilian Hernandez on GoDaddy to find her domain name would be fairly cheap once you purchase
a hosting plan.
You can link up your domain name with your hosting plan and you're ready to go.
Lilian Hernandez dot com are Lilian Hernandez designer dot com sounds a lot better and easier to remember
than be hands.
Dot com slash Lilian Hernandez.
There are a lot of options when it comes to finding a good hosting plan.
I've used GoDaddy in the past and they've been the cheapest.
They also have the option of automatically installing WordPress for you seeing it started right away
building your web site using Wordpress.
Square space is a great alternative.
They provide hosting and a Web site builder that includes some pretty great looking templates.
There's the ability to customize a square space Web site but it's a little bit more limited than a wordpress
template or Web site.
If you're looking for a super polished out of the box template Web site or design then square space
is worth checking out.
There's also the option of building your portfolio on Adobe's portfolio building solution called Adobe
Portfolio.
This is free if you're an Adobe Creative Cloud subscriber.
This also includes free hosting and a great Web site builder.
Although do you find it a little limiting when it comes to total customization like you can do with
that WordPress Web site.
Speaking of WordPress WordPress offers a combination of ease of use and customization.
I use WordPress myself for over 10 years for my business before switching over to the Adobe Portfolio
option.
I use godaddy as my host for my wordpress Web site and also to purchase my domain name.
This was the cheapest solution as WordPress basic templates are free.
Once you learn Wordpress and understand the basics of how templates work and working with plug ins you
can create just about anything even from basic templates.
There are tons of fantastic premium wordpress themes so these costs money each with their own style
and layout focus.
There are some themes that offer out of the box total customization and do not require any coding knowledge.
One of those themes is called a Veda.
I will be listing in the resource guide several great places to find wordpress themes.
If this is the route you plan to go I'll also list several themes that I've used in the past that I
think are not only flexible but would also make great portfolio websites.
I'll be teaching a wordpress course that teaches the basics of getting WordPress set up and learning
all the ins and outs like setting up your plug ins your widgets themes and adding and customizing templates.
I'll be teaching this alongside my buddy Jonathan Davis.
If you're interested in going into more detail about building out a wordpress Web site I'll briefly
touch on the basics but it would take quite a bit of time to go through everything in this course we'll
be focusing on building an Adobe Portfolio Web site and we'll also as I mentioned before be showing
the very basics of building a wordpress Web site and walking through choosing the right template for
a freelance business later on we'll be focusing on building our profiles on several freelancer Web sites
and also building a b Hanscom portfolio as we work through the creation of all these different portfolio
types.
It gets only easier and quicker as we already have gathered our descriptions or photos.
We have our layout ideas we have several graphics now it's just a matter of using different Web sites
and software to maximize our potential and our presentation before we get started.
Building our online portfolios and profiles.
I wanted to show you another downloadable resource that walks through several layout ideas for online
portfolios which when you decide to go with really depends on what will show off your work the best
and what industry you're in.
There are thousands of layout choices some which are not listed but these will give you a head start
in thinking about your layout for an online portfolio.