Let's do another practice quote Before we move into developing our client contracts.
Hi my name is Dave and I'm a Marketing Manager from the big coffee place Inc.
And I was sent your contact information from a trusted colleague.
I was telling him that we needed a custom one time illustration for an upcoming ad we wanted to place
in a national campaign this fall to promote our new pumpkin spice cappuccino.
We are contacting two other illustrators but wanted to see if you did not mind sending us a quote for
this project.
I've attached a sample of the scope of the illustration we will need for the ad if you have any questions
feel free to reach out to me personally.
There is a lot to break down here.
First of all the client is large.
This is a national chain similar to maybe a Starbucks.
This would be a huge thing for our portfolio.
When a client is large the danger of pricing too low is the idea of perceived value when we price too
low.
They may assume we are more amateur than anticipated are new to the business because we did not know
how to properly value or price ourselves.
If we over price we could risk losing this job to the other two freelancers.
There is a fine line here and we're going to do our best to read between the lines and to find the right
pricing so let's review our scales here to help us find out where this project might land.
It's a large client with one single project.
Let's once again try for fixed pricing model just because of its simplicity but also because the fact
that the client is expecting a fixed price quote based on the project type and how that is standard
in the illustration arena the client size they're huge national chain.
They would fit squarely into the Tier 3 client box.
So we're going to have way more pricing power to the upside secondly project exposure is high.
It will be a national campaign and several magazines and maybe even digital ads.
We can always ask follow up questions about whether will be outside of the print medium to get a better
sense of the project exposure or scope.
Lastly experience level let's say I am an intermediate level illustrator and I've done illustrations
for three to five years.
I have a little pricing power but it's not unlimited.
Let's put all this together with the research we gathered about similar projects in the industry by
looking at community posts from Google and other sources.
This is the fix project scale I have price projects on before.
Based on those three factors I feel comfortable pricing above what I've ever priced before but not a
huge jump but a modest jump considering I've never worked with a national client before two thousand
dollars seems a bit too rounded.
Let's tweak that and say twenty one hundred dollars.
That number feels a little bit more customized to the client.
Let's place this quote on a formal proposal and maybe even customize this proposal with some illustrative
work just to impress them when they need to be impressed the most we heard back from the client and
we got the job yay.
Two things.
Now we need to think about first of all client contracts with larger clients.
They usually have one ready to go just to make sure it protects you as a freelancer as well as them.
We'll focus a little bit more on contracts and the next section of this course.
Secondly we need to adjust our pricing scale.
There was no hesitation on the client's end.
They accepted it without any issues or pushback.
That means there's a good chance we could have gotten away with charging more.
Let's readjust our scale a little higher so that next time we have a client and a similar range we can
go for a little bit of a higher pricing.
This is exactly how pricing gets easier the more projects he complete.
It's important to assess client reactions to each project quote to gauge whether your pricing too high
to low or just right.
Rarely you will nail it on the first few quotes but at least you now have a few ways to help you feel
more confident and pricing those projects.
We can also use the same scale for our hourly rate.
We know we'd like to have 32 dollars per hour to maintain or desired annual income but we could take
our hourly rate and put it on the same scales to find out if we need to charge prices lower higher depending
on client size budget and project exposure.
So you've landed a client congratulations.
Now what.
How do we handle client projects timelines and even contracts.
We'll talk about that in the next section.
See there.