Are you ready for a student design challenge.
This one is going to be a bit personal.
Your task is to create a personal brand for yourself or your freelance business.
You may be a graphic designer web designer illustrator or creative writer but all of us have something
personal about us that makes us unique.
I want you to create a logo that best represents your unique approach to your craft.
This could be with use of color symbols abstract art or something and it has personal value to you and
your business.
Branding is more than just a logo the logo is a small part of this or the student project.
The only requirement is to create some sort of logo and name presentation but also to combine it with
other brand assets.
This can be a business card.
A simple letterhead or just a simple social media post using your brand and extending your brand out
to one item so we can see how this works in action.
I would love to see your work so make sure you post in the community area of the course you're currently
taking our post in the student Facebook group or just message me your work.
Remember the following when creating your personal brand.
Number one.
Remember that personal branding is hard.
It could be very introspective and require you to really think about your style skill and uniqueness.
Number two that personal brand development is about hitting your desired target audience.
What type of clients do you want to attract number three that you may go back and forth between lots
of great concepts and still not be able to settle on one.
That is why submitting concepts to a community can be helpful and helping you think and process through
which one might work out best for you if you want to follow the entire personal branding process.
I do so in my freelance masterclass for creatives course that's on both skill share and Udemy.
You are not required to be a student or enroll to participate.
Everyone is welcome.
I look forward to seeing what you guys come up with and I'm expecting this to be a highly active student
design challenge with lots of great projects submitted.