We're going to do a case say now on Linked In Specifically we're going to build a model for Linked In
.
OK.
So by the end of the next two sections you will know how to analyze or build a financial model which
is a crucial skill the analysts should understand in order to be able to value companies.
Once you get past the next two sections you'll know how to model companies.
And then we'll focus on how do you value companies.
OK.
So in terms of the what I going to use Excel and forecast the future.
Okay I remember everything as a percent of revenue.
This will all kind of make sense to you soon.
Okay.
In terms of why are we doing this well well you have to forecast a model if you're going be able to
come up with a target price.
Okay.
And in terms of how we're going to do this well we're going to take everything we've learned so far
.
Okay.
Everything.
And build this model.
Okay.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
Don't worry though if this seems a bit complicate because this will all make a ton of sense by the time
you complete the exercises in this course.
Don't worry.
I'm here to help.
If you have questions.
OK so there's a lot of information in the model I'm going to be showing you in this section OK so please
assume that we are at the beginning of 2016 when we build this model.
Okay.
And please note when you make your models build on them really really slowly take your time okay.
One brick or a step at a time.
Okay.
And we're going to do a more basic model in the next section.
Okay then we'll analyze it in a lot of detail and just remember that after you build your model for
a while once you start piecing it together then what will happen is you'll have this incredible aha
moment.
Okay.
And lastly please keep in mind that Rome was not built in a day. Alright. Let's get started.