Financial model exercise introduction we're getting there.
OK so by the end of this section you'll understand how to forecast an income statement a balance sheet
and the cash flow statement.
So what are we going to do.
We're going to model the three aforementioned financial statements.
OK.
And you'll have a good understanding of how the three statements worked together as well.
There's a link between all of them.
OK.
In terms of why we're doing this well we know so that we can move on to the next section after modeling
which is valuation.
So we can find a target price for the company that we're analyzing and in terms of how we're going to
do this well we're going to continue to use Excel.
We're going to use the financial modeling skills that I've taught you in this course.
And so that instead of eating watermelon like a boss you'll be able to modify initials like a boss.