Let's talk about the cash flow statement by the end of the section you'll understand why a casual statement
is important and how it's additive to the income statement and what is the relationship between all
three of these financial statements.
And then once we understand the connection between the three financial statements then we can learn
about how to create a financial model.
And that's the fun part.
So what is a cash flow statement.
I'll explain in more detail in the next next lecture.
Why are we doing this.
While we're doing this so that we can understand what is accurate and not accurate about the income
statement because equal statement gives you net income but the net income is not always cash and cash
is king.
OK.
How are we doing this while we're to do it with Excel of course and you'll go through an example with
me.
And basically if I give you the balance sheet and the income statement you can calculate the cash flow
statement from scratch.
And so when you do financial modeling you focus on revenue right in the income statement the balance
sheet then talks to the income statement and you didn't have to worry about forecasting the cash flow
statement because it's all done automatically in Excel.
Right.
So again to make a cash flow statement all you need to have are two things.
Number one the income statement number to the balance sheet.
Then you can make it and we'll make a couple to get