All right let's build on the logic from The Last Lecture.
OK.
So we calculated the net present value.
Right.
But what about the free cash flows.
After that last year into infinity that's got to be worth something.
Well how do we account for that.
Well that's called the terminal value the cap and the terminal value calculation is a lot easier than
you think.
So what you do is this you need to calculate the terminal value.
So you take your interest rate which is 7 percent in cash and then you've got to get the long term growth
rate which we assume is 2 percent.
And don't ever assume that a company can grow more than 1 2 or 3 percent into infinity okay.
Look at the U.S. economy.
Hey it's it's a big company it's 25 percent global global GDP but it can't grow more than a couple percent
just because it's big whatever.
So big companies don't grow very much.
OK.
So long term growth is usually one two or best case 3 percent but more likely one or two percent.
OK we cut our interest rate which is 7 percent.
We've got our long term growth rate which we assume is 2 percent here.
So the terminal value formula calculation is as follows.
You take the last year free cash flow.
Okay.
So that's 1100 point for you multiply by 1 plus the long term growth rate.
And then you divide it by interest minus the growth rate.
Okay.
Makes sense.
So remember it's got to be that final year's free cash fall again.
Times 1 plus the growth rate divided by interest minus long term growth rate.
And you might ask yourself way to second guess what the long term growth rate is higher than the interest
rate.
It really can never be OK because interest rates will never stay as low as they are today forever right
.
Interest rates are usually a lot higher.
What they are today
in
long term growth rate can never be more than a couple percent.
All right so let's do it and take our final your free cash flow.
You multiply it by 1 plus the growth rate is 2 percent divided by the interest rate minus 2 percent
.
So it's divided by 5 percent.
OK. Let's build on this slowly and wait for it wait for it.
We get our terminal value total of come on twenty two thousand six hundred fifty two.
And then there's one little step left which is you need to discount that twenty two thousand six hundred
$52 into today.
OK.
And you know how to discount already