All right are you ready for the financial model exercise.
This is a long one and Ken has a lot of work in this one.
I hope you enjoy it and if you haven't already watched the linked in model session in the previous section
please watch it particularly on how to forecast.
And if you haven't already watched all of the cash flow balance sheet and income statement sections
.
Also please make sure to watch those because this is really a crescendo this will be kind of an aha
moment.
Everything we've done so far in the course builds up to this and once we complete this and once you
feel comfortable with the concepts in this section meaning financial modeling then we'll move on to
the next section and we'll cover valuation which is even more fun.
OK so let me explain how to do this exercise you can either read this or I can walk you through it.
So when you model there's two really big important rules.
Number one is most things you model is a percentage of revenue that's why spend so much time forecasting
revenue.
And the second thing is really important is to make sure to look for trends in the data that's all financial
modeling is right.
It's forecasting based on a number of data points in the past know one data point doesn't make a trend
but a bunch do.
OK.
So Step 1 is optional you can read through the modeling guideline and best practices.
Okay.
And step two is there are many many gray shaded boxes like this guy here.
OK.
And what I recommend is come up with the answer first.
Do your own calculations and then take the box off to see if you're right.
Oh can you say OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH OH.
OH
OK.
And I'll go through all the answers in the next lecture.
And then please play around.
Step three play around with the model OK because these four tabs they're similar to what we did in the
LinkedIn model in the last section.
But I want to play around with them and see if you understand the relationships between all four.
OK so it changed a couple of numbers around.
See what happens if you change up the balance sheets that the items don't balance anymore.
That sort of thing.
OK and then you can take this with this model as well and you can make your own financial models based
on this as well.
Remember every model for every company is a little bit different.
OK.
A little bit different but this is actually a pretty good framework for you.
And again in the next lecture I will give a comprehensive review of the answers as well as how all the
financial statements are linked and exactly what each item means.
All right.
Cool.
So what you'll do again is you'll just go through all four tabs and you'll calculate everything you
think goes under this gray box here and then remove it and see if you got the right answers.
And if you don't know the right answer just click through to see the formulas.
OK.
And you know this is nicely set up so you can always look in the formula bar here you know where you
might be right or wrong that sort of thing.
And the same thing goes with the income statement and the balance sheet and the cash flow statement
as well.
And one last thing what ever you do don't remove this box.
OK.
All right.
Enjoy the exercise