Let's discuss the income statement in more detail and make him statement we'll tell you how much money
is coming into you.
OK.
And that's called revenue or sales which is the same thing.
And some people call it the top line because revenue goes at the top of the income statement.
And the bottom line what is your bottom line.
That's net income.
At the very bottom.
OK.
And it also tells you money out of cash is revenue or money in minus money out or expenses equals net
income.
Pretty simple.
Great.
So let's drill down a little further.
OK.
And we're going to talk about an example here.
You have a company and you sell apples.
OK and you sell them for $2 each.
And that's a Canadian to our coin.
It's a polar bear.
Pretty cool.
OK so you sell an apple for $2 each cat isn't.
You sold six apples.
OK so that's 12 dollars in revenue.
Now in terms of expenses it costs you a buck to make one apple.
OK.
That's a Canadian $1 bill called Allouni represent canape here.
So it costs us a buck each to make an apple.
Right.
And we made 6 apples.
And so the costs of goods sold right.
Is 6 bucks.
OK so revenue minus expenses right equals the revenue minus the cost of goods sold right equals your
gross profit.
Okay.
Move on.
And then we have labor right.
You work in this great company and you made a buck.
Okay.
And there's another expense called depreciation.
And this is a beautiful thing but it's not cash out of your pocket.
Let me drill down explain in more detail.
Okay.
So you buy a truck right.
Your truck is going to last you for 10 years you pay 10 bucks for it.
Right.
And so every year you're allowed to depreciate that truck.
OK.
There's wear and tear on it and basically that means that you're going to pay less tax.
And this all makes sense a second OK.
So over 10 years we get to write off 10 bucks a buck this year.
And then we get back next year.
Yada yada yada.
Rinse lather repeat you get 10 bucks.
Cool.
And so that is depreciation get.
And it's a beautiful thing because what we're to do now is calculate taxes and we're to pay a little
bit less tax if we if we didn't appreciate this truck we pay more tax right.
OK.
So what is our tax going to be.
Well our pretax net income is four bucks fall by six months one month one four bucks.
We're get taxed on that four bucks now.
It.
If we did it and we pay a buck in taxes which is say 25 percent let's pretend the tax rates 25 percent
.
If we didn't depreciate that one dollar right for the truck then we would pay taxes on five bucks.
Right.
Which means that we would have paid more in taxes.
OK.
So now net income is three bucks.
Now let's take a closer look.
Revenue earnings.
OK.
Revenue is what we're going to spend a huge amount of time on in this course.
It's more important than any other line item on any financial statement.
And the reason is that once you forecast revenue everything else in your financial models pretty much
is just a percent of revenue.
OK and this will make a lot of sense to you when we do the modeling section of the course.
So the top line is 12.
And the bottom line is three