Investor Relations Investor Relations helps you understand the company better investor relations submit
press releases and financials to SBC dot gov.
So you and I have the same access to information at the exact same time for free as the big hedge funds
and mutual funds do Investor Relations sets up and leads quarterly earnings calls and we'll look at
an example this soon.
But basically companies have to release earnings four times a year.
OK.
Public companies.
And what happens is investor relations issues a press release four times a year usually when the market
closes.
Half hour later they lead an investor conference call.
You'll see a webcast.
And you and I can get access to it just like everybody else in the world because it's available free
on the open internet and Investor Relations sets up management presentations at events where to look
at Investor Relations and our case study for the remainder of this course is going to be linked in.
Let's check out linked into Investor Relations Web site and most large publicly traded companies have
superb web sites that have Investor Relations resources for everybody.
And in 2002 a new law was created called Regulation F.D. which means fair disclosure and it's awesome
because everybody gets access to financial information and material information at the exact same time
and that's great for you and me because we have the same access to information that everybody on Wall
Street or in the large mutual funds and hedge funds do.
It's awesome.
They no longer have the edge on us anymore.
Let's check out linked in business and so we can go through here and learn pretty much everything you
need to know about the company.
Letter about the management team.
They've got a superb management team.
Jeff is awesome.
The investor relations group is amazing there too.
And actually I recommend that you sign up for these as well.
Right you can enter in your e-mail address.
And the second they released something to SCC dot gov which will cover in a couple of lectures.
The second they issue a press release and the second they announce a new event.
You will find out at the exact same second as everybody else.
And so it's always a best practice for you to sign up for e-mail alerts for any company you're looking
at.
And so when I worked in the hedge fund industry I would have 30 or 40 companies e-mail alerts hit me
almost every day or every other day.
OK so you can find out more about the management team here.
Right.
You can learn more about linked and obviously you can find out more information about the board of directors
the Investor Relations team and just F-8 cues are frequently asked questions and this here is Matt Sonnenfeld
.
I think he's actually the best investor relations person on the street.
He also heads up investor education there too he's awesome.
Good guy too.
All right.
So let's see what else we can look into.
So we've looked at the management team a little bit.
You've got upcoming events here and anybody can listen these webcasts.
It's incredible just fill this stuff out.
You don't have to get invited to the Palace Hotel in San Francisco to Washington present you and I have
the same access as everybody else now.
It's awesome.
Ok cool.
And the same with Morgan Stanley.
They had an event right.
They had Keynote with the CEO Jeff Weiner.
You can click here and you can watch it or sign up for it again.
Right.
So pretty cool stuff.
All right.
And you can even look at the presentation from past earnings releases that sort of thing that's pretty
neat printing.
So see what else we have here.
All right so we've got their quarterly numbers here as well.
And so when a company issues earnings.
OK what happens is usually at 4:00 New York time a press release will hit and companies release earnings
four times a year once a quarter and the press release hits the tape and then reads it really fast.
And then about a half hour or so later there is an earnings call which we'll talk about later on in
this course.
Let's just take a quick look here at the press release.
OK.
So LinkedIn release fourth quarter numbers and this is pretty much like all press releases you'll see
they always say really good stuff at the beginning.
They had a great quarter Bob law whatever.
All that good stuff.
And then they'll talk about a couple of cool revenue metrics so here revenue increased 34 percent year
over year.
Right in the quarter to that dollar amount.
Okay.
And then they'll talk about their three revenue line items that they have and we'll go through this
in a lot of detail later on in this course.
So they have three major red line items and we'll talk about that at length later.
And this is important.
They offer something called guidance acads the business outlook where they say while we think in the
first quarter we're in a half revenue in earnings of whatever amount it is and they usually give a range
.
Right.
And then they give guidance sometimes for the full year as well.
And if this guidance is better than the Street expected then the stock goes up and vice versa.
And I think they actually gave poor guidance when they released this earnings result the stock went
down.
I thought it was broken.
A broken stock and not a broken company and I get excited when companies that are incredible secular
growth winners like linked and sell off a lot.
It's always a good opportunity to buy in cash.
And it's interesting because Warren Buffett once said that the New York Stock Exchange is the only store
in the world where consumers sell stuff that goes on sale.
And so what happens is you have prepared remarks from the CEO.
Right.
And then the CFO says a couple of cool things about the quarter.
And then what happens is way way down here they have all the financials.
And so we're viewed how this stuff works.
In previous sections in this course here is the balance sheet.
Right.
And they always provide it on a quarterly basis and they provide a couple of other balance sheets from
past periods as well so you can compare quarter over quarter moves like here over here.
Or you can even compare your year moves like here over here like look at that cash increase by that
amount year over year in cash.
And so this is the entire balance sheet.
And then here we have the statement of operations and this is basically an income statement.
Can they get revenue the top and they've got all the expenses just like we covered.
Right.
And then there's noncash stuff like depreciation cash and then they have information on the cash flow
statement right here.
And so just like we created in the last section we start off with net income right.
This is cash flow from operations net income from the income statement and then we add back all this
other stuff including this which is from the income statement and a bunch of other things as well.
Most of them are from the balance sheet of cash.
And then they have financing activities investing activities just like we talked about before.
And then they have supplemental information and this is really important because they only gave us total
revenue up above in the income statement but here it's cool because they are now giving us a number
of different revenue line that it is.
So that total revenue number is broken down into a couple of different sections.
Okay.
Right here they have all their major revenue line items.
And then here they have it by geography.
Okay.
And sometimes I don't know if I'm going to use this stuff in my model but I put in my model anyway just
in case I use it in the future.
Can and then have revenue by channel field sales versus online sales and these are basically quota carrying
sales reps.
Right.
They have a quota each quarter.
And then these might be telephone sales people.
And then there's something called gap in non-HD gap in the financial statements we created so far at
least the income that we created so far was a gap.
Okay and I'll explain what this means in more detail in future lessons.
But let me mention it quickly here.
So gap is generally accepted accounting principles.
Okay.
And it includes every item cash items non-cash items like depreciation etc. and then there's something
called non-GAAP and non-GAAP is another set of financial statements that's easier to understand than
the income.
We looked at because non-GAAP only has stuff that is cash base so depreciation would not be included
in non-GAAP and it only includes stuff that's ongoing So if there's a one time legal issue that was
in one quarter non-GAAP wouldn't really have that because non-GAAP is used by many Wall Street analysts
to model recurring stuff longer term.
And again we'll come and see it later but this year is just a table telling you how to reconcile between
the non-GAAP and the gap.
And so the way you get non-GAAP in this case here is you take the accounting earnings and then you add
back stuff that was noncash.
Right.
So if you gave employee stock based compensation that's not really a cash based line item.
And the same thing goes with not cash other stuff like depreciation etc. We covered that already.
Correct.
And then at the bottom here of the press release they say hey we're going to have our results webcast
in conference call very soon blah blah.
So it looks like it was access when he was an hour after the market closed that day.
OK.
That's 2 p.m. San Francisco Temperatures 5 p.m. New York time which is an hour after 4:00 p.m. and then
they say here put this on your radar screen.
We're going to have pretty cool events that you can come to or you can listen to over the Internet.
And then there's a bunch of legal disclosures and if you have additional questions you can contact LinkedIn
investor relations.
There are Alington press right there as well.
So let's see what else they have when it comes to financials interactive statements.
Looks cool.
Ok cool.
So what you can do here is you can look at every line item in all their financial statements and there
are cool charts that pop up.
I think you know the rights of sales and marketing.
Remember the best analysts in the world look for trends in the data you know learn to read financial
statements like a good book.
And here we have sales and marketing trends over the past several quarters whatever it is.
And this is all the raw data here a lot of times it's easier to look at charts because you can pick
up trends.
Right.
So looks like all their expenses are increasing revenue is to see revenue here revenues increase and
of course.
Okay.
And then oh cool this is new you can build the chart can actually map out everything here.
I usually do it directly in Microsoft Excel but you can actually create them here directly.
That's pretty cool.
There must be no cash flow as well and an earnings per share in diluted earnings per share just means
non gap.
And again we'll cover that more detail.
And this is what I love right here.
You can export the financials directly.
OK so that you don't have to go and create the financial statements from scratch and it's pretty pretty
good idea for you.
Well let me just pull this into view.
You know you've got a lot of great information here