The next methodology that we're going to look at is this dude right here and this is price to revenue
and this is great if a company is not profitable and won't be for long time and growth investors love
this.
Right.
And what you do is you basically look at the price to revenue.
You think the company will be under three different scenarios.
Right.
So if we're bearish and you know Internet stocks U.S. trade at higher price revenue multiples than this
.
But let's just say it's five times.
So this is five times revenue right.
In each each one of those years that's revenue up there OK.
And then this is just five times that five times that amount.
Right.
And then 2020 that's our revenue estimate five times that amount.
Okay.
And then we take this divided by numbers shares right.
And that's the target price.
And so this is the bear scenario at five times in a bullish scenario which is too bullish obviously
but I'm listening anyway 10 times revenue.
And again 10 times revenue here would be 10 times revenue.
That's a market demand of a number of shares for that price.
Okay.
But we've got to discount them.
Let me get there in a second the just right one is in between the five and 10 times in this hypothetical
example and that's 7 1/2 times armed.
And so in this case we're in it take 7 1/2 times revenue and the target price by that year of that amounts
.
But we got to discount that 484 bucks to today's price.
And so we do that by dividing by 1 plus the whac right from the previous tap to the power forks or just
you know in that over 1 2 3 4 years.
And that's our price