All right let's talk about the financial model exercise.
Answers we'll kick it off with the revenue tab.
So right here what goes under this box for all four corners.
Well it's actually just an addition of revenue line one into from below.
And in terms of what goes under this box here.
Well it's just a percent total.
So this is total revenue up here right.
Which is that plus that well it's just this divided by that.
That's the percent.
Ok cool.
In terms of revenue line item one of two right here while looking at pattern recognition.
This here would be 80 percent right because we went from 110.
Hundred ninety eight.
OK.
So right here this would be 80 percent.
All right.
And then here we'll just follow the same pattern 70 60 50 40 percent.
And then here it's just 80 percent times revenue in under here.
Again just pattern recognition.
This would be 80 percent as well.
All right let's go through the income statement now so depreciation is 5 percent sales across the board
.
Therefore it's also going to be 5 percent right here.
And in terms of what numbers go under this box for all four quarters.
Well it's just revenue from the previous tab right and it's green which means it links to another tab
and it has just toll revenue adds up revenue one in two from the previous tab.
Okay cool.
So in terms of cost a good saw percent of revenue.
Again we look at pattern recognition.
30 percent 28 26.
Well these will be 26 for all four quarters as well.
All right.
And then sales and marketing goes from 60 percent of revenue to 15 to 14.
Right.
So it's just going to be 14 percent times sales right and that will give you sales and marketing as
a percent of revenue here.
Okay.
And then then we have product development as a percent of revenue we go from 15 to 14 percent to 13
so under here is 13 as well as pattern recognition and then sales and marketing under here will just
be 13 percent times revenue right.
And again you can double click on any formula here or box here to find out what the formula is.
Okay.
All right TOSCAN sold as a percent of revenue we go from 24 to 22 at 20.
Therefore here on a quarterly basis it's also 20
22 20 18 16 14 12.
Okay.
Now sales and marketing goes into this box here.
Well it's just 12 percent because we are 13 12 in the quarter.
The numbers are the same in this example as the annual numbers.
And then here we go 12 11.
Again it's 11 percent under here.
And then depreciation is always 5 percent.
Same here.
And then GNAS here is just going to be 10 percent.
Okay.
And then sales marketing here it's expensive ones who cause 11 10 9 8.
And then with product development again pattern recognition 12 11 10 9 8 7.
OK.
So margins are improving and we're actually getting margin expansion here.
And then DNA goes from 11 to ten nine eight seven six.
Right.
Nice leverage kicking in.
And then with other income that's pretty small so it's it's ones all the way across for a total of 4
for the year.
And of course the same thing here for the annual numbers in the future.
Okay.
And then for tax we know it's 30 percent across the board.
Right.
And then what goes under this one here it's just 30 percent times pre-tax income.
And then here 30 percent across the board.
And same with this one here.
Okay.
And then for the share count Ulos it hasn't changed at all right so it's still 11 65 for every single
quarter in year.
So I think we covered everything here that we were good.
All right moving on.
And remember don't touch this one.
All right.
Moving on to the balance sheet.
Total current assets is simply an addition of all these non-present items here in cap ex is 10 percent
of revenue here right.
So we just multiply by 10 on the previous tab Okay.
And here CapEx is always 10 percent of revenue.
In our example cancer was always 5 percent across the board.
Okay.
Now we can actually do the same thing here.
Same for here.
5 percent across the board and then accounts receivable is just 5 percent time sales.
Right.
And then is always 11 percent of sales so he even carried this one here and this one is just 11 percent
across the board.
And in terms of cash Well the difference between this year and this year is cash is quite simply cash
here plus the cash addition from the cash flow statement.
Remember the cash flow statement always explains the difference in cash in one year and the next and
if you're confused you can always just double click here.
It'll take you directly to the appropriate cash flow statement field.
Now in terms of equipment CapEx as a percent of revenue is always 10 percent is pretty easy.
And then depreciation we got it from the income statement remember.
So that would just get pulled over directly and it's green because it's from another tab.
And then the calculation for equipment we own native Huli depreciation and inclusive of cut backs is
quite simply this You take last year's equipment.
Okay.
Net of all depreciation items.
And then what you do is you deduct depreciation from this year and then add back CapEx from this year
and accounts payable as a percent of revenues always 3 percent.
It's just pattern recognition here and CapEx when it comes to depreciation you're just looking directly
to the income statement here.
All right.
And then see if I forgot anyone here know or get a Coke.
All right long term debt here is just five across the board in this example.
And then shareholders equity is just retained earnings plus common shares and calculate retained earnings
you just basically look for the difference in net income year over year.
So you take the most recent quarter or years retained earnings.
And then you add net income.
Okay.
And again if you're confused or just double click and go to the other tab and understand the logic that
way cool long term debt here is 5 am retained earnings here.
Again it's just last periods retained earnings plus net income from the income statement up.
And one more over here.
Okay.
Total liabilities and shareholder's equity it's quite simply an addition of total liabilities Sheryl's
equity.
Right.
So that plus that.
All right we are done with the balance sheet.
Let's move on to the cash flow statement.
This is actually easier than you think because it's just numbers that are automatically linked to the
income statement and then the balance sheet.
And in terms of depreciation you pull it directly off of the income statement.
Okay.
Scared of this all right now in terms of accounts receivable looks like accounts receivable actually
went down and that's a good thing cash wise because we have a little more cash in our pocket.
Same thing with inventory in terms of accounts payable.
The inverse logic is true.
Now purchases of equipment you just linked directly to catbox from the previous tab.
And if you ever confuse what you can do is you hold commands on a Mac and square brackets see and it
goes directly here to cap.
It links directly it's a cool cool little trick.
All right.
Now cash in beginning a period and cash and in a period you just take beginning period plus the increase
or decrease in cash.
I'll show you what that means here.
OK.
And then you link directly to the cash flow statement.
So this here is the cash balance in the Cashell statement okay all the way across.
Right.
And this is cash from last balance sheet and cash from current balance sheet.
Okay.
And then here this is just a cool little calculation a test to see if these two are equal.
Right.
And in terms of net increase or decrease in cash it's just cash flow from operations plus cash flow
for investing plus cash flow for financing.
And then here similar to what we talked about here in the quarterly basis.
But on the annual basis you just take depreciation on an annual basis directly from the income statement
increase receivables.
Same logic you get it directly from the balance sheet.
And if it goes up then it hurts our cash.
It's negative.
And then increase in accounts payable is actually the opposite logic member that so if we owe more money
then we have more temporary cash in our pocket and that's a wrap