Now let's talk about ESI seacock in more detail.
OK and we can use LinkedIn as an example because this is our case study in this course.
So there's a number of different filings that companies have to file with SCC dot gov.
OK.
In fact every copy has publicly traded has to submit files on a regular basis to FCC dot gov so that
you and I have the same access information for free that all the large hedge funds and mutual funds
do.
So there's a bunch of different reports let me kick it off with the 10-Q.
This is a quarterly report and I'll show you an example in a couple of slides of this.
Companies have to file this quarterly and then there's an annual report called a 10-K 10-Q is Coralee
10-Ks annual.
OK.
And these are just lengthy reports that will tell you everything needs to know about a company.
Right.
The finance stuff the quality of stuff the management team the risks.
There's lots of lawyers in this country which is why all the risks are disclosed.
It's not about them.
OK.
And then an AK is basically a very important press release that has material information that might
move the stock.
Right.
They'll file press releases like this directly on sec dot gov called 8K and then you have an s one document
which is one of my favorite ones.
And this is basically an IPO prospectus and what that means is this when a company goes public investment
bankers write a lengthy document that will tell you everything you know about the company.
So you can make an informed investment decision as to whether or not to invest.
OK.
All this information is free and then there's a bunch of other filings called the three four or five
and 13-D.
This basically tells you who owns the shares or which executives at the company might have been selling
shares or buying shares.
OK.
All right.
Let's now go to Iraq.
Gov and I will show you how to navigate documents for Linked In.
This is your one stop shop for all information need to know about financials on the company you're analyzing
.
OK so so click here for company filings.
And then here I like to always enter in the Ticker it's faster.
L and K D.
Fairlington
and there's just a wealth of information here and this is sorted by date.
Okay.
And an 8 K as I mentioned earlier means a material for important press release.
This is the quarterly report called the 10-Q and this is an awesome one called The 10 k.
Right.
And before we do any of this let me do a search on the S one.
So when a company goes public by law they have to file what's called an s one.
OK.
And LinkedIn went public I think was during the summer of 2011.
So a couple of months before they go public they usually file the last one.
Let's take a look and let's click here.
And the last one is amazing because it basically tells you everything you need to know about a company
before you consider investing and there's so many lawyers in the U.S. which makes sure that every risk
is listed in this document which is a good thing for investors of course.
OK.
So this is what an IPO filing prospectus looks like.
And so Morgan Stanley was the leader OK on this IPO.
That's called Top left top right or the second and lead on this IPO is J.P. Morgan and these are the
other firms that were involved.
So usually you get a pretty cool visual understanding what the business is in the first couple of slides
here for an S1 and then you jump right into the text.
Right.
And you can read about the risk factors the use of proceeds from the IPO what would they do with all
that cash.
Right.
You can learn all but the management team the business model et cetera.
It's just an incredible document right.
Legal issues as well and all the financial stuff you need to know exactly compensation.
All good stuff.
Let me go back and just take a look at the most recent filing for the annual report which is the 10-K
and.
OK go.
OK cool.
So since the company's long in public since 2011 it doesn't have that many annual reports filed the
most recent one was filed in February of 2016.
Let's take a look.
Let's open it up here.
And this document is amazing.
I mean you've got everything you need to know about the company listed here.
This is a great way for you to get up to speed on a company.
You can read all about the business the risk factors everything you need to know right and of course
lots of financial stuff.
All right.
So they always kick it off with what is their business.
Right.
They are the world's largest professional network or 4 million subscribers.
Yadi at all good stuff.
And here's where you go to find out more about the competition.
Right.
So they mentioned that Facebook is a competitor Google to lesser extent Microsoft and Twitter.
I don't really think that LinkedIn has any credible competition.
And I actually can't think of another technology company out there that doesn't have any competition
literally.
I mean Google obviously is dominant in search but some people still use Yahoo.
I don't know who they are but they do.
And on some people use Bing whatever from Microsoft.
But but LinkedIn really doesn't have much competition.
It's incredible.
Here they talk about seasonality in the business which means some quarters are better than others.
And then we get into risk factors here.
And one of the risk highlighted his security right.
There's Web attacks all the time.
Here's another risk which is mobile.
I find that sometimes the mobile apps I've used in the past LinkedIn weren't that robust although it
is getting a lot better now.
And let's go back to the table of contents.
OK so we we looked in the business learned a little bit about the risks.
I always recommend reading the management discussion and analysis of the financial condition of the
company.
Right.
And you can read through this if you want but here is where they disclose more information on how each
region is doing and recall that was also in the earnings press release when we went to investor relations
.
And there's a lot of great data in here that's also included in the earnings press releases.
But this has much more additional details.
And here we have revenue by product and here's where we can go to read more about the financial statements
.
But we covered a lot of this in the Investor Relations section in this course but this is actually a
good resource.
If you can't get historical data going back many years on some companies right so sometimes they only
provide a couple of years of data on the Investor Relations Web site.
But you can always go to talk of and look back as far as you can and here's what we can read more about
the management team right.
Can they even actually disclose the salaries or know why they do that.
But anyway it's there and that is a 10-K and there's just a wealth of additional information on sec dot gov
.
If you have any questions about different filings please let me know.