Let's talk about the balance sheet exercise so similar to what you did with the income statement exercise
in the previous section.
Take these items which are sorted alphabetically OK.
And these items from 2015 and 2016 and simply paste them directly in the appropriate boxes here.
And if you're worried or have a concern about the year over year change then right.
Yes.
For concern and then write down why and if the answer's no you're not concerned then obviously don't
you know if the document why.
And please make sure that the balance sheet balances right.
So obviously it doesn't balance in both cases because we haven't put all the data in yet.
Right.
But make sure that you don't get an error message here.
I mean they both bounce.
And the reason this one already bounces is it's just a fluke because I guess you got 75 grand on each
side so enjoy the exercise after you're done.
Please take a look at the answers and then come back and see me please in the next lecture and we'll
go through the answers in more detail.
Thanks