So we always start with net income at the top of the cash flow statement.
And this obviously comes from the income statement and then we get one more item usually from the income
statement which is depreciation and amortization.
You just add it back because of course it's not a cash expense and after depreciation what we do is
we look at the change in working capital and working capital means current assets and current liabilities
.
Okay.
So you look at the current assets and current liabilities and the change and add those here okay.
So accounts receivable went up 170000 which means it's cash kind of out of our pocket.
And remember inventory was an absolute disaster last exercise we are looking at the balance sheet and
so where it is deducted here and we owe $15000 more than we did in the previous time period.
When it comes to accounts payable so that's a net cash temporary benefit for us so we put in your pocket
and that gets to cash flow from operations of this amount.
Okay.
Nothing to do here because there are no changes for these items on the balance sheet.
And lastly cash flow from financing.
We actually increased our debt a bit for short and long term as well as common shares and so add all
that stuff together.
This guy this guy and this guy and that gets you negative.
Two hundred ninety eight thousand five hundred dollars.
And I wrote here.
Please note the change in cash flow has to equal the balance sheet from the current year mice to bounce
sheet from last year's cash position.
So our cash position decreased by this much and the beautiful thing about the cash flow statement is
that you actually only need the income statement about you to make it.
So it's really easy.
And when we do the financial modeling section very soon you'll see that we don't really have to look
at the cash flow statement or really spend much time at all preparing it because it's automatically
prepared for us.
Once we create the income statement about the balance sheet it's automatically prepared because it's
all just calculations that are linked between the income statement of balance sheet.
This will make much more sense to you in a couple of sections.
Thanks