Next step we have the discounted cash flow exercise I'll go through the instructions quickly and then
please do the exercise.
And after you've completed the exercise please watch the next two lectures.
After the exercise because I'll go into a lot of detail on not just the answers from the exercise but
also a different way to look at relationships between some of the cells and just a better way to understand
financial modeling.
If you have trouble understanding the DCF please make sure that you've watched DCF lectures before this
current session.
OK so in this exercise we'll do step one.
It's optional is read this.
Step one is optional.
Read through the modeling evaluation best practices which I've covered in this course and then step
two what you'll do is you'll go on to the DCF tab here and there's a number of different boxes like
this one can and come up with the answer first and then take the box off to look at the answer.
And the best way to take the box off is to keep your finger on shift keep holding then shift click the
box take your finger off shift and then delete OK that's how it works.
That's a cat.
All right so what you do is you click on the DCF tab and just go through these and complete them from
top to bottom and you can you can move the boxes over by either clicking shift and drag and drop or
you can just delete them by clicking on shift click that take your finger off shift and then hit the
delete key.
OK.
And then again when you're done with this please come back to me for the answers and if you want I strongly
encourage this please go through the other tabs as well and delete certain cells or change things around
to see how your DCF valuation metrics change.
Ok really play around with these because the best way to understand and master financial modeling is
to mess around with a model like this one.
A fun