Let's talk about the quarterly earnings call.
It's an amazing resource.
It's incredible.
It's amazing for many analysts on the buy side and the sell side because what happens is by law the
company reporting earnings and companies report four times here they have to disclose all material risks
.
Right.
And so sometimes the only opportunity investors get to listen to managements you know talk about how
business is is during this call.
OK.
And so Horatio will get on the call and listen and so will know but sadly the sell say Alice will more
than likely ask questions for the rest of us.
OK.
And she'll help us understand complex accounting issues as well.
These earnings calls are usually save for at least 90 days.
In case you missed the call and couldn't listen to it live.
OK.
And again we had the same access that everyone else does at the same time.
So you can listen online live or you can listen later on in some companies even provide podcast which
is awesome.
And what happens is they start with the prepared script.
OK.
Investor Relations and a friend of mine Matt Sonnenfeld who's is probably the best investor relations
guy out there.
He'll read a script and he'll introduce the management team.
And I'll also read some legal disclosures as well because they might be making comments about future
guidance.
OK.
And lawyers love to get involved whenever that sort of thing happens.
And so the sell side analysts will then ask questions towards the end of the earnings call.
Right.
It's also ask questions for us on our behalf.
So which facial yields listener earnings calls anyway.
Well it's usually just the sell side and the buy side.
OK.
That's obviously Sally and Horatio and not our bodies that are analysts.
So the CEO talks about qualitative stuff.
Then the CFO gets on and talks about quantitative stuff and then all three of those EXACT is we'll take
questions at the end of the call and the call is usually less than an hour.
So we're to listen to a little clip from an investor relations earnings call hosted by linked in OH
OH
OH OH OH