All right this is the fun part.
This is where we get to forecast the future.
OK let's let's do this and just you know when you do this it's often more of an art than a science.
OK.
It's more of an art than a science.
You need to accept the fact that your estimates will be off but you just need to look at historical
trends and do the best you can in terms of projecting what the future might look like.
OK.
So e means expected.
What we're going to do is we're only in a forecast quarterly numbers for this year and can't and then
we'll do is going forward for 2017 18 19 20 We're going to do those on an annual basis.
It's just much easier that way.
OK.
So let's kick it off by forecasting on a quarterly basis.
Okay.
So remember the conventions the convention is that blue means hard coded.
And then green is from another tab.
OK so let's let's kick it off by forecasting the revenue line items for for.
We'll kick it off with talent solutions.
Okay.
So this here is blue and I'm going to show you how easy this is.
Right.
And again it's it's more of an art than a science and you will never be 100 percent right.
Nobody is nobody can predict the future and it comes to so many independent variables even the company
itself.
OK so let's go over here and I'm going to forecast these quarters here.
I've already done this.
And so what I'll show you is how I did it.
So you can see that the year over year customer numbers has been decreasing steadily over time from
35 to 34 30 to 30.
Right.
That's the average for the year.
And so it's come down by 2 percent there you know 2 percent there so so let's just continue that trend
.
Okay.
So make it 28 here.
Right.
That's hardcoded.
So if I delete it kind of messes up the numbers there you know everything is fed off of that.
Okay.
And then what we'll do is we'll make its 2 percent less here.
Right.
We're keep up with 2 percent less here and 2 percent less there.
Makes sense.
And so for the year we're at twenty four point eight percent and going forward for future years.
Deduct 2 percent or so or 1 percent will assume that the slowing of growth will slow down to 20 percent
year over year growth here which is how it works and memory I showed you a couple of graphs of the beginning
their growth is slowing and we're not assuming they're going to make any acquisitions here it's too
hard to incorporate that stuff into our models.
Okay let's look at revenue per customer.
Okay.
So revenue per customer is all over the place.
It is impossible to model in so you see here revenue per customer was down 1 percent year over year
.
Right.
Then it was up 1/2 percent here then it was up 1 that it was up 11.
And so for the year it averaged 2.9 percent up right and so for us what we're going to do is looks like
there's some seasonality here right.
Some seasonality it picks up.
It's at I guess a Q4 seasonal high.
There are a lot of businesses see revenue pick up just temporarily in Q4 especially in the retail sector
given holiday shopping.
Okay.
So I'll do the same similar pattern here.
I'll make it point five or normalized it here I don't know why it was negative that one time there also
may was kind of a one off and then 11 percent there.
And so for the year I'm at 2.9 percent.
And then we'll go down there just very slowly so that you know growth slows like it like it usually
does.
Right.
Okay And then we've got Lynda.com here in Fort Ghiselin this kind of stuff I don't really know what
to do here.
Growth is slowing a lot there.
I only have a couple of data points I assume it slows down more to their end for the year growth is
going to continue that slow year over year but I'm assuming that growth is actually pretty good for
Linda for a while because a big company bought a smaller company and so the big company has bigger distribution
channels and a good example will be to use Coca-Cola.
So Coke introduced or you know invested whatever in dishonesty Coke had incredible distribution channels
around the world so Coke can distribute Dasani water everywhere.
Right and so if Coke were to buy Red Bull hypothetically speaking Coca-Cola has more relationships around
the world and so Red Bull revenues would spike for a while because Coke has bigger distribution deals
.
OK I digress.
All right.
So looks like we're done there good.
We're done and all this stuff.
Right.
It's pretty easy.
Just a couple little line items here it's percent.
It feeds in to the rest of the model.
Right.
Done so we're done with that revenue line item right.
This revenue line item is really simple it's just hard coded.
Right.
So this is all just kind of extra information given right.
So all this information here is give me given in the press release or the 10-Qs we're not going to forecast
this stuff right.
So let's look at pattern recognition remember modeling is basically everything is present a sales or
pattern recognition.
And it looks like marketing revenue growth which is the second line of three.
So it's slowing slowing.
Right.
And so we're following similar patterns here.
We're slowing it down.
And then eventually on annual basis.
And again it's not perfect numbers see our revenue growth slows and we're done with that.
Okay good.
And then premia I think get a drill down on this one if I don't if I remember correctly.
That's right.
There we go.
But.
All right so.
Okay.
So what we're doing now is premium.
We've made a number of assumptions and it's basically the sales navigator products year over year growth
is slowing a lot.
See here I went from 40 to 29 so we're assuming it's going to continue slow.
And then eventually it'll slow by a couple of percent per year and whatnot.
No cake and the same thing with sales navigator the our poor average revenue per month per user per
month.
That will slow as well right over time slowly over time.
Okay.
And then down here the registered number of users will also slow.
So there's $430 million $4.40 register users as of the last quarter.
Right and that growth is 19 percent slowing a little bit over time see it's going to slow it down here
as well.
It's very gradually over time and eventually growth will only be 15 percent year over year there.
And then it's interesting because only point to 5 percent of 0.4 percent of customers pay.
And so I didn't know what the right number was.
Point 2 6 4 so I kept it out there and just had a slowing a little bit over time.
And the average revenue per subscriber has been 30 bucks for ever and so will include that there and
that's you know kind of on on a monthly basis like I showed you my personal subscription where there
was no credit card and that's it that's all you do okay for revenue and revenue.
We spend the most time on because everything is generally speaking a percent of revenue.
Okay great.
So there we go.
We've got these revenue line items here all the way out.
OK good.
All right so let's go to the income statement and let's model the income statement and the rest of the
model is actually pretty straight forward.
And we're going to get rid of this little crystal ball or whatever that thing is called that's called
.
Okay.
So I threw that over there.
Good visualization.
And then we'll do the same thing here as well and everything here is is going to be a percent of revenue
.
Right.
So here we are e We're forecasting the future.
And again your numbers would be a little bit off.
And don't worry about it.
It is what it is.
Right so here Coskata those sales was that amount and it went up you know a little bit whatever and
then backed down and we kind of play around that seasonality here as well.
And then eventually we assume that there's going to be leverage in the model.
Right.
So expenses that's a percentage of revenue will go down and we do the same thing with sales and marketing
.
Prior to Bellemont Junee depreciation again everything is just a percent of revenue.
And so last year for sales and marketing we see the percents come down slowly.
We'll assume that that continues over time on an annual basis.
You see here how it gradually trends lower.
Same with DNA as general minister.
Same with product development which is also called R&D and then depreciation is just a percentage of
revenue.
Right.
Same thing with stock based compensation it's always just a percent of revenue.
And then eventually we come down to our provision for taxes and we don't know what the tax rate is going
to be longer term.
So we assume it will gradually increase.
Most companies pay low 30s percentage whatever it is taxes depends on the country you're in where the
state or municipalities I don't want to spend too much tax time forecasting taxes.
You generally just call up the company or look in the 10-Q or 10k to see what taxes are and then forecast
in that way.
And a lot of times on the earnings calls they'll have taxes as well.
Right.
They'll they'll talk about that at length.
OK.
So there we go.
We've got our earnings each year going forward.
You can see that year over year growth actually is going accelerate.
And the reason we have it accelerating member when I showed you the charts early on of expenses and
revenue in our model well revenue growth is slowing a lot.
Right.
So the growth is slowing.
And so we're assuming that they're going to be cutting expenses just to make investors happy because
they'll be losing a lot of investors that love the high growth rate of the company.
But they'll be gaining a lot of investors that love the increasing profitability metrics as well.
And that's quite common for a lot of different companies as well as you can see the adjusted EBITDA
which is operating profit margins are increasing nicely over time.
OK so we're done with the income statement again remember that the green numbers are numbers that are
brought forward from a previous tab blue numbers are could it
put it in the balance sheet not as hard as you think it might be a lot lot of people have problems forecasts
and balance sheet.
It's not that difficult because similar to the income statement everything is really just a percentage
of revenue.
And the only reason that we forecast the balance sheet and the capital statement is so that we can do
a certain valuation metric which will cover next class called DCF or discounted cash flow analysis.
The other methodology is we're going to use for valuation like price earnings and price to.
And there's many others don't really use forecasts of the balance sheet.
Okay great.
So these are historical numbers you see they're hardcoded in Blue Angels You don't need to be here it's
just the last data right.
Remember the balance sheet just a snapshot in time.
OK so now we're in a forecast.
And again the green numbers mean it's from another tab right.
And so this green number here is going to come from the cash flow statement.
Okay cash I'll get there in a minute.
You'll see receivables is going to come from the income statement right.
It's just seventeen point five percent times sales.
How did it get that gross.
Well over here you can see that receivables as a percentage of sales changes by the quarter.
So I basically just used a similar pattern there.
It's not perfect but I think you get the idea and then you'll go down through all your assets all your
liabilities and a lot of it is just a percentage of revenue or is pulled from you know somewhere else
.
So in this case 1.8 percent for other assets times revenue.
Right.
How are you going to forecast that is too hard.
Same thing with accounts payables percentage just sales.
Right.
So that is just 4.5 percent tons percentage of sales.
I looked at historical patterns here and tried to model it the best of my capabilities.
Same thing here with and retained earnings which is just pulled from another statement and retained
earnings member is just the increase or decrease in previous years or quarters net income.
Right.
So that earnings earnings or net income are retained and then I add a lot of comments here so I know
exactly where I'm getting the stuff from right.
So here short term investments.
I'm assuming it builds 100 annually hundred million EYLEA as cash flow builds.
And that's just from looking at historical patterns what and again not perfect but close enough.
And then he got deferred commissions which I'm telling you just a percentage of revenue.
Same thing here.
I'm just telling myself reminding myself what all this stuff is from.
OK so I'm not a big fan of forecasting balance sheets or Cashell statements because I'm not a big fan
of DCF which is down here.
But I'm going to show you how to do it anyway.
And the reason I'm not a big fan of it is because there are so many independent variables in DCF.
So if I told you x plus one equals three we all know that X is true.
If I told you x plus why plus Q plus W plus 1 is 3 What is x.
We have no idea.
It's just too many independent variables and that's what DCF is.
But I want to kind of create a menu for everybody here to follow from so I'm including it.
OK let's move on to cash flow and let's forecast the future here.
And you think this might be complicated.
This is actually the easiest one and easiest one because it's actually already calculated for you right
.
Member all the greens are from previous tabs right.
Bleus we don't have any Bleus to enter right.
I just don't know.
I don't know how to you know add a forecast for provision for doubtful accounts just being honest and
sales returns right.
It's kind of all over the place here.
And so are these things excess tax benefits.
I have no idea.
And same with so they they kind of average each other out.
I'm going to make them 0 and they're not going to move that need the needle that much anyway.
OK.
There you go.
And so all these line items are just pulled from previous statements the balance sheet or the income
statement.
And let's double click on them and just see where they came from.
Right.
So let's go here.
DoubleClick at depreciation is right on the income statement we know that right.
Same thing with stock based compensation.
Right.
And that is basically net income from the income statement that's gap right.
Number gap and we're doing all this stuff in the cash flow statement to figure out what real cash flow
is because the income statement is a lie.
That's why we have a cash flow statement.
Ill tell you what the what the real cash is and here you just pull this off your balance sheet was a
change in accounts receivable deferred commission prepaid expenses all the other stuff you can read
that right there it comes right off of the balance sheet.
And then again we've got free cash flow here so free cash flow is basically operating cash flow minus
cap ex remember that free cash flow is operating cash flow of minus CapEx and all this stuff here is
calculated for us so that we can forecast our DCF.
Right.
So the free cash flows will feed into there which I'll cover in the next section and so that's a recap
on how to forecast your financial statements.
Right.
Basically everything is a percent of revenue pretty much.
And then you look for pattern recognition to decide how to forecast it and can and every model is different
.
But a couple of things are similar.
One of them is that most items are percentage revenue and you always look for patterns in the data.
One data point does make a trend but a couple always does