Sometimes SQS isn't good enough for your application use case.
You could want to avoid the pulling process or you find
that you want a more real‑time solution.
There might be many reasons why SQS won't work,
but Kinesis Streams might be perfect for you.
Kinesis Streams is a service for real‑time data transfer. It scales
easily and can have multiple producers and consumers.
It doesn't have fine‑grain control over how messages are handled like with SQS,
but that simplicity might make it better in some situations.
Let's talk about one of the key concepts in Kinesis
Streams, and that is sharding.
Sharding is the capacity unit used with Kinesis Streams.
One shard is equivalent to your Kinesis stream having 1 megabyte per
second of input and 2 megabytes per second of output.
If you need more input or output, you would add shards to your stream.
We're going to use a Kinesis stream to push our hamster race results
similar to the Q, but the consumer of the Kinesis Stream will update
the races instead of the hamsters.
In our case,
we're going to use a lambda as the consumer. One of the main
reasons is that because a stream is real time,
it requires a dedicated consumer,
and our web application is not really the right fit.
Lambdas are actually a great fit as Kinesis consumers.
So this will give you a taste of how that can work. Now, in the next clip, we're going to create our first Kinesis Stream.