For this course,
we're going to use a lambda as a convenient Kinesis stream consumer.
What's easy about this is that you can configure lambda to
be triggered directly from a stream,
meaning you don't have to create or maintain a long running
application to consume all this data.
Lambda's are event driven,
so the lambda will be invoked anytime data comes into the stream. So we'll
start by creating our lambda function. In the script/module_08 folder,
open up the create_kinesis_consumer.js file.
First,
go ahead and update your region on line 5. Now to configure
lambda to connect to a Kinesis stream,
you'll need the ARN for the stream. To get this switch over to the
AWS console and go to the Kinesis dashboard.
Now select the Kinesis stream and then the ARN for
the stream will be right there.
Copy that value and switch back to your code editor.
Paste the value in quotes on line 10.
Now the rest of this file creates a role for your lambda with
permissions to read from a Kinesis stream.
Then it zips up a file that will run on the lambda, creates
the lambda and then creates the trigger that connects the
lambda and the Kinesis stream.
If you scroll to the bottom of the file, you'll see the createTrigger function.
This is the only other part of this file that I'll have you implement.
Go ahead and create a new params const object on line 47.
This params object is going to be passed to the
lambda.createEventSourceMappings function.
The first property will be EventSourceArn,
which will give the value of the Kinesis ARN function argument.
This is what we needed that ARN from the streams console
for. The next property is FunctionName, which is the name of our lambda function.
Give it the value of the lambdaName function argument.
The next property is starting position,
which tells the lambda at which record it should
start processing from the stream.
Just enter LATEST in all caps,
since this will be created before any records even get into the stream.
Finally, add the property batch size and give it the value 100.
This defines how many records will be retrieved at one time from
the Kinesis stream and 100 is the max value here.
Now Our last step is to update the code that will be running in our lambda.
Look in the lambda‑kinesis‑consumer folder and open the index.js
file. On line 5, update the string to your region. This file
doesn't do much Kinesis specific stuff,
but you can see on line 11 that the data you'll be getting from
Kinesis is going to be a base64 encoded buffer,
so make sure you process it correctly when retrieving the record.
Now we can switch over to our command line and run the
command node create‑kinesis‑consumer.js.
This will take some time to run because the role creation isn't immediate.
So I'm speeding up the video here a bit,
and then you'll see the output for the trigger creation in the console.
Once created,
you don't need to do anything else with lambda as
it's live as soon as it's created.
Here's a good point where you can try everything out. To test it
you'll have to redeploy your app to the EC2 instance.
Use the same deployment script that we used earlier.
Once it's live, log in to one of the accounts.
One you can use is user name Ryan and password Pass,
then click the gear next to the user name and click Start Simulation. You can also click Reset Results if you want to start fresh.