Hi everyone.
My name is Ryan Lewis, and welcome to my course,
AWS Developer: Designing and Developing.
I've been architecting and creating applications in AWS for many
years in my work as a senior software engineer.
Amazon Web Services is practically a household name in the software industry,
and an investment in the platform is a solid investment in your career.
With AWS being a key factor in the success of Amazon,
Netflix, and Dropbox, there seems to be no stopping the growth of this giant.
In this course,
we are going to learn how to design and develop applications with AWS.
We'll mostly be working with the software development kit in this course,
so make sure to warm up your coding skills.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include creating and managing
scalable applications with EC2 and Auto Scaling groups,
storing and querying data with Relational Database Service and ElastiCache,
inter‑service messaging using Simple Queue Service and Kinesis Streams,
real‑time communications with Simple Notification Service and CloudWatch alarms.
By the end of this course,
you'll have the knowledge and experience required to make the
most of AWS in your application development.
Before beginning the course,
you should already be familiar with the basics of AWS
and have some experience using it.
It will also help to have some experience with Node since we'll be
using the Node AWS software development kit.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to master Amazon Web
Services with the AWS Developer: Designing and Developing course here, at Pluralsight.