Amazon machine images are sort of like the primer for every painting you want
to create with an EC2 instance. It's a starting point and the base software
that you build off of, but they do have another use,
which is to help you easily reproduce an instance with
your given application loaded on it.
There are a million other uses for AMIs,
but bottom line is that they are ubiquitous and super
important throughout AWS. In this module,
we're going to use the SDK to create an AMI from the instance
we started up in the last clip. To do this,
move to your code editor and open the file create‑ami.js.
You can probably tell just from looking at the file that this will be
significantly smaller than the last few files we worked on.
Start on Line 2 by importing the AWS SDK and assigning it to an AWS const.
Then on Line 4,
configure your region by calling aws.config.update and passing in an
object with the key and the value as a string with your region in it. On
Line 7, create an EC2 const and assign to it a new aws.ec2 object. Now on
Line 9, we're calling our createImage function passing in an instance ID
and a name for this image.
The promise just prints complete once it's done, nothing special.
Let's implement this function on Line 13.
We'll start by creating our params const object first. There are only a
few parameters that the image creation operation needs.
First, is the InstanceId property,
which you can assign the function argument seedInstanceId.
Every AMI needs an instance to copy from. This instance ID
is what should be copied to a new image.
Next is the name property to which you can assign the image name argument.
This name is basically just an identifier for the
AMI. And that's it for parameters.
Now we can return our new promise pattern with the function argument being
passed in. Inside, we'll call ec2.createImage passing in params as our first
argument and our typical callback as the second argument.
This create image is pretty basic and does exactly what it says. In the
callback, just reject if there is an err, otherwise, resolve passing in
data. One note on the CreateImage function.
It will create an image that is private meaning only your
account can launch instances with this image. To change the
visibility, you would use the ModifyImage attribute function
after the image has been created.
The last step is to get the instance ID that we want to create our image from.
We can use the manage‑ec2‑instance file to do this. Open the
file and make sure the listInstances operation is uncommented
and not terminate instances.
Then flip over to your command line and run node
manage‑ec2‑instance.js. You should have some instances output.
In the case that you are just barreling through this course,
you may have both the instance we just created from the AWS
marketplace and then one we previously terminated.
If so, look for this state property.
One of the instances should show as running,
while the other is likely terminated.
Copy the instance ID for the running instance. Now move back to your code
editor and head back to the create‑ami.js file. On Line 9, where it says
instanceid, paste over that with the copied instance ID from the command
line, and finally, save the file.
Now we're ready to create our AMI. Move back over to the command line
and run node create‑ami.js. It should process for a second or so and
then print out complete meaning it's done.
You can go to the EC2 dashboard in your browser,
then to AMIs in the menu to see the image you just created.
One thing I want to mention before we finish this clip is
that even though you've created this image,
the user data startup script that we were using doesn't attach to the image.
This means even if you start a new instance with that image,
the demo project won't be started.
The code for the demo project will be present on the
instance, it just won't be run.
Reproducible user data exists in a launch configuration, which we'll talk about in the next module.