Between SQS and Kinesis Streams,
you should be able to find a solution for any messaging
need you have. SQS provides a more distributed and
decoupled form of sending messages.
And Kinesis provides real‑time and high‑throughput streams.
Let's recap what we covered in this module.
We started by discussing some of the details of SQS, like delay
seconds and visibility timeout on messages.
Then we created a queue and changed our app to send race results
through a queue to update the hamsters table.
Next,
I introduced Kinesis Streams, and then we again sent race results
into the stream while the Lambda function consumed them on the
other end and updated the races table.
Finally, we covered the limits regarding SQS and Kinesis Streams.
In the next module, we're going to look at some communication tools in AWS, like the Simple Notification Service and CloudWatch alarms