We've taken a good tour of what EC2 has to offer,
so you should have a good understanding of how computing works in AWS.
Let's recap what we covered in this module.
We started by discussing some specifics of EC2 instances,
instance storage and AMIs. Then we talked about the different
classes of EC2, like spot instances, reserved instances, and on‑demand instances,
which is what we're using.
After that,
I walked you through how the signing process happens when making a
request to the AWS REST API, and luckily we don't need to manually
do that since we're using the SDK.
Then we started writing code as we created a security group,
a key pair, and finally an EC2 instance.
Once we had that instance,
we looked at other SDK functions like listing
instances and terminating instances.
Then, we took a trip to the AWS Marketplace to pick up an AMI
preloaded with Node. And finally, we created an AMI from an instance that we can use when creating other instances.