Developing an application in the cloud is not always quite
the same as typical non‑cloud development.
As companies migrate to the cloud,
more and more developers are getting their first taste of
operations and infrastructure as they're directed to do
their own cloud deployments.
In your past experience,
you may have been used to just building your application and
then handing it over to another team or engineer to do the
actual deployment of the application.
Because of that process,
you may have thought of your application as only the code
you wrote and other parts as outside of your domain, but
as with everything in tech,
the world is changing and operations concerns are
consistently falling into developers laps.
I believe this is a good thing and will ultimately
improve your career as a developer.
It also does something else, though, and that's a sort of mind expansion.
Once you can utilize everything that AWS offers,
it changes how your applications work and how they're designed,
which really changes the way you think about your applications.
I've experienced this personally over the past few years when I began steady AWS
development and it's only improved the quality of my work.
I like to describe cloud development like this.
Basically, when you begin thinking about a new application,
you'll want to start with the infrastructure.
There are certain decisions you'll need to make,
such as computing, persistence,
routing and AWS gives you multiple options for each.
Each decision you make fundamentally shapes how your application is structured
and this approach is what I like to call cloud development.
With each service that we cover in this course,
you'll add another tool to your application development tool belt.
And when you approach a new feature or application,
you'll be able to consider how certain AWS Services might best be used.
Eventually,
your application will be a distributed and scalable combination
of code and services, this adds resiliency, improves maintainability, and ultimately, results in a better application.