Topics in SNS are single elements where consumers can subscribe to.
When any message is published to the topic,
all of the subscribers are sent the message over
whatever protocol they have configured.
This is basically how SNS works.
In this module,
we're going to set up a topic and subscription so that we can
send notifications whenever races are complete.
We'll start in this clip by creating the topic that
will have messages published to it.
Open up the file in the scripts/module_09 folder named create‑sns‑topic.js.
We'll start with the usual, updating your region on line 4.
Next, on line 7, we'll declare a const named sns, then assign to it a new AWS.
SNS constructor call.
Below that is where we declare our topicName.
Every topic name needs to be unique in an account,
and hamster‑topic is as good as anything else.
Now let's implement our createTopic function on line 13.
First create a new params const object.
The first and only property is going to be Name,
which you can give the value of the topicName function argument.
Topics are super simple,
as this is the only property the createTopic function even takes.
Now inside the Promise, call sns.createTopic,
passing in the params object as the first argument and a callback
function with err and data arguments as the second.
If there's an err object, then call reject with it; otherwise,
call resolve, passing in the data argument.
This file is now complete, so we can switch over to our command line.
Navigate to the scripts/module_09 folder,
and execute the command node create‑sns‑topic.js.
You should get an output and this TopicArn,
something we'll need later, signifying that your topic has been created.
And now that we've got a topic, we need someone to subscribe to it, which we'll do in the next clip.