One of my favorite things about SNS is the different
types of notification options available.
You're not only able to send emails, but also SMS,
hit HTTP endpoints, trigger lambdas, or even send the messages to an SQS queue.
We'll keep it low key for this course and just set up an SMS notification.
We do want to know what happens with the hamster races after all, don't we?
Open up the create‑sns‑subscription.js file.
We'll start by adding a few values.
First, update your region on line 4.
Then on line 9, add your mobile number with country code and no hyphens.
If you've got an American phone number, your country code is 1.
You're welcome.
On line 10, we need to enter the ARN of the topic we just created.
You can get that from the command line output from the previous clip.
Copy this TopicArn value right here, and then paste it in the string on line 10.
Now we're ready to implement the createSubscription function.
Go ahead and start by creating a params const object at the top of the function.
The first property is Protocol,
which we are passing in as the function argument type.
The next property is TopicArn,
and you can give that the value of the topicArn function argument.
The last property is Endpoint,
and you can give it the value of the endpoint function argument.
These are the only three properties you need to subscribe to a topic.
Now inside the Promise, call the sns.
subscribe function, passing in the params object as the first argument,
then a callback function with err and data arguments as the second.
If there's an err object, then call reject and pass it in; otherwise,
call resolve with the data argument.
This will make our file complete,
and we can switch over to the command line to run it.
In your command line, execute node create‑sns‑subscription.js.
It will output the subscription details, and you should be up and running.
Once we connect up our demo application to SNS in the next clip, you'll start getting the freshest race results directly to your phone.