In the last module,
I mentioned launch configurations and how they are the
place you'll persist your user data.
It's true.
A launch configuration is basically the blueprint for
automatically creating new instances.
It contains all the key attributes for how to create an instance,
including the AMI to use, the instance type, instance security groups, and
the startup user data. Although they do stand alone and you can manually
create new instances directly from a launch configuration, they're also a
key component in an auto scaling group.
Let's create a launch configuration for our demo project.
Go to your code editor and open the module_03 folder in the scripts directory.
We'll be modifying the create‑launch‑configuration.js file.
There is not much special going on here,
just setting up some required variables and then
creating the launch configuration.
I'm also taking care of a few annoying things for you now like
importing the AWS SDK and configuring your region.
The only thing you'll need to do is replace the string on line 4
with the region that you're using. On line 7, we need to create
the SDK object we'll be operating on.
This is the auto scaling SDK property.
Create a new const called autoScaling,
then assign to it a new AWS.AutoScaling constructor call.
This is just like the EC2 object we used in the last module and that
there is a host of functions that you can call that perform
different operations related to auto scaling.
One thing that we'll use with our launch configuration that we
haven't talked about yet is an IAM role to give the instance
permissions to talk to other service in AWS. On line 14, a role is
being created for our hamster instances,
and then we'll use that same role in the launch configuration.
Be aware this row gives the instance administrator access
for simplicity's sake during this class,
so make sure you never actually give an instance
admin access in a production account.
Now let's implement the Create launch configuration function on line 18.
We'll start by declaring our Params const object.
The first property is IamInstanceProfile,
which we will assign to the profile ARN argument.
This associates our EC2 instances with the role to give it permissions.
The next property is imageId, which is the AMI that we want to launch from.
We'll use the AMI we created here, but we don't know the id for it.
So switch over to the EC2 dashboard in your web browser and
click on the AMIs menu option on the left.
Find the image that has the name hamsterImage and copy the AMI ID.
Bring that back to your code and paste it as a string as the value to ImageId.
The next property is InstanceType, which is the EC2 InstanceType.
I'll just center t2.micro here since it's cheap and what we've been
using so far. Any instance type could be entered here.
The next property is LaunchConfigurationName,
and this is where you add your launch configuration identifier.
Set the value as the function argument lcName,
which is being passed into the function.
Next, add the property key name,
which will be the key pair the instance will be launched with and give
it the value of the key name const variable. Now add a SecurityGroups
property and set the value to an array.
These security groups define the security group that will be
added to each instance that is created.
In that case, we'll use the security group we created last module,
which is already declared here in the sgName variable, so
add that. The last property is user data.
Since we're launching from the AMI built off the bit NAMI AMI,
open up the marketplace‑ec2‑startup.sh file in the module_02
folder and copy the base‑64 encoded string, paste that as a
string as the value to user data.
Now we can use this params object. Follow the promise pattern by
returning a new promise with the resolve and reject arguments. In
the callback function, use the autoscaling object and call the
createLaunchConfiguration function.
The first argument will be Params,
and the second will be a callback with err and data arguments.
Nothing special here, just reject if there's an err argument.
Otherwise, resolve and pass in data.
Now we can go ahead and run this file to create the launch configuration,
even though the other pieces aren't ready yet, so let's do that. In your
command line, make sure you're in the scripts module_03 folder and run node
create‑Launch‑Configuration.js. After a bit, the launch configuration details
should be output to your command line.
In the next clip,
we're going to create an elastic load balancer as the next piece of our scaling architecture.