An Elastic Load Balancer is an essential resource
for any elastic web application,
establishing a single entry point for web requests
that can handle any size load.
Let's create our load balancer by opening the file
create‑load‑balancer.js in our scripts folder.
I've already taken care of some ancillary functions in this file so
that we can focus on the load balancer creation. But I will go over
them in the course of our modifications.
So, start by putting your region into the string on line 5.
Next on line 8, we need to create an ELB object. Specifically, we'll
be creating a version 2 ELB object. Load balancing has its own SDK
object, different from auto scaling.
Create a const variable named elbv2,
then assign to it a new AWS.ELBv2 constructor call.
Now we need to get some information from the AWS
console for our VPC ID and subnets.
This is needed for the load balancer and target group creation.
Move to the AWS console and go to the VPC dashboard.
We'll get the VPC ID first by clicking on Your VPCs in the
left‑hand menu. You'll likely only have one VPC.
Mine is the default.
So, copy the VPC ID. If you have multiples,
use the one where you've been launching resources so far. In your code
editor, paste that value in the string on line 12.
Now back to the console, click on the Subnets menu entry.
We need at least two subnets for the load balancer,
and they need to be in the VPC that we just pasted.
In this case,
I'll use us‑east‑1a and us‑east‑1b. So, I'll copy these subnet IDs and
paste both of those into the subnet array on line.
13.
Great.
The next few lines do the actual operations to create the load balancer.
The code starts by creating a new security group for the
load balancer that is open on port 80.
This is so that users can access the load balancer over HTTP.
Then, a target group is created, and then a load balancer.
I'll explain the target group in a second.
Then we get the Amazon resource names for the target group and load
balancer and create a listener with those values. I want to explain the
relationship of all these resources real quick.
A load balancer is in charge of responding to HTTP requests and
sending them somewhere. A target group is the destination defined
where a load balancer will send those requests.
This is going to be connected to our auto scaling group
and will basically end up being a group of EC2 instances
with our demo project running.
The listener defines the relationship between the two.
In our case,
the load balancer will be listening on port 80, which is for HTTP, and
our target group will be listening on port 3000 since that's what our
demo application is using. The listener will facilitate sending those
requests between the two ports.
Now let's implement the createLoadBalancer function. On
line 34, create your params const object.
The first property will be the load balancer name, which
is passed in as the lbName argument.
Next are the Subnets property, which are the subnets the load balancer will use.
We defined these earlier in a subnets variable, so add that as the
value. Then we need to add the SecurityGroups property,
which is the security groups for the load balancer itself. Set the
value as an array with a single item named sgId. Now create a new
line and let's return a new promise with resolve and reject arguments
in a function argument. Inside we'll use the elbv2 object and call
createLoadBalancer on it.
The first argument is params,
and the second argument is a callback with the err and data arguments.
If there's an err object, then call reject with it.
Otherwise,
call resolve, passing in data. Below this function are functions
to create the target group and the listener. I've already
implemented these to save us some time,
but definitely take a look to get a better understanding of what they're doing.
Now we can run this file,
move over to your command line and execute the
command node create‑load‑balancer.js.
There should be some output, specifically I want to draw your
attention to the line that says Target Group Name ARN.
We will need this in the next clip, so either leave your
command line alone or copy and save it somewhere.
And with this, we have a load balancer ready for instances to send
requests to. In the next clip we're going to create an auto scaling group that will create those instances.