Throughout this course, you've likely created a lot of resources.
I thought that making a list of what you need to
clean up after might be helpful,
so let's look at what you need to clean up and how to do it.
We'll start with the EC2 Dashboard where most of our resources are located.
You'll first want to delete the load balancer,
then the Auto Scaling group, then the target group.
Once those are gone, you can kill any instances still around.
Delete the AMI we created,
and then delete both key pairs since there aren't any
more live instances using them.
Delete the launch configuration used to make our instances.
Delete any EBS snapshots that were created and any
EBS volumes that are still around.
Finally, delete any security groups other than the default one.
Next, go to S3 and delete the hamster‑bucket.
Then go into RDS and delete the MySQL instance.
Don't bother taking a final snapshot of the database, unless you're
really nostalgic about the results of the Petco 2000.
Now go to DynamoDB and delete both tables.
Then go to ElastiCache and delete the Redis cluster we created.
You can go into Route 53 and delete the hosted zone,
although it doesn't incur any cost.
Then go into API Gateway and delete the entire hamster API we created.
Now go to CloudFront and delete the hamster distribution.
We're almost done.
Head into the SQS dashboard and delete the queue we created.
Then go the Kinesis Streams dashboard and delete the stream we made.
We also have that lambda consumer,
so go into the AWS Lambda console and delete that function.
Finally, go to SNS and delete the hamster topic,
and then go to CloudWatch and delete the healthy hosts alarm.
There's some resources that are still around in IAM,
but they have no cost, so you can delete them at your discretion.
And that's it. It's hard to believe we can delete so much work in such a short time.