Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in meditative for in today's tutorial.
We will be running forward tests for our expert advisor simple system version 5.0.
As you can see here we've already shortlisted six distinct sets for our expert adviser and the way we've
come up with these is through optimizations.
And today we want to pick out the best ones out of them.
So let's say for example that you aim to pick out four sets out of the six.
I'll just bring up a slide that we looked at in one of the Prue's tutorials and as you can see here
we've really done the back tests and optimizations and we use three months of daughter to do that.
And according to this ratio of forward tests should be one month of data and that's exactly how much
we have left.
So by running those forward tests we'll be able to pick out the best four sets of parameters.
Also you can see that the hour is specified here and that's because our is a significant factor in our
trading system.
So it's important to know which set corresponds to which are right away we know we can notice that there
are two sets corresponding to the hour nine and we wouldn't want to include both of them in our demo
tests that are upcoming.
So what we will do is we'll compare the two of them and pick only one.
And but of course given that the results are plausible and comparable to the rest.
And by doing that we will already have one set and then out of the remaining four will only have to
pick the best three and that we will end up with four sets.
So let's go ahead and do that and we will start by looking at the our nine said I'll just cancel this
and show you what we need to do.
So if we go to expert properties and go to load and load our nine click OK.
And when you're going to run the back test again just to see what it looked like.
This was a quite a good back test and in the report we see the profit was $3000.
So now we run forward tests.
We we have to move this to 8th of August and this 2 8th of September QuickStart and look at the chart
.
So the back test isn't as good but it's one of those holding ones so it would be still a right to keep
but let's have a look at the other setting that we have.
So we go to nine be low that click OK.
We go back to the back test just to see how that performed.
So the graph is very similar.
Profit it is a bit less it's just over 3000 that it was a bit more with 3000.
And now let's run the forward test.
So we'll set this one for the one month start and look at the chart.
The chart is much better in this case.
So out of the two nines we will keep only the second one so we'll go to the data will go to say load
and we'll just put at the end of it we'll just put a plus 2 indicator we keeping it in and put a minus
to indicate we're not keeping it.
So now we have to compare these ones.
So since we are loading data might as well just go ahead and load it.
So let's look at the 10 go back to the back test.
This was the back just looked like and the forward test looks like this.
It's not too good it's not going straight up but it is a holding back test for test.
So that's that's right.
We probably can keep it but we need to check out the other three.
So let's go into that for our fourth So we're back at 5.
This is what the forward test looks like sort of the back test looked like.
Now let's look at the forward test
for test isn't too good.
It is quite negative.
So this is one potential candidate to be discarded.
Let's look at the next one.
All right.
That is what our back tests look like.
And let's look at the forward test for test is OK.
It went up.
There was obviously a loss trade here and that brought the deposit a bit down.
But it is profitable So we'll keep that for now.
And let's look at the last one said with our 7.
So that's the back test.
Practice is pretty good.
And we look at the forward test for test is actually not good at all.
As you can see here we have a evident trend going down.
So we would want to see that on our account.
So I think this is even worse than our for.
We're going to have to discard this one.
And there we go.
That's how we can select our winners.
So this is a minus.
This is a plus.
And this is a plus.
So that's that's all great.
That's exactly what we wanted to see to select for now.
Bear in mind that you can of course select more sets as a starting point and then like more for a test
or less.
So up to you and this is just an example I'm just illustrating how you would go about it but I think
in this case self 4 is sufficient for a demo test.
And so that's what we'll go ahead with and we will just saved the reports so we have something to look
at going forward.
So let's slow them.
OK.
But the report to get through Paul will run it for the whole period of the back test plus forward tests
so from May to September.
So let's run that.
These are these are chart.
So go to report click save as report.
And here we'll type in simple says version 5 point on and then set our equals 10.
So just ... just copy this bit save this fit this browser window in here.
So that's our report.
You can see here it says open prices we can very quickly fix that will just go changes every tick.
We know that will be exactly the same.
Just take maybe a bit longer.
There's a graph.
So save as report.
So it was the same one.
There we go.
That's our first one.
Now if we go to settings and we load the second one for.
OK.
And so now we want to save this report.
So it was a report it's going to be our for.
I'm just going to close this one.
So we have the 10 for now we'll go expert properties
7 report.
And finally we want to save them and
there also saved all four of them as the reports just going to zoom out a little bit.
And now we can quickly compare which ones the best so this one was our turn.
It's 4000 are our US 2000.
This is two point thirty two point eight.
And this one three point nine so that's the order that they're in.
So this is the most profitable one.
Our turn and we will call it the first set.
This is the second profit the one where our is 9.
We'll call the second set and this is the third one and where our was for this is the fifth the fourth
one.
So as you can see the charts are all pretty good.
And now what we want to do is we want to launch these on a demo test to see how they will work online
while they're running live and we will do that in the next tutorial and I'll explain you exactly how
it's done and how exactly what's the best way to go about keeping a terminal's up and running 24/7.
It'll be a very exciting couple of weeks while the Demel tests are running so I look forward to seeing
you in the next tural.
And until then happy trading