Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome to the fourth tutorial in our series of tutorials on testing and optimization and meditate
for.
Last time we talked about backtesting and we conducted our very own first back test in the meditator
for training platform.
Today we're going to discuss expert properties as you can see here I have the meditator four platform
open in front of me at the bottom I have the tester strategy tester window open.
Now what we can do is we're going to just select any expert adviser of the available ones and we'll
just click this button up here expert properties.
So these are the expert properties expert properties settings window and has three tabs right away I'll
mention that we won't be talking about optimization type today we'll be talking about optimization parameters
in one of the future toils in this course.
Today we're going to be talking about these two taps in the testing tab.
You can see some some controls which are responsible for the overall test parameters so they're not
specific to the expert advisor you'll see these controls.
You'll see that these controls are the same regardless of which expert adviser you are testing.
And here you can set a starting deposit which means the balance on your count at the start of the test
the account currents and usually people set the currents to match the currency on their actual real
live trading account and you can also set which kind of positions you you want cheer for X robot to
be able to open.
So regardless of the algorithm which is built into your trading system you can restrict the extra effort
from opening.
Say sell orders.
And that way if you choose long only the trading strategy will be restricted to opening only by orders
or so on the other hand you can restrict it to opening only sellers by selecting short only.
Normally this is rarely used and people tend to stick to both long and short.
But in some circumstances circumstances this control might be might come in handy.
So it's good to know that it's there.
So we'll leave this had long short.
Once again we won't be talking about optimization in this tutorial so we'll skip the section of it here
and now we'll go to the inputs and the inputs is the main tab of expert properties window what these
inputs mean is sort of controls that you as a trader can change or to adjust the behavior of the forex
robot that you're testing your backtesting.
And these are the same controls that you will see when you launch an expert advisor on your char to
actually trade you will see the same controls and therefore it kind of matches up.
So depending on your back test depending on the settings that you said here and if you're happy with
them then you can set the same settings in your real when you're trading your real account with that
expert adviser.
And why would you want to adjust the behavior of your adviser.
Well because first of all you might want to have different presets for different financial instruments
or periods meaning timeframes and that is essential because different financial instruments behave differently
and therefore expert advisors would trade them differently.
Also with time you might need to change the settings of the expert adviser or you might have different
preferences for example here you can see a lot of parameter and a maximum risk parameter which are responsible
for the amount of money that they expended.
Why is a trade so therefore you could adjust this to cater for your risk versus your specific risk versus
just different people would have different levels of risk tolerance.
I've prepared a short presentation on expert properties that quickly have a look at that.
So you have an expert advisor which you want to conduct the back test for.
Usually the expert advisor comes with a user guide or an instruction manual.
If it's a purchased expert adviser or if it's something that you developed yourself then you will know
already what the expert properties mean.
That is very handy because based on the instruction manual or your intrinsic knowledge of the expert
advisor you can knowingly set these expert properties to certain values and you will either get unprofitable
results like these too or if you set the parameters correctly if you pick the right premises you can
get profitable results.
And that's essentially what we're aiming for in this course we will assume that we have an expert advisor
and we have knowledge of the parameters that we need to set.
And we'll be aiming to optimize or find the right parameters that will give us profitable results that
and therefore that will warrant using these extra devices on our demo accounts or even hypothetically
real accounts for trading.
Of course with these prepackaged expert advisors moving average in the sample it's quite difficult to
get profitable results.
But throughout this course we will be working with a proprietary algorithmic trading system which I
will introduce to in the next section of the course with that system we will look for profit results
and hopefully will find them.
So let's just go ahead and look at this chart this is the chart we got after our back test in the previous
tutorial for the moving average indicator expert wiser.
And now if we change some of the settings here the chart should change so let's go ahead and quickly
have a look at that's if we change the moving period to 24 moving shift to zero.
For example last 2.5 and then launch so expert wise or now you'll notice that the chart looks different
.
And even though it's still not profitable that proves the point that we do have control over how the
trades are conducted and when the extra advisor enters the market and with what volume of currency.
So that's basically the essence of what expert properties are.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial.
If you are watching and each of disobey scrubs the channel so you can get updated of new free tutorials
that I post.
I look forward to seeing at the next tutorial.
Until then Happy training