Spring is all about making things work better together.
It was designed from the ground up to help overcome difficult
configuration problems common in software development. For JPA,
we use Spring to configure the transactions, data
source, and overall JPA configuration.
With everything configured through Spring, we can then use dependency
injection and inject resources into the rest of our application.
Spring really helps tie everything together in a nice, non‑hard coded way.
Our controllers from our Spring MVC app can now seamlessly tie into our
database and JPA objects without having to go in and hard code or look
up references from within our application.
Now I'm going to remind you,
though, we are not going to cover Spring in its entirety because that's
in other courses I have published here on Pluralsight. We're going to just recap the principles that we need to use for our application