Let's start off by talking about the database for a minute.
JPA is an abstraction layer for our database.
We can use almost any relational database that we have a dialect for.
And if you don't know what dialects are,
we're going to talk about these more in greater detail later in the JPA
configuration section and some of the more detailed things that we can do with
those dialects because it's a pretty advanced topic.
For our course, we're going to use MySQL.
We're actually going to walk through installing that in just a bit.
But since this is a re‑release of an old course,
a new change is that we're going to use Docker to install the database and
keep it contained. Docker has become the industry standard.
And if you're not using it, you should be.
It actually made this course simpler,
and that was one of the deciding factors of why we used it.
If for some reason you don't want to use Docker,
you can install it natively, and all of the examples will work just the same. But I would encourage you to give Docker a shot if you haven't.