In the previous module,
we used the persist method of the EntityManager to
create records in the database, but we never did an update.
The persist method is used only for inserts,
though, and we use a merge method instead for updating a record.
When we created our method we purposely called it save because we were going to
override this method to handle creates, as well as updates.
Now,
this is one of those things that we have to do in all of our repository
classes, our implementations, that just is copy and paste code.
Now, some people get a little creative and create an abstract parent
class and move this code up into that parent class,
well let's show you what that looks like.
This is an example of what our goal method will look like after
updating it to support creates, as well as updates.
A few things to notice about this.
First, we will look to see if it has an Id, so the getId equal to null,
and we can determine from that whether or not it is a create versus update.
Second,
one other thing that's a little confusing is we don't have to
flush because the merge is handled differently.
Third, and lastly,
the merge does return an updated object where the persist is void.
This is because the problem I mentioned earlier about the
various Id generated value methods when defining what Id
type we have on our entity.
Some of the types of Id,
specifically the Identity column, aren't chosen until
after the object has been saved.
So this snippet of code,
this image here, shows what we would update our goal repository Impl to for the save method.