All you need to do to run Docker is to have the Docker Desktop app installed.
And for that, you just go to docker.com and download the
version specific to your operating system.
From there, we're going to add this docker‑compose file to our application,
and it will set up everything.
In this case, we're going to have a database,
and you can tell that by the db: that sets up the container for this.
Its image type is of mysql:5.7, and the container name is conference.
Next,
we're going to bind the ports that are exposed on our operating
system to this port inside of the container,
which is 3306.
From there, we'll tell it where it's going to store the data,
which is underneath our project in a .data directory /db
and then for our environment as well.
We're going to say that the MYSQL_ROOT_PASSWORD is pass, and
the database name is conference. And we have all of our stuff
set up and configured right here.
So this will download that instance for us,
store it,
bind the ports, and set up the username and password and database name for us. Let's add this to our application now, and we can start up our Docker instance.