Setter injection using the Java configuration approach is
really is as simple as a method call.
Some of the mystery of injection just goes away.
A lot of developers I talk to are concerned with the black box
fail of dependency injection or inversion of control, and with
the Java configuration approach,
it's more visible as to what's actually going on. With XML, there's a
lot of wondering what's wired up and what's calling in, who and how this
auto wiring is all taking place, and that just kind of goes away with
the Java configuration approach.
Setter injection is simply a matter of calling a setter on a bean.
We're going to define a bean using the @Bean annotation,
and you can see here that we've got our getCustomerService
method that returns a bean of type customerService, or a
bean named customerService.
And notice, though, that we have the setter injection in here.
As we're building our beans,
we're going to call this setCustomerRepository method
on our customerService instance.
To do that,
we need to have a method called getCustomerRepository in our configuration
that returns the customerRepository bean. This is going to wire the
customerRepository inside of our customerService.
Let me say that again.
We're not going to call an instance or create, we're going to call and get an
instance of the bean from the Spring configuration file.
So when we define a bean such as our customerRepository here
that returns an instance of customerRepository,
you can see that those methods now line up.
I'm going to call getCustomerRepository that's registered as a Spring bean,
and that's going to return an instance for our setCustomerRepository instance
on our service instance. Take note, Spring is still doing a lot of heavy
lifting behind the scenes when a bean is registered,
such as these beans are all by default a singleton and will only
execute the method the first time it's called.
It's a very key point because if I didn't have this set up this way,
it would create a new bean every time we call this. Since it is in Spring,
it's going to register this is as a singleton and only return one instance.
Let's look at what the code would look like not using Spring since it's really the same code.