The focus of this course has since been moved to complete Java
configuration, but to show the XML equivalent,
this is what it would look like.
You may maintain existing applications that still have XML in there,
and the XML configuration actually still works just fine, so I wanted to
show you the two so you could compare and contrast them.
We have a bean for the customerRepository, we have a bean
for the customerService, and the property for wiring the
repository into the service.
That's where our setter injection is occurring.
We created that bean and then injected it through that property into our service instance.