Opening our user object back up,
I'll go ahead and give ourselves some space between our Long id and our
String firstname and specify @Column from javax.persistence,
and we'll give this a name = FIRST_NAME.
And we can do the same thing with lastname.
We'll say @Column, and we will give it a name = LAST_NAME,
and that will get us through the example of what we're trying to
show that we can have different columns named for specific member
variables inside of our entity here.
I do want to also point out that you can also use this
Column annotation with the private Long id,
the primary key associated with our object.
So if you want to name your primary key something other than id,
maybe USER_ID or CONF_USERS_ID, you can use the Column annotation on it as well.
Let's save this and restart our server.
And once it redeploys, we'll switch over to our MySQL Workbench.
Let's refresh our schema. And once we expand that,
we can see that we have CONF_USERS and our Columns are FIRST_NAME and LAST_NAME.
So it went ahead and updated and altered the table how we thought it would,
which was great.
That's actually the functionality we're looking for,
and you can see how we can override column names by default.
I do want to go ahead and change our ddl update to create‑drop.
As we're doing a lot of these changes,
it's often an inconvenience that something gets
stuck because we've changed a value.
So I'm going to switch back over to my IDE and change that right
now. Inside of our application.properties, we left this as
create. We'll change it to create‑drop.
Now I will remind you that as we start adding data into these tables,
this will drop that data.
But as we're making a lot of changes,
you'll notice that from time to time something may get stuck.
You'll change a column that didn't exist or did exist, and you've removed it.
Now it's kind of confused as to the state that it should
be in. By changing this to create‑drop,
and if we stop our server before we make those changes,
it should drop those tables, and things should not get stuck for us.
So I'm going to go ahead and change mine to create‑drop, stop the server,
and it should go ahead and drop all of that stuff for us.
And as we bring it back up next time, it'll keep recreating that exactly how we would like.