A very pleasant upgrade to this course is that Spring has enabled it to
where we don't need a persistence.xml file any longer.
Historically, this is where we would configure database connections,
some various transaction things,
the persistency unit that we were dealing with, things of that nature.
But we can do all of this without this file anymore.
This was actually the last piece of XML that our application had in it,
and we no longer need it.
I leave this slide in here just to show you that if you are looking at
older examples or you're troubleshooting something,
this is kind of a legacy piece.
If you're just doing JPA by itself, you still need one.
But if you're using Spring, we no longer need this file.
And that's a much nicer upgrade to not have yet another place to go
hunting and pecking through, looking for some other configuration attributes. So no longer need this XML inside of our app.