So far,
everything we have seen and have been dealing with
has been simple primitive types.
How do we deal with objects or lists other than simple primitives?
Since JPA is all about dealing with objects,
we need to be able to bind collections of objects to the database.
There are essentially four types of annotations that we can use to
join objects and collections to one another.
There is a OneToOne, a OneToMany, a ManyToOne, and a ManyToMany.
These can be used in various configurations,
such as unidirectional or bidirectional.
And then we also have cascading features associated with them.
The most common is typically the OneToMany and ManyToOne joins, and the most complex is definitely the ManyToMany.