I've closed out all of the open tabs that I had just so we can
focus on doing this one‑to‑many mapping.
Let's begin by right‑clicking on model and creating a new Java class,
and its name is going to be Course.
We're going to annotate this just like we did our registration.
We're going to give it the @Entity annotation, @Table.
We'll name this COURSE, all uppercase.
Inside of our class, we'll also give it an @Id and @GeneratedValue.
We'll have a member variable private Long id.
And then let's give it a couple of other fields just to make it more meaningful.
We'll have inside of here an @Column, and we'll name this name,
which will just be the name of the course,
and it will be a private String name.
And then another column, and we'll name this one DESCRIPTION.
And this is a bug I often see people introduce into their code base.
They will name this field DESC,
which in some database queries stands for descending.
So if you're going to sort the results on something,
you might sort it descending.
Then we'll make this a string as well.
And since we're already in this class,
we'll add the many‑to‑one mapping back to our registration list here.
This will make more sense in a minute,
but to save us from switching back and forth,
we'll do it while we're here.
We'll say private Registration registration.
We'll save that.
Give ourselves some white space at the bottom and Generate, Getters and Setters.
Select all the fields.
Click OK and save that.
Now we have our basic course object filled out here,
and we did half of our one‑to‑many join.
We did our many‑to‑one, which is our join back to our object.
Let's go back to our Registration object now. And inside of here, below
name, but above our getter for the ID, let's add an OneToMany annotation,
and it is mapped by registration. And we're going to set cascade using the
enum CascadeType.ALL. And then this is on a private List of Courses. So
we'll pass in the object Course,
and we'll name it Courses. And this is equal to a
new ArrayList, and we'll save it.
And let's go below our get id and right‑click and say Generate, Getter and
Setter. We'll choose Courses. Hit OK. And we've actually specified our
one‑to‑many join and the many‑to‑one back to it.
One key thing to point out here is that the mappedBy = registration,
that string should tie to the name of the member variable on the course object.
So you'll see we have registration over here.
We have registration here. So that's saying that on the courses, our course
object has a field named registration that we have getters and setters for. Tie
that to that object, and that's how we keep that list, that one‑to‑many mapping in check.