With all of our libraries now in place and all the other configuration,
we can begin to set up our data source, and it's actually quite simple.
If we go to src, main, resources,
we have our application.properties file inside of here.
And we can begin by configuring using the Spring properties inside of here.
So we can just say spring.datasource.url and type in here
jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/conference,
and this should be the database that we created in our docker‑compose file. And
then we want to create spring.datasource.username, and we're just going to use
root for this and spring.datasource.password=pass.
And if you didn't use the same values that I did in your docker‑compose,
you'll want to change those to whatever values you put inside of there. Then
finally, we'll say spring.datasource.driver‑class‑name,
and we will put inside of here com.mysql.cj.jdbc.Driver,
and we'll also specify the dialect for our database.
So we'll say spring.jpa.database‑platform.
We want to set that equal to org.hibernate.dialect.MySQL5InnoDBDialect.
Make sure that you get MySQL5InnoDBDialect.
If you just do the MySQLDialect,
it actually won't generate tables correctly in the next module.
So make sure you've got that exact dialect and then save
this. And you'll notice that inside of here,
all of my name value pairs are blue‑green with the exception of the driver,
and that's because it looks the driver up off the class path.
If you have any red text here right now,
you need to fix what it is pointing to because it's got something incorrect.
Our URL, username, password, and dialect are all correct based off of the container that we set up.