Let's add the code necessary to get our courses tied to our registration.
We're really close to having this done,
but there's a few things were going to tweak to make
it actually easier in the long run.
First of all,
let's change our GeneratedValue that goes with our Id on
our registration to a different strategy.
So we're going to go into the GeneratedValue(strategy = GenerationType,
and we want to select IDENTITY.
And what this is going to do is use the auto‑incrementing IDs in
MySQL to automatically populate our objects.
This is a nicer strategy for when we're cascading things.
The other thing we were doing was working just fine.
This is better for what we're trying to cascade saves across multiple
objects and one‑to‑many mapping such as we're doing now.
Let's do the same thing over on Course.
Let's open it up and change the GeneratedValue here.
I'll say strategy, and the identity here will be GenerationType.IDENTITY.
There's an enum for that.
So everything is saved there.
Now let's go into our RegistrationServiceImpl,
and I want to go here because this is where your business logic should reside.
So let's say that everybody who registers for our
conference should attend an introductory course.
So what we're going to do is we're still going to leave
our registrationRepository setting here,
but what we're going to do is get rid of that return for now and
say registration is equal to that object that gets returned from
the registrationRepository.save.
And if you'll remember,
I very subtly mentioned earlier that I like to always return the object.
This is why.
We're going to actually use that object here now.
So let's get our return registration back inside of here,
and let's go create a repository layer for our course.
So we'll right‑click on Repository and say New, Java Class.
And this will be the CourseRepositoryImpl.
And this is going to be just like the other ones that we did.
You're starting to see a little bit of pattern here.
I'll say Repository.
We'll go inside of here.
We'll inject our PersistenceContext, store that to an EntityManager,
and then we'll create a method that is public,
returns Course, and we'll call this save.
It's going to take Course as a parameter,
and then we will use our entityManager to persist it.
And then finally, we will return our course object that we just created.
So now that we have this,
let's right‑click and refactor and extract an interface.
We'll call this CourseRepository and include that save method,
Refactor, and have it look for any places that it can change.
There are none.
Everything's okay there.
Go back to our RegistrationService.
And now that we're in our RegistrationService,
we can actually auto wire our new repository that we just created in here.
So we'll say @Autowired private CourseRepositoryImpl,
except we want to choose the interface, not the implementation.
Say CourseRepository and save that.
And now since we're just going to create this
course for anybody that comes along,
we could actually retrieve one out of the database,
but this will work for our example.
We'll say Course course = to new Course,
and we'll just set the name on that to Intro,
and we'll say course.setDescription.
Every attendee the must complete the intro.
And then we will now say course.setRegistration,
and this is the registration we saved up above,
and that will pass in registration.
Now we can use the repository we just created.
So I'll courseRepository.save, pass in our course, and those will now be bound.
I want to point out if we go look at our RegistrationRepositoryImplementation,
we are using a pass‑by‑reference here.
Registration gets altered when it gets persisted and handed back
to us to when we use it, over in our service,
it will have the ID stored in there.
So let's fire up our server.
Our web page will pull up.
We'll add a registration.
And you'll see we'll have this course now bound to our registration.
Now that our server has started up,
I can go into our app and click on Add Registration,
type in my name and Add Registration and now switch over to our MySQL Workbench,
and this should all be synced up.
First,
I can click on our registration and run that select * from REGISTRATION
and see that I've got a couple of entries in there.
I've ran it a few times.
And then I can see that I've got ID 1 and ID 2 since I ran it twice.
If I click on select * from COURSE and run it,
I can see that I have associated those correctly.
I've got ID 1 or Course 1. It says that every attendee must
complete the intro, and intro is the name, and it's tied back
to the registration 1. And the same thing, the second one is
tied back to registration 2.
So I have all of my associations correct, and the one‑to‑many and the
many‑to‑one mapping all synced up across my objects.
Now if we deleted our registration since we have that cascade set to ALL,
it would actually delete the course from this table as well.
So we have everything synced up, our cascading set up, our
generated strategy for our IDs synced up correctly. Everything is now wired up for this one‑to‑many, many‑to‑one join.