The Spring Framework started out as an Inversion of Control container,
and although I won't be covering all the details of Spring in this course,
I'm going to cover enough to get you comfortable with
understanding what Spring is doing for us inside of our
application while we learn more about JPA and Hibernate.
Spring was conceived to reduce or replace some of the complex
configuration of the Java Enterprise Edition,
and later it was built around using Java without EJBs.
This is an important point because JPA was extracted out of the
Enterprise API because people wanted to use JPA without EJBs.
So, what is Spring?
It is a framework originally built around reducing the
complexities of enterprise Java development and later also
providing enterprise development without EJBs.
Spring can essentially be used with or without EJBs,
and this is an important point because Spring enabled us to do
enterprise development without an application server.
This is one of the reasons that Tomcat and some of the other lightweight
containers have taken the Java development space by storm.
It is easy to use and lightweight,
and until Spring, you were either using enterprise
features with an application server,
and you had a more complex software development lifecycle,
or you were doing rich client applications.
Now,
Spring enables us to switch over to using a lightweight container like Tomcat,
which is easier and faster to develop applications with.
Spring is POJO based, and POJO, as you remember,
stands for Plain Old Java Object.
All of the objects that we're using can be used and wired without Spring.
The only reason I bring this point up is because some people often think
there's some magic or black box that they don't understand about what's
going on behind the scenes with the Spring Framework.
It is still built around simple POJOs.
We've talked about it being lightweight now,
but we should also point out that Spring was built out of the
frustrations of J2EE and the older APIs.
They looked a lot at the blueprints and things like that and said,
what's a better way for us to use these tools and make our code more testable?
Spring also heavily uses AOP, or aspect‑oriented programming,
to apply things like transactions to your code without you needing to go
through and manually or explicitly define them inside your code.
We will use a AOP,
although you won't realize that it's in your code just
through some of the simple annotations,
and your application will then automatically have transactions.
Spring is also built around best practices and design patterns,
which is one of the most appealing parts of Spring to me.
A lot of developers used to wade through the JEE blueprints
and implement singletons or factories, facades and abstract factories.
You can still do that,
but all of these are built into the Spring Framework as well.
So if you have existing patterns that you've already developed,
Spring will work well with these.
But Spring also does this itself inside the application and
inherently encourages better design in your code.
So these patterns, singleton, factory, and abstract factory,
if you've ever gone through and built some of the older style methods of
making your database transparent to your application,
you've done this, and you've implemented a concrete factory.
But Spring also makes a lot of use of the template method pattern,
as well as callbacks and those types of things.
But lastly, it's heavily annotation based,
and some developers used to shy away from Spring
because of its XML configuration.
With the more recent versions of Spring,
all configuration is annotation based, and more recently,
configuration is all done within Java code, thus eliminating all XML, if desired.