I've gone ahead and shut down my server and closed all the
open files that we had just so we can focus on implementing
projection inside of our application.
Let's right‑click on our model package, so com.pluralsight.conference,
model, and create a new Java class.
We're going to call this RegistrationReport and hit Enter.
I'm going to add three member variables at the top here.
We'll say private String name, private String courseName,
and the last one we'll do private String courseDescription.
And then we're going to give ourselves some white space below those,
and we can right‑click and say Generate,
Constructor.
We'll choose all three of those.
Hit OK.
And then we will right‑click below that and go to Generate again and choose
Getter and Setter and choose all three of them again.
So we've created our basic object,
just a simple POJO for our RegistrationReport that contains our name,
courseName,
and courseDescription and the constructor we're going to use for projection.
So let's save this.
Let's open up our RegistrationController,
and I'm going to grab our registrations method that we created in
the previous demo and just copy it and paste this.
I'm going to change the GetMapping to registration‑reports and
change this to a list of RegistrationReports.
We'll call this getRegistrationReports.
And the same thing down here, we'll change the list type and the return.
And finally, we'll change the method that it calls to findAllReports.
We haven't created this yet.
We're about to.
So I'll save this class,
and let's do the quickfix on it and go to Create method findAllReports,
and it'll take us to our RegistrationService interface.
I can save this.
And when I open up our RegistrationServiceImpl,
it'll tell us that we're missing a method.
And if we do the hot fix for it,
we can say Implement methods, choose that, click OK. It'll give us a space at
the bottom here. We're going to do the same exact thing.
And again, I realize that we're copying and pasting this for the course.
You could put some query logic inside of here for
pagination or those types of things, filtering.
This will work for the example that we have though. Say
findAllReports. And if we do the hot fix on it,
say Create method and save it and open up our
RegistrationRepositoryImpl, we're going to run into the same exact
thing of it telling us that we need to implement this method.
So we'll choose that, and I'm going to grab this method that we had here
up above and use the body of it to help us create this.
So we're going to return a list of RegistrationReports,
RegistrationReports. Because we're starting to scroll off the screen
here, I'm going to create a string and just call it jpql. Set that
equal to this and grab the body out of this method here, jpql. And
we'll define what that is up above here.
So we're going to set up the class name where we call Select new. And
we do have to fully qualify the package in here.
That's one thing that is a little bit confusing.
So we'll say com.pluralsight.conference.model.RegistrationReport.
And from here,
we actually get to specify in the constructor
arguments. So we're going to say r.name,
c.name, c.description. And then let's return that down to a new line.
We're going to pull all of that from registration r, Course c where r.id =
c.registration.id. And then let's put our semicolon on the end of that. I'm
going to give you a second to look and see how I have that typed in. And
notice that at the end of each of these lines,
I do have some white space.
So there is a space at the end of r.name, c.name, description in
between that and that closing parenthesis and the same at the end
of our from clause because if not,
it would be all bunched together and actually wouldn't query correctly.
So make sure you have that typed in there.
You can also opt to grab this query out of the exercise files or the GitHub
repo where I've got this all typed out for you as well,
just in case you're having any problems with it.
So I'm going to say this. I'm going to fire up my server. And
as this loads, I'm going to open up Postman and do a query on
that new URL that we typed in here.
Okay, picking up where we left off in Postman, I'm going to change
this to registration‑reports and just hit the Send button. And
you'll notice the structure that we had before where we were pulling
back a collection and then it had a collection inside of it, that's
going to flatten out.
So when I click Send on this now, you'll notice that we're just one layer deep.
So it's a lot more performant of a query.
It just gets back the fields that we want if we wanted to leave the
course name out or the description out. Notice the IDs aren't showing up
here, any of those things. So it allowed us to create a much more
specific object for what we wanted to return.
I should also note to you that this is a common technique used for searching.
So one thing that people often don't realize in web
applications is that your search is an object,
and that's how you can save search history for people as well.
So searching oftentimes is a JPA entity, and the report back or the results back can be done very well with projection.