So this was a big module.
We covered a lot of things in here and had a lot of demos.
We went over the most common and default annotations using JPA.
We looked at how to override the defaults and what they implement for you.
We went through the service and repository tier from Spring,
and we also looked at joins and using one‑to‑many and many‑to‑one. We
also demoed fetch types, eager versus lazy, and showed you some of the
limits or exceptions you might face with that.
And then we went over projection, one of the most powerful, but
often overlooked usages of JPA in my opinion.
And lastly, we cleaned up some of our code using named queries.
We have one more module left,
and we're going to dive into the actual Spring Data portion of
using JPA and some of their convenience interfaces that they have
and how that can reduce even more of the boilerplate code that we
have inside of our applications.
So some of that copy and pasting we've been doing, you're going to see a lot of that go away in this next module.