Continuing on our timeline of current versions that we're going to be using,
we had looked earlier at JPA, and JPA 2.2 was released in 2017.
I'll honestly admit that releases for JPA versions have slowed down a lot,
and some of that has to do with us tackling a lot of the
problems that we see inside of ORM tools.
Hibernate 5.4 was released in 2018,
and we will be using a new version of this release, just a minor dot revision.
And finally,
Spring 5.3 was released and has all of the current integrations baked into it.
So this is a pretty good snapshot of the current stack that we will be using with possibly some minor dot revisions in there as well.