We talked about tiers and layers,
and we've even started to allude to components inside of our application now, so
how do we represent these tiers with Spring and Spring MVC?
We do that using these three components.
We have our controller, service, and our repository.
We've already discussed controllers already, they just
route where we're going and interpret the user's request,
and then there's the service, and that's where our business logic goes.
It should also be noted that it's where our transactions will likely start
if we're accessing more than one database table as well.
And then there's repositories.
The repository tier is also sometimes referred to
as a data access object, or DAO, and they usually have a one‑to‑one mapping with our database table.