In this module, we talked about what is Spring and a
little bit of the history of Spring.
It's a very stable framework, has a pretty consistent release cycle,
and it's always been very backwards and forwards compatible.
We also talked about what is JPA and kind of the roots of JPA, how it was
influenced from tools like Hibernate, TopLink, JDO, and became a 1.0
specification that was later extracted out of EJBs because people wanted to
use it without using Enterprise JavaBeans.
We also looked at the problem of what our business focus is and
all that JDBC code that really has nothing to do with us getting
this query back, and those are hoops we have to jump through to
find that information.
But really that's one line of query and getting that car object back
is what our business cares about and what JPA and Hibernate will help
us do inside of our Spring application.
Let's get rolling on our application though and look at what we
need to do to download the sample app and do a quick walkthrough of our Spring MVC application now.