Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in Mediterranean 4.
I hope you're as excited about today's tutorial as I am because today we're finally going to tally up
the results of a four week demo test.
I'm just going to bring up the calendar to show what day it is today.
And today is Monday the 6th of October 2014.
As you recall we launched our Demel tests way back on Monday the 8th of September 2014.
So that means that they have been running for a full four weeks.
And so let's get straight into it.
Let's see what the results are and find out who the winner is.
So here we've got simple system said one with our 10 as you remember.
This was the most profitable set on our back test and forward test.
However in the live demo tests we can see that it has been performing completely differently.
It has actually created a loss on the count over the four week period of the demo test.
This set was able to lose so $151 and 98 cents and that's what a stun deposit of $5000.
So this is definitely something that we would not consider putting on a large scale real account because
it's going to lose money and it's great that we found this out on the demo test because we would be
very disappointed to run into this on the real test.
And that's a very good illustration of how sometimes back tests and for tests can show great results
.
But then the live demo test will actually uncover the truth before we move onto the next set I wanted
to show you a couple of things.
So if we're right click here and if we click last month then what you will see is that only the last
month's trades will be displayed.
And sometimes this is the default case and meditator for this way you're only seeing any trades that
were conducted in the current month that you're in.
If this is the case for you right now then all you have to do is right click and click all history to
see all of the trades during this demo test.
And a good checking point for this is if you look at the very top if the trades are sold by an order
of there by the order number or by the time they were created you'll at the very top you should see
a deposit on to your account that was the initial deposit on to your demo account.
Or if it's a real account can do onto your real account.
So that's a good control point.
And because sometimes if it's sunset to last month it might be set to last three months or two custom
period.
So just make sure you click all history so you are seeing all of the trades.
And the second thing I want to show you is sometimes the trades don't fit onto one full screen.
So what you want to do is you right click and you click save as detailed report.
You select a name for a report click save.
Cook Yes.
And what that will do is in all men trader for will convene and conveniently arrange all of your trades
into a an HMO report just like with the back test and forward test.
It's structured a little bit differently.
The trees are on top and the stats are at the bottom.
But the essence is the same.
So here you can see all the trades on one convenient screen at the bottom you can see the chart and
you can see the stats so from this chart right away we can see what was going on.
At first it was losing.
And then there was only two profitable big profitable trades and the rest were small losses on their
count.
And this is something we don't want to continue pursuing further.
So having said that we're going to stop with this damage.
We're not going to.
This is definitely something that we're going to discard and we would never put some very close on to
a large scale real account.
So moving onto the next set set to where Ali was nine this was the second most profitable trade that
we saw in the back test and forward test.
And as you can see here it did yield a profit on their column a small profit of under 10 percent over
a four week period.
Also you can see that it's got quite a few very profitable trades and quite a lot of losses on the canso
to investigate this further we would want to look at the report and see how the graph of this set was
structured.
So let's go ahead.
I've already opened up the report here.
As you can see the trends are also top and let's go down and look at the chart and maybe the stats.
So here we can see that it's kind of like a sword shaped chart is going to go to a few trades going
yielding losses on the column and then one profitable trade and then more losses and profitable.
So it is kind of going up but this is not something that you'd want to consider.
Like look at the profit factor it's one point fifteen.
And as we will discuss further in the course we should aim for profit factors of 1.6 and above expected
payoff is right it's $32 a net profit pro-trade maximal drawdown as 13 percent so that's something like
you'd want to consider in making a decision.
From my experience and my personality I wouldn't put such said on a large scale real account.
However having said that it might be worth putting it on a small real account just to test it out in
real market conditions.
And maybe it will perform better or you will be able to confirm your opinion that you're not happy with
this set.
So it's kind of like in between.
This particular set of simple system.
All right so this one would gain a question mark and maybe it's where further investigation but maybe
not depending on your personality.
So moving on to the more interesting set set number three where our was for as you can see here we've
got quite a lot of profitable trades.
And it just makes you smile when you look at all of these trades on the constancy and the count and
you can see these green tech profits and on the right.
More importantly how much of the profits were as you can see there's a loss trade at the end which is
justified because this happened on the last Friday of our DeMatteis and that happened to be the first
Friday of October.
And as we know every month on the first Friday of every month the U.S. releases non-farm payrolls and
unemployment news that news may have affected our pattern and what we were used to seeing was the pattern
that this expert advisors after.
So usually I don't trade on the very first Friday of every month.
And you can learn more about that and how to though in other ways protect your system from these external
factors.
In my other course that I've planned I haven't started it yet but I'm planning on starting it.
It will be a course on strategy designed for the Forex market so look out for that maybe check for ex-beau
dotcom from time to time to see when I really set course and that's something I'll definitely talk about
there.
But going back to our set as he can see this set yielded three thousand one hundred forty one dollars
and 50 cents of pure profit from a deposit of $5000 in the space of four weeks.
So that some 62 percent profit in 4 weeks.
It's incredible.
It's unbelievable it's something that you don't see often.
And this is something that is definitely worth considering putting onto a live a real minea account
just for testing it out first in real market conditions and then maybe moving it onto a large scale
real account.
So let's have a look at the results in the form of a report.
So I've got this report here.
And as you can see all these trades are up at the top.
And here we've got our chart which is an amazing chart.
And of course you always have these losses on your count which occur from time to time and are inevitable
.
But as will discuss further in the course.
Good systems are able to get out of them quicker than bad systems.
And also you should look at other factors like in this case profit factious 365 which is more than double
the recommended 1.6 expected payoff is incredible $241 net profit per trade.
So it's it's got a lot of good stuff to it like maximal drawdown is only seven point eighteen percent
so that's under 10 percent of maximal drawdown.
I think this is a great set.
I think it's something that we would definitely consider taking forward.
And so this set receives a good grade golden star for its performance on the four week test.
I remind you that it's four weeks because that means we've got a substantial number of trades to have
significant results that we can consider.
And finally moving on to simple systems set for where our WAS 8 here.
We've got another incredible said where most of the trades were profitable.
In fact all the trades except for one were proffered on just trying to.
There we go.
So here it's just amazing looking at these take profits all the trades that were on this account were
profitable.
Last one.
And as we've discussed this may have been affected by non-farm payrolls and unemployment.
But nevertheless the said yielded 1400 and 10 dollars of pure profit on a deposit of $5000 in the space
of four weeks which is 28 percent profit.
So let's jump to the report and have a look at that.
Here we've got those profitable trades and an amazing incredible chart just going up up up and then
maybe a loss and hopefully if this were to continue it would be going up up up again.
Let's look at the stats profit factor is 324 three point twenty four which is just more than double
the recommended 1.6.
Expect to pay off his $108 net profit per trade maximal drawdown is still under 10 percent so it's just
just under 9 percent which is a very good result.
So this is another set that we would definitely consider taking forward putting on a live real account
.
Real account just for testing it in real market conditions were real money and then moving on to a large
scale real account.
So this said risk is another golden star great said great performance very happy will fit.
This sums up our demo test.
It was a great four week run and I'm really glad that we got this kind of mix of sets and you saw how
profitable sets on there were profitable and back to us and forward as can turn out to be to create
losses on real accounts how you've got other assets that can perform really well and they've got a good
mix of trades and they've got quite a lot of entries into the market over this period.
So that was great fun.
I'm really happy that you got to see all of this and see how a demo test should be conducted to make
sure that what you are taking forward is a reliable reliable sets for your expert Yser in the next couple
of tutorials you'll see how to conduct a real test with real money.
And I'll remind you that I'm putting $500 of my own money on the line just to see how this expert advisor
performs in real market conditions.
And that's going to be real fun.
And I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy training