Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in meditative form.
It's a turtle I'll show you how to download and install the simple system.
Expert adviser.
So to start off with We need to open our browser.
As you can see here I've already got my browser window open on the four exposed Web site.
We will need to go to the following address and you'll need to type that in in your browser.
And so the address is w w w dot for X boat dot com slash simple hyphen system.
So that's the address and if we click enter after which type that in the Brossel will take you to the
following page as you can see here.
This is the simple system for Strober page.
And here you can read a little bit about the expert advisor.
I didn't put too much information on this page because you can get all this all these insights from
the Course itself.
And once you've read disclaimer and if you agree to it then you can download the expert was here.
Also you'll see that there is already another version.
So simple system version five point always the original one intended for this course have already created
another one which is version 5.1.
And as you'll see through this course we will be using it and there isn't much of a change I just added
the magic number which I will explain in further tutorials.
This just illustrates that if any more versions become available then you can always download them from
this page.
So now we're going to download simple system version 5.0 and installed in our bright you know metro
area for terminal.
So you can see here I'm already downloading it and if I open open the folder for this file here you
can see it's a zip file.
So what you need to do is you need to extract files them with your zip extractor and they're all available
on any Windows system.
And here you inside the folder you see simple system version 5.0 dot Q4.
So now we're going to go back to the terminal.
And in order to get expert advice in here so we can see it in this tab or in strategy tester when you
go to file and open a folder.
So by clicking open data for the we're going to the folder where all of the data for Medicare reform
is kept for your particular user of the Windows system.
So just be careful that this is not the installation folder.
Therefore as you can see up here it's a completely different fault and that's because of the User Account
Control System in Windows.
And if you want to find out more about that and how to avoid this how to make your daughter folder equivalent
to your
installation folder.
Then you need to launch first you need to launch Myntra to form portable mode and you can find out more
about portable mode and my other course which is called Bulletproof virtual private server set up for
algorithmic trading.
Other than that we're in the data folder now and we need to go to M kill for a hearing to go to experts
and we need to copy the file into this for that as you can see here.
I already have some files here I'll just get rid of them for now.
So we want to copy our downloaded file so from here I'll just make this window it's smaller.
So we just want to drag this file across over here and there.
Next what we need to do is we need to restart our terminal.
So I'm just starting my Melchor for terminal again.
And now if we go into expert advisors you will see that simple system are in Five point.
Is there and also it is available in the strategy tester itself.
So that's how you get the expert adviser into your mission for a train platform and that's all for today
.
I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial where we will learn how to download historical data
for the platform which will which we'll use for our testing.
I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy training.