Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization and meditated for it has been two weeks since
we launched demo tests.
And I just want to check in with you to keep you up to date with what's going on.
I'll just bring up the calendar here.
And as you can see we launched Demel tests on Monday the 8th of September.
Today is Friday the 19th of September 2014.
So it's been two full working weeks that the deputies have been running for and let's have a look at
the results so far.
So this first set simple system said one where our was 10.
It has not created an profitable trades at all.
And moreover it's lost nearly 20 just over 27 percent of its deposit.
So we can quite confidently say that we should discard this set no no and try.
At this stage next one simple system set to where our was nine as you can see there were some losses
but then there was a substantial profit which was about three times the size of a loss just more than
that.
And that kind of helped that recover the deposit a bit and currently is battling to get this profit
on the sell order.
It's at 640 dollars profit right now.
And it just scrape the take profit which didn't trigger it.
So we'll see how that goes.
But I wouldn't get my hopes up for this system at this stage because it does look quite risky.
The next one is simple system set three or four so far as my favorite one because it's had a mix of
profits and losses.
Before we continue I'll just show you a quick handy trick.
So if you drag a order onto the chart so it has to be the same chart as the chart of the same instrument
as the order if you drag it onto that chart then you'll see that the order just appears there and that's
a very handy way to view your historical orders.
Moreover if you want to see all of them then you just click on any one of them hold shift on your keyboard
and drag that order onto the chart.
What that will do is all of the orders for that currency pair will appear on the chart.
Just be careful not to drag a different currency parent child because that might change the chart and
that might affect our expert wiser.
So here you can see there was a profit.
Then there was a another profit a small loss and another profit another profit and no trades in the
past two days.
So it's a good mix a good mix of profit and profitable loss trades in the sense that we kind of see
all the aspects of the system there's a profit.
A lot of the profits are at take profit this profit was like a stop or time don't take profit.
It was caused by the system because I knew order was great.
And then this one as well.
So and if we go into the parameters as you can see that the take profit is 50 and still plus 6 so they're
pretty close.
And I kind of like that system.
It's not too adventurous and so let's let's see how this one keeps going so far as fiery like the result
.
And then finally simple systems set for our eight only profitable trades no open orders no losses.
The profits are quite small so we'll do the same.
We'll just drag this onto the chart holding down shift and you'll see that the profits are quite small
so it's going for small take profits here it's 20 and the stop loss would be three times as high it
would be 60 if it were to occur.
So I I do like this one but it is a bit more risky.
The ratio of take profit to stop loss isn't as good but we'll have to look at it see how it goes in
the coming weeks and make hard decisions that end.
And finally at the end of the story I wanted to mention that today I will be launching a real test of
a simple system version 5.0.
It'll be quite interesting test.
I'll be putting $500 of my own money on the line to see how this 4 x robot behaves in real market conditions
.
Also you'll notice that in the course when you're going through it the real test tutorials come after
the demo test tutorials.
And in that way the kernel chronological order isn't maintained.
However I thought it would make more sense to first have all the charges relating to the demo test and
then all tutorials relating to the real test.
So there's just something to keep in mind when you're going through this course.
Other than that thanks for this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you in the next one.
Until then happy trading