Hi my name is Daragh.
I'm from Dublin Ireland.
Welcome to this course where you are going to become Google Analytics certified in just one day.
And by the end of this course you will have the official Google Analytics certification issued by Google
really showing tangible evidence of your analytic skills and it's an extremely valuable certification
to have because it will enable you to get a high paying job.
Win freelancing clients and use google analytics as a powerful tool to grow your own business or a company's
business and to become certified you need to pass the official Google Analytics exam.
It's a 90 minutes
Multiple choice exam that is 70 questions.
It really covers a broad range of topics
about Google Analytics and I've really designed this course so you can get that certificate in the shortest
amount of time possible and I really designed this for you to get it in one day.
And here is how you're going to do it.
So first you're going to access some key Google Analytics resources.
Second you're just going to watch the Google training for beginner.
I prepared this myself.
The slides are available for download.
It's extremely detailed.
We cover a lot in just 60 minutes.
Then you can watch the Advanced Google and training that I prepared for you in just 45 minutes.
And then you can take the practice test which is really based on the questions in the real exams.
This is incredible preparation.
And then you create your academy for ads account. Just takes five minutes.
This is where you take the exam and then take the official exam another hour and a half and then I'm going to show
you how to add the certification to your resume linked in profile and freelancing sites so you can really get those
high paying jobs.
And win those freelancing clients.
So in total it's actually much less than a day to become certified It's just five hours you can do this.
Right now go straight through and do it all.
And it's a really a tangible profound result in a short amount of time and the process really does work.
You can easily become certified just like these students here.
Kushal says he passed on the first attempt it was totally worth it.
Lukas says here that he got his certificate within hours of starting the course. Ghani here pass the
exam Boo-Hoo he got 94 percent.
So there is nothing holding you back from becoming a Google certified professional.
You don't need to be part of a company to take the exam.
You don't need to have any on the job experience and you don't even need to spend a penny to take the
exam.
The Google Analytics certification exam is free.
So let's get started.
So you can become Google Analytics certified in just one day.