So how do we know what sorts of devices support Amazon FreeRTOS?
Well, there's a few ways we can do this.
One of the first is to just read through the AWS partner vendors,
companies like Espessif, Nordic Semiconductor,
and STMicroelectronics,
all produce hardware that's specifically designed and passed
tests to be able to host Amazon FreeRTOS,
the operating system.
Now this is the same for Amazon Greengrass software,
which we'll talk about later on,
but what if you don't necessarily want to work with a partner vendor?
Well,
then you can use your own hardware and test the hardware
for compatibility with Amazon FreeRTOS.
But how do you do that?
Well, let's take a look at the AWS IoT Device Tester.
It is a Windows, Linux,
and Mac test automation tool for connected devices that can determine if
your device is running Amazon FreeRTOS or AWS IoT Greengrass can be
authenticated by and interoperate with AWS IoT Services.
So essentially this will allow you to test if your own
hardware is going to be an effective device for Amazon
FreeRTOS or Amazon's IoT Greengrass.
So let's take a look at how this works exactly.
Well, the first step is we'd have a machine running the device testing software.
Now this would be a Mac, Linux,
or Windows device that downloads and installs the device tester software.
Now after this, you'll also need the device that you want to test,
which will be a potentially compatible device that is eventually plugged into
the testing machine and a series of tests are then run.
Now these run in sequence because you can't run every single
test at the same time because of potential limitations on the
storage space on these devices.
So several tests will be sent over, the results will be sent back,
and then that process will continue until a full suite
of tests has been run on a device.
Now if after all the tests run, they all return successful,
this means that your device is effectively ready to go and can be used with AWS's device software.