No discussion of AWS IoT device software would be complete
without talking about the AWS IoT Device SDKs.
So let's take a quick look at what these are.
The AWS IoT Device SDKs allow you to easily connect to
AWS IoT and other AWS service s.
They're going to use MQTT or MQTT over the WebSocket protocol,
in order to make those connections,
and they're also going to allow you to do things like publish and subscribe
to IoT topics and interact with IoT rules and shadows.
Now this is a subset of the functionality that they offer,
but essentially you can think of the device SDK as the
massive library of tools that will let you leverage all of
the functionality of AWS IoT.
Now the AWS IoT Device SDK comes in a variety of different types.
It'll provide language support for things like development in iOS and Android,
it'll also allow you to use Python or embedded C,
C++, Java, and JavaScript.
So essentially a lot of different support for many different platforms and
languages to do whatever you'd like to do with your IoT devices.
Now this will save you the work of having to manually code all
of the different API calls to AWS services,
and allow you to take advantage of security benefits and new features down
the road as AWS continues to add more functionality.
So be sure to take a look at this whenever you're starting a project with AWS IoT.