Hello and welcome to my course AWS IoT: The Big Picture.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey,
and in this section we'll be looking at why AWS IoT.
Now before we get started, I just want to briefly answer the question,
who is this course for?
If you're taking this course,
you might want to be either looking for a conceptual overview of the AWS IoT,
or maybe you're just getting started with IoT in general.
You also probably have a general understanding of cloud computing and
potentially some basic knowledge surrounding Amazon Web Services.
Now a quick side note,
for anybody who's a developer in the audience listening to this course,
this is a conceptual overview and reference for many of the materials you'll
be working with when you start interacting with AWS IoT.
However,
there aren't actually any coding demonstrations in this course and
you won't be diving into many of the APIs that are actually used
behind the scenes to use the entire system.
So keep that in mind, if you're looking for a more practical application,
to take a peek at a few other courses down the line.
Now I also want to be sure to answer the question,
what will you be learning from this course if you're not doing
things like coding and hands on demonstrations?
Well,
in this course we'll be going over a bunch of different things
ranging from basic understandings of IoT generally to identifying
capabilities of specific AWS IoT services,
and how you can use those to suit your needs when
you're developing applications,
as well as adding security and functionality to both your
applications and your devices themselves.
By the end of this course,
you should also understand tools outside of the AWS IoT system
and these include other AWS services that you can integrate with
things inside of the AWS IoT suite.
So hopefully this clarifies what you'll be learning in this course,
but let's take a specific look at the overview for this module.
We'll start by taking a look at what is the Internet of Things?
We'll look at some basic surrounding IoT.
We'll also look at what the purposes of the Internet of Things are,
meaning what we'll be doing with them in our organizations
and how we might benefit from using IoT.
Then we'll look at risks and responsibilities that we face
whenever we're working with the Internet of Things.
Before we start looking at how AWS itself fits within our potential IoT needs.
We'll look at how AWS provides solutions for device software on our IoT devices.
We'll also look at how it can provide services to help us
manage and control and secure our devices,
and how we can analyze and enrich the data that's generated by our devices.
Now there are a lot of different AWS services that will
fit into each of these components,
and we'll take more looks at each of these in depth in future modules as well.
But after we've gone over a quick overview of those areas,
we'll start comparing AWS IoT to self- managed IoT.
And we'll look at how AWS IoT is serverless and what that means
for us when we're working with the platform.
We'll also look at security and resilience and how we can
benefit from AWS's focus on security and how resilience is
built into the AWS infrastructure already.
And finally,
we'll take a look at how we can integrate other things with
AWS IoT to get the most out of using it.
Now for each of these different components,
again,
there will be more in depth about the specific IoT
services that we might use in later modules.
So I'll go ahead and see you in the next video where we'll be talking about what is IoT?