So now let's talk about one of the most critical components of AWS IoT,
the AWS IoT Thing Registry.
When we're working with AWS IoT,
we might have a lot of different devices of the same type or we might have a lot
of various different devices of completely different types.
Now when we're working with these,
we're going to want a way that we can allow them to all connect to AWS IoT,
we're going to want to be able to secure those connections to
make sure that they're not forged or hacked,
and we're also going to want to be able to send data from these
varying devices into our AWS IoT system so that can be processed
and evaluated by other applications.
So how do we do all this and what's the building block of getting
started with all of these different devices?
Well that would be the Thing Registry.
Now with the Thing Registry,
you're going to be able to take a bunch of different devices and
classify them into things called thing types.
Now a thing type in this example might be a car,
where we might have an electric car, a sports vehicle,
and just your average everyday automotive,
and all of those could be classified with a thing type of car.
Then if they had similar attributes,
we could actually have each of these cars attributes be stored
and searchable inside of the Thing Registry.
For example, for our sports car and all of our other cars,
we might have the horsepower of the car,
the year it was actually made, and the price of the car,
and those could all be searchable attributes for every single kind
of car that we're using in our Thing Registry.
Now in addition to these three searchable attributes,
we could also have a list of non-searchable attributes that are
essentially just metadata about the car that we can't use the same
way with the searchable attributes,
but still give us useful information whenever we're looking at our IoT things.
So what's some more information about thing types?
Well, when we're working with thing types,
it's important to note that things can have those three searchable attributes,
but when things have a thing type,
they can also have up to 50 non-searchable attributes.
Additionally, you can only have things be associated with one thing type.
Now this is optional,
you don't need to have to a thing type associated with your thing,
but it does give you the ability to add these 50 non-searchable attributes.
Now with that said, you can actually have an unlimited number of thing types.
So this means you can create as many types as you'd like to
sort all of your various IoT things into.
So what are these attributes we're talking about when
we're talking about thing types?
Well,
attributes are essentially just key value pairs and the searchable
attributes are going to help us find specific things,
so if we wanted to find cars with horsepowers above a specific number,
or maybe cars that only have a make of 2017 or 2019.
This would allow us to do that.
Additionally,
we can also have non-searchable attributes that simply provide extra metadata.
Now this becomes useful if we have maybe some cars with
seat warmers or without seat warmers,
we might want to be able to integrate those with our attributes,
but we can't, in the current system of AWS IoT,
have more than just those three searchable attributes.
So back to our Thing Registry visualization here.
We now have thing types, which we can classify our registered things in,
and the attributes associated with both the things
and the thing types themselves.
Now in addition to these concepts here,
we also have the concepts of thing groups.
Now it kind of goes without saying,
but thing groups are essentially going to contain things,
but they can also contain other thing groups.
So we can nest the things and the thing groups together and
keep that going as much as we'd like.
We can also have permission policies that are attached to thing groups,
and I'll talk about that in just a moment.
But in addition to being able to do that,
we can also use thing groups to coordinate update jobs and certificate rotation.
So if we want to have updates across a set of things,
we can use thing groups to do that.
Further, things can also be in a max of 10 thing groups.
So this means that you can't have the same light bulb or the same
car be in more than 10 of these thing groups.
Now this is simple a current limitation that AWS
imposes on us inside of their system.
So with these things groups, we can classify all of our different devices,
maybe across different factories or geographic locations,
and this could allow us to helpfully delineate between these
different devices and also take all of the actions I just
mentioned pertaining to thing groups.
In addition to thing groups, there's also dynamic thing groups.
Now dynamic thing groups,
you can think of as groups that are created using a sort of search query based
on the attributes and other characteristics of IoT things.
Now in this particular example,
let's imagine a search query where we wanted to find any
devices with a battery level of 50% or better.
Now in the case on the right,
there's a bunch of different devices that might be in different locations,
but they all share a characteristic of a battery level attribute,
and this attribute is going to allow us to group all of these
devices together based on that attribute.
Now if the battery level in one of these devices went
down below a certain threshold,
then we would remove that dynamically from the thing group.
Similarly,
if a device with a lower battery level then achieved a
higher battery level than what we needed,
it would be added to this group.
Now dynamic thing groups are created from the search queries,
and they can be much more complex than this.
So what can we do with dynamic thing groups?
Well we can, as we just mentioned,
group things together based on search queries that
look at things like connectivity, metadata,
and other attributes.
We can also apply policies to dynamic thing groups in the same
way we could do it with regular thing groups.
Now these dynamic thing groups can be especially useful
when we want to target devices that need certain
attributes in order to receive updates.
In the case of the battery level example,
in our IoT Thing Registry here,
we could maybe target devices that we knew had sufficient battery
level to run an entire update process without potentially going below
the required battery amount that we needed.
So now that we know about the thing groups and dynamic thing groups,
let's take a look at how certificates and policies
work together to control permissions.
Now when we have a bunch of IoT things,
each of these IoT things is going to need a certificate to
authenticate itself to the IoT Thing Registry.
This certificate will allow those things to say that they are indeed the
verified thing that was associated with a particular certificate.
Now in addition to the certificates that verify the identity of
the device and that it is the device you expect,
there's also policies that can be attached to the certificates themselves.
Those policies will essentially say that anything that can prove it
has that certificate that authenticates its identity should have
this relevant policy associated with it.
Now in addition to associating policies directly with certificates,
you can also associate policies with thing groups.
Now this can be either thing groups or dynamic thing groups,
and in this way you can avoid having to recycle
different policies in the long run.
So for example,
rather than having to attach a policy to every single certificate
out of a million certificates and then renew those as the
certificates are expired and have to be recreated,
you could instead just put things inside of thing groups and then assign
policies to those thing groups that do not need to be rotated,
instead you just manage the certificate rotation and keep
those things within the same thing group.
So hopefully this gives you a better understanding of the IoT Thing Registry.
Whenever you're creating a thing inside of IoT,
you have the option to use all of these different
tools independently or together,
and they can help you form very robust policies for onboarding your devices, or maintaining security, and also for managing permissions and updates.