Let's get started with AWS IoT Analytics.
AWS IoT Analytics is as fully-managed service that makes it
easy to run and operationalize sophisticated analytics on
massive volumes of IoT data.
So what does this actually mean?
Well it's going to make analyzing all of our IoT data
a lot simpler and a lot easier.
Let's start by breaking this out into the two sections of IoT Analytics,
preparing and analyzing information.
We'll start with preparing information by looking at how we can use channels,
pipelines,
and data stores to get us all set up to collect and
prepare that data to be analyzed.
Then,
we'll look at how we can actually analyze this data
using data sets and notebooks.
So let's get started.
Let's imagine we had the earlier IoT rule that we made in a previous module,
and let's just say we sent the data to AWS IoT Analytics rather
than some of the other rules we could configure.
And let's go ahead and say we've done this now and IoT
Analytics is now prepared to take this data in.
Well that's going to get dumped into what's called an IoT Analytics channel.
Now this IoT Analytics channel has a few pieces of the
configuration that we should know about.
The first for the channels are the target for the IoT rule.
Now because channels are targets for an IoT rule,
we can configure the channels as a target or we can
configure the rules as a source, basically it doesn't matter which way we go,
it just depends on which part of the user interface
we're using inside of the AWS console.
But either way,
we will need to start with an IoT rule that outputs
into an AWS IoT Analytics channel.
After that we'll be able to configure our channel to set data retention
settings on how long it wants to keep our information around for.
Now in addition to the channels,
we're also going to have the ability to send the information
from a channel to an IoT Analytics pipeline.
Now this analytics pipeline could do absolutely nothing,
it could just move the data from the channel to an eventual destination.
But it also has the option to take a few configuration settings.
Specifically, we can put an input channel here.
Now this will determine which channel is actually
getting the information to the pipeline,
and then we can say what the output data store will be.
So we can say where are we sending this data.
Now we'd have to have a data store created and configured in
our account in order to set a data store,
and we'll talk about that in just as moment.
But finally, we can also do transformation activities inside of our pipelines,
and these can shift and transform the data that's coming in through IoT
rules and IoT channels to feed into our pipeline.
So what do these transformation activities look like?
Let's take a look at a few of them.
Transformation activities can take the shape of lambda activities where a
lambda function processes potentially more complex data in a customized
manner using code that you write in a lambda function in one of many
different programming language possibilities.
We could also use device registry activities,
which are configured for us in the AWS console or using
configuration through the CLIs or SDKs,
and these are essentially what allow us to go to the Thing Registry,
find information about different devices and enrich the data doing that.
Another option is to use a math activity where we do some math on the
input that's coming in and then output based on that math.
In addition to math, we could do something like a select or filter.
In this case,
we could select information from the input and then
output it to the outgoing message.
Alternatively,
we could filter based on the attributes inside of the message to
determine whether or not we allow it to pass through.
We can do things like look at device shadow activity,
so that would be going to the device shadow itself and pulling
information from that to enrich the data coming in.
And finally,
we could do something like adding and removing attributes themselves.
So we could add our own custom attributes or simply say we
didn't need some attributes that were coming in anymore
and discard them completely.
So this is what we can do in this pipeline stage here.
But after the data moves through the channel towards a pipeline,
it's going to need to eventually end up in a data store.
Now there's a little bit more configuration for data stores as well.
Specifically,
we need to pick how long we want the data to be
retained inside of this data store.
Is this an infinite amount of time or potentially only 90 days?
These configurations do allow us to make sure we're hitting potential legal
requirements or just company policies around our data retention.
So after we've taken a look at all of these different configuration options,
what happens at the point where we're actually done
taking the data in through an IoT rule, an IoT Analytics channel,
sending it over an IoT Analytics pipeline into a data store?
How do we actually take some action on that data and get some insight from it?
Well this is where the next part of the IoT Analytics chain comes into play.
The analyze section will allow us to take a data
store and turn it into a data set.
Now what could we do with these data sets?
Well when we have data sets,
we can configure them with Amazon SageMaker Notebooks.
Now this is going to allow us to run a variety of
different code on the data we have,
including Python code inside of Jupiter Notebooks and other statistical and
programming languages that we could run on these data sets.
Now what does the configuration look like for data sets in Notebooks?
Let's take a look at that now.
When we're doing this, the data sets are going to allow us to set up a SQL query,
so essentially this is going to pick the data store and
potential transformations that we could run on the data store
information and turn it into a data set.
It's also going to determine a schedule with which to run the SQL
query and output a data set from the data store.
So this essentially is going to refresh the data periodically
as it continues to stream in to that data store and provide
us with additional information.
After that,
we can set a retention period for how long we want to keep these
data sets around after we've created them.
We might not want them to get stale.
And in addition to the data set configuration,
we have configuration we can set for notebooks,
and the notebooks are going to allow us to take a look at
a variety of different templates that will allow us to
accomplish different things, depending on what we need the notebook to do.
We'll take a look at that in just a moment.
But the other piece of configuration is, of course, the input data set.
We can take whatever data sets we create and pick which
ones to feed into our notebooks for additional analysis and
visualizations down the line.
So now let's go ahead and take a look at what we can actually do with
some of the prebuilt templates for SageMaker Notebooks.
One of the first and most common possibilities is to
do some sort of anomaly detection.
You'll want to know if there's something weird happening with all of your IoT
devices and this is a perfect way to start checking for that.
You'd also do some output forecasting.
So for example,
if you see some sort of trend inside of the data that you'd like to forecast,
you can do that with SageMaker Notebooks.
There are also templates for predictive maintenance,
if you have maybe a fleet of machines that periodically breaks down,
you want to be able to see which of those machines might break down
soon so that you can call it in early and try and replace faulty
parts or give it preventative maintenance.
Another notebook template would be to use customer segmentation.
For example, if you have a bunch of different varieties of customers,
maybe grouping them together would allow you to target them
more effectively or provide them with products and services
that they'd rather use and see.
After that,
maybe you could do some congestion forecasting and see
whether or not your product was likely to hit its peak
capacity or something along those lines.
Now these are just a few specific examples of templates,
but the power of Amazon SageMaker Notebooks is that you can write
whatever custom code you'd like and you can also use a variety of
common machine learning and data science libraries to power all the
insights that you're trying to generate.
So hopefully now you can see some of the major
benefits that we get from IoT Analytics,
allowing us to not only ingest data from IoT rules,
but to also configure retention periods to determine whether or not we'd like
to transform or enrich our data with the IoT Analytics pipelines and also to
eventually run machine learning algorithms on top of the data sets we create to get more sophisticated insights.