So now let's take a look at two specific examples of improvements to an
organization that were directly the result of leveraging IoT.
First,
we'll take a look at the example of Centratech and then
we'll take a look at the example of iRobot.
Centratech works for the Australian government primarily and helps deal
with things like water shortages and other utility needs that local city
councils and other parts of Australian government actually need in order to
provide utilities to their residents.
Now Centratech previously had been doing manual repairs on
many different devices in the field.
Now those manual repairs were time consuming and expensive
because they had to send technicians all the way out to
the devices to repair them.
They were also doing server management,
so they had to pay their developers to not only develop applications,
but also to manage the underlying infrastructure that they
were building those applications on top of.
In addition to this,
they were previously doing 6 hour trainings for each of
their field technicians so that every time they had to go
out and actually start the job,
it took 6 hours to get the training they needed before they could go
out there and actually repair the physical devices.
Now they eventually ended up using AWS IoT to allow them to
actually have the devices in the field be repaired remotely and
drastically cut down on the amount of time,
and therefore the cost, it took to repair many of those devices.
Additionally, they transitioned over to the AWS IoT managed platform,
which means that because they were using AWS IoT,
they didn't have to pay anybody anymore to manage that infrastructure.
AWS took care of it for them.
Also, after they simplified a lot of their platform and applications,
they were able to cut the training time down to a single hour.
So these were just a few examples of how Centratech actually improved the
efficiency of their organization using IoT technologies.
Now in addition to the Centratech outcomes, we also have the example of iRobot.
Now iRobot is a manufacturer of wireless and cordless vacuums that
robotically go around your home and clean it up.
Now iRobot, back in July of 2015, sold 14,
000 Roomba robotic vacuums just in a single day on Amazon Prime day.
Now it eventually later launched internet- connected Roombas,
which are another version of its traditional robot vacuum machine.
And those internet-connected Roombas then needed to go out and
actually use cloud services to leverage the additional resources
that they developed inside of the cloud.
Now this required some authentication and authorization keys to enable that,
but then they were also able to ingest real-time data from robots
that they had in people's homes to the cloud.
Now this allowed them to continually improve on those
robots and build more features into them,
leveraging the cloud connect that they had and that connection to the internet.
Now this is an example of improving the product itself,
so it kind of falls on the other end of the spectrum that we talked about when
it comes to organizational outcomes with revenue growth.
And these two examples of iRobot and Centratech are just a few of
the examples that I've actually pulled from AWS's website to take
a look at how different people are using and leveraging IoT to improve their organizations.