So we're able to deal with a lot of information when we're working with IoT,
but how do we take a look at a lot of that data and actually do
something with it after we've started to collect it?
Well to answer that question, let's take a look at the Rules Engine.
The Rules Engine is a component of AWS IoT that allows
you to filter data from IoT topics, transform the data,
and send it along to other AWS and non-AWS services.
So let's try and visualize the Rules Engine a little bit.
Let's start with a thermometer and let's say this is trying to
publish information to the topic of thermometer/1.
Now let's imagine that every time the temperature is
warmer than 0 degrees Celsius, so above freezing,
we actually don't care too much about the temperature.
So if we have a temperature of 23 degrees Celsius,
it's relatively warm,
and we don't have to worry about things like roads freezing over.
Now let's imagine that we wanted to create something,
in this case an IoT rule,
to actually say when we're finding the temperature below 0,
to get that information so we can act upon it.
So here's how we would do this.
We would create an IoT rule and we'd have a rule query statement,
which essentially is a flavor of SQL that will select information
from the IoT topic that we're interacting with,
and we can also apply conditions to that topic.
In this case, we're going to say where the temperature is less than 0,
so anything underneath the freezing point,
and we want to get all the information that this matches.
So what this will is as we continue to generate information and
maybe the weather starts dropping and dropping,
closer and closer to 0,
until it gets to the winter months and finally becomes underneath 0,
then this means we will start to actually see this data and this
rule will pick up information in this topic.
Now as soon as it does that,
it's going to start selecting this data and then we can act on it.
So what we'll do next is actually set up either one or
more actions to take with this data.
Now we could, for example,
just pass this information along to a database so we had
a record of when things were below 0,
but maybe we wanted to alert different drivers or alert different
vehicles that might be interacting with this temperature.
Now this could help us actually to prevent traffic accidents
or to do something else along those lines.
So this is how the Rules Engine really starts to help us
because it allows us to go in there and whenever we see some
information coming in from an IoT device,
we can take action on that information.
Now these are just two examples of potential actions we could take.
In addition to these two actions,
there's a lot of other actions we can interact with.
There's direct integrations with AWS services that we could use.
There's also direct integrations with non-AWS services.
Integrations with AWS services through existing integrations with AWS services,
so kind of a leapfrog over one service into another one.
And then there's integrations with non-AWS services that we
can use through AWS services as well.
So what are some of the specific integrations that we can use?
Well, one of the first ones is we can send data to a data store,
like Amazon S3 or DynamoDB,
for durable long term storage that we can reference later on.
We can send either files to S3 or entries inside of a DynamoDB table.
We can also send data to Amazon Kinesis.
Now this is going to allow us to actually stream data through
Amazon Kinesis to any destinations we want and also building
custom applications off of Kinesis streams.
We can do things like publishing messages to simple notification
service topics or simple queue service queues.
And we can process those information in fan out scenarios where we
have multiple applications pick them up or we simply queue things up
for some sort of processing down the line.
We can also use Amazon Elasticsearch service to make all the
information that we're processing searchable very easily,
and integrate things with AWS Lambda functions in a way that will allow
us to essentially do anything we want with the data.
Because AWS Lambda allows us to write our own code,
we can basically do anything we can imagine with our own code.
Finally, there's also a built in integration for CloudWatch metrics and alarms,
which will allow us to both aggregate metrics based on the data that's coming
in or trigger alarms if that's the appropriate thing to do.
These are a lot of the direct AWS integrations,
but if you want a full list of integrations,
you can take a look at this link here.
Now in addition to these direct AWS integrations,
we also have other integrations we can use with IoT rules.
One of the first ones is actually a Salesforce IoT input streams.
Now AWS has a strategic partnership with Salesforce that allows them to
work with them and send data directly into Salesforce.
You can also do things like using AWS Lambda to push data to third party APIs.
And this hints at what I was saying before with the flexibility of AWS Lambda,
for you to write your own code and basically do anything you'd like.
In addition to that, you could use Amazon Kinesis Firehose,
which could process data if you needed to,
and then you could send it to any of Kinesis Firehose's destinations.
That could be anything from a storage bucket inside of Amazon S3,
to other locations like Splunk or Elasticsearch.
Again,
either internally inside of AWS services or potentially
externally outside of AWS entirely.
And finally,
you could also do things like loading data into a relational database,
or Amazon Redshift, using S3 or Lambda.
So these other services allowing you a little bit more
flexibility lf where you put that data down the line,
even within the AWS ecosystem.
So hopefully now you feel confident knowing what you could do with the AWS IoT Rules Engine.