Let's go back to our cookbook project. For now, it's still just
a handful of files and a couple of commits.
We haven't created any branches yet, but you probably know
that as soon as you have a Git project, you also have a branch.
Git creates this branch for us when we do our first commit.
Let's look at the list of branches in the project with git
branch like this without any argument.
And there it is, our default branch that in this project is called
main. By now we're used to looking inside the .git directory, so let's
do it again, looking for branches this time.
What's a branch?
This main branch must have some kind of concrete representation in this folder.
What does it look like?
Well,
Git normally puts branches here in a directory called refs and the
subdirectory called heads. Ignore the other subdirectory for now. And
there it is, a small 41‑bytes file called main.
This is our main branch.
What's inside this file?
You could probably guess it, but you don't have to guess.
It's not compressed, so I can just print its content
to the screen. And there you are.
The file contains a single line,
a hash. And as you probably expect, it's the hash of the
current commit, this commit here. To recap,
we have two linked commits in this project, and we also have a main
branch, and the branch is a reference, a pointer to a commit,
essentially. That's why the directory that contains branches is
called refs, references. And note that this main branch actually has
no special status in Git.
Yeah, Git created it for us, but otherwise, it's just a branch like any other.
And in general, we conventionally decided that it's the main
branch of our project, unless we decide otherwise.
And by the way,
that's why I told you earlier on that I think that the name main is
more appropriate than master because this default branch is usually the
main branch of the project by convention,
but it's not really a master of anything. It's just a regular
branch. And just like any other branch, all there is to it is this small file.
I could actually delete or rename the main branch just
by deleting or renaming this file.
If you're willing to live dangerously,
you could even create a new branch just by writing a new file into
this folder containing the hash on a commit. I wouldn't recommend
that kind of hack in a real project, but on a test project, try it
if you wish. It does work.
But in this training, let's stick to the proper way to do it.
Let's create a new branch with git branch and the branch name. About this
branch, we mentioned that we want to insert our recipes in our cookbook,
but we also get ideas for new recipes, and we want to keep them separate
from the official recipes until we try them. We want them in a separate
branch. Let's call it ideas.
So, our plan is that we can put all our established recipes in
main and the new ideas in the ideas branch.
There we are.
We have a new branch.
We can see it listed among the branches, and we can see it alongside the
main in the refs heads folder. And if we look at it,
we see that it has exactly the same content as main, same commit.
So, this is what we have now, two commits, two branches, and the branches are pointing at the same commit.