Hi, everyone, welcome to this chapter.
In this chapter, we are going to talk about JavaScript, regular expressions.
All right, so what are the regular expressions now by the end of this chapter, you will have a solid
understanding of regular expressions.
So by the end of this chapter, you will know what they are, how can they be used and also why they're
useful.
We are not going to die very, very deep into the into this topic.
We are just going to go over the essentials, if you will, the essentials of regular expressions.
OK, so let's start with the definition.
Regular expressions.
They define a search pattern that can be used to look for specific combinations and patterns in size,
strings and numbers or in general inside characters.
So let's say if you have like like a paragraph and you're looking for something, you can like find
it through regular expressions and you can replace it with something else.
You can check if a paragraph contains an email address or if that paragraph contains a phone number,
you can do that with regular expressions as well.
Right.
And you can also validate five forms like the username, the password, like the client side validation.
I'm not talking about the back end validation, not on the client side validation or the front end validation
of forms can also be done through regular expressions.
So what the way that I'm going to go over these regular expressions is we are going to have four lectures
at first, four different lectures, and each of them is going to be like matching part one all the
way to Part four.
Then we are going to discuss two cases.
In the first case, we are going to talk about how we can limit a user name when the user enters inside
a forum element.
I'm going to show you what that is going to be like dynamically in the JavaScript.
But you can apply to a form as well, even though we have like I'm going to show you how you can do
that as well.
And we are going to have another two cases.
So the second case is going to be a password validation kind of thing.
And then we are going to have a matching part five and then we are going to finally the final lecture
is going to be we are going to talk about the replace method.
So in the matching lectures, we are going to have many examples and I'm going to go over them.
And in each example, I'm going to give you like a different taste of regular expressions.
And if you if you want to resource what I know, this is not an exhaustive resource for regular expressions.
But this these are all the essentials that you need to get started with the regular expressions.
This is a text file.
It is inside the folder.
Right.
And by the end of this chapter, you will understand what all these they mean.
So at first I know they might seem like weird or a nonsense or whatever, but we are going to go over
that.
So first things first.
What I what I'm going to do is instead of writing, I'm just going to paste this sentence.
The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog.
Now, this is the sentence inside which all of the English letters, alphabetic alphabets, all of them,
they have been used here.
So this provides a very good use case for us to use regular expressions.
So we have this sentence now.
This sentence is inside the JavaScript.
All right.
And we have this sentence now.
We are looking for something inside this sentence or we want to grab a certain piece of information.
We want to like like extracted from this sentence, if you will, like, in the hacking kind of thing.
So what are you going to do is I'm going to write example, another example.
That is the wrong tree.
Example one.
All right.
So in this example, what I'm going to do is we are going to match a word in a sentence.
So what we are going to do is we are also going to put it right here.
So we are matching a word in a sentence.
Now, this is case sensitive and we are going to use the test method.
So, you know what it is that we are actually doing in here.
So now using this let key word, we are going to create a regular expression that is going to search
for a pattern.
Now with like with any other variable, we need to give this regular expression in name, which is completely
arbitrary.
So I'm just going to say, Regg, one X, because this is example one.
All right, so that's why I've just provided one.
I think we are going to have 28, almost 28 examples.
So here is where the regular expression is, create the way that regular expressions they're created
is.
We just provide two slashes, not set to forward slashes.
And whatever you're right in here is going to be a regular expression.
So what I want to do is I want to look for the word dark inside the sentence.
Right.
And when I grab that word dark, what I want to do is I want to test.
So we are going to use the test method.
The test method is going to return a boolean.
So it is going to be either a false or a true statement.
All right.
And I'm going to store that the result of that search inside another variable.
And I'm going to call it search one result because this is example one.
We're going to have almost 28 examples.
Now, whenever you want to test something, first off, you you provide what it is that you want to
test it, what it is that you want to test.
It is a regular regex, one Regg, one X.
What do we want to test it with?
We want to test it.
Now, this is the test method.
It's a string on which to perform the search.
So what is the string that we want to perform the search on?
It is our sentence.
And at the end, we are just going to go ahead and cancel the search, one result.
So if I say that because there is dog inside the sentence, we get through.
I could zoom in, I could bring this up, I could like no, not not do that, like do this and I can
increase the width of this window soon.
And there we go soon because the word dog exists in this sentence, we get a true.
So that was our very first example.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to comment these right.
And we are going to dive into our second example because we are going to have more than one example
in each a lecture.
So example number two, now you get what these are.
We just provide something and which we tested against this a sentence that we have and we either get
true or false.
Now, before doing this, I should have probably done like this as well.
For example, let's say if we want to test, if we have cat inside this and if I say it, we get a false.
So this is a boolean expression, right?
So in the second example, what it is that we want to do, we are going to match for multiple words.
We are going to search for a pattern of multiple words and we are going to use the or this is the pipe
character.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's create the reject.
So this is why this is right to X, right.
And I'm going to say what I'm what it is that I'm looking for.
So I'm looking for a dog or this is on top of my turkey or a fox or brown.
So if it finds any of these, it is going to return.
True.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy those lines here because it takes a lot of time like
writing them and I'm going to change this one.
To to and I'm going to save it and we get through and let's say we change this combination to blue and
can't we still get through because dog exists.
Now, let's change it to bird, bird, bird.
We get a false because none of these words, they are inside the sentence.
So this was the second example.
Let's dive into the third example.
In the third example, we want to ignore this case sensitiveness.
And here is where I'm going to give you a flag.
So we have flags inside the irregular expressions as well.
So we are ignoring the case sensitiveness using the flag.
We are still using the test method.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create my regular expression projects.
Right, for X.
And the way we can do this is so if I go ahead and if I write quick, like with smaller case and let's
copy these two lines, let's put them right here.
Let's do this because this is this is not regular expression for this number three.
And we should get these three and we should say three so we get a false.
The reason for that is we do have a quick here, but this quick is uppercase and this Q is lowercase.
So outside this regular expression, I'm just going to provide I and then when I say it, it is going
to say so.
It doesn't matter what the casing is, it is going to return.
True, because the case sensitiveness is ignored.
So this was our third example.
Let's dive into the fourth example, all right, so in the fourth example, what I want to do is we
are going to use another method in here, and that method is the match method.
All right.
And now looking at the clock, I can see that it has been ten minutes.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to postpone the second part of I thought we could create it
in one video, but that's OK.
So from example number four, all the way to example number eight, we're going to complete in our next
lecture.
I don't want to feel like rushed like I'm rushing through this course because we are we have covered
so much.
No, no, it's not like that.
The most critical chapters of this entire course, they are yet to come, which are how the JavaScript
works, like the inner workings.
So I don't want to I don't want to, like, sound rushed.
Right.
I don't want to make this course, like, hasty.
I don't want to be hasty, whatever.
You know what I mean?
OK, I'm not like getting the correct word here.
So we are going to postpone the rest of this lecture to the next lecture.
See you guys that.