What is JavaScript now before answering this question?
I would like to say that.
This is going to be our very first lecture of this course, and I do not want to bore you with, like
a lot of theories, so I want you to get started as fast as possible.
So I'm going to keep this lecture short.
And by the end of this course, you will have like a perfect idea of what JavaScript is and you're going
to have a perfect set of skills that are going to allow you to write JavaScript cleanly and efficiently.
Right.
So JavaScript is one of the most popular programming languages of all time.
JavaScript can be used to write and create web applications there they are the kind of websites that
you are interacting on on a daily basis, like Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, YouTube.
Right.
JavaScript is also used to create server side applications.
Another fun application of JavaScript is to develop games, which I've also included in this course,
and they're going to be a lot of projects and you're going to master game development with JavaScript
as well.
JavaScript nowadays has unlimited potential and unlimited applications.
JavaScript can be used to create native mobile applications for Android and iOS.
Another cool application of JavaScript is to code robots to think and to do something.
That's why in some of our games I have included A.I. algorithms.
By the end of this course, you will also be able to write AI algorithms to train and to create an AI
for some of the games that we create in this course.
That is also a cool part of what JavaScript is.
And finally, I just want to say that JavaScript has a lot of applications and it is way beyond the
scope of any one single course to cover all of them.
So what we would like to do, what I would like to do throughout this course, is to give you the necessary
skills to not only create Web applications, but also server side applications, but also create A.I.
algorithms and create APIs from scratch and also the skills to master mobile development as well.
So without further ado, let's start this amazing journey and let's get coding.