Hi, everyone, in this election, we are going to talk about JavaScript daytimes.
All right, so why do we have to talk about the data types in JavaScript?
The reason for that is whenever we interact with any kind of Web page, we are we are actually interacting,
interacting with different data types.
And by data types, I mean, whether we are interacting with a number or we are interacting with a sentence
which is also called or a word which is also called a string in JavaScript, whether we are interacting
with true or false statements, maybe like a button is clicked, a button is not clicked.
OK, true and false.
Maybe like you have a four input where you insert your phone number that is in no data type.
So data is represented by these all of these different components of any website.
Now we are diving deep into JavaScript, so we have to start from data types.
So after that we can go ahead and we can create applications because then we would know that what kind
of data we have and what kind of data our application requires.
If you take out the data part from any application.
Well, actually, there is nothing left because any application is based off that data.
For example, you create, for example, Facebook.
All right.
You have images.
That is a date, OK?
You have text.
Do you have comments like dislikes or like friend requests your timeline?
Everything is represented by a certain data type.
And when you take out the data, there is nothing left to that language.
Right.
So in JavaScript, we have two very we have actually two data types.
And one is like the primitive, primitive types.
And the other one is the reference steps, the primitive type, the in the primitive type, the actual
value is stored.
Whenever we have data, we should store that data.
OK, so storage and data, they go hand in hand.
We also have reference types.
A reference is stored to where that type is in the memory.
Right.
So we are going to dive into these types and if there is any confusion, we are going to remove it.
And if you are new to JavaScript, you're going to learn all about it.
So in the primitive types, we have seven primitive types, which I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to create a common now the multiline comment of a JavaScript and Cyesis, they that resemble
they are the same.
But actually the single line JavaScript comments, there's just two to four to four slashes and that's
it.
So the first primitive type that we are going to talk about is no.
The second one is string.
The third one is Boolean, which is true or false.
The fourth one is undefined, the fifth one is null.
The sixth one is symbol.
The seventh one, which is a new addition to JavaScript, is big and or big integers.
All right.
So so what I'm going to do is first I'm going to show you a presentation inside the console, so I'm
just going to zoom it in a bit more.
So let's go ahead and let's create a number.
So this console inside this console, any foully JavaScript code can run.
That is just a fun fact about the console.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's increase the console a bit so we can work better with it.
So if I go ahead and if I write 15, this is a number and numbers are usually blue or like this represented
like this.
All right, so we have like let's say 154, this is a number we can say ten, ten, ten.
This is a number 20 to only 20.
This is a number we can apply mathematical operations on these numbers.
We can, for example, say 15 plus 15.
We are going to get 30.
If you want to like a very fancy calculator, you can use it like that.
So let's say we have three twenty one multiplied by one, two and three.
We are going to get that.
We are going to say 394, 83, divided by let's go ahead with five and then we are going to divide it
by we can divide it by ten as well.
So you can do simple mathematical operations, arithmetic operations with the console as well.
We can say like 54 minus 13, we are going to get 41.
All right, so this is the first data type that I want you I wanted to talk about, this is the number
data type.
The second one that I want to talk about is the the strength, OK, strength data type is used whenever
we want to write, like, actual characters.
For example, let's go ahead and let's say let's let me write my own name and we are going to get.
All right.
So strengths in JavaScript, they are written inside quotes be a double quotes or single quotes.
You have to be consistent.
So the starting code has to match the ending code.
If it doesn't match, you're going to it is going to throw an error rate invalid or unexpected token
because the starting code does not match the ending.
Quote, of course, we can write more than one word there and we can just say.
All right, and we are going to get that.
All right, in the no data type, we also have another very unique data, another very unique value,
which is in and now in and refers to not a number.
It has a numeric value and is used to show something that is not a number.
For example, if we go ahead and if we say 18 plus and we are going to get not a number, we can also
say 18 multiplied by one and we are going to get another number.
All right.
We are going to say 18 minus in a and again, we are going to get not a number.
And if even if we go ahead and we divide it by and again, we are going to get not a number.
OK, if you go ahead and divide zero by zero, you're going to get not a number.
If you divide one by zero, you're going to get infinity.
Of course, like exactly the mathematical rules.
And if you divide one by infinity.
You're going to get easier.
OK, so that's it for numbers and for strength booleans, they're either true or false.
So we have a true and we have a false.
OK, it's not flies.
It's false.
OK, so this is another data type.
We also have undefined now, undefined and no, they're sort of the same, but they're actually different.
Undefined is the lack of a value when something doesn't have a real value.
For example, if you go ahead and if we say let my name like and then we are going to get undefined.
All right.
Because we have not assigned my name to anything.
So the value of my name is going to be undefined.
But if I go ahead and if I say my name is equal to Muslim, then we are not going to get undefined anymore.
Right.
And we are going to get so what is the value of my name?
We are going to get Muslim.
All right.
So when there is no value, it is undefined, but no null is the purpose for an assignment of a variable
like we are purposefully not assigning something.
OK, so at first, for example, when a user logs in, when no user logs in, we want the like the registration
form to have, for example, reggi form to have nothing inside of it.
So we just go ahead and we do not assign it to anything and we just say no, that's it.
But later on when the user logs in then this no is going to become the name of that user.
Right.
So let me like demonstrated better.
So we are going to say user name, user name.
It is not by default, but when the user signs up, it is going to go ahead.
And if it is going to turn into something, it is going to turn into a string.
And now user name is Musleh.
Right.
So this is the difference between null and undefined.
And finally in this letter, I just want to talk about the symbol and the rest we are going to cover
in the next lecture.
So Symbol is created by calling the symbol global factory function.
We can go ahead and we can say const, for example, let's go ahead and let's create a symbol and we
are going to call the global factory function.
So now we have created a symbol.
Now the cool thing about symbols is No two symbol in JavaScript are the same.
So this symbol.
Is not equal to this symbol.
OK, and it returns a boolean, which says false.
So no two symbols there are the same in JavaScript.
So no string boolean undefined null.
They are commonly used, especially the number of string and boolean undefined.
And no, they, they're not commonly used.
Symbol is is rarely used.
OK, big integer, big into a big integer we are going to talk about in our next lecture's because it's
a bit trickier to work with.
Right.
And if there are any like sort of confusions and uncertainties about this, let's just go ahead and
re watch it and you can go ahead and move on to the next nachas, because these are actually the things
that we are going to work the most with.
When we were actually we are going to work with it all the time when we create applications with JavaScript.
See you guys in the next lecture.