Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, I'm going to introduce you to asynchronous programming.
All right, so asynchronous programming is the backbone of the modern Web development in JavaScript,
and yet JavaScript is single threaded and synchronously execute single threaded, it means that one
command runs at a time.
JavaScript cannot run two commands at the same time and synchronously executed.
It means that each line is run as the plan for the execution is created during the compile time.
So what if we have a challenge?
For example, you open up the Twitter page and for example, you want to get more tweets from the server.
For example, you're scrolling down, or for example, you open a Facebook page or.
Right.
And when you scroll down and when you want to grab when you want to see new posts until the new posts
load, what if you couldn't do anything else?
What if you had to wait for the server to respond to the scroll event and and send you the data?
And until the data is fetched, you had to wait and you couldn't like like write a comment.
You couldn't, like, do a like or anything else that is called synchronous programming.
All right.
Now, let's go ahead and let's talk about, first off, Synchronoss.
What is I'm just going to give you a very, very, very, very simple example of synchronous JavaScript.
And then we are going to dive into two examples of asynchronous JavaScript and what helps JavaScript
achieve this asynchronous state of the modern Web development, because JavaScript is single threaded
and we know for sure that we do have an asynchronous programming like Twitter or like like like you
can see like in most of the websites where whenever you do something with the Web page, the Web page
sends the information or the data, but the page does not reload.
When the page doesn't reload, it means it's asynchronous programming.
And we see that all the time in our Web pages.
Right.
But what helps JavaScript achieve asynchronous programming are going to get to that, but first, what
is Synchronoss code?
What is asynchronous code?
These are going to be very, very simple examples, but they're going to convey the point of what is
synchronous and what is asynchronous.
Let's say we have a function and this function is going to say just hello.
And I'm going to say cancel that log.
Just say hello.
All right.
And then I'm going to come down here and I'm going to call this function.
Hello.
OK, but I'm not.
Hello, I'm not going to save it, so I'm going to come down here and I'm going to do another concer
lock.
And I'm going to say hello again.
Now, if I save it, you would see that the first executable line of code in the VMS is going to be
this.
And this is going to call this function and the function.
Just basically print hello to the console.
And then the next executable line of code is this console lock.
And then we can see that hello again is going to be printed.
So first off, we are going to say hello and then we are going to say hello again.
So if I were to say it, we can see that.
So this is an example of a this is an example of synchronous code.
And what does it mean?
It means that for the console log line to run, we needed to wait, that this function is executed until
this function is called in here.
And then the parentheses, they execute this function until this execution is done.
We should not see any hello again.
And after this line is done, then we see hello again.
This is an example of Synchronoss code.
I know we we have done a lot of this, but we have not talked about it in the context of asynchronous
programming.
Now we are talking about it in this context.
All right.
So what if I just go ahead and copy this code uncommented out and I pasted down below and I grab the
synchronous JS and I paste it because asynchronous is very, very difficult for me to write and they
just say asynchronous JS.
But instead of instead of calling the function very normal right here, I'm just going to delete it
and I'm going to create a set time out and in here I'm going to pass and the function call and I'm just
going to say hello and then the second.
So the first argument is going to be the time handler handler.
And the second thing argument is timeout.
No one has time and no, let's put it to 1000 milliseconds or one second.
So if I were to save it, what we should see on the console, let me clear that up so we should see
the first stuff we because this is the first executable line of code.
Right.
So we should see that.
We should wait for one second.
And after one second passes, we should see that this Halo function is run, right?
So this Halo function is right.
And what is this going to do?
It is going to print hello to the console.
And after it frenzied, then we should see hello again, because JavaScript can do one thing at a time
and that one thing at a time.
Firstly, it is going to be calculating that one 1000 milliseconds.
So it counts one millisecond to millisecond, 100 millisecond, 900, 999 hundred and ninety nine nine
and then 1000 yay, 1000 milliseconds.
That is up then because it is counting this, right.
It is counting it so it can do anything else.
So logically this should happen that when when the 1000 milliseconds is over.
This Halloween is going to run dysfunction, dysfunction is going to be invoked, and what is the function
going to do is just print and then we should see again, hell.
So let's save it and let's see what we get.
But that is not that is not what we get, because this is asynchronous programming, because said time
out is actually an asynchronous method provided to JavaScript by the browser.
Now browser, these web browsers like the Chrome Safari, Firefox macros are like i.e. they are very,
very, very, very powerful.
Now, in this chapter, we are going to dive into their power browsers.
They provide us with a set of Web APIs.
We have used some of these APIs.
We are going to take a deeper look at the Web APIs.
I think it's let me take a look at it's the lecture after the next lecture and the next lecture, we're
going to talk about the call stack specifically at what JavaScript does at the runtime.
We know what it does at the execution sorry, at the compile time.
But what it actually does at the runtime, we are going to take a visual representation of that, which
is really cool, which is again provided to us by the browser.
So browsers, they're really, really powerful.
When JavaScript is not enough, the browsers they take over and they provide us with web browser APIs
with no background APIs and promises.
And a lot of the API, all of these APIs, they're provided to us by the browser.
This is not Java, this is not JavaScript, this is browser.
So what is happening here is whenever a JavaScript sees this set time out, it is going to hand it over
to the browser.
The JavaScript is going to say to the browser that take this and remind me after 1000 milliseconds that
I have to invoke this function.
And you do this, the browser, a browser, do this graph the set time out and count from one millisecond
up to 1000.
In the meantime, I'm going to execute the next line of code.
So what does this mean?
It means that until the server is going to be sending you the data, that is going to be handled by
the browser.
So the browser comes to the rescue of JavaScript, OK?
And so JavaScript can do other things right.
Until the browser can get this data, can fetch the data.
JavaScript is going to allow you to click to write a comment, to display an image until the images
or until the posts are fetched from the server.
All right.
So that's so there are actually two people working.
The first one is JavaScript.
The second one is the browser.
How is the browser working?
The browsers work is in the form of APIs application application programming interface, which we are
going to talk about later.
Right.
So that's actually how it works.
Just to recap, JavaScript is going to give this time out because it's a browser API, it's a timer,
it is going to hand it over to the browser, say, OK, this is your responsibility.
You got to count from one to 1000 millisecond.
And after your count is over, just to remind me that I have to invoke a function, I don't want to
think about it.
And the JavaScript is going to run this.
And after 1000 milliseconds, the browser API is going to say, OK, here we go, 1000 milliseconds
have passed, go and invoke this function and this function is invoked.
Now, you might be asking, what if I'm just going to copy it down below?
What if I go ahead and come in this one out?
You might be asking.
OK, so this is 1000 milliseconds.
What if we put it to zero?
What would happen then?
So I'm going to tell you what would happen that even though it is zero milliseconds, but this time
out is still going to be is still going to take some time to be handed over to the browser API.
This is actually the browser API.
So until the browser API starts working, JavaScript is going to move on to this.
So JavaScript doesn't care how many, how many milliseconds or how many seconds are in here.
JavaScript is just going to hand this over to the browser and JavaScript is going to move on.
It doesn't matter even if it has zero milliseconds.
So if I run this code, we are going to see the same representation once more.
See, even if we are going to get hello again first, because even if it is zero milliseconds, it is
handed over to the browser.
We are not interested in this part, we are interested in the set time out itself, it has handed over
JavaScript, moves on and runs this line of code first, and then the set time out is going to be reminded
by the browser that, OK, there was only like zero milliseconds and I counted them.
And here we go.
And JavaScript is going to invoke this function.
So this is how actually asynchronous a code is going to run.
And in this chapter, we are going to talk about all of the older technologies, the callbacks, and
then the newer standards, the promises and the API and also the hot topic, which is async 08.
So see you guys in the next lecture.