Hi, everyone, in this lecture, I'm going to introduce you to Estima five Canvas.
All right, so now we have already talked about the team of five, Kanavis, before, maybe like a couple
of times, and especially when we created that drawing gap.
Right.
But the purpose of this chapter is to reintroduce you to Estima five canvas.
What are the methods, how you can draw basic rectangles or squares, how you can draw arcs, how you
can draw lines, and ultimately how you can draw circles.
Right.
And that is basically the entire premise of this chapter.
And there are going to be like there aren't going to be a lot of lectures because we need to do something
practical.
Right.
I don't want to dive into theory too much.
That's why we after we are done with this chapter, we are immediately going to start working with our
projects, which are related to game development with each team of canvas in JavaScript right now before
actually recreating actual games, we are going to have a set of basics basic to intermediate projects
that are going to be several of them.
I'm not sure how many because I'm still in the process of creating those projects, but as many as they
are, they will be preliminary skills for you to master how game development works.
And they are categorized in projects as well because they are projects and but they are lower level
projects than like actual games that we have.
They will allow you to acquire the necessary skills to create awesome games.
Right.
So starting with this lecture, what we are going to do in this lecture is I'm just going to go over
how we can initiate a canvas.
Right.
And how we can select it in JavaScript, how we can give it a height.
And with and how basically we can draw a rectangle, rectangle or square.
Doesn't matter.
Both of them are like the formula or the method for both of them is the same.
That's why I'm just saying, like, it doesn't matter.
Right.
So here we have a basic boilerplate, for example, and our JavaScript file is empty.
We will be working mainly with two files.
One is e-mail, the other one is G.S..
Right.
And in here, first stuff, I'm just going to provide a comment here that is going to say JS file.
And I'm going to script with the source of one G.S..
Right.
And above the title, I'm going to create a style element and this style element is internal access.
So whatever I write inside here is going to be these tiles for this entire Web page.
Now, the elements that we are we will be having here is simple.
We we are just going to have an HTML, just have a canvas element that said so in the EMR body, we
just have our canvas element and then we have linked our JavaScript inside the style.
So let's save it.
Let's open it up.
And here we go, so you can see that there is nothing here, right and right, what is this should be
Fabrica.
Not to Reynolds.
Yeah, it is Phalcon, so if you reloaded, you're not going to see it, that you're going to see it
at first, but then it's going to go away.
So this is going to be our canvas right now.
This is not the canvas.
This is the viewport.
Where is our canvas now before diving into actually drawing our canvas?
Right.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go over some basic styling.
So by default, the Web pages they have and the elements to have some padding, some margin.
And I just want the box sizing to be box.
Now I want to grab the body and I want to say that the mean height of the body should be 100.
And it means that it is going to be 100 viewport height.
It's going to grab all the height available to it.
And we are going to say display flex.
The reason that I'm using using this flex is I want to work and I want our canvas to be self center,
vertical and horizontal.
So for a vertical alignment, we just sell line items for horizontal alignment.
We say justify content and let's set it to center.
Now let's grab our canvas by the elements.
I'm not going to give it to either class or an ID.
We are just going to use the arm and solitaries because we usually have only one canvas.
So I'm going to give it a background color.
It's going to be 40 for one, two, six, six, and I'm going to give it a border as well, so it's
going to be two pixels solid and najiba off 193 oh and 252.
That's why I used to provide all the styling for all the projects, because, like riding all these
styles, it's very time consuming.
And it it takes away from the major point that we are we want to do here.
So basically, this is our canvas and you can see that these dimensions, they have been applied by
default.
So if I come here.
So this is our canvas element.
Right.
And this canvas element sprung this over here.
These are the styles that we have applied.
But what are the default styles?
If I come to W, we should see something.
Right.
So whereas with.
OK, zoom with so you can see that the with by default is three or four and if I inspect it here, it
doesn't show it to me.
All right.
So you can see that the width is three or four and the height is 154.
Right.
So if I go to H.
Height 154, for now, all the styling that you can see here, which are not highlighted, the ones
that are highlighted, they are applied by the browser, but there are some of those stars.
So if I bring this up, these are all the browsers, as some of them have been applied by us, like
this border top, like this background, background style.
But these are these have been applied by us.
These all of these borders have been applied by us, this box sizing.
But you can see that this display and this height, they are a bit like you could say, they are not
highlighted like this.
They're a bit faded out.
So they are the browser styles, if you want to see all of them.
These are all the browsers stars except for the ones which are highlighted.
Right.
So let's bring it down and now what I'm going to do is I'm going to jump into JavaScript and first things
first in order to interact with any external element you need to select.
And I'm going to call this variable canvas element.
Now, this canvas element is actually this canvas element that we have it right here.
So I'm going to say document to query selector.
I'm going to select it using its element selector name.
Right.
We do not need that.
Now, whenever you create the canvas, you need to get a context.
The context allows us to use all the methods to draw shapes on the canvas, to animate shapes on the
canvas.
Right.
So whenever you say and the context, I'm just going to call it canvas context.
You might see this as this canvas context.
Some people you see or I don't know like the context word itself, but I'm going to use canvas contexts
so it's clear.
And then we are going to grab our canvas element and we are going to say get context.
So here it is.
And you can see that there is all the information about the get context in here.
OK, a context object includes information about colors, line widths, fonts and other graphic parameters
that can be drawn on a canvas.
So this is the the base method that we are going to get now, a 2D canvas.
So before doing that, so open this.
Now you can see that the identifier idea of the type of canvas to create and now let's fast forward.
Right.
So it just says that I think is the IEEE doesn't support it.
There is nothing here.
So I'm just going to use a 2D context because we are not working with 3D.
We are just working with two dimensions height and with we are going to say 2D.
Now, what are we going to do here is I'm going to give the canvas a height.
So I'm just going to say canvas height.
Canvas has a property of height and I can set it to 600 and I'm going to grab the canvas element and
I'm going to say that with and I'm going to set it to 800.
And when I save it and if I come here now, you can see that the canvas has a height of 600 and a width
of 800.
Now, how can you draw on the canvas now in order to draw anything on the canvas, you need to call
the canvas context because the canvas context is the variable.
There are all these properties and methods are available for.
So if you want to draw a rectangle.
So if I want to draw a rectangle, we are just going to say fill erect.
Right.
So this one, if I want to change the color, the background color of that rectangle, I'm going to
say fill style.
All right.
If you want to draw a circle.
So where is ARC?
This that first one that we have now, this arc, it creates half a circle, which is ARC or also it
creates a perfect circle as well.
Right.
So all these methods that we need to animate or to we need to create games is all of them are available
on the canvas context.
So first things first.
I'm just going to grab our first tile and I'm going to set it to white.
So the background color of our rectangles, be them rectangles, are squares we are going to get to.
That is going to be white.
Right.
And I'm going to say canvas context.
Dot fell RACT.
And now here there are going to be four numbers you can see.
So the first one is going to be the horizontal position.
This is going to be the vertical position, the skin to be the width, and this is going to be the height.
So aside from the horizontal and vertical positions, if the width and the height are the same, then
we end up with the square, right.
If the width and the height are different, then we end up with a rectangle.
So I want it to be, for example, 100 pixels from the air in the extraction, 200 pixels in the Y direction.
The width should be 50.
The height should also be 50.
And if I save it and if I come here now, you can see we have one one square.
This is square because the height and with are the same.
Now it is 100 percent from the left and 200 pixels from the top.
In this matter we can create as many as we want.
So if you want to create another rectangle and change the color, you first of get the context and NFL
style.
And now let's let's try and RGV value and I'm going to say a najiba, actually.
So I'm going to say two one four two hundred one sixty seven and point five.
Now I'm just going to grab that and I'm going to put it down here.
And now we should have two.
Fill a rectangle.
OK, they are on top of each other, so I'm just going to provide it 100 here.
So now we can see.
So this is our second square.
In this manner, you can't create as many squares as you want.
For example, what I'm going to do is I'm going to start creating squares in different locations.
So the first one is going to be 50 X, 50 Y, then we are going to have 100 X hundred Y, then 150.
Hundred and fifty x, I'm going to give it hundred and fifty four Y, then I'm going to I'm going to
change both them accordingly.
So 200 I should do control D, right.
200.
So 250.
Oops.
300.
350.
400.
For 50.
500 and finally, I'm just going to do 550 and I'm going to make our canvas 600 by 600.
And when I save it, you can see that we get this.
So now you can see that the first one is 50 and 50 X and Y.
The second one is 100 X and 100 Y, 150, 150, 200, 200 and so on and so forth.
So this is how you saw in this lecture?
We created a canvas.
We created squares or rectangles.
It doesn't matter if you just change one of the dimensions to be different than the other one, then
you're going to end up with this.
So you can see that this one the second one is not a square, it's a rectangle.
So you know how this is created.
And that's it for this lecture.
It turned out to be longer than I expected it to be, but we started canvas.
I want it to be geared towards beginners that who have never who have never touched canvas before because
we are I'm going to take you from here and I'm going to create amazing games with you.
OK, I'm going to show you how you can create astounding games, OK, with with these these basic,
simple things, because these are the building blocks of game development in JavaScript.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.