Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to go over the difference between function expression's
and function declarations.
All right, so we know that there are a lot of syntactical differences, but the difference that I want
to point out is based on their scope, which scope these functions belong to and which scope do they
create.
All right.
So on line one, we have a function declaration that has a name of my movie rating and we have canceled
it right here.
We have just called the function.
We have not executed the function.
All right.
So online three, we have a function expression.
The variable name is your movie rating.
However, this function expression is not an anonymous function expression.
This is in named a so-called named function expression.
Right.
And this is the job of this is just this council logs another rating.
We just call it.
We don't run it.
We don't execute the function.
And finally, we have our three consulates.
So the first council log, this refers to this function.
The second one is actually the council lugging this variable that has it, that is pointing to a function.
Right.
And finally, we are going to cancel this another another rating, which is this function.
So before actually saving this and showing you the results here, I'm going to go over the theory.
So in theory, function declarations such as this one, they create or they they add their names or
a slash identifier.
This is the name of the function they added to their inclosing scope.
What do I mean by that?
So if the function declaration is inside the global scope, the identifier of that function declaration
will also be accessible inside the global scope.
Right.
But if the function declaration is inside another function declaration, then the identifier, as is
going to be like a nested scope, which we talked about in the previous chapter, which can only be
accessed within the parent scope.
Right.
And what do we have here is next up.
We have the function, expression and function expressions.
They add their name or identifier to their own scope.
So the name of this function expression can only be accessed within the scope of this function.
So whenever you create a function expression, so this is a preference how you want to code.
OK, this is like the code coding styles.
Everybody has a different coding style.
So it is a recommendation that whenever you create a function expression, do always name that function
expression because you can clearly access the name of this function expression, OK, you cannot access
it inside the global scope.
It means that there is not going to be any naming collision down the road.
OK, so there is not going to be anything like that and it is accessible, you know what the name of
the function is and you know how you can access it.
All right.
So if we were to go ahead and to save this code, we should be able to see this function, this function
and this variables assignment expression.
But we should see an error as far as this another rating is concerned.
So if I say it, we can see that we see our function.
So how does this actually work?
This is a function.
This is a declaration.
And whenever we declare functions, they are they are compiled away.
They are like done in in the compilation stage.
So there is nothing in the execution stage.
So there is nothing in the compilation stage because they are done and nothing in the execution stage
because they are done.
They have been compiled away.
And this is a function expression.
This is different because we have a var, we have a a variable declaration here.
Again, we have initialized to this value.
So the execution engine is going to come to line number three and in here it is going to grab this var
your your movie rating and it can see that it is a target reference to which this, this is apply.
But, but again, because this is pointing to a function, we need to grab that function.
So we grabbed the name of this variable and we put it inside this console.
Luxo this var is going to immediately come to line number eight and it is going to run this, but before
that because we are on the line one.
We have our function and of course, we are going to talk about hoisting in our next chapter, but basically
what that is, is or this lexical scope, how it works is the functions function declarations that are
executed first and then function expressions.
They are executed.
Right.
And so that's why we can see our my movie rating first and then we can see that your movie rating and
whenever we access the another rating, which is this function, we cannot get it.
And it says a reference or another rating is not defined.
So we cannot get a reference to that.
We cannot get the reference.
So what is this another rating?
We don't know what that is.
Then how can we how can we log it to the console?
So just to recap the difference between function declarations in this code, perspective with the function
expression is that function declarations, they add their identifier or their name to the inclosing
scope, a.k.a. in the scope in which their present and function, the expressions they add their identifier
to their own scope.
You might not have seen this very much.
You might see like you might have seen like a function expression, like a variable declaration on one
side and on the other side, you might have seen a lot like an anonymous function.
So that works as well as I told you guys that this is like a preference.
You whenever you get to coding you, you are bound to create styles and methods for yourself and you
will know which way works better for you.
There is this is not a good thing.
This is not a bad thing.
This is just simply a matter of preference.
Right.
Some people love function expressions.
Some people love function declarations.
Some people love aira functions a lot.
They do all of their stuff with error functions.
Some people love name and function expressions.
It depends on which.
It doesn't matter actually which route you take or either you combine all of them together as long as
you know how they work, how they how the scoping works, how this lexical scoping of JavaScript works.
As long as you know that you should be good to go.
This this is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.