Hi, everyone, in this chapter, we will be creating a tic tac toe game.
All right, so what is this game that we will be building, building here, if you're not familiar with
this, we have nine boxes here, right?
So we have a board that is three by three.
Right.
And in this board, there are going to be two players, each of the players that completes three of
their, for example, symbols in a row, B, that horizontally, vertically or diagonally, they will
get they will win.
All right.
So we are going to have OS and access for this game.
Right.
And so let's go ahead and let's actually play this.
So the way it is going to be played is now this is a multiplayer game.
So it is there is not going to be any I'm just going to be two players playing.
So, for example, if you click, you're going to land in.
Oh, for example.
Now, the first player is the OAP and then the X player is going to put one there.
For example, the O puts a symbol here and then the Xbox One there.
And then whoever completes three in a row as this is going to say, wins and directly right after one
second it is going to reload.
You can't risk, for example, in the middle of playing, you can restart it through this button as
well.
And it is going to work.
It doesn't matter in which direction it is.
So I'm just going to place them, for example, diagonally.
Then you can say, oh, wins, it could be vertically, vertically or horizontally.
So let's put one vertically.
Sort of horizontally, and you can see that it's going to reload the game after exactly one second after
the results are shown, then it is going to reload the game.
Right.
So it's very, very simple.
And let's get to it.