Hi, everyone, in this lecture we are going to talk about for Lupe's.
All right, so what are loops, loops, repeat code while reducing the number of lines of code?
So if you want to.
I repeat an action or a logic multiple times, instead of riding it many times, we just go ahead and
insert that within a loop.
All right.
So the first kind of loop that we are going to talk about is going to be for loops.
And the the way that for loops are created is we have three steps.
First, a variable is defined, which is called a starting point.
Then the ending point is defined.
Then how much the variable is incremented is actually declared or defined.
Right.
So this is the syntax for a for loop we have for exactly like if well basically the syntax for for loops
and for F statements is the same except for this for an F word.
So we have an initial expression, then we have our semicolon, then we have our condition.
Right.
Which is the ending point.
Then we have our increment increment expression.
Right.
Which is the how much variable is it incrementing then inside the curly braces, we want to run the
code that we want to run.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's see in action how we can use the for loops, loop her advantage.
So I'm going to be giving you multiple examples and I'm going to be naming them.
So this is example one in the example one.
We first go ahead and create the syntax for a for loop and then now that's provided with the initial
expression.
So the initial expression, we just say that a B equal to one.
Now, the variable name, it's you could provide it A, B, C, D, usually it's the common convention
is I and you could also call it J, K, whatever you want.
It doesn't really matter what you want to provide it with.
As long as you stay consistent, then it doesn't matter.
And we say we want the now this is the condition part.
OK, we want the to go all the way to less than or equal to five.
OK, and how do how do we want to increment a we want to do we want incremented by one by two like they
should be one then they should be two then they should be three.
Or do we want the eight to be first one and then three and then five.
How do we want to increment a we want to increment a one by one.
So eight plus plus means that A is being incremented by one.
Now when this, when this loop runs, what do we want to implement?
What is the code that we want to implement?
All right.
We want to present to the console.
I am a for loop.
We just want to point to the council, I am falling and every guy's going to say, well, now this is
the thing with the console.
It has said that it has printed it five times, but there is only one time.
But it is in here.
It says, fine, you guys can see this is five, which means that this has been repeated five times.
We can check that for ourselves, of course, always.
And to be able to do that, we just print the variable as well.
And then we can see I am for loop one, two, three, four and five.
And the way that this loops were, this loop works is like this.
The the a variable is going to grab the value of one first and it is going to put it all the way here.
So in our first iteration, I am a for loop will be one in the second iteration and in the second iteration
the value is one, OK, and one is either less than or equal to five.
And this condition is met and when the condition is met, the value is going to be incremented by one
and now the value is to the value.
Two is going to be put here and then it is going to be logged in here.
And now we have a value to we check the condition is two less than or equal to five.
Yes, this condition is true.
Then we increment the value.
All right.
So when we increase the value, value is going to be three.
And then we get this line.
When the value is three, we again do this condition.
We check that value against the condition and the condition holds true.
When the condition holds true, we add another one to that.
We increment that for sorry, that three by one and three plus one is going to be four and four is going
to come right in here.
And after that, this line is going to print.
And next time we have a number for as a value for a and we check it against this condition.
Right.
And the condition holds true.
For is less than five.
Right.
And then we increment the four by one, which is five.
And then we get this line.
All right.
So five, we check it against the condition.
Five is less.
Five is equal to is either five is now less than five.
Right.
But five is equal to five.
And we increment it by one.
But now when we increment it by one, we get a we get a number six and six is not does not hold true
against this condition.
So when it doesn't hold true against this condition, the loop is not going to run anymore.
And then we end up with this.
OK, so this is how this loop actually works.
This was our first example.
We are going to dive into our second example.
And in here, what I want to do is I want to get the even numbers.
OK, get the even numbers from zero to 19.
Let's get the even numbers.
How would you get the even numbers from zero to 19?
So we are going to create a for loop and we are going to say let a now this time, let's put it to be
the be.
It should start from zero.
We want it to start from zero and we want the B to go all the way to less than or equal to nineteen
and we want to increment B, but this time we do not want incremented by one because we want to get
the even numbers.
That's why we are going to incremented, we are going to increment it by two.
All right.
And in case you're wondering what the syntax is, this syntax is also actually present here.
So if you go ahead and should I put it here?
So if you put a equal plus equals sign one one.
This syntax is is the same as a plus plus.
All right.
So we have used this syntax here as well.
But I'm using the syntax here as this kind of syntax here because it makes more sense.
And now what do we want to do?
We want to consult, log our variable of the let's save it.
And now we get all the even numbers from zero to 19.
So you give zero two four six, eight, 10, 12, 14, 16 and 18.
And in case you say, okay, two is zero is not an even number, we could just say start from two and
we get this.
So this is getting the even numbers from zero to 20.
We can get the I'm just going to copy this.
I'm going to put it here.
We can get the odd numbers from zero to 20.
We can change it.
Example three, Chenda, the odd numbers.
And for that, what we are going to do is we say that the variable should start from one and it should
go all the way to less than 19.
We don't want it to be equal to 90, but to less than 90.
And we are going to add the same condition there.
And now when we added, we say one three five seven all the way to 17.
These are all the odd numbers if you're provided with everything equal.
So you're going to get the nineteen as well.
So this is get get the odd numbers from zero to 90.
We can also get every third number from zero to 90.
We can also do that as well.
Let me copy the example, put it here and get every third number right from zero to 19.
We can do that as well.
And for that, we are going to create a for loop.
We are going to say.
Let me.
Let this time let's go ahead and let's use a common convention.
We want to start we want to start from zero and the eye, OK, this is not Colan, these are these are
semicolons.
I'm just going to zoom in for this as well so you guys can see we have I semicolon because in our first
in our first lines, we just sit and it's an initial expression, colon condition, colon and then increment
of expression, OK?
So this is how this works and where do we want it to go?
What is the ending point?
The ending point is all the way to less than 19.
How do we want incremented this time?
We want to incremented by every third number.
So we are going to incremented by three.
All right.
And we are going to bring to the console.
I and when I say that we got zero three six nine, 12, 15 and 18, we get every third no.
Right.
If he starts from one, we get one four, seven, 10, 13, 16.
Doesn't really matter.
And he put equal sign here.
We get every third.
No.
All right.
And at the end of this lecture, I just want to give you another example and this example.
Well, I'm not going to actually run this code because my computer is not that, like, super fast or
super capable.
So if I run this, this is how you can create infinite loops when the condition is always true.
So we say start from 10 and go as long as the variable is larger than zero.
So if we go larger than zero, we get infinity number of numbers.
And this condition is always going to be true and it is going to crash my computer.
But if your PC is stronger and faster, is not going to be is not going to crash it.
This is just an example of infinite loops where the condition is always going to be true.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.