Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about closure.
All right, so what is closure and why do we need to talk about it now, the idea of closure predates
computer science itself.
It actually came to us from Lambda Calculus.
Now, to be able to understand closure, we need a firm understanding of the lexical scope.
And as of now, we do have that firm understanding.
Now let's dive into a proper definition of closure that makes sense in the context of jobs.
Now, what is closure?
Closure is when a function is able to remember and access its lexical scope.
All right.
Even when that function executes in a different scope.
Now what?
What do I mean by that?
So let's go over an example right now.
Let's say we have a function.
The function is called book.
The Identifier for the function is book.
And I just passed it in name parameter.
And what does this function is going to?
This function is going to implement a set time out.
And in here I'm going to create another function and I'm going to call it, let's say, other book.
OK, and I'm not going to pass in any parameter, what I'm going to pass is so that said, the time
out to 500 milliseconds, why are we going to passan is a console lock, right?
And I'm going to say no.
So now keep in mind that this console log is actually inside this function, right?
So it's inside this function.
Now, the idea of closure states that if the function other book can access the this name parameter
from the from its parent to all the way to hear and execute it to the console, then it would mean that
this is closure and closure actually exists.
So let's go ahead and let's call the outer function.
And I'm just going to say the two towers.
And when I save it, we can see that we get the two towers here.
Right.
There was a little lag because that was half a second had to pass for this console log to work.
That that's why we did.
We saw like a little bit of lag there right now.
What happens in here is this function, this book function has just completed.
And after it runs, even though the book function is executed, is compiled away, then this other book
function runs.
So typically, we shouldn't have access to this name for a while because it has already completed,
but because closure preserved it.
We do have access to that name variable right now.
You have to keep in mind that JavaScript engines essentially implement closure as a linkage to the entire
scope, not on a per variable basis.
So it is best to assume that closure, even though academically it's per variable, it is best to assume
closure is a skill based operation.
And it is not something you have to do special with a function other than you just have to access a
variable outside and then you have to pass the function somewhere.
That's all you have to do to observe the idea that closure exists.
Think about what it would be like if you had a function that didn't have closure.
Like if you are in a language that had first class functions such as JavaScript and lexical scope,
again, such as JavaScript, but didn't have closure, you'd pass this function somewhere else.
And all of the sudden.
It would forget all about its variables if you have a lexical if you have lexical scope on first class
functions, you're going to have you're going to have to have closure because it wouldn't make sense.
Not right.
So let's go over another example as well.
And this is going to be the last example in this lecture.
Come on, buddy.
Example number two.
So what are we to do in this example as I'm going to create a function called Aske?
So let's say ask and I'm going to pass in a question as a parameter and this function is going to return
another function.
That is going to be other question.
I'm not going to pass in any parameter in here.
I'm just going to say Kansa log.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to access the question, the question variable parameter from
here.
Right.
So what this is going to do is whenever I call this aske function.
All right.
And Passan an argument, so let's call it let's pass in an argument.
This argument is going to get passed inside this parameter instead of this parameter, and then it is
going to be passed in here.
If this this process is completed, the way that I explained it, then it would mean that we do have
closure in JavaScript.
Right.
So let's go ahead on the story inside another variable.
My question.
Right.
And that's call my question.
My question.
And when I say it, we can see that we get really first and then we get the two towers.
The reason that this happens is because time out, that is actually an asynchronous method.
But I don't want to talk about it here.
We are going to cover asynchronous programming after we are done with the object oriented programming.
OK, so I don't want to talk about it.
I don't want to dive into why this really came first and then the two towers.
But what what what I do want to talk about is this scope, this function.
Other question.
It has access to the variable question which comes from this parameter and the value for it passed into
this function call as an argument.
So even though this asked question, it has compiled data, it has run, it is done, it is completed.
We still have access to this question.
All right.
The reason for that is because JavaScript has closure and closure that preserves this question variable
so we can access it.
Right.
So this is going to be at for this lecture.
And I'm sure that you understood closure.
Here is the link to Emdin Page.
You can go ahead and read more about it and like dive into more advanced examples there.
So there is going to be one more lecture in this chapter.
And I just want to talk about what closing over variables mean.
Right.
So see you guys in the next lecture.