Hi, everyone, in this picture, we are going to talk about comparison operators in JavaScript.
All right, so we are going to start our way through the greater greater than comparison operator,
right.
And the results of these operators is going to be a boolean expression, right.
So the way that I'm going to I'm going to going to be showing you guys how these operators work is directly
printing them to the console or logging them to the console.
So let's go ahead and let's see if two is greater than one.
We get it true.
So this is greater than one.
All right.
These are super simple.
So the next one is the less than comparison operator.
Right.
And for that, I'm going to say console the log.
Let's go ahead and let's check it out.
If one is I don't know, like let's see if two is less than one, we get a false it is two is not less
than one.
So we get a boolean, which is false.
The next one is greater than or equal to.
So it's greater.
Than or equal to right, and the way it works is I'm just going to copy it and put it here and we are
going to say if 15 is greater than or equal to 15, we get it true.
Right.
So let's check out another condition.
Let's check it out.
At 16, we get a false because 15 is not equal, neither equal nor greater than 16.
So we get a false right.
So this is the greater than or equal to comparison.
Operator.
The next one that I want to talk about is less than or equal to.
All right.
So these are very, very, very simple.
That's why I'm just copying them down below, because they're super simple, right?
So for the first one, we get it through and for the second one, we also get it.
And the reason for that is because 15 is actually equal to 15 and what it is equal to 15, the operator
actually ignores this lesson than sign.
And you might say, OK, 15 is not less than 50, but it is actually equal to 15.
And the second expression is true because 15 is either equal to 16 or less than 16.
So it is not equal to 16.
And this equality sign is not evaluates to true.
So this less than sign is evaluated to true.
So these are less than or equal to comparison operators.
Now, these are not that like that much exciting and that much like they are important, very, very
important JavaScript, but not as important as the rest of comparison operators that we are going to
discuss.
So the first very, very important one is the double equal equality operator.
Equality operator, OK, it only cares now this operator only cares about the value, not the time,
and doesn't care about the type, it enforces the type to make them the same time.
It causes the type also also called type coersion in JavaScript.
So if we go ahead and if we say cancel the log now, let's take a look at this operator and how it works
and let's go ahead and let's say one equal to one.
We should get it through because one is equal to one.
OK, how about this?
How about one equal to the strength one?
We get a true but this is not actually true because this is a number.
But this part this is not a number.
This is a string.
And because numbers and strength, they have different types.
The quality operator does not care about those types.
As long as the value is the same, it is going to coerce the type.
OK, this is called type coercion in JavaScript.
OK, so let's go ahead and let's take a look at more examples.
This let's say we have a Z word here and this is Z.
It is going to be true, of course.
OK, so let's go ahead and let's see if true is equal to true.
We should get it true.
OK, we did get a true let's say a false is going to be equal to true.
We get a false because in this case, even though the type is the same, this is a boolean, this is
a bully, but the value is different.
This is false and this is true.
And I'm just going to go ahead and give you some more examples, because I I think that this is really
important to understand.
So we are going to say if zero is equal to an empty string and it is true because zero is empty and
empty string is empty.
OK.
And let's go ahead and let's check out if
undefined is equal to now, because both of them have actually the same concept, but the type is different.
That's why it but because this is called the operator doesn't care about the type.
It just makes him like it just causes the type.
So we get it through right here.
OK, so let's go ahead and let's take a look at another one.
Consider log false and zero.
We get it through.
And let's go ahead and let's take a look at two and one.
We should get it through as well.
So this is so this is how this equality, the double equal equality operator works.
I'm just going to comment about everything.
And the next operator that I want to talk about is the strict equality operator.
And it has three equal sides are equality.
Operator and why you should always use the strict equality operator, because this extra this extra
quality, if it also checks, it also checks for the tie that we are comparing.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy all of them and I'm going to put them here.
I'm going to grab these double equals and I'm going to control the everywhere and I'm going to turn
them to triple equals.
And now we are going to take a look at them one by one.
So we get it through because one is the same as one in type and in value.
But this is the this is the cool part one.
The number one is not equal to the string on one, even though the value is the same, but the type
is different.
This is a string.
This is a number.
All right.
Let's take a look at this.
It is true because both of them have the same value and the same type.
This should bring back two as well.
This is false because false is not equal to true.
All right.
Shocker.
This is false because zero this is a number.
This is a strength.
Right.
And this should be false as well, because undefined, the type of undefined is different than the type
of null.
And these two should be false as well.
So this is the difference between these strict equality operator and the usual equality operator and
why you should always use this, because we want to make sure that the type and the value they are equal.
The other two year comparison operators that I want to talk about here, they're actually different
versions of these operators that we have talked about here.
They're actually different versions of them.
And we are going to talk about them in our next lecture.
So see you guys in the next lecture.