Hi, everyone, in this chapter, we are going to implement smooth scrolling for any website.
All right, so what is smooth scrolling?
All right.
So I just want to mention that if you are a student of my flex box, great SATs and advanced developers,
advanced animations developer of course, then in which I have created so far three projects, OK?
And in the future I may add on to those projects more and these effects we have in all I think.
Yes.
And all three of them we do have enough.
But except for the second one and the first and third one, we do have enough.
But when you click on it, it's not going anywhere.
Right.
So actually, a student, a student of mine asked for this.
That's why I included it in the JavaScript project, because I just wanted to show you that this is
done actually through JavaScript.
You can't do it through access, but it's not that well supported across browsers.
And that is this scroll not behavior.
It's not really supported.
So you shouldn't do it now.
It may be well supported, maybe like five or maybe like two years or three years.
But for now we can just implement it through a very lightweight JavaScript.
You could say library, OK, because this is extremely difficult implementing through JavaScript.
That's why we are going to insert a small library of JavaScript.
That is the smooth, smooth scroll.
Right.
And this work works in this way, that, for example, you have four sections in your website.
This is Section one, Section two, Section three, Section four, and when you have four sections,
whenever you want to click the about section, it should go to that section in a smooth manner.
OK, if you want it to go abruptly, you can do that through access, but we want it to go smoothly
there.
So this is how this what we are going to create here.
So if we go to the contact section, click on the home, we are going to go to the home section.
These images, these text, this is this is actually nothing in here.
And I just wanted to go ahead and implement this.
In fact, these these sections, these images, they just simulate a real world kind of situation.
So if I click on the about contact, we can go to home, we can go to services, then contact then about
so we can move along this.
So the first thing that I'm going to do as well.
Well, actually, the JavaScript part is really, really simple.
It's just one constant that we are going to one variable that we are going to create, and that's it.
So if you go ahead to this, open this we are going to you're going to see a script where I have inserted
this, the CDN external JS file.
It comes from the JS to deliver a dot net.
And this is, I think, the person, Ferdinand Ferdinand, smooth scroll, this is the 15th version
and this is the script for that.
Just go ahead and insert it at the end of your e-mail document at the end of your body, of course not
e-mail.
And this is the JavaScript script because this is only one variable.
I did not create another ambiguous file like two to put it there because the lines of code are basically
like two and we don't need that for two.
Right.
So this is the markup.
You are going to go over the markup and styling first and in the next lecture we are going to implement
it.
So first off, we have a diff container, so if I were to go ahead, where is the untack for that if
we don't have it?
So let's create it.
So now let's save it now.
We do have an intact for that for the stove.
So we have a diff which has a class of container inside that.
We have two sections.
One is not for the other, one is well actually our sections.
So we have four sections for now.
You can add or decrease or increase the number of sections in the Navar.
We have our nav ul and regular Elize, but the aircraft has Gosta to the IED of that section.
Now this is the important part.
Now this hash is inserted here because this section has an IED and the idea of that section is home.
That's why it goes there.
Right.
And the same is repeated for the rest of the sections.
And each section has the same idea.
And the idea of the section is inserted in the extra for this agritech.
And yes, I think that's it for the e-mail and the CSIS.
First we have a reset, then we have some stats for the body.
Regular style's very simple.
Then we have our container.
This is the big diff.
That is the container of them all.
Highton With we have the Navar position is fixed because when we scroll up and down we don't want it
to scroll, we want it to be fixed in relation to the scroll display we have.
OK, this one is incorrect actually.
So let me take it out and OK, this is actually the project that we are working on.
This is the complete project.
You see, it works.
But this one, it doesn't work.
It actually works.
But when you want that smooth behavior, you have to insert some sort of like JavaScript code or library.
So without with only access and this is an HDMI out, this is the part why it works because the aircraft
has the same idea of that section.
So if I click on the about it should go to the about section and it does go to the about section.
But the transition is so abrupt, it's not smooth.
And we are going to smoothen it in JavaScript through JavaScript.
We have some number you Elsom properties for that simple flex ally.
We have an I for the anchor tax and properties.
If there is any unique property, I'm going to explain it to you.
As I did explain the object Fed property, these display flags, and these are all flex properties and
they cannot be explained in just two minutes.
Because complete courses should be dedicated to item two topics or discussions of flux and grit, these
are the rest of them.
They are very, very basic properties that we have for home background image for home, and we have
some linear gradient on top of it.
So what I'm going to do in here, basically, I just want to change something.
So I want to grab all the three five.
This is the Alpha Channel and I want to change it to point well, actually, point five five.
So this text has a better contrast.
Oh, right.
So I guess we could go over the JavaScript as well.
So in the JavaScript, what we are going to do is we are going to create a constant and this code actually
comes from this GitHub.
So I'm just going to take a second and I'm going to show you the GitHub page for this.
So I've just I've just opened up the GitHub page.
I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to put it, I don't know, like right here for your reference.
So this is actually to get help page for Smooth Scroll.
And the only thing that we had to do was just insert the CDN and then we are going to add this inside
the script that we have and we are going to go over what that is.
So I'm going to add it.
I'm going to change the VAD to const.
All right, and we are going to create a new smooth scroll here and the smooth scroll is going to be
added to the Navar.
So for that one, I'm going to do it.
So let's go ahead and Colombus these sections to make the navigation better.
So I'm just going to add a number here because we are going to grab it and it is going to grab any Ashraf.
This is the asterisk selector.
This is the asterisk attribute selector.
And we do have an and a hush hush here, so this address is going to select this attribute selector
is going to select any aircraft that has the character of hash in its name.
And that's that's basically it.
And it is going to it is going to select that.
And let's go ahead and let's save it.
So now I think we should be good.
So if I come here and if I click on the about now, you guys can see that this this is smooth, the
behavior is smooth, and that's it.
We just added the behavior.
We can go ahead and modify this.
We can add another function.
Well, not a function actually.
What we can do is we can modify this and we can.
I'd like a speed to it.
What is the speed that we want this to happen?
So we are going to add an object in here and we are going to give it 800 milliseconds.
So now if I click on it, it is going to take 800 milliseconds.
So if I put in like 3000 milliseconds, so let's click on it.
So let's click on this.
It is going to get it is going to take three seconds, three seconds to go from top to bottom.
All right, so it is very, very slow, you could put it to, I don't know, like 700 if you want faster.
So this is faster, but if you want it to be a bit slower, you can go with 800.
So what did we do wrong?
Let's save it and let's click here and it works.
So this is going to be it for this chapter and this project.
We basically inserted the CD in and we added the constant and voila, the project works.
And this is how simple it is whenever you're using JavaScript libraries.
But with vanilla JavaScript, this is like very, very difficult.
You know, you have this as a reference.
Well, because this but this does not belong to me.
This is someone else's library.
So smooth scrolls.
And I've just used it in this project.
Right.
So that's it.
See you guys in the next lecture.