Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to talk about lexical scope and compilation, right?
So here I have a code snippet, but before diving into that, I want to tell you one thing, and then
we are going to jump into this lecture and we are going to formally start this lecture.
Now, I know we have talked about the lexicon.
We have talked about scopes before.
And the reason that I want to restate all this is because now we are looking at JavaScript.
Exactly.
Or specifically at the inner workings of JavaScript, how JavaScript executes code under the hood,
how JavaScript works under the hood.
So now we are popping up the Howard and we want to take a look at the inner workings of JavaScript and
the inner workings of JavaScript.
They start with with the lexical scope because JavaScript is a lexically scoped language.
OK, so now before doing and also I want to tell you that the this chapter and the next two chapters,
we are going to dive really deep into theory.
So there is not going to be a lot of, like, code snippets or a lot of like challenges or exercises
or examples.
They're not there are not maybe like like like five examples and that's it.
But we are going to dive very, very deep into these theoretical parts.
That's why I've situated these chapters here, because now you know how how how you can manipulate the
DOM, how how to make any website dynamic.
But you should know how JavaScript works.
And if I were to like include these chapters at the start of this course, then that would have scared
you away, because these are really, really advanced topics.
And I and I'm and you should have like beginner to intermediate level knowledge of JavaScript so you
can understand how JavaScript works.
This is ironic that you should be like an intermediate developer to be able to understand how it works,
but this is how it's going to go ahead and be shaped.
All right.
So first things first.
What is scope?
Scope is where we look for things.
What do we look for?
We look for JavaScript identifiers like like this X and this Y in here.
Right now, the primary goals of variables in any JavaScript project are either to assign some think,
OK, to assign something to it or to retrieve its assigned value.
So in this case, what we have is this is a target reference.
I'm just going to write in front of its name and I'm just going to call a target reference because we
are assigning to it so.
So any identifier in JavaScript, it is either a targeted reference or a source reference.
In this case, this is a source reference because we are retrieving its value.
All right.
So whenever you're assigning a value to an identifier, it is a target reference.
And whenever you're not assigning any value to it, it is a source reference.
So those are the two scenarios in which any JavaScript identifier can exist, either target reference
or source reference.
Right.
So when the JavaScript sees this variable, it says, where is the position of this variable?
That is number one.
Where is the position of this variable?
The position of this variable is the global scope.
So it is not inside any block.
It's not inside any function.
It's not inside anything.
It is so it is inside the global scope.
And secondly, what scope does it belong to?
So where is it?
It's inside a scope.
What scope does it belong to?
That scope is the global scope.
Now, JavaScript is not an interpreted language.
JavaScript does not run the code line by line, like line two and then line three and then line five.
Right.
JavaScript is actually a compiled language or parsed.
If you feel better about past, it means that JavaScript requires a processing step called compilation
or a compilation.
Doesn't matter, but it does have a compilation or in an in-between stage that we cannot see.
OK, so the way JavaScript code works is is actually the meaning of all these three chapters.
But I'm going to give you a trailer of that so we have a code.
This code is going to be compiled inside here and then it is going.
To be presented to the PVM or a virtual machine inside this browser, which in case of the Google Chrome
is the V8 engine and that V8 engine is going to execute the JavaScript code.
How does the code is getting executed is actually the compiler theory.
The compiler theory is the theory that, well, arguably all the computer science world is based upon.
So if you understand the compiler theory, basically you understand you you get a six degree, OK,
you are a certified computer science engineer, right?
So there are three stages in compiler theory.
The first stages, Lexing and tokenization, Lexing or tokenization, is the process of converting a
sequence of characters such as in a program or a Web page.
In our case, what page into a sequence of tokens and tokens are strings with an assigned and thus identified
meaning.
Right.
The second stage is passing.
OK, so the first stage is writing this.
The second stage is passing which or compilation.
So we have written our code now the second stage is passing and the passing.
We, we grab all of our tokens and we convert them, OK, we convert them into abstract syntax.
And in this third stage we have our code generation.
So the third part is the code generation.
And in that stage we take our abstract syntax tree and produce other executable forms of this program.
So first off, we write the program, then the program is passed and then after the program is passed,
the code is converted to a program.
After the code is passed, the code is converted to a program.
Now, this shows how a program gets processed from its textual format into some kind of representation
that can be executed.
So the very, very essential and critical stage here is the completion stage or the parsing.
That's why I've given you this example here.
So if JavaScript were to like to interpret this code line by line by line, we would see like a console
log of 10.
We would see inside the log a ten and then we would see an error because we are declaring this constant
variable, but we are not initializing it.
So declaring a variable means that you write the variable and the identifier, but you do not write
the assignment expression.
But if you write that, then it means that you have declared it and you have initialized that variable.
So we cannot declare any constant variables without initializing them.
That's not how constants work, right?
So if I were to save this before, like this constant like just comment out the constant, we can see
that we have 10 here and everything is well.
But if JavaScript were and in interpreted language, if JavaScript interpreted this code, run this
code from top to bottom or line by line, we would see ten and then this error.
But we don't see 10 because there is a compilation step involved here and this shows the compilation.
All right.
That's why I've given you this example now before handing this code over to a VM or to the code execution
engine or to the execution engine.
The JavaScript parses this code, compiles it, and it sees an error here.
And it says that there is an error here.
And what is the error missing?
Initialize your and const declaration.
So we have declared this const, but there is no initialize initialization in here.
Right.
So.
When does actually this compilation happen?
It does not happen and runtime contrary to popular belief that the JavaScript compilation happens at
runtime, but it doesn't happen at runtime.
It is actually a two step process.
The first step is the compilation or the parsing, and the second step is the runtime or the code execution.
OK, now you can think of it as like in this case that we have identifiers, OK, and we have units
of scope.
So our X in here is an identifier and we have units of scope.
So before we have before we have sex, we had functions primarily functions.
But as of a year six, we have blocks as well.
OK, because as a few sex we have left and consed, which we are going to dive very deep.
That's why we have started working through these inner workings with this vare.
Right.
Not the letton concept.
And I'm going to now what I'm going to do is I'm going to give you another code snippet right here.
I'm just going to pasted here.
This is very simple.
And I'm going to comment out this first one.
Right.
And I'm going to say example to now.
What we are going to do is we are going to go over the first stage, which is the compilation.
And in the next lecture, we are going to talk about the code execution.
I think this is like a very good approach.
So in this lecture, what in this front, from now on until the lecture ends, we are going to talk
about the compilation compilation or the passing stage.
And in the next lecture, we are going to talk about how this code is actually executed.
All right, so let's go ahead and start.
So before doing that, I'm just going to because this topic is like a bit difficult and it's a bit dry.
We are going to like and talk about it like like in a fun way.
So think of think of it like we have a scope manager or a Scopa and then we have a compiler.
So whatever you write all this, all of them, they are assigned to their specific scopes and those
assignments, they are handled by the scope manager.
And then before the code execution, we have the compilation stage.
And that compilation stage is the is like handled by the compilation manager or by the compiler.
So we have Scopa and we have compiled.
So before handing this into the JavaScript VM or code or execution engine, we need to create a plan
for all of the identifiers and the scopes.
OK, and that plan we are going to call it the execution plan.
Now think of it like this.
So we have novels or books.
Both of them are the same.
So we have novels in here which are our identifiers and we have scopes here which are our boxes.
So think of it like this.
You have a bunch of novels or a bunch of books and you want to put them inside their specific boxes,
right.
So first off, what do we do as an online one?
Now, in the compilation stage we have, we need to compile this code.
So the first thing that the compiler is going to ask the scope manager is that online eight, what do
we have is we have a declaration, OK?
And inside this declaration, we have an identifier called novel.
And and it asks the scope manager that have you heard of this novel?
Do you know what this identifier is?
And the scope manager is going to say, no, I have not heard of it, but here is your scope.
Here is your box.
You can put the VA novel inside this box.
So what does that box?
That box is the global scope.
And I'm just going to write G.S..
This is the global scope, OK?
And then we are going to come to because this is the compilation stage, not the execution stage.
This is how this would play out.
Right.
So in here, we also have a function declaration.
This is another declaration.
So the compiler is going to ask the scope manager, have you heard about the other book?
The scope manager is going to say no, but here is your box.
You can put this this novel or this book inside this box.
And what is that box?
That box is, again, the global scope.
Right.
And then we are going to come to line 15 and we have another identifier.
And we are going to the compiler is going to ask the same question from the scope manager.
And the compiler is going to ask, have you heard of any identifier called write book?
The scope manager is going to say no, but here is your scope.
What is the scope again?
It is the global scope.
I know I have missed this VA and this VA and but after this function, we are going to go back.
All right, because I'm just coming from top to bottom, because this is the first time that we are
talking about this.
So this is not actually how compilation works.
It works.
It goes into this function and from there it goes into this and it after it compiles this function and
goes inside the function.
But for the sake of understanding and for the sake of teaching, that's why I, I jumped from this function
to this function.
Now this function is done.
And after this, we have no declarations, no formal declarations inside the global scope.
So these are not declarations.
OK, this is our execution code.
We are going to talk about this in our next lecture.
So we are going to come back to our other book now because functions, they have specific scopes for
them.
OK, so think of this entire thing.
One big box and inside that big box, you have another small box.
And what is inside the small box?
We have another formal declaration by the name of novel.
OK, so the identifier name is novel.
We are going to ask the scope of this function now.
We are not going to ask the scope of this this global scope.
We are going to ask the scope of this function.
Have you heard about any identifier called novel?
It is going to say no, but here is your box.
So this box is going.
To be function scop, I'm just going to say AIFS or the function sko console log is not a formal declaration,
so we are going to move past and we are going to come here.
So the same thing.
We have a formal declaration inside a function scope, so we are not going to ask the global scope.
OK, so we are going to ask the functions of the scope.
Manager in this case is going to be the function scope and it is going to give us a box.
And that box is called the function scope.
So now at this point, the compilation is done.
And what do we have here now?
The take away is that a lexically scoped language like like japes.
The execution plan is created at the compile time by the compiler, not a runtime.
So and everything that we did here is actually we created an execution plot, a plan for executing this
code.
Right.
This execution plan is used at the runtime, but it is certainly determined at the compile time.
OK, so why why does this happen?
This happens because the engine, the execution engine just runs the code.
This makes the engine work faster as everything is known.
And the engine has received a plan to optimize its work based on that plan.
OK, so what is the plan?
The plan involves our identifiers and involves our scopes so we know where our identifiers are, what
sorry, what our identifiers are and which scope do they belong to?
So we mainly have the global scope and the function scope for our identifiers.
So we are going to take this example to our next lecture where we will talk about the lexical scope
and the actual code execution.
See you guys that.