Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about function declarations.
All right, so we have talked about what functions are and how we can use them to our advantage, but
this chapter is specifically designed for four functions.
So we are going to dive very deep into the topic of functions.
All right.
And we are going to take a look at how we can create functions in different ways.
OK, so the first kind of functions that we are going to talk about are called function declarations
or function statements.
Now, before diving into function declarations, I just want to go over what functions are one more
time very quickly.
So functions are actually reuse reusable pieces of code that we can use all the time.
Now there are two steps to using a function to implementing a function in JavaScript first.
We define a function and then we call the function as many times as we want.
So as long as we call it, as long as we don't call it until we call it, the function is going to be
asleep.
The function is not going to do anything.
So we have to call the function and we have to call it that function.
Do this and the function is going to get up and do that.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to we are going to go through a few examples in this
lecture.
So we are so we can make sure that we fully understand what function declarations are, because later
in this chapter, we are going to talk about function expressions as well.
No function declarations are also called function statements.
So function declarations are what are named functions.
So for creating any function, the first keyword that we have to write is the function itself.
So this function is not the name of the function, the name of the function comes now.
So if I go ahead and if I say my func, this is the name of the function and this is the simplest syntax
for any function.
So we have the function keyword.
We have this part is the function name.
This is the parentheses inside which we pass in a function parameter which we are going to cover.
And this is the function scope, which is which is responsible for implementing a code that we tell
it to.
All right, so we are going to start with very, very simple stuff, very first, we want this function
to log to the console, a message.
The message is going to be I am a function right now.
Now, this function has not been called.
That's why there is no result in the console.
Now, in order to make a function work, we have to call it now.
The function is called by the function name.
So we are going to say my func because it's a function.
We open parentheses and now we just save it and we are going to see I am a function.
Now this function name in parentheses is different than this function name in parentheses as this is
the function name and inside the parenthesis here we are going to pass in a parameter, but in here,
in the function call we do not pass parameters and the function call we pass in arguments.
So I'm just going to go ahead and comment that out at the top in the function name we pass in the function
name.
I'm just going to say function name parameters.
And.
In the function call, you are going to have arguments and that's in the function call, all right.
So whenever you pass in an argument, the argument is going to take the place of the parameter and it
is going to be inserted within the function, which we don't have now.
OK, so this was our very first look at the function declaration.
Now we are going to take a look at a few examples.
So this is our example, number one.
And we and in this first rewrite the function key word and then the function name, which is some nums,
it means that we want to check some some numbers and we are going to say consult the log five plus six.
And when I say it, we don't see anything.
The reason for that is we have to call the sum nums function.
And when we say it, we are going to get 11.
So this is the first example, very, very simple stuff.
We are going to get to the advanced stuff later down the course.
All right.
So this is our example.
Number two in this, we are going to say we are going to create a function and we are going to call
it message.
All right.
And inside the function, we are going to create a variable called red and we are going to give it a
code which is which is going to be cash flow as zero zero zero zero.
Right.
Is tomorrow.
And we are going to say council does log.
We're going to use the tactics, the hex.
I'm just going to go lower case, the hex value of the red color is now we are going to use our template
literals.
And inside there we're going to pass in our our variable.
Right.
So the hex value of the red color is this.
Now, whatever we call the function, the message function, we are going to see that message.
The color of the red sorry, the hex value of the red color is this.
So this is our second example.
Let's go ahead and let's dive into our third example.
This is example number three and in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say function and the
function name is going to be color and we are going to pass in a parameter.
Right.
So the parameter is going to be hex and we are going to say console's Deathlok.
Consider log what?
Consider log hacks and in here we are going to pass, we are going to call the function and inside the
function call what do we pass?
We pass arguments or argument or arguments.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to pass in a color value if one one and oh, and we are going to
save it.
Oh, this is a string, so it should be Pastan in quotes.
Let's save it and we are going to see that.
So what what is actually happening here?
So whenever we call the function and we pass in an argument, the argument is going to take is going
to be passed and right here instead of or in place of the function parameter.
And when when it is passed here, it is going to be passed by this function inside the function scope
or inside the function block.
And when it is open and whenever we see that parameter, we are going to replace it by the value for
the function argument.
So actually this entire thing is going to be passed right here.
We can call the function and as many times as we want, we can pass in another color hex color.
And we are going to say.
Ey ey ey ey.
It's DFC that save it and we are going to see that so we can use the function as many times as we want.
That's basically the whole idea of calling functions, creating functions and calling functions multiple
times.
OK.
E.
S for f random color color codes, right?
So this is our example.
Number three and the final example is going to be our example, number four.
So we are going to say example for and in here.
First off, let's go ahead and let's write the oops.
What was that function keyword itself.
Then we are going to give it a name of calc nums, calculate numbers, and we are going to pass an X
here as a parameter and we are going to say console Deathlok.
Now this is going to be like a rather long one.
So what I'm going to do is first I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create I'm going to create another
one as well.
So this is going to be X plus one.
And outside the the parentheses, I'm going to multiply it by X and when it is multiplied by X, what
I want to do is I want to grab the whole result and I want to divide it by X plus ten.
Let's save it.
So now whenever we call the function calc called nums, we should present an argument for that function
parameter.
So let's say the argument is four and we are going to get this number.
So if we're passing like 200, we are going to get this number because it is going to come right here.
For example, if it is 200, it is going to be 200 plus one to one divided by 200 and then sort multiplied
by 200 and then divided by two hundred and ten.
And we are going to get this value right.
So this is about function declarations.
In our next lectures, we are going to even die.
We're going to dive even deeper into functions.
So see you guys in the next lecture.