Hi, everyone, in this chapter working to create a password, strengthen.
All right, so this is the Uiver application, we will be using regular expressions once more.
All right.
And this UI is very, very simple, but there is actually a lot going behind this application.
So in here in this area, this area is where you type your password and this bar is going to get filled
up with a blue color.
And the more this blue color is going up, it it shows, the stronger your password is.
And whenever you start typing, you're going to get a few suggestions.
And if you well, evaluation's that or assessments, that is going to show you that.
It is going to tell you that what your password is lacking.
So if I were to just go ahead and write, for example.
Awesome.
So awesome, you can see that this bar is coming up and what what what what does it say?
It says the password could be longer.
It has no uppercase characters, no numbers and no special characters.
And if I were to add numbers one to three, you can see that the bar is going up and now it says could
be longer, but says no uppercase characters.
So that's right.
Q w e and now it still says no special character is the right person to join kerosine and it still says
could use more special.
So you have to write at least three letters, three lowercase letters, three uppercase letters, three
numbers, three special characters.
Then you are going to have a very, very strong password.
And also you should not repeat letters.
Right?
So if you have two kids, you can see that the strength is coming down.
And the more repeated letters you have or characters, the more the strength is going to is going to
get reduced.
So if I have D and then it is going past and then again, again, again C see how this is coming down,
because repeating characters is not a good way of creating a password.
So if I just go ahead and add an ampersand, you can see that the strength is full and this is a very,
very strong password.
So this is the interface of our application.
This is the introduction to our application.
I'm just going to make this spec right.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to go over the e-mail and says, well, this is the amount.
This is an our Ashmont each one.
This is our section.
We have a div which is destroying thr.
This is this vertical bar that you can see that is that is going to get filled up.
We have our input type of.
Text, and we have it now out of focus attribute on it, the autofocus attribute allows you whenever
you refresh the page, the cursor automatically goes inside that input.
And we have a diff which says password check and the password check.
Has those text that you saw that that gave you like assessment's OK.
So in the C assess, we have some very basic styling for the reset.
Nothing new.
Again, we have used this reflects on the body because we want this entire thing to be centered.
See, this is entirely vertically and horizontally centered and this is styling for our H1, for the
section.
We have padding and we have a specific height and a specific with 600 and 400.
We have displayed great sort of display, flex and section.
Now, this is a child selector.
It grabs the first child that is a diff.
So inside this section we have to divs, which means there are two children.
So that selector is going to select the first one.
And we have said display flex on that, right, and all right, so here we have strength.
This is going to be our strength here.
And some basic styling for the strength or the height is this entire height is 100 percent and with
this 20 pixels positions relative.
Now, here is the important part.
This is the thing that is going to fill this up is actually a pseudo aliment, pseudo aliments.
They do not have an equivalent initiative.
They're created in success.
So you can create pseudo elements like it's fake elements, but still you can create them.
The thing with them as you should provide content either either that's going to be empty or something
else.
So it's just going to be empty.
Then we are going to position absolute the position absolute is going to take it out of this e-mail
document and it's going to position relatively transparent, which is the strength itself.
All right.
Because for now it doesn't have a height.
You cannot see it.
So if I comment that one out and if I say height of 50 pixels, OK, let's open.
This was life server.
OK, now you considered the height is 50 pixels and you could go ahead and increase it to like, I don't
know, like 400, it is going to go up.
But the thing is that we do not want a hard code this height.
We want this hide to be very, very flexible.
And we want it to be a percentage based Y percentage because the height of the parent is in percent
and calculating person is easier.
If you were to calculate the hide, the height of this entire thing is going to be 600 minus the padding
for the top and padding for the bottom.
So if you were to calculate it that way, that would become like really difficult.
But what we are doing here is we are grabbing a function in CISSP, which is a C assess function, and
we are multiplying the value by one percent.
What is this?
This VAR is actually a C is this custom property a cyesis custom property is any property that is not
available in excess and you make it yourself.
So a custom property looks exactly like any normal Sears's property, but the difference is that it
has two dashes in front of it.
So we have a position here.
This is the property name.
We have colon and we have some value for that and we have SEMICON in the same way Custom Properties
created the reason that we have only called the custom property here is because we are going to create
this custom property in JavaScript dynamically.
So this part that you can see here is actually the property name.
To be able to show you how this actually works is I've just come in this one out and in here I've said
50.
So this 50 is going to be passed in here.
And this zero, in case you're wondering, is the initial value.
If we don't have any other value for the strength amount, we are going to get the zero value.
But since we have 50, this year is going to be overridden by this.
So now we can see that we have a regular property name, property like colon, property value and semicolon.
But the only difference is these two dashes here.
So whenever you create this custom property, you can use it through the VA function.
So you just write VA are open and close parentheses and just pass in the name of this custom property
and it is going to work.
So if I were to say 50 50 is going to come right here and then it's going to be 50 times one percent,
which is 50 percent.
So it is going to be filled up to almost right here.
So 50 percent.
So let's say that it's right here.
It's exactly 50 percent of that high.
If you say 100, it is going to be completely 10 percent, only this much.
But this value, we are going to change it dynamically in JavaScript.
That's why we provide it with this custom property.
This custom properties are very customizable in JavaScript and their custom properties or Cyesis variables.
Right.
There are new additions to services.
Three are right.
So if you are not feeling comfortable with this e-mail and success with the VA function, with the Kalik,
with the Sears's Custom Properties Act, you'll have to see.
It is of course, this one is regarding flexible scripts and animations, which is hands on course.
There are multiple projects and the other one is actually a boot camp which covers almost all of the
essential properties which you will ever need when it comes to success.
And so you could go ahead and check out those courses in case you're not that completely like comfortable.
You're not feeling comfortable with the stimulus.
Iesus So we do have this after Suda element in the in both of the courses I go over to aliments pseudo
classes.
What is the difference?
How can you use them to your advantage, how you can design, you can create and design beautiful websites
and then we have our input, some basic styling for that and we have a password check which is which,
which is a paragraph.
Now this paragraph is going to be created dynamically.
We are not going to create it, I think.
Do we have we created it?
No, we don't.
We have not.
So we are going to create this paragraph dynamically.
And after it is created, after this paragraph is created, then it is going to receive these styles.
So these styles will be added to that paragraph, no matter if the paragraph is created or if it is
inside this HTML or it is going to be dynamically created.
That set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.