Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to implement the functionality of our darkman toggle.
All right.
So basically we need to grab two things in our JavaScript.
So the first thing is, yes, you guessed it right.
It is going to be our button.
So I'm going to say check box.
Oops, the equals sign should come after it.
And we're going to say document dot, query selector and we are going to add it.
We are going to grab it through its input attribute.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to decrease the width and I'm going increase the width on
this one.
So we are going to use it.
We are going to select it through attributes, selectors and for using attribute structures.
We first write the name of the element that we want to select and then inside the brackets we write
the attribute for that.
So it is going to have an attribute, which is name is going to be theme.
So this is the attribute that that input has.
And if you come here, it has an attribute name which with a value of theme.
And the next thing that I want to grab is going to be our etch HTML element.
Well, um, and I mean, this should be capitalized, right, and this is the second thing, and as
with the body element, I finish him of document we do have is a reserved selector for a stimulus element
as well.
And that is the document element.
So whenever you do document element, this line is going to return an e-mail element.
So if we were to go ahead and to cancel the log it.
Consider log HTML element, let's save it, let's come to the console and we are going to get our e-mail
documents, see, so we are going to get the entire esteemable document.
So it is going to return the entire original document.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the check box and I'm going to add event listener because
we are listening for a click.
When the user clicks the checkbox and when the user clicks the checkbox, we are going to run in a function
and in the function, we are going to basically check for a condition.
Now, what is the condition that we want to check?
We want to check that if our HDMI document has a data theme, value of light, if if the data theme
attribute of the original document has a value of light, then toggle it to dark.
And if it has a data stream value of dark, then toggle it to light.
That's it.
That's basically what we want to do.
So we are going to say F so f so first we are going to write a checkbox if checkbox is checked.
Right.
So when checkbox is checked, we are going to grab the HTML element and we are going to say classless
and we are going to toggle what is the class that we want to toggle.
Now this is the transition class because we want to smoothly transition everything.
So this is the transition costs.
Right.
And toggle, as we talked about in our previous project, takes a look at that element.
And if it has that class, it is going to remove it.
If it doesn't have it, it is going to add it.
Right.
And then we are going to grab the demo element and we are going to say set attribute, set attribute.
Now, if the checkbox is checked, we want to set the attribute to dark.
So what is the attribute name?
The attribute name is data dash theme and what is the value that we want to set it with?
We want to set it with dark.
What is the value for this data thing?
We want to set it to dark and else in any other condition, meaning that the HTML, the checkbox is
not checked.
So we have two conditions, whether the checkbox is checked or the checkbox is not checked.
So this else is also going to be applied only on one condition, and that is when the checkbox is not
checked.
We are going to say toggle the transition.
And Xitian.
Toggle the transition.
I mean, we could have said that whenever the checkbox is checked just at the class of transition and
when the checkbox is not checked, it remove the class of transition.
We could do this as well.
But I just want to go with toggled.
That's more that's better and more advanced.
And we are going to say HTML element, dot sit attribute.
What is that truth that we want to say?
It is data dash theme and what is what is it that we want to set it with?
It is light, so let's save it.
And now now the checkbook's is not checked.
That's why it has a data theme of light.
So if I click on it now, the checkbox is checked and it is going to have a data theme of dark.
So that's basically it for this project.
See you guys in the next one.