Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to go over looping through arrays and looping through
objects nested within arrays.
All right, so the first thing that we are going to cover in this lesson is going to be looping through
a race.
OK, and you might ask, why do we need to loop through a race now?
Because arrays are a collection of data.
If you want to grab that data each time, we have to, for example, call it by its index.
Now, the easier way is just to loop through it, OK?
Because as we have covered in our previous lecture, we we we talked about how loops they allow us to
right to repeat code, right to repeat code and to decrease the number of lines of code.
OK, so let's see that in action.
So we have a concept.
Let's create a const, we are going to create a loop and sorry, an array of numbers and the numbers
inside of it.
They are twenty five.
Sixty five.
Ninety five.
Forty five and one thirty five.
All right, so we have five items inside this array and if I want to grab all of them at the same time,
there is no other way besides loop.
If I want to grab all of them then I have to grab each of them like individually by its index.
But a better way is just to go ahead and loop through it.
OK, so for that we are going to create a for a loop.
First off, the structure of the for loop.
So in here, what do we want to do.
OK, so first we have to provide it with the loop variable.
So we are going to say let's equal to zero.
We want the loop variable to start from zero and we want the loop variable to go all the way to one
less then to less than the length of the array.
And you might ask why less than the length of the array.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and comment that out and I'm going to cancel the
log this array, and I'm going to tell you why we go less than the array that length.
So now you guys can see here, what do we have here, it says that the length is five, but what is
the final index?
The final index is for so four is one less than five.
Right.
So if we want to grab all the array items by their index, the final index is always one less than the
length of that array.
Right.
So array length is five, the final index is four.
And the reason for that is the length starts from one to one, two, three, four and five.
But the index, it starts from zero indices in JavaScript, they start from zero.
OK, so I'm going to comment that out and we are going to comment this code back in and we want to go
all the way to numbers that length.
Less than that.
All right.
And we want to each time we want to increment E by one.
And now, first of all, let's go ahead and let's look to the council, our evaluable, and we are going
to see that it grabs the index of zero one, two, three and four.
So it has successfully tapped into the world of indices of this.
Right.
So what do we want to do with this index that we that we can grab now?
Now, let's go ahead and let's print the index that we have and also the numbers associated with that
index.
Let's say that so the number 25 has an index of zero, the number 65 has an index of one and all the
way to number 135 has an index of four.
So this is how we can grab numbers based on their index.
Now, I'm just going to go ahead and give you another example as well.
And that is just numbers and the the low variable.
And then now we can we have successfully accessed all the loop items with just with just one loop.
With just one loop, OK.
Now this is called looping through arrays.
The next topic that I want to discuss is looping through objects nested within arrays.
So I'm going to grab that and I'm going to put it here through objects nested within arrays.
Right.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's create an object.
And I'm going to call it five books or five books.
OK, because this is an object nested within an array.
The first syntax is going to be an array and the array items are going to form like objects.
So the first item is going to be an object and we are going to say book name.
OK, this is our first key and I'm going to call it The Kite Runner.
Right.
And do not forget to separate them by comma.
And we are going to say author.
Or a huge or author is going to be let.
Hossaini.
All right, so this is our first loop item, and we we separate loop items by comma, so this is going
to be our second loop item.
We are going to have a book name and and an author.
So the book name.
This time it is going to be the theory of every thing.
And the author is, you guessed it right, Stephen Hawking.
Right.
And finally, our final object or loop item is going to be the book name is going to be the it's not
going to be the is just going to be Moby Dick and author is.
Herman Melville.
Right, so let's save it.
So this is an object, this is objects nested within an array.
Right.
We can go ahead and consider log this this array of objects.
We can just say the name that is five books and we are going to get them.
So the length of this array is going to be three, but the index starts from one and is sorry from zero
and goes all the way to two.
So this is a representation of our array of objects.
We can go ahead and loop through this array with the same method.
OK, so what we are going to do is we are going to create a for loop structure first and then this time
I'm going to call the loop variable I and we are going to say it starts from zero in the eye, goes
all the way to what, to five books that length.
Less than that.
Right.
And we are going to increment I by one.
So we wanted to start from zero and then go to one because it's incremented by one.
And then when increment one by one you get two.
And why the I should start from zero initially because the index is zero.
That's why it should start from zero.
Right.
And let's go ahead.
First off, log decipherable and we are going to get.
We are going to get all the indices right.
What we can do is we can log our array as well, along with the eye variable, and we are going to get
that the OK, there is a lot of information here.
So the index of zero is associated with this object.
Author of the book named Kite Runner, the index of One Theory of Everything and the index of two,
Moby Dick.
All right.
We can also access each individual object as well.
And I'm going to comment about these two.
So this is our our first object and our second and our third.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.