Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to implement the functionality of the temperature converter
application.
All right.
So first off, before jumping into code, we need to know what we want to do.
So whenever I click inside any of these inputs and I start typing something, I can see that in the
both of the other inputs we can see something we can see in.
No, OK.
Of course, that number is based on a formula which we are going to insert.
But this that number or those numbers, they are being inputted dynamically.
They are being input dynamically.
All right.
So what we need to do is we need to grab all three of these four elements and then we need to apply
an event listener on all three of them, because whenever I type inside one of them, all the rest of
the two, they also change values.
So I'm going to come inside my app that just file.
So first stuff.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to grab all three of the inputs individually because we want to change
their values depending on the formula that we insert.
And then I'm going to grab all the inputs together and the event is going to be on that.
Right.
So I'm going to say Celsius.
Celsius.
Input.
All right, so it is document that query selector, we're going to select it using our query selector
method and it is an input type.
All right.
So it is an input.
And what is the idea?
ID is Celsius.
So each of the inputs, they have their own specific ideas so they can be recognized.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is let's select the Farenheit as well.
So it is.
Um hmm.
So like this Celsius Farenheit they spell correctly Farenheit.
It's a tough one.
I thought the other one was being edited as well.
So let's grab the Celsius control the Ferrin.
Hide.
All right, so and the last one is the simplest, which is Calvin.
All right, so now we have selected all of the input feels individually.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to select them collectively as well.
So I'm going to call them temperature inputs.
All right.
Notice the other ones.
They are just input, but this one is inputs.
And we're going to say document, query, selector.
But this time we are going to say queries, after all, because we are selecting more than one element
and we are going to select them by their element, which is input.
So now let's grab the temperature inputs and we are going to say add event listener.
So we are going to loop over them and then we are going to say out of a listener.
So let's do a for each loop and the loop variable is going to be input.
Now we are going to grab that input and each time the user writes inside one of those inputs, we want
to do something.
So the event because we are working with inputs, is going to be input.
And what about the callback function?
The callback function is going to be an anonymous function with the event as the parameter.
Right, because we want to grab the value of that specific event.
Right.
So before going forward, I just want to consider log a few things because I want to show you how actually
this application works behind behind the scenes.
So first off, I want to consult either target value.
Why now?
We know what the target gives us.
So what about the value?
The value is going to give us the target value for that specific object that has Sara for that specific
event on that specific input, which has been which has been received.
All right.
So let's put it on the side and this is better.
And so if I go ahead and if I click here and if I type 15, we can see that we get one and then we get
15.
And why is that?
Because on each time we change an input inside the input field, this event is going to is going to
be fired.
Right.
So the event is not going to wait until we are done with our input and then the event should start working.
Now, with each input, the event starts working.
And this is the good thing, because in our final application, when I say one, we can see Farenheit
and Kalvin for one.
When I say two, we can see for that three.
So each time we can see that all these they are being changed dynamically.
So that's the good thing about this application.
All right.
So we have successfully selected the input values for any of the events.
It doesn't matter what that is.
So even if I come there and come to Kelvyn, we are going to grab it.
OK, so it doesn't really matter where we are.
We have successfully selected that either target that value.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grant I'm going to grab this and I want to store the value inside
a variable and I'm going to call it that.
And I'm going to say temperature value.
Right.
So whichever number that the user, whatever it is that the user inserts inside those inputs, it is
going to be our temperature value and we have stored it inside this variable.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to do one more console lock here and I'm going to say type of temperature
value.
So let's go ahead and check out what the type of the temperature that value is.
So we know we have a type of operator.
So if I type in 15 or if I just go ahead and if I had one, we can see it says I can just go ahead and
do it one more time to reload the page.
So if I say five, we can see it gives us a string.
We don't need a string because these are no inputs.
We want to grab a number.
We want to have a number.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to you know what?
I'm going to delete this, cancel log, delete this one as well.
And we know that temperature value is not a number.
It is this variable.
This is not a number.
This is a string.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab this.
And on this, I'm going to call not Jason.
I'm going to say pass, pass integer because pass integer method, it converts a string into a number.
And now if you go ahead and if we say concer log typeof temperature value, we are going to get a number.
So if I click, we can see we get a number.
All right.
So we just did this and most of the heavy lifting is done.
Now I'm going to create another variable here.
I'm going to call it inpart name, because depending on the input name, we are going to implement a
different formula.
So we need to know what is the input that the user has clicked in?
What is the input that the user is inserting the values when we grab it, then according to that, we
are going to implement a formula for the other two.
So if the user is riding inside the Celsius, we know that the user is writing inside the Celsius.
So we need a Celsius to Fahrenheit formula and in Celsius to Kalvin formula.
I'm going to give you one more example.
So if the user is writing inside the Fahrenheit, we need a Fahrenheit to Celsius formula and a Fahrenheit
to Kalvin formula.
So we are going to implement an IF statement that we are going to do in our next lecture.
See you guys then.