Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we're going to take a look at the call stack in the browser.
All right.
So here we have a function here we have like a set of functions and we are going to take a look at the
JS runtime or JS runtime at a glance.
So we have a function of multiply, right.
That is called inside the function of some.
The function of some is called inside the function of subtract.
This function is called inside the divide.
And finally we just call the divide function.
So if I say that this is nothing special, we know that this these all these simple operations will
take place.
But how are they going to take place?
Is is the topic of this lecture.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to try this.
I'm going to open this.
OK, so this is our this is our developer tools.
We have elements, console, network sources, performance, memory application, which we have talked
about before.
Right.
So what you're going to do is just jump from console all the way to sources.
Jumpier ignored this.
This is because of the life server that a code injected by life server extension that we have installed,
just if you do that, you're going to see that this is to double the cost browser, that if you click
here, you can see a representation of all of our functions here.
So for the sake of better readability, I'm just going to zoom out a bit so we can see everything at
the same time at a glance.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to this line.
You can see it highlights it, and I'm just going to click.
All right, and it means that we have just added a breakpoint and where is the breakpoint?
The breakpoint is a line number three and then I'm just going to go ahead and refresh the page and it's
just paused in the debugger.
Right.
And what does it mean?
It means that we have passed the code execution.
And now what I'm going to do is we are going to go over this is the call stack right here.
All right, so here is the call stack and here is the scope, we are going to go over the call stack
and we are going to go over the scope as well.
So first off, what is the scope that we are talking about?
The scope is the global scope, and these are all the methods and properties that are attached to the
global scope, which we are not going to go over.
We have covered some of them.
We are going to cover some others.
We might not we might not cover all of them.
But you will have the idea that how they are called, how they are used.
So if I come here, it's a step into next function.
Call 11 or control plus semicolon.
I'm just going to click this.
So if I click this from this divide, we're going where are we going?
To the step into next function call.
All right.
So if I click this, we can see that we come here inside this console.
Sorry, const results X divided by Y, and it gives us this representation here that it says, I think
I should zoom back in like.
OK, I think I should zoom in like two eyes, so it's readable, so, OK, buddy, so let's close this.
Refresh it.
OK.
So if I do this, this is the call stack, this is the scope, right?
So if I click on this, it's a step into next function call.
If I click it, we are going to step inside this function and we can see that we have X is equal to
100 and Y is equal to Fiverr.
These real values coming from they are coming from right here.
Right.
So this is the executable code.
And now right away we can see that inside the call stack we have this divide function.
So this divide function is right over inside the stack and inside the scope.
There we go.
We have a local scope because functions they create a scope.
And inside this local scope, we have two variables.
We have X and we have what and we have there the we have the values for them.
But the thing is that we can see that the result is undefined, OK, because we have not calculated
the result yet.
We are going to get to that and the result is going to be defined later.
So if I click on it, the next executable line of code is concerned dialogue and we can see that the
result is now 20.
You can see that right here.
Now the result is 20.
All right, and the function is still right here, whenever the function is done, what they call the
call, the function is going to be pumped from the call stack.
But because this divide function is not done yet, that's why it is still staying in here.
We can see that if I click on this console log, it is just going to log something to the console and
it is going to be popped immediately.
It means that it is not going to even stay here for like even one millisecond.
So if I click on it, it is run.
It should have like had it should have been like on the call stack.
But it is not because it run, it ran and it popped that set.
So it is done.
So if I come inside the console we can see twenty because hundred divided by five, we get the result
which is tiny and we locked it.
Now this is another function call.
So if I click on this button one more time, we should see subtract added to the cost.
So if I click on it, we can see that we are on this subtract.
But still the divide is right here.
Right.
So this is the call center, the call stack.
Whenever when we get to the end of it, I'm going to explain something to you that whatever you put
in the car stuck in the last whatever is the last, that is going to be the first item that is going
to be pumped from the car stack.
So the last item is the first item that is going to be popped.
Right.
So we are now stepping inside the subtract function.
This is the first line of executable code.
We know the values for X and Y.
Where are they coming from?
They are coming from here.
So X is 50, which is 40.
So if I click on it, we are going to go to the next line of code and the result is calculated.
So this is the and this 10 is stored is allocated to a small space in memory by the VM or JavaScript
engine.
We have talked about this.
So now this is the console because console, it just runs the code and it pops from the stack right
away.
OK, these are not popping because we're not done with them.
That's not that's why they're not popping.
But because we are just this is just one line of code.
There are no dependencies.
We already know the result is not like the result is not a non.
We know the result.
We just log it to the concerts.
If I click on it, console log is added to the stack and is popped from the stack and we can see that
the subtract it is a local method.
Sorry, it is, it has a local scope.
This is the global scope, but it also has a local scope, which is the scope of this function.
And in there we know the result, we know the value for X and we know the value for Y.
And now if I come to this to the console, we can see the ten has been logged to the console.
All right.
So now if I click on this, we should see that we we are done with the subtract function and the this
blue arrow should go one level up to this sum function.
So if I click on it, we can see the same function.
The same thing is going to happen.
We are going to calculate the result with this and then we are going to log it to the console and it
is going to be popped immediately from the stack.
And then we are going to step inside another function call and we can see the local.
And here as well, so if I click on it, we can see that these are undefined or because the result is
not yet calculated, if we come see here, it is 80.
Right.
And because we are inside this multiply function, when the result is calculated, the result is going
to come here.
It is 600 and it's just collapse that.
Right.
And now we are going to go to the console lock and it is going to log 600 because of course, 20 times
30, we are going to get 600.
Now, what is the return value?
The return value is undefined.
And when I click on it now, you can see the final thing is multiplied.
Right.
So if I click on it, multiply is gone because multiply is done calculating.
Whenever the function is done with its calculation or with its return, the function is going to be
popped from the stack.
Now, keep in mind, all these functions are literally on top of each other right in the stack.
So whatever is the the last item or the last function on the stack in the stack, that is going to be
the first item that's going to be pop.
So.
Because Multiply was the last item, it was so it's the first item that you can grab from the stuff,
you cannot grab the device if you want to grab the device.
You should pop, multiply and then some and then subtract.
It is this is also the stark data structure in JavaScript.
So if I click on it now, the sum is popped.
We are done with that.
If I click on it now, the multiply, what was it.
Multiply was it was some and then first was multiply.
Then we, we were done with the sum and then we were done with the subtract.
And now when I click on it we will be done with the fight and now we get back and now we can see that
this is at the end of this line.
And that's why we are inside the global, because we are done with execution, stayed with the execution.
So this is JavaScript runtime at a glance.
This is the call stack.
Right.
And I think it is the next lecture where we will be talking about the Web APIs.
And I'm going to give you the MDN resource for Web APIs, all the APIs that you have access to.
And I'm also going to we are going to go to a website which is called Latent VoIP, and we are going
to see another visual representation of the call stack and the event loop, the callback queue.
And we are going to talk about that.
And then you will understand, OK, what is the job of the browser and what is the job of the JavaScript?
And in here you can see that we have Dom breakpoints, all of the antivenin here we have event listener
breakpoints.
So all of our projects, all of the projects so far that they had, they included manipulation or in
the next projects that we have done manipulation, Dom, is.
Actually, a browser hippiedom is done through browser.
OK, that is not JavaScript.
That is the browser.
That's why we can see here.
This is the fetch.
We are XIKAR in this lecture.
We are also going to talk about the XIKAR or XML HTP request and we're going to talk about them.
But you can see here, this is everything that the browser is going to do, right?
So this is it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.