Hi, everyone, in this that we are going to implement a note playing function for our piano on.
All right, so first things first, let's go ahead and let's grab the elements that we want to work
with.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab all of our keys by their shared class, which is the key.
So this key is shared among all of our key elements.
So I'm just going to go ahead and grab them by that first.
So we are going to say query selector.
All the reason for that is there are more than one.
And then after that, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the Black Keys and I'm going to say
document.
Not do not track document that query selector.
And we are going to say dot, dot, block.
Now, the reason that I've done this and there is no space is because space is a descendant selector
and whenever you use a descendant selector, it means that the following clause, which in this case
is Bluck, is a child of the key clause.
But that is not true.
The block is not a child.
Both of those classes, they belong to the same element.
So in that case, you should not provide a space there.
All right.
So I'm just going to say, can't you know what?
I'm just going to copy this for here.
And we are going to grab the block key word and we are going to say control and replace it with the
white.
So now we have successfully grabbed this now before going forward.
I'm just going to go ahead and cancel that log.
Our kids, because I want to see what is that?
Come on, Soledad, look, I just want to see our kids what this is going to return in the world of
JavaScript, so let's go ahead and open and inspect.
And when we come here, we see that we have 12 items.
The index starts from zero, and we end up with what we end up with a node list.
So we have returned successfully in node list.
All right.
So this is going to give us a novelist with a lot of methods and properties that we can apply.
Basically, this is how JavaScript works.
You select something through the selectors.
It doesn't matter whether it's query selector or document that get element by something.
Whatever the selector is, as long as you select that.
All right.
And then you can consider log it see in the console what what it what it entails, what it what it consists
of.
Very difficult sentence, believe me.
And then according to that, you perform some sort of operation.
So basically, this is how Dom works in JavaScript.
And these are the things that mostly we are we are doing whenever we are making our websites too dynamic.
So in here, so there are two ways of playing this piano.
The first way is like clicking and the second way is like pressing keys.
So I want to implement functionality for this piano in both of the ways.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's take care of the clicking.
So for clicking, we are going to use an event listener and we are going to listen for a click because
there are more than one element element or more than one key.
We need some sort of loop to loop over these keys.
And the most popular is for each and whenever the each runs.
So what I'm going to do, I'm just going to go back and come here now.
And here it says performs the specified action for each node in a list and then in a list.
Right.
So this is going to perform like an action for a specified number.
So depending on which one, which constant or on which variable you apply for each day for each action
is going to be changed because now we have a node list.
And but in here it says an array because this is inside here it works like an array.
But if I remove that and if I click because the keys was a node less, that is going to perform an action
on a node in a list.
Right.
So in here we are going to run a function provided with a parameter of key and this is going to be the
loop variable as well.
We are going to grab the key and we are going to say add event listener.
The event, the Intellisense doesn't work because this is misspelled.
All right, so it is an event listener, and this is another quick way of knowing whether you have misspelled
something or not.
And whenever we click, we are going to run a function.
Now, in here, we could write the function itself and we could also use our error function.
So I can just go ahead and do this.
And this is going to work as well.
So here we are going to run a function which is called plane note and we are going to pass in the parameter.
All right.
So now we have not created this plane out function.
So we are going to create this plane out function.
And the the parameter is going to be key in here.
We have passed this for each variable as an argument to this plane out function.
So now whenever this any of these keys is collect this function, this plane load function is going
to run.
So what do we want to run inside this plane of function?
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a variable and I'm going to call it note
audio.
You and I'm going to say it should be document now in here, I'm going to use our get element by idea
that get aliment by IED.
And now what we are going to do is we are going to grab the IEDs for these ideas.
So what are we going to do is I'm going to say grab these IEDs dynamically.
I do not want to grab this seat and I'm going to take a moment here and I'm going to explain this,
why this is going to happen and why we should do it this way.
Because if I just go ahead and if I grabbed the IED for, let's say, the cenote, then it doesn't matter
what the user process.
The user is always going to hear this cenote sound all right.
But we don't want that.
We want whenever the user clicks on any these corresponding keys, we want to be able to hear the sound
for that for that specific key which has been pressed.
We do not want to hear one sound for all of the keys that are being pressed.
That's why we are going to grab the IED dynamically.
And in here I'm going to pass in key and inside the key, we are going to grab the data set, which
is a property.
Right.
And from there, we're going to grab the note.
All right, let's save it, so let's go ahead and let's consider log this step by step so we can understand
what we have done.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's consider log the key.
So I'm going to zoom out because this piano is quite large.
So it doesn't matter if I if I'm zooming zoomed in or not because I need this console to be open.
So if I click on any key, this event is going to be fired and this event for this event is going to
call this playing out function.
And this plan planet function is going to be called.
And this plan would function is going to only implement this concept, the lock.
So click on it.
We are going to see this.
The C note has been clicked.
This is the C because this is the first key in here.
All right.
So if I click on this, which we get D, then click on this, we get E, so each time I click on any
of these, we are going to get a different key.
And this is exactly what we have done.
This is exactly what we want to do.
All right.
This is exactly what we want to do in here.
Whenever the user clicks on any of these keys, we want to grab that key and we want to play the audio.
Associated with that key, this is going to be it for this lecture, we are going to pick up where we
left off in the next lecture.
See you guys then.