Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we're going to go over closing over variables.
All right, so in this example, we are going to talk about the idea that closure is about capturing
values, but closure doesn't have anything to do with values at all.
Right.
As a matter of fact, if you don't close over a value, there is no such thing as closing over a value.
So in here, what we have is we have a let.
We have a verbal declaration in here.
And this is movie.
The Revenant.
All right.
But if I go ahead and run this code, we can see that Django Unchained, Unchained, where is this coming
from?
So we can see that this council log is right here.
Right.
And it is going to look for this movie, for this movie variable.
It cannot find it within this scope.
All right.
So what it is going to do is it's going to travel outside this scope.
But when it travels outside the scope, it is going to grab this value because this is the latest declaration,
the latest very valuable declaration that we have in here by the name of a movie.
It's like we have declared a movie here, but we have reassigned it to something else in here and it
is going to grab this.
OK, the reason for that is that the function call comes after this movie, right?
So if I were to copy this function call and put it in here, we could see that The Revenant is called
from number eight.
We can see that we're OK.
So, yeah, here is line number five, The Revenant, and then from line number five, Django Unchained.
OK, so closure doesn't have anything to do with the with the value for that variable.
It is just looking for that variable.
That's why it is closing over or closing over a variable.
All right.
It is a code based operation, but it is closing over a variable.
Now, let's go ahead and let's tackle another example.
And this is going to be example number four, and for this, I'm just going to comment about both of
the both of these function calls.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to go ahead and copy this example and put it right here.
And I'm going to uncommented now before I save it.
What do you think is going to happen here right now?
Think of this like you have, for example, multiple handwritten handlers to an array of buttons, for
example, and this function that is being created in each iteration.
And it has the appearance that what it is doing is closing over the the I value in each iteration,
because here we are calling the event the value for that.
So we have said before, I should go all the way to less than three and then we're going to increment
I by one equal to less equal or less than three.
And then each time the eye is iterates over this over this loop, over the slope, it is going to grab
one one value.
So it's going to be one, two or it is going to be three.
Right.
And that value is going to be passed in here.
It means that the first function is going to be called after one second.
The second function is going to be called after two seconds and then three seconds.
And each time we should be able to see the eye variable itself and the value for that I variable rate
and will logically, we should be able to see one eye two and three.
Right.
But when I run it.
What we can see is we just see I'm just going to zoom in and we just see that we have three iterations
and just going to, you know, increase this.
So it is really a really visible.
We don't need that big of Vasko window so we can see that this eye variable with a value of four has
run four, four, three times, even though it says that the eye goes less than equal or less than three.
Why do we have for so first off, I'm just going to explain to you guys why we have four here, and
then I'm going to tell you why why it has run.
This code has run three times.
Why don't we see one, then eye two and then three?
Why we don't see.
So first of why the eye variable has a value for the reason for that is four is the value for the final
iteration.
So when the eye is what we are going to check it against this condition and when this condition is going
to is going to be true, we are going to run this code after this code runs.
We are going to increment it by one.
Now, the eye is two, so I equals two and two is less than three.
So this condition is true.
And then we are going to run this code and then after the code is run, we are going to increment the
Ibai by one.
So now this is three, this condition is still true because it says less than or equal to three, and
then we are going to run this this coat and then excuse me, then we are going to increment the eye
by one, which is four.
And when we compare it to this condition, we evaluated to this condition or we compare, I think compare
is a better word, then this condition is no longer going to be true.
But the eye, the disvalue for the eye variable is what the value the final value that the eye variable
got was for.
I know that this code didn't run.
If this code were to run, we wouldn't see three iterations, we would see four iterations.
But the final value for the eye because we incremented it was four.
That's why we see four.
And why do we need why do we see that?
If I has been repeated three times, why don't we see one eye two and three?
OK, so we are expecting it to print out equal to one eye, equal to two and equal to three.
But when we run it, it it prints out four, four and four.
Right.
Why?
Because there is only one eye variable.
That's why now there is an eye variable rate and it is here on line 18.
OK, there is only one eye variable but and there is only one of them.
OK, so we don't have like any eye variable and then we have a variable or we have another variable.
Right.
And we have three functions.
How many functions do we have?
We have three functions, even though this is one function.
But it is going to be it is going to run four, three times.
So we end up with three functions.
Now, if you wanted to have three separate values, how many variables do we need?
We need three variables, right?
We only have one variable that is in here.
OK, so of course, it can only have one value.
And in this case, it is going to have the value that occurs at the end of the loop, which is the value
for we can't effectively use closure until we I just I just want to go over the theory first and then
we are going to solve this problem in two different cases.
Now, I want to say that we cannot effectively, effectively use closure until we separate ourselves
from that, from that perception of capturing values.
It is not capturing a value, but preserving access to a variable.
OK, so if we wanted to solve this problem and and we analyzed that, I need separate variables, we
have seen several multiple different examples of how to create variables.
Now, if you want to create more than more than one variable with the same name, we need to make new
scope's.
Right.
So we could do an iffy here.
But they are much more common way now that we have ESX, now that we have blocks scoping.
And you know, what I want I'm talking about is to just stick a block scope declaration and the iteration.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this.
I'm just going to copy it and I'm going to comment it out.
I'm going to say example five, let's face it here, so in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going
to create a variable J and I'm going to set it to I and then we are going to grab J in here, I in here
and we are going to pass J there.
And I'm going to pass in here as well.
So now if I were to save this, we're going to see J one J two and we're going to create three now.
So now the letter J.
This part is going to run every time for the loop, every time the loop iterates and it is going to
create a whole new J variable.
In that whole new iteration of that loop, excuse me, so each time this loop runs, we are going to
create a whole new variable and therefore we get the values which are one, two and three.
We see the difference between capturing a value and closing over a variable, but there is we can say
that there was an even better way of solving this problem because that perpetual problem of undoing
for var I in here and then my closure, closure's aren't capturing values.
All right.
So ESX has is six has solved this problem by saying that if you use Aulet on your for a loop we will
automatically create a new life for each iteration.
OK, and instead of creating just one that belongs to the whole for a loop here, there is going to
be a brand new eye for each iteration.
So let's go over that.
Let's see how that's going to work.
I'm just going to comment that part out.
And I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say why they're right.
For example, sex.
Let's face the code in here.
All right.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to change this far to let and when I save it.
We see one eye two and a three now each of these iterations is going to be printed after exactly one
second.
So this takes one second.
And when this is printed after another second, this is printed and then this is printed.
And we can see that each time each time we have a different eye variable because they are they have
different values.
Now, what does that mean?
It means that closure just magically works.
OK, so the point is, if you need multiple different values being closed over, you need multiple different
variables.
You need to close over different variables and not try to capture different values.
So we just saw that.
How close in the past in the previous letter, we saw how close your works actually what closure is
and how it works and why it works.
And in here, we just solved a problem that with that was created with VA and we just solved it, Willette.
And now we know how we solved it.
The reason that we solved it is whenever we stick this let into the scope, it is going to create a
brand new.
Variable, each time this for loop runs, it is some it is something that you want whenever you're creating
for loops.
That's why you passan let I be passing the little keyword, right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture and also for this chapter.
See you guys in the next chapter.
We finally we will start talking about object oriented programming, and I'm super, super excited for
that.
See you guys then.