Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to implement the functionality of this project.
All right.
So and the first thing that I'm going to grab, the first HTML element that I am going to grab are are
going to be actually our sections.
And I'm going to say document dot, query selector all because we have more than one section as I want
this to be like accessible.
Whenever you want to create your website, whatever you want to incorporate it in your website, then
I should I should say all sections, because definitely in your website you're going to have more than
one section, right?
And we are going to grab them by their element names, which is section, and then I'm going to grab
our our chance as well.
This is the dif the empty diff for which we have that background color.
This is actually the background color of the death for which we have that background color.
And we are going to say document that query, select tau, not all just simple query selecter.
And what is the class name.
It is trance like transition, that sort of thing.
I couldn't come up with a better name.
And then we are going to have an array of our gradients for which I'm not going to type out.
The array of the color names are really difficult to type.
I'm just going to post it here with Korrell Char to use I think chocolate and we have created blue.
Let's save it.
So we have selected our sections, the the thing that we want to transition and the color that we want
to transition with that thing.
All right, so what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to create a constant and it is going
to have a value, the constant name is going to be options.
And this is going to be an object because I want to give it a threshold and the threshold is going to
be zero point seven.
And you might ask, OK, what is this?
What is you know, what the option is?
You know what the object is?
What is what is the threshold?
The threshold basically specifies where we are in that section to be able to see that.
Come on, buddy, where we are in that section to make sure that that chance is actually flipping from
home to about.
So whenever we go to almost 70 percent of that section, see, so almost 70 percent.
Come on, buddy.
And now this is almost so from here to here, we are almost in the 30 percent of this section, so when
70 percent of the section is passed, we are going to switch from one color to the next.
And so this is the four full 100 percent.
If we come down here.
So round about here, we should be able to see the color switch.
And there we go round about there.
And in this image, we should see it round about this this line in here.
So round about here, we should see the color switch.
And this is the threshold that we give it to see.
And when we go up, it is basically the same thing.
So this actually means that before reaching that section, we want to change the the the we want to
switch the image before reaching that.
So if I put it to point nine and seven and then when we come here, we are going to go really, really
close to that section, then it is going to switch.
So before it's switched here, but now it switches here.
So this is completely up to you where you want to put it.
This is why we have a threshold.
This basically says where we are in the page and in that section, where do we want to change it?
Now, we have created our threshold.
Let's go ahead and let's use it.
So I'm going to say that observer equal to this is our observer pattern.
And we are going to see a new intersection, observer, inter section observer.
This is our intersection observer.
And now in here, we are going to pass in two arguments.
This is the intersection observer.
It does exactly what the name says.
It is looking for any intersection.
And when it grabs that intersection, when it finds the intersection, it is going to do something with
it.
And what is it that is what what is it that this is going to do with that?
And for that, we are going to implement a function.
And another argument is going to be our options object.
So this options object is called in here as well.
And now this is a function this is our NAV scroll function and this is the thing that this intersection
observer is going to implement.
So now let's go ahead and let's create our function.
So this is the function name is going to be enough scroll.
All right, and I'm going to give it and a parameter of interest.
Now, what do we want with that dysfunction?
Do so whenever we scroll up and down, we have multiple sections.
So the ideology is that we have more than one section.
Whenever we scroll up and down, we want to switch the background color for these links.
Right.
So basically what we want is we want to create a for each loop because we are dealing with more than
one section.
Whenever we're dealing with more than one element or one thing, then we are going to create a for each
loop.
So this is going to be our forest for each loop and then we are going to give our for each loop a variable,
I'm just going to call it entry.
And whenever this entry variable loops over these sections, what do I want to do?
So first things first.
I just want to go ahead and I want to consider log the same entry.
So now we can see what is actually the nature of this loop variable.
So we are going to come here and I'm just going to do this.
So there are next to each other and we can, I think, know we are going to need the full with.
So if we come here and go to the console, we don't have anything.
So if we come here, come down, we still don't get anything.
We should get something I mean, let's go ahead and let's open it with Life Server, we should see something
in the console.
Life reload is enabled and we don't see anything in the console.
That's KLECK.
And I think we need more code.
This is this function is going to run.
This is the concept of lock.
All right, so.
I'm going to reload it one more time.
And let's go to our console and we should see something whenever we cross the intersection so we have
our function, the function name is Snarf Scroll and the parameter is entreats entries that for which
we run a function and the function parameter is entry, which is the loop variable, and we log the
entry.
So whenever we scroll the front the sections, we should see something here.
But oh, the problem is here that this foreach this entry, it has no idea that it should observe something.
Now this observer has no idea that it should observe.
So we are going to say sections dot for each.
All right.
We are going to add another for each year.
And when the foreach runs, we want each section to receive the following code or to do the following
thing.
And we want to grab what is grip.
It's like Øvrebø.
We want to grab our observer and we want to tell it to observe.
Now, this is remaining because it's not actually observing our sections.
Whenever it observes the sections, then it is going to log something and we are going to use this information.
So I'm going to trash it.
So if I go up, if I go down, we are going to see a lot of information here and we are going to go
over this information.
All right.
And what information or what kind of information from here we are going to use.
So I'm going to just go ahead and we need one of that.
So if I click here now, you guys can see where we actually get the bounding plates rectangle, which
which actually gives us the X Y the with a lot of information in here which which actually we're going
to use in our gallery carousel, this method.
All right.
And then we have intersection ratio, intersection rectangle is intersecting true.
It is intersecting.
We are going to use this is intersecting at the end in this function, in this nouf scroll function.
But what do we want to see.
What what is it that we want to grab?
This is actually what we want to grow.
This is the target.
So whenever we cross any any element, we are going to grab a target for that.
So let me try it and let's come down so we can get only one.
So now we got this one.
So if I come here, it's a section at home because this is the section, the home section that we are
crossing.
So if I come down, we are going to get another one, which is actually this should be the section Daraban.
So this is what we are looking for.
So it is the entry, the target.
It is the target property that we want.
And what is the class name for that target property.
Let's come here, let's find out the class name.
So the class name is about we are going to grab this class name because whenever the class name is about,
we want to add a background image to it.
So we are going to grab our entry and we are going to say grab the target and inside, oops, I should
not be there.
This is an entry.
When it is, we are going to grab the entry and we are going to say the target property and from there
the class name.
And we are going to store this inside a variable of concept class name as well.
So we are just going to call it class and we are going to store it inside here because we are going
to use this class it that said for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one where we continue making our Navar effect.