Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create the password input event listener.
All right, so first things first, we need to select three things from the e-mail, and it's those
three things that we have created.
So we need to select, B, strengthen.
The text input and the password check, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to say const consed and
I'm going to call it string thir.
All right, and I'm going to say document that query selector.
Query selector, and it has a class of strength.
Right, and after that.
What I want to do is I want to select the password input, surpass password input.
OK, so the password input, we are going to select it using the type, so we are going to say it is
an input.
And it has a type.
Make sure you spell it correctly so it has a type of what is the type of this?
It has a type of pass.
No, it doesn't have a type of password.
The reason that I didn't provided with the type of password is because if I type something, you're
not going to be able to see it.
So it just has a type of text.
So we are going to pass and text messaging.
This is smaller.
I think we can work with that.
OK, and finally, we have our password check, so.
I'm going to say password check and the class name is going to be password dash check.
Now we have selected our items, the event, the input event.
Of course, it is going to be on the input.
So we are going to say password, not check input dart at a wellness center.
And we are listening for what?
For an input event.
And when the input event is fired, we want to run a function.
So it is update strength.
This is the update.
Strength, function, strength.
Right.
Which I'm not going to create here.
I'm going to created as a stand alone function declaration.
So I'm going to say function, update, strengthen.
Now, they're not going to be any parameter.
All right.
But what I'm going to do here inside, first things first, I want to create an assessment variable.
Now, the assessment variable is going to assess our password.
We are going to have multiple different assessments, assets, assessment functions for for example,
for the length of the password, for the whether the password has uppercase characters, lowercase characters,
whether it includes numbers or special characters.
So each one of those is going to be a different assessment function.
So in here, what I want to do is I want to create I want to call a function that is calculate password,
pass word strength.
All right.
So this is going to be a different function that we are going to call here inside this and we are going
to put the value inside this variable.
And this calculate password strength is going to be the function that is going to that is going to house
all of our assessments.
Right.
So from this function, what do I need?
I want to grab the password.
Input value, so whatever the password input that value is, I want to grab it from this function and
then let's go ahead.
And that's, for example, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say let strength write, not strengthen.
I'm going to say that strength and I'm going to set it equal to 100.
I'm going to comment it out for now.
So now what I want to do here is that I want to grab our password check.
And I want to say in our e-mail, all right, first off, I want to set it to nothing in case there
is something we don't want to put into anything.
The passwords check is this area right here.
And after that, we are going to grab our assessment because this calculate password function, password
strength function is going to give us more than one assessment.
Or to be accurate, it is going to give us an array so we can call for each method on it.
And each time we call this method, we are going to pass in an assessment, so assess and I should probably
write this as assessments and this one, this is going to be an individual assessment.
And what do we want to do with this assessment?
So first things first.
We want to check if the assessment is if the assessment is zero, if the user hasn't put and hasn't
hasn't typed anything inside that password password fields, if the user doesn't type anything, we
just want to return from this function.
We don't want to run it.
All right.
So we need to always check for whether there is something.
So I'm going to say equal to null.
If it is null, then we want to return.
So simply we are going to say return otherwise.
So let's come down here.
Otherwise, what do I want to do, I want to grab our strength.
Strength and I want to remove from it the strength.
All right, the based on the assessment.
So this is how it is going to work.
We are going to receive an assessment and then we are going to pass in a strength that we lose, which
I'm going to call it strength lost.
And I want to remove it from that strength variable that we have created here.
So the strength is going to be originally 100 when the strength is originally 100.
Now we are going the other direction with this application.
So we are not going to start from zero to 100.
We're actually encoding.
We are going to start from 100 to zero.
So we assume that the strength is 100 when there is no password and when the user types something,
the strength is going to get decreased and we are going to increase it once more when the password has
insufficient, sufficient assessments.
So we are going to set assessment date strength.
Strength lost, we have not created the strength lost we are going to create.
Don't worry about it may not be in this lecture, but we are definitely going to create it in the next
lecture.
And then we are going to say, conse, let's create another variable.
And then now I want to create the password check aliment, the elements that you sign here, those paragraphs
for which we already have the stuff.
So I'm going to call it WD check e l element and I'm going to call it document that creates element.
We know how we can create an element, so create element.
What is the element.
Just passing the tag name, which is P and then what do we want to do.
We want to grab that P WD check element and we want to say enter HTML.
What is the inner ystem are going to be the average HTML is going to be our assessment.
Dot, from the assessment, what do we want to grab?
So now the assessment so far, we know that it has one property, it has strength lost.
What is the assessments?
Other property that it is going to have?
It is going to be W.D. Check.
It is going to have a check property as well.
We are going to create a don't worry about it.
So it is not E-L.
We are just going to pass it p check.
All right.
And then we are going to grab our passport check and we are going to have a child.
Whenever you create an element, you have to find a parent that adopts that element.
So what do we want to pass?
And we want to pass in the check p.
D check password's check aliment.
Right.
And finally.
So now this for each is completed.
Each time the user does something into something, enters and input, all these assessments are going
to run.
They're going to take a look at them.
All right.
And we are going to grab this strengthen.
I say style, OK, dot set property, so set property.
What is that we want to set the property to say, don't you remember that we have a a custom Cyesis
variable and it is right here.
And what is the variable name?
The variable name is strength amount.
We want the value for this strength amount to initially be zero and then we want to dynamically change
it based on something the user type.
So I'm going to grab that.
So we are going to put it right here and I'm going to sit I'm going to put it there, and then we are
going to pass on our strength.
Now, the strength variable is created here.
We have we have subtracted from the strength, the strength that we have lost.
All right.
And then we want to pass that strength, value for which property that we have for the strength amount
property that we have already created here.
So that value is going to come right here and is going to be multiplied by the one percent and then
we are going to get our high.
This is how we get this dynamic right.
So we are done with this function.
I know it is not working.
It's not going to do anything.
In fact, let's go let's open this council and let's see if we have any errors.
So far, we don't have any errors and should make this one a little bit bigger.
And let's zoom out a little bit and.
Okay.
So now everything should be working properly, zoom up and go up.
So what we are going to do in the next lecture is working to create this calculate password's strength
function.
And after that, we are going to pass in our assessments function.
So again, we have different assessments for different criteria of this application that we want for
this form input that we want, which we are going to start creating in the next slide, starting next
lecture.
And all of them, all of these I'm going to be explaining along the way.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.