Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to implement the read text functionality.
All right, all right, so first off, as with any other JavaScript project that we have created, we
are going to select the elements that we will be interacting with through JavaScript.
So the first one that I want to select is going to be text display, and this is going to be our text
area.
So we're going to say document that query selector and it has an idea of text.
The next thing that I want to select is Consed, come on buddy consed, it is going to be the speed
BTN or a button are going to say document dot query selector.
It has an idea of speed, not like the movie.
All right.
And what is this.
I do not want it that way.
Then we have our red button read between.
You know what, I'm just going to remove this.
Right, let's remove it, let's copy it three times, one more time, so we are going to say this is
going to be read, right?
But this is a class I'm just going to provide it for all three of them.
The next one is going to be Paw's.
OK, and finally, we have to stop, all right, so what I'm going to do is what what is it that we
want to do here?
So first off, let's open this one life server, and that's.
Come on, buddy.
All right.
So we say that whenever we type something here and when we click on the read button, it should read
it.
OK, it means that we want to click on the read button or we need an event listener.
So I'm going to say reading functionality, right.
I'm going to say a reading functionality.
And we are going to grab a read button and we are going to add a listener.
And the event that we are listening for is going to be a click, of course.
And when that happens, we are going to run a function.
OK, so what is the function going to do?
The function is going to call another read text function.
And as arguments inside this function call, they're going to pass in our text display because we want
an updated value value.
All right.
So now let's come down here and let's create that read text function.
So we are going to say read text, text function.
OK, retakes function, so let's see how we can do it so we already know the name, which is read text
and we know the the we know that we have one argument inside the function call.
So for that argument, we need to provide a parameter, a parameter.
The parameter that I want to provide here is going to be text.
Right.
So this is going to be text.
Let's open up the function and in here, before even writing anything in the function function, we
need to take a look at something that is called speech synthetics utterance.
And I'm going to paste in the euro right here and it is not going to take long.
So speech, synthetic, synthetic utterance, interface of the Web speech API.
So now we are working with the Web speech.
API represents a speech request.
It contains the content.
It contains the content, the speech service should read and information on how to read it.
Right, so first off, what we are going to do here is.
We are going to create a constant so I'm going to say const.
And I'm going to call it utterance.
All right, you can call it anything you want.
And in here, we need to create we need to request a speech Santarus, OK?
And through that, we can make the computer readout, our text.
And to be able to request that we are going to we are going to say speech Santarus.
Utterance, right, and just just like that, so we have requested that and we have stored it inside
this utterance and now through this utterance variable, we can grab methods of this speech synthesis
utterance.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come in here and I'm going to say utterance, utterance, dot
text.
Right now, this is a property of the speech, synthetic utterance that is available to us.
And it says, Rantes, that utterance, that text equal to some sort of string.
What is that string that we want the computer to order out to us?
That is going to be equal to our parameter that we have passed right here.
Right.
So I could go ahead and change this a little bit up.
Change, change, change it up.
So this is not confused with this property.
We could change it.
Text, text, or should I call it a bit difficult to not lose the meaning.
So it's going to be test text
Ruden test.
I'm just going to call it test.
Test text.
I think it's not a problem.
All right, so after that, we have specified what we want our our insurance to do, what do we want
it to do now before going there?
What I want to do here is I want to consult.
I want to log to the console, our utterance and let's take a look at it.
What is it what is it exactly that we have here?
So let's go inspect and let's go into console.
So we are inside the console.
All right.
And if I click on the read button, we are going to see here, it says speech, synthetics, utterance.
We have text.
We have rate rate is negative one.
All right.
By default rate is the speed at which the computer is going to speak is going to be speaking.
So the text is as an empty string.
The text is something that we provided as developers or at the end user is going to provide it.
And we are going to be working with the range, with the right rate as well.
We don't want this pitch or the voice or anything else.
So we whenever we use speech, then that is utterance.
There are a set of properties and methods like any other object.
As you guys can see, this is an object.
Like any other object.
We have a set of properties and methods that are available to us that will be available to us as soon
as we specify speech.
And that is utterance that we can use inside our application.
That's where this text is coming from.
We use the dot notation to access the properties or methods of a specific object that we want to work
with.
Right.
So that's about that.
And let's go ahead and let's say utterance that right now.
What do I want the rate of this utterance to be?
I want it to be the speed button that we have.
So if I increase the speed button, I want the speed at which the computer speaks to be faster or slower
if I like, decrease that speed.
OK, so I'm going to say that value because we need to grab the value and in case we do not touch the
speed, we want the default to be what you guys saw that the default rate is negative one, but we want
the default to be one.
So it's either of these either of these sites.
So this is a logic.
This is an or a logical operator.
It is going to evaluate to true one side of this expression.
And if it finds even one side that is evaluated, it's true this is going to return.
True.
So we either grab the speed button's value or we set it to one.
If we do not change that value we said it to on the reason that it is one is we have specified one here.
So the minimum is zero.
Point one, the maximum extend, the step is zero.
Point one, the value is one.
That's why we specify one.
So it's either it should be one or the speed that we manually specify for it.
Right.
And I'm going to say text display dot disabled to true disabled.
I'm going to set it to trip.
And the reason that I said it's true is because this is another method that is available to us.
And whenever the computer is speaking, if I come here, for example, if I write this is a book, whenever
the computer is speaking, you can see that you cannot change the text while the computer is speaking.
That's why the text area is going to be disabled.
And finally, to make our computers speak, they are going to grab speech and that is.
And we are going to access a method called Speak Very, very simple, and inside there, we are going
to pass in our utterance.
Now that's come here.
Let's I'm going to grab our previous text.
I'm going to paste it right here and I'm going to, you know, let's decrease this to here.
The quick brown box jumps over the lazy dog.
So now this text is read aloud.
OK, that is solved.
But there are quite a lot of issues.
The first thing is that our screen, our text area is disabled.
We have disabled it, but there is no way of enabling it again.
So we have to go ahead and we have to apply that functionality.
And also the pause button, the stop button, none of them work.
So let's see if the speed works or let's put it to four point seven.
There was nothing to write there.
I'm going to pasted there and put this to seven clicks.
So the speed definitely works.
But still, there are other issues that we need to fix, which we are going to do in our next lecture.
See you guys then.