Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to implement the vertical and horizontal position manipulation.
All right, so before being able to apply all these logic, what we have to do is first we have to select
the block and then we are going to select our because what we want to do here is whenever we change
these whenever we change this range, we want this block to move.
So first things first.
We are going to select this block.
And secondly, we are going to select this position y range slider and this position X range slider.
All right.
So coming in here, right.
I'm going to do this.
I'm going to say let and I'm going to call the block block.
Right.
I could also say block Elliman, just to differentiate between the actual ID name and the variable name
that we create in JavaScript.
Now let's go ahead and get selected.
Now, if I come into the e-mail, OK, let's expand these as well.
Now, this blog has an idea of blog.
So what I'm what I can do is I can just say get element by ID or I can just do our our very overused
query selector.
Right.
So there is actually no difference.
So I'm just going to go ahead and query selector and we are going to put in the numbers sine or hash
sign for the ID.
Now we have successfully selected that.
Now after this I'm going to select our horizontal position range slider and the vertical position range
slider.
So I'm just going to call him those vertical position.
All right.
Very generic name.
We're going to say document a query selector.
By now, you're very familiar with this process of selecting and then implementing some sort of functionality
on elements.
And there was actually no need for me to, like, make you go through all these selections.
But this is a good habit because we are in the early chapters.
This is Chapter 23 and because there is a lot more coming.
That's why I'm saying that we are in the early chapters of this course and we should get as many as
much practice as we can.
All right, and I'm going to selected by its I.D. and we are going to save position dash Y for the position
X, I'm just going to copy it down below and I'm going to put it to X and we are going to say this as
per position.
Horizontal Hari's on.
So, all right, the next thing that I want to do is now there are a lot more select tourists that we
have to do here.
But I'm going to I'm going to write those variables whenever we get to those specific sections.
But in this lecture, what I want to do is I want to grab the vertical and horizontal positioning and
I want to apply dynamic, dynamic ness to it or functionality to it.
So I'm just going to put in a comment here and I'm going to say vertical position changer.
Right.
Direct opposition, right?
Yes, I guess so.
So we are going to grab the vertical position now.
What is this vertical position?
The vertical position is the vertical range slider that we have right here.
So this input, which has a type of range, has an idea of position, Nashwa.
And we have selected it right here.
This is where it is selected.
So we have selected that and we are going to say that event listener.
OK, now the event that we are we are listening for is not a click event because we are talking about
rain.
Slider's, the event is going to be a change event.
Right.
And whenever that event is fired, we are going to run a function.
What does the function is going to do?
The function is going to do one very basic thing.
The function is going to change the position of that specific block.
So in here, I'm going to grab our block element and I'm going to tap into the Cyesis world and we are
going to say that a right to top it always does that.
And we are going to grab the vertical position, OK?
They're going to grab the vertical position and from there we are going to access the value and we are
going to add pixel to it.
Let's give it Skowhegan and let's see if it works.
All right.
So if I click here now, the block moves down.
If I click here, the block moves down.
Right.
Now, let's go ahead and let's cancel the log, the vertical position, that value as well so we can
see what what is it that we are actually getting so that value, let's save it and let's go into inspect
console.
So whenever I click, I should be able to see something inside the console.
Now the value is 250 and this value is pixels because we have added a pixel value at the end of it.
So the vertical positioning that it is done, we have successfully implemented that.
And this is a very, very simple project, it does a lot.
OK, there is there is a lot of things going on, but the idea and the concepts there are very, very
simple.
So let's go ahead and let's test it forward and backward.
Yes, it works.
So the next thing that I want to do is I want to.
Implement the horizontal position changer horizontal.
Very difficult to spell.
I want to implement this in this lecture as well.
So we are going to grab the horizontal position in a range and we are going to add eventless into the
event that we are listening for.
But which is which is done by the user is going to be a change event.
And after the users changes that input slider or input range, we are going to implement a function.
The function is going to grab the block element and it is going to tap into the sea assessed world and
it is going to say left.
And we are going to say horizontal position, dot value, and we are going to add a pixel unit to it
as well as well.
All right.
So now if I click here, Noguez can see that the block is moving horizontally as well as vertically.
So we could reset the position.
Right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.