Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to talk about the Nonet quality operator and these strict
nanny quality operator.
All right, so we have covered the equality, the regular double equal equality operator, and we know
that this operator does not take into consideration the time.
It only cares about the value, OK?
And when the values match, it is going to return it through.
OK, it is going to return a boolean of true.
All right.
But this strict equality, the operator or the triple equal equality operator, it not only cares about
the value, but it also cares about the time.
So even though the values are the same in this case, it is going to return.
It returned a false because the tie is not the same.
So first off, I want to talk about the non equality equal, the non equality operator, which is actually
like a sibling of this operator, OK?
It is the and we have an exclamation mark with a with an equal sign.
It is non equality.
Equality operator.
Right.
So this is the non equality operator and let's check it out in action.
You know what?
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and copy everything that we have because we we have
a set of data types that we want to mix and match and we want to compare it together.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab both of the double equals and I'm going to control the
everywhere and I'm going to replace it with this.
All right, so what does this operator actually means?
It means like this is a negative sign.
Think of it as a negative sign in mathematics.
So if if one is not equal to one, return a true if one is equal to one return, they're false.
So we know that one is equal to one.
Right.
And one is not equal to it is not not equal to one.
That's why it returns is false because this statement is actually incorrect.
This is false because one is equal to one.
OK, and when it is not equal to one, we are going to see it through.
OK.
So let's I'm just going to keep it there.
Now, this statement should also be false because it says one is not equal to one and it is incorrect
and we get a false here.
How about this one?
This one is exactly the same as the rest of the two Y because Z.
It says Z is not equal to Z, but it is equal to Z.
That's why it is going to return false.
OK, so now this one is going to return their fans as well.
How about this one?
It says false is not equal to true.
That is true.
And we get a true.
And let me do like another example here.
So it is crystal clear to you I'm going to put an X and in here it says, let's come and tell this to
in here, it says Z is not equal to X, and that is correct.
It is true.
So we should get it through.
Yeah, we did get it.
So this is false.
This is true.
And how about this one?
This should be false because it says zero is not equal to an empty string, but it is equal to an empty
string.
So we should get a false.
How about this one?
So the rest of them, which of them should be false and all of them are false.
Now, the nine equality operator acts in the same way as the equality operator, but it, like it says,
is not.
That's that's the difference.
And also, it does not care about the type, as you guys saw here.
So now let's go ahead and let's talk about the final equality operator that the final comparison operator
that we are going to discuss.
And that is the.
The strict.
The strict non.
Equality operator.
All right, so now what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab everything from here and I'm going to paste
him here and I'm going to grab all the triple equal signs and I'm going to change it with this.
And now we are going to talk about that.
So this one says that one is not equal to one neither in type nor in value.
And this statement is incorrect.
So we should see a force for this one.
So let's save it.
We see it false, right?
I'm just going to put it right here for you.
OK, maybe I should have done this for the previous ones as well.
What?
You can't do that as a challenge for yourself.
So let's come in this and.
And now it says that one is not equal to one neither in type nor in value.
OK, and this this should return.
True.
And I'm just going to put it through because because one is not equal to one.
This is number one.
This is string one.
They're not equal.
So the other the results should be true.
And we do get a true there.
The code for Minor brought them back.
So this one says that Z is not equal to Z nor in value, neither in type, which is incorrect.
Of course, we should see if this one says this one should also be false because they are equal to each
other.
This one is true because false is not equal to true, neither in type nor in value.
It is the same type, but the value is different.
All right.
So this strict equality operator, what it does is there are two conditions there and whatever either
want, even one of them is true.
Then we are going to get it.
So in this case, we should get it through because false.
This is District nine equality operator.
So false is not equal to false in value that that is that that part is correct actually.
But it is the same time.
So out of the two conditions, one of the conditions is true.
So we should get it through here.
So let's say that we do get it through.
Let's take a look at this one.
It's true.
This one.
This is true.
This one true.
And this one is true.
So that said, for our comparison operators, starting from our next year, we are going to talk about
how we can control the flow of logic, the flow of code inside and our inside our applications through
if statements.
See you guys in the next lecture.