Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we will set up our game canvas and the canvas context.
A ride, so in the stadium, if we go over this team, we just we have linked our script in the CSIS.
We have a reset, basic stalling for the body just for that background color and overflow of hidden
also with just the center of our canvas element.
So now let's go ahead.
And we are starting from a very from an empty file.
So we will be typing everything.
OK, so first thing, I want to create our game parameters.
So parameters.
So first off, let's go ahead and specify a height for our game, which I'm going to put it to 750,
then let's go ahead and let's create the grid size.
The grid size is going to be 10.
Then I'm going to create a constant 40 frames per second.
Now, we are used to using.
The request animation, from the reason that I'm putting this AFPs here is not that I'm going to use
this set interval, it is because of that delay that you see after either the game is is one or the
game is you're going to see a delay and then a new game is going to start.
This is just for that.
It's not for a requesting animation.
French.
So we are going to have a delay and that is going to be delay end and it is going to be two seconds.
So it's going to be seconds until a new game starts.
After that, we are going to have some derived dimensions.
Derived dimensions are the kind of dimensions that are based on something else.
So first off, let's go ahead on this half hour with so the width is going to be high times zero point
nine, then we are going to have the cell size, which is going to be the width divided by grid size
plus two.
This is the size of the cell plus the left and right margin.
Right.
Next up, we are going to create the stroke.
The stroke is going to be the cell size divided by 12.
All right, and.
Let's create the constant for the dots as well, so constant dot, it is going to be equal to the size
of the stroke that we have and we are going to create our margin as well.
So consed margin now this margin is going to be the top margin so we can create that score the names
on whenever the game ends, like the game over text as well.
So it is going to be the height, minus the great size, plus one times the size of cell.
Perfect.
Now I'm going to create some colors as well, so let's say.
Colors.
We are going to have Consed, first off, the color of the board, I'm going to call it color board
and it is going to be hash zero f three zero five seven.
And I'm going to copy this a bunch of times because we are going to have a color for border.
So color border and the color for the border is simple.
It is going to be yellow, then we are going to have a color for the dot.
And the color for the date is going to be white.
Then we have our color eye or color player one, and that is going to be orange.
And this is going to be color a high, I'm just going to put it I.
Then we are going to have a color for the ehi light and the light color is that color.
Whenever you hover over it, you can see you're going to get the light.
And when you click, you're going to get the like the dark, darker version of it.
And that is going to be a najiba.
So RGV and 255 166 zero zero point three of Alpha Channel, then we are going to have the same kind
of format.
So I'm just going to get rid of this, the same format for the player.
So first off, we are going to have let me just grab that.
We are going to have player player color and then the color player light.
So it is going to be Lorne Green and the lighter version is going to be a lighter version of it.
Basically has some alpha channel.
I haven't done anything else to it.
So it is going to be one and six to fifty, two to fifty to zero and zero point three.
And finally we are going to have a color for tie whenever it is a tie.
So and that color is going to be white.
And that is going to be whenever you see that on the screen, it says draw, it is going to be that
color.
So let's go ahead and let's actually create our canvas.
So canvas, this letter is basically dedicated to setting up our game, first off.
And this canvas is going to be created dynamically.
Meaning that we are not going to create it in the e-mail, we will be creating it in the japes and we
will be refreshing the page and each time the page refreshes, we will be creating this canvas all over
again.
That's actually the ideology behind it.
So canvas element is going to be a document to create element.
What is the name of the element that is canvas?
We need a height for the canvas.
So we are going to say canvas element does height and it is going to be the height that we have specified
above.
We will be needing a width for the canvas.
So canvas element with and it is going to be the width that we have created up above.
Let's go ahead and let's provide the canvas with a parent.
So we are going to say append child.
And let's pass on the name of the element, the name of the variable for that element, which is canvas
element, and I'm going to initialize a canvas rectangle, a context as well.
And that is going to give me all the like dimensions, the coordinates for the canvas, the top left,
the whenever I hover on the canvas, I need to get the exact points.
And that is a familiar method and that is get bounding clent rect, which is going to give us all the
coordinates that we require.
So we are done with the canvas.
And I'm going to grab let's go ahead and let's grab the context and I'm going to call it Conex canvas
element to get context.
The context that we will be getting is 2D.
We are drawing this game in 2D, we are creating it in 2D.
So it should be 2D.
The line with is going to be.
Stroke we'll be using this line with I'm just going to create it right here, and then we are going
to have a text, a line for whenever any of the players they score or they create a box, they're going
to have like that alignment of the text within the box that these alignments, they belong to those.
So text align.
It is going to be center and Conex start a text baseline.
It's going to be metal.
Perfect.
So right after that, what do we have to do next is I'm going to go over the game, the loop itself.
So the way that in our previous game we had the comment pattern that we had in our previous game, I'm
going to do the same thing here.
So I'm going to I will be creating a longer, like Dasht comment and then the name of the whatever it
is that we are creating.
So it is going to be the game loop and I'm going to maybe like just make it a bit stand out.
I'm going to add stars there.
So I'm going to create a function and I'm going to call it a play game exactly like what we had in our
previous game.
The play game is going to request the animation from the requested animation frame is going to play
this function 60 times per one second because the screen refresh rate of my computer is sixty hertz.
It is either 30 or 60.
But there are I believe there are some mobile phones.
Who is refresh rate is 120.
So imagine how smooth something would run on a smartphone.
Would that would that sort of refresh rate we are going to pass in our game loop as a as an argument
here.
So we have created our game loop here.
The next thing that I would like to do, as I would like to go ahead and actually draw our board so
we can see something on the screen.
So first off, I want to come down here and I'm going to call a function draw board.
Perfect.
And let's go ahead and let's actually draw that.
So let's grab this comment.
Should save this so everything is fine.
Let's actually open this up with Life Server.
All right, so this is our game, this is what we will be building.
I'm going to open up the console in case there are any errors.
So we have to fix them.
All right, so let's come down, let's grab this comment.
And let's put it down here, and I'm going to change it to the draw board function, perfect.
So now let's go ahead on this, actually draw our board.
So let's think what it is that we will be needing for the board.
So we will be needing a color, of course, then some coordinates and then actually we have to draw
the right.
So first off, let's actually give it the color.
So function draw board.
And we're going to say, let's grab our context and Phil style, the style is going to be the color
of the board that we have created right there.
And I'm going to get I'm going to create the border around that border as well.
So Conex that stroke's style, because that is going to be a line, right?
So stroke's style and it is going to be color border.
Let's create our border first.
So fell rect.
The exposition is going to be zero, the position is going to be zero, the width is going to be the
width of the canvas, the height is going to be the height of the canvas.
Perfect.
So now let's create the that border.
So we are going to say stroke.
The exposition is going to be stroke divided by two, Sarid divided by four.
The Y position is going to be stroke.
Also stroke divided by four.
The width is going to be the width of the canvas, minus stroke two times point five or divided by two,
and the height is going to be basically the same.
So I'm just going to copy this part.
So it's going to be hard right now whenever we increase and decrease the the width of the screen, the
width and the board are going to get increased and decreased at the same time.
So let's say that let's come here and let's come here.
So this is where we are actually drawing our board.
So.
I think let's go ahead and it's actually called the play game function down here, so I'm going to say
play a game and let's save it.
Let's come here.
There we go.
So this is the board that we have, so it is going to be directly in the middle because of that display
flex property that we have at it.
So I could keep it here and open the keep open the console right there.
This is going to be our final game.
I'm going to reset that as well.
So there we go.
Our board is drawn.
The next step that I would like to do in this lecture, because there are still 13 minutes.
I mean, we have 20 minutes.
So the next thing that I would like to do is I want to draw the grid as well in this lecture.
So let's go ahead and let's do that.
I mean, why not?
So I'm going to call a draw grid, right?
And we are going to call that function inside our game loop.
So let's say draw a grid.
Perfect, so they draw a grid function.
What do you think it is going to do?
The draw grid function is going to give us a number of columns, column dots to be accurate, and the
number of red dots, but.
It is actually going to be a bit different because now let's see, so we have 10 columns, so one,
two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
Let's count the column.
So one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10 and 11.
Right.
Why do we have 11?
Because in order for four for this box truck to work, we need an extra column of dots.
And in order for the row boxes to work, we need an extra row of dots.
So we will be adding one to our loop.
So let's go ahead and let's actually create the function draw.
Great.
All right.
And we are going to say for let I equals zero, we are going to loop over that.
I is going to go all that all all the way to great size plus one, OK, because of that extra rawhi
or extra column of dots or dots that we will be having, then we are going to increment I by one.
Now this is going to be for the for the why.
All right.
Now let's do it for the other direction as well.
So we are going to sell for let Jay.
So keep in mind that we have rows and columns, so we need to iterate over both of them.
Jay is going to start from zero, then Jay is going to go all the way to criticize plus one.
And we are going to increment by one each time.
All right, and in here, I'm actually going to call another function or another method and that is
going to be draw dot.
All right.
Within the draw dot function, we will be calling to other functions for the first one is going to be
get grid X and I'm going to pass in J.
And then we are going to say get grid Y and I'm going to pass.
And I so let's go ahead and let's actually create these other helper functions as well.
So the first function that I would like to create is going to be the draw dot function.
All right.
So within the DOT function, I'm just going to put that in there and I'm going to call this dot function,
draw dot within here.
We just want to draw a simple dot.
Now we need to pass an X and Y, all right.
Because they are Pastan as arguments.
So first off, let's go ahead and add the AFL style for a red dot.
So it is going to be filled style, the color of the dot that we have specified above.
Let's start the path.
So we are going to begin path and DOT is going to be a circle.
So we need the ARC method and we are going to pass an X and Y as the positions.
The radius is going to be the dot that we have specified above.
Starting angle is going to be zero ending angles going to mean math dot pi times two and we are going
to say fell flat dot perfect.
So we have created the dot function.
Next up, I would like to go ahead and create the Grid X and grid Y functions because they are pretty
easy as well.
So I'm going to come I'm going to bring this down a little and in here.
I'm going to grab this.
It's just I'm going to put it right here and I'm going to say get grid, get grid X.
First off, let's create that a function, get grid X.
We are going to pass and call him for that.
Right.
And we are going to say that this function is going to return return the cell size times, the column
that we have, plus one perfect.
So that this is going to be the grid X and I'm just going to copy this down below.
Just copy it down below and I'm going to say.
OK, so we are going to say that this is going to be the great wavefunction, get Broadway and we're
going to pass and row and this function is basically going to return.
There is an extra you there.
So this is going to return the margin margin.
Plus, sell.
Times the road that we have, so instead of calling plus one, we're just going to pass and row, let's
save that.
So we have our get grid X, we have our get grid Y and.
All right, so we have all these functions right here.
The grid is not drawn yet.
Because we have still some way to go to be able to see our grid, so I'm going to create our square
class first.
So I'm going to say the school where class.
But before actually creating the square class, now that I'm thinking about it, they should be able
to see a regret and we still don't we don't have any errors.
So we have set up the size of the grid, the color of the size of the doors, the color of the dot.
Why is there a no sign?
So let's remove that and save it.
There we go.
So this is our grade.
You can increase or decrease the size of the grid.
You can set it to five and you're going to see a grid, a five squares.
All right.
And you can set it to 15.
I guess you're going to see that a lot of them.
So the bigger the grid, the higher the number of squares that you have to fill.
Right.
So for a grid, a 10 by 10, you're going to have 100 squares for a grid, a five by five, you're going
to have like 25, I think.
Yeah.
So now let's go ahead.
And it's actually create the square constructor, the square class on the constructor.
And I'm going to say, hmm, I'm going to say class.
You know what?
It has been 20 minutes or so and that is a different topic.
So why shouldn't we cover cover that in our next lecture?
See you guys then.