Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to implement the functionality of our testimony on Schlyter.
All right, so first things first, what is it that we need to grab?
We're going to grab all of our slides and all of our indicator images.
So this these texts, there are slides and these images, there are indicator images and basically that's
it.
That's the only thing that we need to grow.
So I'm going to say consed I'm going to call this variable slides and we're going to say document that
query selecter.
And we are going to grab this later, right, but we don't want the slider itself, we want the children
of the slider, right.
So let's say let's calm down.
And the next thing that I want to grab is.
It's going to be indicator images indicator IMGs and you're going to say document that query selector
and we are going to grab the indicator and inside the indicator we have the images.
So we are going to grab all the children of the indicator.
That said, these are basically the two things that we needed to grow.
I'm just going to go ahead and make this model smaller so we can increase the width of this one, just
maybe like a bit more.
And come right there.
All right, so the first thing that I want to do is I want to loop over this.
I want to loop over the indicator images and we are going to use our regular loops here.
All right.
So I'm going to say for that, I'm going to use iut first.
We want the AI to start from zero and we want the AI to go all the way to indicator imagist length.
And from this, you guys you guys know that length is a method, is a property of an array.
We can use it on an array.
And this is going to give us an array.
Right.
This constant variable is going to give us an array.
That's why we can access the length property.
All right, and we want to each time we want incremented by one.
All right, so in here, what I want to do is I want to add an average listener for the indicator images.
And this for loops for loop allows us to repeat this at event listener three times or as many times
as we have images.
So I'm going to say indicator images and we are going to grab the loop variable and we are going to
say add event listener.
So this is a new way of adding giving listeners.
And let's provide and say quotes, and then we are going to run a function.
So what is the function going to do?
We want this function to do two things first, we want to grab the indicator images and we want to remove
the active class to be able to add it later.
And the second thing is we want to grab our slides and remove the active class if if any of the slides
have it to be able to add it later.
Right.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to come down and I'm going to create another forum for Loop.
This time I'm going to call the loop variable J.
Right.
I'm going to say let J equal to zero.
We want it to start from zero and we want the J to go all the way to indicator images dot length.
All right.
And we want to incriminate each time by one, so each time when we click, when we click any of these
indicator images, this loop is going to run, this loop is going to only run whenever we click any
of these indicator images.
And we are going to grab our indicator images and we are going to pass in the loop variable and we say
classless.
So I want this this loop variable j to go ahead and search inside this indicator images and find the
class of active and remove it from any of the indicator images that currently have this.
So whenever it removes the class, what do I want to do?
I want to add it to the loop variable of the eye and the loop variable of the eye is the loop variable
that we have just clicked.
Right.
So indicator images I that class list, so first we make sure that the class active is removed from
every every from every other, like from all of the indicator images, then we add it.
Right.
First off, we just make sure that it is removed and then we add it.
So now let's save it.
Let's click.
And then you guys can see now we do get our effect, the images they're switching, but the text is
still staying the same.
So the first part of this functionality is done.
The second part of this functionality is to get the slides.
So I'm going to create a constant I'm going to call it ID.
And this is where the data I'd attribute comes in.
And I'm going to say indicator images and I'm going to say I we just use our Adjaye loop.
I'm just going to call a loop just to make sure that we have removed this the class of active from any
indicator images.
And then we just added it here.
Right.
So this is for safety purposes.
All right.
We don't want to add this class to this.
We just want to add it once.
So we remove it from any element that has it.
And then we re added.
All right, so we go ahead and we grab our indicator images which are over, which are the children
of the indicator, and we get the attribute, what is the attribute that we get?
It is the data data dash I'd attribute that we want to get.
Now, we have grabbed the data.
It is value which are zero one and two.
What do we want to do with that?
We want to loop over them as well.
So we are going to say let OK, we start from zero.
The reason that it starts from zero is the first data ID value is actually zero.
And we are going to say, go, Kay goes all the way to slide's.
That length and we have created the slides.
OK, now this is not accurate.
That's correct.
And it's based right here.
We have created the slides variable right here.
You're going to access it and we are going to say go all the way to slides that length, less than that.
And each time we are going to implement, we are going to increment the Lutherville variable by one.
And what do we want it to do?
We want to grab our slides, passing the variable, and we want to make sure that none of them have
the class of active.
And when none of them have the class of active, the last thing that we want to do here is we want to
add it.
We want to have this class of active, classless and.
It let's go over this concept one more time.
First, let's check it if it works, if I click on it.
OK, now here we should pass the I.D. because this constant of I.D. grabs the value for this data I.D.
So it's going to be zero then.
It's going to be one that is going to be two.
So let's save it.
Let's click on this and let's click on this.
So it definitely works, but let's go over this concept one more time.
So we created a loop because we want to repeat our event listener three times inside the event, listeners
function.
First off, we check that we don't have this active clause.
If we have it will remove it by looping over the indicator images.
And also we check for that active clause inside our slides by looping over the slides.
Right.
And whatever that that is done, we whenever that is done and we have clicked on any of these indicators,
we want to add the active clause to that indicator and the active class is going to be added from here.
So this is the active clause for the indicator of images.
And we are also going to the active clashed our slides as well.
All right.
So whenever we click first, we check whether the removed remove classes there, if it is there to remove
it.
And then we added to the item that we have clicked and we also check for the slides.
If there is the active class and if it is there, we remove it.
And then we added to that specific slide that we want to see.
All right.
And the active class for slides comes from right here.
So we have selected all the slides and we have said display none.
But on the on the first slide, which is.
OK, so this is the first slide slide number one seats.
I'm just going to collapse two and three seats on slide number one.
We have added the active clause, but in here, we we want to remove that active clause from there and
we want to add it to any slide that we click on it.
All right.
And this is how this project works.
That said for this, let's see you guys in the next one.