Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to make this video controller function.
All right, so first off, let's open up a live server and you're going to wait for it.
So this is our video controller.
This is how it is originally looking.
But we can see that the speed is not changing, so it is not functional.
So the first thing that I want to grab is going to be CONSED.
I want to grab our video element that has a class of video, I think.
Yeah.
So I'm going to say document that query selector and let's grab it by the class, which is video.
Video, yep, better and next, let's go ahead and grab our speed container and we are going to you
know what?
We are just going to grab that copied and pasted here and the classes this time speed.
And finally, we are going to grab our speed bar as well.
And I'm just going to call it bar, so I'm going to call it bar.
And in the class, we are going to add speed as well because the class speed bar.
So we are going to grab our speed.
And we are going to add an event listener to it now, the event that we are adding to it is a mouse
move event, which we have talked about a lot in our previous project, that whenever you move your
mouse, it doesn't matter if it is clicked or not.
If the mouse is down or up, it doesn't matter if you just move your mouse.
This event is going to fire and we are going to grab our event object and we are going to create a an
X variable.
And this variable is going to grab the distance in extraction that this speed controller travels.
So we know how we can get the distance.
It is E, page, page X and we are going to subtract from this value the value of speed that offset
left.
And the reason that we offset left, the reason that we subtract it is because this speed is not actually
attached to this page.
So there is there is some offset to this speed and this we need to subtract it because whenever I'm
here, I want the page X to be zero.
I don't want it to be like zero plus all the space.
I just want it to be zero when I'm here.
I want the page X to be, let's say, 600.
I don't want it to be 600 plus this value.
So we need to subtract it from that.
Next thing is, I'm going to create a percent value because according to this percentage, the speed
is going to increase or decrease and this percentage is actually taken into consideration.
This with so the percentage is related to the width of this container with off the speed bar as well.
So we are going to say X divided by which we were ever we are.
We are going to divide it by the speed that offset with offset width.
And you can find out more about offset left and with in the MDN.
I show you the offset I think I've shown in the offset left.
You can just type there and you can read more about them.
Now I'm going to grab and I'm going to create a minimum value, which is zero point one.
So our increment is going to be by point one.
So it's going to be zero point one, then zero point two and then the zero point three and then zero
point for all the way to five.
So the const maximum value is five for us.
All right, so the maximum is five.
We're going to use these variables, don't worry.
So now let's go ahead and let's create a dynamic with four hour playback.
So for that, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab our percent.
And multiply it by 100.
All right, and I'm going to add a percentage sign to it, so it is going to give us the with.
So but this the problem with this is so if the page X is, let's say like two or one, the problem with
this is that are going to end up with decimal numbers.
So what do we have to do is we are going to go ahead and wrap this inside a method that is math dot
round, because we want to get the rounded numbers at all time.
We don't want to end up with decimal points.
We just want, like, whole integers.
Right.
And finally, we are going to create the play back, write the playback rate and we are going to say
the playback rate is percent is our percent times our maximum value, minus minimum value plus the minimum
value.
Right.
So what does this mean if I were a person, let's say it's 10 percent.
All right, the width is going to be 10 percent, multiply by 100.
It is the width is going to be 1000.
Right.
And plus percent, it is going to be 1000 percent.
All right.
So then our percent, which is 10 percent, is it is going to come here.
So it is going to be 10.
Our maximum value, let's say it is one, our minimum value is zero point one.
OK, so one minus zero point one point nine nine.
So 10 multiply by point nine nine, we end up with nine point nine.
And when we add zero point nine to it, our playback rate is dynamically 10.
All right.
So our playback rate is dynamically the percentage that we have set it.
So we are going to say Baudot style now.
We are going to apply these styles that style.
That width should be what should be the playback.
Right.
So where is the playback rate darte to fixed right now, this to fixed it returns a string representing
a number in a fixed notation, number of digits.
OK, now a number of digits after the decimal point, it must be in range of zero point to inclusive.
It means that whenever we increase or decrease, we can only see two decimal points.
That's why we say it should be fixed to two decimal points.
And I'm going to put in two and and also we are going to add X to it.
And this adding extra.
It is actually this X that we have.
So if I come here, this X is added to it.
So the number is generated dynamically.
The X is added in line.
All right.
Hardcoded there and also I want to give you a resource if you want to read about the following property
and it is the playback rate, it is the An API digital media aliments API.
And in there we have our playback rate.
You can read more about it there.
But basically what we want is we are going to grab our video and the playback rate that we have created
should be equal to the playback rate which is available to us by the API playback rate which is available
to us by the API.
So let's save it.
Let's go ahead.
Let's come here.
And it doesn't work so well with that, with
OK, I think I've made a mistake here.
So the width should be equal to that with that we have here that we have specified there and we are
going to change the text content as well.
So the text content is going to change based on where we are with our mouse.
Right.
So we are going to say playback rate.
And in here I'm going to say to fixed.
Sorry for that mistake to fixed.
Come on, buddy.
And we are going to say to we are going to add not zero two and we are going to add the X, so the text
content is going to have a number generated dynamically and X is going to be tossed at the end of it.
And the bar with is going to be the way that we have calculated right here.
So we know what the width is.
So if the person to extend the width is going to be 10 percent of the entire with.
So what is the entire with?
Where is it?
It's in here.
So the entire with is going to be twelve hundred, twelve hundred and ten percent of that is going to
be one to one.
Right.
And then based on that with the width of the bar is going to be that amount.
And also the text content of the bar is going to be the number which is produced dynamically based on
where we are in the width and we are going to add an extra in this playback rate is added for us dynamically.
All right.
So we are going to say I think this is the Web speech API that we should add here, and this is our
playback rate that we have created.
Yet now it works.
So if I move, you can see that not only the no updates but the with also updates and you don't need
to click or do anything.
So now let's go ahead to this, cause I'm super excited.
But still let me decrease this.
We can see that it doesn't work here now.
The speed is not increasing or decreasing.
So let's go ahead and check it out and the code.
And so everything looks fine here, and I think if we see here, it says play back, this R is capitalized,
so let's capitalize the R, save it and let's click on this.
Yeah, now it works.
So the problem was this, so if you were to go to the Mozilla developer website, if I just pasted and
if we go there, we can see that we should see that the playback rate, the rate is capitalized.
It is complicated.
All right.
I just forgot to cancel it and now it works.
So if I come here and if I play this.
It's fast.
So first things first, what does this call?
See this as Animation's.
All right, so this is going to be it for this chapter and this project, it was a relatively short
project, but it is something that is most often dropped out of wherever the websites.
They have a they have a video.
So if you have a website that has a video, you can go ahead and add a playback speed.
Of course, I've added it to five.
You can go all the way to ten.
I think that is the maximum.
So if we come to here, the idea is muted when the fast first slow motion outside the range for recommits.
So it is from zero point to five to five.
So that is going to be the range from zero point to five to five.
And you can add it to your websites.
Basically, this is like a cool feature, I just wanted to, like, show you how you can do this based
on the mouse movement.
And that's it.
See you guys in the next chapter.