Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to go over the lexical scope one more time.
All right, so the reason that I'm reviewing this lexical scope is because for our next two lectures
in this chapter, we are going to talk about the function scope one more time and also the EFFI pattern,
the immediately invoked function expression.
And also we are going to talk about the block scoping finally the block, scoping the scope, which
was newly created in starting the E 2015 version of JavaScript.
All right.
So lexical scope is this idea that there are two stages to running a program, OK, inside the browser,
running an application inside the browser.
So the idea of scoping being nested in each other, which are decided at compile time, not a runtime.
And also the idea and secondly, the idea of a compiler or parser like the idea that a compiler or parser
is figuring out all the scope's before code execution happens.
So the compiler is going to go ahead and grab all the formal declarations in here like this line line
number one, line number three, and then line number four, line number six.
And that's it.
So all these four formal declarations and it is going to contact the scope manager for their scope's.
The scope manager is going to specify that this war movie has a scope of global scope or like the global
box.
The other movie also has the global also is present inside the global box.
This VAR movie isn't is present inside the other movie box.
This again movie declaration is also present inside this this other movie box.
And after that we have no formal declarations.
The compilation is done then.
Now this stage of compilation, this happens very, very fast and it is usually transparent.
This is like actually transparent.
You can see it, we can understand it.
We know that there is a compilation stage, but we don't see it actually like running and asking all
these questions.
Of course not.
And then when we get to co-generation, we grab this like we first specify whether and a declaration
is a target reference, a variable is a target reference or it is a source reference.
If it is a target of reference, you are going to grab the value and store it inside the like.
We are going to allocate a small like a space in memory.
If it is a source reference, we are going to trace it to the source, which is right here, and then
we are going to go over that.
So if the source is a function, then we need to create another like scope for that.
Even though the scope is created, we need to allocate a different portion in memory for this function
because this is present inside a different scope, this variable declaration and this function.
Right.
So this is actually how it works.
There is another kind of scope as well, and that is the dynamic scope.
That is not what JavaScript is, not a dynamically scope language.
It is a lexically scoped language, a right and well, dynamically scoped languages that are not that
common, like languages like Perl and com unless they allow you to switch between the static scope,
static scope and dynamic scope.
And they're not actually that common.
So JavaScript is lexically scoped language.
And this is how we would like to think that this code is generated.
Well, not that this is how actually the code is generated.
Right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
But before wrapping up, let's go ahead and let's save it.
We get our error because we talked about this code since before.
We know that, again, movie belongs to this to the scope of this other movie function or box, if you
will.
All right.
And it is accessible only within that scope.
It is not accessible outside that scope.
That's why we see an error at line fourteen.
So this is going to be it for this year.
And the next lecture, we are going to talk about the function scope and the EFFI pattern and why we
why we should use Effi and where we should use it.
Right.
So see you guys in the next lecture.