Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to implement the functionality of our cursor effect.
All right, so inside the JavaScript file, we have nothing.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I want to grab this this circle.
If I reloaded the circle that we have on the top left corner.
So I'm going to say const I'm going to call it mouse cursor.
Notice the camel case, right?
We have document query selector.
We are going to select our elements like using query selector and query selector all like all the time.
And what is the class name for that?
We are going to select it through the class name.
And now what I want to do is I want to grab our allies as well, because this effect actually happens
on the allies.
As far as the Sepah effect is concerned, we have accomplished that in the success.
But in the JavaScript, I just want it to be applied on the allies.
You can do it on anything else.
I'm just giving you like a world of possibilities here.
And I'm going to call this variable NAV links and we are going to say document inside this HTML document
through the query selector method, grab all the allies.
We don't want to make this mistake again.
Right.
And what how can we grab them?
We're going to say enough links, this is the class name for their parents and there we are going to
say a lot.
So inside the quotations is the realm of any success, Violencia says Selecter.
So this is a valid Cyesis descendants selector because space is a descendant Combinator Selecter.
All right.
So what do we want to do?
We want to add a reveal listener on whenever the mouse moves.
So what is it actually that we want to add this event on?
So when the mouse moves, if I come here, so when the mouse moves inside the window, wherever we want
to add that effect, we want whenever we move our mouse around and like this one, we don't see anything.
We want this circle to be moved around with it.
So we are going to grab the window, which is the global object, and we are going to say an event listener.
What is what is it that we are looking for or what is it to be accurate?
We are listening for a for a mouse move now.
Whenever the mouse has moved, it doesn't matter whether the mouse is moving over something or moving
out of something.
Right now, we haven't we haven't talked about the mouse move because we have a lot of events and that's
why I've just covered a few in the three chapters, because we have a ton of projects.
We are going to cover the rest of the important stuff in those projects.
OK, so instead of covering them all in the theory and then in the projects as well, I just gave you
the idea and now we are covering move.
So think of the mouse move as the key press event that we have talked about.
So key for us doesn't care if the key is pressed down or up, it just cares about the key is press.
That's.
So Mouse Move does not care about whether the mouse is moving over something or moving out of something.
As long as the mouse is moved, this function is going to run and we are going to run a function.
OK, now this this way.
We have not added any event listener.
All right.
And I'm going to I'm going to I've done this because I want to show you we can add functions for our
event listeners in other ways as well.
Now, this cursor is a function actually we have called the function here, but we have not created
the function yet.
So we are just going to say, cursor, OK, what what is that cursor?
And this is the cursor function.
So whenever we create the function here and when the user moves their mouse, the function is going
to be called.
Now, this is a second way of creating a development centers functions.
You just called the function and just create a standalone function.
So in that case, we had function expressions or in both cases this is going to be a callback function.
But in this case, we had a function expression.
This is a function declaration.
Right.
So in here, what we are looking for is an event object.
So this function again, I just want to mention this is what the difference between this function and
the function that we used in our previous event listeners is nothing.
You can do it both ways.
We usually do it this way when we have more lines of code.
We do not want to clutter our event listener.
We want our listener to be here.
And maybe the function is way down here somewhere.
This is just an example, right?
So let's go ahead and let's consider log our event object, which we have covered before.
And if I go to the concert log and if I come here.
So now you guys can see each time I move the mouse, you're going to see that I'm going to bring this
up and I'm going to zoom.
And so this screen X, screen Y client, client, client, X client, why it is going to give us the
mouse event.
All right.
And all of them are going to change.
But what we are looking for is page X and page Y.
So if I, if we go there.
So if I, if I just move, everything changes.
All right.
So now you guys can see where all these numbers, they're changing.
The reason for that is our cursor is actually moving around.
All right.
So what I want to do is I want to grab the page X and the page.
What they are going to give us the exact location where this where these links they are situated.
Right.
So this is the target that we are going to get and we are going to say mouse cursor, dot style, dot
top.
Oops.
I don't know why I get that every time I touch I type style.
So we are going to grab the E page X, the page Y for the top because top is from top to bottom and
it is in the right direction and we are going to add to it a pixel string.
All right.
We have just successfully selected the Y variable sorry, divide, divide, coordinate for the event
object and we have given that to the top property for this mouse cursor.
So so now we can see that we can move in the top and bottom direction.
So now you can see.
But I cannot move around like from one side to the next set because the left is still remaining.
All right.
So now you guys can see the circle is moving.
So now let's go ahead and let's add the X to the left, because X moves from one side to the other and
X is the.
The one side to the other coordinate.
So now you guys can see we do have our earth, now the cursor has what what is this style for the cursor?
The style for the cursor, which is the circle comes from the coordinates for the event object.
It's that simple.
So the cursor had only a style of a circle.
So this circle grabs its coordinates from the event object and the event object shows exactly the coordinates
of the cursor that we have.
So if I go ahead and if I come to the body and if I say cursor and if I just come and the cursor not
and now you guys can see whenever we move a recursive, the circle behind it is going to move.
And if I just go ahead and comment and these two lines as well and coming back in this, I should have
probably done this.
So now if I move now you can see wherever I go, these numbers are going to change.
So right in here.
Right.
And there we should see.
Let's go ahead and check out the page X and the page you saw in the X.
We are 01 in the whyever, too.
So basically, we are grabbing the OK, that was the offset.
Sorry, but still the page X Y are the same.
All right, so we are grabbing the coordinates of the the cursor coordinates of this cursor and we give
it to the mouse cursor, those coordinates, and so the mouse cursor can move along wherever we go.
It does have a little lag.
I think that's because I'm recording on your screens.
It might not have this lag, but it's not that noticeable.
So we should be cool, right.
So let's come and talk this one again, and we are going to comment out over this one as well.
So now for the final piece of the project, what we are going to do is we are going to grab our links
because now we want to add that's that beautiful effect whenever we hover on those links.
But now, again, the question arises, we have three links.
Do we want to add event listeners for each of them individually or do we want to loop over them?
Which one is better?
So we want to loop over them and we are going to say for each.
And we are not going to do any aerial functions, we are just going to do our simple function and to
each the parameter is going to be the link.
And this link is actually a loop variable, which is going to grab the value from home, the value of
the service and then the value of the contact.
And whenever this for loop runs, what I want to do, I want to go ahead and I want to grab the link,
which is the loop variable.
And I want to add the event listener, because this link is at the end of the day, is going to have
three values or as many values as they as we have as many values as the number of links that we have.
So for those, what I'm going to do is I'm going to add an event listener in the event we are going
to listen for a mouse out.
All right.
OK, so when the mouse is out, we want to run a function and what is the function going to do?
The function is going to grab our mouse cursor.
And it is going to it is going to add a class to it.
At a.
So what is the class, the classes, link, dash, grow.
Though, let's save it, let's move over, we don't.
OK, so now it says I'm going to reload it when I hover on top of the lake, when I hover away, of
course, this is mouse out.
When we hover away from the link, we are going to see that effect.
So when I'm on the left, when I hover away, we are going to see that right.
But this is not actually the effect that we want.
Whenever we hover away, we want to remove that.
So let's go ahead and let's say remove.
We want to remove the link.
Right.
So I'm going to come here and I'm going to add another event.
Lessiter.
And you're going to see an event listener and we are going to listen for what?
We are going to listen for a mouse over.
And when the mouse is over that element, we want to run a function.
And what does that function?
Basically, I'm just going to grab it and I'm going to pasted here and I'm going to sit at it, save
it.
So now, whenever we are on the link that the this is going to increase in size our cursor and when
we are away, it's going to decrease, increase, decrease, increase, decrease.
All right.
But there are a few problems there.
We can't see our text.
The text is white and let's see what else.
So the text should be black and we still have our border.
And I think we should remove the border as well.
So in here, let's go ahead and let's add another class to our and we are going to say class, let's
start at what is the class that we want to add.
Here is the Harvard ed and case.
Let me check it out.
So this is the class that we want to add.
And in this class is just this color block.
So if I hover on it and if I save it, oops, we should remove it in here because this is the removed
part and mouth out is the remove and mouseover is the ad part.
So if I hover on it it's going to go black.
And in case you're wondering if I just go ahead and come and tell this part, if we go on, it's OK.
But if we hover away, everything is going to stay the same because Mouse Out has been commented out.
That's why we add whenever you want to add it, you should remove it as well.
So added, remove, add, remove, add, remove.
All right, and with this, our project comes to an end, and that's it for this project, and I hope
you have enjoyed it and that's it for this chapter as well.
See you guys in the next one.