Welcome to the first part of randomising drawing shapes.
All right, so in this part, what we are going to do is we are going to go over how we can draw shapes
randomly.
So that is a very tedious thing.
If we were to, like, draw circles one by one, like manually inside JavaScript.
I mean, isn't there like a way to automate this process?
There is.
And we are going to use the four loops.
So this is this lecture is drawing drawing shapes randomly.
And in this lecture, we are just going to draw rectangles and squares and let's get started.
So inside the HTML, inside the system of document, in this style, we have the things that we just
discussed in our previous lecture, except for this overflow.
We just don't want any scroll bars in our screen.
Right.
And then we have our basic canvas element.
And I'm going to save this.
And we have selected our canvas element and we have initiated our canted context.
Now, the width of the canvas now is the window to enter.
The height is window, that inner height and the width is window that inner with.
And so the height starts from right here, goes all the way here and the width starts from here and
goes all the way there.
So the canvas takes up the entire viewport height and with.
All right, so the first example that I want to talk about is I want to randomize the location.
So I'm just going to create a long come and write like this.
And I'm going to say drawing rectangles, slash squares.
Right.
Squares randomly, randomly.
So the first example.
Example, what we are going to say, randomizing randomizing the location, right?
So now how can we do that?
Now I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create a for a loop and we are going to sell it, I.
Equal to, for example, we want to we want the idea to start from one and now how many how many squares
or rectangles do we want?
So here is where we specify the number.
Let's say I want to I want 11.
Right.
And each time the I's done, we are going to incremented by one.
Now, where is a logic right now?
The logic is inside here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say canvas that context.
First off, let's go ahead and provide a color for those.
And I'm going to say so let's just say white and now let's draw them.
Right.
So I'm going to say Phil RACT now the Phil Rectangle, it requires four things X, the horizontal position,
vertical position within height.
So the horizontal position is going to be dynamic because if I hardcoded, then what is the point of
this Falu?
We want we want to randomize the location Arcady position.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to put an X for the horizontal position and put in Y for the
vertical position.
And I'm going to say a square of 50 by 50 right now.
We need to specify X and Y, right.
So I'm going to say X.
Should be equal to now we want to randomize, so for the four randomisation, we have a math, the random
method.
Now, this is going to give us random numbers from zero to one, right?
So what we are going to do is whenever we get this, because we are dealing with the inner high inner
with an inner height of our screen, we want to randomize our rectangles within this space.
So what I'm going to do is because the inner with an inner high, they have some dimensions.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to multiply this with the window dot inner with because it's X and
X is horizontal.
We are just going to multiply it by inner with and we're going to say let y be equal to the same thing.
So math, not random, is going to give us a number between zero and once a zero point one zero point
two all the way to zero point nine.
And we are going to multiply that number by the Anahi by the inner high.
So let's say the inner height is, for example, one like for me, I think it's 15 thirty six by seven
hundred and something.
So let's say 1500 and 700.
So if it is 1500, 1500 multiplied by for example, point one, it's going to be I think 150 or something,
something like that.
So this is going to randomize the location.
Right.
So now if I were to go ahead and save it and come here now, I can see that we get ten.
So one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
The reason that we have ten and not 11, because it starts from zero.
Right.
So we get ten.
So if I click on it, so each time what we get is we get randomized.
Squares, right?
So this is the first example that I wanted to go through to go over now in the second example, what
I want to do here is now first off, I'm just going to create a comment here so we do not confuse these
examples.
And I'm going to copy this example because it's way similar to this.
Right.
So I'm going to say example to randomizing the color.
How cool is that?
So I'm just going to I'm going to leave that.
I'm going to leave the height and the width.
So I'm going to say randomizing the location plus color.
So I'm going to leave the X and Y as they are.
What are how can we go ahead and randomize the color?
So if I were to say, oh, how can we use colors in Tomalski assess as we have color X codes, we have
color names, we have RGV codes or methods for the colors and we have excel for the colors.
If you use, for example, color names such as white, blue, violet, coral, indigo, like light,
sea, green or whatever, then you need to create an array and then loop over that array.
And each time this for loop loops over that array, this is going to grab one value.
I mean, that's one way of doing it.
Right.
But instead of doing that, we know that math, that random returns of a number.
So we also know that we have RGV as well.
So what are we going to do is I'm going to say let's read.
Right.
And I'm going to say math dot random.
And I'm going to multiply now, what is the range of this red in the context of RGV?
What is the range?
The range starts from zero all the way to 255, so multiply by 255.
But keep in mind, this is going to give us also some decimal points as well.
So I'm going to grab this entire thing and I'm going to say to remove the decimal points and to reach
the nearest integer, we are going to say math, that seal.
All right.
And so this is the red.
Now, we are going to do the same thing for green and for blue because RGV, aside from their color
like variations, there are logic works in the same way.
So I'm just going to change this to green.
I'm going to change this to blue.
So now we have RGV colors right now.
What I'm going to do here is instead of hard coding like this, we are going to remove that.
And I'm going to use these tactics and I'm going to say RGV.
So what is the first color?
The first color in RGV is red and then put in a comma.
Now, this structure should resemble that, that a date of RGV that we have in excess.
So that is the structure, Rajeeb.
And finally we have our blue.
So now if I save it, we should get random squares with random colors.
Now let's go ahead and let's increase the number to 21 so we get 20 and then we can see.
So if it doesn't matter how many times they refresh, we are never going to get the same pattern.
It doesn't matter how many times you refresh, so you get random colors and you get random locations.
Now, for the final four, the final example in this lecture, what I want to do is I want to randomize
the location, the color plus the size.
So we get squares.
We get rectangles.
Right.
So I'm going to come in this one out.
Let's grab this entire thing, put it down here and I'm going to change this to three.
Randomizing the location, the color plus size.
Now, that's uncommon.
This is the reason that I'm just copying it, because I don't I don't want to write all this because
it's the same as that one.
So how about the size?
So you can see for the size we have 50 and we have 50.
So basically what we need to do is I'm just going to provide a space here.
So these are the colors and I'm going to provide a space here.
So this is the size I'm going to say let with.
So this is the width of our shape and I'm going to say math round.
We are going to use math the random a lot when it comes to creating games and I'm going to multiply
it by 200.
So the maximum size is going to be 200, right.
And I'm going to the height should be 200 as well.
Now, even though they are, they're going to go to 200.
They're for the most part, they're not going to be the same, like the height and the with.
They're not going to be the same.
Why?
Because this is going to generate a random number.
And this is general this is going to generate another random number.
The chances of this random number being equal to this random number is very low.
I mean, it is possible.
And that's why we have done it like this, because by chance, they could have the same value.
But other than that, I don't want him to have the same value.
And now let's pass the width right here and the heights right here.
Let's save it.
Let's come here.
So now he can see that.
I think in this case, I think that they look the same.
But but I think the height is a little bit bigger.
So it doesn't matter how many times you refresh.
Not only that, you get random locations, you get a random background color and you get random size.
So this is actually how we create multiple things on the screen, right?
And with this, our lecture comes to an end.
See you in the next one.