Hi, everyone, in this that year, we are going to start talking about Arae methods.
All right, so the first method that I want to talk about is the shift shift method, and this method
removes items of an array or values from an array from the start.
So let's go ahead and let's create an array of movies.
All right.
And I'm going to name them the lake house.
The lake house.
And I'm just initially I'm going to provide two movies inside this array and I'm going to create another
string memento.
And let's go ahead and cancel the log movies.
Let's save it and then you guys can see that this area has a length of two, right?
We have the lake house and we have momentum.
Right.
And now let's go ahead and let's remove from the start of this array.
And for that, we are going to grab our array.
All right.
And we are going to grab our array and we are going to close the shift method because shift is a method.
We should provide it with parenthesis.
Right.
And then we are going to consider log our array one more time and then we guys can see that the first
array has and the first area has also been changed.
But in here in the first array, we have the lake house and the memento.
And when we call the movies that shift, the lake house has been deleted.
And we only we are only left with the momentum and the length is going to be one.
The index is zero.
Right.
So this is the shift method that we have.
I'm just going to comment on all kinds of dialogues and I'm going to keep this the second method.
I'm just going to name these methods as well.
So this is a shift method.
The second method that I want to talk about is the UN's shift on shift method.
And this method adds to the start of an array.
Keep in mind, shift on shift, they remove or at from the start for the end.
Do we have other methods?
Right.
So we are going to grab our movies, movies.
And we are going to say on shift.
And because this is a method we are going to provide it with parentheses and what do we want to add
to the start of this array?
I'm just going to come in here, removes from the start, right.
And this one adds to the start, right?
So it's not confusing.
We are going to add to the start The Great Gatsby.
When we say it now, let's go ahead and let's consider our Ray.
And now you guys can see, so our original story has the Lake House and Memento, but The Great Gatsby
has been added to the start of this era.
So this is the uncuffed method.
The next method that I want to talk about is the pop method.
It is the top, so it is method number three, it is pop method, and it does exactly what the name
suggests.
It pops an item from the end of an array, removes from the end, it removes from the end of an array.
So we are going to grab our movies array and we are going to say pop and that set.
And now let's go ahead and let's consider the longer array as well so we can see the changes.
And now you guys can see, because our original array has two items inside of it.
It has the lake house and Memento.
Memento has been pumped from the from the end of the array.
And we are left with the lake house.
All right.
So this is the pop method.
The next method that I want to talk about is the push method, which adds to the end of an array push
method.
Adds to the end.
All right, so first off, let's go ahead and let's let's call our Iran.
So this is our right and we are going to say that push, because this is a method we provided with parentheses.
And let's push to this array, another movie which is departed.
All right.
And now let's go ahead and let's check it out inside the console as well.
So originally we have lake house momento and now we have lake house momento and departed.
Right.
So this is how we can add to that.
So now we know how to remove from the start, add to the start, remove from the end and add to the
end.
All right.
The next method that I want to talk about is.
The slice method now this returns a piece of the array, for example.
This is where I'm going to come and out the array and I'm going to create another array here.
First off, let's go ahead and let's create an array of numbers.
Right.
And we are going to set it to one to three, four.
I mean, this is 54 hundred and fifteen.
That's 789.
Maybe like seven.
Eighty nine.
That's three.
Twenty four.
That's it.
So this is our right now what what's what this slice method does is it returns a piece of this array
as a as another array.
So it copies this, it grabs this array and then it slices there and it returns that slice that we want.
OK, so in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to write this is our method number five.
We are going to say slice method.
And for your reference, I'm just going to add in here so we have a slice.
This is the syntax and the arguments that this slice method is going to accept a starting index and
ending index.
OK, this is just as a reference free.
And I'm sure the slice name is comprehensive enough.
So what we are going to do is we're going to say, for example, and whenever it provides us with that
slice, what I'm going to do is I'm going to store that slice in another variable.
So I'm going to say let no one be equal to OK, so let's grab our array.
And the array is numbers.
So this is our array and we are going to say that slice.
So what is this starting index and what is the ending index?
I'm just going to cancel the log our array numbers.
Let's consider log it.
So let's say we want the starting index to be one and the index and the ending index to be four.
So let's put it let's put it to one and four.
Let's save it.
And now let's consider log this one as well.
So this is number one, and then we can see we have two, three and four because the starting index
was was one and the ending index was four.
Right.
So we get two, three and four.
It doesn't capture the ending index.
It only captures the starting index and it goes all the way to the ending index.
So we have two, three and four.
Right.
So this is how the slice method works.
There are a couple of other variations that we can use with the slice method, for example.
We can also I'm just going to come in this one out and I'm going to say let no one be equal to we can
use negative numbers as well.
We can use negative indices as well.
So the index, they start from positive numbers for start from zero zero zero one, two, three, four,
five, six and seven.
So this is ours.
But what if we want to count from the other way?
So from the other way, this is going to be negative one negative two negative three negative four negative
five negative six negative seven.
And this is going to be negative eight.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's say we grab our numbers array and yeah, we call the slice method on it
and we want we want to grab items from from the end of the array by two.
So we just add, for example, if I just add negative one, we are going to get we are going to grab
the last item because the negative one, the end is the index of the last item.
All right.
But if I add negative to.
Negative.
We are going to get our negative one and negative two because now we are slicing from here all the way
to here, right.
So we can go ahead and add some let me put it back to one and commented out, common this one out.
I'm going to do one more and I'm going to put it to four.
So this is negative one, negative two, negative three and negative four.
So you guys can see it has created another array for us.
This is a copy of this array and we have the numbers that we have desired.
So this is negative one, two, negative three and negative four.
So it has grabbed all the all four numbers and it has created another array for us.
This is the slowest method and the final method that I want to talk in this video to talk about in this
video is the splice method.
And this method, it changes the original array by removing or replacing existing items from an array.
All right.
So for this, we have to capture the array inside another variable as well.
So first off, we are going to say this is method number six and this is Pliss method.
Keep in mind, this changes our array, OK?
And for your four for your eyes, I'm just going to provide it with the arguments.
So the first argument is going to be our starting index, and the second argument is going to be a number
of items to be removed, removed.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's grab we are going to work with our numbers.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say number two should be equal to splice.
First off, we should reference our array.
It is numbers that and then we call the method and it is splice.
Right.
Because this is a method we provided with parentheses.
So what is this starting index?
So let's go ahead and let's take a look at it.
Let's save it for now.
And we see OK, so let's say the starting index is zero and we want it to go by four.
OK, so this is the starting index and the number of items to be removed.
So I wanted to start from zero and I want to remove four items.
Right.
And now let's go ahead and let's call it one more time.
Let's just call this one number two and let's save it.
So now you guys can see that it has it has spliced out of this array, this one.
All right.
So if I were to consider log our numbers there, you guys can see that this is our numbers are going
to come out, this one.
So it is crystal clear you guys can see that our numbers area has been changed.
It changes the original array by splicing it.
Right.
So this is the first way that we can do it.
It either removes or replaces or adds.
OK, so we are going to talk about all three, all three possible combinations.
So this was removing.
OK, I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to come in this one out and the next one is removing and replacing.
We are going to remove and replace.
We are going to say it numb to be equal to numbers.
Numbers, dot supplies, right?
So what is the starting index, the starting index now?
I don't know.
Let's put it to zero again.
This is the starting index.
So this is the starting index.
How many items do we want to remove?
We want to remove two items.
Now, this is also called replacing.
All right.
So we can't replace these two items by two other numbers as well.
So the first item inside Aurora is number one.
The second item is number two.
So we have successfully chosen number one and number two, and we can replace them by one hundred and
eleven and two hundred and twenty two.
Let's save it.
Let's check out both of our arrays here.
Uncommon them.
And now you can see we have spliced out one and two and we have successfully changed the original array
from one, two, three, four and whatever to one one, one, two, two, two, three, four, and whatever.
So this is removing and replacing.
I'm going to go over this syntax one more time.
This is the starting index.
This is the number of items that we want to remove.
And this these are the items that we want to replace with those items that we have just removed.
It's that simple, right?
So this is a removing and replacing, there is another scenario that is just adding it if you want to
just add it, OK?
And for that, I'm just going to copy this one and I'm going to post it here and I'm going to uncommented
all of that.
And we are going to say that we want to start from the index of two, but we do not want to remove any.
So if you do not want to remove any, you just provide the number of items to be removed equal to zero.
So if you make the zero, then none of the items from our original array of numbers is going to be removed.
But still, we would be adding one, one, one and two to two to the original array.
Let's save it.
And then you can see originally that's coming this one.
And originally the length of our array is eight.
But now we have successfully added two more items without removing to there.
OK, so the starting index of this item is two.
So the starting index, this has been changed as well because it changes the original array.
So this is zero.
This is one.
And what is the index of this?
This is this has an index of two.
And we have successfully provided two new items to our array without removing any item from the array.
I'm going to go over this syntax one more time.
We want to start from the index of two, but we do not want to remove anything.
That's why we provided with zero.
But we want to add we don't want to remove.
We just want to add.
So when we want to add, we just provide it with the number of items that we want to add with the items
that we want to add.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture, guys.
See you in the next one.