Hi, everyone, in this last year, we're going to talk about the lexical scope and the executing of
the code.
All right, so we know how this code is compiled.
We just talked about it in the previous lecture.
Now, in this lecture, what I want to do is I want to talk about now that that now that our plan is
set up, what is the next step?
What is the executing the execution engine or the executioner is going to do?
All right.
So there is no more declaration, OK, just executable code.
Now, in this case, line number two is actually two statements, it might seem like as one statement,
but it is actually to stem the novel part.
This part, this part.
Remember it just the compiler asked the scope manager, have you heard of this identifier novel?
And the scope manager said, no, but here is your scope.
You are inside the global scope.
We never talked about this value, right?
We didn't talk about the value of that novel because the value of the novel is the second part.
And this part is handled by the execution engine right now.
The compiler created the plan for the identifiers and it gave it to the execution engine.
OK, now, in the previous lecture, we talked about how a variable has two goals.
It could either be a rough front, a targeted reference, or it could be a source reference where the
variable is defined, where the identifier is defined or is initialized.
That's where the that's the assignment of a value.
That is where it is a targets reference and where it is called right here or right here in these two
cases.
Then they are in the source reference or in the source position because by this to function calls,
we want to retrieve their values.
OK, the target and the source references are created at the execution time and at compile time we create
formal declarations.
So we created formal declarations and their scope.
So in this case, the people who are talking are the scope manager, again, the scope manager.
And at this time, because the compilation is done, the virtual machine or the jet engine, or which
I would like to call it the executioner, is now the execution engine and the scope manager or the scope
manager and the executioner.
They're going to talk now.
The executioner is going to grab the identifier, which is the target reference from the scope or the
scope manager, and assign a value to it because it should dedicate a location in memory to it.
So it is going to ask the scope manager, have you heard of this novel?
And the scope manager is going to say, yes, here is the value for it and this value is going to be
stored.
Nasacort stored inside a tiny space inside this, the memory by the execution engine.
All right.
So what we are going to do is we are going to go to line number four, OK?
And because this is a declaration, we are not going to.
This is not executable code from there, we are going to move on to line number nine because this is
another declaration.
We are not actually assigning any value to this.
These are declarations we are not going to ask for anything from the scope manager.
So we are just going to jump into line number 14 and line number 15.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and remove that, OK?
We don't really need to write code execution at that point.
So what do we have on line 13?
Online 13?
The other book is in source position, right?
Because we are not assigning anything to it.
So we are retrieving values from it.
The parenthesis, these parentheses, they execute the function, these they the other book is going
to call the function.
The parentheses is going to execute the function.
Right.
And the other book references the function that has a scope of itself, this is very, very important
in here.
Now, the execution, what is the execution or the execution engine is going to do?
The execution engine is going to go to line number three in this case.
All right, but the console identifier has not been declared there, so it is going to go to line number
four before that, OK?
It is going to go to line number four before that.
And we know that the VA novel, it has not been it has been specified here.
And the value for that is Moby Dick.
And it is going to grab this and it is going to grab this value.
It is going to store it inside the memory.
All right.
I hope you are not getting confused when we get we call the function a line number 13.
This is the function call and these parentheses, they execute this function.
So whenever we want to execute any function in the at runtime, we should go to the function itself.
So what do we have inside this function?
We have a formal declaration.
All right.
So inside this formal declaration, even though it is a formal declaration, we have an assignment of
a value.
This value should be stored inside the memory because we might use it down the road.
Right.
So this value is going to be used and this value is retrieved from the scope of this function.
And then the execution is going to go to line number five.
All right.
And in line number five, because this console, this console, I'm not talking about the log method,
this log method.
This is this is actually a method.
So we have a console.
The console is not specified or it is not declared inside this function.
What do we do then?
Now, the key to understanding any lexically scoped language is, oops, what did I do wrong here?
So the key to understanding any just going to say console the log.
What did we have here?
I think we had some book in here, I'm just going to add some book now, the key to understanding any
lexically scoped language is whenever we cannot find a reference to an identifier inside a specific
scope or in this case, inside a function scope.
This is very important.
We go one level up, so consider log is going to come is going to get out of this function scope and
it is going to come to the global scope.
Now, inside the global scope, we do have an identifier called console.
I know we have not explicitly specified that, but it is available to us by JavaScript.
And this identifier, it has some properties and some methods.
One of the methods is Laucke, right.
And it is going to log some book.
That's why there is no error on this line, because JavaScript is a lexically scoped language.
It has a lexical scope.
And in lexical scope, whenever we cannot find a reference to a source identifier, we go one level
up.
And when we come to this global scope, because console is defined inside the global scope, because
it is defined there, we are not going to see an error, but we are going to see that some book has
been printed to the console here.
So I'm just going to go ahead and save it.
Some book has been printed here, right, because of this function.
So now the execution engine or the executioner is going to come to line number 14.
And because this is and this code is executable now when it comes to here, because this code this part
is the is the calling, the function and the parentheses is actually the part where executes the function.
So we are going to go inside this function.
We are going to go to this function.
So because functions have scope's, we are going to insert the scope of this function.
So we have a formal declaration from which we are going to grab the value and we are going to store
it inside memory.
And then again, we have the same thing.
We have a concept along the console is not specified inside this function, but this console is different
than this console because this console, online number 10, it actually grabs the value of this identifier
right now.
So before this console moves one level up, this console is going to grab the value of the right novel
and it which is why and it is going to print it to the console lock, which is going to print it to
the console because it is going to grab the value and it would seem something like this.
So we have a console lock.
It is going to grab this value the value inside this.
It is going to grab this, copy it and it is going to paste it.
Right.
Oops, where am I.
So it is going to come here.
It is going to paste it here and put it inside quotes because this is not a valid identifier and it
is going to come up and when we save it we get that right.
So this is actually how it how the council log works and how a lexically scoped language works.
All right.
So so far we have talked about the and what was the previous lecture?
We have talked about the compilation and also we have talked about the execution.
So the takeaway here is that when we reference a variable in a target position, we need to look it
up.
When we reference a variable in a source position, we need to lock it up.
So a look up process is like like a lock up process is involved in here.
OK, so far we have looked at everything that we have looked for.
We were able to find them.
What about if we look for something and we cannot find it now?
We are going to talk about that as well.
But I just want to make sure that you understand this these two processes.
This is a two process kind of thing in JavaScript.
First one is the compilation where all the identifiers and the scopes are, and second step is the execution,
where all the compilation of parsing runs.
OK, and at the end of this lecture, I want to congratulate you, congratulate you on understanding
how JavaScript works.
You have learned how JavaScript works.
So see you guys in the next lecture.