Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we talk about the big and primitive data type and the reference data types.
All right, so the big and data type is a special numeric type that provides support for integers of
arbitrary length.
Right.
So, for example, if we go ahead and if we specify a big event, let's say let's just give the variable
name big enough and we can provide like an arbitrary length, for example, this.
So we have one, two, three, all the way to zero again.
So these are ten, ten numbers.
They're ten here.
That's 20.
That's 30.
So the length of this arbitrary number is 40 digits.
And that is a lot.
And when you toss in just an end, at the end of that number, that number becomes a big integer.
Right.
That's why it is called a big integer, so if you go ahead and if you call big and we are going to get
that number right.
So this is the first way that the beginning to created a big int is created by appending end to the
end of an integer literal or by calling the function begin that creates begins from strings, numbers
or whatever.
All right.
So we can create big int in another way as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to say big.
And to and for that, we are going to call the big event function.
OK, so this is the function and inside here we can create begins of any string or any number.
In this case.
I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to create of of of this number.
So whenever you call the function begin, you don't have to toss in the number.
Right.
So now if we go ahead and if you call it big and two, we should be able to get our number and there
it is.
And then we guys can see that even though we have not added an end at the end of the number, we still
get.
And because this is a big integer, we have said so in here by creating the function.
Right.
So this is how big an works in JavaScript.
The next part that I want to talk about is the reference types in JavaScript.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to come in this copy this line pasted
right here and I'm going to change it to two reference.
Reference types in JavaScript.
So there are actually three reference types in three major reference types in JavaScript.
We have a lot, OK, but the main ones are iRace.
Fire objects and functions.
OK, and we in this lecture very quickly, we are going to talk about each one of them.
So arrays are like they are a global object, that they are used in the construction of arrays, which
are high level lists like objects.
So in simple layman terms, arrays, they are used to store information.
Now, what kind of information now arrays and objects, they are actually called JavaScript data structures.
All right.
And I have dedicated separate chapters for iRace objects and functions.
So this is just an introductory lecture to the world of arrays.
We are going to talk about race a lot in this course, a race they are used to store list information.
Think of a race sort of list you will or will list in the.
OK, let's think of it like that.
We just have items inside the list.
So the way we create an array is first we use our variables in JavaScript.
We select, now we provide the name of the arrays, which is numbers.
Now what what does this numbers array has inside of it?
So the syntax for an array is is brackets.
All right.
The syntax for an object is curly braces and the function is like a combination of parentheses and curly
braces.
Right.
So inside here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say one, two and three.
So right now we have successfully created an array that has a name of numbers.
And the information stored inside that array is numbers one, two and three.
All right.
So this is our array.
We can take a look at our array inside the console.
So we just go ahead and write the name of the array.
Right now, in this case, you might ask, OK, that this numbers it's actually a word, right?
It's a set of characters.
So this is a string.
Right.
So we should we should put it inside quotes.
But this is not actually string.
It is a valid JavaScript identifier.
It means that it is a variable name now, variable names.
They should not be represented inside quotes, only strength's.
This is not a string.
This is a JavaScript identifier.
When we use JavaScript identifiers, we do not surround them by quotes.
Let's say it.
All right, so let's go ahead and open it with Life Story first, let's go to the console and we should
be able to see right here.
I'm just going to go ahead and say it again.
So this is our right.
And you guys can see that we have the item.
The first item has an index of zero.
The value is one.
The second item has an index of one, the values two.
And the third item has an index of two values through the length and the length is three.
One thing to keep in mind is that the index number is always one less than the length and it says a
right right here.
Right.
So this is how we can create an array.
We can create objects and functions as well, which I'm just going to go ahead and show you how we can
do that as well.
Now, keep in mind that this is actually like an introduction to a race.
So I'm not going to go in-depth into these topics because I have dedicated separate chapters for separate
data structures in JavaScript.
All right.
So the next data structure that I want to talk about is an object.
The object class represents one of JavaScript data types.
It is used to store various key collections and more complex entities.
Now, arrays and objects, both of them store information.
Now, you might ask, okay, what is the difference between an array and an object?
The first difference is that arrays, they only store values or only store one pair of values.
OK, so it means that we only have one, two, three, or we have like John Mike Ross channeler or whatever.
OK, we either have that or we have only values in arrays, but in objects we have a combination of
key value pairs.
All right.
So I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to create an object and I'm going to use another JavaScript variable.
And that is the concept.
All right.
And I'm going to say person, OK.
Now, objects, they're represented by curly braces.
So in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to say name and I'm going
to put the name inside the quotes.
And then you guys can see this.
Mike is a string.
It's not a valid JavaScript identifier.
That's why we should put it inside and inside the inside quotes.
And I'm going to say age and the ages, let's say 35.
And because age is no, we don't have to put it inside, inside any kind of quotations or quotes.
So this is the difference between an array and an object.
You guys can see that we have a key and then we have a value.
And this key value is called a pair.
OK, this is key value pair.
OK, and Joe and objects, they are collections of key value pairs or I'm just going to call them properties
or they are collection of properties.
Right.
We are going to use this term properties a lot.
We can take a look at our object inside the console as well.
And we just for that, we just say cancel the log and then we provide the name of the object, if you
put it here.
So this is the difference between an array and the representation of an object.
The object, the H has a value of 35 and the name has a value of money.
And if this seems odd to you that the name comes first and then the H, it's because that it has been
Alphabeat basically rearranged and it says object.
OK, I'm not going to tell you what these are because these are way advanced down the road.
All right.
So this is an array and this is an object.
The next thing that I want to talk about is a JavaScript function.
Now, functions that are not data structures.
Functions are used to calculate some something or to perform some sort of logic for us.
OK, so I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to create a very, very simple function to create a
function.
We just write the name, the keyword function and then the give the function and name, which is at
right now.
What do we want this function to do?
We want this function to combine, to add twelve to three and then divide and then multiply the result
by ten.
All right.
Let's say that nothing happens.
I'm just going to go ahead and comment about this, console the logs, because I want the console to
be empty.
Now, nothing happens y because whenever you create a function you have to call that function.
Now all functions in JavaScript are asleep.
Think of it like this.
They are asleep.
Right, whenever you want the phone.
And to do something, you have to poke it with a pokey thing and you have to wake it, you have to tell
it to wake up and perform this and do this.
So in order to wake any function up, we have to call the function.
So the function name is ADD and we are just calling the function.
And now the function has been called and the function is awake.
We can see the result, but it doesn't mean that the function is still sleeping.
We can see the result for ourselves as well.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to provide this and in parentheses
and I'm going to say cancel the lot because I want to show you the results of the function.
So the function grabs 12th 12 and it adds three to it.
That's 15, 15 times 10.
We get 150.
So first four again, I'm just going to go ahead over this idea one more time, that whenever you create
a function, that function is asleep.
You have to call it if you want the function to perform some sort of task or to implement some sort
of logic.
When we call it, we call the function by its name.
OK, like let's say, hey, the add function, get up and add this number and do this mathematical operation
and the function gets up and does it.
That's it for this.
Let's see you guys in the next one.