Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to make this keyboard dynamic.
All right, so first things first, we need to grab what we need from our e-mail, so I'm going to say
CONSED.
I can never spell this right and we are going to say containers container's so first off, we are going
to grab our key containers.
Let's capitalize the C to follow the camel case naming convention.
And now we are going to select document that query selector.
But because we have more than one key container, we are going to say document that key query selector
all and we are going to grab our keys from here.
So basically we are selecting these diffs inside of which we have our inputs.
All right.
And the next thing that I want to select is going to be text area, and we are going to say document
that query selector and now the text area is inside the div of display and it is the text.
Text area, save it.
All right, so what I'm going to do is I'm just going to do some console logs for for the key containers.
I just want to show you guys some things.
Right.
Which are really important to understanding how to be able to create this keyboard and how to make it
dynamic.
All right.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead.
I'm going to console the lock, the key container's let's save it.
And in here we see you.
You guys can see that we get a necklace.
And this Notley's looks like an array.
And the good thing about this is we can use arrays, properties and methods on this Nobelist, even
though it is a no.
This it looks like an array and we have indices.
So we have difficulty zero index index number one.
Number two.
And this spacebar is going to be the index number three.
And whenever we click on these arrows, it is going to show us everything there is.
All right.
And now let's let's go ahead and let's find out, I don't know, we can see the inner HTML and text,
we can see the.
All right.
Let's go over it.
See, we can see the data set.
We can see the first child.
We can see the first element.
Right, and we can see the children, so if I click on these children, we are going to see every individual
input.
So this is how we can access every individual input.
That's why we have selected the parent, because when we do kids, when we do key containers that children,
we are going to be able we are going to be able to access all these keys, all these individual keys
that you guys can see here.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to comment that one out and coming this one.
And I'm going to say, let's see, let's grab the child, which has the index of zero.
Let's save it.
And now we get this first row of keys.
And inside there we have all our kids.
I'm going to comment that one outcome in this one.
And now let's grab all the children.
Let's save it.
And in here, we can see that if we have grabbed all the inputs and this is an HDMI collection.
All right, and this system of collection is again surrounded by brackets, meaning it behaves like
an object and we can use object, it behaves like an array, and we can use an array of properties and
methods on this.
Right.
I just wanted to show you how this works because this idea is crucial to creating this.
So now we are going to create our first and last event listener and we are going to add event listener
containers that basically we are not going to do out of and listeners here because we have four sets
of.
Keys, so this is the first set, second set, third set forth.
So if we do keep containers out of the listener, it is going to add to the first set, but we want
to loop over them.
So we are going to use our foreach loop and we are going to add a function.
And the function is going to contain the key, which is the event, which is the loop variable.
Right.
And each time this loop runs, we are going to grab our key containers and we are going to add add an
event center so that kikkan we are going to grab our key, of course, not key containers because key
is the loop variable and key is actually something that is being looped over and over and over again.
All right.
So what is it that we are listening for?
Of course it's a click.
And in here, I want to log I want to pass in as a parameter the e the event object itself, because
I just want to log it and I want to show you guys, basically the process is a bit like this, but I
want to show you guys something, OK?
And we are going to go step by step because I want you guys to really understand.
So I'm going to say cancel that log.
First off, let's log cancel that log.
First off, let's go ahead and log the event object.
So whenever we press a key, we are going to say log is not defined.
OK, what is this?
Just say this is a key and we are going to see that it says it's a mouse event.
All right.
So if I come down here, what I want to do here is in this for each loop.
What I want to do is whenever I click the Z key, I want to be able to print to the screen the Z letter.
So I want to find the path to this letter.
So let's go ahead and let's dive inside this path.
OK.
And from inside this path, we are going to go to this input.
And from the input, we are going to go to the let's go and let's find the value.
Let's go to V.
What is the value of that key?
So is it down here?
So the value is, as you guys can see, it is.
So this is this is actually what we want to grab.
So if I click on the X now, let's see left, let's click on the V.
And if we come here inside the path from the path, if we go inside the input because the rest of them
are not the input, this is the input.
Let's go inside the input and let's take a look at the value.
So we just pressed was it the C?
Where is the value?
It was the V sorry, so we just pressed the V and we get the V right here, right.
So this is how it works.
First off, I just cancel the E, then I'm going to cancel the path and I'm going to say that path because
this is a prop..
And when I click on it, we are going to get the path to this input.
All right.
I'm going to come that one out.
And from this input, I want to grab the index of zero because this is an array.
I can just write zero and I can save it.
When I click on it, we get that input.
So you guys can see this is how we can move on and how we can grab these individual keys that are being
clicked.
And from there, what do I want to grab?
I want to grab this value.
Right.
So I'm going to come that one out, coming in and in here.
I'm going to save.
So whenever I cook, I cook the Z key, we get Z, so X, C, F, D, so now we have successfully selected
or accessed each individual key.
The only thing remaining is just just printed on the screen that that's the only thing remaining.
But first things first.
Whenever we click anywhere else you guys can see, we get undefined.
So if you click on the queue, you're going to get.
Q But if it click like besides the Q like on the right of the queue, you're going to get undefined.
We do not want to get that right.
So before going there and before applying an F statement to control the flow of the flow of the logic
of this program, what I want to do is I want to cut this video right here.
And in the next lecture, we are going to continue creating this keyboard.
See you guys in the next one.