Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create the dimensions of the game.
All right, so this is the very first real lecture in which we will start to create this game and first
things first, we have selected our canvas.
Now there are some preset styling here, sort of preset code here.
And I'm going to go over them and then we are going to jump into like actual actually writing code.
So we have selected our canvas.
We have initialized the context.
We have some game parameters we are going to add onto this.
So we have our grid circle, which is the circle size is a fraction of the cell size.
Which is 70 percent of the cell size, that is the great service circle that you can see that the fraction
that is not highlighted, this wide space, that is the circle itself.
We have seven great columns, as in the original game, and we have six grid rows and the margin is
going to be zero point zero two.
And we have some colors.
So the background color is going to be the color that you can see on the background.
Then we have our color for the frame.
And so this is our frame that you can see the thing that's holding all the cells inside of that.
That is the frame bottom that you can see there.
We have the color for the eye, which is long green, and we have color for the eye, which is also
dark green.
So if I select that, there we go with that green color, we have color for the array, which is orange
and color are dark, which you have not used yet, which is dark golden rod.
Right.
So the first thing that I want to do is I'm going to I'm going to be commenting this out because this
is a pretty extensive project.
We are going to have like many hundreds of lines.
So I will I will try to comment everything out to so nothing is confusing for you.
So the first thing that I'm going to do is I'm going to create our dimensions.
So it is dimensions, so set, dimension's.
OK, and there is not going to be any parameter, OK, so what is the width of the game?
The width is going to be the window dot and with.
OK, so the height.
The height is going to be a window in our height.
What is the canvas elements with?
So we are going to say the canvas elements with is equal to the width and the canvas elements.
Height equals height, perfect.
So right after that, right, I'm going to do is I'm going to specify our margin as well.
So I'm going to say margin, OK?
The variables that we have on top there and I'm going to say math dot minimum.
Right.
So this the main method, what it is going to do is it is going to numeric expressions to be evaluated,
returns the smaller of a set of supplied numeric expressions.
So if you provide two values here, it is going to give you which whichever is smaller and I'm going
to pass in height and I'm going to pass in with this height and with this height.
It is coming from here and the width is coming from here.
Right.
And finally, after that, I'm going to create a function that is going to be called the new game,
the reason that we do this is because we we need to find out which orientation the pages in.
So whether it is landscape, for example, in this case, its landscape, or is it a portrait in the
case of like mobile phones?
Right.
So right after this one, I'm going to do as I'm going to go on top here and I'm going to create the
new game function.
Right.
And the new game function in here.
The only thing that I want to do is, OK, first off, let's create the function function, new game.
And in here, I just want to call the create grid function.
I know we have not created that grid function, but I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to call
that function.
All right, so right after that, what I would like to do is I need to set some variables because we
need to keep track of the time difference.
For example, what is the current frame that is playing?
What is the next firm and what is the what was the last frame?
So we need all this because we need to create our game loop.
The game loop is going to grab our time difference.
Also, the last time, the time which was dedicated to the last frame, we are going to grab our request
animation frame.
And in here I'm going to pass in a function which in just a sec we are going to create and this is going
to be the game loop function.
So function play game.
And there is going to be a very parameter of time now.
So first off, let's initialize the time last.
So I'm going to comment at initialise time last.
All right, so if it is not the time last, then why did it what is it now?
First off, if the time last is not true, it means that the time time last, the term which was dedicated
for the previous frame, has not been specified.
What does that actually mean?
It means that the game has not yet started.
So when the game has not yet started, we should specify the time last as the time now, because the
time now is actually the first frame of the game that is going to run.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to calculate, calculate the time difference.
So I'm going to save time.
Diff is equal to the time now, minus the time last.
So time now, minus time last.
And because we want to find find them out in one second, I'm just going to divide it by 1000 milliseconds.
And this is going to give us seconds or seconds and seconds.
Right and right after that.
Now, whenever each of the frames each frames those 60 frames per second, each of the frames they pass
and the next frame comes for the next frame.
We always grab our time now and we set it two time last.
And then when that passes, that is going to become the time last.
And the next frame is going to be the time now.
So I'm going to say time last equal to time now.
Perfect.
All right.
And finally in this, I want to call our the next frame as well.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say calling the next frame.
Right.
And for that, we are going to request information from and I'm going to pass in the game.
All right, so so far we have created the dimensions, the new game function, we have called the play
game function.
We have created our game loop.
Right.
And.
There is still a lot that we need to do now.
The logic of this game works in this way that we need to do a lot of things for us.
So we so we are able to actually do something real with this game.
Right.
OK, so the next thing that I would like to do is I'm going to go on top of the set dimension's.
And I want to create were the background, because now I want to draw that background that we have and
then you know what?
I'm actually going over this and we are first drawing the background, drawing the frame, the bottom
of the frame.
Then we are going to go over the dynamic.
Is the reason that we do all of this in JavaScript is because we actually don't don't want to do anything
in the demo.
You could draw that.
I guess you could do that, but I want to do it all, all the game.
I wanted to be drawn in JavaScript dynamically.
So let's go ahead and let's draw our background.
Drawback ground function, right, and in here, what I would like to do is let's first off create that
function.
Trah background, now, this function is going to have a canvas, context, canvas, context, art,
fair style.
So what is going to be star?
Now, we do not want a hard code, the film star.
So I'm just going to pass for now.
I'm going to pass and the color biji.
So this is going to be the background color and we are going to have a canvas context of fill in.
The background is going to be a rectangle.
That's why we say Felde Rect.
It's going to start from zero and and zero for the zero for the Y, and it's going to grab the width
and the height.
So if I say that and now let's open this up with life server, you should see something and I should
close this one because we're not working there.
We're working here.
So let's reload that.
And do we see I think it's very light.
OK, so if I come here, we have our color Viji, so let's see if we have specified that if nine.
If nine F nine.
Perfect.
We need to call that function as well, so that's why we don't see our color.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to open up this one, this inspector.
I'm going to go into the console, OK?
Let's go ahead and let's create the create great function, let's define that as well.
So we we have created the grid function there.
We called it inside the new game.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to call create that function as well so we can really see something
on the screen.
So this is going to be a way to create a grid function for a staff.
That's right.
The function name create grid.
And this grid is going to contain all of our roads.
This is an empty array.
You know, this is this is going to contain all of our roads and all of our columns.
So from now on, whenever I call this grid, what I actually mean is I am actually calling our entire,
like, layout of the game.
Right.
So first off, let's set the margins.
So I'm going to say set up cell size and margins.
Right.
So let's create this cell variable.
And I'm not going to give it any any value.
I'm just going to say cell.
And then I'm going to create the margin X and I'm going to create the margin Y.
Perfect.
Now let's find out what is the orientation of the device or device orientation.
All right, so first, the first thing that we need to find out if the device in the port Rotarian station,
so f if the with so let's let me put that there.
So if the with minus margin safety with minus the margin that we have divided by two times the grade
rose, we just multiplied by the grid rows.
And I'm going to grab this entire thing and I'm going to divide it by the columns, by a number of columns
that we have.
OK, read columns, if this is less than the height minus the margin, the reason that we always subtract
the margin is we need to account for the margin as well.
Time, too.
If this is the case, then it means that the device is in the portrait orientation and then we are going
to grab the cell.
And basically we need to define the size of that cell because we we declared the cell, but we initialize
the cell.
But we did not declare it.
So in here, let's go ahead and let's declare it.
So each cell is going to have a size of the width times the margin because each cell also has a margin
times to.
And then we are going to divide that by the number of columns that we have, right.
So the next thing that we need to do is we need to grab our margin X as well, and we need to define
it.
So the margin X in case this is portrait, it means like its upright, the margin X is going to be equal
to margin, but the margin Y is going to be the height of the cell that we have.
Margin Y is going to be the height of the cell, the height of the canvas or minus the cell size times
the grid.
So there we go, there is our grid rows and we are going to divide all of this by two.
So this is going to define for us if the device is portrait orientation or else, oops, let's put in
the comma device landscape.
Landscape orientation, orientation.
And I'm going to put passing the house here, so if it is the landscape orientation, what it is that
we are going to do differently.
So a landscape orientation is this orientation right here?
Right.
And in here, what we are going to do is in this portrait orientation, the cell size was the width
with times, the margin time, Stu.
But in the landscape orientation, the cell size is going to be the height minus the margin.
Time stood divided by the grid rows.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to calculate that as well.
So height minus the margin for each of the cells, times two.
And in case you're wondering about these times, two for the margin, that's because the margin for
any cell, any cell has to sort of margins the margin left the margin right.
In this case of portrayed, what we have is margin left and margin right.
In the case of landscape, we have margin, top and margin.
But that's why when when we are talking about the margin, we always multiplied by two and then we are
going to divide it by the grid rows that we have.
Right.
So in the portrait, what we had was great columns, right.
Because the location is standing up, the orientation is standing up or upright, but in the landscape,
because it's like like like this, then we are going to have a grid rows.
OK, now let's specify the margin.
Now we know that for the margin, for the Latin, for the device portrait orientation, we had margin
X equal to margin.
But for this we are going to have margin Y equal to margin.
So I'm just going to pass it.
And what is going to be the margin X now, we know that we we need to two sort of margins, right?
And the margins are on the each side of the cell.
So if I come here so you can see in this in this this is landscape.
So the margin for this cell is going to be half of this margin and half of this margin.
So we need to divide that by two at the end of the day.
So let's grab our margin X and I'm going to say divided by two.
But what should be divided by two?
We need to grab the width of any cell and then multiply it by the number of cells that we have.
So this is the width of the cell that we have from here all the way to here.
And then we need to multiply it by the number of cells that we have in this case.
What is the number of cells?
It's actually the number of columns or column one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
So we need to multiply it by that.
But we need to subtract from the with the cell itself, because cell is a fraction of this entire circle.
So this is this the cell.
This entire thing is going to be the circle or our road that we have.
So we're going to grab the with and I'm just going to say minus the cell size that we have times the
entire number of great columns that we have there.
So how many great columns we have?
We have seven and it is going to multiplied by that.
Now, keep in mind, the reason that I'm not hard coding these great columns and grid rows is you might
want to change the number of columns and the number of grid rows you might want.
For example, like let's say you might want like 10 columns and like eight rows, for example.
Then you would have to come in here and you would have to change them dynamically as well.
The reason that we are passing it in is because these are dynamic values.
If you change them, there are going to be changed here as well.
All right.
So so far, we're not going to see anything and we will get to that as well.
So where are we?
We were right here.
So we said that if the with minus the margin on each of the sides times, the grid rows.
Right.
I'm just going to go over this concept one more time.
So our with we subtract it, subtract from the margin because the margin, when we subtract it, we
are going to get the width of that specific circle that we have times, the grid rows, how many rows
that we have.
We have one, two, three, four, five and six rows because this is a portrait we need to count up
when it is landscape.
We need to count from one side to the next.
So ports, right.
We need to count from the top towards the from the bottom, towards the top.
If the rows divided by the columns is less than the height.
It means the devices portrait in the portrait, the width is always less than the height.
Right.
But in the landscape, the height is less than the width.
OK, so this is landscape and landscape.
The screen size is 15, six by 720.
That's the landscape.
But if it was 720 by 1500, then that would be landscape, right?
Sorry, that would be a portrait for devices.
Our margin X is going to be simply the margin, but the margin why we have to subtract from a decent
size and the number of rows that we have because we are counting up.
We need when we are counting up, we have the number of Rosero one, then row two, three, four, five
and six.
And whenever we are in the landscape orientation, we need to count the number of columns that we have.
So this is landscape.
So one, two, three, four, five, six and seven.
That's why we have passed them right there.
That set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.