Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about Web APIs.
All right, now, we we did touch on this topic in our first nature and just to recap where we are used
to extend the capability of JavaScript because JavaScript is single threaded some there are some tasks
the JavaScript is going to ask the browser to do.
All right, and those are Web APIs, those are the browser features that the browser actually does for
us, right?
That's how we can implement asynchronous programming through JavaScript because JavaScript is not alone.
Web APIs are there with JavaScript.
So this is an Indian Web page.
This is Web APIs.
And here is a list of all the APIs that are available.
Now, I think we have talked about a few of these.
So let's start from the and I just want to say that I wanted to do a project with the Bluetooth API.
But unfortunately, you know, that's the thing with Afghanistan.
I couldn't find like Bluetooth devices like Bluetooth lamps or Bluetooth like RC cars and that sort
of thing.
So I you know what?
I decided to not to do it because there was actually a website for it where you can change the color
of the light bulb on the screen and there was no actual physical device.
So I didn't want to do that because that wasn't like a very, really interesting thing to do.
I wanted to for example, if I could find in the market like buy something like a drone or a car or
like a wireless Bluetooth heartbeat detector.
But I couldn't find anything.
So I decided to not do this Bluetooth API because I thought this was like really, really cool, really
interesting that you can do these kind of things with JavaScript.
But unfortunately, maybe like if I could find I'm going to update this course with that project, I'm
going to show you how you can control it.
Drone with your browser.
That was really cool.
But I couldn't I couldn't find any device, so I just decided not to do it.
That was something that I wanted to share with you.
So in the see in this section, we have talked about the canvas API where we implemented the drawing
application.
We are going to dive more into the canvas later on when we get to our game development section.
We have talked about the console.
All right.
We have used it a lot.
So here we can see the dumb.
So dumb is also a Web API.
All the dumb events, click handlers, everything, event handlers, all of them are handled by the
BI, are implemented by Dume.
You can see the rest of them all here.
I'm just going to go over the ones that we have covered.
We have talked about the drag and drop API.
You can see that we have geolocation gamepad.
There are a lot of things we are going to cover the API as well.
All right, so now if I come here, we have talked about the pointer events and see assess, right.
And OK, so what else have we covered here?
We have talked about the storage, which was local storage.
We used it for the budget app and for the to do list app.
And this WebSocket, this is also a cool thing.
It allows you to create a real time chat application.
All right.
So, OK, so what else have we covered?
I think that's a there is nothing else that I can see that comes to my mind that we have covered so
far because we have had a lot of projects.
So this page is available for you.
It's right here.
So if you open this, we don't have any codes here in this lecture.
This is just like I'm just going to give you a few resources.
This is the first one.
This is the second one.
There is a third one as well.
This is the third one, actually.
I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to this is actually the second one.
So we pasted there.
So now we know what we were APSA.
We were using them, but we didn't have a proper name for them.
We'd never said that drag and drop is like an API.
I might have mentioned that what, once.
But we never like really like we never really grasp this idea of API.
OK, so in this in this chapter, what we are going to do is we need to master asynchronous programming
and the idea that we have Web APIs now we know what the Web is, right.
But we don't oops.
We know what what this part is.
But what about this part?
What actually is an API right now?
You can see that APIs like like everywhere on this page and you're going to hear a lot and you have
heard it a lot.
But if you're not sure, I'm going to try to explain it using this website.
This website is just going to grab videos from YouTube and you can create them, create a playlist,
for example.
This is the MNM.
And when you click on this button, it is going to play this video.
And I'm going to explain to you what appears what an API is through this video.
But before diving into what an API is in the world of programming, we need to know what an API is in
real life.
Now, APIs, they do not only refer to Web APIs, we we have a lot a lot of different APIs now, actually,
for other devices that we have.
We don't call them API, OK?
We just call him an interface.
Now, API is an application programming interface.
We are going to start with the interface word.
Now, the interface of a device allows you to interact with that device.
For example, you have a keyboard.
What is the interface of the keyboard?
All the keys that you can press on, you can press.
You have a TV remote.
That remote allows you to interact with the TV.
Right?
So we have interfaces in our real life.
And what the interfaces actually allow us to do are two things.
One, they allow us to interact with that specific device that we want to work with.
And number two, they abstract away the implementation part.
So whenever you're using, for example, your TV remote, TV remote.
Right.
And when you switch channels, you don't care or and you don't know how actually that TV remote switches
the channels.
You don't know that.
And we are not concerned about that.
We are only concerned about, for example, like switching to our favorite channel.
Right.
So that interface allows us to interact with that TV.
And also it abstracts away the implementation part, which is the part that we don't want to concern
ourselves with.
Now, imagine like there are a lot of devices.
I'm just going to go with electronic first.
There are a lot of electronic devices in our lives, more so in foreign countries than Afghanistan.
But still here we do have electronic devices.
Now, imagine if you wanted to use any of them, you would you would have to go through the process
of learning how that device works, but and how difficult that would have been.
OK, that would have been like frustrating all the time that I have to learn, even though even even
when I'm eating, I have to learn.
Even when I'm sleeping, I have to learn even when I'm like walking.
I have to learn.
Now, that's the good part about interfaces, interfaces.
They allow us to, for example, turn on that oven right.
Turn it on and work with it or bake something or cook something without even thinking about how that
oven works.
So this is the whole idea of an interface now.
And application programming interface or an API is a computing interface which defines interactions
between multiple software intermediaries.
It defines the kinds of calls and requests that can be made, how to make them the data formats that
should be used and the.
Conventions to follow.
All right, now let's try everything back to go together, interfaces allow us to interact or communicate
with an object now, be it a physical object or a software object.
Now you're getting how we are coming back to JavaScript objects, right?
As a user of the interface, we do not need to understand the implementation.
Right.
We do not need to know how a how the how it works.
We just need to know what we have been allowed to change your seat.
So you're changing the channels.
That is what you're allowed to do.
We don't care about anything else.
We just care about what is allowed to us to do.
All right, interfaces, as I told you, abstract away the implementation.
Now, while the UI is made for the user of the application, the API is made for the application programmer.
Now, we as a programmers, we are not concerned with the interface.
We are concerned with the API, with the application programming interface.
We are concerned with the code side of this entire application.
So here we have a website.
I don't know how this this is pronounced this you list you.
I don't know what how this is pronounced, but still so this we are not concerned about how these how
all this works.
We are concerned about the code behind this, OK, the code that fetches this data for us.
We are concerned about that.
Right.
Why?
Because whenever you're interacting with an API, for example, the canvas API, you remember when we
initialize this canvas in our Web page, we needed to to say what kind of canvas it is that we want.
We wanted a
2D canvas.
All right.
So that is the expectation of the API.
API expects you to use it in a certain way.
And the canvas API is used in a 2D.
Right.
And that expectation allows us or sets the limit for us on how we can use data that API.
So how actually this API works.
Now we know what the APIs but how actually this works.
So if I'm just going to like lower this volume like maybe like to six when I click on this button,
even though this button has nothing to do with this YouTube page.
But what it does is when I click on it and HTML sorry I e-mail an EPA request is made to the YouTube
servers.
And what is that request?
The request is to play this Eminem rap song.
Right, to play this video and the web.
The YouTube server is going to respond with this video.
Right.
So if I were to reload this, it might take like a few seconds.
Until then, I'm going to explain this.
You can see that whenever you reload, you go ahead.
You can see everything like many singers here, for example, Maroon five, if you click on it, it
is going to show you all the lists.
When you clicked, you made a request.
What was the request?
The request went to the server of the celesta and it asked, OK, I want to grab all the songs of Maroon
five, which are on your server.
Just give them to me.
And the server responded with this.
All right.
OK, so this is how AIPA calls they're made, OK, this in simple terms, you make a request and the
person on the other side is going to give you something.
Now, the channel through which.
OK, the channel through which you make this request and the channel through which that other person
is going to give you your response, that channel is very simple.
Again, I'm just going to reiterate this.
When you make a request to a server for data and that server responds with the data that you asked for,
the channel through which this communication happens is called an API.
Right now, we have a lot different types of APIs you can see here.
These are Web apps.
We have many other each website, for example, Spotify has a way as an API, for example, PIXELS has
an API, YouTube has an API, Facebook has an API.
All the Web pages that you can see on the on the Internet, all of them, they have APIs.
Some are some are available for you to implement in your programs, for example, like the YouTube API
is is available for you to implement in your program.
And what that API would allow you to do is, for example, you can grab a list of, for example, songs
or music videos, video, music, music videos.
And you can you can just insert that into your website without doing any extra thing.
And it is always going to be there.
If the author of that playlist changes that playlist, the playlist is going to change automatically
in your website as well.
So this is what an API is.
This is what why we use APIs and we are sort of done with this discussion of the API.
If you're not sure, you can just go ahead and like we watch this video one more time.
And at the end of this video, I'm just going to give you one other resource as well.
And this is just to visualize the call stack, what the Web APIs they do.
And what is the call by?
Q What is this?
You can see these arrows of the circular arrows.
They're called the event loop.
OK, so if I were now we have this code here and what this code is, what this does is we have a button.
When we click that button, we are going to run a set time out function.
That's a time that function is going to run a function timer within that function time or function.
We're going to log to the console.
You click to me.
Right.
And that's a timeout is going to run after two seconds.
In the meantime, we are going to run console log and then there's a timeout and then this console.
So before actually running this, let's go over the how this is going to run.
I'm just going to zoom in a bit more like I think this is readable now.
Now, how this is going to run is whenever I say save and run, it is going to run this code first.
But it it it it is going to find out, OK, that this is a click event.
This happens whenever I click this button.
So this code, because this is a DOM interaction, it is going to be handed over to the Web API to this
section on the right.
And then we are going to come to this line of this line of code, because this is done by this is actually
a done by the this is a console API.
This is done by the Web API as well.
But but we are not this is not like any click event that we have to wait for the user to click or this
is not a set timeout function that we have to wait for
for some time so we can implement this function.
This is just log in to the console.
Hi.
So we are going to immediately push it to the call stack and then pop it from the call stack.
And the result is just going to be high in the console and the and the console off the webpage and the
console of the browser.
Right.
And then we are going to come to this time out function now, this time out function.
It requires five seconds to pass.
Now, this is going to be handed over to the Web APIs because timers are are handled by Web APIs as
well.
This is an asynchronous code, right?
Asynchronous code means that this code can run in here.
And in the meantime, we can run the other line of code as well.
It means that in at the same time, we can run multiple tasks, even though JavaScript is single threaded,
even the JavaScript can run only one task.
That's what the whole ideology behind asynchronous programming is.
So we are going to pass it to the Web APIs and we're going to ask the Web API, OK, this is this is
your job.
You should handle this.
And remind me after five seconds, after five seconds pass, they are going to come to the callback
queue and the event loop is going to push it to the call stack when it is pushed to the constuction.
We are not.
No longer concerned with the sad time on because said time out is not our responsibility.
It is the responsibility of the Web API when the timer finishes the function, said time out is going
to come to the callback queue.
Now, think of this callback queue as a way of reminding the JavaScript engine once more that you have
something to do.
You should have done this.
You should do this after five seconds and now that five seconds have passed, grab your function and
implement that function.
It's no longer my responsibility because I counted from one to 5000 milliseconds and then I gave you
the function.
The rest is up to you.
What do you want to do with it?
That's what the callback is.
The callback queue is going to grab the tasks from Web APIs and it is going to push it to the cost.
The cost stack is the territory of JavaScript, VM or execution engine.
Right.
So in the meantime, the set time out is calculating in the Web API because you can see we have three
friends actually in here.
Well, this is not actually a friend, only these two.
This is just pushing it back to back to the stack.
In the meantime, we are going to run console log as well.
So I'm going to say and save and run it.
And I'm just going to let you just go ahead and watch it.
It is going to run a bit quickly.
And that's where they should have made it like a bit slower.
So it's really visible.
But still, I'm going to run it a couple of times so you can understand what happens.
So there we go.
All right, so we are done with this process.
So actually, what happened?
I'm just going to go over this one more time.
Whenever we click and we run, this is calculated, OK?
When this code is run, it is because this is a dumb it is going to be passed to the dumb.
Why it stayed here is because of this click.
If I click, then this code runs.
If I don't click, then this code will never run.
Right.
So whenever we run the code, this is going to be passed to the Web API and then we are going to run
the console like, hey, we are going to run it.
And then immediately it is going to be popped from the stack because it's done.
When it is done, it should good.
It should go away when it is done.
And then we are going to go to sit time out and said time out is going to be passed to the Web API and
then after five seconds it is going to come to the callback queue.
The event loop is going to push it back to the call stack.
It is it's going to push the time out function, not the set timer.
So time out is done and the time out is going to run this call, this console log.
But even before this five seconds runs, we are going to log to the console.
Welcome to Lapore Loop or whatever.
So it goes to the Web API.
This is run it pages pass to the Web API and this console luggage run.
Oops.
I think I should do it one one more time.
So console log is run popped past to the Web API, this console longest run and popped and we wait for
five seconds, see the timeout function and the timeout function implements the console lock and then
we are done.
Now we are waiting for the click.
If I click on it what is going to happen if I click on it?
You are going to run a function which is the click the clock event.
We are going to run that which is going to run this set time out and we are going to wait for two seconds.
What in this case, what do you think in this case?
What do you think in the case of said this Satima, what do you think is going to come to the callback?
You.
You're right, the timer function is going to come to the call by Cube because that is the part which
is not yet run, the timer runs in the Web API.
We don't run it again.
When the timer comes in, time or function comes into the callback.
The envelope loop is going to push it back to the call stack and the call stack is going to run the
set time this time or function.
What is this time or function going to do?
It is simply going to log to the console.
So let's run this one more time.
All right.
Clear set time out.
This runs time function, which is time out comes here.
It comes here.
It runs the console log and then both of them pop.
And when I click on this, you see unclick it runs this set time out, set time and waits for two seconds.
This is timer and timer, just console logs it.
So this is the entire ideology behind asynchronous programming.
Starting from our next lecture, we are going to dive into Ajax, asynchronous JavaScript and XML and
we are going to work with the real data.
We are going to grab data.
We are going to make requests.
So this chapter is starting from next lecture is going to get really, really, really interesting.
See you guys.
The.