Hi, everyone, welcome to the second lecture where we make or no effect dynamic.
All right.
So we have successfully grabbed the U.S. class name that we are on and we have started inside this variable.
We are going to create another variable called Active Link.
I'm just going to call it active link because whenever we are on that active link.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's grab the active link.
We are going to change the background image of it.
We are going to say the background color of it.
Sorry, we are going to say so.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to do back Tick's here.
This is the good thing about queries that actually can do anything.
And we are going to grab the data dash page attribute, but the value for it is going to Krampf is going
to come from our class and we are going to store it dynamically.
You're going to say Klusener, the reason that we store it dynamically is.
OK, so I should pass in that one as well.
The reason that we story dynamically is because whenever we're scrolling up and down, we do not want
a hard code which section it is that the user is scrolling.
For example, you have created a website, and whenever the user scrolls down, you're not going to
go to the user's home and you're going to recode your website for each individual user.
What you're going to do is you're going to make sure that it acts dynamically.
It is functional on its own.
And this data page attribute actually comes from our HDMI from right here.
So the data page has home about services and contact.
So where are these going to come from?
From Klusener.
So the class name comes from entry, the target date class name.
So if we are on the home, we are going to grab the class name is going to be home and we are going
to pass it right here.
And this data page is going to be home when we are on the about the data page is going to be about services
or contact.
It's going to act in the same way for all of them.
Right.
So after that, what I want to do is I want to create another constant and I'm going to call it aliment.
I meant index and I'm going to store it in and I'm going to say basically we are going to store some
information in here.
So now we are going to grab the index of that element that we are on.
And that element is we are going to grab the index again from our e-mail, and that is data index.
And you guys can see that the index in this area, we don't have indices starting from zero.
They start from one.
Right.
But in JavaScript, they start from zero because we are going to use this data index in JavaScript.
That's why we have given in zero right away.
All right.
So it starts from zero, even though we have four sections, the length of the section is one greater
than the last index.
So in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say entry.
The target now from there from the target.
What I want to do is I want to get an attribute, get attribute.
We do have this attribute inside the target as well.
And what is the attribute that we want to get?
It is the data Dasch index.
We want to grab that that attribute.
All right.
So now what I want to do is we are going to know we are going to grab the coordinates as well.
And I told you about the bounden client rectangle or binding contract that we are going to use in here
and also in our.
Gallery carrousel, because we want to make sure which positions exactly belong to our sections, so
to avoid the confusion that if we are, for example, on our first section, we don't want this background
color to go to the content.
We want to make sure exactly where we are in the page and what are the exact coordinates of our section.
And then we are going to pass it inside the JavaScript to make sure that JavaScript grabs the exact
coordinates of that section.
So we are going to say active link, dot, get bounding client Recht.
This is going to grab all the coordinates of top bottom height and with top and left all the information
that we want to grab when it comes to positioning is going to be stored inside the cordon and it's very
variable.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a directions object because we are going to store
key value pairs.
So I'm going to set height.
So the height is going to be equal to the coordinates that height.
And if you remember, coordinates is actually our target bounding client direct.
And the height actually refers to this get bounding client.
Right.
We are going to say with so the width in the directions, it has to come from a circuit bound and client
rucked as well.
So we are going to say coordinates with.
We are just making sure that we are selecting all the edges of that section and that section is in the
correct spot and where we want it to be and when the section is in the currents is in the correct spot.
We want to apply a background color to the novel length associated with that section.
So this is the part where I told you guys that it is it's not difficult, it's easy, but it's a bit
trickier to do.
You know, we we have tricky things and we have difficult things.
This is not difficult.
This is super easy, barely an inconvenience.
But this is tricky.
You should know what you what you are doing.
All right.
So now we have successfully grabbed on the directions.
So the last thing that I hear that I want to do is I want to create an if statement because I want to
control the flow of the document.
All right, so if.
And create the structure of the if statement, if entry does not enter, if entry is intersecting,
is intersecting, if the entry is intersecting, which I showed you, which disvalue was true, whenever
we we we went up and down.
So let me comment that in.
And I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to leave it there.
So whenever we go up and down, let me try this.
So if I go up, we are going to get this.
We are going to get this whenever the end is intersecting entries.
True.
So if I come here, we are going to see is intersecting.
Well, this is false in this case.
But if I come here, this one should be true.
This is true.
Whenever we get that with whenever we get that section, the intersection, sexting is going to be true.
But when we don't get it, it is going to be false.
So if I come here now, this should be true and this is true.
So if I go to the top and grab the final one for this one, it is true.
But if I grab the previous one now, this belongs to our services in here.
Let's go ahead and let CNN and then here it says is intersecting is false because this does not belong
to our home section.
It belongs to the about section.
All right.
Or the service, whatever section that we are not on that is going to have and is intersecting property
are false.
You know what?
I'm just going to go over this concept one more time, and I feel like this is a bit confusing.
So whenever we scroll, we get some sort of date, right, so whenever we grab that data, we want to
make sure that we grab that section's data and whenever we don't grab that section's data, we don't
want to run the code.
So whenever the section data belongs to the home section home, we want to we want to run that code.
So if I go ahead, come down, we are going to see another one.
And when it is intersecting in here, it says intersecting.
Whenever it is intersecting, we want to apply that background color.
That's how simple it is.
So we are going to say Tranz.
That style, that background color.
Oops.
What is that dot background?
Background, you're going to make me type, aren't you?
So we are going to say that style, that background color, well, actually, we are not going to say
background color.
We're just going to set a property to it because we have already defined the background colors here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say set property.
This is another very useful, useful method with.
With the CSI style, right, so in here, we are going to pass in a height, so whenever the trans style
has a height, what do we want?
Where do we want the property value come from?
So this method has two arguments.
The first argument is going to be the property name.
Like in here we have a position as a property name and each property name has a value like this.
Sticky is a value for this position name.
So what what do we want the height to be?
We want to provide back to because we want to grab the high dynamically.
So we are going to say directions.
Where do we want to grab the height?
We want to say that height now heights they usually have BEXELL.
So we are going to add the pixel as well.
Let's comment out this concept of log, and I'm going to provide three more, because we are going to
change these two to eidetic with these two to top and these two to the left.
Right, and now, finally, whenever we grab the proper place for the sections and for our trans transition
background.
We want to grab the chance and we are going to say color and now we are going to say background.
Back.
Ground colour, we are going to set it equal to our array, whatever it is, gradients.
Aliment index aliment, come on, buddy element.
Aliment index, let's save it and now it says, cannot set property background, color of undefined
Tranz background, color gradients.
So let's click here.
It says entry.
This is undefined.
So we do have a bunch of errors.
We have actually a radar for each anonymous and we have kind of set off undefined.
So if I click there, it says Gradients Element Index.
Undefined, so what is undefined in this one?
Background, color.
Of undefined.
All right, this isn't tape error, and then we have a radar for each and then we have intersection
Observer Danowski 21.
So I think all of these errors are going to be resolved with only one of them if you resolve one of
them.
So in here we have gradients, we have our chance.
This is this is the problem because we have not tapped into the world of the style.
We have simply said color.
We should write style.
And when we save it now, all the errors are gone.
So now when I reload it and if I come down, you guys can see we still do not get our effect right.
All right, so let me make this window a bit smaller and this one smaller as well.
OK, this is not something that we want.
So let's go full screen and let's close this.
We do see that the colors, they change, but the position is incorrect.
This is not where the colors should change.
And now you can see.
So this is the home color.
Keep in mind the size of these rectangles.
So if I come down when we get to the about, because home about are about the same size, the rectangles
of the set are the same size.
But when we come to the services, because services is a bigger word than about this rectangle just
got bigger and then it gets a bit smaller because of the content.
I hope you can see that.
So we are grabbing that, but the position is incorrect.
So this position we have height coordinates, height with coordinates, with top coordinates, top and
left, with coordinates left.
We have height coordinates, directions, height with directions, with pixels, top directions top.
And we have the left directions height.
Why is it why is this one height.
I mean when we copy that we forgot to change it, so let's save it.
And now it is working.
So if I go ahead and if I come down to the 70 percent, we should be able to see that it switches to
the about.
And if we come down and switches to services and then contact.
So basically, we are done with our project and our chapter and see you guys in the next chapter.