Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to get our exchange rate.
All right, so the euro that we will be making requests is this and you can see that it has an axis.
Well, technically, when you're creating programs, you should hide this axis key and no one else should
use it, because if you're fetching data from a paid you ORL or paid API, you and you don't want to
pay for that you are or for the for the requests that you make, then you will you will have a limited
amount of requests either per day or per per hour or per month or per week.
It ranges from 50 per day to 2000 per hour or even 20000 like per hour or per day, something like that.
So you're going to have a limitation if you don't want to pay.
So you need to, like, hide this access.
But because this is for teaching purposes, I don't want to hide it and I want to show it to you.
Otherwise, how would you create this?
And if you exceed the amount that is allowed, the I mean, the requests, then you are going to get
a four to nine error that is going to say, which is a client error.
And HTTP status is for tonight.
It is a client error and it says that you have made too many requests and just go ahead and and wait
for an hour or two and then make requests and then it should go away.
Now, the reason that this is being displayed like this inside the browser is because I've installed
a Jason Vue extension for Chrome.
I'm not sure what this extension is available for Firefox or not.
You can just go ahead and and check it out if I deactivated and reload.
This is what we are going to get.
Very ugly.
Right.
But if you come to Extension's and activate it and reload the page, you can see that we sort of get
like a mini text editor or something like that.
So that's what I wanted to show here.
These two tabs, I'm not going to talk.
Hopefully we I want to talk about.
But if if we take too much time, I'm not going to talk.
And then we are we have to talk about it in the next lecture.
So what do we have here?
Let's first decode the code that we have here and then we can actually come up with a way to find out
how can we experiment with this and how can we create this application.
And on the second and the second on second thought, we will be talking about these two tabs in this
structure as well.
So you can see this is the date that we are getting these conversion rates.
But now the thing is this base.
So the base currency is going to be EQR or Yero, right.
So this is the base currency.
It means that all the rest of the currencies that you can see here, all of them are calculated based
on the euro.
So one euro is one, one euro is four point three.
I'm not sure what this is.
I think it's an Australian.
No, no, that's a Yudi.
I'm not sure what this is.
So we could always check it and say it in the browser.
A Z is a tided a Z currency.
I'm just going to check this one.
I'm not going to check the rest of the.
It's Unirea, United Arab Emirates, their home, their home, yeah.
So one euro is this many dirhams, this many Afghanis, this many Al and I'm just going to use the popular.
So one euro is how many USD?
Easy to decode for everyone.
So one euro is one point one seven two, so you can see that the data that we get is actually have a
base of euro.
And why is this something that you need to know?
You might ask.
The reason for that is the thing that I'm mostly going to be working with is my own current country's
currency, which is Afghani or Afghani, as you are used to hearing it.
So one Afghani equals zero point zero one three.
All right.
But one Afghani is zero point zero one one euro.
You can see how different these are.
Right.
So if I were to, like, copy this and put it right here and let's say change it to one, I don't know,
like, let's see, one barony, Bahamian dollar or Canadian dollars, Canadian dollar.
So if I change it to.
Where is the where were you, Canada?
Yeah, here it is.
So you can see that one Canadian dollar is actually ninety point one oh Afghani's.
So we get different exchange rates for different.
I should have done the other way around, but still, that's OK.
But the thing is that when these are different and our base of the data is euro, how can I change this
this zero point zero one three to zero point zero sorry, this zero point zero one one to the zero point
zero one three.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the calculator.
So let's go ahead and let's grab this calculator.
The calculator is right here.
So what I'm going to do is so we have our basic URL, right?
And that is euro, not base euro based currency.
This is your right.
And we know that euro to Afghani, Afghani to euro is zero point zero one one.
And I just see if I can get it the other way around because, you know, right away right now the Internet
is disconnected and because the electricity is gone.
And basically I'm speaking from the top of my head.
So forgive me if I say something that I'm not supposed to say because my thing you can see that it's
not working.
So it doesn't matter what I do, it's going to show me the same thing because there is no Internet connection.
So I'm just going to go ahead and explain this part.
And if electricity comeback's comes back, we are going to continue the structure.
If it doesn't, then I'm just going to cut it and I'm going to wait for whenever it comes.
So that's the thing about this country, all right, so one euro is going to be zero point zero one
one sorry, one Afghani is zero point zero one one euro and one if one is zero point zero one one one
three dollars.
So it's different.
How can I make sure that the value that we get is actually correct?
Why is this a problem?
This is a problem because whenever you want to create that application, because the base is euro,
you are limited to euro.
So you can change from a currency, from a certain currency to euro or from euro to a certain currency.
So either one of these two currencies should be euro.
So in that sense, you're limited.
You cannot, for example, exchange, let's say, USD to like a Z or a Canadian dollar or Australian
dollar.
You cannot change something that is not euro to something that is not euro.
You're not you're not able to do that with this set of data.
All right.
But how can we do that?
So the way that we can do that, as we have to find out the exchange rate.
So the what is this exchange rate?
This is not the exchange rate.
Right.
What is the exchange rate from Afghani to Europe?
So the way that we can get that is so we know that one euro is ninety point or two six.
Right.
If I want to get the exchange rate for that, the only thing that I have to do is I want to divide one
by this.
And when I divided by that.
Let me put it on the side here.
Can I bring come on.
Yep, we can do it.
So you can see that the screen is lagging because there is no electricity, so I'm just going to put
it one divided by I see to this ninety point.
Come on, buddy.
So it's ninety point oh two six seven one five.
And if I save it, this is what we get.
So the exchange rate is zero point zero.
So one one actually, we got that here.
All right.
So this is what we get how we can we convert this to zero point zero three.
The the way that we can convert this is so this is the base that we got.
Right.
If I can if I multiply this by the base for the USD that we have based on the euro, what is the US?
So we have one point one seven.
So if I multiply that by where is that?
It's right here.
I'm going to keep it there by one point one seven two six two six eight four.
And if I save it, you can see what it is that we get.
We get zero point one three.
And isn't this the same as what we have here?
So in our function that we will be creating what we are going to do is we are going to grab the base
currency and we we are going to find this out because this isn't a currency companioned.
The currency companion will allow you to exchange currencies without going to Google.
So we need to find this one out.
And when we find this one out, we just what do we do?
We grab that currency that we want to convert, a.k.a. from currency cote, and then we divide upon
it one.
OK, so we say one divided by by that from currency, so one divided by this.
And we are going to get something called right.
We are going to get a number and then that number will be multiplied by the currency to which we want
to change.
So in this case, we want it to change from Afghani to dollars and that's how we did it.
So if you want to change it from Canadian dollars, which should be up here, Sead, so this is the
Canadian dollar.
So if you want to change Canadian dollar to, let's say to CDF, what do you do first?
You say one divided by the Canadian dollar.
So let's do that.
So one divided by one point five four nine oh three three.
This is because we want to get the base.
I multiplied it to one divided by one point five four nine oh three three.
So let's save it.
So this is the base.
So one euro is going to be sorry.
One Canadian dollar is going to be zero point six for Europe.
So now we get this when we get this and we want to change not to euro, but Canadian dollar to CDF or
whatever the says or to you and the United States dollar.
We just have to multiply this by one point one seven.
So multiply one point one seven two six.
So we get so this is the conversion rate.
All right.
And if you multiply 1000 Canadian dollars by this, you're going to get seven hundred and fifty six
dollars.
So 1000 Canadians, if I am not mistaken in my calculations, is going to be 756.
And you can see that it's one point five four and it is one point one.
So point four is different and that is going to account for two hundred and fifty sort of dollars or
two hundred and forty.
Three, I think, if I'm not mistaken.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to cut to right here.
So we are done with our lecture.
And in the next lecture, what we are going to do is we are going to dive into this code.
There is no reason and diving into this code because there is no electricity and this Yooralla is not
going to work.
So we need to work for.
We need to wait for electricity to come back.
And then I'm going to come back for you.
It's just going to be like the time that you just go ahead and press on the clock and you go to the
next video.
You just press on the next and you go to the next video.
For me, it might be like a few hours or a few days.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.