Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, I'm going to show you the necessary setup for this course.
Now, I know that you have previous experience of achievement and success and you definitely have a
code editor of your choice, using that code editor is perfectly fine.
That is OK, be that viscose, be that Atem Brackett's sublime text or even notepad, that is cool as
well.
I mean, if you're comfortable with it, then that is going to be OK.
Right.
But if you want to code along with me exactly the way I do, what I would want you to install is going
to be the visual studio code.
This is the in my opinion, of course, and this is highly subjective, the best code editor in the
world.
Right.
And you can install it by going to this website code, that visual studio dot com, and it is going
to probably detect your operating system and it is going to give you an option for downloading it on
your operating system.
Or you could just go ahead and choose it for whatever it is you're operating system.
Once you have downloaded it, the installation process is fairly simple.
Just have to go ahead and breeze through it and that's going to be no problem.
And then right after that, you can go ahead and open it up.
You're going to get a welcome page, which I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to close it.
On the left side, we have some tabs.
The first one is whenever you want to insert files and create files.
Right.
And first stuff I want I'm going to walk you through some settings that I think are going to be beneficial
for you.
So go ahead to file the file tab from there to preferences and then settings.
And in here type font size, you can increase the font size.
For me, it's eighteen.
You can increase it.
You can decrease it.
All right, and the next thing is now, whenever you have a line that is too long for the width of the
viscose window, you're going to see that there is actually like this a a horizontal scroll bar.
If you want to avoid that, you're just going to say word.
Rob, and just go ahead and grab the word Rob and say on and then whenever the line breaks at the page,
it is going to go to the next line.
Right.
So that's these settings.
And as far as the extensions are concerned for this fiasco that I'm using, I want you to install a
few of them that are necessary to to go along with me.
So the first one is going to be the code formatter, the prettier code formatter.
And you just you just have to come in here, search extensions in the marketplace just right.
PERTIERRA And you're going to see this.
And in here, you're instead of seeing the disable button, you're going to see something like install,
just click on it and it is going to install it.
The next theme, the next extension that I want you to install is going to be the life server.
And this is used whenever you type something.
And when you save that the changes, you're going to see the changes on the Web page in real time.
The next one is going to be JavaScript code snippets instead of that as well.
And finally, install the bracket PAKKALA Ricer.
Now, before actually wrapping this lecture up, I would like to show you some extensions.
And these extensions are actually Vrsaljko themes.
I've got a bunch of them, and throughout this course, I will be changing, I think, to to maybe like
a couple of times, like I would like to change stuff up, you know, to make sure that things they
stay interesting.
Right.
So at first you're probably going to see the the original and the default theme for the voice code.
You can go ahead and search for any theme that you want.
But towards the end of this course, I will be using the one dark pro theme which I recently found and
which is really, really, really awesome.
And I do have another awesome theme as well, and that is Dracula.
So if you just go ahead and search for Dracula and depending on your Internet connection, it is going
to pop up very, very soon.
And it says that I don't have an Internet connection, even though I do.
That's why it doesn't show it.
So it's Dracula and I'm going to show it to you guys here.
I do have it installed.
There it is.
This is Dracula official.
You can go ahead and install this as well.
And I think that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next chapter, where will we will start talking about JavaScript for real.
So let's get coding.