Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create the superhero entry class.
All right, so the way that I'm going to tackle this OLP project is we are going to create this application
in relatively shorter videos than we used to do.
Like even I am going to try to keep it under five minutes.
So they are, like, easily digestible.
Right.
So first things first.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create the superhero entry class.
So what we are going to do as a general, what we are going to have is we are going to have three classes
and one is going to be for superhero entry, which is going to deal with our form.
The second one is going to be our superhero list, which is going to deal with the right part of the
screen where all the superheroes are listed and the third class is going to deal with local stories.
But first, we are going to go over the first and the second class and all the methods.
And at the end of this, towards the end of this chapter, we are going to implement the local stories.
So to be able to create any class, we just ride the class keyword and the name of the class.
The difference is that the first character in that name should also be capitalized.
So we say superhero entry.
I'm just going to call it entry.
And in here we are going to have a constructor.
Now, the purpose of this constructor is whenever we call the superhero class and we pass in parameters,
those parameters are going to start arguments.
Those arguments are going to pass inside its constructors parameter.
Right.
So the first parameter, because this is entry, we are basically involved.
We are basically working with three different parameters.
So one is going to be superhero name, superhero universe and then superhero power.
So I'm just going to say superhero name and I'm going to say superhero universe and.
Universe, and we are going to say superhero power, right, and in here, what we are going to do is
we are going to say this, that superhero name first one is name this that superhero name.
Why is it the smallest should be kept?
All right, so this one is going to be, when we say this, that superhero name should be equal to a
superhero name and we are going to do it for the other two as well.
So this superhero universe is going to be a superhero universe.
And this that superhero name is going to be superhero power.
So now we have created our class for superhero entry.
And this what this class is going to do is going to grab the user entry, which is for superhero named
Super Hero Universe and superhero power.
OK, so the next class, the next class that I'm going to create is going to be the superhero list.
So super hero list list class.
I'm just going to ride the class here as well.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say class.
Let's capitalize the first word.
So it's superhero and I'm going to call it list.
Right.
So what what do we have here?
And now inside here we are not going to have any constructor.
Right.
But inside here, we are going to have multiple methods.
So the methods for adding a superhero to the list, clearing superhero inputs when that list, when
the hero is has been added and validating the superhero for errors, the superhero form for errors,
validating the superhero form for success.
And basically we are going to implement all of these inside inside this class except for the local storage,
which is going to have a different class.
So everything that we will be doing inside this application will be added as methods are as functions
to this class.
And as far as Les is concerned, we are going to provide a different class for that.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.