Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to fetch jokes.
All right, so before actually implementing this concept, you always need to go over the documentation
for that specific API that you want to make requests to, the reason for that is there are actually
two general reasons.
And the first one is that any website has a different basis or a an EDP or out to which you can send
it and a request or an API endpoint.
First off, you need to grab that API input input from their documentation.
And secondly, if there are some headers required, some authentication required, you need to know
about that, because if you do not provide the headers or the authorization, you will not be able to
fetch any kind of data.
So you can see that this is going to be this is the link that I gave you in here.
OK?
It's right here.
It's that link.
And if you open it, you are going to come here and it says can be used for an API, for fetchingly
random geo specific joke or searching for jokes in a variety of formats.
We are not going to complicate this process because this is going to be just a very simple case of fetching
the jokes.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here is we are going to go ahead and you can see that this is going to be the
euro that we have.
So this is going to be our base.
You are right.
And what I'm going to do as we do have this.
So I'm just going to click there.
I'm just going to go to Extension's and I'm going to do that and I'm going to close this right now.
We shouldn't get that perfect.
So this is the euro that we are going to making requests, which you can see that, OK.
Let me show it to you here.
You can see that we have an accept property here as well.
And if you do not provided this accept applications, Jason, you will not be able to fetch any kind
of data.
So you can see that it says when you do this, you're going to get this response.
So now let's go ahead.
So this is our application.
I just opened up, opened it up with live server.
So what we are going to do is whenever I click the button, I want to generate a I generate a joke.
So first off, let's let's grab the joke button.
So joke.
I'm just going to call it a joke.
Beaton It's going to be document dot query selector.
And I'm just going to select it with the element selector.
And then we have our joke paragraph which I'm just going to call Joke Para.
OK, document that query selector by now, we are very familiar with this query selector.
I'm going to select it with the class, which is a joke.
So whenever the joke button the event, when the joke button is clicked, I want to get a joke.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create this function.
Now, keep in mind, this is going to be an async function.
So you need to provide the async keyword in front of the name of the function.
So function get a joke and there is not going to be any parameter.
So how are we going to be able to do this first stuff?
I'm going to create a variable and I'm going to say joke you are al and that you are l that I showed
you.
I'm going to store it in here.
And so let's come here and let's grab.
So this is the you are else.
It says that you should do a get request to this.
You are right.
So let's go ahead and let's face it.
So this is where you are now.
Let's go ahead and let's say a response.
Consed, come on.
Response.
Right.
And we are going to fetch our data now, the Fed is going to grab the euro and any other headers that
or authorizations that we might have we have not talked about in this context.
That's why I included this, because all APIs are not going to be straightforward.
Some of them, they require authorization or some headers.
All right.
So first off, we are going to pass our joke, your URL.
So there is the joke, you URL, and then you put in the comma and then you open curly braces inside
the curly braces.
When you do headers, you can see that it gives you headers, a header object, an object literal or
an array of two items item or an array of two item arrays to set requests headers.
So whenever you are doing the request, you need to send the headers.
So we are going to open another curly brace because is going to be a set.
But this in this case, you are just going to say accept our application.
Make sure to spell it correctly, CIG's where is this coming from?
It's coming from right here.
So when it says accept applications, Jason and you can see it says EDG, I'm going to zoom in.
You have to provide it inside the headers, right?
You have to provide it inside the headers.
Then you are going to get this this results.
So now that our fetch is complete, if I were to say Consols log response, let's see what we get.
So this is going to be our this is our application where we are working.
Let's bring it down.
Let's go up.
Bring it up, come here.
So now if I click on this, you can see that we get a promise so that Fach was successful, but in here
it suspending.
Why does it say pending?
The reason that it's suspending is we have not added the await key word.
The key word does literally what it says.
It is going to await our response until the response is completed and then it is going to storeyed within
this variable.
If the response is not completed, it is not going to stop it.
That's why the async a wait keywords, they go hand in hand.
They are a combo.
You cannot use one without the other if and this way it only works when you have a sink.
So now if I save this, we should get some sort of response.
Can see we get the response, we get all this mumbo jumbo.
But the important thing is that the status is 200 and you can see our headers right here, OK, that
we have at it now what how can we turn this into something meaningful and we know how we can do that.
We basically say const response HRIS pontes data.
I'm going to call it response data and we are going to say response Dargis.
So what does Jason is going to do?
It is going to read it, convert it into Jason file and then pass it into something the JavaScript can
understand.
All right.
But these three processes, they take some time.
So we need to wait until these processes are complete and then store it within their response data.
So response data now, we should get some meaningful response.
Now you can see that we get this is a joke.
Doctor, do you want to hear the good news or the bad news?
Patient good news, please.
Doctor, we are naming disease after.
So most of the jokes I don't get I don't know, maybe it's my second English second language or something,
but this one I actually got and it was funny.
So what we're going to do is we are going to say response data joke and then we are going to get that
joke.
I'm just going to simulate that for you.
So now click.
This is the joke.
Click It doesn't matter how many times you click it, you're going to get a joke, right?
What do we want to do with this joke?
Very simple.
We want to grab ours and not joke joke para.
And we are going to say that inner text, inner t text and basically set it to response date.
Let's save it.
So we should be done here.
OK, Kleck.
All right, where is our this?
We don't see it, so joke parody that in our text, have we selected it correctly?
Does it have a class of joke?
Yes, it does have a class of joke.
So query selector, let's see if there is a problem there.
So the log joke para excuse me, and.
There we go.
There it is.
If I click on it, it doesn't put of their.
Of course, we are trying to put their response, we are not trying to put the jokes or we need to do
response dated a joke, that was the thing.
Here we go.
Come on, buddy.
Guma.
Give me the joke.
Is it not working?
We're doing something incorrect, so we have response data that this was supposed to be a simple project
in straight forward, for that matter.
And so if I say consolidate log and say response data.
Oh, there are three ends.
Oh, my goodness, that was a mistake.
There we go.
How does a Darth Vader like his toast on the dark side?
All right.
So there we go with our joke.
And I'm just going to test it a few times.
So when you click on it, it is going to give you a joke, right?
And each time, hopefully, it is going to be a random joke.
So that's it for this lecture and for this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.