Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to get the random animal images.
All right, so first things first, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab all these three deaths
and I'm going to grab all these three buttons.
So let's go ahead and let's say consed I'm going to do let let Cat be equal to document that query selector.
So the class first off we get the diff.
So it's going to be cat.
And then we are going to change it to dog and we can also change it to.
OK, let's change it to Fox and I'm going to bring Fox in the middle.
All right.
So we have successfully selected all the three debates and now let's select the three buttons.
So I'm just going to call them that button and we are going to document that query selector and the
classes get get Cat Scoppetta two times.
I'm going to change this to dog.
So it is dark and I'm going to change this one to Fox, so now that this is out of the way, what do
we want to do here?
All right, let's think about that first now.
OK, so I'm just going to go ahead and open the live server so we can see our changes.
All right, so there we go.
So this is a project, it doesn't work, of course.
So what do we want to do here?
Whenever I click on this button, I want that image to be fetched for this project.
We are going to use the fetch API.
All right.
But this is going to be the fetch API object that is included in the JavaScript.
And then in the next project, you are going to use async awaked.
Right?
So whenever you click on this, this click event is actually associated with a fetch API call.
Right.
So whenever you click on it, it is going to call the server and ask for an ad for a specific image.
All right.
So what we are going to do here is we are going to add event listeners for all of the buttons.
So we are going to add event listeners.
The event, of course, is going to be click.
And when the click event happens, we are going to say get random cat.
So we are going to have three events because we are going to have three
three functions and three animals.
So I'm going to change this to Fox and I'm going to change this to dog.
Let's make this F capital, the Saudi capital.
So first off, let's come into the public APIs repository.
So we have Cat, we have Fox and then we have duck.
So inside the cat you can see whenever we make a call to this, you are Al and it will require.
So this is going to be the real this is the data or the response that we are going to get.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's implement the random cat images.
So what I'm going to do, I'm just going to comment out.
I'm going to say get random cat images.
Right.
So we want these images to be fetched whenever we click that button.
So we are going to say, let's call the get random cat.
So, all right, whenever we click it, we want to fetch that.
So for using the fetch object, it's very simple.
You just have to pass and TTP the the DPR.
So let's copy that and let's put it right here.
All right.
And then.
So this is going to return a promise when it returns.
A promise we can tag on a dot then and we are going to say so the response, not capital.
Right.
So the response, what is the response going to be?
The response is is just going to be a return response.
OK, well, there is something that I need to tell you about our functions.
If you want to return something, just don't provide the curly braces.
If you provide the curly braces, only in that case you're allowed to write the return keyword.
That's why when I wrote it, you can see that there is an error actually here because we don't have
curly braces.
When you have curly braces and you see a return, that's OK.
But if you just want to if you if it is just one simple line of code and you want to return it, don't
just don't provide the curly braces.
OK, so we are going to say a return response, Jason, so we know that the response is something that
we need to do the Jason on it.
And why do we and what is the Dodgson method going to do?
The Jason method is going to do three things right.
So first thing, it is going to read it, convert it into a Jason file, then it is going to sorry first
is going to read it, then it is going to convert it into adjacent file.
Then it is going to pass that JSON file for us.
Right.
So now if I say it, we are not going to see anything else because we have successfully passed the data,
but we have not like used it anywhere.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to say response data and I just want to I just want to log
it to the console.
So we are going to say cancel the log response data.
So let's say that it's come here.
So this is where we're working with.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going I'm going to go in to inspect and let's bring it down.
Let's go to council, get random fox.
So until we specify until we define these functions, I'm just going to call them out.
So if I click on this, I get a cat image, you can see that we get the same URL that we get here,
right?
So this is actually that we have an inside ops room inside this object.
What do we have?
We have only one property, and that property is actually the source for that image.
So what do we want to do?
We want to create an image element.
And for the source, we are going to provide this dynamic source, which is right here.
Right.
And where is this source coming from?
So if I were to say response data, dot.
If I were to say so, what is the name of this, it is going to be file.
Is it the cat?
Meow.
Yeah, it is the cat, so I'm just going to say response file, response data, I'm going to say file.
So when I say file, we're going to get that specific URL for that image.
So if I click on it, you can see this URL, we get that era.
So what do I want to do with that?
You are I'm just going to cut this and I'm going to delete this console log.
And instead of that, I'm going to create curly braces.
So we want to grab our fox sorry, our cat.
So right here, that diff.
So I'm going to say can't enter HTML should be equal to what the cat that Interreg HTML should be.
I'm just going to provide in here tactics.
So let's create the image element and the source for this image element is going to come from that response
data that file, but we need to provide it inside this, this template literals.
So it, it, it actually when you provide it inside the template literal, it is going to grab the value
of response data file and it is going to put it right here.
So if I were to save it, we can see we don't have any errors here and no errors inside the console.
And when I click the cat image when we should be able to get this image and there we go.
So we have we have gotten this image.
If I click on it, we are going to get another image.
So it doesn't matter how many times you click it, you are going to get a random image for a cat.
So I'm just going to close this.
So we have successfully implemented this cat.
The rest of the two are going to be easy.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to create them in this video and I'm just going to copy this
comment.
Creating it takes a long time.
So the second one is Fox.
So what do we do?
We have created the Center for the Fox.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create the function.
Function and get random folks.
All right, we are going to say fetch and.
What is the URL so.
Get random folks, I'm just going to copy that you are htp real, let's put it there.
So it is going to return a promise and we can say that the procedure is going to be the same.
First off, we get the promise and we convert it into something that can be converted into something
that can be passed by JavaScript, can be read by JavaScript through this response.
Jason method.
So we are going to see a response and let's say a response, convert it to something that can be read
by JavaScript.
And then then after that, we want to grab our response.
And I'm just going to call a response data.
And what do we want to do?
First off, let's go ahead and let's log it to the console response data so we know what we are working
with.
Right.
So let's come here.
So now if I click on the Fox, we should get something inside this console and we don't get anything.
So let's take a look at it.
We have response to Jason and we have.
Response data council response data, right, and it is get random Fox, Fox, b10, oh, this is incorrect.
So let's change it to Fox.
Let's save it.
Now, if I click on the Fox, we get this.
You are now inside this.
You are.
We have two things.
Keep in mind, we have to think we have two properties.
The first property is going to be image.
You know what?
I'm just going to bring this up and zoom in.
So the first property is image and the second one is like we are interested in the image.
So if I were to say here, dot image and save it and click on it, we should we get a source for for
a specific image.
So we are going to do basically the same thing.
I'm going to copy, I'm going to cut this and I'm going to remove the cancer log and I'm going to say,
what do we want to do here?
We are going to grab the fox container and we are going to say that enter HTML should be equal to let's
create that image tag.
You can see that that image tag is not present inside this inside the e-mail, we are creating a dynamically.
And what is going to be the source?
The source is going to be basically response date and let's put them inside current braces.
And Idella, so now everything should be working perfectly fine.
So if I bring this down and if I click on it, we should get a fox image here and there we go.
Instead of one fox, we go to Foxy's.
All right.
So now the fox is done as well.
And I'm just going to go ahead and implement the dog one as well.
So let's grab this.
Put it right here.
You can see that this API is simple.
You just have an API and whenever you contacted you are going to get a response, convert it to read
it, convert it to Jason and then pass it.
And then we see what's inside that file.
And when we and then we grab it.
Right.
So this is going to be the simplest API that we're working with.
So for now, for this dog, we are going to come and this one back in, get random dog, get random,
not Fox Dog.
And again, we are going to make a fetch request.
So let's remove the clause that so this is going to be worth the design.
Right.
And we are going to say fetch.
Let's just put in the you are it is going to be a promise.
So we are going to sell a response and we just want to return response to Jason.
And when we return that we are going to say that then and we are going to say a response data I could
console log it.
So console log to see what what it is that we get, actually.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
So I'm just going to close this one.
And if I click on the dog, what do we get?
We get this.
So we get a u r l in this time we get two properties file size bytes.
So this is the size and we get a you are out.
So you are of course the you are l is the thing that we are interested in.
So I'm just going to write here.
How is it lowercase.
Yeah it is lowercase.
So we are going to say that you are l and when I say that when, when I click on the dog image we get
this.
You are a keep in mind this, all of this data is is being fetched without refreshing the page or so
called on the fly.
Right.
So let's cut this, remove this and what do we want to do?
We want to grab the dog container and we are going to say that.
Our HTML, let's create that image tag, so image, let's provide the source for it, the source is
going to be that that's surrounded by curly braces and put in a dollar sign and that's it.
That's basically it to doing to grabbing and generating random images.
So we just very, very simple.
Just created just grab the device, grab the buttons, create a function inside the function, just
fetch.
So if I click on the dog, we should be able to get an image for a specific dog.
So now reload the page, click.
We get a cat image and reload the page, we get a fox image, reload the page, sorry, click this.
Why do I keep saying reload the page?
No, not reload.
Just click on this button and you're going to get a different dog image.
So different, different, different.
It doesn't matter how many times you click on it.
Now, what is the use case?
You might ask the use cases, for example, whenever you want to create a specific for example, you
want to create a website and inside which you don't want to like, you can see that it is going to give
you gifts or gifts as well.
And you don't want to like, let's say, insert images and like increase the size of your entire project.
Right.
You don't want to do that and you just want to grab images on the fly.
So that way your website loads faster, then this is one of the ways that you can do it.
All right.
So that's going to be it for this lecture and this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.