Hi, everyone.
In this election, we will be creating the square cloths on its properties.
All right, so let's say Class Square and we are going to put in our constructor, we're going to have
an exposition in Y position A with and a height, they're going to say this start with is going to be
equal to w this dot h is going to be equal to height, this start button.
Bottom is going to be equal to the Y position, plus the height of this dot left is going to be equal
to.
The ex that we have this dot, right, is going to be called to X plus the width that we have.
Then this top.
The start top is going to be equal to the Y position.
Now I'm going to provide because whenever we hover on the grid, any of when we hover inside, any of
the specific that target square either of the sides, whichever is closer to where the mouse cursor
is pointing, that is going to be highlighted.
So we need a highlight as well.
And initially that is going to be zero or null.
We are going to also check for how many sites have been selected, because based on that, we can say
that whoever has completed the final side and whenever that square has all four sides felt or connected,
we are going to draw a score there.
They're going to put it to zero initially and we're going to grab the owner of that cell initially.
No cell has any owner.
Then let's go ahead and let's grab all the sites.
So first off, let's grab the side bottom and the side bottom is going to have is a small object.
It is going to have owner, which is initially null and it is going to have a selected property, which
is going to be no, sorry, false as false.
Let's create let's copy that three times.
And in here we have we are going to have our side left for which the owner is null and the selected
is false.
Then we have this side right there with the same object and then side.
Top.
All right, so we have we have successfully created that the next step that I would like to do as I'm
going to go top and I'm going to create some game variables.
So below our context, I'm just going to right here game game variables.
And here we are going to create our current cells so grown cells are ready.
So this is going to be current cells.
We are going to create the players turn, whichever players turn.
It is so players turn.
We are also going to create a squares, a right that is going to contain the squares which have been
selected.
Right.
So what do we have here?
Here we have current cells, players turn and squares.
Right after that.
I would like to create a function called New Game.
So I'm going to come down here and this is going to be responsible for calling a new game for us.
So let's go ahead and let's create that.
And it's going to be a new game function, new game, and it's not going to have any.
Parameters.
So the first thing that I would like to do here is I would like to create a coin toss kind of and kind
of situation.
Let me rephrase that.
I would like to create a situation in which we have 50 percent chance that it is going to be the player's
turn player one and 50 percent chance that is going to be the player to a.k.a. computers turn.
OK, so we are going to say player's turn is going to be equal to math, dot random lowercase times.
It is going to return the boolean.
So we are going to check whenever it is equal to a zero, whenever it is equal or greater than zero.
So, OK, so we should not put in a multiplication sign there and it is going to return that bullet
for us, right.
So.
The next step that I would like to do here is.
We have to draw our squares as well, so why don't we why don't we go ahead and actually draw those
squares and.
We are going to call the hour, draw squares, function within our game loop, so inside here, what
I would like to do is below the board and I'm going to I'm going to call a function that is going to
be draw squares.
So we will have two functions that are going to sound a bit similar.
One is going to be draw squares.
The other one is going to be draw scores.
And that is going to be something that we will be doing towards the end.
Right.
So let's come down here.
Where is this is a drug threat and I'm going to grab this and we could go ahead and collapse these,
I mean, if we needed them, we are going to expand them.
But for now, I'm going to keep this new game open because we are going to work a lot in there and this
is going to be draw squares perfect.
So we are going to have a function, draw squares.
So what are we going to have inside this function, we want this function to draw squares for us now
before actually drawing squares.
This function should be able to handle should be able to get some sort of like an array from us.
Right.
Because in our game variables, we have said that this squares is actually an array.
So what I'm going to do is before actually creating that function inside our new game function, I'm
going to go ahead and I'm going to say setup the squares array, because if you don't have any array,
how would you how would we be able to actually iterate over it and in each iteration draw it?
So let's actually reset it first in case there is something.
And after that, we are going to say for let the AI is going to start from zero, I'm going to go all
the way to less than what?
Less than the grid size.
Perfect.
And we are going to increment I by one.
Right.
This is in each iteration.
This is going to have a specific value which we are going to store inside our inside a new array, and
then we are going to iterate over the grid size one more time.
All right, and working for Aulet J equals zero and J is less than the grid size.
Perfect, and we are going to increment by one each time and each time this happens, we're going to
call our squares array and we are going to pass and I and Jay.
And this is going to be equal to our the instantiation of our square class.
So we are going to say square now for that.
What do we need to pass?
So we have a constructor that is going to accept four parameters for each parameter we need to pass
in one argument.
So what is the exposition?
The exposition off the grid is going to be that get grid X that we created before and I'm going to pass
in there.
What is the Y position that is going to be the get grid y position?
And I'm going to pass on either what is going to be the with the with if the South is going to be the
sell itself, the height of the sell is going to be sell as well.
So let's save that.
Let's come here.
We don't have anything.
Of course we don't have any highlighting.
We basically first setting up the squares and highlighting we will handle later.
So now that this is in place, where is our draw squarest function?
We need to go ahead and we need to actually draw these squares.
So now we have our array and we know how we can iterate over it.
So we are going to say for a row of what is the array?
The array is squares for that row of squares.
And then we are going to iterate over each cell as well, our each square, to be exact.
Michelet Square.
Alvira.
So what do we want to do with this?
We want to grab our loop variable, which is square in this case, and we are going to call a method
that is going to be draw sides, that's going to draw the sides.
And we are going to call another method as well that is going to be draw fail.
So whenever we hover on that.
Oops.
Close, this was cited, so whenever we hover on that, you can see this is our highlight and then when
you click, you're going to see that it says that it is going to be like actually filling this right.
So we need to set both of them up as well.
So what will what I am going to do as.
I'm going to go to my class, so we have created the draw squares, so within the class, right?
But before actually doing that, I would like to pass in a situation as well, so I'm going to create
a function that is going to be contains I'm thinking that do I have to pass the function right now or
I should wait until it comes up.
Hmm.
So we have to create that at some point.
All right, and we are going to create this function whenever we get to actually highlighting, so I'm
not going to confuse you any further.
I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to create the draw sites for now and I'm going to create this
function later, because this is going to be used for calling the highlighting itself.
So what is the function name?
The function name is going to be draw sides.
This is going to be a function expression and actually an error function.
So in here, what is it that we want to do?
First off, we want to check if there is actually some highlighting going on.
Right.
So I'm going to say hi.
I think they're going to f this dot highlight is not is not null.
If it is not null, then we want to draw the site.
OK, if any side has not been highlighted, we do not want to draw that.
So we are going to call a draw side method in here.
And for the drop side method, this is not going to be draw sides.
So keep in mind we have one for draw sides, one for drawing each individual side.
And we are going to pass on this does highlight whichever side has been highlighted and we are going
to call another helper method, which is going to be get color, which is going to give us the color.
So the color is going to be based on the player's turn.
And the second.
The second argument in here is going to be a boolean, and that is whenever we call this get color,
we are going to pass on a boolean because we want to check if any site has not been highlighted and
we want to highlight it, then we want to highlight it with the light color.
So it is going to be true.
So the light is going to be true if and then we are going to call this function again for whenever we
want to complete that or fill that highlight.
So when the side is highlighted and we want to fill that, in that case, we do not want to grab the
light color.
So the light color is going to be false in here because we are highlighting it.
It is going to be true.
Ah, right.
And let's go ahead and let's create this jet color function, so what I'm going to do as.
I'm going to come on top here and I'm going to grab this comment, let us start one.
All right, so in here, let's just pass it on and it is going to be get color.
Function, get color and.
We have two arguments, so we need two parameters, right, because we are basically checking which
players turn it is and either we need to grab that light color or that like not so light color.
So we are going to pass in player and we are going to pass and light, not night light caite.
All right.
So if it is the player's turn, if it is if player is true, we want to return.
We want to return.
And in this return, we are checking for something.
If it is light, we will return the color player light.
If it is not light, if light is not true, we are going to return color player.
Very simple, as if it is not player's turn.
It means it is either the other players turn or as we would like to call it, in our next game.
It is the eyes.
So it's in this game.
It is going to be two players.
One of them happens to have a name of EHI or a computer.
In our next game we will automate that thing.
All right.
So I hope you're not getting confused by this.
Return if lt is true, we want to return for for the I want to return the light light if it is not true,
we want to return that not so light color that we have there.
Right, so now that we have created this function, we have what I'm going to do is I'm going to go
on top and I'm going to create an object and I'm going to call it cites.
The reason that we recreate that is we don't have to.
I think we did the same thing with our breakout game where we created a directions object just to avoid
typing directions all the time.
We are just going to store it within an object and then reuse that object as many times as we want.
So right below here, I'm going to create a side object.
So in this case, of course, it's not going to be directions, it's just going to be any side that
has been highlighted.
So I'm going to say const capital aside equal to an object.
So the first side is going to be bottom and the value for that is going to be zero.
The second side is going to be left for which the values one right after that we have right.
Which is two.
And finally we have TARP, which is three.
So now that we have created this, what I would like to do, as I would like to create a function that
is going to be called draw a line, and this function is actually responsible for drawing lines for
us.
All right.
So where should I put this function?
I want to comes beneath this drug gret, this drug line is going to be responsible for actually drawing
any line that we have, so we need to call in that canvas methods, the canvas methods.
So we are going to have a function that is going to be draw a line.
We are going to call this function within our draw side function, which we are yet to create.
So draw a line, the parameters are going to be X the zero zero position for X and then the zero position
for Y, these are the starting positions X one is going to be ending position for X and Y, one is going
to be ending position for Y as well as color.
So first off, let's pass on the color.
So Conex start stroke's style because there are lines we are just going to call stroke and the color
is going to be the color that we pass in here.
Then we're going to say, let's begin our path.
So where the lines should start, the line should start to move to zero and y zero.
What are those points?
We're going to pass them on later.
Where should they go to?
So line two is going to be X one and Y one.
And finally, we are going to say stroke.
Strauch.
Perfect, so let's actually go ahead and let's create the draw side function, so I'm going to come
down, I'm going to collapse this function, the squares function square row, all right.
It's collapse these and inside our draw sides.
Inside our square cloths on top of the drawer sides, I'm going to create a function that is going to
withdraw side singular.
Perfect.
So what do we want to do inside this draw site?
Basically, we are checking if the use of the user highlights.
If I hovers on the right side, we want to highlight that.
We want to create that line if it is on the left, create left top and the same thing for top and bottom.
So we are going to say switch.
That's passing the site.
And as for this draw site, you can see that it has two arguments.
We need two parameters.
The first one is going to be the highlight.
Which is going to be the side, so I'm going to pass and side here.
The second thing, the second one is going to be color.
So I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to pass and color here.
So in know we're switch.
And the first case we want to say if side is the bottom side.
We want to draw a line, right?
And what are going to be the X zero Y zero x one, y one in color, the zero is going to be this star
left.
The Y zero is going to be this dot bottom.
The next one is going to be this start, right, and the why one is going to be this bar.
All right, when it hits the bottom side, I have to show it to you so you can really understand it.
So when it is the bottom side, for example, for example, this is the bottom side.
The bottom side.
Has your relationship with this done left and then this dot bottom.
This the right.
And then again, the start bottom, right, so the bottom is going to have a distorted bottom, this
the left and this start bottom, this that right.
That's exactly what we are doing here.
This dot bottom, this the left, this dot bottom, this the right.
Perfect.
So after that, we are going to break out of it.
All right, and we are we should also pass on the color.
Let's pass on that color, so we are going to repeat this three more times for the remaining three sides.
So if the side is going to be left for the left side, we are going to have this.
The left now left has a relationship with top and their relationship with border.
So this the left, this start top and then again, this the left.
This Darbar, the same thing for the right.
We have drawn a line for the right now, right, has a relationship with the top and the bottom.
So this is right top and then bottom.
Perfect.
So we are going to have this start.
Right.
So first off, let's pass on this top and again, the studd right and the start bottom.
Perfect.
So that is going to be that finally we have this top.
So the top has a relationship with left and right.
We are going to say this, the left and the top.
This dot right.
This top.
Save that, and I don't think we are going to see anything here.
We do have an error that says can't access property, semiliterate squares is undefined.
Why is it undefined?
We have defined that hard line.
98 square is undefined.
Let's come.
Let's check it out.
So in here, it says online 98, the squares is undefined.
Have we called a redraw squares?
Skewers.
It is the same function.
So why is it undefined?
We have called in our squares right here, right?
So if I grab control, collect the squares is there, then we have set for let a row of squares.
Squares is going to be oh, we have not called our new game function.
It's.
So on top of that, I'm just going to call the new game function, let's save it and hopefully this
message is going to go away.
Go away.
It is going to say square drawerful, and now it is a different error.
It says Square, the drawerful is not a function.
That's because we have not yet defined it.
It's referring to I believe it's here, this drawerful.
We are going to create that function as well.
So that's that was a good error.
It reminded me of calling the new game function here.
Perfect, so now that we are done with that part, I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to go ahead and
move on.
So the next part is I would like to do something real in this lecture.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to create the highlight site function as well.
So let's go ahead.
I'm going to go on below the grid.
Why perfect in here?
I'm going to copy that and I'm going to pasted and I'm going to say a highlight highlight grid.
So it's going to be a function highlight.
Oh, it's not going to be a highlight grid.
It's going to be a highlight site for now.
We do have a highlight grid as well.
So highlight site.
They're are going to be parameters X and Y for that.
All right, so let's actually go ahead and create this function, so for what this function is actually
trying to do is we are trying to highlight the side which is hovered on.
So for this function to actually work, we need a mouse event as well.
And we are going to create that right after we create this function.
So don't worry about it, so we have our highlights site, we will have to highlight side functions.
This is one of them, but this is not the function that we will be creating here.
That function is actually going to be a function within this class is going to be a property and method
of the square class.
So I'm going to say highlight side and this is going to be a function expression.
So let's actually go ahead and create that.
So first off, we need to calculate the distances to each side, so in here I'm going to pass an X and
Y, how can we calculate that?
So first off, let's call that distance bottom.
So the first one is going to be dist. bottom.
The distance bottom is going to be this dot bottom minus the y axis, the Y position, whatever comes
after that, we are going to subtract it by wherever the point is and then we are going to have dist
left.
Distance left is going to be our exposition minus the left of that square.
Then we are going to have let distance right, the distance right is going to be our right position.
Right position minus the X and let's go ahead and let's create the distance stuff as well.
So dist. top and that is going to be the Y position minus the top point.
Now we need to have a variable for the closest side.
So I'm going to say distance closest, whichever is closest to where we are pointing.
So for that, how can we grab these the smallest of these?
So four, that we have a method that is math dot in math, dot man is going to return the smallest of
office like a set of numbers.
So this is closest and I'm going to pass on this bottom.
Dust left, dust right and dust top perfect, so it is going to return the smallest of these and are
going to store it inside there and now we want to highlight the closest, the closest site.
But first, we need to check if that is not already selected.
If it is selected, then we do not want to highlight it.
So first off, we are going to say that if the closest, the closest distance is equal to the bottom
distance, we want to highlight it, but we need to check that that is not already being selected.
So if this and also this dot side bottom dot selected is false, if if it is not selected and the it
is closer to bottom, we want to highlight that and we are going to say this DOT highlight is going
to be able to decide that object that we have created inside that bottom.
So we have created this and I'm going to copy this and we are going to repeat it for all the other sites
so else.
And we're going to do it one by one.
So I have distance closest is equal to the left, is equal to the distance left and the side.
The left is not selected, so side left is not selected.
Then what it is that we want to do, we want to highlight the side left.
Very simple.
Now let's put that here again.
If the distance closest is equal to the right.
And that right part has not been selected already, so side right has not been already selected.
We want to highlight which part the right part.
And finally, for the top, if distance closest is equal to the top top and also it is not selected,
we want to highlight it.
So let's say top.
We want to highlight it.
And after I if after all of this, it doesn't do anything, it doesn't return anything, what do we
want to do?
We want to return and return this dot to highlight.
Perfect, so now with this, let's go ahead and let's actually check so our grid is gone.
Let's see what this I think this is the draw fill function is not a function and it is a key.
It is going to keep repeating it until we go ahead and we draw that.
And I know this is not going to work because we have not actually created the mouse event.
We need to create that mouse event.
We need to call this highlights site somewhere for this to work.
So this was the part one of actually highlighting sites.
And in the next part, we will go ahead and we are going to complete this highlighting of the sides.
So see you guys then.