Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create our questions.
All right, so the first real thing that we do.
What this application is to create questions, but before creating those, I need to grab whatever it
is that we want from our team.
So I'm just going to click on this one and I'm going to remove the Dargis from there.
So we need I need to show you what it is that I'm grabbing.
So let's move one, two, three from there.
So first off, let's create a contest.
I want to grab our start button because these are the things these are the elements.
All of these we need in JavaScript to apply some sort of functionality or to do something with it.
So let's say document, dot, query.
So I try I will try to be like quick, because this is very simple.
This is the start button, right, and the next is going to be the case and then the question, so let's
grab the start and let's change it to quiz the next one is going to be our question.
OK, that is incorrect.
Was.
All right, so we have successfully grabbed our start button start if the question if Assad acquisitive
and the question the next thing that I want to grab is all of our answers choices and I want to store
them all in search choices.
And all these are actually these for answer choices, all in search choices.
And I want to say document.
That query selector.
All right, and I'm going to grab them by their class, which is diet choice.
All right.
So the next thing that I want to do is I want to grab them individually as well, because I want to
fly an avid listener on all of them.
And I want to play an event listener on each of them individually.
When the user clicks, I want to run it against the correct answer.
And I want to know for sure if that answer that the user has clicked is actually the correct answer
or the correct answer.
So I'm going to create another contest and I'm going to call it answer choice, eh?
So this is going to be answer choice.
And this is going to be let's you know what, cuppy this button right here and it has an idea of a so
let's copy it three times.
Let's grab this a.
Let's grab this, let's change it to be change this, to be change this, to see who's to see.
Let's grab this a change it to see, grab this one and we are changing it to death.
So we have selected all of our answer choices.
The only two things remaining are the timer.
Right.
Actually three things we need to get our timer container and core container.
So to be able to get those, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab this and I'm going to paste it
right here and I'm going to change the start to counter.
And so what is the class name for the counter?
The class name for the counter is actually counter itself.
So let's say counter.
Right.
And let's create a two more times.
The next thing down a grab is going to be time gauge.
Right.
And the class for that is time gauge itself to copy the class name, put it right here.
And after that, what I want to grab is going to be the progress.
And then we are going to grab the score div the score container, which we are going to save it inside
this quarter.
So let's grab this one.
I'm just going to call it progress.
Right.
And the class for this is progress container.
Let's put it right here.
I should probably call it progress container.
All right.
So this is progress container.
And finally, we are going to have our score diff.
Or score, we could call it container, it is better it's a better name score container and let's change
it to the container is the same.
Let's just convert it to score.
So we have selected everything that we needed here.
Right.
The next thing that I want to do is our questions.
Let's create our questions now.
We do not need these two panes here.
I think if I remove this so open it once more, I'm not really comfortable doing this multi window thing.
I've never done it.
I just wanted to do in this lecture.
These are questions.
Now, there is something that I should mention here that these questions this is not a proper way of
doing it.
The proper way of doing it is that these questions, they're either going to come in through a different
platform, through an API, or they're going to be fed through the through a certain database and the
questions that are going to be there.
And each time any user logs into their account, they're going to see a different set of questions with
a different set of background images for those questions.
But for the purposes of this front and application that we are building inside JavaScript, we are going
to create the questions and we are going to mimic a database inside the JavaScript itself.
So I'm going to say let questions questions right.
And I'm going to create an array.
And inside this array, we are going to have ten objects.
Each of the objects is going to have I a question as a key.
The value is going to be the question string itself.
Then we have the question image, our four choices and then the correct.
I'm going to create the first object and I'm going to copy paste the rest of them.
So what is the question?
The question is going to have a key off question itself and the answer is going to be inside these quotes.
And we are going to say how many I'm not going to type.
It's you know what?
I'm not going to type it out.
So this is our very first question.
This is where you can change the questions and this is where you can increase or decrease the number
of questions that you want.
There is a problem with this application.
This is not actually a problem.
This is something that whenever you work with a front end application, this is something that you're
bound to have.
All right.
You're you're going to have it.
So this is the what I've done is I've just.
Right.
Click on the page and I'm saying view page source and this is the HTML.
So here is the JavaScript update.
And if I click on it, we can see our entire JavaScript code for this application.
But the problem is that we can see our questions and our correct answer as well.
That's why we never want to do this.
We never want to store sensitive information in the front end.
Like imagine if you if you created a Facebook account and or a YouTube account or like not YouTube,
like an Instagram or Twitter account.
And your password username would have been saved in The View page source.
And everyone could have used every other person's like identity that would have been like really messy.
Right.
That's why we store these sort of confidential information on the server and server is somewhere the
user can never access unless they hack it.
All right.
So this is our first and key value pair.
The next one is going to be question IMG, make sure to spell it correctly, question IMG and we're
going to provide it with the path.
So the path is the image is there inside the image folder and the the number is one that jpg.
It throws an error here because there is no comma here.
So add another comma.
Now we have our choice.
A this is the answer choice.
Say it is 100, then we go to choice.
Choice.
Let's you know what, let's just copy it.
So for the choice B we are going to have.
A hundred and fifty four choices.
We are going to have ten.
OK, this is C. And this is D. This is going to be 27 and the final key value pair that we are going
to have is going to be correct.
Answer.
Now, here is where we will insert our correct answer, which is 100.
And whenever we run, this is where we are going to run this or whenever we run this event.
Listener, it is going to grab our correct answer and it is going to evaluate it against whichever choice
the user has clicked.
If these two strings they are equal, then it is going to that that little box is going to turn green.
If they're not equal, it means it's wrong, then that box is going to turn red.
And we have created our very first object and I'm going to grab the rest of the objects and I'm going
to paste them down here because this is very tedious and time consuming.
These are basically all the same.
So we have our correct answer here.
We have our choice DCB a question, image and question itself.
So we have created our questions.
I'm going to collapse all of the questions and I'm going to keep either the first one or the last one
doesn't really matter because we are going to access the values from this object, the properties of
this object.
And I need to have one of these shown on the screen.
This is going to be it for this lecture in the next election.
We are going to continue building this massive application.