Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about JavaScript conditionals.
All right, so the first set of conditions that we are going to talk about are going to be if statements
and the second set is going to be the switch statements.
All right.
So we are going to start with the very basics of statements and why we need them now if statements in
JavaScript, they allow us to control the flow of code.
For example, if we want to check for a condition and when that condition is met, we want some sort
of logic to be implemented.
And when that condition is not met, we do not want that logic to be implemented.
All right.
So starting from the basics, first off, we are going to take a look at the if statement, which is
checking only for a single condition.
All right.
You could call these if statements these conditional generally the decision making process in JavaScript.
So let's go ahead and let's dive into the syntax.
So for creating an if statement, first off, we just write the F and we open the parentheses and then
a set of curly braces.
So this is the regular syntax for an if statement in JavaScript.
And what this means is if some kind if a condition is met, which the condition comes inside, these
parentheses say the condition.
All right.
If this condition is met, then run, run this code.
The this is what basically an if statement does and how it works.
It checks for a condition.
And if that condition is met, it is going to run a code and that's it.
This is how simple if statements are in JavaScript.
All right.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's take a look at the first condition that we want to take a look
at.
Right.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to create a name that is Tom.
And I'm going to check if Tom is equal to Tom.
Right, Tom?
And this is our example.
Example one.
Come on, buddy.
All right, so if this string, Tom, is equal in both value and time to the string of Tom, we want
to run a code that says conservate log.
Yay, Tom.
Right now, let's see what we can see our results right here, and this happens because Tom is equal
to Tom in both value and in both tie.
All right.
So this is our first example.
And in case they are not equal, then this coat is not going to run.
I'm going to show you that in our second example.
All right.
So this is example two in here.
First off, we just tried the keyword and then a set of parentheses, followed by a set of curly braces.
And we said if.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's ride over condition, so we said if Jack is equal to Tom, console
the log.
No way, and it's safe and we don't see anything because if we want this code to run inside the console,
this condition should be true.
If the condition is not true, the code is not going to run.
This is how we can control the flow of code, the flow of logic.
Let's say you have, for example, 10 lines of logic inside your statement and 100 lines of logic before
that.
If statement, if the condition of this statement is met, then then the rest of the code is going to
run.
And if it does not meet, the rest of the code is not going to run.
This is how if statements work.
So I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to give you one more example and then we are going to take it up a notch.
Right.
So this is going to be our example.
Number three, first off, let's go ahead and let's write our condition and we say, let's say time
is equal to, I don't know, like, oh, 700, let's go militari on this.
So that time equal to, oh, 700.
If time is equal to oh, 700, we are going to consult the log.
Good Morning, America.
All right, so if time is over 700 means it's seven a.m. we print.
Good morning.
If this example is actually I've provided this in a deliberate way, because in in later on in just
a few minutes, we are going to.
Take this and we are going to take it to the next level, OK, and we are going to build up on this
example.
All right, so when the time is, oh, 700, we want to cancel the log.
Good morning.
But if it is not 700, for example, if it is 800, then we don't see any message.
OK, but this is not accurate.
So we are going to make make sure that this stays accurate.
All right.
So this is a simple if statement, simple if statements they check for a single condition.
We can also we have an an F üç statement which checks for two conditions, checking for two conditions.
Two conditions, right?
Now, if a condition is met, then we want to run a certain code and if that condition is not met,
we want to run a certain other code, that's basically the ideology behind this.
So we are going to say, if so, before writing the F, I'm just going to create two variables and I'm
going to say let's score be equal to 10.
All right.
And I say F score is equal to 10.
Right.
I want to present to the console console of log.
Great.
Let's put it inside quotes, great.
Hey, and now, if this condition is not met, then what in that in that case, what do you want to
do?
Then we write and our statement.
All right.
And here we are going to say consider log.
And I'm going to explain it one more time.
It says, great, we.
So now, because the score is 10 and the condition is met, we run this code and the L's statement and
in a condition on says that in any other scenario we want to run this code.
So if the score is nine, run grade B, if the score is eight, then run grade B if the score is.
If the score is, let's say, seven, then run grade B, it doesn't matter what the score is, as long
as it is not ten, we will bring to the council A, grade B, so the F, the L part of this conditional
says in any other scenario, run this code.
All right.
So if this if the condition is met, we are going to run the first code.
And if the condition is not met, it doesn't matter what the number is, even if it is 10000, we are
going to see grade B because other than 10, every other number is our every other scenario.
This is how the statement works here.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to we are going to dive even deeper into this.
So this is the statement.
I'm just going to go ahead and remove the F from the start of it.
And now we are going to go ahead and we are going to create another if else statement.
If statement that is going to check for more than two conditions, if our statement checking for more
for more than two conditions.
Right.
This is the first statement, so we are going to create a variable and it is going to be score, I could
go ahead and work with this time variable.
All right.
But I'm not going to do the score is a better this is a better example.
So we are going to save score is equal to 10.
All right.
And first off, we initialize this variable, and that is let's score equal to ten.
If if score is equal to ten, then what do we want to do?
We want to present to the console what grade?
Hey, now, what if the score is not ten?
OK, what if the score is eight?
We do not want to print, for example, for the score of five grade B because that is not accurate.
So instead of writing and if an else statement alone, we are going to write and else if statement.
Right.
And we can write any number of F else if statements as we want.
All right.
So else if the score is let's go ahead and let's say the score is nine, then run the code, cancel
the log.
Grade B, right?
And what if the score is seven?
So what if when the score is seven or when the score is eight?
I do not want to play into the concert grade B so I can go ahead and I can create another elusive statement,
because it doesn't matter how many Ancef statements you create, you are free to do that.
OK, so we are going to grab the score and we are going to put it here and we are going to change it
from nine to eight and we are going to copy that and put it right here.
So when the score is eight, we want to present to the Council of Great C..
OK, and what if the score is seven?
So when the score is seven, what do we want to do?
We want to present to the council if the score is seven, we want to present to the council grade.
Right.
And in any other scenario, in any other scenario, we want to present to the council grade F.
Great, let's save it.
So first off, because the score is 10, we are going to get great, eh?
All right.
So this is an NFL statement.
It is checking for more than two conditions as you get.
And now you guys can see this is our first condition, second, third, fourth, and this is our fifth
condition.
But in the first if statement, we can we could only check for one condition in the statement, we can
only check for two conditions.
But in the NFL statement, we can check for more than two conditions.
All right.
So if score is ten, we are going to see a grade A F score is nine.
We are going to see grade B.
When the score is eight, we should see great, see?
All right, and when the score is seven, we should see great.
And in any other scenario, we should see great effort.
So if I put it to six, we are going to see a great F..
Now, this this example is not actually like a completely done.
It is not like a full application because there are there are a lot of problems with this.
What if the score is not 10?
What if the score is 11?
What is one of the score?
15.
What if the score is nine point five?
Right.
What if in that what happens in that condition and that condition?
We don't have any other scenario.
So in any other scenario, we are just going to go ahead and print F to the console.
So if the score if the score is let's uncommented and let's put it to 11, we are going to see grade
F, OK?
If the score is nine point five, we are going to see grade F, even though nine point five classifies
as grade grade B or B plus.
But still we are going to see a grade F. So this is the problem with this application, because this
is just we are just getting started with if our statements we are just getting started with conditionals.
So we do not like create four applications here.
That's why there are like a ton of projects in this course.
So we can come up, we can make up for any other condition that we want we might have.
So we want to make sure that whatever problem that you might face in the real world, you have a solution
for that in mind.
Or you can come up with a solution, which is the best thing that you can do.
OK, so that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.