Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create our generate password event listener.
All right, so now what I'm going to do is whenever we click on this, I want you guys to pay very,
very close attention because this key is actually what is it?
It is actually an input type of Zimet.
So as far as inputs which have types of submit their concern, whenever you click on them, the page
reloads, what does it mean?
It means that this is a form and when you click on the input it is going to submit the form.
That's why after the forum submission, the page reloads.
This is not something that we want.
So if I click on it, you can see that this page, it flashes, right?
This title, this e-mail markup, it flashes.
It means that this form is being submitted.
And whenever it does submit, we will never be able to generate our password.
So what I'm going to do is in this lecture, I'm going to prevent this default behavior, our form submission.
Right.
So before doing that, we need to grab a few more elements in this in this to be able to work with them.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm just going to grab our form.
The form has.
So let's come here.
Let's create a constant I'm just going to call it form.
I could say form, aliment or form, contain or let's call it form container.
So this is going to be a reform container.
Let's go ahead and say document that query selector and let's see what does it have.
So this is our form.
Let's grab it by the I.D. and let's put it right here.
So now we have successfully selected our form.
I'm going to come down here.
All right, and I'm going to say generating generating the password when the form is submitted.
All right.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to Gravois form container and I'm going to add a listener.
Now what what is it?
The event that we are listening for?
It's not a click.
It is submit event.
Right.
So we have talked about some of the events that we in the theory, in the theoretical lectures, but
I didn't that was on purpose.
I purposefully did not cover all of them because this course is a very, very practical and hands on
course.
And I just wanted to show you I just wanted to give you an idea of what events are and how we can manipulate
them through functions.
And then because we have a wide range of events, I decided that I would cover them whenever they came
up in our projects.
So now in here we have an input event and a submit event.
And when the summit event is received or is listened for, we are going to run a function inside the
function.
We, of course, you are going to grab our event object and there is a method called prevent default
that is going to prevent the default behavior of this form.
So I'm going to say that prevent default.
This is a method.
So I'm just going to open parentheses and this is going to be let's save it.
Let's come here.
So now when I click on this, I'm sure you are hearing you can hear the clicking.
The page does not flash, it means that this is not being submitted.
So this is one of the first steps that we need to be able to create and we're password.
All right.
So the next thing that I want to do here is I want to create our generate password function as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to store it inside a variable called password, and I'm
going to call the function generate function.
Oops, generate password function, all right.
And inside this function, what I'm going to do is now this is a function expression and for function
expressions we do not want and we do not need to provide the function.
Key word, right.
I think I made a mistake here saying that this is a function and this is not actually a function.
This is a function call.
We are going to create the function outside this event.
Listener.
Now, this is a function call when the function is called.
We want to store the value that comes out of it inside this password password variable.
Right.
And this function call has four arguments.
The first argument is going to be our character is going to be a character amount.
The second argument is going to be include not include uppercase, upper case.
The third argument is going to be what does this include?
Include upper case.
So this is include upper case.
The third argument is, what do we have for a third argument?
We could say include no.
Or a numbers, and for the fourth argument, we could say, you guessed right, include symbols.
So symbols include symbols.
Let's save it.
So now this is a function call, right?
We have called our function inside this form container and why why we have done this because in our
final application, when we say when we specify the number of characters, let's put it to 41, we say
to include numbers, to include symbols and to include uppercase.
And you might ask, okay, why do this and say this form container form containers, eventless listener.
The reason for that is this is the event that is handling our password generation.
Right.
So when this event of submit is fired, this function is going to be called the function of generate
password and the value is going to be stored inside this variable, which we are going to use later
on.
All right.
So when the function is called, we are going to call the character amount.
Where is the character around how we specify?
No, we have not yet specified it.
We are going to specify we are going to create these as we go on.
All right.
I'm going to tell you where this where does this where does this come from?
This is our character, Amand.
We have uppercase, we have numbers and we have symbols.
So whenever we say click, whenever the user clicks on that generate password, which is a submit event,
this function is going to be called and the value is going to be stored inside this password.
And then that value is going to be swabbed with this value of that.
We have hardcoded for this each three, which is the password display value.
We are going to do that these step by step.
So now what I'm going to do is before moving forward, I want to create these variables right here.
But even before creating that so we have a correct character amount.
The character amount is the number of characters that we have.
We have include uppercase, include numbers and include symbols.
First off, we need to go ahead and we need to select them.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to reference them here and I'm going to store their values inside
these variables.
So the first one is going to be numbers element and I'm going to call it document.
We are going to select it through the query selector.
Let's pass and the ID, which is numbers.
And let's create two more, so this is going to be.
Call it, say, symbols, and this should be uppercase and we are going to check it, of course, that
we are are we are doing it correctly, so uppercase.
So the numbers input.
Yes.
So the numbers input has an idea of numbers, the symbols has an idea of symbols and the uppercase has
an idea of uppercase.
The reason that we are selecting them is because they are checkboxes.
Whenever the user checks these checkboxes, then the user will be able to include numbers if numbers
is checked, symbols if symbols is checked and uppercase if uppercase is checked inside their own like
customized password.
So now we have selected all three here and now let's go ahead and let's create the constants.
So this these arguments, they are not out of place.
So I'm going to say so the character, a man that I've passed here.
It's going to be the number of characters that we have.
I have not selected the number of characters, have I?
Or we have created so this is I have selected that, so I don't need to select it again.
So this is going to be a number of characters.
What is it that we want to graph from there?
It is, of course, the value which we have talked about before here.
So this is the value, right?
Now, it is going to be that and then we are going to create our numbers.
So let's go ahead and let's call it numbers.
Or I'm just going to call it include, because this is the name that we have specified here.
So where is this?
Right here.
So.
Let's grab our numbers.
No element does dot value, we are going to grab the value of it, let's create two more and provide
a space.
So this one is going to be.
So that's numbers.
This is, you know, what I'm going to created in the same order.
So the second one should be upper case.
I'm just going to grab the upper case and put it right here.
And the second one is numbers and the third one is symbols, symbols.
And now so the first one is upper case.
Upper case.
This is numbers and this is symbols.
All right, so we have created four of these include.
Symbols.
OK, so that is capitalized.
So now we have created four variables and each variable holds the value of each of these input types.
So one of the variables holds the values, the value of number of characters.
The other variable holds the value of the numbers.
The next one holds the value of the symbols.
And finally, the last one holds the value of the uppercase.
Whenever the user clicks on that, we want to include these inside our password.
So when the user clicks numbers and generate a password, we can see numbers.
When these are symbols, you are going to see symbols and uppercase, you are going to see uppercase.
All right.
So I hope you're not confused.
This is really, really simple.
We have I'm just going to recap very, very quickly.
We have grabbed our four container and inside there we have said that we have grabbed this submit event
of the form and we have prevented the default behavior, which is the form submission, so we can generate
a password.
Then we have called our generate password function, which which we are yet to create, of course,
with for arguments and y for arguments, because we have one, two, three and four form inputs here
and we want to include them inside the function call.
And then because these very these arguments, they are not created, they're not defined, we have just
defined them here with their specific value.
So character amount is no characters that we have done here.
We have selected their value and then uppercase element that value the numbers element, that value
and symbols element that value that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.