Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to make our next and previous buttons dynamic.
All right, so in the previous letter, we were able to successfully set our images or arrange them
next to each other, so in this lecture, we are going to accomplish two two tasks.
The first task is whenever we click on the right button, moving images to the left and whenever we
click on the left button mode, move images to the right.
So now let's go ahead and let's apply this logic.
So what is the right button?
The right button is the next button.
So let's go ahead and let's grab it.
And what does clicking mean?
Clicking means we are listening for an event listener.
So what is different?
Yes, it is.
Click and then we are going to run a function.
All right, and so what is it that we want to grab here?
The first thing that I want to grab here is going to be our current image that we have added.
So where is the current image class?
It is right here.
So I want to grab this current image class of this a lot in here.
All right.
So I'm going to say Consed Current I.
And we are going to say a list dot query selector.
Now another method of doing query selector is just on a specific element.
So we could just say document that query selector.
And in that case, we would be saying that go ahead, grab the document and search for the current image
class.
But in this case, because we know where the current image class is, it's inside the list.
We can just say, let's start query selector and it would only go ahead and search inside that element,
which has a class of list, and it is going to grab that current image.
So this is like a faster way of it, faster way of doing it.
It's not going to make that much of a difference.
But you can what?
You can do it this way as well.
The next thing that I want to do is I want to grab the next image, because whenever we click on this
button, we want to go to the next image.
Right.
So I'm going to say I'm just going to call this variable, next image and the next image.
OK, so before doing this, I'm just going to comment it out and I'm going to consider log something
for you.
And it is the current image and we are going to see what that is.
All right.
So when I whenever I come to the inspect, we are going to see that.
Consider the log current image, we should be able to see it.
Come on, buddy, let's reload it.
It's 15 thirty that's so common that out.
Whenever we click on it, we see it.
All right, so this is an event when we click on it, we see our current image and this is the current
image that we have.
So if I come here now, the image that is displaying on the Web page is exactly our current image,
as you guys can see here in the preview.
All right.
So this is our current image and we have successfully selected that.
So but there is something else in here.
Whenever we select the current image, we want to grab the next element sibling of this current image.
All right.
So what is the next element sibling of this current image if we come to our e-mail?
So this is our current image.
What is the next element?
Sibling.
So this is the sibling and this is the next element sibling.
So image gallery dash two should be the next element sibling because why do we need that?
Because whenever we click on this button, we want to go to the next image and the next image is the
actually the next element sibling.
So I'm going to grab the current image and I'm going to say next element sibling.
And now if we go ahead and cancel the log, the log, the next image, next image, let's say let's
come here.
So now if I go ahead and if I click on it, we should be able to see the next image.
And in here, an interesting thing has happened.
We can see that an inline style has been applied by JavaScript.
Now, this style left fifteen thirty six comes from this function, all right, because we have successfully
grabbed the with with 15 36 as we have placed it here and it has been called from there because we're
accessing the images to the next image.
Right.
And this is our second image.
So whenever we click on this area, we get the second image.
Now the logic of the dome works in this way, that first stuff you need to create variables.
Now, this is general.
It may not work all the time, but for most of our projects at this stage, it is going to work like
this.
Now we grab whatever it is that we need.
For example, in this case, we need the current image class and then we store it inside a variable.
The reason that we store it inside a variable is that so we can select it, we can use it somewhere.
If it is not stored, we cannot selected.
This is how JavaScript works.
You have to store it within something to be able to to access it.
OK, so when we store inside this current image, we are going to grab the current image and we're going
to say next Alman sibling, the next development sibling is going to give us the next element.
And finally, the next thing that I want to do here is going to be I want to grab the next index as
well.
So I want to grab the index of the next image as well.
And for that, I'm just going to grab our images are right from this, from here, from the top.
And I'm going to apply if a method on it and it is going to be fined index.
And in the finding index, what we are going to do is we are going to pass in a function and that function
is going to look for the next index, for the next index of the next image that we want.
So I'm just going to pass on a function.
Right.
And in here, what do we want to do?
We want to put in a parameter here.
So the parameter is going to be a single image because we are looking for the next index of that single
image.
All right.
And we are going to say that we want to find whenever image is equal to so triple equals, the next
image to the next image.
So this and this method, what it is going to do is this function is going to return the index of the
next image because we have given that index and name, which is the image.
And this image is going to have a numeric value.
It is going to be one, two or three or whatever.
Right.
So, so far, so good, what I'm going to do is in here now.
Now we have completed our I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to remove these council logs because they're not professional and they look like they crowd
our code a lot.
So I'm just going to go ahead and remove it.
You can't use admit, you know, how to add them.
Now, the next thing that I want to do is and actually it is one last thing.
We have one other thing to do in here as well.
But what I want to do in this lecture is whenever we click on this write button, we want to be able
to move the images to the left.
So for that one, I'm going to do is I'm going to grab a list and I'm going to say style and I'm going
to say transform a right.
And because we are transforming them, we are translating them.
And translate is a property value of the transform.
And we are going to say translate open parentheses because translate is a function we are going to provide
with a negative value.
And the reason for that is we are moving them along the negative x axis.
And this is translate X.
All right, and in here, what I want to do is I want to grab I want to just add in space first.
I want to concatenate a space and we are going to grab our target image.
But for now, I'm just going to call it the next image or let's go ahead.
Let's go with the target image, because it's not going to always be the next image.
It could always be.
It could be the previous image as well.
And we are going to say that style that left.
Right.
And we are just going to see plus and I think this is going to be it.
So we have our list style transform.
We grab the target image.
Right.
And we select the style and we go to the left.
But here we have our next image.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and change it to the next image for now.
OK, and.
OK, so the next thing that I want to do is I want to grab the current image as well, and I want to
add I want to add or either remove a clause.
So first off, I'm going to remove a clause from it and the class is going to be yes, you guessed right.
It is going to be the current Dasch image.
And whenever the next for example, when we have our current image, we want to remove the current image
clause and we want to add that current image clause to what?
To our next image.
We want to add that current.
So I'm going to say class.
Let's start at and let's go ahead and let's say current dash image.
All right, so let's save it.
Let's come in to our Web page.
Let's close this and let's click on this.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's click on this image, so when I click on it, we can see that
we go to our next image, but actually we are not going to our next image.
Our next image is appearing from the right to the left.
We are styling the property, the left property, and this is where the property lies.
OK, so it's this transform is going to grab the value of the left from this image, right?
And the value for the left of this image has been calculated right here, which is what this Jet-Black
bounden client rectangle that with, which is fifteen thirty six.
And it doesn't matter how many times we collect it, we are always going to go to the next image, but
we don't have any more images now.
There are quite a lot of problems here.
First, whenever we go to our last image, we still see this arrow.
We don't see our left arrow and we cannot go back as well.
So those problems we are going to start fixing in our next lecture.
See you guys in the next lecture.