Hi, everyone, welcome to the second part of creating a note playing function.
All right, so we have created this function, but we are not done with it yet, there is a lot of things
that we want this function to do, and I have created a constant of note audio and we have selected
the document and the idea.
But the idea is dynamic.
And now we have to make sure we understand this dynamic idea that we have created.
So I'm just going to go ahead because we need real estate on the screen.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's increase the width of this, Ed, so we know what the key is.
Whenever when we said we have said key document that element get document that determined by the key.
We know what exactly that means.
It means whenever we click on any of these keys, we are going to get get that specific key associated
with the click event.
Right.
So we have successfully understood that.
Now, let's go ahead and let's talk about the DOT data set.
What is this?
So let's let's consider the consulate to the log and let's go over it, click on it.
And then here it is going to give me a dumb string map map and inside that and you guys can see this
is an object.
Right.
But this is not an object.
It is a dumb string map.
It is going to map for whatever it is that we are working with.
It behaves like an object, but it is not an object.
It is not a true object.
It's not pure of heart.
Right.
So we can whenever we have an object, we can access the key value pairs of that object.
We can access the properties of that object right through the dot notation.
That's why we say that note.
And in here you guys can see it says note.
All right.
So if I were to comment that out and come here and say dot note, we should be able to grab this specific
note that we want to play whenever that specific key has been clicked.
So click we are going to play C click D flat click E flat click, G flat, A flat and B flat.
Right.
So we have successfully done that.
And this is why we say key the data set that note.
And what I'm going to do is because this is going to get very, very clutterham I'm going to remove
the council box because that part is easy.
I just wanted to get you up to speed of what we are doing because this seems like a very, very cool
project.
So I want to make sure that you understand every part of it.
So now we have successfully selected this, right?
So what I'm going to do is let's go ahead and let's call in another method and that method is going
to be play.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come here and I'm going to say no dot idea.
Why do I keep writing?
It is not known that I do.
It is this constant.
What is the name of this constant?
Let's put it here and let's say play.
Save it.
It does point C and each time the sound is different now, this is another method that we can use.
Basically, we grab it by the element ID and we say play the note and we know what that note is because
the note has the same name as well.
All right.
So it is going to play this note, right?
And it is going to grab the idea and this idea belongs to an idea, and whenever we grab the idea,
it is going to play the source for us.
So we have successfully been able to click and play.
So each time we place a different one.
So what if I go ahead and click multiple times on this so you can hear the clicking?
So when I click.
The first time it is going to play the note, that's cool, we have understood that part, but what
if I click a second time very quickly after the first time?
Now, it is not going to play it like a real piano.
So whenever you push a piano, keys, a piano key multiple times, it is going to play that note multiple
times.
It is not going to wait for that note to end to play the second time.
I'm going to repeat myself whenever we have a real world piano, whenever we have a physical, tangible
piano, and when you press a key on that piano, it is going to play a note.
When you press it very quickly two times it is going to play that note two times.
But what happens in this case is because first off, this is not a physical piano.
Right.
But we should get close to a physical piano.
Whenever I click on this, it is going to play that note.
And when I double click on it, it means I'm just double tapping.
So I should hear the note being played twice.
So let's let's hear it now.
We just heard it once.
The reason for that is we are going to hear that the second time, whenever the first time the audio
has been done, the audio is finished.
So when the note and then another note place, we don't want that.
We want to be able to play this key multiple times quickly.
That's how real world pianos work.
So I'm going to come on top of there and I'm going to say no to audio.
Let's grab our constant and we are going to say current time.
Now, this is a very, very cool property property and we are going to set it to zero.
And what this current time does is whenever we click on it, it is going to basically this is going
to play the note according to our clip.
So let's hear it.
Well, correct.
There is an end missing.
I was kind of like, oh, this is not playing.
I was panicking in my mind, in my brains, in my head, in my head.
Right.
So now let's click on it.
And I'm sure you understand the difference.
I'm just going to go ahead and do it one more time.
It's so fun.
So see, so what we had before was.
I'm sure you can hear the clicking.
It was like bam, bam, bam, and now it's blue.
It's like this.
All right.
So we have successfully done that as well.
So now let's go ahead and let's implement the color.
So when I click on any of these keys, it is going to switch the Carter showing that that key has been
pressed.
Now, let's go ahead and do that for that.
We do have, if you remember correctly, we have an active class.
So now let's go ahead and let's add this active class.
So we are going to say a key dot class list.
Come on, buddy.
Keep that class list dot at.
What is the cost that we want to add?
It is the class of fact, so let's save it.
And now we do get but there is a big problem.
The class is not being removed.
So whenever the note is done or whenever the clicking is done, we want to remove the class.
So now the class has been added.
The class has been out.
And now let's go ahead and remove it.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and create.
Let's go ahead.
Let's grab the node, that idea.
And we are going to say that at a event listener, you're going to add an event listener.
And the event listener is going to listen for an extended event we do have in that event as well.
And when the note is ended, when the event is ended, actually, what is the event the event is like?
So when the event is ended, what do we want to do?
We want to run a function.
And what does the function is going to do?
What does the function?
What is the function going to do?
The function is going to grab our key and is going to say classless that your guests are right to remove
it is going to remove the active class, save it now click.
It is going to go away because whenever the note is done playing, it is going to remove the C.
We can still see two keys being played.
Of course, whenever you're playing piano, you might have you might be playing like clicking or pressing
multiple keys.
But still, when you're done with that note, the key should come up.
This is basically like a like showcasing a real world piano.
Like whenever you see this background color, it means that it means that the key is being pressed.
So sort of we are done with this play note function.
So the next thing you can say that this project is done.
But what I want to do is I want to implement the key functionality, the key of the keyboard functionality
as well.
So we are going to start implementing those from our next lecture.
See you guys then.