Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we will be creating our constructor.
All right, first things first, we have selected our canvas element and we have got the context 2D
on the canvas element and we have stored it inside the canvas context.
The canvas with is the inner width of the window.
The canvas is height is the inner height of the window.
So first things first.
What I'm going to do before actually grabbing the creating the constructor that we are we will be working
throughout this project.
I want to create the game loop.
So I'm just going to say the game loop.
And the game loop, I'm just going to call this function, and he made balls, so it's going to be animated
balls and there are there aren't going to be any parameters.
So this function is going to request the animation frame.
And inside that, we are going to pass in the functions name.
And right after that, I'm just going to clear the canvas.
OK, so we have talked about this in or I think previous chapter was when we talked about a really a
lot.
I'm not going to go over it like any more.
So we basically, whenever this animation happens, it means that the ball is constantly being redrawn
with every time the screen is being refreshed or with every frame in that refresh state.
And basically, whenever we get to the next state or next frame, we want to clear the previous one.
So we do not see the previous iterations of that or the previous evolution of that.
If we see it, then it is going to take away from the illusion that this is an animation.
All right.
So we have created that.
And I'm just going to call this function right here so we can get to the fun stuff quicker.
Next step, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go on top of on top of it.
I'm going to create a class and I'm going to call it run balls class.
Right.
So this is going to run the balls on the screen.
And I'm going to say class.
We know how classes are created.
We just have to provide the class keyword in front of it.
And the name should be capital.
Like the first letter should be capital.
And let's open this.
So this is going to be a template for an object.
That's why it's called object oriented, even though it has a class keyword in the object oriented paradigm.
We use classes.
Right.
So in here, I'm going to pass in a constructor.
The idea behind constructor is whenever we call this run balls and we provide the arguments for this
class, all the arguments of this class are going to be parameters are going to be the values for the
parameters of the constructor of that class.
So what do we need here?
Because we are creating circles.
So we need an exposition, a Y position, a the circles will be moving with different speeds in different
directions.
Basically, we will be having different velocities.
So x the velocity in the extraction, the velocity in the Y direction, and then we will be having different
radii, the same radius and then our colors for the circle.
So red green.
I'm going to do we have done this color a lot.
So I'm just going to do I'm just going to follow that.
So after that, let's say this EXPE is going to be the exposition and then we are going to say this,
dad, why he is going to be the Y position of the circles.
This dot xvid, the velocity is going to be the velocity that is going to be passed as the value for
that parameter, which is S.V..
Then the same thing is going to come for the Y v.
Right, and right after that, we have our.
This dart radius is going to be equal to radius, then let's get the colors, this red, red and this
dot green is going to be equal to green.
And finally, we have this blue is going to be equal to blue.
So now we have created our constructor, right.
What I'm going to do is inside this class, I'm going to create a function that is going to draw the
ball.
So I'm going to call it drawing the balls.
And I'm just going to say draw balls.
And this is going to be a function expression with no parameter, so how can we draw a circle on the
screen or a ball on the screen?
We are going to grab our canvas context.
And first off, I'm going to specify the film style because we do not want to provide it a stroke.
We want to fill that circle.
So for that, I'm going to use these tactics and I'm going to say RGV.
So what is the first color?
It's red.
The second color is going to be green and the third color is going to be blue.
So it's Passan Blue, but this is not going to work because we have no reference to the screen blue
and this red, green and blue.
We need to passant this the red in that case this red is this one and the value for that is going to
come from there.
So I'm just going to click there and hold out multiple times and I'm going to say this, dot now these
values are going to be referenced from this key word, right?
So this is the film style.
Let's begin our path.
So begin path.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to call the canvases our property and our method.
This is going to take in the exposition.
So this expe, this dot, why the y position.
So y and then the circle is radius, circles, radius and we have the starting angle zero and the ending
angle, which is going to be math that pi times two.
And finally we are just going to say canvas get context fill.
If I save it and if I let's just go ahead and open this up with a life server, we are not going to
see anything on the screen except for this cat.
The reason for that is we need to instantiate this class.
I mean, this class is created, but we have not instantiated here.
I'm not going to instantiated in this video because I just want to make sure that the collision is there
for for the ages.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say collision detection on it just right.
And I'm going to create a function.
I'm going to call it update balls.
And this is going to be a function expression.
So we are going to function.
No parameters there.
And I'm going to say, if now when we have our balls on the screen, how can we provide it with that
idea that the balls should not go off the canvas?
So you can see that when it hits.
For example, let's take the right side first and I'm going to you know what?
I'm just going to enlarge them.
So they are a bit better visible so we can really talk about them, how we can implement this.
So we say that whenever.
Now, in this case, in the case of this collision detection, what I want to do actually is I want
to change the position.
I want to change the velocity when they hit the ball.
Now we are going to have two different kinds of collision detection.
The first kind is going to be that whenever any circle or any ball hits any of the edges of the screen,
it should bounce back.
That's first line.
The second kind is whenever we create these circles, they should not be created outside the canvas
or like half of the half of the diameter should be outside the canvas.
No, they should be created inside the canvas, not off the canvas.
That's going to be the second kind which will be talking about.
So whenever the exposition, for example, if the exposition, if a ball is right here, if the exposition
of the ball is greater than the width of the canvas, it means that the ball is off the canvas.
Right.
And we need to add in the radius because we need to make sure that not only one part of the circle is
off, but the circle is off the canvas by its full radius.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to say if this if the position, the X position of the ball.
Now, what I'm going to do is this is just for collision detection on the right side.
Keep that in mind.
If the if the X position of the ball plus its radius.
So it's Grobin, the radius, it means that the position of the X is off the canvas by its full radius,
going to say canvas element with if it is greater than that, it means it's off the canvas.
What do we want to do?
We want to grab the horizontal velocity so this X V and we are only interested in changing the direction
for that.
So if it, if it goes that way and it and it tries to go off the canvas, it should bounce back.
So it's very simple.
So this is going to take care of the right side.
What about the left side for the left side?
Because if we if we go towards the left, it means that it is getting smaller than zero.
So greater than zero is right.
Smaller than zero or negative numbers, which are smaller than zero are going to be towards the left.
So what we are going to do is we are going to if the X position of any ball is less than zero bytes
for radius.
Right.
So this is going to be a logical or operator and we are going to if the X position of any ball bytes
for radius.
So minus this, the radius, the reason that we say minus is because we are moving in a negative direction
is greater than sorry is less than zero.
We again, we still want to change the the velocity, we want to say that if the velocity, whichever
direction the velocity is just bounced back and this is going to be the same for the Y direction as
well.
So I'm just going to copy it and I'm going to put it right here.
So if the Y position of the of the balls plus this radius is greater than the canvas height.
So first off, we just talk about the bottom side.
So this is the bottom side, because when we come towards the bottom of the page, that's where the
things they get bigger.
And when we get towards the top of the page, that's when they get smaller.
So if the X Y position of the ball plus is for radius is higher than the canvas is high, whereas canvas
element that height, it's this bottom part.
If it is greater than that, it means the ball is off, the canvas just bounces back.
So we are going to say bounce the ball back.
Right.
And if the ball is off the canvas from the top, it means it's less than zero by for radius.
Just bounce it back again.
And what I'm going to do is because we need these balls to keep moving, I'm going to add the ball velocity,
I'm going to added on to the position.
That's why the balls, they are constantly moving because we are constantly adding this velocity to
it.
So we will be creating all this like this, the velocity.
And in our next structure, of course, we are creating the X position, the Y position, the X velocity
device, the Y velocity.
OK, and then you will know, OK, whichever value the Y velocity has, the Y position is going to be
added on by that.
So if the Y velocity is one, the Y position at first is going to be one and then it is going to be
one plus one and then is going to be two plus one and three plus one.
We will be just adding it on to that.
So I'm just going to say y position plus plus equal this dot y v.
All right.
And.
Basically, that's it, so that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one where where we will be creating our for loop and in the next lecture we
will be actually creating the circles on the screen.
And you will be seeing that how these circles they actually move.
So I'll see you guys then.