Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to talk about nesting.
All right, so first off, we're going to take a look at nesting objects within objects, right?
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to create an object called user and we are going
to open our curly braces, which is the syntax for object, OK?
And I'm going to create my first key, OK?
And it is going to be Thunderbolt.
Thunder Bolt.
Thirty seven, right, and the value is going to be another object, OK, so the key is Thunderbird
three seven and the value is going to be another object because I want to pair some information as the
value for the thunderbolt.
Thirty seven key.
All right.
So I'm going to say my name is Ross and job is classified.
Right.
And then we are going to put in a comma.
Now, this is the end of this key value pair, and we should put in a comma, OK?
And I'm going to say paygrade.
Paygrade is a right, let's save it now.
OK, so now we have successfully nested one object inside the other object, right?
So let's go ahead and let's consider log user.
And we have Thunderbird 37.
You guys can see that on the outer part we have our curly braces, which means that it is an object.
And inside there we have another object.
OK, so it's an object nested within another object.
This is how we can nyst objects and we can access the information of the nested object as well.
All right.
So the way we do that is usually the best practice is through the bracket notation.
So I'm just going to say Thunderbolt Thunderbolt three seven.
If I save it now, we get another object.
And this object has two key value pairs.
One is job classified and the other one is named Ross.
We can get those information as well.
We just say Dutney and we've just got Russ, all right, and we are, as far as the key value pairs
themselves are concerned, we can use dot notation.
All right.
We have talked about how and where we should not use dot notation or the DOT syntax and the brackets
syntax.
All right.
And we can grab the job as well.
And the job is classified.
All right.
So this is nesting objects within objects.
The next thing that I want to talk about is nesting arrays within objects.
We can nest arrays within objects as well.
All right, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create an object, and
inside that, we are going to nest an array.
All right.
So it's again, it is going to be user and we are going to open our curly braces for the.
Object syntax, right?
And again, we are going to say Thunder Bolt 37, right, and the value is going to be another object.
So it's actually nesting an object in an array within another object.
Right.
But the main part is the array that we are going to nest inside.
You name is.
You know what?
I'm just going to go ahead and copy it, copy all this from there.
And I'm going to post it here and I'm going to uncommented all of them.
So so far, we know how we can do that and the way we can this scenario is we just open brackets and
that's it.
But this is not an array.
This is the value.
Right.
Where was the name?
Where is the key?
We should provide it with keys as well.
So we are going to say hobbies and this, that hobbies is going to be the key and the value is going
to be another array.
And we are going to say golf.
Walk and because this is a strength provided in quotations and we are going to say give out.
Orders.
Let's save it, so now we have successfully nested an array within another object, right?
We can say console the log user, let's save it.
It's come here.
So we have this Hobie's.
It is an array.
Right.
And we have the rest is an object and we do have another object nested inside as well.
And this is usually the way that JavaScript is done when we get to our real work projects, because
when we work with real world projects, we are working with very, very complex data and we usually
pair up arrays and objects together to meet our demands to meet the demands of the application.
Right.
And the way we can grab or access the values is we can just go ahead and say hobbies.
We are going to get an array QAQA and we can say, for example, we can access the items within an array
through their index.
For example, the index of zero is going to give me gothe.
OK, so we can do this as well.
Well, actually I should provide them in two different console logs, so it is not confusing.
All right.
So this is nesting arrays within objects.
We can nest objects within arrays as well, right?
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead.
Nesting objects within a race, we can do that as well.
Now we are going to create a constant which is user again, and now we open brackets, which is the
syntax for arrays, right.
So the first key sorry, the first value or the first item within this user is array is going to be
an object and that object is going to have a name and the value for name is going to be Tony.
And the job is another key and the value for that key is going to be complicated.
All right and OK, so this is the first item inside this, even though this item is an object, but
this is the first item inside this array.
All right.
So the next item, we can just go ahead and write compassionate.
All right, and another one we can also add, as you guys know, we can nest arrays within arrays as
well, so I can create an array here as well.
So making a right.
So where is the BRAC?
The quotations, making suits.
All right, and.
Destroying, destroying suits.
All right, so now we have successfully nested an object and another array within the user's array.
Let's go ahead and log it to the console so we can see our data.
And now you guys can see the outer brackets, they are represented by the outer parts, they're represented
by brackets, meaning that it is an array and the array length is three.
But this one, if I click on this one, this is an object.
Right.
And we can of course, of course, all always we can access very easily the information that we want
so we can access them because they're arrays.
We can access them by their index.
That is the easiest way that we can do.
And we get an object and from there we can access the information within that object as well.
For example, let's grab the job and we are going to get complicated.
All right.
And we can use a template, literal as well here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to cut this part and I'm going to use back ticks and I'm going
to open our template literal.
I'm going to put it there is toonies Char.
OK, complicated is Tony's job getting Yoda away?
OK, so that is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.