Hi, everyone, in this letter, we're going to go over very bold declarations and variable naming conventions
in JavaScript.
All right, so JavaScript is a case sensitive language and uses Unicode characters set right in JavaScript
instructions are called statements and are separated by semicolons.
And the way that JavaScript passes code and makes our website dynamic is that the source text of JavaScript
scripts get scanned from left to right and is converted into a sequence of input elements which are
called tokens.
And you guys saw the token when we in one of our previous chapters and I think I think it was the previous
chapter.
Right.
And control of characters line Terminator's comments or white spaces right now comments.
We have talked about the comments.
It's the kind of code that you don't want it to run inside the browser.
They are discarded during script execution.
Right now, let's go ahead and let's talk about the main topic of this lesson, and that is variable
declarations.
JavaScript has three kinds of variable declarations.
Right.
So I'm just going to go ahead and create a multiline comment.
The first one, which was used for a very long time is var the second one, which is the newer syntax
is led and the third one is Consed.
I'm just going to write a variable declarations.
Right.
So these are variable declarations.
There are three kinds of variable declarations now before diving into declaring variables with these.
What I want to do is I just want to very briefly talk about the naming conventions for a variable declarations
and I want to tell you why we should talk about naming conventions.
Now, first things first.
VAR declares a variable optionally initializing it to a value that declares a block scoped local variable
optionally initializing it to value and const declare the blocks code read-only name constant.
Now what is the difference between let const and var?
We are going to discuss the difference between Leron const, but we are going to postpone the different
the talk of war to one of our next chapters.
Right.
So now go ahead, let's go ahead and let's talk about the variable naming conventions and why we should
talk about such a topic.
So I am inside my e-mail file.
OK, I just want to show you practically why we should talk about that.
So in here, I created.
Let's go ahead and let's say I create an one and I give it a class of main dush heading and I say some
very important title.
OK, it says some very important time.
Now, the naming convention for classes and team is separating.
If there is one word, just write the word mean.
And if there are two words, we just separate them by a dash.
OK, it's happening.
All right.
So this is the naming convention for a class inside the JavaScript Asara Inside Stadium.
This naming convention also applies to IDE's in an e-mail.
So each language, be it a markup language or a stylesheet language or a programming language like JavaScript,
has some sort of naming convention.
It doesn't matter what the naming convention refers to.
What matters is that we have to follow that naming convention.
All right.
So if we go ahead and if we say hatting, if we do it like this, it is very well valid.
But this is not the naming convention for HTML.
This is actually the naming convention for JavaScript.
OK, so in JavaScript, the naming convention is the same has the same underlying concepts as a.
It has to.
The first thing is that it has to make sense.
All right.
So this is on each one.
This is an element.
This is a title I can't write here like let's say main dush para like like a call it.
This is the main paragraph.
It doesn't make sense because this is an element, this is a heading element and we should call it a
heading.
So this is the first thing that this the name, the name has to make sense.
And this concept applies on the Java in JavaScript as well.
I'm just going to show you in a minute.
And the second thing is that it has to be understandable.
OK, now if I go ahead and if I say like main head or if I just go ahead and if I say title, no title
is a very valid class name for this H1.
But what if down the road we have an edge to that has the same class.
That's a title I have, I have the same class name.
Come on buddy class.
Now what about this?
Now, this is not a good practice because whenever you have an one, you have different starling's for
each one and different Starling's for a stick.
Now both of them are very valid class names, but they are not understandable.
OK, so we have to make it.
We have to write class names in a way that they are understandable.
For example, main title subtitle.
Now these are understand.
OK, now the third concept, which only applies in JavaScript is that they should be Tamela cased.
So I'm just going to write the concepts here.
The first one is it should make.
Come on.
What has happened to me, it should make sense.
The second one is it should be understandable, understandable.
And the third one is should be camel.
Camil case and the Campbell case syntax says that the first word should be all lowercase.
OK, and starting from the second word and onwards, the first letter of each word has to be capitalized,
for example.
OK, so this is a word, Camil, and you guys can see that this is lower case, but this case is a second
word.
And the first letter of this second word is capitalized.
And if there were more words, then each of the words, the starting letter has to be capitalized.
OK, I'm going to show you this.
So if I go ahead and if I say let AIG call 25, let's say it, let's go ahead and log it to our console
so we can see our result and we are going to get 25.
OK, so this is when we have one word inside our variable declarations.
I'm going to tell you what this line means in just a minute.
All right.
What if we have more than one word?
What if we have two words like first name?
We could go ahead and we could say first name like this.
But this is not a good practice in JavaScript.
This is an e-mail naming convention, not a JavaScript naming convention.
So for JavaScript, we have like in here, we have two words.
The first word is first.
The second word is name for the name.
The first letter should be capitalized if there is any other word, for example, the first name and
second name.
And now you can see that the first letter of each of the second each of each of the words after the
second word is capitalized.
And the reason for this is that this syntax, this naming is much better readable.
Then let's just like putting it like this or maybe like first name and second name.
Now, this is not that readable as opposed to this one.
Right?
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to remove all of that.
And I'm going to say and we are going to say the log.
First, not first, first name, and when I say it, it brings it prints it to the console.
Now, this is one of the variable declarations.
Now, why do we need variables in JavaScript?
Is whenever we want to apply dynamic ness or functionality to any website, we first have to grab that
HTML element.
And when we grab that is element, because JavaScript is a programming language, we have to store that
element somewhere.
Right?
We have to store that element somewhere now to store an element.
We can use our primitive data types, which are numbers, booleans, strings and that sort of thing,
and we can use our reference data types.
That's why we have primitive and reference data types, because they store information.
And what information is that?
That is our HTML elements, just as an example.
OK, this is an example.
It is valid, but it is a very beginner level example.
Right.
So we store that information.
Think of this as a box.
Think of any variable in JavaScript as a box.
So the box, for example, you're moving out, you're moving to a new city, you're moving to a new
house, for example.
You have purchased a house for yourself and you move to that house, OK?
So you put all of your stuff inside these boxes, OK?
And you call one of the boxes like frijoles.
The other one like like, I don't know, like cushions or the other one like picture frames and the
other one like books.
So that box is going to be your variable.
OK, I'm just going to write it here so it makes sense and you do not forget it.
So the box represents our variable.
All right, so the box label represents our variable variable name and these naming conventions, they
are applied on the variable name and I'm just going to write here like LAT Consed or Vah.
OK, so these are our variables.
The variable name that we have used here.
I'm just going to write first name, right.
And whatever is inside the box inside or I'm just going to say box content is going to be variable stored
info.
OK, and in this case, in the case of our first name, it is Muslin or let's go ahead and remove remove
the quotes because we just store the information.
This is the information.
So again, variable is our box, like let constant vare and then we have the box label which which is
the variable name, because if you like, if you do not name your boxes, then how would you find,
for example, like where do you put your box?
So naming the variables is an easier way for us to find which kind of information or which kind of books
in this case information we are looking for.
OK, and what do we get that we get the variable stored info or the box content?
OK, so this is how variables work in JavaScript.
Now, that is the difference between left and const, is that whenever you you declare a variable with
the left, you can read assign that variable, for example, here, ages 25.
Let's go ahead and let's talk about this first name.
I'm just going to comment on the H.
So here first name is Muslim.
We can go ahead and we can say first name and set it to, I don't know, like John.
And if we save it and if we copy our consular log and now guests can see now the first name was Muslim.
Now it is John.
OK, it doesn't matter how many times we call it.
It is also is always going to be, John.
Now, this is perfectly valid in inlet, but as far as cost is concerned, you cannot really change
the name or reassign the variable to something else.
You cannot change the variable stored information when it comes to const and the primitive data types.
But when it comes to const and the reference data types, you can do that because reference data types
are not stored inside the JavaScript memory, inside the computer memory.
A reference to that data structure or reference type is stored.
We are going to talk about that a lot when we get to their specific chapters.
So in here, if I go ahead and if I say first name, let's set it to Muslem, let's consider the log
our first, not inside the quotes or first name, and then we get our Muslim.
OK, but what if I go ahead and if I grab the first name and I reassign it to Mike, and if I do that,
it says uncaught type error assignment to constant variable.
And it even gives us the address.
And if I click there, it comes from line twenty six.
This is where the error comes from.
It says that assignment to constant variable, even though it is a variable, it is a constant variable.
So we cannot reassign constant variables.
And you might ask what is the use of a constant variable when you have a large application where you
have a lot of like hundreds of variables and thousands of lines of code, it is a good practice to use
const because when you assign first name Muslim, for example, and many hundred lines of code later,
when you by mistake, of course, or unknowingly, of course, you re assigned first name, it is going
to throw an error.
It is going to it is going to tell you that you have assigned first name before.
So it is a good practice to use const, but const has definitely its pros and cons most of the time.
Some of the times we want to change the variable like first name is first Muslim and then the first
name is John and then it's Sandra.
And then it is, I don't know, like Monica.
And then it is like whatever.
Right.
So sometimes we want to reassign it and other times we do not want to reassign our first name and our
variables.
And that's where we use const.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.