Hi, everyone, welcome to the second part of drawing lines and circles on the canvas.
All right, so we have specified some initial values, right, for the size, for whether or not the
click is pressed or the mouse is down, for the color and also for X and Y coordinates.
Now, there are actually three steps to using canvas through JavaScript.
The first step we have implemented is to find or to address the canvas element inside our JavaScript,
which we have done here.
The second step is creating a drawing object, which is this one get context study and the third step
is actually drawing on the canvas.
Now, to be able to draw a line, we need two methods.
The first method is move to and the second method is aligned.
Now the move to method defines the starting point of the line and the line to method defines the ending
point of a line.
Right.
And first off, we are going to go ahead and implement the line and then we will be talking about the
drawing a circle.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to grab our canvas and I'm going to add a listener.
Now, the event that I'm listening for is going to be Moorestown.
And I'm going to I'm going to tell you why.
Moorestown.
Right.
And when the mouse is down, what I want is I want to run a function.
And I want to grab the event object as well, because we will be needing that.
So when the mouse is pressed down, it means that we want to start drawing on the canvas and in that
case it means that the is is equal to true.
So we are going to grab or is pressed and we are going to set it to true.
Right.
Very simple.
Initially the is pressed is fast because the user has not clicked.
Has the mouse is not down.
All right.
But when the when the event is fired, the march down event or the click event is fired.
Why do we want we want to say that the express it is true now.
We want to specify exactly where it is that the user has clicked.
So we are going to grab our X coordinates, which we have specified before, and we have set an undefined
value because we don't know what the values and we are going to grab our event object and we are going
to say off set X.
All right, so the X is going to be the offset of X and the Y is going to be the offset of Y, you guessed
it right.
All right, just grab this wire and capitalize it.
We can go ahead and check check these out in the council as well, where exactly they are.
So we are going to say.
Let's let's just consider log X for now.
So we are going to come here.
This is a project.
Let's inspect it.
And when I click there, it is going to give me the what?
The X coordinates.
All right.
So in here, the offsets should be almost zero.
This is towards zero.
And in here it should be towards 1500.
The reason that it is near 1500 is that we have specified the width of our can.
Where is it in here?
The width of the canvas is 1500.
So the starting point for the X on the canvas is zero is right there zero.
And the ending point should be 1500.
See if we can get it.
There we go, 1500, but what about why so for the why the starting point is again zero and the ending
point is 600, we can't conceive that we can log it to the council as well.
But I'm not going to do because.
Very, very simple.
All right, so we have done this now, the other event listener that I want to add on the canvas is
actually the polar opposite of this.
So I'm going to say canvas that Adamsville listener.
And we are going to listen for a mouse up.
For a mouse up event, right, and we are going to run a function.
Oops, not there.
We are going to run a function when the mouse is up.
Function, they're going to grab the event object as well, right?
So when the mouse is not clicked or the mouse is up, we want to say that the press is going to be equal
to false.
It means that the user is not pressing because we have just received a mouse up event.
A mouse up event has been fired.
When the mouse up event is fired, it means that the user is not clicking.
When the user is not clicking, we just want to set the express defaults once more.
And the X coordinate is going to be undefined and the Y coordinate is going to be undefined as well
because the user is not clicking, we do not know where the user is clicking because the user is actually
not clicking.
So the values, they're not defined anymore.
All right, so now we will move on to drawing the line, I think we talked about how we will be first
drawing a line.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's create that function right here.
So I'm just going to call it drawing line.
Drawing lines, just color drawing lines.
And I want to create a function and I'm going to call it draw lines or just simple, like singular,
and we are going to grab our we are going to pass in four parameters, which we will be using, of course.
All right, so and we have talked about how we need a method force for the start of that line and a
method for the end of that line.
All right.
So for the ending of it, so the starting points, I'm just going to call him X1 and why one and the
ending points?
I'm going to call him X2 and why.
All right.
So we are going to grab our object and we are going to say.
Begin path, so begin path.
Where is the Intellisense there, so now this begin path method is actually going to start, if you
like, that path that we want to create, the next method that I want to call on this city acts as the
move to that we have talked about move to and this method is going to grab these starting points for
a line.
So the starting points are X one and Y one.
So I'm just going to go ahead and pass them right here.
So it's Copperas, pass them here as function arguments.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the seats and I'm going to say line two, this is
going to be the ending points for a line.
So let's grab the X2 and Y two.
Let's pass them right here.
So now the line is drawn.
All right, whenever the user clicks.
But we don't have any actual way of linking this function to these events, which we will do in our
next lectures.
But for now, what we want to do is we want to accomplish drawing the line function and drawing a circle
function.
The next thing that I want to do is I want to grab the seats and I want to specify the stroke style.
So stroke style, which is dealing with the color.
And I want it to be the color that we have specified here and it is going to be black.
So that is the stroke style is going to be black.
The width of the line for the stroke, I'm just going to call it our line with all right, it is going
to be size for now.
I'm just going to leave it a size, but we are going to change it.
So the size is going to be 10 initially.
And finally, to complete this, we are going to say stroke.
Just we are going to call this stroke method.
All right.
So the function for the draw line is created.
Now, we are we are going to go ahead and create the function for draw circles.
Drawing circles are right.
It is going to be almost the same, but a bit different.
Of course, we are going to call it draw circle.
All right, and you're going to pass an X and Y in here, so we are going to say begin path.
So whenever we want to, we want to create a line or we want to draw a circle.
First off, we need to tell it to begin that we begin drawing that path.
All right.
Now, the creating the circle, we we have multiple things, right?
The method that we are going to call upon the.
The reason that we are grabbing the seats is the seat object is actually is the thing that is going
to allow us to create 2D drawings on the canvas.
Right.
And now looking at the clock, it's been ten minutes and I do not want to prolong this video.
So we are going to complete these functions in our next lecture.
See you guys that.