Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to draw lines, arcs and circles.
All right, so we have the exact same styling for our e-mail elements, and canvas is basically the
same.
So that's come into our JavaScript.
So in the JavaScript, again, we have selected the canvas.
We have initialized the 2D context.
The Highton with are the same.
What we are going to do is we are going to draw lines, draw arcs and draw circles.
Now this is a link to a website.
This is Mathis's fun fun.
And we are going to go over this over the irradiance.
Right.
So first off, how can we draw a line now?
The first thing that you need to do is always just get the canvas context because all of them are reliant
on this one now for drawing the lines, for drawing lines, arcs and circles.
First, you need to begin path.
You need to start a path.
Now the path is just started.
It it doesn't have any coordinates yet, but it is started.
Right.
And then now when the path is started, what is the initial points for that path?
Because this is a 2D context we need in XPoint and we need a waypoint or a horizontal point and a vertical
point.
So what we're going to do is we are going to say get a canvas context move, too.
So this is where the position is.
I'm just going to say 250 by 250.
Right.
And now now this is the starting position.
We say that our begin path should go should move to this coordinates and it should start the path and
where it should go to it should go to get that canvas context line, too.
Right.
So where do we want it to go to?
We want it to go to 400 to move along the extraction and 350 along the way.
So when it starts from 250, it goes by this distance and in each of the directions now.
Still, we don't have any life style for our line, if I save it, we are not going to see anything.
So let's grab our context.
And we are going to say stroke's style, right, because lines, they don't have any dimensions and
they just they just have strokes, right.
And it means like we we don't have to say, like, fill that line.
We just say like like lines are like borders.
We just have to specify the color for them.
And I'm going to set it to white.
And finally, in order to draw the line.
Now, all of these they were this has started the path.
The path should start from here, go to here.
But what is the method to actually draw that line?
It is the stroke method.
So if I save it, we should see some light.
So you can see that the line starts from 250 along the x axis and what was.
Yeah, 250 along the Y axis.
And then it moves to 400 along the X axis and 350 along the Y axis.
Right.
And so this is our first line.
I'm just going to say a line one.
You can't create jobs.
You can't create as many lines as you want.
So by creating if you want to create more lines, you just say a line to whatever line to.
And I'm going to say a line three, line four, line five, line six, line seven.
So what about line two?
We want the line two to be 600.
So we're going to put it 600 and 150.
So it should go up, right, because it is going to decrease its height from 350 to 100 to 150, the
line number three.
So I'm just going to for a sec.
Oops.
For a second, I just want to commend those ones out, and you can see that it decreases its height
because it went from 350 to all the way to 150.
So the line number three is going to be I want it to go 700 and the extraction and 450 in the Y direction.
Line number line number four, I want it to go 1000 in the extraction and 50 in the Y direction.
So it goes really, really up.
Then I want it to go 50, 100 along the X axis and 250 along the Y axis.
Now you can see that at this point it has increased its horizontal distance and it is coming down from
the top.
So it's 50 and now it's 250.
The other line can be 250.
So now you can see that it goes back in the negative direction and this is going to be 650.
It has come way down.
So if I save it, where are we?
We are right here.
You can see that.
Right.
So this is what is that, 250?
And this is 650.
Right.
And finally, what I want to do is I want to create another another line here as well.
And I'm going to call it six.
And I want it to be 650 and then 650 to 250.
And finally, line number eight should be 250, back to 250.
And I'm going to call this line number eight.
So let's save it.
You can see that we created this.
So this is a basic drawing here.
Now, this is drawing lines and then we have drawing arcs in the drawing arcs.
What we have is we have radians instead of degrees.
So what irradiance?
This website is really fun.
It explains in a very simple term.
So the angle made when the radius is wrapped around the circle.
So this this angle that you can see when if if we get this radius and wrap it around the circle, like
literally around this angle, then the angle that we get is one radius.
And here is the animation for that.
So if I click play, you can see that it is being wrapped around that angle.
And this is one radion.
I can I can show you this.
I have to show you this as well, because one PI is three point one four one five nine or three point
one four one six and half a circle.
Half a circle is pi radians or one hundred and 180 degrees.
So one entire circle is 360 degrees, but half a circle is hundred and eighty degrees.
One entire circle is two is to pi r or two pi radians.
Half a circle is one pi a radius.
So if I click on it and why is it three point one four one six.
Because we get one radion two radion three irradiance and this little part is one four one six point
one four one six.
So if I click on it this is one radion two radians three radians and then three point one four six.
It's five radians which equals one hundred and eighty degrees.
All right.
And there is a lot of information in here that you can go over.
And this is really, really fun.
And it's this one.
Radion is fifty seven degrees and it proves it to you why it is that it is going to get right.
So this is actually a gradient.
So if I say if I grab the PI because in JavaScript PIs are not pi degrees, they are pi radians.
So one pi radion is 180 degrees which is half a circle.
So if we were to create one entire circle we should say PI times two.
Right.
We should multiply it by two because 180 degrees multiply by two degrees we get we get 360.
So let's go ahead and create that.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say canvas.
Canvas.
Canvas context, but I'm going to begin the path I know we have already begun the path, but this is
a different path and if I do not begin, then the circle will attach itself to these lines and I can
show you that.
All right.
So I'm going to say canvas context, that arc.
So this art creates arcs and creates circles.
So first off, we get the horizontal and vertical dimension positions.
So let's say I want it to be 750 along the x axis and 350 along the Y axis.
Then we need to get it.
The radius.
So radius is this so far from the center of the circle to the circumference of the circle?
That is the radius.
Right.
So radius, if you go if you connect one part of the circumference of the circle and move past through
the center of the circle to the other part of the circumference of the circle, then that is going to
be one diameter.
Now, one radius is half a diameter.
Right.
So this is one radius.
This is this is the circle radius.
And this is how we circle is created.
So the radius is 50, it means that the diameter is going to be 100, diameter is always twice the circle,
then we get the start angle.
Keep this in mind.
This is in radians, not degrees.
And then we get the end entangle because we want to at first I want to create an arc.
Right.
I just want to create ARC here.
So for ARC, basically we just say multiplied by PI.
So the end angle is just one pi because we know PI is actually half a circle and this is an arc, half
a circle is an arc.
So I need to pass and pi.
Right.
But in JavaScript PI is a property of the math object that set the other variable that the other parameter
that we have here is anticlockwise or clockwise.
So if I said it's true then it is going to draw anticlockwise like it should be like this.
It should go from right to top then to left.
So if I save it and if I come here, we are not going to see anything because we have not called the
stroke method.
So can this context stroke?
Let's save it.
And now we can see this is anticlockwise if I put it to false.
This is going to be clockwise.
OK, so I'm just going to go ahead and remove it because we are concerned with drawing circles.
So by default, it's safe.
It is going to be and is going to be clockwise.
Right.
So we got the horizontal position, vertical position radius and mathaf.
So this is how we draw a circle now in case I remove the begin path.
You can see it attaches itself with this line because the line started the path, but we do not want
that to happen.
So this is our drawing arcs.
Now I'm going to come down to drawing circles.
Basically, we are going to have the same thing.
So I'm just going to copy it, put it here.
I'm going to change the positions.
So I'm going to say twelve hundred and to 200 in the Y direction.
Right.
So.
That part is clear, the radius is clear, the start angle is clear.
Now we want to draw a circle.
We don't want to draw an arc.
Now, half a circle.
We know half a circle is pi.
Now, an entire circle is going to be two times pi, two times half a circle, we get in a complete
circle.
So if I save it and if I come here, you can see that we get a perfect circle right now.
You can create as many circles as you want.
You just have to repeat this combo.
Right.
I'm just going to hit enter here and here, for example, for the second one, I'm just going to say
200 and 300.
I'm basically changing the positions.
All right.
And then I'm going to say 400 and 400.
And then I'm going to say.
600, 500, and finally, 800 and 600.
That's what it's come here.
So basically, we have created these circles, so now creating all these circles by hand manually,
not by hand, of course, like putting it in this way, it's not an efficient way of doing it.
Doing it in this way is not an efficient way of doing.
That's why in the next lecture, what we're going to do is we're going to discuss our second part of
drawing shapes randomly.
And in the second part, we are going to draw random lines, lines randomly, circles and arcs randomly.
Right.
And in case you're wondering, we will be coming back to this website over and over again, because
one of the most important aspects of game development with a team of five and can it's just him team
of canvas.
And James is actually doing a lot of math.
And I do not expect you to be good at math.
If if you are, then that's a bonus.
But if you're not, I'm going to I'm going to explain this stuff to you the way like in the way that
I'm going to assume that you don't you have nothing.
You have no knowledge of math.
OK, so I'm going to be explaining the mathematics part simply like in a beginner tone.
But the game development part and as far as the logic is concerned, of course, they are going to be
high level because we have done so many projects and we have covered so many advanced concepts of JavaScript.
And these the code should be simple right to you.
But if the math is not simple, I'm going to make sure that we go over it many times until it is clear.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.