Hi, everyone, welcome to part two of coding an eye for the DOT connector game.
All right, so before actually getting started with this lecture, I want to point your attention to
a mistake that I did.
Just go ahead and make this.
I'm sure you got this.
I mistyped it as Daehlie I or it should be delayed and just come here to our EHI function and convento
these two as well, because I want to show you something.
And what do we have in here is.
That we can actually see the I think, and actually select something, not actually select something,
but actually like think and try to select something.
And you can see that the I paused for one second, which is the selection process, and then passed
on the turn to the player, so.
There we go.
So I just wanted to show you that that the eye is actually working, but not the way that we want it.
So we need to make it work the way that we want.
So we have created these coordinates.
Now, let's go ahead and let's actually choose.
So choosing from a random site, a random free site.
So it is if it is free, we want it to be randomized.
That's why the wanted this one time.
It is like grabbing top, then bottom, then left and right.
So it's just all over the place.
That's because it is random.
So I'm going to create an array, an empty array, and I'm going to call it free coordinates.
All right.
So.
And then if that side, that specific side which the is trying to select is not selected, then we want
the state to select it.
So we are going to say, if not this side bottom.
That's selected, if Sidebottom is not selected, then grab our free coordinates.
And Pushtu at that specific site called Net Bottom Perfect Arezzo, we are going to repeat this for
the other three as well.
And one more time, not two one.
If the site which is not selected is left, then we want the coordinates of that left side to be pushed
to the coordinates of the site, which is not selected is right, then we want the coordinates of right
to be pushed to that array.
If the side which is not selected to stop, we want the coordinates of the top to be pushed to that
site.
Now, after all of these, what do we want this function to return?
We want this function to return coordinates, right.
And because all of these are free, we are going to return them randomly.
We don't want to we don't want our A.I. to be predictable.
We want it to be random or unforeseeable, something like that.
So we we have like some sort of challenge in front of us.
If we know the pattern along which the A.I. selects, then it is going to be supremely easy for us to
beat the right, but it should be some sort of a challenge.
So let's pass and length.
And now that this is going to give us.
A random sight, what I would like to do is let's come here to first off, let me take a look at this
here.
Perfect.
The to spell is correct.
So I'm in here now.
I'm going to comment that one out and I'm going to remove the players, turn right and.
I think we are ready to test our air.
So now you can see I'm just going to reload.
Now it is my turn.
If I select something, it is first highlighted and then selected.
The same thing goes for the computer.
The computer first highlights and then selects.
There we go.
Computer just selected.
Now let's check our A.I. You can see because there are free sites, they're happening randomly.
One was right here, the other one is there.
Now, what I would like to do is check our A.I. for like deficiencies.
For shortcomings.
All right, good, I good.
Very good.
They are we will be tracking this behavior very closely, so we need to be very careful where it is
that the A.I. has selected.
If we are careful, we might be able to find out what the problem is, if there is any problem.
All right.
That is one way.
Perfect.
Oh, there we go.
So this was a mistake, by the way, you can see that we have these other options like these one, two,
three, four, like almost 10 options.
But why did the guy go for this one, even though that we have said that whenever two sides are completed,
that is the third option.
The third priority.
What are the first to the first two is if any square has three sides completed.
So clearly the eye didn't obey that priority.
The second priority actually has two options, whether the square has zero sides like it's an empty
square or one side.
Why did the AICC grab this and selected it is because the I thought that this line actually belongs
to the circle.
Sorry, I'm keep I, I keep saying circle, I mean square.
So the er thought that it was the square.
And because it had one, two, three sides empty and only one side completed, then it just went for
it.
But this is a problem because the A.I. did not account for the top neighbor.
So we need to grab the valid neighbor as well.
And we need to pass on some code for that as well.
I'm just going to finish this so you can see that the eye guided itself.
So clearly, our first priority is working.
The say the third priority was actually was we we have not tested death yet.
We have tested our first and second priority.
The third priority is when the A.I. gives a point deliberately.
So let's test it for that.
There we go.
This is a mistake.
This is not our third priority.
This is actually our first priority today.
I thought that this square was empty.
That's why I selected the top part, OK?
And this is going to be our second priority, zero or one side's.
Hmm, this is clearly another mistake by the.
So you can see how incompetent it is so far.
Right, so we're shit.
I'm going to give him these points.
Of course, first priority clearly is working good, and this is going to be our third priority because
there is no other point, there is no other priority.
They cannot select a square that has three sites completed.
The I cannot select a square that has one zero or one side is completed.
So the I select a square that has two sites completed and that is going to give a score.
And I would have to give this to the FBI and the FBI is going to beat me.
Yeah, it is.
So even though this is not that competent, I it just so even with that, it is like a pretty good eye.
But still we have to do some stuff to make sure that it is competent enough.
So what I would like to do where we were, we set up the options for the air.
We need to manipulate these options.
So first off, I'm going to create a variable called sites and this variable is going to call a function
get Valette neighbor site, which we are going to create and we are.
And it is going to accept the row and the call.
Now, the basic thing that we want to do here is to remove a bug in which the FBI gives a point to the
player.
And how is this actually happening is by selecting a third side, eventually allowing us to select the
fourth one.
Now this function is going to return two things.
One, if it returns nothing.
What does that mean?
So basically, there are two cases.
So I'm just going to go over to the theory first and then the implementation if this function comes
back with nothing.
It means that our current cell that we are selecting has no valid neighbors.
All right, and it means that the FBI is going to be giving us the point, what is the priority in which
the FBI gives us the point that is the third priority.
So if the FBI is giving us the the point, why is that?
Logic should be contained within our case, one within our second priority, we need to push it to our
third priority.
That is point number one by number two.
If this function does come back with some sort of coordinates or options, then.
It means that the FBI can use the squares to select his side.
Now, what does this what does all of this mean?
It means that we need to set the priority dynamically.
Right.
How do we do that?
So first off, I'm going to create a priority variable and I'm going to set it to this size length that
we have and we are going to check for the length if the length is greater than zero.
What does that mean?
It means that the.
Now, if the sides length is greater than zero, it means that the FBI has come, sorry, this dysfunction
has come back with something.
Whatever it is, we want that to be contained within our second priority, we said that if it doesn't
come back with anything, then we want to push it to our third project.
So if it does come back with something, we want to push it to our first priority.
And if it is, and else we want to push it where third priority, which is right here right now, we
need to modify this options as well.
So instead of just saying option one, we are going to pass in our priority and then we are going to
create an object here.
So the object is going to have to properties, the first one is going to be square, which the square
is going to be this array that we have.
I'm just going to pass it right here and then.
We need to take into consideration the sides as well, because we are within the realm of controlling
that weird behavior, we are going to set the sights key to the sides value, which is going to be supplied
from here.
Now, I'm going to ask you a question now, our code has significantly changed, right?
This code doesn't match this.
This pattern doesn't match this one.
Now, what do you think?
I know you think that, OK, we should put this one here as well.
But what do you think the sides is going to accept as a value?
We know what the square is going to accept.
That is the square itself.
But what about the side?
What do you think it is going to accept now, because whenever we are in our first priority, we do
not care which neighbor it is, we just want the EHI.
Basically, the EHI does not care what neighbor it is.
The are just the I's just concerned with filling that fourth line and scoring.
So we don't need the sides here.
So I'm just going to delete it and I'm going to set it as an an, an empty array.
What about our third priority.
So aside from the fact that we are pushing one of the options to the third priority, the third priority
is nowhere.
Where the aid is going to take is going to be like care is going to care about any neighbors, because
in this, the eye doesn't have a choice, doesn't have to think about neighbors because there are no
neighbors to think about.
So basically, the sides is going to be an empty array.
Here as well.
Now that that is going to be it for this lecture, because we talked about a lot of advanced concepts
and we are going to pick up where we left off in our next lecture.
See you guys then.