Hi, everyone in this actually working to dry the canvas aliments.
All right, so we have selected our canvas here and we have got the context and these are the canvas
dimensions, the first thing that I want to do is going to be drawing the canvas.
Now we are going to draw the canvas right here, OK?
And I'm going to create a function.
All right.
And I'm going to call this function, draw Recht.
Right.
And it is going to grab an X position.
A Y position.
We know all this, right.
The A with
a height.
And also a caller, right?
So this is going to be our canvas now, we're going to initialize our canvas with the canvas context
and we're going to say Phil style and let's set it to color and then canvas context, dot, fill, ract,
fill, rect.
And this is going to grab a horizontal position, a vertical position, the width of the canvas and
the height of the canvas.
So this is going to be the first element of our game.
The second element of our game is going to be drawing a circle, which is going to be the ball.
Right.
And so I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say function.
We are not going to call these functions just yet.
When we get to our game loop, we are going to call these functions there.
All right.
So we are going to say function, draw, circle, draw, circle.
All right, and this is going to accept in exposition a Y position, a radius and a color.
So inside here we're going to canvas context, Phil style, Phil style.
What is it going to be?
It is going to be the color that we pass.
And now let's open our let's begin the path.
So I'm going to say begin path.
And for drawing the circle, we have the ARC method, which is going to grab an X position, a Y position,
a radius.
The starting angle is going to be zero.
The ending angle is going to be math dot pi times two.
And then finally we are going to say canvas.
Context that fell, all right, so we have successfully drawn our circle as well.
We're not going to see anything because we haven't called these functions yet.
So I'm going to I'm going to draw the text as well.
So I'm going to say drawing the.
OK, so drawing the text and I'm going to say function, draw text, draw text.
And what is the content of the text?
Let's put it there.
What is the horizontal position?
What is the vertical position of the text and what is the color of the text?
So in order to draw text with canvas, first off, we are going to grab our context, canvas context,
and we are going to basically the first style is going to be the same.
So it is going to be the color that we have.
And then we can we have to say that what is the font properties of that color?
So that text so I'm going to say 25 pixels is going to be the size or initially it was twenty five.
I'm just going to increase it to 35 so it's better visible.
So this is the font size and sans serif is different family.
This is how you create fonts and canvas.
And finally, we are going to say, as with circles that we say fell for this one, we should also use
some sort of fell method.
And it is called fill text.
And fill the text with the content, with the position of X and position of Y.
Right.
So this is going to be a four hour draw, a text function.
The next function that I want to draw here is going to be the next thing that I want to draw is going
to be drawing the net.
Right.
And for that, let's come down here, let's say function and it's going to be draw net.
No parameters in here, and we are going to say basically whenever we draw the net is we are going to.
So let me come here to our original game that we have so you can see that we have multiple iterations
of this line, which seems to be like we seems to have like all of these lines.
They have the same height.
Right.
So what we are going to do is whenever we create this.
So if I zoom out, because the start of this top, this is canvas height equals zero.
So whenever the canvas is height is equal to zero, we are going to start our first line.
And the second line is going to start when the canvas height is 15 pixels.
The height of this line is ten pixels.
So 10 pixels minus this entire space, which is I'm going to zoom in so you can really see.
So from here to here is ten pixels from here, all the way to the edge of the next line is 15.
So what is this space?
Five pixels.
That's how we calculate it.
Right.
So I'm going to zoom out.
I'm going to zoom back into nine to one hundred percent.
So we are going to say four led because we don't want to repeat this function like maybe 100 times for
each of the lines.
We just want the loop to take care of it.
We are going to say that the loop is going to start from zero, which is the top side of the canvas.
At that point, the canvas is height to zero.
So it is going to go to all the way to canvas element that height.
Where is this?
Whereas canvases and the height, it's this bottom part.
So this is going to be the canvas element at height, this bottom part.
Right.
And how do we incremented we incremented each time by now and here we're not going incremented by one
working tormented by 15 pixels.
So the first line is going to be at the canvas height zero.
The second line is going to be at canvas height 15.
The third line is going to be at canvas high thirty.
And the gaps that we end up with is going to be five pixels because the line itself is going to be ten
pixels.
And in here we are going to say draw Recht and let's grab this method.
Now, the reason that I've just specified this to draw, not the draw canvas, is because whenever we
draw those lines, there are two rectangles so we can use this function.
If we draw a canvas that's a tangle.
We can use this function.
We can use this function for our panels as well, because our models are also rectangles.
So we just create one function, one utility function, and we reuse it many times over.
So in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to call that function and I'm going to say that the net
which we are, which we are yet to create the net object's exposition.
And then the net objects y position, we will be creating these nets as well, right, and then the
Y position is going to add on the AI or the variable.
So that's how we get that dashed line.
Then we are going to send net worth and a net dot height.
And finally, next door to color, right, so we have successfully created these and if I come here.
There we go.
So there are no errors yet.
I'm just going to put it to the bottom.
All right, I'm just going to put it here.
And in case there is something that I need to show you there.
OK, so all of these are spelled perfectly correctly, the next step that that is the logical step that
we should do as I'm going to create an object for the players paddle.
Right.
So for this panel, I'm going to create an object, another object I'm going to create for the aeppel,
another object I'm going to create for the ball.
And the fourth object is going to be for the net.
And why do we need objects?
Because I'm going to store inside them some properties.
For example, the height of this paddle, the width of this part of the X position, the Y position,
the color, for example.
What else do we have?
And also the score, all of them are going to be stored within that object so we can reused instead
of riding those properties over and over and over again, we just create objects and we reuse objects.
So that is what we are going to do in the next lecture.
See you guys then.