Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to fetch our data.
All right, so I'm going to go inside the JavaScript file, but before writing anything, we need to
go over what it is that we want to do.
So whenever we type inside of this input, we want to show some cities, of course.
But so first things first.
We need to grab this input and we need to add an event listener to it that is going to listen for whenever
the user types something so and then that when the user types something, some suggestions are going
to be shown inside the school.
So we need to grab this input.
And this year.
Well, all right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come here and I'm going to say const all right.
And we are going to call it search input.
And document to query selecter, right, and what is what is the class, the classes search and next
thing, I just want to grab the suggestions as well.
So I'm going to say suggestion's container.
Right.
And you're going to document to query selector and the class is going to be suggestions.
Suggestions.
All right.
So now we have selected them.
Now, the event listener is going to be on the input because whenever these are types, something inside
that input is when we want to show something on the screen.
Right.
So the event listener is going to be on the input.
So let's grab the input, search input, add a listener.
So what is the event?
That's the important part.
Now, when it comes to inputs, we have a change event and the change event is going to be fired whenever
the input is changed.
So you write something inside the input and when you click away, then this event is going to be is
going to fire and then we are going to call a display matches function.
Right.
But so what I'm going to do is I'm going to come here and I'm going to grab this function, display
matches, and I'm going to basically say cancel log.
In part.
And third event, fire.
Let's let's test it out, all right, so let's go into cons. Let's bring this up, maybe put it on the
side.
That's better, right?
So if I click here, for example, new, you can see that nothing is being fired.
But when I click away, you can see that the event is fire.
And that is not something that we want.
Whenever we start typing, we want the event to fire.
So additionally, we are going to add.
I think it's like that.
Additionally, we are going to add another event listener, and that is going to be on the key up.
So whenever the key is up, we want to run this display functions or call that function as well.
So if I were to say and you can see the event is far different, is fired, W. Devant is far.
So we have successfully implemented this.
All right.
And I'm going to leave this here.
So now let's go ahead and let's fetch the data.
So first off, I'm going to create a constant call.
Cities and cities and states or cities.
States, right.
So it is going to give us all the cities and all the states.
Right.
So it's cities.
What is this?
So city states.
And I'm going to initialize it as an empty array.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's call our object.
So what is the URL for this?
The URL is I'm just going to pasted right here.
Right.
So that's going to be the URL.
Let's remove both of them.
So this is going to return a promise.
What we can do is we can grab that promise.
And we can change it to something that JavaScript can read, right?
So let's say response.
Jason.
So so far we are not going to see anything.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to add another dot then and I'm going to say response data.
And we are going to say, let's let's go ahead and let's log it to the console console that log response
data.
Let's save it.
OK, so now you can see that we get this function.
OK, this is the function that we have.
So we have a response.
Oh, I forgot the parentheses.
There we go.
So this is the array that we get.
Now, keep in mind, this area is no longer adjacent.
It is a valid JavaScript array.
Right.
And you can see that the Proteau says a reservoir.
And this is like a like a massive array.
We have 1000.
The length is 1000 objects within this array.
So what it is actually that we are looking for.
So if I, for example, go ahead to Phoenix number five, you can see that we have a city, OK, you
can grab the growth from 2000 to two thousand thirteen.
You can grab the latitude, you can grab the longitude excuse me.
You can grab the population, you can grab the rank, you can grab the state.
So the data that I want to grab, you can grab the latitude and longitude from here as well.
But I'm not interested in that.
I just wanted to show you that all this data is available for you and you can use this data.
Right.
And this from this data, we are going to grab this property and we are going to grab this property
and we are going to show it on the screen.
So inside this array, what we are going to do is we need to loop over this array or actually what we
are going to do is we are going to filter this array for city and for state.
Right.
So what are we to do is at this point, what I'm willing to do is I want this array to be pushed inside
this array.
Right.
So I want to grab all the items of that array and I want to put it inside the city state array.
So how it is?
How can we do that?
All right.
So if I grab the city state's array and if I say that push and let's put in the response data, let's
see what we get.
And if I push it there, we don't see anything here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to cut this.
So let's cut it, let's provide the curly braces, let's say Kansa lock, I could do this or I could
just put everything here and then say console.
Console, come on, console Deathlok, let's grab the city states and let's take a look at it.
So now you can see that we have.
An array within an array, right, so you can see that this is an array and inside that array.
We have another array that has 1000 objects.
So we have nested this array within that array.
That's not something that we want to be able to push the objects from this array into this array.
There is a method called there is an operator called the spread operator.
And what the spread operator basically says is that we want to grab the this the data from the array
and we want to spread it just just provide three dots and we want to spread it inside this array.
That's basically what it says.
So now if I were to save this and check out a result, you can see that we get the same array right
here.
Right.
So that this array is now you can see that we don't have any array within an array.
We just have objects within that array and the objects are 1000.
So we have successfully retrieved our data and we have pushed it to this city state array.
And now what we can do is we can actually do meaningful stuff with it, which we are going to do in
the next lecture.
So in the next lecture, what I want to do is I want to create a function that is going to find the
matches and we're going to leverage our knowledge of regular expressions, because whenever you write
something here, it it this word should match the word which is inside this this string.
And you can see that this matches this.
So some sort of regular expression is involved in this process of matching this.
Yeah.
Here is the Albuquerque.
It was not a LBA.
It was LBG.
You Albuquerque.
All right.
See you guys in the next lecture.