Hi, everyone, in this that we are going to continue studying the properties and methods.
All right, so back to our property, number four, so this property in this property, we are going
to traverse the dome.
OK, now there are actually four properties, but I've just combined them into one because they basically
do the same thing.
Either we go one step up or one step down or to one side or to the next side.
So one step up is going to be the parent element.
One step down is going to be children.
Previous elements, sibling is going to be to the left.
And next, a sibling is going to be to the right.
So these are all traversing the dumb sort of properties.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to grab the concept that we have.
We are going to grab our paragraph.
And let's do a name for that variable, we're just going to call Okpara and say document.
That query selector for as of now, we know what is our favorite way of grabbing any Estima element.
All right.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to say cancel the log.
Now, what do I want to log to the console?
I want to log to the console, the parent element of this P paragraph, tag or paragraph element.
And I want to know the parent element of the Parro.
So I'm going to say parent element and I'm going to say and it is going to give me body, because if
you come to our e-mail, we see that we have in each one we have a para, we have an image and we have
a URL.
So Parreira, the parent of the parent element of the paragraph is going to be the body.
And when we hover over, it's going to show us everything.
And in here, this is basically is an esteemed representation of the console in the console off our
Web page.
So this is the parent I'm just going to go ahead and hit a comment here and I'm going to say one and
I'm going to call it parent.
Parent element.
All right, so this is the parent element, next stop, we are going to use the children elements,
so I'm going to call it, too, and this is going to be children.
All right, so in here I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to grab the body and we
are going to take a look at what are the children of the body.
All right.
So we are going to take a look at that.
So we are going to say const.
Consed body, not boy body, and we are going to say document that body, so to be able to grab the
body, we can just say document that body.
We don't have to do like any fancy query selector because there are some reserved selectors in JavaScript,
like native JavaScript selectors for the optimal alignment and for the body element.
These are reserved, right?
So we can take a we can use them.
So we are going to say consider log.
And in here what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the body.
This is actually the element name that we are grabbing.
So I'm just going to give it body by the one and I'm going to say, what are the children?
And when I say it, we are going to grab an e-mail.
We are going to see an e-mail collection.
And each of the children, they are indexed from zero all the way to five.
Right.
OK, so the length is six and it is an extreme element in our collection, so if we want to grab any
of these elements, we can just do our array methods, OK?
And we can use we can use the index to be able to grab that specific element that we want.
So what I'm going to do is in here, I'm going to say give me the element which is associated with the
index of zero.
And when I do that, it's going to give me this title and then.
You know what, I'm just going to zoom out the console, I'm sure it's still readable.
And we can go ahead and say, give me the element that is associated with the index of four and we are
going to grab we are going to get the script maybe like go ahead to three.
We're going to grab it.
You will.
So you, Earl, is going to have a lot of allies, three allies inside of it.
Right.
So this is how we can grab children.
Next up, we are going to talk about the elements, siblings, previous elements, sibling and next
element sibling.
So I'm just going to go ahead and say three previous elements, sibling.
Now, siblings are the kind of elements which are on the same level.
So these allies, all of them are siblings of each other.
Right.
So this is a sibling of this, sibling of this.
And we have a previous element, sibling and the next on sibling.
So consider this funny.
The previous element sibling is this ally, which is loyal.
And the next element sibling is this good company, ally.
We can't select elements based on elements based on their siblings as well.
So what I'm going to do is I want to create a concern.
I'm going to name it item, and we are going to go ahead and we are going to grab the document that
query selector, and we are going to grab it because this inside these quotations or quotes is the realm
of Cyesis selector.
We can do any validity as a selector.
So I want to go into a manual and from there I want to grab any Daehlie, which is the ninth child number
two.
So I want to grab the middle one, the funny one, because this is going to illustrate better for us
the previous element sibling and the next on its sibling.
So both of them are going to come here.
Let's add another like this.
All right.
So now we have successfully selected our second item.
So let's go ahead.
Let's go to the console and I'm going to say item that previous.
Previous elements.
And it is going to give me loyal because if I solve the log.
The item itself, we should get funny.
So this is funny.
So this is the middle one.
The first one is going to be the previous and the last one is going to be the next.
So this this is how we can grab elements by either by traversing the dumb.
Right.
So this was our property.
Number four, we are going to take a look at one more property and then we are going to wrap this lecture
up.
So for property number five.
I'm just going to sit here and I'm going to change it to five and in here.
Well, basically, this is the style of property and the style of property inside JavaScript allows
us to use this style inside the JavaScript file.
All right.
Now, changing Cyesis properties with Geass.
These styles will be converted to inline Cyesis, which have the highest specificity encases.
Everything is empty because there are no inline styles applied right now before even diving into that.
There are no standards applied here, but we can apply some styles there.
So if you go ahead and if we grab the image, all right.
And we say document that query selector and let's grab it by the element selector, which is image,
and I'm going to do one for the paragraph as well.
So let's put it there.
And this one is going to be P and let's call this Para.
So now if I go ahead and if I say cancel the lock, I am image and now in here, this is this is the
element that we are grabbing.
And I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to grab the power as well.
And I'm not going to comment comment them out because I want to take a look at them when we apply styles
on them.
All right.
So all sorts of styles are camel cased in JavaScript.
This is something that I want to get it out in the open.
So if there are any styles which are which have two words in them, they cannot be applied until you
use camel casing.
All right.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's grab our image.
And for that, I'm just going to increase the size of the window a bit more, the chrome window.
So I'm going to grab the image and I'm going to say, dot, whenever we do dot, we reference or we.
Access either properties or methods, but style is a property, so I'm just going to stay up.
And now whenever you write style and head dot, these are all the Cyesis styles that you can ever use.
And now you can see everything is Kemakeza.
So if I come here to the top, we have an image delay and cyesis we have animation, dash dilli animation,
dash direction, animation, dash duration.
But in here they should be cummock.
So when, when you do style dot you are accessing all Sears's properties.
And this is how cool Dom as it allows you to access all the elements.
And all they see is his properties, so in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say with
and I'm going to set it to five now, let's set it to 700 pixels.
And when I say it, boom, you just saw this image get bigger.
This image is bigger, right?
We can do a lot more properties.
We can do whatever we want.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to say back ground color this
one, and we are going to set it to thisll.
But I want this to be applied on the para.
Let's save it.
And now it has a background color of thisll.
All right.
We can go ahead and apply some.
Parting on the paragraph as well.
I'm just going to say parting, but this is not the optimum way of doing it, but you can do it.
And I'm going to add like 20 pixels of padding all around so you can see how this is this is changing.
And and whenever you change that, inline styles are applied in here.
So this is style, background, color, thisll padding to any pixel.
And these styles, they have the highest specificity.
So you should be careful when using these these dots style in line style of the JavaScript for success.
All right.
So now you guys can see that these properties, this with is 700 pixels.
It doesn't matter how many times you you set it to here.
If you set it to like tenth, 1000 or 10000, it's always this inline style is always going to be applied
because it has the highest specificity.
We can provide, I don't know, like some color, it's a color should be let's set it to white and the
color is white, we can apply some.
Well, it is it shouldn't it shouldn't be white.
And let's let's go ahead and let's set it to blue.
Let's color this is also let's change this and that one will be applied.
We are going to say line.
Height, let's set it to one point eight, one point eight.
Let's say that the color is blue, very, very terrible design it.
This illustrates that I'm not good at design.
So we end Fadela for the final style that we we are going to add is font size.
So these double words or multi word Cyesis styles, they should be cavalcades if you want them to work
and it should be 20 pixels.
And when I say that they just get bigger.
So we can do this as well, but this is not the optimum way of doing it.
All right.
Now, what is the optimum way of doing styles with JavaScript is the topic of our next lecture.
See you guys in the next one.