However, one in this letter, we are going to create our ad to do function.
All right, so before diving into that function, let's go ahead and let's create some variables and
we are going to store inside these variables the e-mail elements that we want to work with.
Right.
So the first thing that I know that I'm going to grab is going to in our clear button.
I'm going to call it clear BTN.
And we are going to say document that query, selected and selected using our query selector method.
All right.
And it has a class of clear.
Right.
The next thing that I want to grab is the to do list.
So this is the you will because we are going to grab this you, Al, and we are going to give it to
children.
Right.
So consed I'm going to call it to do list.
All right.
And we are going to select it again using our query selector and it has an IDF list.
The next thing that we need is our to do input.
So what is the to do input.
This is the to do input the to do input as the input where we write our to dos and whenever we hit enter
or we click on the plus side, we are going to see that, that to do is added here.
Right.
So we need to grab this input.
We also need to grab this plus sign as well.
And as far as the enter key is concerned, we can just use the code for that, which is number 13 and
we can select it and add an event.
Listen to that.
So we are going to do input.
OK, document that query selector we usually use query selector, you can mix and match, you can mix
them up, you can use document that get Alman by ID, but I really like query selector.
It's really broad, it's really fast and it's good.
It's a good practice as well.
So consed we are going to do.
And B10, right, and this is the plus sign that we are going to grab now, this one we are going to
grab by its class and the class is a very, very unique class.
It is a dash plus dash circle spotted here.
Let's have it now.
We have successfully selected what we wanted to say.
So what I'm going to do is not go that way.
I want to add a I just want to separate different sections of this website, this application, because
I think there is a lot that goes underneath.
There is a lot more.
The inner workings is very, very delicate under the hood of this application.
And I do not want you guys to get confused.
I want you guys to really understand what we are doing.
Right.
So right after this, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to write here a comment saying, selecting
the icon class class names.
Now we are going to select these icon class names, but I'm not going to tell you why right at this
point.
Now, maybe like within this lecture or in the next lecture.
Definitely.
I'm going to try to tell you by the end of this lecture so we have a check.
But button.
OK, so what is the check button?
Where is our check?
OK, it's not inside here because we are going to add a dynamically, of course.
So I'm just going to grab the you know what?
I'm going to grab all three of them.
I think we have styled them here, so they should be here.
So this is our line through.
We are going to grab that.
This is DFA dot f a dash check that dash circle.
We are going to add that class dynamically to an icon.
Right.
And the next one that I want to grab is uncheck BTN, which we are going to which which which is going
to allow us to revert back to that thin circle that we had.
So if I come here, where is that circle?
How can we find it?
So do we have it here?
I think it is it is also dynamically added, so I'm just going to ride the class name here.
So it is a dash circle dash fan.
OK, and finally, we are going to grab our text line through.
Right.
And what is the class for that.
The class for that is present inside the C assess the classes which are inside the courses there only
for styling purposes.
The reason that this thin circle is not inside the success is because whenever we are dealing with this
circle, we do not want to style it.
It is added as it is.
That's why we are not going to add a specific style.
But whenever we're dealing with this green one, with this check one, then we will be dealing with
some sort of styling.
That's why this class is added inside the success.
So these are selecting the icon class names.
You are going to feed them to this application dynamically.
And now let's go ahead and let's create our add to do function.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say I'm creating I'm just going to call it add to do
a function.
All right, so this is our ad to do function, they're going to say function.
Why do I always misspell that ad to do right now in here, I'm going to pass in four parameters and
I'm going to explain why four parameters, the first one is going to be able to do, which is very simple
to understand.
Right.
The second one is going to be the IED.
The IED is a number according to which our items or a to do list to do list items, they're going to
get arranged.
So if I were to come here and to write another to do even though both of them have the same text, if
I come into application and come in here inside the storage, what we are going to see is that the to
do the first to do has an idea of zero, OK?
And the second one has an idea of one.
That's how they are arranged inside this this to do list application and where we see that we have a
done which is false and we have a track which is false, meaning that we are going to add two more parameters
here.
So we are going to say Don and Trish, because each to do is basically working with four different things.
The first one is the to do text.
The second one is the to do number in order write.
The third one is going to be the status of that to do OK.
The status is either done or like or not done, which is trash.
Right.
So in here what I'm going to do is I'm going to create another constant because inside this constant
I want to store a To-Do done so to do done.
OK, so whenever that to do is done, what does it mean?
It means that we are going to grab this parameter, OK, and we are going to put it here.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to use a ternary operator.
So if you know what, at first I'm just going to go ahead and delete this.
I'm just going to explain it like this.
And then we are going to store the results inside that variable.
So if done is true, what do we want to do?
If done is true, we want the check button.
If it is not true, we want to grab the uncheck button.
Very simple.
So if done is true, it means that if I click on now, you can see that this done is false.
So if I click on it now, this is done is true.
It means that the to do is done.
If done is true.
If you just put it simply here it is going to be a boolean expression.
We have talked about this.
If done is true, we are going to implement check button.
If it is not, we are going to show the uncheck button and what is the uncheck button it is in.
If it has a class of Faida Circle dash, then that's why we selected these.
We have written the text of the class names individually right here.
So now the result of this is either going to be this or it's going to be this, right?
So it is going to be one of the above.
I'm just going to grab and delete that.
So whatever the result is, I want to store it inside this variable.
All right.
We are going to create another variable here.
And then we are we will wrap up this lecture.
Right.
So now so this is the first thing that we want to do.
The second thing, whenever the done is true, as F done is true.
We want the text line through to apply as well.
So whenever the to do is done, there are two things that we do.
The first thing is we show this icon, this Tegmark icon, and the second thing is we can see this line
through here.
So we want to show both of them.
So if done is true, why do we want to do is we are going to show the text line through, otherwise
we are just going to show an empty string or an empty string.
Right.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to save the result of this to a variable called to do a line
that's set.
And now we are going to use these this data dynamically to create a list item, which we are going to
implement in our next lecture.
See you guys then.