Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, working to create the length assessment function.
All right, so we know that all of our assessment functions are going to be housed within this calculate
pass for strength function, so let's create that first and the calculator Strache password strength
function is going to grab the password as a parameter because here we have an argument.
This argument requires a parameter.
So in here, first things first, I'm going to.
I'm going to declare that assessments are right, that we have that we have all right, and then we
are going to push to that array.
We are going to push to that area.
Certain criteria, certain assessments.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say assessment.
Right.
And I'm going to initialize it as an empty array.
And then we are going to push the length lower case, our upper case number and repeat character assessments.
Very simple, right.
So let's grab the assessment and we are going to say dot pusch and what what are we going to push to
get?
First things first, we are going to push the a length assessment function and it is going to have a
and an argument of password.
So now let's come down here and you know, before going down, I just want to say a return assessment.
Return assessments.
So if I come down here, let's go ahead and let's create that length function so length assessment function
are going to pass and the password as a parameter.
All right.
So now what do we want to do inside this length function?
All right, length assessment.
We want to assess if the password has there are going to be two, three criteria, actually, if it
has five or less than that characters, if the characters are 10 or less or the characters are more
than 10.
All right.
So in these cases, we are we want to print different messages here.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's grab the length of our password and let's save it inside the
password at length.
I'm going to go ahead.
I'm going to cancel log this length.
So we are on the same page.
So if I put it Q W you can see that we get two now because there is nothing here.
You can see that it is 100 if I do.
One, two, three.
Now you can see there are five.
So the length is going to be five.
So where is this value coming from.
It is coming from the because we have arguments which, for which the values, the arguments, values
they come from.
Sorry, we have parameters, the values for the parameters they come from the arguments, password input.
That value is this value.
And when we say password input that value and then we say that length is going to give us the length.
So this password is actually if I were to say password input, dot value, then it should work in the
same way.
So if I type anything, you can see we have we have something here.
So there are eight.
So if I write let's clear this.
If I write one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So the final one is going to be nine.
So we have the length is going to be nine.
Let's go back.
So now that you understand where this is coming from.
Let's implement our control flow and we are going to say if length is equal to or was less than or equal
to five, what do we want to do?
We want to return an object.
What is the object going to do?
The object is going to have a PWI check.
We have already created that.
Where is the PWI check?
OK, pass password, yeah, right here.
So now we can see that this assessment, it can have this assessment isn't is an array and the array
has multiple objects inside of it.
So when you say DOT passwords, check, it is going to grab the this from inside, this from inside
this assessment array.
So what do we want to do with the passwords.
Check should say password is too short.
All right.
So this is going to say a password is too short.
We need a strength lost as well because we had for the assessment we had two properties.
One is strength lost and the other one is password check.
So I'm going to grab the strength lost and I'm going to define it right here.
And what is the strength that we are going to reduce it by?
It is going to be 40.
So if the password has characters less than five, we are going to reduce it by 40 percent.
So if I type one, you can see that the password strength is exactly 60 percent.
But when we go above that, we are going to go to 100 because we don't have any other criteria so far.
So this is the first if statement that we have here.
The second one is going to say, if the length is less than or equal to 10, this is still not a good
idea to have equal to 10 characters or less than that.
A password should have more than 10 characters.
So for that, we are going to return another object, the past.
It is always going to be that this password check and strength lost because this is what we have provided
here.
So you can see here.
So what is what is the message going to say?
The message going to say password could be longer, could be longer.
And what is the strength that the user is going to lose?
The password is going to lose.
We are going to set it to 15 percent.
So if I were to say like one, two, three, four, because it's equal to or less than five, we get
the message that says password is too short.
Even if there are even if there are five, then it's still going to say password is too short.
And when we say this is the password, you can see that the length, just this strength, it increased
incremented, it was incremented by.
So it was 60 because 100 minus 40, we had 60.
And then now it is, um, why am I.
So now the password strength is less than 15 percent less.
15 percent than 100 percent.
Right.
So it is 75 percent.
It was increased by 15 by 25 percent.
So 40 minus 15, we get 25 percent.
But still you can see that we lose 15 percent because the strength lost is 15 percent.
And why do we lose it?
Because strength is 100, 100, minus 15.
This is what the sentence is going to do.
It is going to say 100 minus.
Minus 15.
What is this going to give us 85?
So 85 is going to be the value of the strength.
Very, very simple, right?
And we are add on keep this in mind.
When we say a positive sign, an equal sign or a negative sign and an equal sign, we add on to it.
So if there were only like a positive a negative sign here or an equal sign, then the next value would
have overwritten the current value.
We don't want to do that.
We want to add on to it.
That's why we say plus plus we have done this multiple times in our previous applications.
But the difference is we have done plus we have never done negative.
So if we go more than that, you can see that we get the password.
It goes to 100 because we don't have any more criteria.
So let's reload this page.
The password starts from zero.
So now we have created our length assessment function.
What we are going to do, as in the next lecture, we are going to create our lower case and hopefully
some other functions as well.
So see you guys then.