Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to fetch no facts.
All right, so this is the website, and this is how the kind of data that we can have, if you go deep
into this, you can have the type of trivia type, which is trivia math date year.
And it is the default value or the default type is going to be trivia.
And this is going to be the API to which we are we will be making our requests excuse me.
And if I put it here and put like, I don't know, like 30, I don't like let's say 99 aged 99, you're
going to get this.
So an unknown number of names of a lot of the names of attributes of God and Corran.
Yeah.
OK, so I could say like 10, we are going to set a number of dots in a to track to track to.
All right.
So that's basically the API, the API in point to which we are we will be making our calls.
And now if we come down here, let's see what else we have.
So we have this is going to be the call to that API and.
All right.
So we have the call to that and see if if we need to make another request to this.
All right, so that is going to give us this, but the thing is that this EPA is going to give us a
tax.
So instead of the Jason method, we are going to use the text method.
All right.
So, yeah, right here.
So you can see that it says dot text and it is going to give us the data.
So we are going to use the text method instead of the dot, Jason, because we are going to be getting
text.
So let's go ahead and let's create our UI.
What I'm going to do to save you time.
I'm just going to paste this.
This is the fact button fact input and fact paragraph.
When I click the fact when I put the fact input and click the fact button, the fact itself should come
inside this paragraph.
And now so the event is going to be on the fact button.
So it's going to be added.
Event listener.
Let's go and say click and when we click we want to run a function.
All right.
Now what when whenever we click that button, what do we want to do?
We want to grab the value of the input and provide it to that function for fetching the data.
So how can we find out the value of the input?
So I'm just going to call it number.
And it's simple.
We just say fact input value.
And this is going to give us the value for that.
We can go ahead and log it to the council to just check that our theory works to come here.
All right.
Let's open this up with my server.
And there we go.
So let's open up the console.
I'm just going to put it on the side.
Let's go to console father, always daughter.
So if I were to provide here like 65 and click this button, we are going to get 65.
It doesn't matter what what number you provide, 61.
You are going to get 61.
73, you are going to get 73.
Now, it's cool, right?
We are getting the number.
But the problem is that this number, it is not actually a number.
It's actually a string.
You can see that's why it's it's white.
So we need to convert it to a number and to be able to convert it to a number.
And I'm going to say pass and you could use percent or parts float.
Doesn't really matter.
So now it is converted to a number.
Let's store it somewhere and I'm going to say no data or no.
Hmm.
No, I'm just going to call it number of fact.
And now if I cancel log that we should get a blue one.
Right, so now if I say 15 and 13 click, you can see now we get a blue and it means that this is going
to be a number.
So if I say type of.
Type of number fact.
No fact we get on the fine should be in inside a foot inside here, so let's go Sloggett Typesof.
No, no fact.
You should get no.
And we need to enter, that's why it didn't work click we get a number.
All right, so we are done with this part.
We have successfully grabbed our input and we have converted it into a no.
The only thing remaining is just fetch the fact.
So I'm going to create that function in as an argument.
You are going to pass and the number.
So this is going to be our async function.
So I'm going to say function fetch fact, let's passan number.
Right.
So, all right.
So first off, I'm going to create a fact, you orl constant variable and I'm going to grab the euro,
which we know what that is.
We just work with it.
Right.
So this is going to be the euro, except the number.
The number is something that the user inserts.
So I'm just going to put it right here.
All right.
And then what we are going to do is you can see that this is HTP.
It's not a https.
So it is going to create some issues if you want to use this API in a real world application.
So what we can do is there is actually something called the course anywhere.
And I'm just going to give you the URL for that.
So this is going to be, of course, anywhere that Heroku of dot com.
And if we use this euro, it is this is going to be a proxy uttara and simply it is going to allow us
to use this http inside a HTTP website, https website.
So we are going to just copy that and let's come here and I'm going to create a constant and I'm going
to call it proxy Uttara.
Let's put it right here, so that's simple, it's just this simple, right?
If you want to read more about this, you can just go to the GitHub repo, just click on it.
So if you just select this and open it right here, this is the GitHub repo in case you're, like,
interested in reading more about it.
It's all here.
This is a report that.
Right.
But I'm not going to go there.
The you are all of this is stored right here.
And through this, you are all you can grab that GitHub.
Now, let's actually fetch the data.
So we are going to say CONSED response and we are going to wait until the response is completed.
Right.
And we are going to say fetch.
So the fetch is going to grab our proxy.
You are a first.
So proxy you are.
And you know what, I'm just going to use we could use this method.
I'm going to use my tactics.
So first off, we are going to pass in our proxy URL.
And then.
I'm going to pass and the fact you are the earl of itself, the fact numbers, and then so the user
has to enter a fact, right?
A number.
And that number we saw that it has to be at the end of this.
You are right.
That's why we have the proxy URL is first and then we have the fact you are and at the end of the fact
you are, we are going to pass on that input that the user is going to do.
And what is the input?
The input is going to be simply no.
So the value for this is going to be passed here and then passed here.
Right.
And now, because we are we are getting taxed.
We need to specify through.
We need to specify our method.
And let's say method is going to be get let's specify our headers as well.
So the in the headers, what we are going to do is we are going to say X.
Dasch requested X, Dasch requested Dasch with.
Now this request comes from this proxy.
You are all that we have.
We need to specify what is the kind of request that we are making.
So I'm just going to say plain text and we should be good to go.
So we are going to say Kansa log response.
You should get a response of pending.
All right.
So if I enter a number of like say, 88 and if I click on it.
We get this response.
All right, so this is the response is not pending because we have a wait here and now let's convert
it into something that's readable by us, of course.
So I'm going to create another concept and I'm going to say response data.
We are going to wait until that response to data is parsed.
So response dot, this time we're going to use the text method and now let's put in their response data
inside the console.
So if I add 64 Kaleck, we should get a response.
You can see is the number of demons in the dictionary inferno.
All right.
Very dark.
Golden desks in the myth of the Tower Hanoi, right?
Weird stuff.
So we have successfully grabbed our response and now the only thing is we need our FACTA paragraph,
which we have already grabbed it right here.
And we say that in our text, this time to ends response date.
So this time, like in contrast to the joke that we did, response dated a joke.
We don't have anything like that.
We basically get a text.
That's why we do the text method.
If you do the Jason, then it is going to give you a syntax error with the token of Jason.
Right.
And this response, these variable names, they don't have to be this these variable names, they are
arbitrary, optional.
You can name it whatever you want.
You can say Rick Morrey and I don't know, like Simpson, whatever.
Right.
You can name it, whatever you want.
So if I say 34 click, we should get a number.
We should get a response here.
So and if I say 51, Area 51, do we get that they are done with number of antimony.
All right.
So with this, our lecturer comes to an end.
So whenever you enter a number and click a fact, you are going to get a fact which this is besides
the point.
The point was we were able to fetch data using the async a weight function.
Now, these two projects, they were very simple, becoming projects.
They are they have a more real life kind of tone to them.
Of course, you can use this as a fun thing inside your applications.
But those projects, they are going to have like a little bit more with the Saddam manipulation, because
there are two sides to asynchronous programming.
One, you need to be able to fetch the data and that should be your priority facing the data.
When that fetch is successful, then what do you want to do with that data that you have just retrieved
from a specific API endpoint?
So the the one side is fetching, the other side is converting that data into a meaningful form to be
used inside your application.
That's it for this chapter.
See you guys in the next.