Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we are going to cover while Louise.
All right, so we have talked a lot about for a loop so far, but there is actually another way of implementing
loops in JavaScript as well, and they are called while loops.
Now, while loop syntax is different than the if statement that it started and then the full loop syntax.
Right.
But the functionality is the same.
They basically implement the same thing.
All right.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a multiline comment here.
And this is just for your reference.
And whenever you want to create a wire loop, first stuff, you have to declare a variable.
Now, the loop variable is declared outside the loop itself.
All right.
And then you write the wire loops keyword.
And in here you're going to have a condition.
All right.
And when the condition is true, you're going to run it.
For example, run run the code or whatever.
Right.
So when the condition is true, you run the code, right.
So think of this more like an F statement.
All right.
So you have the you have the variable declared outside.
And as long as the condition is true, you run the code.
And where is the instrumentation?
Decru and mentation comes after you run the code.
Right.
So at this point, you just go ahead and increment the variable like a variable, for example.
Plus.
Right.
So it comes after that.
You separate it like that and you put it here.
All right.
So I'm just going to provide it with some space.
I hope it sticks.
Yes, it does.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's create ourselves a while, so I'm going to give you two examples,
right?
So this is our example, number one.
So now, first off, we have to declare a variable.
So we are going to say, well, it can't be equal to one now.
That's right.
The key word for the while loop.
And let's create the syntax first.
So this is a while now inside the parentheses, we have a condition.
So what is the condition?
What do we want this loop to do?
Or or actually what we wanted to do?
It comes inside the curly braces.
How many times do we want this loop to run?
Actually comes inside the parentheses.
So we want this loop to run, for example, for ten times.
So we said as long as the K is less than or equal to 10.
So so when that condition, which is as long as care is less than or equal to 10 is met, what do we
want to do?
We simply want a council log, a work variable.
And after we do that, because the key variables value at first, initially, it is going to be one,
it is one.
And then the concept of log is going to say one, that's it.
And then we have to increment it either by one or by any other unconventional method that we have studied
so far.
All right.
So now when when we incremented and when we save the code, we are going to see this.
So the loop starts from one, goes to two, all the way to ten.
So how does actually this work?
So the variable value is going to be one at first.
All right, so when it is one, it is checked against this condition.
So one is less than 10.
All right.
So this condition holds true when the condition holds true.
This code is going to run.
Right.
So this code, when this code runs, we are going to get one because initially the value is one and
then that one is going to be incremented by one.
So one plus one, we are going to get two.
So two is going to be evaluated against this condition again.
And then we are going to get like this condition is going to be true because two is less than 10.
And again, this code is going to run inside this curly braces and then we incremented again by one
and then two plus one is going to be three.
OK, so, so, so forth and so on until we get number 10.
So this is how a while loop is created and how it works.
So let's go ahead and let's take a look at while loops.
Let's take a look at an array and let's see how we can iterate over that array or through that array
using a while.
All right.
So in the second example, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create an array and I'm going to say
Kohn's colors and I'm going to provide it with the RGV.
All right, Red.
This is going to be green and RGV, this is going to be all right, so let's go ahead and let's declare
the variable for a loop.
But and that loop variable is going to loop through this array.
Right.
So this is not the loop variable.
This colors is actually the array itself.
Right.
So we are going to declare a loop variable this time.
I'm just going to call it I.
All right.
And we are going to say, while a condition holds true, run the following code.
So what is the condition?
We want the AI to go all the way to less than not equal, less than colors that length.
So the concept is the same.
The concept of condition, part of the wire loop and the for loop is the same.
And we know that so far.
Right.
And when that holds true, when that holds true, we want to log to the console, the eye variable itself.
And when it is logged, we want to incremented by one as well.
So we are going to get the index of zero, the index of one and the index of two.
Lets copy it down below and commented out.
Let's take a look at the numbers and sorry, it is the colors, array colors and let's put in our Ivanovo
so.
In the first iteration, the four is the first index, which is zero.
We are going to get red and then green and then blue, OK, we can also go through one another example
as well where we just get the color names, OK?
So without any index or anything.
So this is how one loops work in JavaScript.
And and I think that set for this lecture.
So see you guys in the next one.