Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to fetch recipe's.
All right, so first off, let's see what it is that we want to grab.
We want to grab this entire form which which wraps around this input, then we are going to grab the
input, the form, because we are going to add a fourth event, which is submit and then the input because
we need the value from the input and then we are going to grab a wrapper.
So.
And then we are also going to grab our search results, all right, so that's what we are going to do.
So first off, let's go let's go ahead and say CONSED.
Uh huh, I'm going to I'm going to say search input, so this is going to be our search input and I'm
going to say document dot, query selector.
Right.
So we have document that query selector.
What is the class for that?
What is the class, its search input, very generic.
So let's put it there.
And the next one is going to be search result.
So I'm just going to swap this with result and I think we changed it to results.
So I'm just going to call it results.
And the next thing that I want to grab is going to be const form document, query selector.
And I'm just going to say for right, so now let's go ahead and let's grab our form and we're going
to add a listener on Samat.
And when we submitted let's grab the event object and when we grab the object, first thing's first,
let's prevent the default behavior, which is to reload the page, submit and reload the page.
The next step is going to be what I want to do is I want to grab the value from that search and put
so search in.
I'm going to say search query and OK, so we have search query.
Let's grab our research inputs of search input, data value, and then what I want to do is not not
not not value, just start value.
What I want to do is, oh, come on, math.
What I want to do is I want to call the fetch recipes for recipes function.
And I want to put in our search query, not searching, but search query.
Right.
So now that that is out of the way, let's create our function.
So we are going to say function and it is fetch recipes, so fetch recipes.
And we have our search query right here and now.
So we are going to say const.
Like always response a weight fetch.
So how is this going to work?
We know how this is going to work.
We we have already seen that if I come up here.
So first off, we need to pass and this htp, this request and then the query and then app ID and then.
So there are four things that we need to pass.
The first thing is this, and then we have our search query I.D. And so instead of using that, let's
put it back ticks here and I'm going to say so first off, we are going to say a recipe.
You are.
And right after recipe, you are out.
We are going to put our search query right after that.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to grab our.
Right after that, let's see what else is in the between.
So we have an ampersand we have in here after a search query, we have an M percent.
So this is a search query.
So I'm just going to provide an ampersand here and then dollar sign and our curly braces.
And we do have one and percent right after app I.D. So let's copy this.
Let's provide it right here.
And so the first one, what is this?
The first one is going to be your app I.D. and then we have application key.
So I'm going to say app I.D. I.D. and then we have our app key.
Perfect.
So this response is now completed.
We can safely say CONSED response.
Data and we can sit await response, response.
Jason.
All right, so response that, Jason, and we should safely be able to log in to the console.
Hopefully there is no problem there.
And let's come here, let's open up the console.
Let's go there.
Let's say Sarlat enter and we get all these kind of errors.
All right, so have we done everything correctly, so this is our search query, right?
So we have our QE there and then we have provided recipe you, Earl, and after the recipe URL, we
have our search query and.
Let's let's pass in our response.
Let's take a look at the response, what is the problem with the response?
And fetch recipe search query comes from searching for that value and everything should be working correctly.
So let's say Sarlat.
Access to fetch from Origin has been blocked by Schaus policy.
And if anything, a response was set felt to fetch 21, so from line 21, we were found to fetch.
Let's see.
So we have a recipe.
You are right here, which is this and right after that.
And what if I just go ahead and insert these in here?
So if I inserted there so this is going to be our search query.
And right after the search query, where is our search query question?
Sine we have an ampersand, so we have our ampersand and then we have app I.D., which is right here.
Your app I.D., so, oh, we should write the app ID word itself.
Oh, that that's the problem there.
So when I do this, you should write it and then you should write the app key word itself as well.
So we just passed and the values, that's why the we got that error.
So I think we should be able to grab our you are all now so recipe you URL and let's save it.
So are we good.
Are we good.
I don't know.
Let's check it out.
Yep, we are good.
So this is a response, response was a status of 200, so it's OK.
So now let's grab our response data.
Let's save it and let's say Sagada.
We get solid, we get hits 10 because we didn't define to what so far for us to be able to define to
what, and you need to just keep in mind that just add another 10 percent and say two equal to 30.
Just add it and we should get 30 hits.
And this is 30 heads right there, so we do get our 30 heads inside each of the heads.
We have a recipe.
You are we inside the recipe?
We have the calories which we are going to get.
We have the diet level.
It doesn't have any depth level.
It does have some health labels.
And this is the ingredients.
Now, this is why I'm telling you, this is massive.
You can log in here the ingredients as well.
For example, I'm not going to do it because whenever you want to read about it, you just save your
recipe and then you can take a look at the ingredients.
This is the label which we are going to grab, and this is the URL which you are going to grab as well.
BBC Good Food.
All right, so now let's do something meaningful with this data, and you know what, I'm just going
to postpone that to the next lecture.
However, I'm going to create the function here.
Right.
And the function is going to be.
You know what, I'm just going to do hits, let's see what do we get?
So let's say it's it's funny.
OK, so here we get 30 hits, right?
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to pass this heads inside a function called display recipe display
recipes, and we are going to create that function, display recipes, and we are going to pass in recipe
results.
Recipe results.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture in the next election.
We're going to display our recipes to the UI.