Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about blocks coping.
All right, so in this lecture, we are specifically covering blocks, coping with vare blocks, coping
with letters and blocks, coping with CONSED.
So so this is the syntax for a block.
All right.
And in here, first off, in the global scope, we have a var variable, a declaration and it is initialized
with this name equals Clent.
We have another name and now the identifier is the same inside the block and outside the outside the
block, inside the global scope.
So inside the global scope and inside the block we have the same identifier.
But the expression assignment is different.
The value is different.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is first off, I'm going to comment down the block and we are going to run this
code.
And we know that we can we are going to get Clent.
All right.
So what if I go ahead and if I run the code inside the block?
Now, we know that VARs, they are not block scoped.
They are either function scoped or their scope is the global scope.
So they have only they attach only then they attach themselves only to two scope's the scope of the
function or the global scope.
So this block scope shouldn't have any effect on this var and we should see the value of this name changed
from Klann to guard.
And if I say that we can see that in here inside the block, which is line number six, we can see Guardian
and outside the block, inside the global scope, we can see Gardian as well.
So it means that if you provide blocks or if you don't, they have no effect on var.
So what I'm going to say here, I'm just going to write no effect.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come and copy this and coming this out and now we are going
to go ahead and paste it right here.
And now what I'm going to do here is we are going to change inside this block.
We are going to change the the VA to let and we will discuss that.
OK, so we know that War Avar doesn't work because it attaches itself to a function scope or to the
global scope.
All right.
But why do we have to like test it for letting consed?
I think it was the previous Luxuria.
It was the previous lecture that we talked about the immediately invoked function expression pattern,
the EFFI pattern and one of the great use cases of an F.
But what is six or is or accurately e 2015 gave us was block scoping created with let and var we can
follow the principle of Leia's exposure or at least privilege by using a block rather than an iffy so
we can use a block to do the same thing, to hide the information that we do not want any developer
to change by mistake.
Of course they are not doing it deliberately, but by mistake.
All right.
So let on const were created so we can make a declaration inside a block, OK, and they turn that block
into a scope block or into a scope and blocks are not scope's until until they have let or const inside
of them and that makes them a block.
Now you have to keep in mind that not all curly braces are scope's because we just saw that we had curly
braces here, but this wasn't its scope.
Right.
But if we have curly braces here, this is not a scope until we use either let or CONSED.
This is one of the major reasons that we use lead and const.
I mean, like most developers, they do prefer a like let or consed let consed over the VA because they
think OK, that VA doesn't have any use case, but in fact VA has its own use case.
I know it's like old syntax, but there are many things that are old syntax like the function declaration.
But we still use them right.
So va they have a different use case letter and const they have a different use case.
I mean they do create a scope of themselves, but they are more like error prone than VA because va
we know that it only attaches itself to a function and we know it attaches itself to a to the global
scope as well.
But what let whenever you use it, let inside any curly braces that curly braces becomes a a scope.
And whenever you want to think about it, that how that code runs, then you have to create another
scope inside during the compilation or the passing stages as well.
So it makes things a little bit more complicated, but at the same time, we can, like, follow the
principle of the least exposure.
So there are some upsides and there are some downsides to using let in concert.
We are going to discuss in cons along with VARE even more in our next lecture, sorry, next chapter.
When we get to hoisting, we will talk about that as well.
And what hosting is and is it even a real thing?
And so at this point in this lecture, we are just like we are just we just want to know how this light
creates a block and whether or not it does create.
So in here we have a variable, we have an identifier name which is declared with VAR and here the same
identifier, but declare with let.
The result that we saw with Vav us was that VA didn't care about this coronaviruses.
So it was as if these curly braces, they weren't present.
And we re for example, we, I know there is no such thing as real declaration, but we did declare
this a reassign the variable, this identifier to different value.
But in here.
So what we have is we have Veillette and we have we have we have log to the console name and we have
log to the console name outside this block club as well.
Now, we are going to go over this because it creates a scope from these inside these curly braces.
It means that this identifier of name is not accessible outside the scope.
It is not accessible.
So when it is not accessible, what is going to what this console log is going to do?
It is either going to throw an error like undefined like name is not defined or or if the name is defined,
it is just going to log the value to the like to the console.
So if I were to save this, we should see Guardian and then we should see Clent.
So let's save it.
And this is how how this is the difference.
Of course one of the differences between Lit and VAR.
And the differences in their scope, it doesn't mean that war is bad, let is good.
No, no, no.
The differences in their scope and you should know how these work when you know them, you will understand
where I should use which.
OK, so when it comes to functions, it doesn't really matter if you use Valette or Kohn's, but when
it comes to a block, a set of curly braces that you want to make a scope, then you should go with
Let or CONSED.
And you should keep in mind that these declarations, they should always be at the top of the scope.
All of your variable declarations should be at the top of your scope.
That's why during the past twenty six projects, all of our declarations for the most part there were
at the top of the scope.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is just going to copy this and I'm going to come in this one out and we are
going to come down and see and pasted here and I'm going to change this led to CONSED.
Now we know that Consed cannot be reassigned and all that.
But what, what if what, what is going to, what Consed is going to do here.
So Consed is going to do the same thing.
So I'm just going to trash this so that the variable which has been the identifier which has been declared
through const or initialized through const, will be only accessed within that specific scope.
So this concept the should give us Guardian and this council, the log she should give us either an
error like it is not defined or when it is defined here we should get like Guardian and then for this
one we should get Clent.
And when I say it, we get the exact same thing printed on the lock and in the console.
So VARs they attach themselves to the function scope or to the I'm just going to write has fact.
I think this conveys the point so far.
They attach themselves to function scope and to the global scope that they attach themselves to the
block scope in any scope that they are.
They create a scope for themselves.
And of course they do attach themselves to the global scope whenever they're used there.
So this is going to be it for this lecture and this chapter in the next chapter.
We are just going to go over what hosting is and how you should allow what it is, how it works and
is it even a real thing?
All right.
So see you guys in the next chapter.