Hi, everyone, welcome to your very first hands on JavaScript lecture.
All right, so in this lecture, we are going to go over how we can create a JavaScript file and how
we can connect it to a map now as this course requires an intermediate knowledge of HTML and Cyesis.
You guys know how you can link Cyesis file to an e-mail file?
Well, linking JavaScript is sort of the same.
All right.
So first things first.
We need a folder.
And this is this folder is called Chapter two Resource Files, because this is the second chapter.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to write click and I'm going to
say open with code.
All right.
And here is our chapter to resource files.
Let's go ahead and let's close the welcome page.
All right.
So in here, what I'm going to do is, first off, we are going to create an HTML file.
OK, so I'm going to just go ahead and I'm going to name it for Dasch.
Index dot e-mail.
All right, and OK, so this is our e-mail file, I'm going to create a simple boilerplate and I'm going
to name it to creating a JS file, creating a JS.
So for sure, I'm just going to call JavaScript.
Sometimes I'm going to call it genius, right.
JS file and linking.
Linking to mouth.
All right, so now we have created our e-mail file, so how can we create a JavaScript file while creating
a JavaScript file is almost the same as creating an e-mail file except for the extension.
So we are going to click on this icon that says new file.
And we are going to insert first the name of the file, which is for Dash, let's say out now the name
of any JavaScript file.
Well, it is highly arbitrary.
You can choose to name it anything that you want, but the common convention of naming a JavaScript
file is either a machine or is either main or app.
Usually developers, they call it app and the extension name is just JS.
And you guys can see that it says JS in yellow as well here.
So this is an empty JavaScript file.
So how can we link the JavaScript file to an e-mail?
Now, when we were when we wanted to link is Cyesis file, we went ahead and we went into the head section
of our estimate document and there we inserted a link tag.
Right.
But JavaScript is actually inserted at the end of this at the end of the body element, OK?
And it is a script element.
So script is for JavaScript.
All right.
So this is actually a JavaScript.
Whatever you write inside this, this is JavaScript.
And I'm just going to go ahead and create a comment here.
And this is called Internal JS.
All right.
So whatever you write in here is will be internal.
Yes.
We also have facetiousness, a style element and whatever we write inside here will be our internal
Cyesis styling.
We also have internal JavaScript logic as well.
Right.
So whatever we write here is going to be our internal.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to give you a demo.
But first off, I'm going to create an element and I'm going to I'm going to just go ahead and create
a button.
All right.
A create a button.
And I'm going to just name it button.
Right.
And now let's go ahead and let's open it with live server, here is our page.
I'm just going to bring it here.
All right.
So this is the name of the file Extremophile, and this is our button.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to make it smaller and I'm going to make this ed smaller as
well.
And I just want to put them side by side, all right, because I don't want them to take, like, a
lot of space so we can work and see our results at the same time.
So there we go.
So we have a button element and this is our button.
All right.
I'm just going to zoom in and 300 percent.
Now, how does internal JavaScript work now?
We haven't officially started studying the language yet, but what I'm going to do is I'm just going
to go ahead and I'm going to make this very, very simple and low level website, make it dynamic.
So when we click this button, what I want to do is I want to change the background color of the body
whenever I click the button.
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to grab the button.
All right.
So I'm going to name the button B10 and JavaScript.
So let's go ahead and let's grab it the same way in in that whenever we want to style an e-mail element,
first we have to selected.
That idea works in JavaScript as well.
When whenever you want to apply functionality on any element, you have to selected first.
All right.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab our button and I'm going to say an event listener,
we are going to listen for a click, because when I click, I want I want the background colors to change.
And when the click happens, I want to run a function.
The function is going to grab the document.
So we want to change the background color of the body.
Right.
So for grabbing body in JavaScript, we just say document that body.
And now we want to tap into the CSX world.
Whenever you want to tap into the sea, this world inside JavaScript is just red dot style.
OK.
And from there, I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to say back ground color.
Right.
I think I have misspelled document document.
All right, so it is background color, and let's put it to, I don't know, like olive olive drab.
Let's save it.
So now if I go ahead and if I click on this button, the background color should change, which it doesn't
because there is another typo here as well.
Now, let's go ahead and click it.
And now you can see that the background color has changed to olive drab.
We can go ahead and we can inspect that as well.
So if I come here, it says, so let's grab the body.
And it says olive drab right here.
Right.
So this is internal JavaScript.
All right.
We also we can also link an external file.
OK, and that is interestingly the same script.
OK, we just write a script and we give this script a source.
Now, where is the JavaScript file?
As you guys can see that the JavaScript file and the EMR file there on the same level.
So if I go ahead and if I just write the name of the file, we should be able to grab it.
Here it is.
So now I'm not going to go ahead and I'm going to write another code of JavaScript.
I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to paste it here and I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to
save it.
Now, this code is commented out.
It doesn't work anymore.
But if I click on it, the code comes from here.
Right?
So this is how you can link a JavaScript file to an e-mail file.
Now, you might ask, OK, which which way is better now if the same thing, the same idea as with Cyesis,
if you have very few lines of styling or you have very few lines of code, then you should use an internal
script.
But if you have a lot of lines of code and a lot of like logic, it is best to create another JavaScript
file.
Right.
But in any case, you know, it's a best practice.
You just write your code to separate.
It is called a separation of concerns in programming, and it means that you separate all of your files,
OK, your case file is separated, your e-mail file separated, and your JavaScript file is separated
now at the end of this video.
I just want to introduce you to another very, very important idea in JavaScript, and that is the developer
console.
Now, you guys can see that this is actually our.
This is the developer tools in here, all right.
And the developer tools is used to inspect any Web page or to debug our code.
All right, so I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to increase the size of this window and we are
going to reset this to 100 percent.
Now, we are used to working in the elements tab where we have our HDMI markup on one side and we have
a series of styles on the other side.
We also have our computer styles well with all of the browser implemented styles.
But what about JavaScript?
Where does JavaScript come inside this browser tools and that JavaScript comes inside the console.
Now, the primary function of the console is not to create applications or right.
When whenever we create applications, we want our applications to work within that, within the donc,
within the e-mail document.
All right.
But console is used to test our code.
So we are going to work a ton inside the console.
But for now, I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to give it give you a demo of how console works.
All right.
Because as soon as these are the beginner chapters, we are going to work a lot, a lot with the console.
But as we move on and once we get to the advanced chapters, we are going to work with the console less
and less until maybe we had a bug or something.
Right.
So so in order to top the console, we just write console that lock.
Now, that console is actually this console right here, OK, on the right in the browser.
Right.
So this is the console.
Now we want to print something in the console.
We want the console to show them something.
So for that, we said log.
All right.
Now, log is a console method.
Now, keep in mind, there are some codes which are reserved for JavaScript, but there are some browser
logic as well.
Console log is a browser code.
It is not decent.
This code is not actually a JavaScript code.
The syntax.
Well, actually, it it resembles JavaScript.
But this line of code, it is not JavaScript code.
It is the browser code.
Right.
So inside the log, what do we want to say?
I just want to say hello, world, a very overused and generic line.
All right.
Hello world.
Let's save it.
And now whenever I click on this button, we should be able to see the world down in the console.
There we go.
It says Hello World, and it even gives you where the hello world comes from.
So if I were to click on this for Dash Abdah, just line five, we are going to go to our line and this
code resembles our code in our code editor.
So this is the good thing about console.
I know a number of sources and about these tabs inside our developer tools and that's why we use them
in here.
You guys can see we have our no errors, no warnings.
So we if we have any errors or warnings, we are going to get them here as well.
So this is a very good thing to be used, especially for beginners.
And we are going to use console a lot because we want to play around with JavaScript code and we want
to test it so we can understand it.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.