Hi, everyone, in this that you're working to create properties for our game elements, all right.
So I'm going to come in here on top.
And what I'm going to do is, first off, if you just open your this explorer, is it explorer?
Yeah, you can see that there is a folder called Sounds and we have ice core had our ice core and wall.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to call these sounds and then I'm going to create
sources for them and then we are going to call them whenever we get to those parts.
So first off, I'm going to say let our AI score equal to new audio.
So the new audio is going to be a a function or an object function that we will be instantiating just
a moment.
So we have our eye score.
The next one is going to be a score.
Then we have hit and then we have war.
Right.
So there we go.
So now we have created these.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to grab each one of them and I'm going to.
Outsource to them, so I'm going to say our ice core s our C should be equal to we should go inside
this sounds folder and from there grab the arrow score.
You know what?
I'm just going to go ahead just to speed this process up.
I'm just going to copy paste all of them here.
So we basically grab them.
That's it.
So now that now when that's out of the way, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say the are I player
panel.
All right.
So let's create that.
So I'm going to say const.
Player parol are I this is our paddle that we are create here, so the first property that I want to
add in here is going to be the exposition.
What is the exposition going to be?
The exposition initially is going to be zero.
What is the Y position?
Right.
So what do we want to do now?
Whenever we create this game and we start, you can see that both of them are in the middle.
I know that the A.I. is moving, but our paddle is directly in the middle.
So the middle is the middle X is still zero.
We do not move in the direction, but a Y is completely in the middle.
So the height if I divide the height by two, we are going to get this.
And if I divide the paddles, the paddle by two, then we get directly the the we get exactly the center
of the paddle aligned at the center of the height of the canvas.
So that's exactly what I'm going to do.
I'm going to say why p so we are going to grab our canvas element tight.
And we are going to divide it by two.
Right, and from that, we could go ahead and we could grab.
Our paddles with and just our paddles hard and just say 50, or we could just grab our paddles height,
which is 100 and divide it by two.
I know we have not created that.
We are just going to we are going to create it right now.
So the paddles height is going to be 100 pixels.
The paddles width is going to be 10 pixels.
You could increase the width.
I guess you could do that.
The color.
This is where you change the color.
So the.
Sorry for the.
For the r.i, the color is is going to be D to E, D to E six 03, so this is the color for that and
the score is initially going to be zero.
So this is going to be the three player panel for the I would basically have the same properties but
with different values.
So I'm going to change this air.
All right.
I'm just going to change it to Ehi.
So it's going to be so the exposition of that is no longer zero.
Why?
Because you can see that the r.i or our panel is right at the starting point of the width, but the
title for the A.I. is right at the farthest side of the width or at the canvases with.
But if I provide the canvases with and then provide like a width of 10 pixels, that width of 10 pixels
is going to move off the canvas and the pattern is going to come up right here.
So we need to decrease.
We subtract from the width of the canvas, the width of the pattern.
So the paddle appears on the canvas, not off the canvas.
So first off, I'm going to grab the canvas element with and from that I'm just going to subtract 10
because that is going to be over with.
So for the height, it's going to be the same thing.
We grab the height of the canvas and we divide it by two.
And from that we subtract half of the height of the paddle.
And that is going to give us the exact direct like the center point of the paddle is going to be at
the center point of the height of the canvas.
And the color for this is going to be orange.
In case you want to change of the colors for the eye, you can change it right here for the IRA.
You can change it right there.
So now that we have created that, there are two more things that I need to create in this lecture,
and that is creating the ball.
Let's create that.
And for that one, I'm going to do as I'm going to create a constant I'm simply going to call it ball
and the exposition.
Now, whenever we start the game, where is the ball going to appear?
So let's let's take a look at it.
You can see that the ball appears right here.
So we're right here.
Right here.
As if we were to divide the canvas as high divided by two is going to give us this point.
But it's not actually doing is going to give us this point.
It's going to give us this point.
And then if we grab the canvas with and divide it by two, it's going to exactly give us this.
So we would have four parts of the canvas on the center point is right here.
So the exposition is going to be canvas element dot with divided by two, so we get the center, the
Y position is going to be canvas element, canvas element, dot height divided by two.
So we got that the next thing that I want to add to the ball is going to be a radius because it's a
circle, the radius is going to be 10 and then the ball is going to have a speed.
The speed I'm going to set it to seven if you want to increase the speed of the ball.
This is where you could increase that.
Now the ball is going to have velocity as well, because the speed without direction is nothing, we
need to provide a speed, the direction, and that's why we give it velocity.
So X V is going to be five.
The velocity in the extraction Y, V is going to be five.
The velocity in the Y direction, the color of the ball is going to be wide.
This is where you can change the color of the ball.
And after that, the last thing that I want to create in this lecture is going to be our net.
So I'm going to say let's create the object.
What is the position of the net?
Because the net is exactly in the middle of the canvas canvas with so we need to divide the canvas with
by two.
But what do we want to do?
Because the net has two pixels of width, if I want the net to be exactly in the center, one pixel
of the width should be on the left side of the canvas with the other pixel of the net with it should
be on the right hand side of the canvas, as with.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to divide canvas by two.
That is going to give us the canvases metal point and I'm going to decrease from there one pixel.
That way our net, which is two pixels, half of it is on the left side of the canvas with the other
half is on the right side of the canvas with.
And then this net becomes directly in the center.
The Y position is going to be zero, the width is going to be two two pixels.
The height of each of the those segments is going to be ten.
And the color, in case you want to change it is going to be why this is where you change.
So I'm just going to come in this one end as well.
So creating the net, let's say that we should not see anything because so far we have not called our
functions yet.
So you can see that these functions now we need to call these functions like draw a circle and these
properties should be passed and within these functions call.
And that said, what that's what we are going to do in our next lecture.
So in the next lecture, what we are going to do is we are going to create our game loop.
See you guys that.