Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create the drag leave and drop if listeners.
All right, so we know that whenever we grab our item and when we say drug, enter.
It is going to change the background color of the container, but whenever we leave the background,
color still stays the same, which is not something that we want.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab our list and we are going to add another event, listeners,
and we are going to say drag no.
When the drug leaves, what do we want to do?
We want to run a function.
The function is going to run simply one simple thing.
All right.
And that simple thing is just a background color.
So we are going to grab our list.
You're going to see a list style dot background color, and we are going to set it to a color now.
The color is going to come from this Cyesis because the reason for that is so originally this is the
color.
What is this color?
This color, which is right here.
It is this color at this point, which has the point five at the end of it.
All right.
But whenever we drag our item, the item is entered.
It changes color to grayish kind of color.
And when it leaves, we want the container containers background color to revert back to its original
color.
So for that, I'm going to grab the color, which is the original color of that container, and I'm
going to put it right here.
Let's save it.
It's come here.
And now when I leave, it is going to change color.
Go leave.
See, now it changes colors.
All right, so this is done as well.
The last thing that we need to do here is that we need to create the drop event listener because all
of the drug VolitionRx there are completed and the final one accompanying them is going to be the drop
event listener.
And then the drop you are going to grab our list and we are going to append a child to it.
And what is the child?
The child is whichever item is the drug item.
Very cool.
Right.
And then and then what we are going to do is whenever we drop it there.
So you know what?
I'm not going to do anything else.
Let's go ahead and let's see what happens.
So if I drop it here, we can do that, right?
So we can drop it here.
We can drop it here.
We can drop it back here, drop it here, drop it here.
So wherever we are dropping, we are actually changing the background colour.
So if I were to grab this item number five and drop it in the final container, we change the background
color.
If I grab the item number two and and bring it over here to container number one and drop it, we are
changing background color.
OK, this is not something that we want.
We want whenever the drop event is happened, we want the background color to be to to return to the
same color that we had.
So if I were if I were to hover over on any of them, we will be seeing that some valid target spots
that we can drop our item to.
And whenever I drop it, when they drop event happens, we can see that the background to color it reverts
back to its original color.
Right.
And we can do that.
We can bring it down.
Bring this one down.
Bring this here.
Here you can do you can bring anything, anywhere that you want.
But in here where it says not allowed, you cannot do it because there is no event there.
All right, so with this this project comes to an end, I hope that you guys enjoyed this and I hope
that you guys learn a lot from this project, even though this was a relatively sure project.
But we covered very, very key concepts of dragging in JavaScript.
That's it for this project and this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.