Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create in a dynamic element.
All right, so so far we have come to our aid to do function, so the next thing that I want to do is
I want to grab our knowledge of this to do done and to do line so far.
And I want to create an item dynamically.
So when I just start to create it, you're going to understand exactly what I mean.
What am I doing here?
Const.
I hit him, all right, so I'm going to use my tactics here, and the reason that I'm using these tactics
is that we will be using our.
We are going to we are going to create a dynamic element, right, and we will be using template strings
inside aerobatics.
Right.
So what is going to be this dynamic element?
The dynamic element is going to be an ally inside which we are going to have three children.
The class for the ally is you guessed it right.
It is going to be item which should come right here.
And then let's close the Solomon.
So there I'm just going to hit tab.
The first element that I'm going to create is going to be an icon.
Now, this icon, whenever the to do is created, it is going to be a thin circle and one that to do
is collect done.
It is going to be a tegmark.
All right.
So we have to toggle the class dynamically.
That's why I'm not going to call the class.
So the class is going to be.
And it's add it so it is the FAA is shared, whether it is a thin circle, whether it is a circle fan
or whether it is a circle, whatever check.
Right.
So this FAA, this first class share, the second class is going to come from this constant that we
have created there.
Right.
So I'm going to use our template strengths and I'm going to pass it there.
So what does it mean?
It means if done is true, we are going to show we are going to display the check button.
The check button is stored inside this variable.
And we are going to use this variable right here inside our template strength, which allows us to access
the value for this to do done variable.
All right, and then why do we need to do as we're going to add another class of complete, which we
have already styled inside our success?
So this is the eye which has a class of complete.
These are the styles for that.
So whenever that to do is done, we are going to we are going to use the class of complete.
The status is also going to be complete, which we are going to use later.
Right now, we go to the I.D. So what is what do you think the I.D. should be now instead of riding
the I.D., like manually zero, one, two, three.
What we are going to do is we are going to create this I.D. dynamically.
Right.
So for that, what I'm going to do is.
I'm going to come beneath here, right, and in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say
to do container.
All right, so here we create our to do container.
And what does this container mean?
It means that all of our to do is they're going to come right here inside an array that we are going
to create here.
So let's go ahead and let's create that, let's say, to do container.
So this is to do container and we are going to initialize it within with a set of empty array, with
an empty array.
Right.
And we are going to grab our I.D. and we are going to initialize it to zero.
We are going to set it zero by default.
And now in here, instead of hard coding, the idea, we are just going to use it from here and then
down inside the same function, we are going to increment the ID by one.
Whenever we add an item, we are going to increment the ID by one.
So let's add the ID here.
This is our ID.
And after that, so I think the first one is done.
So this is our I can't accept that the closing tag is still missing.
So this is our first element that we create dynamically.
So this is the first one.
The second one is going to be a paragraph.
Now, the paragraph is going to have a class of text.
All right, so it is going to have a class of text, which we have already styled right here, the paragraph
has a class of text, but how do we know how to add that line through that?
We had to this paragraph in case that to do is done.
So now is the time to add our second constant to do line.
Now you can see how these different parts play different roles.
So what does this mean?
We know what this means, but what about this one?
So we know whenever that done is true, we want the check button to show as well as the text line through
to be applied on the paragraph.
So when done is through text line, through will be applied on the paragraph and the class is this line
through and this class has been styled right here.
So the style is going to be applied.
Let's close this first opening tag, and so what about the data first stuff?
I'm just going to close this element.
Now, what about the text, the content of this paragraph?
Where does it going to come from?
Where is it going to come from?
It is going to come from from this to do parameter that we have inserted there.
So we are going to add a dynamically right here as well.
So the second element is done.
Let's move on to the third one, which is, again, another icon, which you guessed right.
It is our trash icon that we had, for example, one, two, three.
This is our trash icon that we have there.
Right, and we are going to add a class to it now, the class of fair is common.
What about the class of trash?
So because we only have one class and we do not toggled that class to either check or uncheck, it is
just going to be a trash icon.
That's why I'm going to hardcoded here, because we do not want to toggle that dynamically because there
is no other class there.
We only have one class and we are going to add a delete class, which we have already styled.
And here this is our delete class, which we have styled their.
All right, again, we are going to add a status.
The status is going to be delayed.
The status is delete and whatever ID, so we are going to do the same thing for this idea that we did
for this one.
All right, so we are going to copy the ID and we are going to put it right here.
And let's close this element.
I think we are done here and now for our very final part.
Let's go back one step and let's close this line as well.
So now we have created an ally which has a class of item inside which we have three children.
And this ILLI is going to be a child of this list that we have.
Right.
So our dynamic element has been created.
Now, what I'm going to do as now, whenever we create that element, we have to specify it with a position
where do we want to insert that element?
So for that, I've just opened up another page.
It is elements that insert adjacent HTML.
This is the method that we are going to be going to use, right.
So we are going to grab our element and we are going to call insert adjacent HTML.
It says Method of Aliment Interface parses the specified text as HDMI or XML and inserts the resulting
notes into the DOM tree at a specified position.
Well, in simple terms, what it means is we are going to grab a parent and whatever we say, insert
adjacent HTML.
It is going to add an item to that parent, right.
So there are four positions that we can insert that element.
The first position is is called before begin, which is before the element itself.
So if I if I added to the list, we we know that we should add it to this list.
If I say before I begin, it is going to come right here.
It's going to go before that list after begin, just inside the element before its first child before.
And this is where we are going to insert it just inside the element after its last child.
And why is that?
Why after it's last year, so you guys can see that this is one, two, three.
If I add four or five, six, four or five, six is going to come after the last child.
So what is the last child?
The last child is one, two, three and four or five.
Six is going to come after that because whenever we create these lists, we go from top to bottom.
We do not go from bottom to top.
We don't want to go in this order that whenever I create four or five, six, it should go on top of
this.
One, two, three.
No, I want it to come beneath this.
So it is called before and before the last chance.
If I click on it, this is called before entry.
All right.
And after and after the element itself, which is not something that we want to use.
So feel free to go ahead and check this.
There is a lot more stuff here.
Everything you need to you need to know about that.
I think there are some examples here as well.
But we are going to use our before and I'm going to copy this and I'm going to provide it inside or
inside of a JavaScript as a resource for you guys.
Now, inserting the those and the rest of the code we are going to accomplish in our next lecture.
See you guys then.