Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to implement the background color changer.
All right, now, before going forward, we need to select what we what we want to implement.
So the first thing that we need to implement is going to be these are in our Arga color, then the be
sorry, then the G and then where is the B. This is the B and then the Alpha Channel.
So we need to select all four of them.
Right.
Now, let's go ahead and let's select them.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come on top of here.
Now, this is the style you should come here, right?
And we are going to select RGV a I'm going to say RGV a R the first one is R and we are going to do
document dot, query selector.
So what is the idea for this one?
The idea for this one is going to be rgv a dash r.
I think this is going to be the idea.
So yeah, this has an idea for Dash R and RGV a dash are I'm going to copy it three times.
You're going to change the second one to B and this is going to be sorry.
So this is always mix this argy bargy, this is going to be G as well are G B this is going to be B
and B as well and this is going to be a RAJEEB A a.
A great now we have successfully selected this one, I'm going to do as I'm going to select the RGV
container as well.
So this is the RGV container I'm going to selected by its class name.
Right.
And I'm going to call it RGV, a container.
Document dart query selector, let's add.
And the class name.
And I want to grab the RGA inputs, all of them at the same time as well, and the reason that we select
them, select these inputs twice is that we first off what we what we are going to do as we are going
to loop through all of them.
And whenever we want to change the value for any specific one of them, we are going to use these selectors
right here.
So in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to create another variable and I'm going to say
RGV inputs, inputs, all of them.
And we are going to grab our Rajiva container.
And from there, we are going to say, query, select all because there is clearly more than one and
we are going to grab all the inputs, right.
So let's implement that.
They are going to say RGV or I'm just going to say background color.
Changer, right?
So.
How does this actually work the way that we are going to implement this as we are going to loop through
all these elements and whenever the user changes one of them, we are going to apply that on the block
element that we have already selected in the JavaScript file.
All right.
So we are going to create a for loop and we are going to sell it AI equal to zero and the AI is going
to go all all the way to our RGV.
AI is not container inputs that length.
All right.
Because the index is going to be always one no less than the length the final index.
And each time we are going to increase them by one increment the loop variable by one.
Now we are going to grab our Rajiva inputs and we are going to pass an AI.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to consider log this council, log RGV inputs and we are going
to pass.
And I say that that's come here and it's going to inspect and let's see what we are going to get.
And now you guys can see that we are going to get all of them, so.
We are going to get all of them right, because this for a loop is actually looping over all of these
inputs at the same time.
But this is not what we want.
We want to apply a functionality to it.
So whenever each of these is clicked or changed because their range or has changed, we want to apply
a specific function.
So we are going to say RGV a input's that out of a listener.
Right.
And we are listening for a change event.
When the change event is fired, we are going to run a function.
OK, and what is the function going to do, the function is going to grab our blog comment and it is
going to style it and the property is going to be background, color, background, color.
Right.
And now here is the tricky part, what should be the background color, the background color is, of
course, and our value.
So inside any RGV value, what we have is we have a red and then we have a green, then we have a blue
and then we have an A for the alpha channel.
So let's go ahead and let's replace all of them.
So for the red one, I'm going to do as.
We are going to use our specific or our individual
variables that we have created on top.
All right.
So for the red, what I'm going to do is I'm going to pass.
And first off, let's go ahead and let's remove all of them, because we are going to we are going to
pass in quotes, OK?
So I'm going to remove the red and I'm going to say and I'm going to concatenate a space here as well.
So I'm going to grab the RGV a our value because this is the red and we are going to use the value from
there.
OK, and we are going to add another.
So let's go ahead and let's remove the remaining.
So this is the RGV, a dot value Arga are that value and we want another value here as well.
And that is the for the green and for the blue and another one is for the Alpha Channel.
So in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to add in a comma because this should look like a Cyesis
property.
All right.
And then we are going to select the next color, which is RGV a G dot value.
And let's add in another comma in here.
And then we are going to grab the RGV A, B, RGV A, where is the B dot value K, where is the plus
sign for this?
Here it is.
Here is the plus sign.
And then finally, we are going to add another comma.
And finally now it is finally.
This is really difficult to type.
All right, and we are going to grab the RGV a a dot value, right?
And I think this is going to be it.
Let's save it.
And the Vaska prettier does this in the end.
All right.
So it says Oncotype for now is not a function.
Rajiva Input's is not a function.
Of course it isn't.
We need the loof variable as well.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
We don't have any more errors.
So if I bring this here, the red is changing.
The block has disappeared, so.
So if I come here, it is blue.
So the blue is working, the green is working, but the red the red is also working out.
Right.
So if I decrease the alpha channel, it is going to go away.
So let's put it there and decrease it.
It doesn't work.
The Alpha Channel does not work.
So let's go into our JavaScript.
Oh, this is our baby.
So I'm sure you've got that.
Save it.
And let's click here.
Now, this is the Alpha Channel.
This is the blue.
This is the green.
This is the.
Ah.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to close this, increase the size, bring it to almost center,
bring it a little bit down and now we can work with it.
So this is how you can implement cyesis property change.
Very, very visual.
All right.
So if I come here into the inspect.
And let's grab our block, so can we grab it?
Yes, let's go into computer and now you can also grab this.
For example, you you are looking for color, I don't know, like ideas.
Right.
So the way you can use this background color is just just inspected and you're going to see that this
is the background color.
So if I put the red almost to end, almost do this for the red, the to one should be 255.
So now it is two hundred and fifty five.
Let's put the G it is going to be 255 and if I put it to blue then it is going to be completely white.
So this is a white color.
This is going to be it for this project.
See you guys in the next one.