Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to create the lower case and upper case character assessments.
All right, so we are done with this length assessment, but I'm going to do is we are not going to
work inside that anymore.
And now we we know what we are going to get from the.
From the length assessment function and we have pushed it to this array, the next thing that we want
to push to that array is going to be, let's say, that push.
We are going to say lower case assess.
Meant and we're going to say password, right?
So we are going to push the lowercase character assessment and also the uppercase, so I just copied
it down and I'm going to say Humper.
Case now let's go ahead and let's create these two functions, so I'm going to come down here and you
know what?
I'm going to common this length.
Assessment function.
All right, so let's copy this, let's put it right here, this is going to be lower case, a character
assessment.
OK, so let's create that function.
It is going to be lower case assessment and we are going to pass in the password.
So what do we have inside this lower case assessment now?
Inside this lower case assessment, we are going to have our regular expression that is going to check
for lower case characters and it is going to print all of their occurrences.
All right.
So what we are going to do here is first off, let's go ahead and let's create our regular expression.
So I'm going to say consed I'm going to I'm going to say matches.
So or.
Character match.
So let's call it character match.
It's a better name.
So what do we want this character match to have?
So we want to grab our password and match it to a regular expression that we create and we want to store
the result inside this variable.
Right.
So let's grab our password and we say darts match.
And what is the regular expression that we are going to pass in?
Very, very simple.
We want to grab.
All the occurrences of small, lower case numbers, all the occurrences of those.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say inside Brackett's.
Lowercase, A. all the way to lowercase Z.
And we want to grab all of their occurrences, so that's why I just provided e.g. there.
So I want to grab our password and match it against this regular.
Very, very simple.
Right.
So what are the conditions of this match?
All right.
There are going to be two conditions.
The first condition is going to be when the password has no length.
We are going to say password has no lowercase numbers when the length of the password is zero.
Of course, we know that the password has no no characters at all.
So how could it have lowercase characters?
So we just say the password has no lowercase characters.
And when the length is equal to two or greater than that, we are going to say password could use more
lowercase characters.
So let's create those two statements.
Very similar to what we did in the length are very, very similar to this one.
In fact, I could just copy it and I could put it here, but I'm not going to do it.
So we are going to say character match.
So this is our character match.
OK, we're going to say that the character match Dath length because this is going to return characters
dart length.
If it is equal to zero, we are going to return.
An object, what does that object, the object is going to have two properties inside of it.
One is going to be PWI to check or password check.
The other one is going to be strength lost.
We are going to say password has.
Now.
Lower case characters, passport has no lower case characters, and we are going to reduce the strength
by 20 percent.
I mean, you could change these strengths up and down.
Doesn't really matter as long as when you add all of them together, it should add on to 100.
So what and the next condition is if character match length.
So that length is equal to or is less than or equal to two, if it is equal to two or less than two.
We are still going to say that it is not something that we want and you should use more lower case characters.
So in this case, we are going to return this.
Copy this.
Let's put it here.
Password.
Must have more lower case characters and we are going to reduce the strength by, for example, five
percent and let's save it.
So this is the lower case assessment.
We have created this function.
We have pushed it to this assessment and it should print the message here.
So if I were to say one, two, three, OK, cannot get what is this error?
So it just cannot read property length of null at line fifty five.
So this is line fifty five character match that length.
Why doesn't like and let's log it to the console, let's see what character match is going to give us.
Right.
And oh we are going to say this is going to be a and or logical operator.
OK or logical operator.
We are going to say if it doesn't have any match return an empty array, because in this case we we
have only numbers.
That's why it's just type error.
Right.
This is an error on our part.
We are going to say if there are no matches, just return an empty array.
Right.
So let's go ahead and log it to the council, this character match as well.
So if I were to, like, make this a little bigger and put in one, two, three, you can see that reference
error, upper case assessment.
It's common, this one out.
We have not created that function.
So one, two, three.
You can see that it returns an empty array and it says password has no lower case numbers because it
doesn't have any lower case numbers.
OK, so it is going to return that.
And if it has any lower case numbers, for example.
Q W it still says password is short.
I think it is going to come.
It comes from the length, so don't worry about that.
And it says password must have more lower case characters.
Let's add this s in here as well.
So let's do a D.
It says more lower case characters and if I do one more lower case character like A.W., then that message
goes away because we only print the message if the if there is no lowercase character and we print the
message if there is to or less than that.
So now that we have created this lowercase character assessment function, what we can do is we can
basically the same thing happens for uppercase.
Only the regular expression is going to be different.
And this instead of this lowercase, we are going to say uppercase.
So that's why I just copied it, because it's basically the same thing.
I don't want to waste your time.
And the regular expression is going to be simple as well.
And it is going to be a uppercase A. and an upper KCC.
Very simple, so let's remove that, and if I do QE, it says password must have lower case.
OK, let's come in this one and we have commented this one out.
It doesn't push it to that assessment array.
So if I say QE, it says Password has no uppercase characters.
OK, no, let's add as here, this ad is here, let's save it.
So if I do want to know, you can see that password is too short, password has lowercase, has no lowercase,
no uppercase characters.
If I add Q w e, it says password has no uppercase characters.
If I do like C V, it has a good password.
Must have more uppercase characters.
I could say D CVT and it says it could be longer.
All right.
Because we need to provide it more than ten characters.
And if I provide for five six it is going to be 100 percent.
Right.
So basically, we have created this and now you can see that I'm not going to we are not going to do
anything else in this video except that I'm going to explain this part that at this point you can see
that we have a lot of duplicate code.
Right.
So when we get to our numbers function right here and special characters function, then we will have
four functions that basically do the same thing that basically have only.
So the difference is where the difference is, inside the function, inside the regular expression and
inside the time.
That's the difference.
So when all of the code is almost similar and only the difference is that much, what do we want to
do with that?
We want to create a function, a universal function that is going to be called each time this lowercase
assessment or uppercase assessment functions.
These functions, they're called.
And that function is going to house our criteria along with the parameters for regular expression,
because this is going to be different for this type, which is going to be different, and then it is
going to have a password, which by default, all the functions have as a parameter that we are going
to do in our next lecture.
See you guys then.