Welcome to Part three of Coding and I.
All right, so this is where we left off in a previous lecture, we changed our code inside or whenever
we wanted to populate the options.
Now, when this code is changed, the option code has all must also change.
Now, I don't mean like changing it to here.
Now it is this is the general code.
This is the specific code that we need to change.
We need to accommodate for that side.
We need to get the coordinates of that side.
So I'm going to pass on the side here and let's go ahead.
And that's before actually passing it here.
What I would like to do is let's actually define it, so we are going to say no.
Now, this is going to be each of those individual neighboring sites.
If option dot sites dot length is greater than zero, it means that we do have some neighboring sites.
We want our site to be that neighboring, to be one of those neighboring sites.
So option DOT sites, which side it is, that is going to be the job of EHI to find out.
We are just going to randomize it for the perfect.
So we are going to say math are random and let's multiplied by the length of the options options sites
that length.
Perfect.
Now we do have our site.
Now this site is going to be an argument in here as well because this get free site coordinates is actually
responsible for getting the coordinates to that to the sites.
Right.
Perfect.
So why don't we go ahead and let's why don't we go ahead and modify this now?
There is one more thing here, and that is you can see that inside our options push.
We do have a square property there, right?
So that square property is a property of the options array, array of objects.
But that is going to be a property of the each individual options as well.
So options are going to have squares.
Option is going to have square, plural, plural, singular, singular.
So we need to pass in the dart square here as well.
So I'm just going to pass it there and let's travel downwards.
So here we are seeing that get coordinates.
Of each site now here we did coordinates of a free site and we are going to say otherwise.
So we are going to do coordinates of each site, otherwise we are going to graph coordinates from a
free site.
Right.
But we need to be prepared for both of the scenarios.
So it's going to be coordinates.
And first off, this is going to be no, we don't have any coordinates.
Now, let's go ahead and let's check for that site.
And the side is right here, right, and let's see, so in our case, our first case.
The side is bottom.
What do we want to do?
We want our coordinates.
Which is here to be that coordinated bottom coordinates, bottom right, and then we want to break out
of this loop.
Perfect, so let's do this for all of the sites three more times and enter, enter and enter.
So what if it is left, then the coordinates is going to be Kurnitz.
Left, right.
What if it is right?
Then it is going to be the right side coordinates.
And finally, if it is top.
It is going to be the topsides coordinates.
OK?
And if after all of these if statements switch cases, still there were coordinates is no.
We just want to return it.
So.
If Kurnitz.
Is not is not null if it does not know if it is or if it is not null, we want to return it.
If it does, no, we don't want to return it.
So we are just going to say return cordin.
It's perfect.
Now, one final thing, I promise one final thing, and that is we just have to go ahead and create
that function that we called and that is good, valid neighbor sites.
So this function.
Let me grab the name, very, very long name.
And I'm going to come on top of the function and let's put it here, commented out and say function.
We are going to say function, put it right there.
Now we need to pass in row and column is parameters.
What do we want this function to do?
This function is actually B is going to be responsible for handling the side Y because the side is actually
equal to this function.
The function call is stored within the sides.
So this function is actually going to give us whichever side it is for the neighbor.
And I keep in mind this is not the side that the H is going to choose, but this is the side that the
A.I. is going to choose from its neighbor.
Right.
This is the sides neighbors side that the is going to choose.
So that side that you saw how the animator made a mistake because it was the neighbor's side, the I
didn't care about the neighbor this function is going to make is going to train and we're able to take
care to take the neighbors into consideration as well.
So we are going to set for a size and our size is going to be an array.
And then let's go ahead and let's create our square in here as well.
The square is going to be squares, row and also column.
Now, we are going to do some stuff in here that I'm going to try my best to explain.
All right.
So first off, I'm going to say checking for checked, not for checking the left hand side, checking
the left hand side if it is.
Not selected already.
Now, if it is selected already, it means that the will make a mistake and give us points.
Right, and we are going through all this hassle just to make the I not do that.
We don't want to we don't want the air to give us points we can score by ourselves.
I mean, we are big boys, right?
So we are going to say F oops, not there.
So the same thing.
We are going to say f the squares, the squares left side.
First off, I mean we used to do the bottom first.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's do the bottom first.
If the squares bottom side is not selected now this is being selected.
Right.
But if I put in the non-equity operator, it is going to say not selected and checking the bottom hand
site if it is not selected.
So when it is bottom, it means it's in the vertical direction.
So in this case, we are going to check for the.
What do we want to check for the ROE?
When it is bottom?
It means we are at the end of our game, right at the end of the rows.
So what is the end of any array?
The end of an era is the length of that array, minus one.
So squares the length minus one.
So if Roe is the final ROE or.
Our squares array our squares, array, row plus one in this in this, we are going to say plus one
because we are adding it, the column is going to be the same and then we are going to send some selected
is less than two.
What does the selected is going to give us?
It is going to give us the number of sites that are selected.
Now keep in mind, we are remedying the the problem that the D.A. has and that that problem arises whenever
the number of sides are less than two.
That problem arose, I think arose in our second priority.
Second priority was when the number of sides were less than two.
If there are three, that is first priority that I was going to do with ease.
If it is if the sides are ready to write, it is not less than two, but two, then the I will have
to give us some points.
I mean, we don't we have already handled that as well.
The problem that we faced is in the second priority when the square has zero sides or one side.
So zero and one, they're less than two.
So we are going to say less that if this is true, we are going to grab our sides are and we are going
to push to it which side it is.
It is the side, but perfect.
Very simple.
Right.
So now that you have understood this, we're going to do something similar for I'm going to do them
one by one because they tend to get a bit confusing.
So checking the left now.
We are going to check the left hand side.
So in the left, we are in the starting point of our our game or our grid.
So for that, we are not actually checking.
When we are moving from left to right, we are working with the columns.
And because it is left, it is going to be our very first column.
So I'm just going to say zero if column equals zero or now we are no longer working with row and because
we are moving to the left, we are going to send negative one.
If that is, if if this condition or this condition is true, then we want to push to the sides side
left.
Perfect.
Copy that.
Put it down here.
Now let's check right as well now.
Right is whenever we have a lot of columns, right?
Basically, it is going to be double length, minus one.
What is the length of the columns?
The length of the columns is going to be like this length, minus one.
Length are perfect and or what is the or condition that we want to do because we are moving to the positive
direction, we are going to say Collum plus one, if this is the case, let's grab it and let's push
this the right side to the sides array.
Keep in mind, this side's array is actually disvalue that is going to be returned from this function,
and we know we have two situations for that, right?
Perfect.
So the right side is also done.
And what is the final side that we need to take into account?
That is going to be the top side.
So let's copy that.
Let's put it right here.
The top side.
I'm trying to go a bit slower because this is a bit difficult to handle.
That's why I'm slowing down a little.
So what about this side top?
So whenever it is tough, we are moving in the arrows, right?
Top bottom.
We are moving in the rose, left, right.
We are moving in the columns.
Perfect.
So when it is top, it means it is going to be the starting row.
Right.
And we are no longer working with the column.
And when it is stop it is in the negative direction.
So minus one and we are going to push top to the side.
So.
Right.
All right, and finally, what do we want this function to return?
Now, keep in mind, this function has to return something.
It has to return either something or nothing.
And we know what those those two cases are and we are going to return sites.
So site it is either going to contain something based on all these pushes that we did here or it is
just going to be an empty array.
And we know in both conditions what we will do.
Right.
So let me just go over this, so this is square zero and square is the length.
All right.
And let me take a look.
This is option two that push options zero.
And this is options priority that Bush.
All right, right.
So let me reload this a couple of times.
There we go.
We don't have any errors, right?
That that's a good thing.
Always.
Now, let's go ahead and let's go to toe to toe with the computer.
And let's see if our A.I. requires any more finishing touches.
OK, let me grab that line.
There we go.
So now it is at the this is going to be our.
Second priority were the eyes selecting free sites where we provided it with the coordinates, remember,
and it is random, that's why it's like all over the place.
And this is also second priority, where it selected a square that has already won site.
Oh, there we go.
OK, we need to keep keep an eye on the.
OK, perfect.
So far.
Okey doke.
Let's put one here, one there.
I'm just going to close the path there.
So so far, the air hasn't done any mistake, right?
So if I closed the air is going to score with this, I don't think I'm going to I'm going to keep this
because this is actually a good move.
I'm going to keep it for myself.
We're going to see if the.
I knows that that's.
Oh, there we go.
The air.
I just got it.
So this is way more powerful than what we had.
So if I grabbed that or the other one doesn't matter.
Right, so I'm just going to grab it.
There we go.
They did that and the I got that one and I think I'm going to have to give the air some points because
all of them have two sides completed.
So this is going to be six points, four points, three points, so this is the smallest.
This is five.
This is three, four, five, six, seven.
Wow, that's big.
So if I give this one to, the idea is going to give me so I'm going to have one eye then.
One, two, three, four, five.
I think eventually the guy's going to win because of how this game actually works.
So let's go ahead.
There we go.
The FBI gave me these points I'm going to give him for so he will have to he or she I don't know what
what that is, we'll have to give me one of those three go.
So.
Oh, they I actually won.
Because I'm 12, this is six, six plus seven, there's is going to be 13.
So you can see that this is pretty formidable, right, and computer one, I'm going to go one more
round with this.
I was just noticing there and I know that DEA is working fine.
I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to mess around with this EHI.
Right.
So I'm going to try to make it to and to get it to make a mistake.
Purrfect.
If I don't do any mistake myself on the way.
O kay.
Let me put one here.
One from here.
All right, so there we go.
Pretty powerful ally, right, there we go.
So this is the first one that they gave us.
Now, let's check out if the there was there was another choice and if the idea could give me these
three points with the choice to give me more.
That's a oh, yeah, I missed this.
I don't know why.
Let's take a look at it.
I'm going to grab that.
OK, it was pretty intense.
Oh, so it's.
Going to be like that, I'm going to give you two points and you will have to give me all of this.
Perfect.
So this is this time with, like a lot of difference I want and this is going to be the last time I'm
not going to make you watch any further.
We are going to see that if the eyes.
Yes, sort of following me.
No, it is not.
That's what I want to hear from.
Let's see if the air grabs that idea.
I did so first priority is working splendidly.
Okey dokey, so let me put one here, there.
It doesn't matter where I put the ads, the score.
I mean, there are clearly these two options here.
I mean, it is clear that the air requires some touches.
But, hmm, the I did this one.
But still, I mean, this is like a powerfully high.
It is giving away a whole lot of points, the.
Let me just reload the page, just go over the we have we have our options, we have our options, we
have pushed the square squares and sides to that, to our second priority.
And it's basically always the problem with the second priority.
So let's go ahead and it's actually check out the sites function.
So for the left, if square that side bottom.
Oh, that's why Diaz is acting funky.
It's because all of these are bottom.
They should be different.
So I thought there was something wrong with the A.I. So it is left.
That's why they even even with that, the I managed to beat me.
So if we correct this problem.
So we have right, right, left, left.
Bottom, bottom and top, top, so let's save it.
OK, already I can feel the A.I. being more powerful.
OK, let's try to beat it.
You can see it's acting more confidently.
I could I can tell.
OK, I can see it's.
Very, very good.
Oh, you can see that the edge just got it.
It was my mistake in the air.
I got it.
Yeah, this is what I'm talking about.
Perfect words, can I put it here?
Yep.
And very, very confident.
So I think I think I will have to give him some points or her.
I God, I wish it is whatever, I'm not going to finish that sentence, so if I give it this one, is
there any possibility for me to get out of this now?
Yeah, see, now this is the power of this.
It just gave me one instead of giving me, like, a whole bunch.
Now, this is going to be very difficult to beat.
So I'm going to give you two hopefully.
And probably it's going to give me.
Oh, did I miss that?
Oops, well, my problem.
Wow, this is way ahead of me, so I'm going to give you these tools.
You will have to give me five more.
Yeah.
Oops, I made a mistake.
Now, this is not fair, I'm just going to relive this.
Well, I didn't have to reloaded it with reload itself, so let's see what we can do here.
So I would like to shorten our paths.
Right.
And I would like to create one here.
Short paths.
Just to not give away too many points.
Perfect, the ice trying to do something sketchy.
OK.
Mm hmm.
There we go.
So I'm going to put out there and scrub this one.
Let's see, so this one, it doesn't matter.
So I think I can select this one.
Yeah, so there we go.
So the air had no other choice but to give me some points.
I'm going to give you one, buddy.
Yeah.
I am about.
So one, two, three, four, five, one, two, three, four, five.
Wow, that's a lot.
So they will give me this one and I'm going to give give the eye this one.
And if no, not that one.
Actually, I could give the I'm going to beat this.
Oh.
Oh, well, I didn't see that coming.
It's been from.
Wow, so powerful.
I did not see that coming.
You know what, I'm going to do it once more.
I mean, we are basically done here.
So you could I mean, technically, you could skip to our next lecture, but I have to beat this on
camera.
This is like a fight for all of humanity.
I'm going to be more careful.
I mean, I don't remember the last time that I played this game, so it is it does really require you
to think.
OK, so I'm going to close this path.
Close this path as well, close this one.
Others close that one, so.
Let's see.
No, not this one, so this is too this is still a lie.
I know this is three, actually, and if I close that path, that is going to give given to but I'm
not going to give them to.
I'm going to give them one.
Oh, so there we go.
We got four out of it.
So.
Spotted here.
It's a pretty smart so.
It is definitely up to something, so if I eventually if I give him this, he is going to give me this
one, two, three, four, five, six, and I'm going to have to give him this.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
So there is going to be ten plus to 12.
Either way, I'm going to win.
All right, so the I chose to give me this one perfect.
Either way, I'm going to win, buddy, so that's it for this chapter and for this project.
See you guys in the next one, I hope.
I really hope that you have enjoyed this one.
This was one of those really awesome games that we created here.
See you guys then.