Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to talk about the marching part for Arri, so these lectures
that were supposed to be these fires, like eight examples in one lecture.
Well, I designed them to be like only one lecture, but they are spanning over two lectures.
So originally I was I was I thought I was going to have like five marching parts, but I think they
are going to go to ten.
So it doesn't matter how many parts, as long as you understand what how these patterns they work.
So getting the matched characters with lazy matching and the it is going to be the question mark.
Now, what is lasing matching now by default, whenever rejects regular expression searches for a pattern
inside a string or a line of code, it does a greedy match.
What is what does it mean?
It means that it finds all the irrelevant and possible patterns.
It finds all of the patterns.
It's not like sufficing to one pattern.
It's going to find all of the patterns.
And what we can do is with a question mark, we can change this behavior from greedy, like getting
all of everything too lazy to getting none of anything.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's take a look at this, an example.
So we are going to say let Reg.
So this is going to be 13 X be equal to now.
First off, I'm going to show you a grid match.
So let's say we have a T there is any word inside that string that we are looking for.
And that word starts with with a T, with a capital T, of course.
And then we are going to provide the wild card, a character, the wild card character is going to grab
everything that comes after this t right.
So let's go ahead and let's save it.
So I'm going to grab this, put it right here, common this one.
And and let's grab this to say 13 and this should be sentence first.
So if I save it, we can see that we get only t h if I put in the G we get the t h again because there
is only one occurrence of that and we only got that.
So what do we want to do?
We want this wild card character to grab everything that comes after this t so I can show you the greedy
part and that think actually can have zero or more occurrences, which means that this wild card character,
this dot can have zero or more occurrences.
And if I put it in a star, you can see that we have selected everything.
That's because this is the wild card character.
It selects everything there is.
But for it to select, we need to say that this one character at this dot, it occurs zero more times,
meaning that this dot is going to go ahead and grab this edge.
It is going to grab the value of each and then the value of E and then the space.
And then one.
All right.
So this dot, it occurs zero more times.
That's why we just provided with the asterisk.
And this shows us the greedy much.
So how can we make sure that our matches, they are not greedy, but they're lazy.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to provide in the question mark and when I save it, we just
get the T so we don't get anything.
Even though there is a wild card character in here and it is going to grab the T that after which there
is something.
We don't know what that thing is.
There could be h like in there or there could be like E in T.
Right.
So this is called lazy magic.
We just go ahead and grab the first occurrence of that.
The next thing that I want to talk about is our example, number 14, where we are matching the beginning
string patterns.
This is where that Carrott character has a.
Different meaning.
So let's go ahead and let's create Regg 14 X, and what I'm going to do is I'm not going to use brackets
and I'm going to say, give me give me the there, which is at the start of that at the start of the
string.
All right.
So I just want to get that the now the kerosine is outside the brackets, so it matches the beginning
only it only matches the beginning, even though we have something towards the end.
So let's go ahead and let's provide t e at the end as well.
So it's the same thp scra these what I'm right about right here.
That's uncommon them and.
Let's provide 14 so we get only one tea, and why is that?
Because this says that we only want to get the tea, which is at the start of that string.
We don't care about the ending.
So even if I put in the case in certain instances, insensitive flag, the I flag, we still get one
Tichy.
Right.
So it doesn't matter.
The next example is almost the same thing, and that is the matching the ending string patterns.
So we are going to grab whatever it is at the end of that.
So for that, I'm going to again use this example and I'm going to scrub this 14 and I'm going to change
it to 15, comment back everyone.
And now kerosine.
It grabbed the beginning.
But for the ending, we are going to use a dollar sign.
And if I save it, we just get the now the index of this is 89.
But what about this?
The index of that is zero.
You can see that we have selected the ending tachy and we have selected these starting to in here.
So these are calls the beginning and ending string patterns.
This is how we can grab them.
And finally, we are going to talk about the W which selects.
So I'm just going to.
Put in the comment, so this is example 16, we want to match all letters and numbers.
And underscore, so it is going to much underscore as well.
So let's create that regular 16 expression.
So if you provide a backward slash, I think it's called the backwards and a lowercase.
Keep in mind, this is a lowercase W. So I'm just going to say lowercase W..
Right.
Now, a lowercase W matches, what does it match?
It doesn't light it up, it just matches it a r, a through Z.
And number zero through nine.
And underscore, so it matches all the letters, all the numbers and also underscore.
So if I were to go ahead and try to copy this, but I'm here and log them to the console, we are going
to see the results.
So we are going to see this right now.
So why is it t so we have oh, we need to get all the occurrences of that.
So I'm just going to provide I want to print all of them to the console.
So now there we go.
So we have selected everything.
There is all the digits.
But let's say if you have an add sign, so at whatever, so add it is not going to grab the outside.
You can see that there is in the outside you can provide in like two percentages, like an ampersand
asterisk, parentheses, brackets.
It doesn't matter what you provide because the w it only grabs letters, numbers and the underscore.
So if I were to provide Fox underscore, we are going to see the underscore right here.
Right.
So this is it for matching part number for next lecture.
We are going to talk about the matching part number five.
See you guys that.