Welcome to part two of highlighting the site.
All right, so first things first, I'm going to go to top, and I would like to create that mouse event
and I'm going to come underneath there.
We are going to grab.
I'm going to put in a comment here and I'm going to say mouse move.
And this is going to be the mouse move event event listener.
Lost perfect, because we are going to have one for a mouse move and one for click or mouse click.
So let's go let's go ahead and grab the canvas at the event.
Listener It is going to be a mouse move.
And we are when we are moving our mass, we are going to highlight great, right, so highlight great.
So let's go ahead and let's actually create this function.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create this function, been on top of or highlight a side
that we have created here, we are going to create that next.
So don't worry about it.
We have two two methods that have the same name, but they're because they're in different scopes,
it shouldn't matter that much.
All right.
So within this highlight, great.
We going to pass in our event object as well.
So function highlight.
Great pass in the event object.
Now, if it is not player's turn, we want to return.
Right.
All right, but that's not actually what it is that we want to do, because in this if statement, what
we actually want to do when the game ends is we want to check when the time is up, if the time is up,
if the time up or the time end is greater than zero, it means that the game has ended and we want to
return.
So instead of just switching now and actually
then coming back here and then doing the time.
And what I would like to do is I would like to create that time and variable first and then we are going
to pass because we do have a delay.
And the only thing that we don't have is going to be our time and variable that is going to be responsible
for the game over status.
So time and we are going to declare it right there and we are going to come here and we are going to
save time and is greater than zero.
We are going to return from this function.
And I'm going to you know what, I'm going to save this, hopefully we are not going to see any weird
errors for that.
No, we didn't.
So let's go ahead and let's continue with our highlight great function.
So we want to get the mouse's position relative to the canvas, so we are going to say get mouse position.
Relative to.
Relative to canvas, so it is going to be so first off, describe the exposition, the exposition is
going to be that client X, but relative to canvas, it's going to be canvas direct that get bounding
client wreck that we have dot left.
And for the Y position, we are going to grab the top and it is going to be that client Y and it is
going to be y smaller small letters y and then based on these positions we want to highlight the squares.
Squares side, and for that, we are going to call a highlight side function and we're going to pass
an X and Y.
The highlights side function is going to be the function that we have right here.
All right, so.
Let me come in this one in and within this highlight a side function.
So it is going to call this one right, because they're in the same scope within this.
First off, let's go ahead and let's be clear if there is any previous highlighting, we would like
to go ahead and get rid of it.
So we are going to say clear previous highlighting and let's come down here.
So let's go over the looping that so let's go over looping actually over our squares.
So for a row of squares.
So we do have our squares are right because we have rows and columns.
We are going to loop over it twice.
And the second time we are just going to call it square for let.
Square of row, and we want to we would like to grab our square, and from there we would like to grab
the highlight property and we are going to set it to know this is going to clear any existing highlighting
for us.
And then we are going to go ahead and we are going to check each cell.
Right, for if that cell has been highlighted.
So we are going to call in rows.
The rows are going to be the squares length, that length.
The squares that length, and then we have our columns as well, the columns are going to be if the
squares like the columns are going to be based on the indices of the square.
Right.
Not the length of the length of the indices of that square.
That is going to be the number of the column.
So we are going to grab our squares and from there we're going to grab the first item, first items
length.
OK, so let's go ahead and let's loop over this and check for whichever side has been highlighted.
We are going to sell it.
I equals zero and then I is going to be less than Rose.
So this person I'm going to Parsons is as well.
And we are going to increment I by one each time save that.
So let's come here.
And we are going to say that because this is looping over rows and you know that we have rows and columns,
we are going to iterate over columns as well so that J equals zero.
J is going to be the loop variable that is going to iterate over columns.
J is going to be less than the number of columns and each time we're going to increment by one.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create a statement here now we are going to say that whichever side that
we have highlighted, if it has the coordinates that we are just going to pass in here, then we want
that side to be highlighted.
All right.
So first, we need to check for that as well.
So, of course, I j has a we are going to call now.
We are going to call the contents function if it has these coordinates, what it is that we want to
do, we want to store that side inside the squares, the store, the side inside the side variable and
less person i j so I.
J basically means that each of each of those individual scores and if that is the case, we want to
call the highlights side on it.
With that same coordinates.
All right, so I think.
And finally, let's go ahead and let's actually.
Let's break out of it, let's break and I'm going to break out of the outer loop as well, so we are
going to say outer as well.
So this should be semicolon.
Let's save that and.
Let's go ahead and let's actually check for our hmm hmm.
We need to create this contains function as well.
And I see there is a problem here.
This should be askew, u.a.e.
Perfect.
So I'm going to go down there, I'm going to go down and I'm going to create that contains function.
So inside our class, the contents is only going to go ahead and contains as just responsible for passing
the X and Y coordinates of that, whichever score it is that we are hovering on it.
So this is going to return if X is greater than or equal to this dot left and if X is less than this
dot.
Right.
This should be and.
And why is greater than or equal to this top?
And also, why is less than this dot bottom?
All right, so the reason that we are doing this bullying in here is because we are actually grabbing
the center.
So it is either it is greater than the left, it is less than right.
It is greater than top.
It is less than bottom.
So it's directly in the middle of that square that we want.
So let's save this.
Let's come here.
We can see that we do have we still have our drawerful and we are not actually ready to do that.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to create that function, but I'm not going to do anything
in it.
All right, so now the function is created here, and finally, after two lectures, we should be able
to see something real.
We can see that the error is gone because that draw and I'm just going to refresh it a couple of times.
So if I hover on it, we should be able to see some highlighting.
There we go.
So I'm hovering on there is going to give me show me that, you know what, excuse me, for the purposes
of this highlighting, I'm just going to reduce the number to four so you can really see, oh, I shouldn't
have done that.
I should reduce the number here.
So let's let's decrease the size of the grid to four to a four by four grid.
And there we go.
You can see that we have this is the orange color.
I think this is the eye or the or the player number two color that is being highlighted so far.
Refresh you can see that each time you refresh it is going to be completely random.
So it is still that still refresh.
And you can see now it is there.
So if I, if I hover there, it is going to highlight that side, this side, this side, this side.
And everything is working perfectly fine.
So you can see that we I'm actually being able to toggle this from the center of the square so you don't
even need need to have to go to that side to highlight it.
So you have to stand in the center.
If you go slightly towards the top, it is going to highlight up slightly towards the bottom.
It is going to highlight bottom right and then left.
That's exactly what the job of this.
Is.
The contents of this contains is it is going to give us the center for that square, right.
The center.
And if you move slightly to any side, you will be able to highlight it.
And we are not actually able to go ahead and fill it for that.
What we need to do is we need an event listener for for Kaleck.
And I'm not going to do that because we have done a lot of code and you need to go over that a few times.
And and just one more thing.
I would like to go ahead and I would like to decrease this by, I don't know, like two, because very
soon we will be testing this for the different conditions winning which player wins the score and all
of that.
So I just want to keep it out here and you can see the highlighting better.
So if I refresh and it is computer refresh.
Player one refresh.
PLAYER two OK, so we are done with the structure.
See you guys in the next one.