Hi, everyone, in this last year, we are going to complete the drawing lines and drawing circles functions.
All right, so we have created the draw circle function and we have provided with two points, which
are the X and Y coordinates.
And we have told it to start the path, but we have not specified what the circle size is going to be,
what the diameter is going to be for the circle.
All right.
Now we are going to call the ARC method.
Now, the ARC method is responsible for the first half.
We are going to give it in an X coordinate and then we are going to give it a Y coordinate, then the
radius.
Right, which is going to be our size, then the start angle, which is going to be zero and the end
angle, which is going to be another number.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's complete this according to this Intellisense.
All right.
So for the X, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to pass an X as the as the argument and I'm going
to pass on the Y there initially undefined.
And when the mouse is done, we have set him to offset X and offset Y.
When the mouse is up, we have again reset him to undefined and now we are going to pass in the values
here.
The next thing is going to be the radius.
The radius is going to be the size that we have, which is ten.
And after that we are going to give it the start angle, which is zero.
And the end angle.
The ending angle is going to be our math object.
PI right now PI has a value of three point one four one five nine, something like that.
But whenever you're drawing a circle, PI also means 180 degrees.
So if one PI is 180 degrees a circle, a full circle is 360 degrees.
That's why we are going to have to multiply it by two.
So this is this arc is going to create for us a circle.
Now let's provide the color of this circle and we are going to say fill style now for the line.
It was stroke's style for the circle.
It is Phil style.
And we are going to set it to our color variable that we have prespecified and we are going to grab
the seats and we are going to tell it to fill.
We are going to call it the DFL method.
All right, so now these functions, they're created, how do we know that they actually work?
We need to call them.
All right.
So we are going to grab our canvas and we are going to apply another lesson.
Now, this listener is going to listen for a mouse move.
Mouse move.
Right now, this is a mouse move event and it is going to run a function and we are going to grab the
event object as well.
Now, why is it mouse move now when the mouse is down the express?
It is true, right.
And whenever the is pressed is true, we want to grab the X coordinates and the Y coordinates.
Right when the mouse is up, we don't we actually do not want to do anything.
So ignore this part for now.
So when the mouse is done, the rest is true.
Right.
So this is the part that I'm focusing on.
So when the expressed is true, what I want to do is I want this function to also kick in when the expressed
is true, because then when the user clicks and then moves the mouse, OK, it's not like whenever you
click, when you click and then move, it's not going to do anything.
But when you click and then mouse move.
OK, now this is actually two events firing at the same time.
OK, I'm going to explain this one more time.
The first event is Mouse Down.
This is the mouse.
Don't.
I'm sure you can hear the clicking whenever you click that is the mouse down and when you move the mouse,
this is going to be the mouse move.
All right.
So we are actually firing two events at the same time.
And we won those two events to basically do the same thing, to work together, not do the same thing,
but to work together.
That's why I'm telling you for now, just ignore this mouse up.
So when the mouse is down, the expressed is true.
And we are going to add an if statement here and we will say F is pressed is true.
All right.
So now this condition is going to return whenever the expressed is true.
So let's go ahead and let's consider the let's let's log to the console.
One, two, three.
All right.
And I'm going to show you how this actually works.
So let's come here.
This is our project.
And initially we don't have anything.
So if I click and if I unclick, nothing changes.
We don't see anything to the console.
But when I click and move the mouse, you can see that we see 123, 293 times it has been printed.
So whenever we click and move our mouse, then the event is going to fire.
I'm going to go over this one more time when we click, it means that this event is fired and we and
when this event is fired, it means that the express is true.
And we want a map where the user we want to go to the exact spot where the user has clicked.
And when we go there, what do we want to do?
We want to log to the console, the number one, two, three, whenever the user moves their mouse or
mouses like that.
So click we don't see any one to three, but whenever we move, we can see that this number is getting
increased.
So it's three hundred and eighty four now.
It's five hundred and forty two.
Right.
So this is actually how this is going to work and this is going to return for us.
A Boolean statement.
If the Boolean is true, this if statement is going to run, because when the boolean is true, this
condition of is Prast is true, but when the condition of is pressed is not true.
This code is not going to run.
So it doesn't matter if I just go ahead and hover on it and move because this is mouse up and in the
mouse up, the X and Y there, undefined and expressed is false.
Then this event is not.
This event fires when this event fires, this event and this one, they're not going to fire but and
vice versa.
Of course, when mouse down and mouse move, they fire.
This is not going to work because they're polar opposite.
This is mouse down.
This is mouse up.
This mouse move works in conjunction with this mouse done.
So now that this part is clear, we are going to create two more constants and I'm going to call them
X2 and I'm going to set it to E that offset X and I'm going to create another Y two constant and I'm
going to put it to equal to either offset Y.
And now here is where we are going to call our draw circle and our draw line functions.
So whenever we call the draw circle function in the function call, we pass in arguments.
So what are the arguments that we are going to pass in?
There are going to be the X2 and the Y two.
We are going to call our draw line.
Function as well, and we are going to pass, and because that function function has four parameters,
we need to pass in for argument's so X, Y, then we are going to pass and X2 and Y to know these functions
there past the the only thing remaining is we just have to set the X to X2.
And the why two white.
Why, to save it and let's come here and whenever we click and move, you can see that it is drawing
something now is the part where I'm going to explain to you guys why in the first place why we needed
to draw lines and circles in the first place.
And this is actually the most critical part of this entire application.
If you understand why I not understanding this function is very, very simple, very understanding.
This function is easy as well.
But why did we need these functions?
And I'm going to tell you why.
I'm just going to show you first.
So I'm just going to click here and I'm going to move very fast and I'm going to zoom and we are going
to inspect what is happening here.
So in here, you can see that we have a line here, right?
I'm going to zoom even more.
It's blurry, but it proves my point.
We have a line and we have a circle inside that line.
So either the circle is on top of the line or the line is on top of the circle.
We will never find out because they have two different colors.
We can find that.
Find out.
We can just go ahead and say, let's put it let's put the line to red.
And now when I do this and now we know that the line is actually on top of the circle, that's not the
point.
The point is, oops, come on, buddy.
The point is something else.
The point is why we needed to draw a line and a circle, so in the final project, if I click here and
if I move very fast, we can see that this line is actually uniform.
It doesn't mean that there aren't circles in there.
There are circles.
And how do we know that because of this arc, you can see this arc.
This shows that this is not a line.
This is a circle.
So this arc specifies it's a circle.
This arc specifies it's a circle.
But this straight line, it shows that it is a line as well.
But where is the circle in sight here?
We can see circles inside this line, but we can see those here.
The reason for this is because this circle is arc has actually a size to wise of this line.
I told you that we will be returning to the size to this size of the line with the line with is going
to be 10.
Is initially 10, but if you go ahead and if you multiply it, let's say by three.
Let's save it and let's see what is going to happen.
Now, let's go very fast.
And then we can see that this line is actually bigger than the circle and this is not the thing that
we want.
So whenever the user draws this bizarre thing, this is not what we want.
We want to make sure that the circle and the line, they have the same dimension and going coming back
to why we needed to draw to draw a circle.
And their line is whenever we use canvas and we want to draw like we want to do drawing the drawing
is consists of is consisting of a circle and a line.
The line is doing this.
So let's go ahead and let's come into the circle.
Oops, I was not supposed to.
Now, if I go ahead and if I come on, buddy, I don't think we can draw a line because it is dependent
on the circle.
Let's see if we can.
No, we cannot.
So I'm just going to go ahead and come to doubt from here.
Mm hmm.
No, we cannot.
So they are dependent on each other.
Come on, buddy.
Sometimes it's so frustrating, it's not even doesn't it does not even work.
Close it.
All right, so the reason that we need a line and a circle function is this circle and line function.
They are going to work with each other to create the smooth line that we have here.
This is not smooth, but this is smooth.
All right, so this is smooth.
All right, so this line is consisting of lines and circles, right?
That's why we need we need to right.
Both of them.
OK, so I'm just going to put it to size to let's save it.
Let's come here.
So when I draw a line now, this looks very, very uniform.
But of course, these they do not work.
If I go ahead and change the color, it doesn't work.
Some of the functionality, this functionality of the toolbar is remaining.
But as far as the canvas is concerned, we have been able to draw.
Now, whenever the user clicks somewhere and drags this, the user will be able to draw a line.
All right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.