Hi, everyone, in this nation working to create the game loop.
All right, so I'm just going to create a comment here and I'm going to say the game loop, it's going
to be a bit different than the previous project that we had in the sense that we are going to use set
interval.
Right.
So I'm going to call this function run game.
All right, now, inside this function, what I want to do first is I want to draw our ball so we can
see something on the canvas.
So I'm going to say drawing the ball.
Right.
So we know that in order to draw a circle, we first off, we should say begin path.
So begin path.
And right after that or before that first style doesn't matter where you provided canvas context, Phil
style should be orange and then canvas.
Context, dot ark.
Now, here is where things get interesting, so what do we have here?
Right, so we have our our horizontal position, we have our vertical position.
Right.
And we need to pass them right here.
OK, so what are we going to do is I'm going to grab our horizontal position and then the vertical position,
then the radius starting angle and math dot pi times two ending angle.
And finally, we are going to say canvass context, dot phil.
So now if I say we are not going to see anything on the screen.
Right.
The reason for that is we need to call this function.
So I'm going to say I'm going to come here and I'm going to say set interval and we are going to say
set interval.
Let's click on it.
All right, so what do you want to do in here, so in here?
First off, we are going to put in the name of that function.
We are going to call that function.
How many times do we want to call it per second?
So 1000 milliseconds is one second.
We want to call it AFPs times per one second.
So it's going to call it 60 times for one second.
And you can see it does it is being called.
But the thing is that all of these circles are being drawn on top of each other.
Right.
How do we know that?
So let's go ahead.
Actually move the circle.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to sort of be able to move the circle is for us to do one thing,
actually two things.
We need to change the position of the circle so we know that the position of the circle is in the middle
and let's change it.
All right.
And what is the value that we want to change that position by?
We want to change it by its velocity.
So the velocity is speed plus direction.
And then we have our position, current position.
So current position, speed, plus the right direction.
The ball is going to go to the right speed, plus the other direction.
Ball is going to go to the to the top and you get the idea.
So what are we going to do as I'm going to be right here moving the ball from its current position.
Right.
So we are going to grab the XP and we want to add on to it.
We do not want to like let's say we do not want to clear the ball all together.
We just want to add on the velocity to it.
That's why we are going to say, plus, if you don't say plus is just going to move to that specific
position and then it is going to stop.
All right, so and we are going to do the same thing for the for the Y position as well, you're going
to add on to it the Y velocity.
So let's save this.
Let's see what's happening.
There we go.
Save it.
You can see that it happens to be in multiple directions.
Why is that?
It is because of our current situation that we have here.
So if the coin toss returns something that is not too we are not going to do anything if it is to sorry
if if sorry if it if it returns something that equals to zero, then we are going to change the direction,
the velocity for the extraction.
If it doesn't we are not going to change it.
The same thing applies for the Y.
So each time I reload we are going to get because this is random, each time you reload it is going
to generate a random number and that's why we get different directions for this feat.
And what you might be asking, why is this being elongated, the reason for that is because we are not
clearing the canvas and we can see all the iterations of that.
Now, how can we see that better?
I showed you in the previous project, I'm still going to show you in this project as well.
So instead of Phil style, we are going to say stroke style instead of Phil, we are going to say stroke.
Let's save it.
Let's come here.
There we go.
Now you can see the circles being drawn and because we are not clearing the canvas, we can see all
the previous iterations of the circle.
I'm going to zoom out so you can really see it, see?
Circle is being drawn on top of each other, so that's not something that we want.
So we need to clear the canvas.
So clearing the canvas, so how can we clear so we're going to say canvas context that clear rucked.
And zero position zero, so starting from the zero position in the X and Y, go all the way to the canvas
elements dot with and canvas elements dot height and clear everything.
So now there we go.
Our ball is finally moving.
We don't have any collision detection.
That's why it's moving off the screen.
So let's bring back our film style so we can actually see the ball moving.
All right, so let's save it.
See, now the ball is moving in different directions.
The velocity is also different, you can see velocity is higher, slower, higher, higher, slower.
So so the only thing left for us to do is to.
Detect the collision, and I'm not going to do that in this lecture.
It's already been seven minutes.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to postpone that to the next lecture and we are going to detect
some edges.
So see you guys in the next lecture.