Hi, everyone, in this letter, we we're going to show and hide our different tabs.
All right, so so the first first things first, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say income b10
you know what?
I'm going to go with the expense first doesn't really matter.
But this is the way I've structured my code and I'm going to say event listener.
All right.
So this is the expense event listener, the expense button and by the expense button, I mean this this
tab that we have selected.
So this is the expense b10 tab one incompetent to all be tab three.
So let's grab the expense BTN and we are going to add an event listener, the event is going to be kaleck,
so we are listening for a click event and then we are going to run a proper function.
So whenever we click on the expense button, let's first off see what should happen.
So when we whenever we reload the page, we can see that the all button it shows like here in this.
But when I click on the expense all button, it doesn't show anymore.
It is like faded a bit.
The income tracker is faded a bit as well, but only the expense structure.
So whenever we click on the expense side income and all, click on the income side expense and I'll
click on the all hyd expense and income sort of like that.
So we are going to call in a function and the function is going to be show and it is going to show the
expense element.
So we are going to call in the expense element and it is going to hide.
Why is it doing this?
So it is going to hide.
It is going to hide what?
It is going to hide the income element and the all elements.
Right.
And it is going to add we are going to call another function which is active.
Why does it do that?
So the active function and whenever we call in the active function, we say it should be as a parameter,
as an argument.
We pass in the expense button whenever we create these functions, you know what I mean?
But for now, I just want to go ahead and do this.
And the inactive inactive is going to be inactive is going to be again, the income button, income
button and the all button.
So we want to activate the expense but expense button and deactivate the incompetent and the all button.
So this is the expense and listener.
All right, and we have two more event listeners as well, so the next one is going to be income.
I could just select all expenses and I could convert them into income.
So whenever the income button is collect, I want to show income.
I want to hide expense.
Expense, right.
I want to hide expense here and expense Arment and all element.
All right.
And I want to activate the income button and I want to deactivate the expense expense.
I want to deactivate the expense button and the all.
But and as far as the all is concerned.
Whenever we click on the old button, we want to show the old button, we want to deactivate the income
element, we want to hide the income element and the expense element.
And also we want to we want to make active the all button and also the active the expense.
But here so we have created this event, listeners, what about their functions, whatever the show,
the hide, the active and the inactive functions, so these functions are what we are going to create
now.
We are actually going to create all four of them.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to call in.
I'm going to say show function.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's create a function.
Let's name it show.
And we are going to pass in an element in here, all right.
OK, so we are going to grab our element, whatever that element is.
And we are going to say we are going to stop there.
We are going to grab their list of classes and we are going to remove the hide clause.
All right, so what is that element, the element in the case of expense button is the expense element
in the case of income button, that element is the income element.
In the case of the all button, it is the all element.
So let's come here.
So if I click on this, we can see the now the the income tracker is shown on the express track or is
shown.
But whenever I click on the income, so whenever I click on this, this should go away the all button.
I should only be seeing this income.
And when I click on the expense, the income and the all, they both should be hidden.
So let's create those functions as well.
The next thing that I want to do is I want to grab and I want to create the hide function, hide function,
and we are going to create a function.
And the name is height.
We are going to insert elements, not element.
And the reason for that is we have passed in two arguments inside an array like the structuring style.
And here that's why I'm just going to say aliments, because it refers to both of these two.
Right.
And inside this function, what I'm going to do is I want to grab our aliments.
Aliments, and I want to say for each we are going to use our for each method because there are an array,
right?
And I could do I could use this syntax, which is the arrow function syntax.
But I think this is a little bit confusing.
So we are just going to go through our regular syntax element.
So this element is the dysfunction parameter as well as this loop variable.
And we are going to say for each element that has been clanked, we want to add a we want to grab the
class list and add a class to it.
What is that class?
The class is high.
And for the high side, if we remember correctly from our success says visibility heading so high,
I'd say that let's come here.
So when I click on this one, you can see that this is completely hidden.
All right.
You can see that everything is gone and now like all is gone.
Right.
But we need to fix that and we can fix that whenever we create the active function and the inactive
function.
So let's create the active function.
Very simple stuff.
So we have a function that is named active.
You're going to pass an element in here.
And whichever element that is, we are going to add a class list to it.
Don't add and that class list is going to be active.
And finally, let's create the inactive function and let's say function in active.
And we are going to because for the inactive, we still again, we have a set like an array.
That's why we are going to pass in elements and we are going to say aliments dot for each.
And whenever this for each loop runs, we are going to run a function.
The function R parameter is going to be element.
And whenever that function runs, what do we want to do?
We want to grab that specific element that we have clicked on.
So we want to grab that specific element and we are going to top their class list or their list of classes
and we want to remove.
Remove the active clause, let's save it.
Come here.
So now if I come here, if I click on the expense, we can see that this all is is getting removed.
Right.
Which it should not do this.
We are going to fix that.
We can see that it works for these two.
But what about this all?
So if I come here for the whenever I click on this, we are going to hide the whenever I click on the
expense, we are going to hide.
Hide the income element and the hide the all element, we are going to make activity and expense button
and deactivate the income button and the all button.
All right, and actually, this is not all aliment excuse me, this is all list, because the whole
element doesn't have anything inside of it.
All right, so if I come inside this all elements, so this is the all element.
But what we are going to do is we are going to grab the whole list because the list has that style to
it.
So where is this is the list?
This is the style for the old list.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to my JavaScript, and so this is the all element we have
selected that because we need it as well.
But from here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab all the all elements.
And you know what, I'm just going to select them one by one and I'm going to call all list.
All lest we want to hide the all, lest we do not want to hide the all element right in this case,
and I think and we want to show the all the list because we have hidden it.
We want to show it.
So now if I click on this, we can see still the is remaining here, so clicking, clicking, clicking,
everything is working properly.
Now, the reason you might ask, OK, why do we want to show the list?
But in the case of income, we want to show the all income element.
This is going to be answered through this e-mail.
So if I come here and let's go ahead and let's use two tabs, because this is a great use case for that.
So what is the expense element?
The expense element that's come here?
Has this is the expense tracker.
So for the expense element, we have selected this diff.
So this is the diff.
All right.
But whenever we set height, you can see that the H3 is actually out of this, if I said hi to the expense
itself, then the H3 is going to hide as well.
But we have set it to expand structure.
We want this expense structure to hide.
And whenever we click on the expense structure, we want the expense structure to show because the inputs,
they are inside that expense structure.
So this is the you know, you can see inside the all we don't have any inputs, but inside the expense,
we have three inputs inside the tractor income tracker.
We have three inputs whenever we click on this is three.
We want to see this whenever we click on this is three.
We want to see this whenever we click on this three, we want to see the list because this structure
is different for all.
We have a div, but we have three.
If I grab and if I say hide this, it is not only going to hide the list, but it is going to hide these
three as well.
That is the all elements you can see the whole element has an idea for which is this element.
And if I said the display hidden to this element divisibility hidden, then this H3 and this UL are
going to hide.
But I don't want these three to go away.
If it goes away, how can I switch back to it?
There is no element there, so I just want to hide the list.
Keep in mind, we just want to hide the list and the inputs associated with this list in case of the
trackers.
But in case of the all, we don't have any inputs.
That's why we are only in hiding the list itself.
Ariete.
I hope this is clear.
This is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.