Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create the vertical velocity and randomize the size,
speed and location of our stars.
All right, so if I come here insight into this page where it says Pythagoras's theorem and what Pythagoras's
theorem says is that if you have a right triangle, right angled triangle, it means that the angle
is going to has to be like 90 degrees.
If you have this triangle and you have two sides of this available, you can find out the third side
using this formula.
So it says A squared plus B squared equals C square.
Now we have our speed, which think of it as C, we do half hour A sorry, B, which is the horizontal
velocity, but we don't have the A, which is the vertical velocity.
Now, if I were to rearrange this mathematical formula, we would.
Now I want to find out the A..
So I would have to move B to the other side of the equality.
Now, the sign of B is by default is positive.
And if I if you move something to the other side of the equality when it is in and in the sort of addition
or subtraction formula, then the sign is going to change.
So if I move this B square to here, we will have C squared, minus B squared.
So A squared is going to be equal to C squared, minus B square.
Now we do have these squares, right.
And if I take a root, a square root and added to this side of the equality and added to this side of
the equality, that this this power of two is going to cancel that square root.
So we are going to end up with an A and that square root is going to stay here.
So basically what we end up with is going to be something like this.
So we have a equals, we have a square root in JavaScript, his language, and then we have C, which
is to the power of two minus B, which is to the power of two.
So basically we have this mathematical equation and now we have to convert this into the language the
JavaScript can understand.
So first off, I'm going to say I'm going to sell let vertical velocity.
And I'm going to say now we have a square root function in JavaScript and keep in mind that all these
mathematical formulas, they are.
They are like within this math object.
All right, so and that the name of that is EQR t or returns the square root of a number.
So so the a part is this part right here.
Now, this square root that we have is going to be a security.
Square root, and then inside of that, we have C Square.
Now, keep in mind, C squared is our star speed that we have found out.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say now, how do you say something to the power of something
in JavaScript?
For that, we have yet another cool method, and that is Pough.
P o w so we are going to say math dot pough, and now keep in mind it returns to things.
It requires two things the base value of the expression, the exponent value of the expression.
So if I open this up, it is going to give us a more sensible explanation.
So it returns the value of a base of expression taken to a specified power.
So we have no and we have no.
So the first one that you have to provide here is going to be that variable that you have and that variable
is no longer speed its stars speed.
Right.
And the second one is going to be the power of that room number, the exponent exponent value of the
expression.
So see to the power of two.
This is see to the power of two.
So this is how JavaScript handles powers.
Right.
And so we have completed that.
And after that, what do we have?
We have a negative side.
So I'm just going to go out of it and I'm going to provide negative side.
And then we have B to the power of two or horizontal velocity.
So we are going to say math dot pough.
It's not poor like the dog's paw.
No, it's po po W..
All right.
So for that, we are going to grab our horizontal velocity.
Horizontal velocity and what is then the power, the power is going to be to?
So basically, we have completed this now, this is always this, sometimes it is going to give us a
positive, sometimes it's going to give us a negative velocity.
All right.
But we want I'm just going to remove or I should I keep it here?
I'm just going to comment it out now.
What do we want?
We want to multiply as as with this one.
We want to multiply by multiply this by the random sign as well, because we want to find we want to
have a positive or a negative sign as well.
So either it's moving or if it is moving towards the top, it's negative.
If it is moving towards the bottom, it's positive.
So that's why we are going to add the random sign as well.
So that's it for our vertical velocity.
Now, underneath here, I'm just going to say randomizing the stars speed, size and location and we
have done this.
This is extremely simple.
We are going to say four, let I equal to zero.
So we want to.
Why is that?
Plus.
So we are going to start from zero and then I is going to go all the way to less than stars.
Stars, what stars no.
And that is one thousand and then we are going to increment the eye by one each time.
So first off, we know that Stars is an empty array.
So all of these locations, speed and size, we want to push it to this.
So that's why I'm going to say stars I saw each time this for loop runs, the eye is going to have a
certain property.
And that property, the set of properties, which is actually an object, this object, each time the
eye runs, this object is going to be pushed to the stars, which is an empty array.
So what do we have?
What are the properties that we have here?
The first one I'm going to call Star Radius.
And so this is the radius of our star.
And of course, because we have different star sizes, we're going to have different radii.
Right.
So we are going to say math are random times the size that we have here, because this is a fraction
of that.
How do you know it's a fraction of the the screen that's a maximum star size as a fraction of the screen
with.
How do we know that?
Because we just multiplied by the canvassing board with.
That's how we know it.
Right.
And now we can leave it like this or we can even divided by two, because to get a smaller and even
smaller number.
Excuse me.
So if you don't divide it, you're going to get like a slightly bigger one.
But if you divide it, you're going to get a slightly slower, sort of slightly smaller number.
And then we want to have a horizontal position.
So we want to create a circle for a circle.
We want we need a horizontal position, vertical position, radius, start angle and angle.
All right.
So we have created the radius.
Now we need to create the horizontal and vertical positions.
So I'm going to call it horizontal position as opposed to horizontal velocity.
And what is the position?
So we are going to grab our math are random because we are we are randomizing the location or the position
as well.
So I'm going to multiply it by the canvas.
We have done this, that width, because this is vertical.
This is horizontal.
We are going to multiply it by canvas done with.
Now, keep in mind, the random is going to give us some decimal points to remove these those decimal
points.
I'm going to wrap this inside a math dot floor function.
So my third floor is going to round it to the smallest, to the nearest integer like Florida.
So if it is one point one, it's going to be one.
If it is a one point four, it's even if even if it is one point four, it's going to be one.
Even if it is one point nine, it's going to be one.
That's how math that floor works.
We are going to have the same thing for the vertical position except with a difference.
And that is going to be canvas element tight.
So now we have created these properties here.
And what I'm going to do next is now we need to specify the velocity for these as well.
So the horizontal velocity, the horizontal velocity is going to be equal to the horizontal velocity
times, the speed, what I like to call boost what, not three those two to us.
What a speed boost.
So if I were if I come here now, you can see some of them the travel faster than the others.
That's why I'm going to multiply it by speed.
But we are yet to create it, so I'm just going to create it here.
Speed boost.
So it's going to be random number.
And what is the speed boosts range?
So it depends how does it depend?
It depends on how fast do you want it to go.
So now for this animation, the speed boost is one point five plus point five.
So the maximum is going to be two.
So the speed boost is maximum two and minimum point five.
So if I can if I change it to like a maximum of five.
You can see how fast they go, right?
So this is a maximum of five and a minimum of point five, you can say a maximum of 100.
Then it's like like firing all the time, except for this guy.
This is the the difference, the different one than the others.
So some of them are faster.
Some of them are slower.
You can go 1000 and it's practically shooting.
Right.
You can go 10000.
And now you can see that my computer is not working properly.
So it depends on what you want.
I want it to be the maximum, should be two and the minimum should be like this.
So I think this is better or maybe like the maximum should be three minimum should be point five.
So we are going to say at times, so I'm going to say the maximum should be three, the minimum should
be point five.
So whenever it gives us one, this matter random gives us one one multiplied by 2.5, we are going to
get two point five plus point five.
We are going to get three.
So the maximum is going to be three.
But when this matter random gives a zero zero times 2.5, we are going to get zero zero plus point five.
We are going to get point five.
So the minimum is going to be point five are right here, right.
OK, not that comma, and we are going to do the same thing for the vertical velocity ver vertical vertical
velocity that I spell it correctly.
Perfect, perfect.
Now, we are basically done with this as well.
We have come a long way.
We still we can't see anything here.
The reason for that is we have not drawn anything to the canvas.
So now what we are going to do is in the next lecture, we are actually drawing something to the canvas.
So far we were basically involved with the logic of this effect and from the next lecture onwards,
we will be printing them to the screen.
So see you guys then.