Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to create our character codes.
All right, so before diving into this lecture, I want to show you the character codes that we will
be using inside this application.
So this is the part where this application could go a thousand different ways.
We could go ahead and create different arrays with these letters and symbols that we have.
But we could also use the character codes, the SCIRI character codes table and cheat sheet, which
is available at this YORO, which is at your disposal right here.
Right.
So here we are for each letter.
We have a different code and we could use that code to access that letter, OK, to generate to include
it inside our password, generate function.
All right, so, for example, the upper case letters, they start from 65 all the way and go all the
way to 90.
The lower case, they start from ninety seven, all the way to 122.
We have our symbols.
We have our numbers.
And then we again, we have our symbols.
All right.
So now taking this resource into consideration, we are going to create our character codes.
So first off, before creating them, I'm just going to create a function inside of which we are going
to insert an array that is going to loop over these characters character codes, and each time is going
to grab one value from there.
So I'm going to call this function.
Oops.
I'm going to say character codes, looping function.
It's not a good name, but it definitely conveys the point.
All right, so let's create a function.
Let's call it Ray, low to high.
I don't know, something like that.
OK, and we are going to insert two parameters of luks, not low and high.
All right.
So we are to loop.
So we are going to use a for a loop the loop variable.
This time is going to be high and it is going to start from the low and it is going to go all the way
equal to less and less than or equal to high high.
And each time we are going to we are going to increment I by one.
And what does it what is it going to do?
It is going to grab an array and it is going to push everything that it has created that push.
Right.
And what is it going to push to that array?
It is going to push our low variable.
OK, I'm going to explain this one more time.
But first off, let's create our array.
So I'm just going to call it a flat array for this stuff.
I'm just going to set it to an empty array.
And after that, when the loop variable runs our character codes and it grabs each time one of those
characters, it is going to pass it inside this empty array.
And then we are going to grab this material and we are going to call a string method of joint to convert
it to a string so we can display it or a user like this whenever we click.
This is an array which is converted into a string and we can display to a user.
All right, so at the end, what we want is we want to return or that said, this is it.
So this is this is what's going to loop over our character.
All right.
So let me remove that space maybe like provided now let's go ahead and let's create our character counts.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create the lowercase character codes.
Right.
So I'm going to tell you why not now maybe like in two more in the next two lectures.
So first off, I'm going to call it lower case.
Character Charcot's lower case character codes, and we are going to call our Arae our function of a
real low to high and it is going to iterate from one number all the way to another number.
So what is the lowercase character code?
So we are going to come in to our website, not my website, of course, and it is going to start from
97 and go all the way to 122.
So we are going to say.
Start from ninety, go all the way to 122.
So now this has been created, the function knows what are the values, what are the numbers that it
is supposed to start looping?
From and what is the number that it is supposed to loop until that number, so the starting point is
97, the ending point is 122.
We have called this function once.
We are going to call it like a few times.
So the next variable that I want to and before creating that, whenever dysfunction loops over these
numbers, it is going to grab a number and we want to store that number inside this variable.
That's why we have called this function inside this variable.
We want to store that value here so we can access this value later on.
OK.
So the next one is I'm just going to call it no character codes, no Charcot's or character codes,
you are going to call our function and we are going to pass.
And so what are the number of character codes?
Let's come in to our website.
It says they start from 48 and they go all the way to 57.
All right.
So we are going to say 48, 57, starting and ending point.
The next thing that I want to create is going to be our symbols, symbol, character, codes.
Let's go singular, not plural symbol character cotes.
OK, and we are going to call in our function of our low to high.
A real low to high.
Now let's see where our symbols this is going to be a bit trickier than the previous two.
So let's see.
So first off, our symbols, they're going to start from right here from 33 and they are going to go
all the way to 47.
So now, first off, let's pass those in 33 all the way to 47.
And then if we go ahead and take a look at that, we see that from 58 all the way to 64.
We again have we have our symbols.
And then from 91, all the way to 126, we again, we have our symbols.
So we need to add on to this array and the method that we are going to use for this kind of thing.
Whenever we want to add on to an array we are going to use.
A concat method, it says that additional items to add to the end of Array one combines two or more
arrays, right?
So it combines two or more right in here.
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to include from 58 all the way to 64.
So this is going to be 58 all the way to 64.
And then we are going to call the concat once more.
And this time it is going to start from 91.
All right, so we have included it is going to start from 91 and go all the way to 96.
All right.
Because this is not 97, this is 123.
So it is going to start from 91 all the way to 96.
And finally concat, we are going to add more items to the end of this array from 123 up to 126.
All right, Sawan, 23, up to 126.
Let's save it.
So this is going to be the symbol character codes.
Each time that this function loops over these numbers, it is going to give us one specific or a specific
range of numbers, codes, and we are going to convert those close into actual characters and we are
going to store them inside the symbol character codes.
All right.
So lower case number and symbol there, Don.
The only thing remaining is our upper case.
So I'm going to call it upper case character code.
Right.
So it is uppercase character code.
And we are going to call in our function and let's pass on the two values.
So from here for the upper case, you can see that it starts from 65 and goes all the way to 90 because
it says upper case right here.
So 65, 90, 65, all the way to nine.
Oh, let's save it.
So now we have successfully created our character codes right here.
And what we're going to do in the next lecture is to create our very final function.
And that is, of course, the generate password function for which we have already created the function
of call, but the function itself is still missing.
So in the next lecture, we are going to create that function.
See you guys that.