Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we will be moving the panel from one side to the next site.
Perfect.
So first of all, what I'm going to do as I'm going to we have to set up some events, all right, for
the left Iraqi and for the right Iraqi.
All right, so what are we going to do, as I'm going to say Araghchi?
Arrow key events right now, what it is that we want to do.
Whenever I press down on the left key, I want the paddles to move and when I release the key or when
the key up event is fired, I want to I want the paddle to stop right there.
So the same thing happens for the right one.
So let's grab the document and let's say a wellness listener, and we are going to grab the key down
event and create a key down function.
And we are also going to grab the key up event and we are going to create a key up function.
Right.
So we have created this.
So now let's go ahead and let's actually set them up.
So.
Now we have to create the key down function and the key up functions.
So what should we put them right after the draw was?
So I'm going to come here and I'm going to grab this.
Let's copy it.
Let's put it right here and.
All right.
All right, so here we have our drawls, so instead of that one, I'm going to do as I'm going to right
arrow keys, let's add another is up there as well.
So Arrow Keys events here.
We have arrow keys functions.
Because both of the functions are going to be right here.
So the first one is going to be key down, so key down.
We are going to pass in our event object.
And first off, what I want to do is let's think so whenever I press the key, the arrow key left one,
I want the paddle to move to left.
And when I press it to right, we want the paddle to move to.
Right, right.
So we know that we will be needing conditionals, right, and so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
use which case this time.
So I'm going to say idot key code.
So for the arrow, for the left out of the key code is going to be 37 for the writer to the key code
is going to be thirty nine.
Right.
We know that because we move the ball remember.
So in here.
So what is the first case.
So the case in the case that the event is that key code is thirty seven.
What do we want to do.
It means that it is the left arrow and what do we want to do is move paddle to left.
Perfect.
So I'm going to hit.
Left.
And so we are inside the switch.
We are going to create we are going to call a move padel function and in there we are going to call
our directions object.
And from there we are going to grab the left and then we are going to break out of this statement.
In the case it is 39, we will be doing basically the same thing, so we have our right arrow, so right
arrow.
And that said this to 39, let's remove the other one.
Move Padel to right, left.
Perfect.
So in here, we are going to call the same function I know we have not created that.
We are being created right after this step.
Right, so.
OK, we are going to grab our directions object, and from there, let's grab the right one and right
after that we are going to break.
Perfect.
So this is the key down and for the key up, we are basically implementing sort of the same thing.
So we are going to say key up.
Right, and in here, I'm going to pass in the event of object as well, and we are going to say switch.
So a switch in the parentheses is going to be our condition.
So key code.
Is the condition, if the key code is 37.
If the key code is 37, we want to stop moving.
If the key code is 39, we also would like to stop moving.
But for both of them, I'm going to apply only one condition, because until you break from this case,
we know that the other statements will also run.
So I'm not going to break from 37.
I'm just going to go to 39.
And for both of them, I'm going to say direction that stop and now we are going to break them perfect.
So I think these are completed.
So right after there, I'm going to grab this comment.
I'm going to put it right here.
And we are going to create the move parallel function and then move parallel function what it is that
we want to do.
So let's see.
So we have the move panel function and in here, because we have an argument, we need a parameter for
that.
And I'm just going to call it direction, because that is going to be the direction and we are going
to say switch direction.
So if the direction is going to be left, move, we are going to we are going to change the direction
of the velocity.
So case direction dot left.
Do what we are going to grab our paddle and from there we are going to grab the X velocity and we are
going to set it to paddle.
That negative padel X velocity, we just change the direction of the velocity.
And now let's break out of there and in case the direction moves, the direction is right, not right.
Oops, not eight.
Right.
In case the direction is right.
What it is that we want to do, we want to grab our panel and the X velocity and we are going to say
we are going to set it to a positive velocity so it moves to the right.
So and then we are going to have to break from it.
And finally if the direction in case the direction is stop.
We are going to grab the paddles x velocity and set it to zero and let's break from that as well, so
we should be able to see something.
So if I go right, I'm not you should click there.
I'm not going anywhere.
We should see something, but we are not actually moving.
So we have grabbed every we have created these situations, they switch cases, but we have not actually
updated the current position of the panel.
So we are going to grab our paddle and we are going to update it with the update, the position with
the velocity that we have just done here.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create an update paddle function,
so.
I'm going to come beneath our set dimensions, so whereas I'm just going to collapse that one beneath
our set dimensions.
What I'm going to do is, you know what, I'm just going to expand this, so in case there is something
that you want to you can see and there is an error that you fix, for example, there is something that
you have mistyped and you see it and you just want to, like, type it again or something like that.
When we have a lot of code, I'm going to collapse the ones that we are not going to need.
So in here, let's grab these set dimensions comment.
But are there and now let's update the position of the power.
So update, paddle,
paddle function.
So let's say function and.
So within this function, we will be actually accomplishing two things one, we will be updating the
position of the panel, and two, we will be implementing collision detection for the panel as well.
So first, let's move the panel.
And we are going to create a variable called Last Paddle Last the Last Paddles Exposition, and we're
going to set it to current position.
All right.
And now let's grab the current position, the position and add on to it.
Now we are going to add onto it the velocity X V, but the velocity is going to give us pixels per second.
We don't want to we don't want pixels per second, we want pixels per frame.
So you remember in our previous game we had time last time difference time now.
And the the idea behind those was to convert any pixels per second to pixels per frame pops to P F.
But now in this game, I didn't want to do that and I wanted to go through a different approach.
And here is so we have pixels per well, actually, this is to be more accurate.
This is going to be pixels per milliseconds.
So first off, I'm going to divide it by 1000.
So this is going to give me pixels per second, and when I multiply it by the speed that I want, for
example, 20, then this is going to give me pixels per frame, right.
So this is actually in pixels per second when I divide it by that, not only it is going to give me
the seconds, but also the pixels per frame if I multiply it by two.
So in each frame, the X is going to be moved by 20 in each frame.
Keep that in mind so you can reduce this.
You can set it to zero.
But I want it to be like a bigger number.
So this is going to be our movement of this, the paddle that we have here.
So updatable, let's actually call this so our paddle actually goes ahead and moves.
So I'm going to come here to our game loop and in here I'm going to just say update functions and in
here.
So we are going to have two different categories.
We are going to have draw functions and we are going to have update functions.
So the first update function is going to be update paddle.
Let's say that that's come here.
And if I move to the left, it is not moving to the left and it is not moving to the right.
It should move.
I don't know why it is not moving, so let's come down here and.
Let's actually see what's happening here, so we have selected the paddles exposition, and what we
want to do is we want to add on to it the velocity.
So we have added on the velocity.
And we have also, you know what?
I'm just going to go ahead and comment this one.
And and I'm just going to save this.
Let's see.
Still, it is not moving, it should move.
I mean, have we provided let's see if this function even runs.
So Consolo if it runs, we are going to see a lot of one, two, three.
There we go.
So this function is running perfectly fine.
Oh, such a rookie mistake.
So instead of actually changing the we are basically we are going to add on a positive and negative
speed to the velocity because velocity is initially zero right here.
So we need to add onto it and then change the direction.
So we are going to get the speed, which is a fraction of the screen size.
And in here we are going to get the speed.
And if I say that now, you can see our paddle is moving.
But the problem is it is going through the walls.
So what we are going to do as we have to specify the collision detection as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and close that function for now.
So this is going to be moving the paddle, I'm going to initialised Darrah's declare that, but we are
going to talk about that later, right.
So I'm just going to put it there.
And you know what?
I'm just going to remove it for now, so you don't have to really worry about it.
Perfect.
So what should we do now?
Now we have to go ahead and we have to.
Implement the wall collision.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say a wall collision, so the collision is going to happen in
the extraction we have in the in the left, which is going to be like on the left wall and right, which
is going to be on the right wall.
So wall collision detection.
For Parul.
So we are going to say f f the paddles, we have done a lot of collision detection, so I'm not going
to really overcomplicate this.
We are going to go very simple.
So f the left of the paddles exposition is less than the wall, plus the panels with panels with divided
by two.
It means that if half of the panel is trying to go through the wall, what it is that we are going to
do, we are going to reposition the panel to what it is right here.
So let me just put it there and let's just change it to an equal.
Very simple, right?
So this is the left side al-Assaf.
Very, very simple, right, collision detection is simple, and I think I mentioned this, that the
collision detection is going to be the simplest thing that we need to concern ourselves with.
There are many other advanced topics.
So if the paddles exposition is greater than the canvasses elements with, it means it's going off the
right side, minus the water is moving through the wall by and trying to move through the wall and half
of the width, minus half of the with what we're going to do, we're going to reposition the panel to
what it is right there.
So let's.
Put it there and let's save it should work this time.
Now you can see there we go so it can half of the paddle is trying to move through the wall and it can't.
And this this time this side, you can see half of the panel is trying to move, but it can't.
Perfect.
So we have completed collision detection as well for our panel and we have also updated the position.
Perfect, and the next thing that the next logical thing that we need to do is actually to go ahead
and create the ball and have the ball start from, say, if I reload the page, you can see it starts
from the metal.
That's because of the new game that is being called.
And we want the ball to start from top of the paddle.
First, we need to create it and give it an initial position paddle and then bounce off the walls and
then also bounce off the paddle.
And then we will move on to creating the bricks, these amazing bricks that you can see here.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.