Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we will determine the winner.
All right, so we have created the now for each of the boxes we need to provide a an event listener,
the event is going to listen for a click because basically we are clicking inside these boxes.
All right.
So I'm going to grab the box and I'm going to add event listener.
The event is going to be click whenever the user clicks, we are going to grab a function and call that
function box collect.
Now, the rest of the game is going to be fairly simple, so I will just go ahead and breeze through
it.
So we have our box clicked and I'm going to put in the E!
Now all of our boxes, they have Idiz zero one to all the way to eight.
We can leverage that.
So first off, let's go ahead and store it inside a variable so we can reuse it.
We are going to say a target.
That idea is going to give us the idea for that specific element.
And we are going to say if the ID if the if it is not, the space is.
Out of the box IED.
All right, so because we have like nine spaces, and if the IED for the box, IED for that space is
that we have or actually we do have choices here, because in my original thing, I created spaces that
Sweitzer spaces.
If this is not true, it means that the IED doesn't belong to this.
What do we want to do?
We want to grab our choices.
And the backside.
The box eyed and we want to set it to the player, Mr..
So each time it is not true, it is going to be the next player's turn right.
And what do we want to do exactly at that moment?
We want to grab the entire text because whenever we click, we are actually changing the entire text.
So inner text should be whichever player it is that is blank.
So I'm just going to set it to players turn.
After that, we are going to switch the player.
So we are going to say player's turn is going to be first.
We need to check if it is the player one turn because that's what we did above.
So if players turn equals player one.
PLAYER one Then we want to switch it to players, too, otherwise we want to keep it at player one right
now in here.
What I would love to do is I want to do and if statement and we are going to create this function,
that is going to be player one, not play one.
Player one.
And we are going to pass on the players turn now, whichever player wins and this statement becomes
true, what do we want to do that we want to grab our result, which is that I want and we want to change
the entire text.
All right, what do we want to change it to?
So let's open our tactics and we want to change it to the players turn so the players turn is going
to either say oh or X, and then we just want to say wins.
So either O wins or X wins.
And then because the board is going to be reset it automatically, we are going to do after one second.
I'm just going to increase it to maybe like one point five seconds.
We are going to call a function that is going to be reset board and it is going to be called after 1500
milliseconds.
Now, first off, let's go ahead and let's create the player player once a function, play your player
want.
Now, this function is going to be fairly straightforward.
We are just going to hard code all the possibilities in which a player can win.
So the first possibility is whenever you either put three in a row, like in the first row or in the
first column, first off, I'm going to do that.
So what is the so we are going to grab this.
So this is going to be our pivot.
So from this pivot, if I have two in the row in a row or if I have two in a column which match, whichever
it is, whatever it is inside this pivot, it means that this player has won.
So let's go ahead and let's implement if statements for that.
So we are going to say f the choices, we are going to grab the zero index.
That's the first pivot that we are talking about.
Let's grab our player.
Now, if if it is the first index, we only have two possibilities.
I'm ignoring diagonal because we are going to handle it later.
So for this, we just have row in column.
So we are going to say that.
And if the choice is now, first off, let's grab the row.
So what is the index of this?
It is what what is the index of this?
It is too.
So we are going to say if this equals this or the index of one equals the index of two choices.
One equals the player that we have.
So the player is going to be displayed that we passed in there and choices.
So what was the other index?
That was two, if that is also equal to the player, what it is that we want and say we want to return.
True.
Right.
So this is going to take care of that.
I'm just going to also say council log when.
All right, I'm going to say pivot, pivot, one when one, I'm just going to say one pivot one, one,
right.
That's open up the console in here.
There we go.
So if I put one here and if I put one, that was the Anex, OK, so I'm just going to reload the page.
One here, one here, one here, one here and one there.
And you can say it says that player one, of course, the reset board is not created yet.
So in order to just avoid that, we are going to say just commented out.
Now, this is when the choices is zero.
Keep this in mind.
It means that we are using this.
So we have handled the let's go ahead and let's handle the column.
So for the column, what do we have?
What are the indices?
So the index is three.
So zero one, two, three, four or five and six.
So three and six.
Now, if the choice says I'm just going to copy this just to save you some time because the ideology
is the same.
So three and six, we are going to return the same thing.
So let's just put it right here.
Pivot one point one, pivot one, point two.
So now let's create that pivot one point two.
There we go.
So we were able to do logic for that.
I'm just going to put in pivot.
I hope it makes sense.
This word pivot, if it doesn't make sure to change it with anything that makes sense to you.
Now, the next thing that I would like to do, I would like to travel diagonally to this side and I'm
going to provide
I'm going to provide one for whenever we go up and whenever we go left.
Right.
So let's go into our coat and we're going to grab what is the index of the what is the index of that?
The Spivet, the index of this Privett is the last index, which is index number eight.
Right.
So let's grab that.
And for that, we could just go ahead and copy this.
So I'm going to say pivot one and I am just going to put it here and I'm going to say pivot to.
So the index is eight.
We want to say that whenever five and two are equal.
So let's just put it to five.
That is two.
We are going to say pivot two point one.
And whenever it is seven and six, so it's going to be seven in six, we are going to say pivot two
point to perfect.
So let's go ahead and test it.
There we go, pivot two point one, reload the page
and also pivot to point to and we are done with that as well.
So this was pivot to and we will have only one other pivot.
And within that, we are going to handle diagonal movements.
So the pivot is actually going to be the center point that we have.
So let's copy that, put it here.
Let's change it to pivot three, right, and now what is the index of this?
The index is going to be force.
I'm just going to put it for now for this.
We are going to have four different conditions.
Right.
So this is not only diagonally, but also in these ways.
So first off, if it is, I'm just going to put one here.
If it is horizontal, the second one is if it is vertical from top to bottom.
This one.
This one and this one.
The third one is going from either from this diagonal diagonal to there or going diagonally to here.
Right.
So whenever you put it from in this direction, from left to right, keep in mind that right to left
is also covered.
So you don't have to provide if statements for those.
So it is for first off, we are going to get the horizontal.
So on one side of the four, we have three.
On the other side we have five.
So let's put in three and let's put in five.
Let's grab this three point one and three point two.
So on top we have one and we have seven.
So we have one and we have seven.
Perfect.
I'm going to copy it two more times.
Four diagonal movements.
All right, so diagonally we have three, so this is going to be three and this is going to be six,
so let's pass them.
And so it's three and this six, we are going to say three point three and the other diagonal is going
to be zero and eight.
So this is going to be zero and this is going to be eight and we're going to pass in three point four.
So let's save this.
So it should work in all directions.
Perfect O wins, perfect to reload the page.
It should work in this direction as well.
So I'm going to do it like this.
And it didn't work, it must it should have worked.
And player one.
OK, so what did we do here?
Players turned and we said zero.
OK, so this is private to eight, and for the eight, we had five and two and we had seven and six.
Perfect.
So for the third private, what we had was whenever it is choices four, we have three.
Oh, this is not three.
So whenever one is three.
So let's take a look at it.
Three this on one side and the other side it is five.
Perfect.
So now this is this should be working and let's put in double equals and just going to click everywhere.
And I could, I could just grab both of the quality sides.
And we could just pass in another, uh, equality sign there and another here.
And why have we done to.
I have no idea, so let's just rectify these as well.
So we have one and seven, so it is ours one.
And so this is one.
And this is seven.
And this is three.
And this is five.
Perfect.
Then we have three and six.
I don't think this is correct, so this is diagonal, right, so diagonally, this is not three, this
is two and six.
So we made a mistake here.
Well, actually, I made a mistake.
And this is correct.
Zero and eight.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
So let's check it diagonally first when it's perfect.
We are going to check it this way as well.
Wins perfect and let's check it top to bottom wins, check it sideways wins, and I think it should
win in all cases.
I mean, in this way, it wins perfect, so the only thing remaining for us is going to be handling
the reset button.
So let's go ahead and let's actually grab our reset button.
I'm not going to postpone it to another video.
We are just going to go ahead and added here.
All right, so we have our event listener and it is going to be Kleck and then we are going to call
a function that is going to be a reset board.
Right, that's commented in in here as well.
One point five seconds and let's create this function.
So it is going to be function reset board.
And we're going to grab our choices, they're going to set it to an empty array.
We are going to grab all of our boxes and we are going to say for each of them, we want to grab our
individual box and.
And that individual box is.
Inner text is going to be an empty and empty quote or an empty string, right?
And after that, we want to grab our result because whenever the game is reset it, instead of saying
who won, we want to change the results in a text to the tic tac toe.
So let's say tic tac toe.
Perfect, and finally, we want to change the current the players turn, so it's going to be a player's
turn.
It's going to be player one.
Perfect.
So let's save that and let's check it out here.
So.
There we go.
And after one point five seconds, it is going to go away and you can see it's this pivot.
One point to this should be pivot to point to point to the we.
And did it show who won?
Yep, went.
So now, uh hmm.
All right, so let's test it a few times, we can see that the player is there, the player is being
changed, and we actually we do not need to go ahead and hardcoded there.
And because each time the game is reset it, we want another player to actually play it.
So and now it is it has to be exis.
There we go.
So I think that's it and the only thing remaining here as just the restart button, which works fine,
you can just click restart it and just to restart the window.
So restart the board.
So you can see no one went there.
Yeah, except one.
So basically you can we started using this button as well.
That's it for this game and for this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.