Hi, everyone, in this we're going to implement that mouse move effect.
All right, so this is where we left off in our previous lecture, and we have all these like almost
500 of them on the screen, and you can see that they bounce off the edges of the screen and whenever
we reload the page, they do not get recreated outside the canvas.
So what the only thing remaining here is implementing that mouse move effect that we have, you know,
that we have right here before implementing that, I'm just going to resize them to their original,
which was five.
So this is what their original was.
Right.
So what we are going to do here first is I'm going to create an event listener, so I'm going to come
on top of that and I'm going to say mouse move, event listener.
Well, Senator.
Right, and we are going to add this event on the window, because whenever the mouse is moving in that
entire window, that event is going to be fired.
So we are going to say that at a listener, it's going to be mouse move, no coykendall required, no
nothing, just mouse move.
And we are going to execute this function.
First off, let me go ahead and cancel the event.
Right.
And let's say, well, let's come here.
I'm going to put it to side this console.
So now I'm just going to clear the console.
And whenever I hover on any of these balls, I haven't seen any of them.
You can see that when I hover on this entire page, it's not like I'm hovering on a specific ball.
No, it's like I'm hovering on this entire page.
Right.
You can see that this event is being fired.
And if I open up one of these here, we have an X and Y, right.
So if I were to clear this and if I come right here, so in here, we should have a small number for
X, I mean, right there.
And I'm just going to go out of it.
So you should have a small number for X and we have to have a small number for Y.
There we go.
So five pixels along the x axis and two pixels along the Y axis.
So basically this is going to give us this X and Y.
These values are going to give us the exact coordinates of where that mouse is being is actually moving.
Right.
And we can use that to our advantage.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a mouse effect.
Right, but actually, before creating this here, I need to create an object, so I'm going to say
let a mouse effect.
So this is going to be an object.
What does this object has?
Now, let's think about it first before actually implementing it.
So whenever any ball comes in, in in a close proximity to this pointer that the size of the ball is
going to get increased.
Right.
And what is actually happening here whenever any balls, because they're moving with different velocities
in in different directions, whenever anybody comes in contact to like approximately 20 pixels, the
size is going to enlarge.
Right, that's what we are going to do in this and particularly in this lecture, so whenever the ball
comes in and like comes close to this pointer, so how can the ball come?
The ball has only two dimensions, sorry, two directions that it can travel.
So one is going to be the X and the other one is going to be the Y.
So what I'm going to do is within this mouse effect object, we need to trace for the X.
And for the why so initially I'm just going to set him to undefined.
Because we don't know where actually the mouse is, that's why I'm just going to set it to undefined
initially, we are not we don't know where it is.
And how do we know where it is we are going to know where it is when we move our mass, right?
So in here, I'm just going to say mass effect.
So I'm going to select the X property from that object and I'm going to send it to IDOT X and I'm going
to do the same thing for Y.
So let's put it to I, right, and now if I go ahead and if I log to the console, the mouse effect,
let's see what we get.
So if I come here, let's change it.
And if I hover on it, you can see that we get the X and Y.
OK, so it says that, for example, right here, the Y 726, the X is five twenty for the X goes all
the way to nine thirty eight.
Y is seven 10.
So this is going to give us the, the dimensions.
But keep this in mind that if you crack open any of these objects and if you come, you can see that
this is actually an object.
And which object is that?
I can see all of these prototypes inside the protoje of this object, but this object has it has two
properties, which is which are right here.
So basically we have modified the value for the X and the value for the Y.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a maximum radius.
So I'm going to say maxcy radius and I'm going to set it to 40.
I'm going to set it to 50.
So this is the maximum size that the circles can get.
And let's sit in a mini radius.
This is the minimum radius that the circles can get.
So Maxey radius, mini radius.
I'm going to set it to five.
Right.
And after this, now, we need to implement the logic that and whenever any of the balls come close
to the pointer in the distance of 20 pixels, we want to enlarge those balls.
So when we see that we have a function of date balls here, now we have inside our constructor, we
have two methods.
The first one is actually drawing, but the second one is responsible for moving them.
Right.
So this is the function that is responsible for moving.
So inside here before this, I'm just going to come down here and I'm going to say mouse move effect.
All right.
And.
And here I'm going to say, if I give this F Mass Effect dot X, we know what that value is.
That is the value of the pointer along the extraction minus this dot, the X position of the F, the
horizontal position of the pointer when we subtract it by the horizontal position of the ball if it
is less than 20.
And now this is going to be like chaining logical operators and and if the mouse effect acts or the
horizontal position of the cursor minus.
The horizontal position of the ball.
Is greater than negative to any pixels, it means that it's less than 20 pixels all the way to greater
than 20 pixels in that in that range.
Right.
So this is for the horizontal direction, whether we want to do for the vertical, basically, we are
going to do the same thing.
So I'm just going to go ahead and copy this and I'm going to put it right here.
But there is one thing missing, and that is a logical operator right here.
So we are going to f also the Y position of the cursor minus the Y position of the circle is less than
20 pixels.
So they are close to each other and along the right side of the window.
Sorry when this is why.
So this is going to the positive is going to be towards the bottom and if it is X the positive is going
to be towards the right and also the Y position, whenever it is less than minus 20 pixels.
What do we want to do in this?
So we know that we have successfully traced that.
I'm just going to save it.
So the code for formatter, take care of take takes care of it.
And why do we want to do we want to apply that an if statement in here.
Because if this dot radius.
Now what, what is the radius.
The radius is 30.
If 30 is less than the maximum radius, the max radius, it means that we want to enlarge that circle.
It means the circle is small and we want to enlarge it.
And I'm going to say this dot radius and I'm going to enlarge it.
I'm going to add on one to it.
Right.
If elusive.
Also, the radius of the circle, which is 30, is greater than the mini radius.
What do we want to do?
We want to subtract from the radius.
So basically, we want to keep it between the radius, the radius of the circle.
We want to keep it between the mini and the max.
So this is the radius.
We are going to subtract one from it each time.
Let's save it.
Let's come here.
So this is what we have so far in here.
Let me refresh the page.
So when I hover on the circle, you can see that the circles, they get bigger, but they still they
stay big.
Right.
And.
OK, so let's hover on that, they do not get back to the normal size, they should get back to their
normal size.
So we had if the mass effect minus this Star XP is Lessner and the also greater than negative 20 pixels,
less than 20 and greater than 20 pixels.
What do we want to do?
We want to grab the radius of the radius is less than the max radius.
We are going to add to the radius.
Ancef, the radius as.
Hmm.
All right.
OK, I think the reason that it is not working is because this ownself is in the incorrect position,
because the NSF is going to be a part of this in this bigger if clause, because we have if all these
conditions are true, we want to add on to the radius.
If even one of these conditions is not true, we want to reduce the size.
So the size should not be provided within that, because if the circle is not is not close to the pointer,
we want to decrease its size.
That's why whenever I hover on them, they get increased.
For example, this blue circle, but we're in a hover away.
It doesn't get smaller.
Right.
So let's save this.
Let's come here now and see all of them.
They get smaller, they get bigger, and when they move away by tiny pixels, they're going to get smaller.
So we end up with this.
Now, this effect is going to be better if I just go going to go ahead.
And at 1000 now, I can see that we are going to get more balls in here.
What if I do like 4000 and.
So it's you can see that this is slow for me, so I'm going to change it back to 2000, for example,
let's see, it looks fine.
This is smooth and we get this kind of effect.
So whenever you hover on the circles and when the circles are in that close proximity of 20 pixels,
you're going to get big.
And when they go away by 20 pixels.
Farther than that, then they are going to get smaller automatically so we don't even have to move the
cursor to see the effect.
See, there we go.
So this is going to be it, I'm just going to set it to 1000, I think that's better.
That's it for this project and for this chapter.
And before wrapping this up, I want to say something that.
Starting our next game, starting our next actual game.
All right, these were actually some things that I needed to do in order to, like, solidify this,
the foundation of game development.
And starting from our next chapter where we started, our first game is going to be Pong Ping Pong,
and we are going to play against an A.I..
All right.
And it's going to be a very simple eye.
It's not going to be like crazy mathematics.
No, not something like that.
That's not something that I want to do in this course, because for that, we need to dedicate a complete
course, not just to do it as a part of another course, like complete A.I. development training and
all that.
That's basically another course.
But what I want to do is I just want to create that game and I want to implement it by like I want to
go against an AI and we are going to implement an intelligence level for that, because if if we play
against the AI, the AI is never going to lose.
I mean, that's just like a fact.
You can't win and we can just only win that game.
I've created that.
So I'm just giving you like a mental idea of what the game is going to be like.
And if we play the game against the AI when it is in its full power, we will never be able to beat
it.
I mean, the pong, we will never even be able to score one.
And the reason that I'm saying all this is because starting from our Pong game until the end of this
course, until our last project, I haven't created that yet.
I don't know what that's going to be.
I have an idea and I'm not going to give away the spoilers or the surprise.
I'm not going to give you that.
I'm just going to work on that.
And I expect you to to be to follow what I'm saying, because we have done a lot of projects.
This was our project for three.
We have completed 61 chapters.
Aside from the course introduction, we have completed 60 chapters where we have talked about a lot
of beginner intermediate and a ton of advanced stuff.
And we have covered literally everything you will ever need when it comes to JavaScript.
The theory for that, the practicality of that, and if there is anything that you're not feeling comfortable
with, the course is at your disposal.
Go back to whichever chapter or whichever lesson it is that you think that you have not gotten gotten
the full grasp on the topics, that sort of thing.
Because when we get to our next game, next chapter, when we start actual game development, there
is going to be a lot of ideas that are going to be interconnected.
And I'm not going to be explaining, like, how a for loop works or how a form of work works or how,
if else statements they work, how functions work.
Now, we have covered all of that and I do not want to go over that anymore because there are a lot
of new stuff that we need to cover.
And as far as the collision detection is concerned, like bouncing off the changing the direction and
changing the velocity, these are the very, very beginner stuff that we have done like in the past
for projects, including this one has three projects.
And this one and I'm not going to be going over like in depth.
Of course, I will be explaining that, but not in that depth.
And I expect you to follow.
And and I just want to say that what I'm trying to say is when I created these games, I've created
two of them.
So the next one is going to be the Kinect for a game, which is which has like a ton of game game development
logic, which is really fun when I created these two games and they're going to be like a couple of
a couple more, I assumed that your level is advanced to experts.
You know, I've not assumed that your level is beginner.
Your JavaScript knowledge level is beginner.
I have not even assumed that your JavaScript level knowledge is even intermediate.
I have assumed that it is advanced transitioning to expert.
So that's how would that mental mindset is how I created those games, those games and how I'm intending
to create the upcoming games right after that, as many as there might be.
All right.
So I just wanted to say that and I do not want to scare me away.
I just want to show you what the true power of JavaScript is in code, what is the power of code and
what you can really build with code.
Right, and again, if there is anything that you think that there are like uncertainties, just go
back to it just just just like brush over that knowledge.
And after that, come with me to the next lecture.
Well, we will create our very interesting game, which is the Pung.
So see you guys then.