Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to create the character type assessment.
All right, so what do we need to do is I'm going to come down here and I'm going to create a comment,
in fact, I'm going to paste it here.
So we are going to say character type assessment.
So what is the type?
The type could be upper case.
Could be lower case.
Could be a special character or a number.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create that function here.
So let's say function, character, type, assess meant what is the parameters, what are the parameters
that this is going to take in?
We know that this is going to grab a password that is necessary.
Now, you might be asking how do you know which parameter a function takes?
Because this is like sort of confusing as well.
Sometimes, of course.
Are you whenever you create this kind of universal functions, you need to think about what the function
is going to do when you know what the function is going to do, what task the function is going to accomplish.
So what is that task in this case?
The task is to grab at a regular expression and match it and match.
All right.
That to a certain criteria and then return a certain message and do a certain strength lost.
Right.
So we do multiple things.
But what are the most important things?
Some things like this returning this, it has nothing to do with this parameter, right?
Only this part has not this entire return.
Right.
This character match doesn't have anything to do with it, but this regular expression does.
So let's go ahead.
That's why I created both of the function.
Take a look at the similarities and take a look at the differences.
That's one other way you can tell where there is a difference.
Just pass it as an asset, as a parameter so you can see that this match is different than this one
and these regular expressions are different.
So we are going to have a regular expression for a number that is going to be different than this.
So this second parameter is going to be a regular expression because it is different.
So it is the second what is the third parameter that is different?
So character length is the same here, here, here.
That is the same.
Right.
The return is the same password checkers the same strength last values, the same strength last here
and here.
But where is the difference.
The difference lies in the key for the password check.
You can see that it says in here it says lower case and in here it says uppercase.
So this lowercase, an uppercase actually specify the type of assessment.
Right, the type of assessment, that's why this function is called character type assessment, so I'm
going to I'm going to run another I'm going to put in another parameter that is assessment type.
And now you will see how actually this works.
So I'm going to grab this entire thing and I'm going to paste the right here.
So now we do have our password, but not we no longer hard code this match because this regular expression
is going to be fed wherever this character type is called.
This is one of the fundamental use cases of a function they can be used to.
They can be called multiple times.
We're going to call this function four times.
So now this regular expression is passed.
It means if the character type assessment function is called within the uppercase, what is the context
of this function?
It is going to be uppercase.
What is the regular expression of this function?
It is going to be the regular expression for the uppercase.
What is going to be the assessment type?
The assessment type is going to be uppercase.
So I'm just going to grab that.
And in here, what we are actually going to do is I'm going to we are going to grab this entire these
quotes and we are going to convert them to back to X, right.
Because we are going to use a template literals.
So let's grab this.
And dollar sign.
OK, so in here, we are going to pass in our assessment type, so what what is the assessment in this
context?
It is going to be upper case in this context, it is going to be Lorqess.
Very simple.
So now let's grab this type.
Let's put it right here as well, but this is not a template literal, so let's convert it to that and
this tactic.
So let's do that.
And we can see that all the three parameters, they have been passed inside the code because the strength
lost for all of our cases, it's going to be five percent in the case of less than two.
And in the case of zero, it's going to be 20 percent.
We don't change that.
So now we don't need all this code here.
What do we need here?
We are not going to need all this code here as well.
You can see that how much simpler this is.
The only thing that we need here is just to call this character type assessment function, character
type assessment function and pass in three arguments because we have three parameters.
We need three arguments.
So what is the first argument?
We know that it is password, right?
So the first one, it is going to be password.
And then the second one says it should be ready.
So what is the regular expression for this?
Let's passino regular expression right here.
So for the lower case, we go A to Z and we grab all occurrences of that.
And what is the third one?
Which is the assessment.
So in case this character, this is called in the context of lower case, we should say password has
no lower case characters.
So I'm just going to pass in a string lower case characters.
And I'm going to do the same thing for this one, except this one is going to be the same.
But what about the regular expression?
The regular expression is going to be different.
This regular expression is it is an argument is going to be passed here and then it is going to be part
right here.
And then this entire character type assessment is going to convert to uppercase.
So let's change this to uppercase.
See, we have we call this function multiple times.
It's very simple.
And now you can see this code is much cleaner.
And now let's check it out, see if I do one, too.
We get.
Password is too short.
Why don't we get this uppercase characters we have called this character type function?
We should get that so is our regular expression, oh, this should be inside brackets, certainly not
curly braces, just inside brackets.
Let's put this one inside brackets as well.
So now if I say one, two, it is still going to give me that.
So now let's see if if these functions are being called at all, so I'm going to say concern of lock
one, two, three.
I'm going to say uppercase, uppercase.
And for this one, we are going to say console does log lowercase.
So if I yeah, we do call them uppercase and lowercase, so it's this character match an assessment
P W.D. and, uh.
Hmm.
We should call it here.
I'm not sure what's wrong in here.
So it is going to be called here and we do call it here.
But this message is not being printed out.
So if I were to say character match password, I think that's because it's CONSED, it doesn't let it
change it.
So Consed.
Save it to still get upper case and the events are firing, but we and these functions are firing,
but there is something missing in here and I'm not sure what it is that I am missing.
So we do we do have our brackets character match.
It is not being called here.
Character match does length and.
All right, so this council log works, so.
Wee wee, wee, wee, wee, it worked.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to get rid of this council log and this one and.
I'm going to log this character much as well so it becomes a log character match and I'm going to convert
this back to CONSED because we didn't have any error.
That's like this, so if I do want to, because the regular expression does not match, we get an empty
array.
But what of the regular expression matches?
So if I say, Ben, we can see that we get this lower case, so this function is working properly.
But the problem is with this.
With this return object, this return object doesn't work.
This part works, this this if statement doesn't work, we know that much because we can see the lower
case.
And if I do see video, we can see the upper case as well.
So it is grabbing it and putting it inside this character, much of this array, but it is not calling
it.
So if I come here, we have called the function here and the function is called here.
But so what what what does this function do?
This function is just calling it.
This is not correct.
We need to return this function.
All right.
So let's return it, because this function should do something.
We want to return that function.
So let's save it and let's do who.
And now we get our no uppercase characters because we have to now because we have two lower case characters.
It says it could use more lowercase characters and Password has no uppercase characters.
If I said W.H, then it is going to have it must have more lowercase characters and it must have more
uppercase characters.
And I could say like we and we and now it says it could be longer.
And now we can see that if I increase, if I remove this or add to it, you can see that how the strength
is is changing.
All right.
So the problem was, was with this one, with this keyword, that we didn't return anything from the
function.
Basically, the function didn't do anything.
It just invoked this function and didn't do anything else.
The function didn't pass these lowercase D parameters, the regular expression, this one and this password
didn't do anything.
The function just called this function.
But we need to return it so it does actually something.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
In the next lecture, we are going to wrap this project up by completing the numbers and special and
repeat character assessments.
See you guys then.