Hi, everyone, in this that we working to make the toolbar functional.
All right, so we have covered so far this, but we have we cannot increase the stroke with we cannot
change the color, we cannot update this number and we cannot, of course, clear.
So these are the things that hopefully we will cover in this lecture.
The first thing that I want to do as I'm going to grab our increase button.
So I'm just going to I'm just going to comment it and we are going to say increase between now the increased
PETN is already selected and the JavaScript and we are going to add an event.
Listener driven listener is, of course, going to be click and when the user clicks, we are going
to run a function.
Now, usually this is not for for the most part, not always.
For the most part, this is not an optimum way of doing even listeners.
Of course, when there is like there are two scenarios.
The first scenario is we used fat arrow functions, which I do not like calling them fat, just I'm
just going to be calling them error functions.
That conveys the point.
And the second thing is, whenever we use whenever we do event listeners, we usually call the function
here.
We just write their function name and we specify or we write the function down here or up there.
Right.
So we usually do that whenever we have a lot of lines of code inside our event.
Listener, that is a more cleaner way of doing JavaScript.
But for the purposes of these beginner to intermediate level projects that we're working now, this
is going to do fine.
So whenever we click on the increase button, what do we want to do is we want to increase the size
and each time.
Now, here is the fun part.
So if you want to click on this plus sign and you want to increase this by one, you just add to the
size one.
So you just say plus equal to one.
That said, if you want to add five to it, whenever you click this plus sine you want to add five,
you just going to say five.
But we want incremented one by one.
But there is going to be a level, there is going to be a limit to the amount of instrumentation that
we are going to implement and the level is going to be sorry, the limit is going to be 50.
So if it is above 50, we want to keep it at 50.
So, for example, if the user wants to go above 50, like 60, 70, we are not going to allow the user
to go above that.
So we are going to keep it at that.
So if size is greater than 50, this is where programmed logic comes in.
If size is greater than 50, we are going to keep the size at 50.
That's it.
So this is the increase button.
Let's go ahead and let's see if it actually works.
So now I'm just going to click on it and we see this line is thicker already.
So let's click a bit more.
And now this line is thicker, very visual.
This is a good thing.
And now this line is thicker.
Of course, there are some problems with this.
We are not updating this number, which we are going to get to it later in this video or in the next
video.
So this is going to be the increase button.
The next one is the decrease BTN.
We are going to grab the decrease button and we are going to add an event listener.
And again, we are listening for a click.
We are going to run a function and the function is going to decrease the size by one.
So we, we want to increase the size by one.
Each time we click on the plus side and in the same manner, we want to decrease the size by one whenever
we click on the negative side.
So we are going to say size is equal to is going to be equal to one, but there is also going to be
a limit.
So we need to control the flow here.
Whenever the size is less than one, the size is less than one.
We do not want to go there.
That's why we are going to keep the size at.
One, all right, so the user cannot go less than one.
So whenever I refresh the page, the size is going to be 10.
So let's try it.
Hi, this is ten now.
Oh, this should be one.
So you can see this is the difference, right.
So we have successfully implemented the increase button and the decrease button.
However, we cannot go away.
We cannot.
So far, we are not able to update our increment on the screen, right, and now let's go ahead and
let's create that function here as well.
So updating updating the stroke with.
Dynamically, dynamically her, right, so we are going to create a function and we are going to say
update size, right?
And we are not going to pass in any parameter what we are going to do is we are going to grab our stroke
thickness, which we have selected right here.
This is a stroke thickness, which is the size and the size is this number right here.
So this number is initially 10, but we want to update it to 11.
If the user clicks on the plus sign once or to nine if the user clicks on the negative sign once.
Right.
Meaning that whenever the user clicks on either of the increase or decrease button, we want to update
that number accordingly.
So the way we can do that is we are going to grab the stroke thickness and we are going to say inor
text.
In their text, there are three N's, make sure you spell it correctly and we are going to set it to
Sise save it.
Let's come here.
So when I click on this, it doesn't show anything.
And the reason for that is we have not called this function.
So this is a good point because this function is asleep right now.
We need to wake it up.
So in order to wake it up, we are going to come into our increase button and we are going to say update
size and we are just going to call it fair and also call it here.
So let's provide a space here.
Let's save it.
So now this function is called here and the function is called right here.
So it's klegg, it still does not work, so we have to update size.
Stroke thickness there.
All right, so stroke thickness in her text, make sure you spell it correctly, so let's klegg.
This is this is working.
So now the size is going to be 26.
This is 26.
This is 36.
Bigger, of course.
Let's go all the way to 50.
So we need to check at the boundary as well.
So this is 50 and it doesn't matter.
OK, leave it.
It doesn't matter how many, many more times the user is going to click, it's not going to increase
beyond that.
And let's go all the way to one.
Let's see if it goes below one, which you have specified it should not go and let's see if it does
so.
C, it does not go below one and this is one.
So these functionalities there are done.
The only thing remaining here, actually the only two things remaining here is whenever we change the
color here, we want the strokes style to take on this color.
All right.
And the colors to change to this.
And whenever we click on the clear, we want to clear all of the all of the canvas, which we are going
to implement in our next lecture.
See you guys then.