Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to instantiate our classes.
All right, so first off, before doing that, let's go ahead and let's log to the console, what we
are going to get.
So superhero name, we have superhero universe, superhero power.
Where is it?
There we go.
So if I click, if I see Superman and say DC and say Fly click, we get Superman D.C. fly.
So we were successfully, successfully able to grab the content that the user is writing.
Now, what we need to do is just grab this content and put it right here.
I mean, like saying it is way easier than actually implementing it.
All right.
So first off, what we are going to do is we are going to instantiate.
Yeah, yeah.
I said it instantiating this is the correct verb that you have to do the you have to say whenever you
want to, like, wake a class up like that sort of thing.
So it's instantiating the superhero entry and class.
So I'm going to say const entry.
Okay, come on buddy.
Const entry and I'm going to say new.
We know what new is, what new does.
I'm not going to go over it any more.
We are going to say superhero entry and now this superhero true class has been instantiated.
OK, and the next thing that I want to do is I want to instantiate the superhero list as well.
So superhero list, let's come down here.
We are going to say consed last new superhero list.
Perfect.
This has been instantiated as well.
All right.
Now, what I'm going to do here, because we still have time, is I want to go ahead and I want to create
our very first method, our very first function for the superhero list right in here.
So now that the superhero list has been instantiated, we can go ahead and set list dot at Super Hero.
I know we have not called it yet, but we sorry, we have not defined it yet, but we can call it here.
Right.
So this is going to be the first method of this superhero list class, which is this one.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come come in here.
Now, before going there, I just want to console logit, I want to console less, let's see what we
are going to get.
So if I click on this list, that ad is not a function ad super.
We have not defined it.
So let's go ahead and let's define so in here.
I'm going to say ad super hero and we are going to pass an entry excuse me, because.
Ah OK.
So the reason that we are going to pass an entry because that entry is actually an instance of the superhero
entry class and we have we have said that the superhero name and the superhero universe and power,
we have said this, that these so the values for these are actually going to be supplemented from here,
instantiated into entry.
And they are going to go up there.
Right.
So.
Now, this is not going to work like this because we need to pass and the arguments as well, so the
arguments for these is going to be a superhero name.
I'm just going to copy it so you know, where where they're coming from.
So it's going to be a superhero name.
And now you can see that they are being highlighted because we are calling them when it calls something
in JavaScript is going to it tends to wake up.
So now, whenever we say superhero name is Superman, Superman is going to come down here and then in
the instance of this superhero entry and this instance of this superhero entry is going to pass it all
the way here.
And we are going to say this superhero name is going to be Superman.
So this in this case is going to be pointing to is going to have a value of Superman.
All right.
So that's going to be actually ad for this one in the next lecture.
I'm going to create this ad superhero entry, and I hope I'm not going too fast for you.
That's why we are breaking down these lectures.
See you guys in the next chapter.
Next lecture.