Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we are going to implement the highlighting functionality.
All right, so so far we have created the frame, the bottom of the frame, this is the circle, which
is the thing that is in the middle of the cell.
That is this entire thing, the circle that is being highlighted.
But the highlight functionality is still missing.
So what I'm what I am going to do is let's come down towards our new game.
There it is.
So on top of the new game, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create the highlight.
Highlight what was the name was the highlight, great function, so let me just say highlight great
function.
So let's create that as well here.
OK, so we are going to say function, highlight grid.
And we are going to pass in the event object here as well.
So what are we going to do at first is I just want this to return.
I just wanted to return something and I'm just going to go ahead.
And you know what?
We are going to first test it.
So we are going to test if it is not player's turn.
Players turn and if it is not, game over.
If it is not players term and if it is game over, then we just want to return.
We do not want to highlight anything.
So whenever the game is over now, I did not play this completely.
So if the game was supposed to be like, oops, the computer won there, so if the game is over, then
the highlighting is not going to work.
And if it is not any player's turn, then it is the highlighting is not going to work.
And we we would just returned from the game.
But I'm going to come in this one out.
We are going to commented and later.
Let's create the highlight cell function for the highlights, so we are going to pass in the IDOT Client
X for the exposition and the IDOT client Y for the Y position.
Let's save that and let's go ahead and let's create the highlight cell function.
So I'm going to come on top of that highlight.
Great.
So there we go.
And I'm going to create the highlight cell function.
So let's say function highlight cell now because it's got two arguments we need to pass in two parameters.
So we're going to pass in the X coordinate and the Y coordinate.
And now first off, we have to identify which column is empty.
Now, keep in mind, whenever we hover on it, whichever column is empty, that column is going to specify
whether it is null or not.
It means that do we have even an empty column?
If we don't have, then we should not put in any highlighting.
So first off, and we need to grab the column now and I'm going to set it to null and I'm going to I'm
going to right here identify the chosen column.
And now let's loop over the rows.
Right.
So we are going to say for that row of gret, what do we have within rows?
Within rows we have cells.
So let's sell off row.
First off, let's clear all the existing highlighting, clear the existing Hai Lai.
Think so you're going to grab the cell and we are going to grab the highlight now, this highlight is
going to come from our class constructor class and we are going to set it to know and then let's get
the collar, get the column, and we're going to say if the cells position contains the X and Y, we
are going to create the contents function as well.
If it is if it contains the X and Y coordinates, we are going to say the column is cell column.
Perfect.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to our constructor and I'm going to create that contains
function.
Right, so.
Perfect, so where is our constructor or constructor is right here and now let's go ahead and let's
create that contains function, so contains function and I'm going to say contains.
And is it the same, the spelling?
It's this and it's click on it.
I mean, do we get that?
Yeah, the that is the same.
So let's go up.
So we need to pass on the X and Y coordinates, right, so X and Y.
Perfect, what is going to be the X and Y, so we want this function to return if X is greater than
the disk, the left position, if X is greater than the left position, and when the X is also less
than the right position and you might say, OK, what does this actually mean?
Greater than the left, less than the right.
So in this case, if the X is right here, it should be greater than the left and this is the left.
So it starts to go all the way to here and it should be less than the right.
So greater than the left is this way.
Less than right is this way.
It means we should always stay within the range.
And also, we need to do the same thing for the wider direction, so the Y it should be greater this
the TARP, we should come towards the bottom, but we should keep in mind that it should always be less
than the this dot bottom.
So we just want our this function to return this.
Let's save it so it returns X is greater than this, the left and X is less than this dot, right?
Why is greater than this top and why is also greater than this bottom?
All right, so we have specified the range for columns.
I'm going to come to reserve function due to the highlighted cell function, and I'm going to go out
of that this loop.
So where does it end?
It ends there.
And I'm going to put in a comment and I'm going to say that even with all of this, if no column is
chosen.
OK, if a no column is still chosen, we want to we want to return from the from the function.
So we are going to say a column is equal to is equal to no.
It means there is no column.
We want to return from the function.
All right, so how this actually highlighting is going to work now, we know that we want to highlight
something, how how would this actually work?
We want the highlighting to start from the bottom.
So so if I if I hover on this column, you can see that the highlighting starts from the bottom.
It doesn't matter where I highlight even on this one, on itself or on the top or on the part of the
self from it.
The highlighting should always work, should always start from the bottom.
It means that.
I'm just going to write the comment, highlight the first on Que PIDE cell, it means that we are going
to reverse and we are going to use a reverse for a loop.
So for the reverse for loop, we are going to set the eye should start from the first from the last
row.
So we are going to pass in minus one and the I should go to top all the way until it is greater than
or equal to zero and we are going to decrement the R each time by one.
Now we are also going to say if the great role I and the great column you remember this dot owner equals
now, then we want to highlight Rutt.
So if the owner is not, it means there is no owner we want to grab that creates the column and that's
specific.
The specific road, the specific column, which is J.
And we want to call that highlight and we are going to say that whichever player's turn it might be
and then let's return that gret.
Because we are going to highlight the column, not any specific row I'm going to pass in the column
right here, and this column is this column that we have specified as not previously.
And finally, let's return from this function.
So if still nothing is highlighted, it means that the function doesn't need to run, the function doesn't
return anything, and it returns to normal.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
And Jay is not defined at the highlights of this.
Jay should be our column.
So let's pass and the column.
Let's hover on it.
We don't see any highlighting.
I mean, have we?
We have the highlights.
Well, we have called the highlights cell right here.
And let me just do this.
If it is not oh, this is this only works if it is player's turn.
OK, so let's see.
So we have set for Aulet.
We want the it start to at the bottom row.
And we wanted to go all the way to greater and equal to zero, and then we want to dichromate we diclemente
and we say if the great column owner equals no, we want to grab the Gretz column, the highlight,
and we are going to specify it as the players turn.
And then we want to return that.
And finally, we are going to return the return null if nothing is highlighted.
Let's see if I if I have spelled this highlight correctly.
So we have highlight's cell for letter of great, cell of RO.
And if cell that contains X and Y, you are going to say cells that call and all right, so if column
is no return that.
OK, so let's come here.
We don't see anything and there is no air, so something is missing.
That's why we don't see any errors there.
OK, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to our new game function and I'm going to create a
coin toss situation just to make sure that it is a player's turn or it is not a player's turn randomly.
So I'm going to say coin toss and I'm going to say player's turn is math dot a random.
Tones less than zero point five, so if it is the player's turn, if it if it if it returns zero and
we can say safely say that zero point five is greater than zero, it returns true.
If it returns one, we can safely say that one is not less than zero point five and it is going to return
false.
So we are also going to grab the game over.
We are going to set it to false because the game is not over and we are going to grab the game tied.
We are going to set it to false.
Let's save that.
So with this in place, we should be able to see some highlighting.
So you can see now it is the r e player.
If I refresh the page, it is still that because it is randomly now you can see that it has changed.
The reason that it changes is because I'm just reloading with the five key.
I'm not coming actually here and reloading it.
So it's orange claque, it's green, kaleck, orange kaleck, green claque, green again and again.
Green, orange you can see.
So it is going to give us some highlighting there.
The next thing that I want to do is I want to create the actually the click function.
Right.
So the click function, we are going to create it right after the game.
Variables that we had.
Right.
So let's go on top, where is our game variables, so the game variables, these event listeners are
just going to create the click function right there.
OK, so we are going to grab our canvas.
Element, and we are going to say that out of a listener, that at a wellness center and we are going
to listen for a click and when we hear the click, we are going to create the click function.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's actually create the click function words or create grid.
There it is.
So in here I'm going to say click function.
So this click function is going to handle that selecting or selection of the cell.
So whenever you come like this, if you click, you can see the cell has been selected.
So the click function is actually going to handle that.
First off, let's go ahead and create that function click.
And first off, we need to check if the game is over or not.
So if game over, if the game is over, we don't want to be able to click anywhere.
Right.
So we just want to call a new game and then we will return from this function.
If if it is if the game is not over, then we need to check if it is player's turn or if it is not the
plaster, if it is the player's turn.
Player's turn.
It doesn't matter which player, the other player, the other player should not be able to click.
Or to select a specific cell.
So we are going to see if it is not player's turn return, right?
So we just return.
But I'm going to come in this one out for now.
OK, I'm just going to go ahead and commented out.
And then we are going to call our select.
Select cell function as well, right?
So what I'm going to do next is going to be let's go ahead and let's create that select cell function.
All right, so I'm going to come down here on top of the dimensions way down, and we need to create
our select cell function.
All right, so let's say select cell function.
OK, so we are going to write function, if I can spell it correctly, come on.
One f perfect.
Select, not interval, select sell, and there is not going to be any parameters for that.
OK, so what do we want to do?
Whenever we want to select a sell, we want the highlighting to go away.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's grab our highlighting.
Highlighting.
And you are going to set it to false.
All right, so.
Let's create a loop, so we are going to loop over all of these cells in our rows, so we are going
to say for that row of grid and then we are going to say for that row of.
Where is.
Is row for that cell of row, so we are iterating over all of them, if the highlighting is not if the
cell doesn't have any any preexisting highlight, it means the highlight of that cell is equal to.
Then we want to be able to highlight that.
So we are going to grab the highlighting and we are going to say true, and then we are going to grab
the highlighting of the cell.
We need to set it to once more.
So highlight should be cool to know right after we said the highlighting to true, we are going to remove
the highlight highlight from the cell and then we need to specify the owners of cell.
That owner is going to whichever whichever player is, whichever player is playing.
So we remove that player's turn.
And finally, we need to check for a win, so I'm going to create a function here.
I'm going to call it a function check when we are going to create that and we are going to grab the
rows and the columns, which we have specified before.
And whenever we need to check right after that, we are going to grab our game over and we are going
to set it to true.
Now, this is going to be one iteration of this loop.
And with this one iteration, the loop is going to be done.
And we need to break out of this iteration so we can go to the next iteration.
There is a key word called Alattar that we can use to break out of this loop.
And we need to reference that to to whichever loop it is that we are breaking out of it.
So we are breaking out of that loop.
So we are going to say that with this iteration, we just want to break out of it.
All right, and let's let's go ahead, where does this loop and it ends right there and whenever.
Whenever we are selecting something, we should not allow the highlighting to work as well.
So when we selected a specific cell, we do not want the highlighting to work.
So I'm just going to say do not allow.
Selection, I told you that the logic is pretty advanced for this game, this game might seem easy,
but the logic behind it there is like a lot of a lot of things that we need to consider for this to
game.
It seems like a very simple game.
You just connect four dots.
But but there is a lot of things that you're not allowed to do whenever it is the computers turn or
whenever it is someone else's turn, if there is a right, if there is no highlighting.
Right.
So if there is no highlighting, we do not want to tell, if there is no highlighting, we do not want
to allow any selection.
So if there is, the highlighting is not true.
We want to return from this function as well.
And finally, what we want to do here is let's go ahead and let's switch the player, OK?
So we are going to say switch the player
if there is no game over.
If the players are playing and if it if one player has selected a cell, we want to switch to the next
player until the game is over.
So if it is, the game over is not true.
It means the game is not over.
We want to switch to the player.
And it is very simple.
We just say player.
Players turn should not be players turn it mean whichever player is playing, we just want to switch
that right after the highlight, this selecting happens.
So the next thing that we need to do is actually go ahead and create the win the Czech win function.
Right.
And I'm going to go on top and I'm going to create that function as well in this video.
OK, so I'm going to create it right here and I'm going to say check when function for now, I'm not
going to do anything special with this function.
So let's grab the check when and I'm going to pass in the row because the row is going to be the cell,
that road that we called it as an argument.
And we're going to grab the parameter of columns.
Well, for now, I just wanted to return false.
We don't want to check for if there is any any of the players, they have one or not.
So you can see that if I go ahead and if I click, I can click for instead of the computer as well,
because we have not created the A.I. for this yet.
We are going to create it eventually.
So it is going to switch.
So when it is the players turn, then it is not the player's turn, player's turn, not the player.
So each time that I click it is going to give me a different circle.
OK, there we go.
So we can select this, we are not checking for any or any of these cells to win or not.
So now we can see that no selection is allowed anyway.
And right after this is completed and there is no definite winner, we would show the game is tied or
draw or something or something like that.
So with that, this lecture comes to an end.
See you guys in the next one.