Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to detect the collision.
All right, so what it is actually that we are going to do in this lecture, what we're going to do
as first off, they're going to detect collision for the for the bottom and then.
Right, because they're positive, they're simpler and then top and then left.
Right.
So if I come in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to detect the collision inside this run game
because this run game is the function that is being run or called 60 times per one second.
So I'm going to call it collision.
Detection, right?
So now first F, now F F the vertical, the no, consider what's in charge of moving this ball.
It's the vertical velocity now of the vertical velocity.
First off, we are going to check it for the bottom.
So if the vertical velocity is greater than zero, what does it mean?
It means that the ball is moving towards the bottom right.
And we are going to use logical end operator and the vertical position is greater than the canvas height.
All right, then, what do we want to do?
We want to reverse the velocity.
So when it hits this edge, canvases, that height is going to give us this edge, this bottom part
of the canvas.
When it hits that bottom part of the canvas, we just want to move it back, bounce it back.
So let's convert that code.
So bottom boundary, perfect.
So for the bottom boundary, the ball has to be moving towards the bottom.
So for that to be moving toward the bottom, the Y.
V should be greater than zero.
If it is less than zero, it means the velocity is negative.
When the velocity is negative, which direction that is, does it move?
It moves to the top direction.
And so both of the expressions should be true for this.
If statement to run and the Y.
P has to be if it is greater than remember or equal to canvases, canvasses, height minus the radius.
We did this in our previous lecture.
If this is the condition, what do we want to do?
If this is the condition, it means that the ball has touched the bottom of the canvas, what do we
want to do?
We want to reverse the direction of the velocity.
Very, very simple.
So the wive is equal, is going to be equal to negative YV we just want to reverse it.
So let's say let's check it out if it actually works.
Boom.
There we go.
So you can see when it hits the bottom, it deflects back in that in any direction that it is, that
that is going to make sense.
You don't have to worry about in which direction it goes.
Just reverse the direction and JavaScript engine is going to take care of it.
Boom.
There we go.
So that's the bottom boundary, and next, I'm going to do the right boundary.
So our Eigsti boundary, it's almost the same as what we did in our previous project, except that we
are checking if the ball is moving in that direction, if it is not moving in that direction, we don't
want to do anything.
That's why we are going to have four stand alone if statements.
So let's just provide some dots there, because these are the headlines or these are the things that
we're doing.
This if statement is a part of this collision detection, I don't want to miss anything up here.
So.
Right.
Boundry.
So f the same thing again.
F the X velocity is greater than zero.
It means that the ball excuse me, the ball is moving to the right.
So when the ball is moving to the right and the horizontal position of the ball is greater than the
canvas.
Allen.
Alan, come on, canvas elements with minus the radius, then what do we want to do?
So in this case, the ball is moving to the right when it hits the canvas.
We want it to move.
We want to move it back.
So what do we want to do?
We just reverse the direction of the velocity.
X, v, so let's check it out.
So it should reflect back the country so it doesn't go off the side of the screen anymore, so boom,
see, it deflects back.
Check it out one more time.
Come on.
Give me, like, a straight one.
Yeah.
Come on, buddy.
Come on.
OK, better one better.
Oh, that was better.
We lost it.
I mean, this works as well, so when it hits it, it deflects back.
Bounces back.
So we are done with the bottom and the right, and now we are going to go to Tom Boundry, so we are
going to say F now for the top.
First off, we need to check that the ball, the velocity is in the in that direction is headed in that
direction.
So we say if y if AYP is less than zero.
So when the velocity of that's the that's the position when the velocity is less than zero, it means
the velocity is negative, negative.
It's moving towards the top.
And the vertical position which is the Y p is less than or equal to radius.
We did this that in the previous lecture.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to grab the Y v and we are going to reverse its direction y
v and you know what?
I'm going to I'm going to test it and then we're going to do this.
So so this to work.
There we go.
So it hits it and bounces back and it goes to the left.
So left boundary f first off, let's check if the ball is moving in that direction.
So if X V is less than zero, it means the ball is moving to the left.
What do we want to do?
We want to check if the ball is moving to the left.
And also or as well, we want to check if the position of the X is less than or equal to radius.
It means that the ball has gone off the canvas.
We don't want it to go off the canvas.
That's why we provide a condition and we say just grab our velocity and reverse the direction of the
velocity.
That's it.
Check it out.
Let's watch this.
So bounces off.
Bounces off.
Bounce back, bounce back.
There we go, bounces back.
So I'm going to check this out.
You can see that we could go faster.
I could go like two oh one, which is going to be really fast.
See, it's this is how it is going to look like, so this is just to test that all the boundaries,
they work perfectly fine.
I mean, we could do, like, not that crazy fast.
We could do like five oh one.
And.
All the boundaries, they work well and it and when it hits a collision part now, the collision has
been defined on these four edges when it hits any collision point.
Then it bounces in an angle that makes the most sense that you don't have to care about, that JavaScript
engine is going to do it for you, not JavaScript is going to understand, OK, in which which direction
should I bounce off?
So whenever it hits this and if the direction is like this, it is going to go this way.
So that's the sensible way of going it going about it.
Right.
So some of the physics that we have added to the canvas should be added by by US developers.
Some very, very minor parts have been added by JavaScript itself.
So we don't have to really worry about everything.
You can see that we just reverse the direction and it does everything else on itself.
When it hits here, it should go in this direction.
But but it actually goes in a diagonal way, right?
Because that is the logical way of going.
So there we go, all the edges are perfectly bouncy.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to check if it actually bounces off the edges, not anywhere.
So I'm just going to say one and I'm going to say one.
And I'm going to say for both of them, I'm going to say zero point five, that's so it has it's going
to be very slow.
It's actually going to be really slow, so let's convert it to five.
So it.
Come on, buddy, it's not even moving one inch.
So I was going to return that.
I'm just going to give it like a 10 here.
And it's 10:00 here, so now it should be moving, but, oh, right, it's very slow.
50 maybe.
I just want to make sure that it truly bounces off the edge.
Oh, come on.
All right.
Boom bounces off the edge.
And it should be perfect.
It shouldn't be even one pixel off.
If it is one pixel off, then it means that the user experience is going to be not that good because
users are really good at games like we are good at games.
We are good at pointing out mistakes in other people's, I don't know, whatever, and that's not going
to be a good user experience.
So you can see that it bounces perfectly off the edges.
So with that, Don, I'm just going to convert it back to to a one.
I think it's proper speed.
And that's it for this lecture and for this project.
In the next project, we are going to create a fantastic effect and we are going to dive into more of
these at this collision detection.
And I'm going to show you how you can do object oriented programming for game development.
It's going to be a small project, but I'm going to give you a template, basically a template to be
able to create games using the object oriented paradigm of JavaScript.
That's it.
See you guys then.