Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to display our matches to the screen.
All right, so this is where we are working with here, and I'm just going to create a constant first
here because I'm going to call this find matches function in here and I'm going to say, hmm, matches
array.
Right.
And OK, what should I call this calling is really, really, really difficult and find I'm just going
to call it find a right and let's call that function, find matches.
So what are you going to be the arguments?
The first argument is going to be our word to match.
And then so the this array is going to be the same.
So I'm just going to pass it right here.
So the word to match is going to be a bit trickier to to do.
So, first off, I'm going to do a Consolo, so you really understand what it is that we are working
with.
So here we have this keyword.
So what is the this keyword is going to point out whenever I save this and I go back to the screen.
So the this keyword, whenever we want to find what it points are, we need to go to where this has
been called so that this keyword has been called inside the display matches function.
Where is the function called for?
This display matches the function call is right here or right here.
Doesn't really matter.
And what does this function has been called on?
It's desertion, but so that this value is actually going to be search input that value.
So if I come here.
All right, so if I just go here and if I type new, you can see that we get and we get an EWR.
So each time we type something, I'm just going to clear this.
So if I type and we get NCW space Y or ARC, you get the point right.
So this is going to show us how the user is going to be searching.
Right.
So when the user types and all these cities and states that have an inside their name, they're going
to show when the user types the E in front of the name, then the search.
Each time the user types something, the search result is going to get narrower and narrower and narrower.
Right.
And we know what the this value is going to refer to.
So let's cut it from here and let's remove that.
It's common.
This one it so our first argument work to match is actually going to be this that valley.
Right.
And now let's go ahead and let's create a an element, OK?
And this element is going to be the element that our suggestions you well, is going to is going to
adopt.
So I'm going to comment this one out as well.
So our you our suggestions is going to be asking to adopt this element.
So I'm just going to say match match element.
All right.
And let's whenever also inside this match element, we are going to grab our find.
Oops, find her right.
Because this is going to return to us an array.
We can map through it.
All right, so we are going to go ahead and map through and when we are mapping through it, what it
is actually that we are looking for.
All right.
So we are looking for a state and a city.
So I'm just going to do a map and.
All right, so I'm going to say place this time I'm going to say place and let's create oops, let's
create this.
So before actually creating that line that we have.
Right, that elai that we are going to we are going to give it to the suggestions to adopt before creating
that what it is actually that we are trying to do.
So we are looking for a specific city or a specific state.
Right.
And when we get that specific city or specific state, we want to put the value of that inside a span.
Why span?
Because spans are in line elements.
It means that they do not create new lines inside this HDMI.
What page?
It means actually that whenever you say new, you can see that the city and the state, they are on
one line, if you do div device are block level elements and spans are inline level elements.
We need inline level elements.
You could do block, but you should have to, you could do def, but then you would have to change the
display property, which is like extra headache.
So we want to we want them to appear in one line.
That's why we are going to use a Ispat.
So one of the span's is going to grab the value of this our city.
The other span is going to grab the value of our estate and then we are going to create an ally.
And inside that ally, we are going to insert both of our Spens.
That's basically what it is that we are trying to do.
All right, so first off, let's create these variables, but before creating those, we need a way
to be able to find that match.
What is that way that we can find the match?
Right.
So we have already talked about it right here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to do the same thing here.
So we have our regex.
This regex is going to find that that that value that the user has typed in and it is going to match
it.
OK, it is going to match it to what's inside that list that we have.
Right.
So, OK, I'm going to say New Reg XP.
And we are going to pass in this dot value.
We know what this dot value is, so this dot value from here is going to be passed here and from here.
It is going to be passed to the word to match and this dot value.
So the second one, the second argument is going to be our flaks.
Where are the flock's?
It's even written right here.
All right.
So the flags are going to be G and I global and insensitive flag, right?
So now we have a regular expression.
Let's create our aliments.
So Consed City name, I'm going to call it city name and we are going to say place that city.
So place that city is going to give us the city name.
Right.
And then we are going to replace that.
We are going to call the replace method.
What do we want to replace?
We want to replace regular expression.
What is this?
Regular expression is going to return.
It is going to return.
The thing, the value that the user has typed, it is going to return that.
What do we want to replace it with?
Now, this is the cool part.
We want to replace it with a span.
So let's create that span.
So span and span, what do we have inside the span?
The span is going to have a class of very cool highlight there.
This is where the highlight is coming from.
And then the spine is going to grab the this value, this dot value, because this value is the value
that the user has typed.
We want to put it inside this span, this stored value.
Very simple.
Right.
And now I'm going to do the same thing for our state name as well to just speed this process a little.
So we have instead of city name, we are going to have state name, state name.
And the first one should be lowercase.
So we are going to say place dot state that replace replaced replace the regular expression, just replace
that regular expression with this pan and this pan has a class of highlight.
And what is this man actually going to do.
This, this, this you can see here this new which is which has been highlighted.
It is actually a span.
That's why there on the one one line, I can show you that.
So if I come inside this aliments, this is the trick behind this.
OK, so now if I can you can see that we have an ally and everything is inside that.
But what do we have inside that ally?
We have a span.
What do we have inside that span?
We have two more spans.
So one span is going to be have a class of highlight for the new, which is the state, which is the
city.
And the other one is going to be new for the state.
You can see these are the spans that we are creating.
So this part is going to stay the same.
This part is going to be replaced very, very, very, very simple.
All right.
So if I were to say Tulsa and now check inside this elai, check this out.
We just have one span, and that is for Tulsa.
So as many cities and states are being highlighted, those many spans we want to create.
Right.
So now we have created this one as well.
Now, what do we want to do with this?
Basically, we want to return a year from this return.
Return what it is that we want return, return.
Certainly not a an ally.
So let's create that ally.
So it's going to be Elai.
And in here we are going to say, Ally, in case you're wondering, if you just click, you can see
this.
I'm just going to zoom in so you can really see you can see this yellow underline.
It's because I have a an extension.
I don't think I've shown you I think we talked about it in the first chapter, it is, let's see, highlight
matching tack.
You can just go ahead and stall this.
And it is very useful in JavaScript because you, unlike HTML, you can see how it works in e-mail as
well.
But in e-mail, if you just click here, it is going to show you the ending taxe.
The ending is here, but in JavaScript it doesn't say if you just click here, it can show you the ending
tag word address.
So this law is going to have a class of.
I'm just going to call it name and what do we have inside this alley?
This is the important part.
First off, we are going to have our city name and then a comma.
So what is the structure?
We have our city name, then comma, then Oklahoma.
Right, and then state name, this is where you can change the structure, you can change it every every
which way you want, don't change it inside the span.
The span has nothing to do with that.
Just change it inside this ally.
And finally, after we get that ally, where do we want to put it?
Now, keep in mind this map one more thing.
Very importantly, this map method, it actually returns an array.
So we need to convert that array to a string.
So we just say don't join.
Join at what?
At the at an empty string.
And what do we want to do with this match element?
We just grab our.
Suggestions container.
So where are you?
So this is our suggestion's container.
Let's copy that.
Put it right here and we are going to say that inner turmoil is going onto the match element and save
it.
We don't have any errors here.
No errors here and it's there.
So let's see.
Our new oops can see there.
Find error is not defined at 28.
So let's go to 28, find a red dot.
Oh, you can see that I'm just going to zoom in for you, so it's really visible.
You can see that this F is capital, this F is lowercase.
You can see how sensitive identifiers are in JavaScript.
You need to be really, really careful.
Another way is if you pay really close attention, I'm going to zoom in even more and you can see that
I hope you can, that this match element, because it has been called here, is highlighted.
But this find area is not highlighted.
It's a little bit faded out, as you would say.
But if I change it to this, you can see that it just got highlighted like that.
So there we are.
I think this is the zoom level that we are at.
So now if I save this and if I come here and if I say new, you can see that we get all the results
for the Newquay.
So I'm just going to say, Merryland, we get all this.
If I say D.C., do we have D.C.?
Washington?
Yeah, we do have Washington, District of Columbia and let's say Ohio.
We do get Ohio.
Um, let's say California.
Ah, Arizona.
Yeah, I really like Arizona.
So we have Phoenix, Taksin, Mesa, Chandler and Arizona.
I didn't know it was in city name.
I always thought it was a character name.
OK, so what does our project comes to an end.
I know it wasn't that API oriented, but it was a lot like regular expression oriented.
And it's actually based on the this data that we get from here, because getting a data are getting
some sort of data from and from an external API is usually the easy part.
It's the making a sense of that data is is the part which is a bit trickier and a bit more difficult.
Right.
So so you saw how simple it was to give this data and to push it inside this array, but actually using
it in a in a meaningful way.
That was what made our process a little bit lengthy.
I wouldn't say difficult, but critical, but very, very important.
You not only you should be able to to grab data, to fetch data, to retrieve data, but you should
be able to use that data in a meaningful way.
And and the and that's the main reason for getting the data.
If you don't want to use it, why do you want to fetch it?
So so using it in a meaningful way is as important, I would say even more important than actually getting
the data, because getting the data is the simple part.
The the difficult part is actually making sense of that data.
OK, this was a very, very, very small example right now.
Think of Facebook, think of YouTube, think of Twitter.
What is the logic behind all of their data when whenever you just click like on the like button, what
happens in the background?
You can see that an array of operations, they take place and they're not visible to the eye.
But because you are developers, you will get to understand, OK, what actually happens when the page
loads, when we get data, when when we want to load that data.
For example, when you're working with the YouTube API and you want to, for example, update the title
of your video based on the number of views that you have.
Right.
Some some YouTube words do that.
And that's simple to do, but it is the API implementation of YouTube.
Right.
And it is making a sense of that that data.
Is is what makes this entire process interesting and difficult at the same time.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next chapter.