Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create an add expense and an ADD and come eventless dinner.
All right, so so far, what we have implemented in the end regarding this application is whenever we
click on any tab, we can see the information related to that.
OK, now what I'm going to do here is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to say.
And expense, I'm going to create an event listener for the ad expense and expense event unless Tegner
right.
And we are going to create one for ad income.
Now, these are listeners.
They are going to be received in income.
They are going to be fired or received by us as developers.
Whenever the user either clicks on this ad button or the user clicks or just the user presses the enter.
Now, there are two.
If the keyboard if your computer keyboard is like the big, big ones, I don't know what they're called.
If they have like a calculator on the side, for example, on the on the right, if you have that sort
of keyboard, it means that you have to enter keys to return keys.
One is in your regular key, the other keyboard and the other one is in your calculator on the side,
which is beneath this plus sign.
OK, I can show you because this is a screen recording, not a keyboard recording.
But what I mean is you have you have to enter keys.
So if I go ahead and if I take a look at this one, I think this is the regular one.
Yeah, we don't have any.
So if I go ahead and if I increase it, still just the keys soon here.
We just have one in Turkey.
But if you have a calculator on this side, then right here instead of these two buttons, you're going
to see another in Turkey.
So whenever the user either presses this enter or this one on the right bottom side and or the user
presses this, add clicks this add button, what do we want to do?
We want to run a certain function.
Now, that certain function depends on two things.
One, is it the income or is it the expense?
So if it is the income, we are going to run a budget and function.
If it is an expense, we are going to run a budget out function.
So let's go ahead and let's implement this functionality.
So for this, I'm going to grab our add expense button.
Right.
And let's go ahead.
And let's just very quickly take a look at this.
What this is.
So this is the ad expense.
These are our input buttons and this is the input which has a type of submit.
And if I come here, this is actually our input adding ad add expense.
So when the user clicks this button or presses both of either of those enter keys, I want to do the
same thing.
So out of listener, what is the event that we are listening for?
It is going to be click and when the click happens, I want to run a budget out function.
Now what is this budget about function and why don't I specify it here?
Because I'm going to call this function more than once.
I need to like create a standalone OK, not inside.
I like not as a callback function.
Right.
So I'm just I'm going to call it the budget out.
And for the add income, even the center, we are going to grab the add income that add a wellness center
and we are going to listen for a click.
But the function is going to be different.
Well, it is going to be budget and OK, so this is one is income and the other one is outcome or expense.
So now before diving into the function, I want to create another event listener as well.
And in that of a listener, we are going to listen for a key press and I'm going to trace whether that
key is the in Turkey or not.
All right.
So I'm going to say.
We could we could call it add expense and tur key, we could call it add expense in Turkey or.
The I think we could call it both of that, so because this is going to be the same for both of them
in Turkey event.
Listen.
All right, so what do I want this event to be attached on?
I want this to attach it to be attached on the document.
And whenever on the document, which is our e-mail page, we we receive a key press.
Now, we have talked about the key press.
We have a key down whenever the key is pressed down, key up whenever the key is pressed up again.
But when when we have a key down plus key up, we have a key press, we are going to run a certain function.
But this function, this is going to be a callback function because I want to trace our event object
now because this is on the document and key press and literally we have 100 more than 100 keys.
We want to trace a certain key.
We want to find out if the IDOT key is not equal to enter.
So this is the name of the turkey or if it is not equal to enter, we want to return the function.
So unless the user presses the turkey, we are unless the user presses, we are not going to run that
function.
So we could just go ahead and see that in action.
So I'm just going to say, hmm, the enter key is pressed, so let's save it.
Let's come and tell our application and let's go to inspect.
So in here we can send the budget out as not.
We are going to define that.
So until we do, let's go ahead and comment them out to not get any more errors are right.
So we are inside our documents.
So if I click here and if I press, for example, the shift key, nothing happens.
But if I press the enter key, we can see that the entire case is précis is pressed.
Right.
And now if I even press the other enter key, we are going to see that and this.
And how does this actually work?
I can show you I can just go ahead and log the event itself whenever we press the turkey.
So this is the event.
Keep it.
Pay attention.
I'm not going to collapse it.
I'm not going to expand it.
So this key, it says enter.
We can see that the event is an object, right?
Objects.
They are key value pairs and they have properties and methods.
We are interested in the key property.
And if I come down, it's says key and the value for that is enter.
Now keep this in mind.
So if I just remove this, if I press the first kind of enter and the second kind of enter, now you're
going to see what what, what is it, what it is that I exactly mean.
So both of them have in Kiev enter, but this one has the first one, which is the real enter key.
It says enter, but the second one, it says numpad enter and the location is different.
See, even the key code, that should be different as well.
So the key code for this one is thirteen.
But I think now the key code is the same.
Only the location is different.
So the location for the original enter key is zero.
But for the numpad in Turkey, which is numpad enter, it is going to be three.
But what do they have in common?
They have in common the key.
So you could write this in another way.
You could just add a like chain, like a logical or a logical or operator.
But instead of doing that and complicating this code, I just went ahead and said, enter, OK.
And if the key that we have not a of the key that we have clicked on is not enter return, it means
do not like calculate this function, just pack it up and go.
All right.
But if what do we have clicked on is the enter key, what do we want?
We want to run two functions.
So the first function is going to be budget out and we are going to pass in the event object.
The second one is going to be budget and budget.
And because whenever we pressed the enter key, it is going to be either the add expense or the add
income.
So the budget out is going to be rendered when we press on the add expense and budget and on the add
So now I'm going to come in these guys back and let's go ahead and let's create these two functions.
So I'm going to say budget out.
We could go either way.
We could we could create the budget out and then the budget and or the other way around doesn't really
matter.
So we have a function that is budget out there where we are going to pass and the event object, notice
that this is green because this function is is defined.
And in case you're wondering what kind of theme this is, this is the Dracula theme control katee a
right.
That is the short shortcut control capability.
And this is this Dracula theme.
You can see I have like a ton of themes.
I'd like to change up themes in my during the recording, during the recording of my courses.
So if you have followed my other courses, my previous course, the Flexibles course, I've changed
theme like three times.
This is what I do.
I like to keep things like a diversion like like, hmm.
What is the word.
I want to change things up so I'm not going to first we had this dark visual studio, but we just changed
it to Dracula.
Another cool one if you're looking for is Cobalt two, which is a blue theme, very, very soft on the
ice.
So I really pay attention to whether or not the theme, that specific theme hurts my eyes or not.
So that's really important.
All right.
So budget out.
What do we want to do here?
First off, because we are working with a form, I'm going to prevent the default behavior.
So prevent default behavior.
We do not want the form to supplement, OK, because this is an input type of submit and this is a form
element and it is going to submit.
We are we do not want to do that.
Now, what do we want to do?
Is whenever if if what we have clicked on is if what we enter right is not the title or nor the amount,
we do not want to run the function, what do I mean by this?
So we are going to use our not operator and we are going to say expense.
Title dot value f f the expense title, that value is null or the expense.
Amount where the amount that value is now.
We want to return this function.
Now, what does this mean?
It means, OK, budget, and we are going to define that.
Don't worry.
So it means that if we are in the expense and there was nothing written inside these fields, when the
user clicks add we do not want to print anything.
This is basically preventing the user from doing that.
Now let's create an expense object.
Now this object is going to be the first item which we are going to push to this entry list array and
that array is going to be stored inside our local storage as well as be displayed on the UI.
So first off, the first key that I want to pass is going to be type and I'm going to call it expense.
Then we are going to have our title.
Now what what does the title is going to be?
The title is going to be expense title data value.
So whatever the title is going to be, whatever value the user puts there.
And finally, the amount, what is the amount, the amount is going to be expense.
Amount dot value, whatever the user writes.
And then we are going to grab this expense and we are going to push it to the end, shrillest dot push
because we want to add items stoehr list.
We are going to use the push method.
And what is the item name?
It is expense.
OK, and we could go ahead and say Kansa log expense.
OK, so what do we have actually inside the expense, so if I it still says budget and I mean it's so.
OK, that's coming that out.
Let's come here.
So if I go ahead and if I say rent and say 2000 and when I click add, we can see that it has been added
here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to zoom out.
I'm sure you can still see this UI.
I just want to work with this one more.
So it is exactly our object.
The object has an amount of 2000 tied on a front type of expense.
I know this video is 14 minutes and I'd like to keep videos short in this course.
I haven't done a good job of that.
But there is something that I want to show you.
Notice this 2000.
This is not a number.
This is a string.
So how do we know that there is another operator in JavaScript and that is the type of operator.
So if I go ahead and if I say type of expense.
Type of expense, let's grab the first one and OK, so let's add it rent to like let's say 200 and Klegg,
it is going to say undefined.
I don't think it has grabbed it.
Type O, it should be this, not this one.
It is expense.
It should be number two.
I think we should be able to grab it, grab the type.
If we couldn't then we are getting you, we are going to go a different route.
If I click on it it still says undefined expense to oh sorry I should say that amount.
Type of that amount.
That's like I was accessing it like an array, and that is not an array and it says a string, it means
that this number is actually string.
We don't want it to be a string, because if this is if this number is a string, what does that mean?
It means that we cannot add it like we cannot say two plus two because it's a string.
It is going to grab two plus two and it is going to give us 22 because it is going to put the other
two right next to it.
So there is a method called pass.
We could go pass, float or pass integer.
It doesn't really matter.
This is the method.
It is going to grab a string and it is convert that into a floating point number.
We could say pass integer in T and it is going to tell us it is going to give us this information,
a value between two and thirty six that specifies the base of the number and num string a strength to
strength to convert into a number.
Right.
So this is going to convert a string to a number.
And let's say expense amount, dot value.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to cancel that log our expense and then we are going
to cancel log type of that.
So let's enter that.
Let's say rent one hundred.
And if I click on it now, it says a number.
And now you guys can see that this is not surrounded by quotes.
This is blue.
It means that this is a number and type of operator says that this is actually a number.
This is it for this letter.
See you guys in the next one.