Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we will draw the ball.
All right, so first off, I'm going to go to the new game function and I'm going to call that ball
variable that we have declared on top.
Where is it?
Right here, I'm just going to call that in here, because Ball is going to be a constructor as well.
So we are going to say new ball and we are going to pass and the ball.
What that is going to be, we are going to see that in a minute and we are going to pass him the ball
speed as well.
So next stop, let's go ahead and let's create the class.
So on on top of the panel, I'm going to come here and I'm going to say the ball class and I'm going
to say class ball.
Let's give it a constructor.
So the constructor is going to have two parameters.
The first parameter is going to be the ball size.
So that wall that we've passed up there was actually the ball size that we have and we have the ball
speed.
Perfect.
So first off, let's define the width of the ball.
The width of the ball is going to be ball size.
As with the height of the ball, we are going to go to the X position of the ball.
What is the exposition?
The exposition.
Now, keep in mind that the exposition of the ball and the exposition of the paddle is going to be the
same because we wanted to start from there.
So paddle that x the Y position, it should be on top of the paddle.
So we need to subtracted from half of the paddle.
So this start why we are going to have our paddles y position minus.
Let's subtract the paddles height half of that and let's also subtract the ball's height, the start
half of that.
Perfect, so divided by two.
There we go, this start speed is going to be equal to the ball speed, which is a fraction, and we
are going to multiply it by the height because the ball speed is going to be dependent on the height,
right.
So this should be capital perfect then we have our now because the ball is moving in both directions,
we are going to have X velocity zero.
And we are going to have y velocity 00, so this is created, we don't have any errors.
Perfect.
So now.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go to our new game function, right?
Where is our new game function right here and let's see underneath this, I'm going to call in a function
called drawable.
I'm not going to save it because we have not actually created this function yet.
So let's go ahead and let's actually created right here.
Right.
So I'm going to.
We know we have called it the drop ball function, so I'm going to grab that comment, put it right
here and I'm going to say BA.
And we are going to say drop the ball function, it is not going to grab any parameters, we just want
to draw a ball.
So the Conex start, a field style is going to be Phil style is going to be the color of the ball that
we have specified on top.
Then the.
Then we are going to call in the film Recht, because basically we are, we are we want to draw a rectangle.
The exposition of the ball is going to be ball dot x minus the ball dot with divided by two.
And the Y position is going to be it's going to act in the same way.
So baldest Y minus bolds height divided by two.
We want half of the ball to be on one side and half on the other side.
That's Y and half on the top.
Half on the bottom.
We want to grab that exact point.
The width of the ball is going to be the ball with and the height of the ball is going to be double
height.
So let's say that.
Let's come here.
There we go.
This is where our ball is now.
The problem is if you move our paddle, the ball is stationary.
So far, we're going to get to actually moving the paddle with the ball, moving the ball with the paddle
as well.
So for now, the ball is stationary there.
OK, so the next thing that I want to do is I want to update the position of the ball with the velocity
that it might have.
And what I want to do is I want to let's come here.
First off, I'm going to come into our update functions.
And right after the update, Padel, I'm going to I'm going to call a function called Update Voll and
we are going to create this function.
So let's come down, where is our update, Per?
Where have we specified the update panel?
So this is our update panel.
So on top of the update panel, I'm going to create our update function.
Of date ball, perfect, so let's create that function of date ball.
No parameters and what do we want to do here, basically?
So in the update bar, what we are going to do is we are going to grab the exposition and we are going
to add on to it the ball's, what, X velocity?
But we're going to divide it by 1000 to get a second, actually, to get a second and then get a pixels
per frame after that.
So I'm going to multiply it by 15 and we are going to do the same thing for the Y position.
So multiply it by the Y.
Save it.
It is not moving, it should move.
Is there any typo we have done here?
We have called the update all the way velocity.
Oh, where is the speed we should increment?
This should add the speed as well, because the velocities are zero for now.
All right, so, uh, hmm.
All right, so whenever the game starts, we don't want to whenever we refresh, we don't want to move
the ball, you can see.
But when we had the space bar, then we want to move the ball.
So what we're going to do is I'm going to go to my key down where is the key down function.
So this is the key down function and I'm in here.
I'm going to create another case and that is going to be for the space.
You can't change it to any other key that you want, but I'm just going to go with the space.
So the key code for that is 32 and that is space key.
And we are going to call it to serve the ball.
Perfect.
So in here, what do I want to do?
I want to call a serve ball function.
Very simple, I just want to call a serve ball function.
So now what should we do as we should go ahead and we should create the serve all function and.
Hmm, where should we put it?
Right here.
I'm just going to go on top of the set dimensions and in here I'm going to create a function that is
going to be served.
All right.
So first off, we need to check if the ball is still not moving, if the ball is is moving.
So first off, let's create the function, serve ball.
So if the ball is currently moving, we do not want to serve it again and again and again.
So if the ball once the user hits the space, doesn't matter how many more times the user is going to
head the ball is just going to be served once.
Why why should we care about this?
Because each time the user serves the ball, the angle of the ball is going to be different.
Now keep this and take a look at this one.
So I'm just going to reload the page if I had it.
You can see it goes to.
Right.
Reload the page, hit it again.
It goes to top reload the page.
It goes to the left.
So each time I serve the ball, the ball is going to have a different bounce angle.
And if we do not check for this condition when the ball is moving towards the the bricks, the user
hits by mistake space, then the ball is going to deflect midway.
And that's not what we want.
Right.
So first off, if.
If the ball ball is already moving, do not do not serve.
Do not allow, serve, serve.
OK, so we are going to say f ball dot y velocity is not equal to.
Is not equal to zero.
We just want to return false.
It means we are returning from this function.
We do not want to run anything now.
What we are going to do is we are going to grab a random angle and we do not that we do not want that
random angle to win, not less than the minimum bounce angle, which we are going to specify.
In just a moment, so first things first, let's go ahead and let's zoom in bounds, and I'm not talking
about this one.
I'm talking about this.
So we have a we are going to have a variable that is going to be in bounds and risk for angle and then
bounce angle.
And when we divide it by 180 and then multiply it because we want to grab degrees, we don't want to
we have degrees so far.
Right.
So whenever the ball is moving to the left, the common sense is that we say, for example, 30 degrees,
40 degrees.
So in our mind, we have degrees.
What do we want to do is we want to change it to radians so we can apply sine and cosine to it, so
we can say math, dot pi and this is going to return for us radians.
In just a moment, this is all going to make sense.
Let's put it there.
There we go.
And let's specify a range for that as well.
So what is going to be the minimum and the maximum range for that?
So for the for the range is going to be math that pie minus the minimum balance angle that we that we
have times to and the angle itself.
It's going to be a random angle, so we are going to say math are random, divided by the range that
we have, plus the minimum bouncing.
So let's say that the range angle is going to give us, for example, the range angle is going to give
us 50 degrees.
And here we have math that random multiplied by 50, let's say that match their random returns one and
one times 50 degrees is going to be 50 degrees, plus the minimum bounce angle.
The minimum bounce angle is going to be 30 to 150.
So 50 degrees plus three degrees is going to be our angle.
Right.
And in here, I'm just going to call a function and that is apply speed of light, ball, speed, ball
speed.
This is the function that is going to take care of the ball speed and we are going to pass and the angle
there.
Perfect.
So what we are going to do next is we are going to create this a fly ball speed function.
So I'm going to come down here and let's grab this comment and put it right here, a fly ball and speed
function.
Fly ball, speed function, apply ball speed, and we are going to pass and the the parameter as well,
so what it is that we want to do here for the X velocity, we are going to use the cosine because the
cosine is the adjacent of that triangle.
If the triangle and for this Y velocity, we are going to get the same.
But because for the Y velocity.
So first off, let's do the X and then let's talk about the way we're going to grab the ball speed.
You can see that we are setting the ball speed to the X velocity, but times the math dot cosine math
that cosine of the angle that we have passed.
And for this it is going to be math that sine because it is moving upwards, because it is moving upwards,
it is moving in the negative direction, we are going negative.
And you're going to add YV there.
So let's press the space.
It doesn't work yet.
All right, so I think the the problem is going to be this cosign, so this was con, but it should
be co-sign and we have not specified this minimum balance angle.
She should go to the top and let's say CONSED.
Let's specify that as well.
So I'm going to call it we have already called this minimum bounce angle and the minimum bounce angle
is going to be 30 degrees.
Right.
And I'm just going to put in a comment as well here.
All right, let's grab it.
Let's put it there.
So the minimum bounce angle from the horizontal in degrees.
Perfect.
So let's save it.
Let's come here and let's press space.
There we go.
So the ball moves in the in the 30 degrees.
Doesn't matter.
Now you can see that the minimum the minimum is 30.
It could go greater than that.
But the problem is that why is that when I had space, why is this space is moving?
So why is this panel is being moved?
This paddle is constantly being moved to left.
And if I were to guess, is there we did not break out of that case.
That is my guess, that we did not break out of it.
There we go.
We should break out of it.
If we do not break out of that, you can see that this is running as well.
And then we have the break.
That's why this is not running.
So let's save it.
Let's see.
So the ball is being served when we press space each time it is going to have a different direction,
a different angle.
The next logical thing for us to do is going to be the implementing the collision detection.
Or bouncing the ball off the of the walls, so that is going to be the first thing that we will be doing.
All right.
So I would like to do that in this lecture as well, so just to keep the continuity going, so inside
the in here I'm going to say move the ball.
Right.
So that is going to be.
For moving the ball next, let's go ahead and let's come down here so we have two different kinds of
collision detection.
The first coning two is going to be bouncing it off from the wall.
The second kind is actually bouncing it off from the from the paddle.
But what I am going to do is I'm going to bounce it off the wall first and then we are going to bounce
it off the paddle.
So in here, I'm going to say bouncing.
The ball.
Off the walls, so we need to detect when the ball hits the part of the wall.
So we are going to say if the first we are going to go with the left direction.
So if the ball's X is less than the walls with by a half its width.
Divided by two.
And what what do we want to do?
Now we want to we want to do two things first, we want to reposition the ball so it would not go beyond
that.
And the second thing that we want to do is we want to reverse the velocity so it bounces off to another
direction.
First, we want to stop it there and then and then bounce it off to another side.
So we are going to grab the ball V and we are going to say minus that X V, perfect.
So we are going to have a lot of like a couple of more conditions here as well.
But now first, let's go ahead and let's see if we can.
But it doesn't go first.
It was for the left.
So there we go.
So we have successfully implemented that.
I'm going to do it one more time.
It should bounce off the wall.
There we go.
It bounces off the wall on the left wall.
Let's go ahead and apply it for the left, for the right one.
So we are going to say, al-Assaf, if the balls it's sort of like the paddle that we had greater than
the canvas elements with.
All right, and the with minus the wall, minus the bulls, half of the balls with so ball, that width
divided by two, what it is that we want to do, we want to first reposition the ball.
So let's put it there and let's set it to equal.
And then we are going to grab the balls x velocity and reverse that velocity.
So you should get it to bounce off that wall as well.
So I'm just going to reload the page so we get it.
We get a good angle there.
No, no, no.
There we go.
Oh, so we have it says uncaught x V is not defined to 177.
So let's see that XIV.
This is one seventy seven, why is not we just used it right here, so it's the same thing we say that
if the balls exposition is greater than the canvas with minus the wall, minus the balls with time divided
by two, we want to reposition the ball as exposition to their right.
And you know what?
I'm just going to come here and I'm going to go to the top.
This is still one seventy seven and is going to be uncaught.
Reference error is not defined ls.
If the world's exposition is greater than the canvas is with minus that elusive.
If that is the case.
We want to everything seems to be working fine.
Why do we have that?
So if I comment that one out and if I just do a console log, let's see.
Right it.
Let's put it there and let's clear that.
Why do we get that?
Still 177 words.
One, it's right here.
So I have removed it.
I'm just going to open it up.
With life server one more time, this is the thing with the game loop, if you do one mistake, it is
going to repeat it over and over and over again.
So now there is nothing.
So let's reload the page.
Perfect.
That's.
So it bounces off perfectly fine and.
Right, hit, so it does head it and you can see that we have grabbed the position and the position,
you saw how it was sliding against that, against the wall.
So this is how this should work.
If I copy it from there, even though they're identical, let's put it here.
I don't know why it's not accepting it.
It should.
What is the problem?
So let's reload the page.
There we go.
So maybe that was a bug or something, but it works now, so it bounces off the left, it bounces hmmm.
It should bounce off the right.
Right.
There we go.
When it hits, it is going to print that right hit.
So let's remove that.
I don't know, maybe there was something that I did wrong here.
Oh, it was of course, I'm sorry for this, we should put on the board that XIV.
Yeah, it was my mistake, it wasn't a bug.
It was a bug in me, of course.
There we go, should bounce off, so now that we have done that, why shouldn't we go ahead and implement
the same thing for the top so we can see that our Ballot Bowl is truly bouncy?
So if the balls y position is less than the ball, so the left and top are going to be the same almost
and the right and bottom are going to be almost the same.
So we are going to grab the war bonds height divided by two, and we want to reposition it to that.
And we also want to grab the wave of the lost city this time, and we want to change the direction of
the velocity.
OK, so our balls should bounce perfectly fine, so bounce, bounce, it comes down and even if I move
this panel, it is not going to the panel is not going to grab it.
It didn't grab it.
Perfect, so we should how about if we implement the bounce from the paddle as well, so I'm going to
come on down here because that is going to be the continuity of this lecture, bouncing the ball of
the paddle.
If you are feeling like this is a lot, you can pause the video and take a break.
That is the good thing about these online videos that you can pause it, you can rewind it, you can
go back, you can go forward.
You can do whatever you want that fits your needs.
Right.
That fits you better.
So and here we are going to say that now we need to account for all sides of the ball.
So we are going to get the ball, stop the ball bottom the balls left and the balls right.
So first off, if the balls y is greater than the paddles y, but we need to reduce to subtract the
height of the paddle.
Paddle tight times, point five or a half of the height, minus the ball, half of the height of the
ball, so half of that if this is the case and but but I'm not going to write the end there.
I'm just going to pass into the end here.
So and the ball's so that was the top of the game.
The actually the top of the paddle and the bottom of the ball.
Now we should do the bat, the bottom of the ball, the top of the ball as well.
Right.
So we are going to say that Y is less than the paddles y paddle.
Dout, why is why, plus the panel's height, plus the Pardo's height times times zero point five,
let's say.
Let's see how the code is going to rearrange that.
So the viscardi ranges like that, which is perfectly fine.
So we are going to go to the next slide.
Now, let's do the same thing for the X, so for the X and for the Y, for the for the both sides of
the X.
I'm just going to copy that, sir.
Remove this.
Let's change all the whys to access this.
Change all the heights to withs.
And we say that if the ball's exposition is less than the paddles exposition, minus the paddles half
of the paddle with within half of the balls with and if the.
Bozz Exposition is less than the paddles time, plus the half of the paddles with plus half of the paddles
after half of the balls with as well, then what do we want to do?
We are going to grab this first condition and basically we want to reposition it to this first condition.
Let's save it, let's put it right here, and so let's put in the equality side.
Right here, so we just change the paddles, the balls y position to the paddles y position, minus
the half of the paddles height minus half of the balls height, perfect.
And when that happens, when we reposition it, we want to change the velocity direction as well.
So we are going to say negative ball that YV.
Perfect, so let's save it.
But before actually going there, what I want to do is I want to come back to my bouncing the ball and
I want to hear I want to call a function that is spin ball.
And this function is going to be responsible for that deflection of the ball that we will have.
So I'm going to put it right here and I'm going to grab it and I'm going to put it in all these three
cases.
All right.
And hmm, and OK, so also I'm going to you know what?
I'm just going to first stuff coming this one out, because this is going to throw a lot of errors.
Let's first off check if it is going to bounce off, then we are going to do the rest of that.
So bounce off.
Bounce off.
Come on.
There we go.
So it does bounce off.
And then we can see this is a cool game that you can play.
And but this is not the game that we are going to build here.
So the some of the functionality of the game is being is done, is being completed.
The rest are still remaining.
So it bounces perfectly from the all the sides and the paddle itself as well, and I think that is going
to be it for this lecture.
And see you guys in the next one.