Hi, everyone, in this last year, we are going to refactor our code to make it look cleaner.
All right, so here we have an if statement nested inside, another if statement.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab all this if statement and I'm going to cut it and I'm going
to put it inside its own function.
And the function name is going to be check for match.
Right.
And we are going to put in this statement right here.
And we are going to call this function here.
Check for match.
OK, let's put in the parentheses.
So this looks way better than before.
Right.
This is more readable because this function is not cluttered a lot and we can read it.
We know what how everything works.
But there is still some refactoring that we need to do here.
And the the way that I'm going to do is now this disabled cards and then flip cards, these names,
I've added them intentionally because each of them is going to be the name of a function inside which
we are going to run these two lines of code.
So first off, I'm going to create a function.
I'm going to call a disable cards.
Right.
And in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and cut this and I'm going to put it
right here and I'm going to delete this comment.
And I'm going to I'm going to excuse me.
I'm going to call that function right here.
Right.
And the same thing goes for our
handful of cards.
Right.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to create a function and I want to call it unflavored cards.
And inside here, I'm going to grab this, which ends right here.
And I'm going to pasted right here and I'm going to save it.
Right.
And I'm going to delete this.
And we are going to call the function here.
Right.
So we have a check for match function, which is called right here.
And inside this function, we have callback function.
So we have other functions.
When a function is inserted as an argument or as a return value for another function, it is a callback
function.
So these are callback functions.
All right.
Now, this disable cards does this and this flip cards does this.
Now, there is something that I forgot to mention that whenever we grab the first card and the second
card and when we remove the flip, we have to add the flip class first and then we can remove it.
All right.
Now, here we had a toggle this the class listed are Tuggle.
Now, toggle was just for demonstration purposes, but whenever we want to remove first, we need to
add it.
That's why I commented out the toggle.
I'm not going to remove it.
I commented out the toggle and we added the flip class.
And then when we are done, when they do not match, this is the answer.
Of course we are going to see the cards for for one point five seconds and then the class is going to
be removed.
Right.
Now, this is just going to remove this comment because the function name is pretty comprehensive,
check for much disable cars and flip cards.
Right.
And what I'm going to do here is that we have an if statement.
We have talked about the term operator and each of these F statements.
They basically run a single block of code.
They run a function call.
What we can do is we can't even we can take this if statement one step further and we can simplify it
even further.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a variable and I'm going to call it as matched.
And we are going to set it to this value.
I'm going to put it right here, right.
And we are going to use our Turner operator.
So if is matched is true.
If it is true.
So if you just provide it with is much, this is going to be a boolean statement.
The the value returned from this is matched is either going to be true or false.
If the first car matches the second card in both type and value.
Notice the strict equality operator.
If they match in both in TypePad value, then this is matched is going to be true.
And if this is matched is true, what do we want?
We want to run the disable cards function and if it is not true, we want to run the unfoiled cards
function.
Now what we can do is we can go ahead and remove that.
That's it.
So this is how we do refactoring in JavaScript.
We could do a lot more.
And we when we get to our further lectures, we might even implement more refactoring.
All right.
So we have not talked about refactoring before.
This is the first lecture that we talk about that.
So from now on, when we talk about cleaning up the code, we actually mean refactoring.
All right.
So when the is matched is true, it means that the first card equals the second card.
We are going to run the disabled cards.
It means that when the first card matches the second card, we want to disable the cards.
We do not want to flip them again.
But if the first card does not match the second card after one point five seconds, we want to flip
them.
OK, and the logic works, right?
So I guess this is going to be it for this next year.
See you guys in the next one.