Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create our generate password function.
All right, so first of all, let's go ahead and let's create the function, the name is already specified,
which is generate password.
The parameters are actually the arguments that we have passed.
So I'm just going to pass it right here and then open up the function function block.
All right.
So first off, before doing anything, I want to console to the one I always say console to lock, but
it's actually I want to log to the console or print as as in Python or print to the console.
The lower case character counts.
I just want to print this.
All right, so let's come here and let's let's you know what?
I'm going to keep it here.
And now we are inside the console here.
So let's go ahead and let's click on this.
If I click on one, if I click on this, what do I get?
I get all the character codes and associated with our lower case numbers.
So we have ninety seven all the way to 122.
So if I bring it here, it says ninety seven all the way to 122.
Right.
So we get all those.
So it means that our generate function is working properly.
I'm just going to come out and I'm going to keep it there.
I'm going to create another variable.
The reason for this variable is that I'm going to tell you why.
And it it takes its roots from this argument that I told you why we specify lower case, lower case
character quotes.
First, why we are going to use we are why we are going to give this.
This these character quotes preference over the others, and I'm going to tell you why, that's why
I'm going to set our character codes to exactly this variable.
So I'm going to say I'm going to call it Charcot's in general character codes, and I'm going to set
it to that.
And that set the reason for that is let's come into our final application right here.
So I'm going to reload our page.
So everything is zero.
I'm going to go to all the way to number 10.
Now, you guys can see that we have only specified our number of characters with which has nothing to
do with either with the with the password being lowercase, uppercase or or with the password, including
numbers or symbols.
So this number of characters is an independent variable that we are using here.
So before clicking on any of these checkboxes like numbers, symbols, uppercase, even before clicking
on those, we can still create a password, we can generate a password.
And when I click, we have a password here.
And when I click again, we are going to get another password now, this password doesn't include uppercase,
does not include symbols and does not include numbers.
So this is a lowercase password.
So by default, so what?
What does it mean?
It means that by default, when the user doesn't want to include numbers, symbols or uppercase, the
user is going to get a lowercase password.
I hope you're following, so our default password style is going to be lower cased, that's why we are
giving this lower case precedence.
OK, so if I go, it doesn't matter how many times I click, it is going to only show me lowercase letters,
right?
That's why I have set initially the character codes initially is going to be set to our lowercase character
codes because when the user has not checked any of those checkboxes, the user should be able to see
some sort of password.
It's not like when these are not checked, the application should breakdown.
No, no, no.
We don't want that to happen.
We want the user to see some sort of password, even if nothing is checked, for example, even if the
number of characters is a default.
So let me reload.
And when I click, we are just going to get a password.
I know it's only one character, but that's not the point.
The point is this one character is lowercase.
So by default, the default password style that the user is going to get is going to be a lowercase
password and the number of characters is irrelevant of the rest of them.
So I'm not I'm not talking about this.
We talked about this in our very first JavaScript lecture, and that was the synchronization and that's
it.
All right.
Now we are talking about the rest of them.
So we have lowercase, no symbols and uppercase.
OK, so now that that's clear, we are going to come down and we are going to control the flow of this
application through of statements, so we are going to say if include numbers is true, what does it
mean?
If it is it has been checked, then it is going to evaluate to true.
So when this include numbers has been checked, what do we want to do?
Let's open our if statement block and now we are going to grab our character codes and we are going
to concat tonight, this array to it, because this include numbers.
It is going to when this is true, it means that when this has been clicked is the include numbers,
they include numbers comes from numbers element that value.
All right.
We have specified that here.
So this is include numbers that value one that has been checked.
When the value is true, then what do we want?
We want the character codes to be to have another array added to it.
Why and why another array, you might ask?
Because originally the value of the character codes is lowercase character codes and lowercase character
codes is going to give us an array, see an array from low to high.
Where does this array come from?
It comes from this function that we have created here.
So when the initial value of character codes is set to an array and we want to add on to that, right,
so we are going to use our concat method and why you might say that we want to add on to that.
Why not just set it to to this to this numbers?
Because the reason for that is whenever we create on this, we are going to see a lowercase password.
But when we say no and let's set it to 10 so we can talk about it, when we say include numbers and
claque, we can see that we have numbers and lowercase.
Right.
It's not like when you when you click on the numbers, then the lower case is going to go away and you're
just going to have numbers.
It's not like that.
We want a combination of both of them.
So when we click symbols, it's not like numbers and lowercase, they go away and we only end up with
symbols.
No, no, no.
We want a combination of lowercase numbers and symbols.
That's why we are going to add them on to each other.
Right.
So we are going to concatenate and what is it that we are going to concatenate?
It is going to be the number character codes that we have created in here.
So we have created these character codes and we are going to reference them inside our generate password.
That said, that's basically what we are doing here now.
Now that this if statement is completed, this basically runs one line of code so we can even simplify
this.
Let's remove the block and let's put it on the same line.
And when we save it, it's just going to basically do the same thing.
It's more readable this way.
So let's copy it two more times, so we have include numbers, then we have to include symbols.
What is that?
Include Assemblance.
Do we have this variable include symbols?
Yes, we have it right here.
So when they include symbols is true, we want our character codes to be concatenated.
By what?
By the symbol.
By symbol character codes, so we write it correctly, where is it, symbol, character code.
So let's copy it.
Yeah, it is correct.
And when the password if the password includes uppercase, include uppercase, we want no character
codes to be added or to merge with with this upper case.
Right.
With this upper case that we have created on top.
So it is going to be uppercase character codes.
So let me grab this and this should be highlighted.
Yes, it is highlighted.
All right.
So now we have created our program flow.
Now we know how we can access that.
But how can we actually know?
Technically, we can generate a password at this point in time.
But the problem here is that we have no way of making that password random.
So each time that the user clicks this, this this should show us a random password that we are going
to implement our next in our next lecture.
See you guys then.