Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to talk about Function Expression's.
All right, so what our function expressions now functions when functions are stored inside variables,
they are called function expressions.
So let's go ahead and let's open this with live server.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to bring it here.
And let's close this page.
Let's open it with let's go to the console.
All right.
So when functions, they are passed in as stored data for a variable, then they are called function
expressions.
So when they are standalone named functions, they are called function declarations or function statements.
And when they are stored inside variables, they're called function expressions.
Function expressions are also anonymous functions.
It means they have no name.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's create a regular function.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a function expression right off the bat.
So we have illit and we are going to give it a variable name that is Calc Nums.
All right, and we are going to set it equal to function now, keep in mind that this function has no
name.
So we do not provide it with the name.
Right.
And we are going to say Z and W, we provide two parameters for this function and we want the function
to return.
What does it what should it return, it should return zipless to W, divided by Z minus, let's save
it.
So now what we could what we can do with this, the way we can call this function is remember that when
we call the function, we call the function by the function name.
Now here the function doesn't have a name, but this variable has a name and that variable name acts
as the function name.
And you might ask, OK, how is this possible?
The reason that this this is possible is because functions are not objects, but they behave like objects.
Other data types would be them prime, primitive or reference steps.
They can behave like objects, but they are not objects.
Right.
So the way we can access this function is through the variable name and that variable name becomes the
name of this function.
All right.
So let's go ahead on this call coconut's.
And when we open parentheses, we get an Intellisense that we can insert a number or the result is going
to be a number and we should insert Z first and then W so if I were to insert Z 15 and had comma, you
guys can see that the underlying has shifted from Z to W, and when I put it to any five there and unsaved,
we are going to get as a result negative for.
All right, so let's pass in another value.
We could call it as many times as we want 50.
We are going to get three.
All right.
So this is a function expression.
We use function expressions because when when we just one right off the bat control, the result of
that function is stored inside a variable.
All right.
So this is a function expression.
We can also use functions in arrays and objects.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to go ahead and we are going to work with functions in arrays
and in objects.
I'm just going to go ahead and paste in this comment.
So now let's go ahead and let's see.
We have a a function we have a function declaration that says average mike score.
Notice the camel casing and we have two parameters, one is score, and the next one is my score.
All right, so this is a function and this function is going to return.
What?
It is going to return my score plus five.
Divided by score, right?
So this is what this function is going to return.
Now, what I want to do is I want to create another function, which is actually a function expression,
just to show you how we can work with these functions and function expressions, OK, and how we can
use them inside arrays and inside objects.
Right.
So now.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to just call it average Joey score, so the naming convention is the
same.
So we have average my score, average Joes score.
Right.
And we are going to say it is equal to function.
Let's create the block as well.
And we are going to pass in two parameters as well.
And the parameters, one of the parameters is going to be score and the other one is going to be Joey
score.
All right.
So in here, what do I want this function expression to do?
I wanted to return to just go ahead and return the JOI score divided by the score.
Now keep in mind the mix score, whatever is the mike score is going to be added by five, then divided
by score because Mike has been a good student.
So I just give him five five scores for free.
But as far as Joe is concerned, Joe is not a super attendance student, is like the attention is all
over the place and I'm not going to give him five extra scores extra mark.
OK, so keep this in mind as one.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create a I'm going to create a
an array because we want to use these two functions inside an array and why they are function declarations
and function expressions.
Because I want to show you guys that inside arrays and objects, we can use both kinds of functions.
So it doesn't matter whether you have a function expression or you have a function declaration.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to use const for creating arrays because this is a good practice,
if I can get it right.
So this is CONSED and I'm going to name this const this array scores and in here I'm going to call the
functions by their function names.
Right.
So I'm going to say average my score and average Joe we score.
Now keep in mind that this is, this is let this is a variable declaration and this variable declaration
has been done in the global scope.
It's not limited to any scope when it is granted in the global scope.
It is accessible in any other scope that follows it.
All right.
And this function has also been declared in the global scope.
So we can access this because global scope is the parent of all other scopes so we can access the values
from the parent, or that's why we can access these two functions inside this array.
And keep in mind, they are not strings.
They're are valid JavaScript identifiers.
That's why we do not provide them with quotes or quotations.
So now what I want to do is I want to loop loop through this array and we know how we can do that.
We create a for loop and then let's go ahead and let's get provided with the structure as well.
The loop variable is going to be I and it is going to start from zero.
So this is the initial expression.
What is the condition in the loop should run as long as the scores.
Scores that length and what is the scores dazzling?
So first off, before before even applying that, let's go ahead and let's consider.
Look, I mean, I should have done it before.
Let's consider log.
The scores are right and let's see what what we get there.
And then you guys can see the lengths to and we get two functions.
And when I click on it, we have a function and this function.
And in the end, the what is this called?
The tooltip kind of forgot the word there.
The tooltip shows me the function itself.
I mean, it doesn't it doesn't calculate anything because we have not Pastan arguments to these parameters.
That's why it returns the arguments as no.
And this is where no one is used, because we have we have provided it no by like deliberately.
And until we pass in arguments, it is going to show no.
And the arguments are no, the color is no.
And the length is to the name is Mike and the rest of the information there.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to comment that one out.
So what do I want this for loop to do?
I want to create another variable that is a result and I want to capture the result.
So the result is going to be the scores whenever the scores and we are going to get the index.
So when the new variable has a value of zero and when it comes here, this course that has we we are
going to access an index of zero.
So what is the index of zero?
The index of zero is going to be the average mix score function.
That is going to be the index of zero.
And for the second time when this loop runs, which I just forgot to add the increment.
The variable is going to have a value of one and the discourse is going to access the item that has
a an index of one associated with it and it is going to grab the average Jobi score.
Right.
And we want to store this information inside this results variable.
And what do we want to do with that?
We want to simply cancel the log in.
Of course, in real world applications, we are going to do so much more with that.
But for now, we just want to consider log it.
Consider last resort, let's save it, and now you guys can see we actually get the functions back because
we have not provided any arguments to those functions.
That's why we get the functions.
So how can we add the argument to those functions?
Now we know that this cause this cause Arae, it grabs either the first function or the second function.
So whenever it grabs the first function, this is how it is going to look like.
So when the eye is zero, it is going to grab the index of zero item, the item which is associated
with the index of zero.
And the item associated with that is this function and it is going to be passed right here.
So when the function is passed right here, so technically we can add parentheses and inside those parentheses
we can add our arguments.
So this is how cool it is.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go back to the scores array and I'm going to do this.
All right, so whenever whenever we grab the I'm just going to pass in the eye because that's why we're
using the for a loop.
All right.
So whenever the eye has a value of zero, the condition is true because the length of this entire array
is two and zero is less than two.
Oops.
I shouldn't have saved it shows both of these scores here and zero is less than two.
So this condition is true and this code runs.
And when this code runs, we grab the scores are right and the eye has a value of zero.
So we access the item that has an index of zero.
What is that item?
The item is the average mike score and even the average mike score is access.
We pass in two arguments to that.
The first argument is going to be the score and the second argument is going to be the score for that
specific person.
That's why for Mike, for Mike, we are going to get point to five and for Joey we are going to get
point to and the reason that we get point to five is because we added five to this score.
All right.
And then we consider the results.
This is how cool it is when we use functions with arrays and when we use loops with arrays.
Right.
This is how cool it is.
So this is how we can use.
A race with with functions now, well, actually, I wanted to, like, combine I wanted to finish this
lecture here, but now looking at the at the time, it's been 14 minutes almost.
So the object and function part we are going to cover in the next lecture.
So see you guys in the next one.