Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we're going to talk about even more dumb methods.
All right, so the door method four and five, they are kind of related.
All right.
And they are creative element and append child.
So we have to we have a covered how we can create an element through inner HTML, but there is actually
an easier way.
Right.
So this this this approach requires three steps.
So the first step in the first step, we create an element.
So let's go ahead.
Now, what do I want to create before just diving into the code?
I want to create.
I want to create another item, I want to add another item to this list so we have loyal, funny and
good company.
I could go ahead and added in the HTML, but then why am I then why are you studying JavaScript if we
can just do it through e-mail?
Now this is why.
Because we want to do it dynamically.
That's why we are going to do it through JavaScript.
All right.
So what I'm going to name this new element is going to be new item.
This is actually a better way than that.
Are going to say document.
We are going to go into document and we are going to say create element.
That's it.
So what is the element that you want to create?
It's ANELLI.
That's how simple it is.
And now Anelli has been created.
Now, it's nowhere to be found, of course, but the line has been created.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to do to console locks to console and
not console luck.
So the first console is going to be the Diaa.
And we are going to take a look at the new item.
So what?
It is an ally, of course, but when I click on it, we are going to see all these properties and methods
that we can apply exactly like any other HDMI element that we have.
And it here it says e-mail.
And so we have created successfully an element.
So after that, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say Konzerthaus lock new item.
Let's take a look at it, what it is.
So now we have successfully created an ally and this method is better because you don't have to worry
about the opening tag, the closing tag, whether an element has an opening tag or not.
This this way is better.
We let JavaScript decide what element it is.
We just give it the name.
If you want to create an ally, just give it the element name, OK?
You can create by element names.
You want to create a you'll just give it to you.
Well, that said.
So this is the first step in the first step.
I'm just going to go ahead and name it.
So in the first step, the element is created in the second step.
What do we have in the second step?
The element is given content or text.
The element is.
Given content slash text, right, because now you can see that this element is completely empty.
There is nothing inside of it.
So what we are going to do is we are going to say new item, dot, inner text.
This is where the inner text comes in.
And you might ask, OK, why don't you use inner content?
Because inner content is going to show the content as though it is inside the document.
And we do not want that.
We want to show the content as though it is inside the Web page, because ultimately when we create
a new item, we want to showcase it inside the browser.
So why don't we start there?
So the enter content is cute, super simple.
Now you guys can see that it has updated and now it has a content inside of it.
So we have successfully created another ally and we have given it some content.
I'm just going to go ahead and zoom and this console a bit more.
So this is better visible now and now it is the turn of the third step and the final.
Now we need a parent for the element to housesit in.
We need a parent for the element to append it to.
All right, now we want we need we need a parent to adopt.
Adopt this element.
That's how simple it is.
We have created the element, we do have a child.
Now we have to give it to a foster home.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and let's grab our, you know, items.
They are adopted by us, right.
So let's grab our you and let's make it adopt this elai.
And this is like fully in our control.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's find the parent.
All right.
So we are going to look for the parent.
OK, like like you are in like an adoption agency.
They look for parents like we are looking for a parent.
And let's go ahead and let's find a parent.
But the difference is this is way easier, OK, with computer.
And real world is really difficult.
All right, so we have query selector and now let's go ahead and scrub the parent.
It is as simple as this.
Now we have grabbed the parent and now let's go ahead and let's introduce the child to the parent and
give it to the parent.
And that's it.
All right.
And then we are going to say list dot, append child.
What is the child that we want to spend?
It is the new item.
It is Billy Batson, save it, and now here we go, it's as cute, see, and it doesn't matter how many
times you refresh that, it's always going to be there.
It is always going to be there.
And now we have that's why Method four and Method five were related to one another.
We have successfully created another element.
All right, so this is going to be it for this lecture in the next lecture, we are going to talk about
different, other, different ways that we can insert e-mail elements into our Web pages dynamically.
See you guys in the next lecture.