Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to go over the matching part five.
All right, so in the previous lecture, we ended at matching all the letters and numbers and also the
underscore, but now we are going to go over the matching, not all the letters numbers and underscore.
So we are going to match which what is not a letter, a number and the underscore.
So let's go ahead and let's create our regex.
So we are going to Raj a 17 X now.
What should we put in here now?
In the previous lecture we put a lowercase W to match all the letters.
Numbers underscore this time we are going to put an uppercase.
That's why I told you that you have to make sure that it is a lowercase this time it is going to be
the uppercase.
So the uppercase W matches.
It's Kopit, that's oh, he did copy matches everything that is not A through Z and zero through nine
and underscore.
So let's create our search and we are going to say search 17 result.
And we are going to say that we want to grab our sentence and we want to match it with what?
With this regular expression number 17 and we want to talk to the console, the results.
So we are going to say search 17 results.
And if I save it now, you can see it matched everything except the letters, the numbers and the underscore.
So we have an underscore.
We don't see it here.
We have numbers.
We have letters.
But you only have.
So I accept that anything except that.
So the space says this at the percentage, the ampersand, whatever there is, if that's not a number,
a letter and underscore it is going to match it.
So so this is an example.
Number 17, let's dive into the example.
Number 18 now the in the example number 18, we are just going to go ahead and match all the numbers
so that 18.
X be equal to so how can we match excuse me, all the numbers, just the numbers, nothing else.
We don't care about the.
We don't care about the symbols and the characters and the like, the letters, nothing, we just care
about the numbers.
Now before going there, I'm just going to come in this one out and I'm going to you know what?
I'm going to come in this result and this.
So let's just grab it and come into the back end of that part of this comment and I want to comment
this one out, we can get the property length as well.
So the length is 48.
I just wanted to show you this length as well, because we are going to use it below as well.
So now let's come in this one out.
All right.
So in here, we just we are just going to go ahead and provide aid.
That's it.
So when you provide a lower case, D. it is going to match all the numbers.
If you provide an uppercase D, it is going to match not all the numbers.
So or it is going to match all non numbers, all numbers.
All non numbers.
OK, so I should provide I should grab this.
I should say non ladder's.
I should say, not numbers and not underscore.
Right, so nonono not a right, let's copy these three and let's put them right here.
Copy this for there and change the search results 17 to search results 18.
That's comment out the length first.
So we just get the numbers.
That's it.
So the numbers are from zero to nine so it just provides the numbers.
But if I were to comment that out and grab the length, so there are 22 digits inside this string.
So that's what basically the length is going to give us.
Now, moving on to example, number eight, number 19 as we want to match all nine numbers.
Right.
So match all numbers.
So for matching all numbers, basically, we have the same thing here.
The only difference says and you guess you're right, we are going to pass in a capital city.
Right.
And we are going to change all 18 to 19 and save it.
So it matches everything.
That is not a number.
So you can see that it has grabbed the symbols.
It has grabbed the letters, uppercase, lowercase space, whatever, as long as it is not in number
and we can get the length as well.
The length is 100 Arri.
So this is example number 19.
We are going to go ahead and we are going to talk about example number 20, and this is going to be
the last example that I cover in this lecture, and it is matching all the white space.
Now, the white space could be space.
Could we enter, could be tapped, could be whatever.
As long as it is white space, we can grab it.
Right.
And now I'm sure you are getting to know what these are.
So we are now this is what we are looking for.
This is what we are going to discuss.
It is grabbing all the white space, not all the white space.
We have talked about the deep, lower case, upper case, lower case and upper case.
So we are getting around.
Right.
So let's create our regular expression.
It is rejects 20 X and how can we match all the whitespace?
We just provide s that set and we want to grab all.
We want to print all of it.
That's why we provide the G.
We want to grab globally all of them.
Right.
So we can go ahead and copy these and put them right here.
And that's uncommon this.
Uncommon this.
And I'm going to grab this 19 oops.
I'm going to grab the 19 and I'm going to throw that, I'm going to select everything, save it.
And now you can see that we have grabbed all the white space.
I know.
Like if I had tab there ahead to enter, it is going to throw an error, like it's another line.
So it's if I put multiple tabs and if I save it, we selected that multiple terms, like, let's put
it at this start.
Yeah, it is going to just provide because all of them, they are basically just one space, so it is
going to grab all the white space, see?
So now let's go ahead and remove all the tabs there.
So.
So this is what it is going to give us.
It is going to give us all the white space, the white space, be the white space being created by space,
enter whatever.
Right.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.