Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to display recipes to the screen.
All right, so before going forward, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab these items, this one,
this one and this one, and I'm going to common them out.
Right, so let's cut them out, save it so we just click, you can see all of them are commented out
and if we come here now, we can see there is nothing here.
All right, so.
Inside here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to tag on and one more thing here.
So for that, for me to be able to show you what actually that is that I'm adding there, I'm going
to say console Dahlborg response data.
So we have our response data.
And from there we get the hits and from the hits, let's get the recipe.
So let's say that let's come here.
Let's say Salyut.
And we get undefined recipe, right, so we get hits.
Oh, so let's do let's save it.
Let's do salad one more time.
Why did we get undefined?
The reason that we got undefined was because this recipe this is actually an object.
So in fact it is an array item.
So this array has 30 items and this is one of them.
So we cannot just say recipe dot Rike response data hits the recipe.
We need to loop over that.
That's why we need a function.
So I just wanted to show you that and now let's create our function.
So in this function.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create a recipe element and this recipe element is going to be
the element that this.
Recipe results is going to adopt, right so down here now, let's go over the recipe results and let's
loop over that loop over them recipe results.
So where is recipe a recipe results dot for each.
And we are going to say, I'm just going to say recipe results or recipe.
Russ, recipe results, and we are going to run an arrow function, so each time we get a single results,
what do we want to do to it?
We want to add add on to this to this recipe element.
Now we want to add it on to it.
So we need to add a plus ecocide.
So a recipe element.
Recipe element, and we are going to say, plus equal and let's create our tactics now in here, I'm
not going to go over the trouble of creating the element.
We already have the structure for that element.
So I'm just going to grab it from here.
It doesn't matter whichever one you grab and it just go ahead and put it here and now make sure the
indentation is correct.
So grab all of these had a tab and these are indented perfectly.
All right.
So we have our image element and then diff and then add another perfect.
So what where is the source for that image?
I'm just going to remove this piece.
Where is the source for that image?
The source for the image is a recipe let's put in our tactics.
So I'm just going to put in the tactics and we are going to see inside them recipe results, dart recipe,
dot image.
So this is going to give us the image and then we need to grab the recipe title.
What is the recipe title we are going to say?
I'm just going to copy this line because it's repeated everywhere.
So that recipe dot label you remember, right?
Label, you know what?
I'm just going to copy this line.
It's repeated.
So that's going to be the recipe title.
And for the view recipe, we are going to we are not going to change anything here, but we are going
to change the it's rough because that's what's responsible.
That's what's responsible for showing the actual recipe.
So let's put that here and then it is what you are.
But keep in mind, if you collect this, it is going to open within the same directory.
That's not something that we want.
So we are going to say target.
Underscore blank, right, so that's that now let's come inside the recipe description, and we can't
we can grab our calories right and in front of the calories, I can create this.
So it is not calories.
Calories, right.
And then we have our diet label just put in this and it is diet labels.
Right.
And in front of this, we are going to get our health labels, health labels.
And finally, we get the sauce, so let's create this, put it here and sauce.
Now, we have created our aliment.
We need a parent to adopt this element.
And what is that parent?
That parent is going to be our search results.
So I'm going to come down here.
Now, keep in mind that you should be within this for each, because each time that this element is
being created, it is being adopted at the same time.
So we are going to say search results.
That inner HTML.
In our e-mails should be recipe.
Let's save it and let's check out our exchanges.
Let's see if there is any error so we can debug it or hopefully there shouldn't be anything.
So let's say solid saw it.
And after that, we do start solid.
We can see there is no error and we can see that there is one row, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine and 10.
So we get 30.
Right.
But and let's check it out.
So if I click on this, we go to another page that is eating well, dot com and it is chicken salad,
stuffed tomatoes.
So stuffed chicken salad, stuffed tomatoes.
And it's you can see that the health label is undefined and the dirth labels, it works, but the health
label is undefined.
And you can see that the calories is also like a large number.
So let's do something about that.
So first off, I'm going to say to fixed.
And we just need to two of them, right, two of the decimal points, so now if I search for solid,
we should only get two decimal points and we do.
But still, the health label is undefined.
Maybe it's a typo.
So health like labels?
Yes, it was a typo.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
Let's check Salyut.
And we do get the health level as well, so some of them do have a diet level, they're both somewhat
don't have some of them do have.
So it's calories, low carb diet label, health label and source.
And when click on The View source, it is going to get you there.
Shrimp salad.
You can't search for anything.
Of course, we are done with this application, so all if.
All right, so we get Olive.
It's a little slower, but we do get that, so if we do figure.
For example, fake GM, perfect.
You can see that you are going to get a recipes to be able to create cheese.
What is that fig jam?
Or you can just go ahead and grab that.
I don't know what's now loading the images.
It should load that.
So.
So bring this up to the console, some messages, let's go to the network, I'm just going to detach
it.
And inside the network.
You know, it's like on this one and then.
It's blocking some things, nine coquis.
All right, so inside the network.
Let's do fig jam until one more time, and now we get that if I click on it, it says the method is
status code is 200.
This is the method and it is coming from that.
Our API request.
You can see that it's exactly the same thing that we have inserted.
And this is a query fig jam.
And this is the response that we get headers and a lot of different stuff.
And this is our object, right?
30 inside of it.
So we get the recipe URL.
This is the arrow sorry array.
This is the object itself.
And inside there we get all these different.
So you can go ahead and grab any of the information that you want.
For example, ingredients, ingredient lines and yields.
You are I and a total wait.
Total time.
What else.
Total daily.
You can see that this is a massive API zenk, it's got this many in this person, Zenk, what is that?
This is vitamin K, vitamin D, vitamin B 12.
So it gives you the nutritional facts nor nutrition facts as well.
So it should be calcium then.
We have energy.
Kalari This is you can paste these so you can put these to the use for the user as well.
And that is when you want to create like a very, very extensive application.
What is this beer?
Can roasted chicken affect jam source?
We are.
All right.
So that's going to be it for this lecture and this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.