Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about Arah functions and lexical this.
All right, so let's come back to our neighborhood friendly lexical this and also narrow functions.
All right.
So here we have a movie shop object inside of which we have a property movie and a method movie.
Funt And we are using the.
Implicit binding or the context or the context object to call this function all right.
And in here inside the movie Funk, we have a timer which is which uses an arrow function as a callback
function and is going to run this movie.
All right.
So what do you think this is going to refer in the context of this era function right now?
The this keyword inside this error function, because error functions, they are not hardbound functions,
it is with any other lexical, with any other lexically scoped variable, it is going to go one level
up the chain or one level of the scope because this lock console is not referenced in here.
Console log is going to go on the floor.
But what about this?
This movie?
If we look at the call site, movie shop, dot movie Funt, this movie funk is called Right Here, but
from the movie Funk, we have no idea what this is going to refer to.
But when the console log is going to come one level up inside this movie funk, then we know that movie
funk is a function which is this aware arrow functions can never become this aware.
Now many people have in their minds a mental model that an arrow function is essentially a hardbound
function.
All right.
But that is not accurate.
The proper way to think about an arrow function is an arrow function does not define at this keyword
at all.
There is no such thing as a this key word in an arrow function.
That's why in tutorials you're going to see they're going to define like a variable like let Salaf equal
to this and then they're going to use this inside the arrow function.
But actually the best way to do that is just use a regular function.
All right.
All right, so in here, what we have is so that this is going to if I just log this, we are not going
to get anything relating to this arrow function.
We are going to see hell or high water is a masterpiece.
The reason for that is because we can we can get a reference for the council log.
It is going to go one level up.
And this movie funk is going to become a this hour function.
And this our function is called right here on this context object of movie shop.
And this movie shop has a movie property.
So this movie is going to reference that.
And if I can't Sloggett, we can see that it says hell or high water is a masterpiece.
So an error function is a function that doesn't have a this at all, right, and so it resolves it lexically,
it just keeps going and going and going up until it finds a function that defines a this cure.
And whatever the discover points for that function, that's what it what it is going to use.
OK.
And in the SPAC, it says that an arrow function doesn't have an arrow function, doesn't define local
bindings for arguments super this and new target.
So to rob this lecture up an arrow function is a function that doesn't define a this kiwa.
The reason that I created this is because the lexical this tends to confuse many people.
All right.
And especially beginners.
But actually what lexical this is, it's like any other variable.
It is going to go one level up the chain to find any function that is this hour.
And it is going to point at how that function is called that set.
Very, very simple.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.