Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to detect the edges of the canvas.
All right, so what are we going to do first is I'm just going to get rid of this line of code right
here and now before diving into the detection, we need to specify the other directions that the ball
is going to move as well.
So we are going to say F now, in case you're wondering why we are not using the F alse, because each
of these F statements, they have to work separately from the other.
So if you use if else own like you use F statement and then you are going to have three else clauses.
Right.
And then that in that case we can only travel in one direction and the ball is not going to travel diagonally.
And why is that?
Because only one of the conditions can can can become true.
But in this case, two conditions can can be true.
But in the case of F ls, only one condition can be true.
No.
Two conditions.
So if you have F and F else, in no circumstance the F and if else can be true together, that's what
we are looking for.
We want two conditions to be true together.
For example, if you want to move the ball to the bottom direction and to the left direction.
So the bottom end, left, right.
I'm going to show it to here.
So this is going to be bottom and this is going to be left.
If you do bottom left, you're going to get a diagonal movement of the ball.
So you can see that I'm going to show you to see.
So if I want to move it to top and to right, I'm going to get a diagonal move.
So top right.
See, bottom left, top left, bottom right.
So now you can get a diagonal movement as well.
You have to keep that in mind.
If you change on these if statements, then only one condition can be true.
But we don't want to do that.
The same goes goes to this our own parts.
The same goes to these ones.
It's basically the same ideology.
So for the second one, I'm going to say if the down direction is true, grab the position of Y for
that for that ball and then do what?
Because in the down direction it's positive.
We are just going to add the speed to that coordinate of the ball so the ball is going to move down.
Let's save it, check it out here.
So now the ball is moving down, the ball is moving up.
We are not detecting the edges.
We are going to do that in this lecture as well.
And now let's do the same thing for the extraction.
So if the left direction is true, do what grabbed the extraction and from the extraction, subtract
the speed, because when we are moving to the left, we are actually moving in the negative direction
of X, right.
That's why we are going to subtracted from the speed.
And finally, what we have for the right is for the right dir to be true.
Grab the X position and from the X position.
Just add speed to it.
So now let's save it.
Check it out, huh?
Going up, going down.
Going left, going right.
So going diagonally.
Going diagonally.
And there we go.
So now this is done.
The only thing remaining for us to do is to detect the edges.
So I'm just going to come here and I'm going to write collision detection.
How can we detect the edge?
Well, basically, the way that we can detect the age for the most part, is going to be just using
gift statements.
So first off, I'm just going to create a function and I'm going to call it collision detection.
With a small CD section, you can call it boundary detection as well, doesn't matter as long as you
get the idea.
So first off, let's do collision detection for the.
I'm going to do for the top direction because that's top boundary.
That's the convention that we have done so far.
So I'm going to say f the Y position of the ball is less than the radius.
You know what, I'm going to do it for the bottom first so that in that case it makes much more sense.
I can explain it better that way.
So bottom boundary and I'm going to say f the Y position of the ball y position of the ball is greater
than canvas element height.
All right, do what?
So let's see guns on that log.
Uh.
Collision.
Detec.
Come on, I'm just going to say detected collision is very difficult to spell.
So now what does that mean?
What does that canvas element Dutkiewicz mean?
So this is our canvas, right?
This this blue box and this top part of the canvas.
What is the height for the top part of the canvas?
The height for the top part of the canvas is zero because that's where the canvas originates from.
So the original point of the canvas is always going to be this top left corner for the why it's going
to be this point.
So this point is actually zero.
Why?
And what is it for the X?
For the X?
This is going to be the zero X as well.
So if I move from this line, which is the top part of the height of the canvas, which is in this in
this entire line, the Y is always going to be zero.
Keep in mind, we are not talking about the X, we're just talking about the Y.
So in this case, we can see that we have not moved even by one pixel in the Y direction.
So the Y is zero.
And now keep in mind that now let's say that we travel all the way to here.
So this is where the canvas ends now.
Here is where the canvas is height s.
So we have said that the canvas height is 600, so zero pixels all the way to 600 pixels at the point
of 600 pixel.
We have the canvas height.
If the Y position of the ball, which is the center of the ball, keep in mind the Y position of the
ball and the X position of the ball is going to be the center of that ball if the center of the ball
passes this.
So it's going to be something like this.
You can see that we are going to fire that event.
OK, it didn't fire.
Right?
Let's come here.
So what's happening here?
So we said, oh, we did not call this collision detection.
So what I'm going to do as I'm going to call the collision detection, that's why the function is not
doing anything.
Now, if the center of this ball.
Passes, come on, man.
All right, so if the center of this ball passes, the canvas is height, we should bring something
to the console.
So let's bring this down.
There we go, you can see that the collision is being continuously detected and you can see that the
collision is not detected because the center of the ball is not passing the height.
So this is when the collision is being detected.
But the cool thing is that and the weird part is that we do not want to determine the collision right
at the center of the ball.
We want to determine the collision at the circumference of the ball, not the center of the ball.
This is where things get interesting, not weird.
I take back what I said.
Interesting.
All right.
So when the position of the ball, the Y position is greater than the canvas is height y position is
for 300 when it is like 600 and one, we are going to fire this event.
So if I clear it and if I come down here, you can see that this event is continuously being fired.
I'm going to zoom in so you can really see it like that.
See, this has been fired continuously.
So in order to detect the center of the ball collision with this canvas height, what we can just do
is whenever the ball is right here, just go ahead and stop the ball to here.
Do not go down.
But this is not called this is not collision detection.
All right, so what is collision detection?
Collision detection is whenever the ball hits the ball, circumference hits this bottom of the canvas.
That's what so we need to add on.
We need to add on this radius.
The distance, which is from the center of the circle to any side of the circle, is going to be the
radius.
And you can see that if this is our circle, we have four sets.
So we have top.
We have left, we have right and we have bottom.
So the top part is going to be determined whenever we want to collide with the top part of the canvas,
the left part of the circle is going to be determined.
The radius, whenever we want to collide with the left part of the canvas and so on.
Bottom, bottom and right and right, right.
So now we need to pass in the radius somehow, somewhere.
So if I say that the Y p and if I go ahead and if I add it here, let's see what's going to happen.
So the radius plus that and we should see it.
So now if I come here.
Right at the edge, right at where we get the edge, you can see that this event is being fair.
So it means, you know, I can't, like, actually get it to go there.
So I'm just going to decrease the speed to, for example, one pixel at a time.
So now this this is going to be better.
So whenever it touches this, that edge, the event is being fired.
See, so now this is called collision detection.
So there is another way of doing it as well, and that is if I just remove the radius from here.
OK.
And say, canvasses, height minus radius, this is going to detect that for us as well.
So let's come down here.
And there we go.
So it's actually up to you which way you want to do it, if this way makes more sense that the white
position plus the radius, so radius is going to be 50.
So we are going to have six of 350.
Right.
And whenever we pass the 600 mark by by an amount greater than 600, which is going to be traversed
by this, the position of the ball, then the edge of the canvas is going to be detected.
Right.
And so whichever way is cooler for you, you can suffice to that.
You can do that.
And it's actually OK, because in both cases we are we are going to detect the edge of the screen.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to leave it right here, or I think
it is going to make most sense if I just leave it here and we say, why plus radius.
So now, instead of doing this, what I want to do is I want to grab the Y position and I'm going to
say canvas element, height minus radius.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
Let's see what we get.
So if I come down here.
There we go, so we can no longer go down, right?
So if we were to now what what it is that we have done here, so we have changed the wipers whenever
the position of the ball plus the radius is greater than the height.
What do we want?
Do we want to reposition that ball?
So the.
And in which direction?
In the wide ruction.
So in the right direction.
This Y position.
Where is it?
It's it's 300.
Right.
Initially it's 300.
But when it does touch, it has touched the bottom of the canvas.
We want to change their value to the canvas height, which is 600 minus the radius, which is 50.
All right, so you can do this as well, and for this to make a better sense, I'm just going to put
the radius right here so you can see that if it is greater than the canvas height, just just make this
can white position equal to that canvas height minus radius.
And I'm just going to specify a plus an equality sign here in case it is equal to or greater than that.
Then we want to fire that event.
Now, if we do not provided the equality sign.
I hope I can show it to you.
And we should see detected what you might ask.
What is the difference.
So if I come down here.
Oh, boy.
There we go.
You can see that it says detected, but if you look closely here, it seems as though I you know, it
seems that the ball is is moving out of the screen by at least one pixel because the ball has to move
off the canvas for this to be detected.
So we don't want to do that.
We want to say if it is equal or greater than that whenever the ball touches it or goes off of it,
we just want to position that.
So let's save this now.
Let's put it to back to ten.
It was.
So right here now you can see that we are not moving off the screen, even by one pixel, and this event
is being fired.
OK, so we have done collision detection for one one part of our.
Our canvas, so collision detection for the left, for the right and for the top are still remaining.
I planned on completing this collision detection in one lecture, but it seems like I have to spin it
over to lectures.
So in the next lecture, the ideology is going to be similar, but the direction is going to be different.
So what we are going to do is in the next lecture we're going to apply this collision detection principles
for the left, right and up part of our canvas.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.