Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to hide and show Århus.
All right, so first off, what I need to do is I'm going to go to our next button and we are going
to apply the Hyde and show arrows there.
And then we are going to play it on the previous button.
We could do all that.
And what we could do is we could not do that and we could just create a function, complete the process
there, and then just call the function here, which makes the most sense.
Right.
So that is actually the professional way of doing it.
And the reason that I did that, that I created the move to image function at the end of the previous
lecture was to show you how this process works, to show you where those numbers they come from.
All right, so first off, what I'm going to do as.
I'm going to create a function.
All right, but in real world, this is how it is done.
So I'm just going to call the real the real world function.
I'm going to call it the height show, Arrow's very generic name.
And I'm going to call it I'm going to call our const variable and I'm going to name it Height Show and
Rose.
Hijo Århus, and let's create the function itself, and we are going to have a bunch of parameters here,
so the first parameter is going to be our images array, then we are going to have our previous button
because we want this function to be called within the previous button's event listener and we want it
to be called within the next button event listener.
And we want to grab the target index as well.
And I'm going to tell you where this target index comes from now in our next button event listener,
we have a next index.
And in the previous we have a previous index, which we have not used yet.
This is why we have created this index.
OK, and you guys can see it's a bit like the color of this is different than the color of this because
this has not been used.
OK, it has not been accessed now.
Instead of calling this target index, the next index or the previous index, we are just going to call
that the targeting index is the same methodology that we used for naming convention that we use for
target image, because when we want this function to be universal, we cannot specify.
We kind of like restricted to just the next image or the previous image.
The same goes to this, so whenever we talk about the targeted index in the next button context, the
targeted index is going to be the next index and the pre and the previous button context, the target
index is going to be the previous index index, next index index, previous index.
I keep saying index.
It's not like that.
So we are going to add an IF statement because we want to control the flow of our program.
And we say if the target index is equal to zero, then what do we want to do now?
Let's let's talk about the logic here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to our finished version and we are going to go to our our
first image now indices in JavaScript, they start from zero.
Right.
So the first image must have an index of zero.
And we say when the target index is zero, what do we want to do?
We want to apply the hidden class on the previous button.
And what does the heading class have inside of it?
It has a display of Ainun inside of it.
So what does it mean?
Whenever we are on our first image, which has an index of zero, we want to we want to remove our.
Or disappear or hide.
Our previous button, and whenever we are on the last image or a lost index, we want to.
Hide the next button, so actually we are going to have three scenarios, the first scenario is going
to be the first image.
The second scenario is going to be the last image, which is come on, buddy, which is this one.
This is the second scenario.
And the third scenario is all the images in between where we have both of our buttons available or shown
on the screen.
So we actually have three scenarios that we have to work with.
So let's go ahead and let's first off talk about the first scenario.
So in the first scenario, when targeting Dix's zero, it means our first images showing we just talked
about it.
We are going to say previous button and what do we want to do?
We want to add a clause to it.
And what is the class, the classes headed and what does this mean?
It means that whenever we are on our first image, the previous button is going to be headed and the
next button.
Is going to have a class list and we are going to remove in case it has that class.
We are going to remove the class of heroine from it.
So this is our first scenario in the second scenario.
What do we have is whenever we are on our last image.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to grab this target index and I'm
going to post it right here.
So how can we grab the last item of an array?
We don't how can we do that?
We access the array and we say depth length.
And what is the last item or what is the index?
For the last item, we just add minus one.
So minus one is going to give us the last index for the last item in an array.
We have talked about this, how we can get the last item within an array and if the target index equals
to the index of the last image.
Now we have 10 images in this array.
Right.
So the last image is going to be image number ten.
But what is the index of that image?
It's going to be nine because length is always one more than the number of images sorry, one more than
the number of the index.
So index, the final or the largest index in an array is always going to be one less than the length.
One less than the.
And when this happens, it means we are on our last image, so let's go to the last image and what happens
in this last image.
The previous button is shown, the next button is headed.
So previous button.
Is shown, it means that we remove the head in class.
And the next button is heaven.
It means that we aren't the hidden costs.
Next.
OK, so now two scenarios are done, but what if what if we are in between where we can see both of
our our arrows or both of our buttons?
So what about then, what about in this case?
So what do we want to do in this case?
So in every other scenario and every other scenario means that we are in between.
Either we are on the second slide, third slide, fourth slide, fifth image on the sixth image.
You want to call it damage.
Your slide doesn't really matter.
You could call this a gallery slider as well.
The way we use these names interchangeably, even if we are on the image number nine image and image
number eight, image number seven, as long as we are not on the first image and we are not on the last
image, then this else is going to kick in and we are going to grab our previous button and we are going
to say class list.
We are going to remove the head in class.
From the previous button, and we are going to remove the head and glass from the next, but let's save
it and now this function is not going to work because it has not been called.
So let's grab it.
Let's face it, right here and now, inside the function, call less pass in the arguments.
So the first argument that we are going to passant is going to be the images itself.
And what is the second argument is going to be the previous button, then the next button.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and let's pass those in.
So we have previous B10 next veton.
Next, Beaton, and after that, we are we have a targeted index, which we had a very long discussion
about.
So the target, the index and the context of this event listener is going to be the next index.
So I'm just going to go ahead and copy it and I'm going to call it here and I'm going to copy this.
And I'm going to call this function in here as well.
And this is our previous segment, The Listener now Imagists, previous button, next button.
But instead of the next index, we are going to grab the previous index.
Let's save it.
So now.
I mean, right.
OK, so for this class to work, we should provide it with a reference, so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to add a button here as well so that BTN that hidden.
Now let's save it.
Let's come here.
We can we can still see both of our buttons.
And, um, let's go ahead and let's remove the B10 from here and let's add it by default, our hidden
button.
Let's save it and let's come here.
So now you guys can see we are on the first image.
The previous button is has been hidden.
But when I, when I just click on the next button, the previous button comes back.
If I go back it goes away.
It should go away.
Come on, buddy.
It's I think we should reload it and why do we have to reload every time it should go automatically?
So let's take a look at the code.
So whenever we are on our previous button, we want to add the head in class to the previous button
on the first target index is zero.
And you want to remove it from head entry and remove it from previous added to next, remove it from
both places.
I mean, we don't have any errors here.
This code should work technically.
All right, so we have called it images previous previous index and images, previous button and next
index.
So let's say let's open up the live server one more time, it should work.
So let's click on it, it comes and let's go to the last image.
And this one is not disappearing.
It should disappear.
Save it.
We got our first image.
It does disappear.
Let's go to our e-mail and let's see.
So this is the button.
All right.
We have selected it right here.
It is the button, right.
And this is the bottom left.
OK, so what are going to do is I'm just going to open with live server one more time, so if I go there,
it appears that if I come back, it does not go away.
So the rest of the code worked.
So we are going to go inside this next button and now this part doesn't work.
So let's go ahead and let's consider log it.
What is that console.
That log.
Let's grab our next index.
Let's save it.
Let's check it out here.
So if I go into the inspect and if I go to the console, trash everything.
OK, so let's close this one, let's click, we get a negative one, but the index of the next image
is one.
We should not get a negative one.
Negative one is returned whenever there are.
Now, this method runs this find index and it returns to negative one when it cannot find anything right
here, find the index or otherwise find index returns a negative one.
If such an element is found, find index immediately returns that element index.
Otherwise it returns.
Find index returns minus one.
So this clearly doesn't work.
So let's go ahead and let's remove our function.
And instead of our regular function, we are going to use an arrow function, we have not gone over
the syntax yet, but we are going to go over the syntax.
So in here, we are going to use an arrow function and we are going to see if that is going to work
and you are going to basically do the same thing, but save it.
OK, so this is an arrow function.
We are going to go over it.
And now let's click on this.
You can see cannot access this next index before, OK?
It should not be next and it should be next image.
So m m g.
Save it, let's click on it one more time and now we get one.
All right.
So we get two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight and nine.
So the final image has an index of nine.
So now we have successfully been able to grab the index.
So I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to paste it right here.
And instead of next, an image, we are going to see previous image.
And now let's say that that's come here and let's close the console.
So now when I click, the arrow appears.
When I click back, the arrow disappears.
So that was a minor like minor hurdle along the way of coding this project.
And now let's go to the last image and now the last arrow disappears.
As what?
So now we should have used the arrow function in here and when we used it, the problem is solved.
So that is it for this chapter and for this project.
See you guys in the next one.