Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about the array with this method.
All right, so the reduced method executes a reduced function that you provide on each element of the
array, resulting in a single output value.
So we are going to get a single output value right now.
Let's go ahead and let's dive into this lecture so we have an array of numbers, one through five.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a variable called total.
And in here I'm going to call this arrays array and I'm going to I'm going to grab the array and I'm
going to call the reduced method on that array.
So this method is going to call it is going to grab a callback function.
The callback functions name is going to be some and there is going to be an initial value.
All right.
So the initial value, I'm just going to pass in zero.
Now, what it is that we are actually trying to do here, we want to grab this number zero.
And each time the function grabs each of these values, each of the items of this array, we want to
combine their sum this with the zero.
So the first one plus zero, we are going to get one and then two plus the initial value of zero changed
from zero to one.
So this is going to be three and then three plus three.
We are going to get six and then four plus six, we are going to get ten and then five plus ten we are
going to get 50, something like that.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is let's go ahead and let's create the function.
The function is some right.
And we are going to have two parameters in here.
The first one is going to be a cumi accumulator and the second one is going to be value.
So the accumulator has it and an original value of zero.
Right.
And this value is going to be the value that is going to be passed by from this array into like in here.
And now what do we want to do when this function runs?
We want to return the accumulator plus the value.
All right.
So now let's oops.
Let's go ahead.
Now, we have created this function and we have called it here.
That's Longet to the console our results.
And let's see what what we are going to get so total.
Let's save it.
We get 15 and I'm just going to do this one more time.
So in the first the first time that this callback function grabs the items from this array in the first
the first time that it does that the accumulator is zero because this is the original value of the accumulator
and the value is going to be one six zero plus one.
We are going to get one and this zero is going to return to one.
And this is going to go on all the way to this to the final item, because before the final item, we
just have one plus zero.
We get one, then two plus one.
Remember, now this is one.
We get three, three plus three.
We get six for plus six.
We get ten.
Five plus ten.
We get 50.
All right.
So this is the array reduced method.
See you guys in the next lecture.