Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create the add superhero method.
All right, so we have called the method right here.
So what do we need to do is we need to go up here and we need to really define this method.
Right.
So.
What we are going to do is, first off, let's think what this method requires, because this is the
superhero method, this is the most important method that we have.
So this adds superhero method is going to grab our entry from here and is going to add it here.
So this is the stage where we create our dynamic elements.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here is, first off, we are going to grab the parent.
So we are going to say CONSED, I'm going to call it less data.
You might be wondering what parent that is.
It's this parent.
You can see it's empty.
It requires children.
So we are going to grab it and append children to it.
So we are going to say document, query selector and what is the class.
The class is going to be super hero.
A superhero lest data, we have successfully selected that and now what we are going to do is we are
going to create the list container so list.
OK, const consed.
Well let's go up consed list container.
Right.
And we are going to say document to create element.
So this element that we are creating here is actually going to be a well and all of our list items,
they are going to go inside the sewer.
And before doing that I want to grab this list container and I want to add an attribute to it.
What is the attribute?
The attribute is going to be ID, what is the value for that attribute?
It's going to be list.
Now, what I want to do is I want to grab this list container and I want to push children to it.
What are those children?
Those children are actually the superhero entries that the user makes.
So name universe and power and also along with that trash icon.
So we are going to list container dot enter e-mail berganza plus equal because if you just say cool
and you create a superhero and you create a second one, the second one is going to override the first
one.
So what you need to do is you need to make sure that the second one is added to the first one.
That's why we say add on like that.
Let's use our very favorite template strengths.
Now we are going to create an ally here.
All right.
So I'm going to say Elai and for wriggly.
So this is our element.
Now, what is this element going to grab?
This element is going to grab the superhero name.
Where is it going to grab it from the entry that we have.
All right.
So if I were to create this, we would say that entry dart superhero name where?
A superhero name.
Superhero name.
All right.
So the entry is going to be passed from here.
But this superhero name entry, that superhero name is going to come from right here, the value that
we have here, because these values have been passed here.
Then from here, they have been passed here and from here we are actually using it.
Where where are we?
We are going to use it here.
All right.
So we know what we are doing.
Right.
So when we say entry, this is the entry that we say and because it has a property on it, property,
superhero name and superhero universe, superhero power.
When we say entry, that superhero name, it is going to give us this value entry.
That superhero universe is going to give us this value entry, that superhero power is going to give
us this value.
So we are just going to do it like that.
And I'm going to copy it two more times and I'm going to say universe.
And we are going to say power.
And now, finally, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create our icon, so it is I with a class that
is equal to fair.
Yes, this is the class for trash icon.
So it's FASFA trash.
And let's put in the closing tag.
So this is it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.