Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we will handle filling the boxes.
All right, so let's go ahead.
Actually.
Create the logic for that.
So what I'm going to do inside are we're just going to collapse this one for now inside our Haisla and
select site right beneath here.
What I would like to do here is.
We are going to select and fill the square, right?
So, first off, I'm going to create a variable and that is going to be filled square and I'm going
to set it to false because initially we don't have any squares filled.
Then we are going to loop over our current selves for let sell of current cells if.
Our squares.
If our squares and in the squares we have rows and in the squares, we also have columns or so we have
row column, if that's going to be if that side is selected.
So we are going to call in our select site.
If that is selected, we are going to say that the right.
So let's get out of here as well.
We are going to say that Failed Square is going to be true.
Right?
So if it is that the highlighted the selected side and after all the selected sites are selected, then
we are going to say that that square is actually filled.
And right after that, I'm going to I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to cut this and I'm going to
put it right after for a loop.
So we're for a loop ends right here.
And I'm going to cut this one as well.
And I'm going to tell you where we should put that, because we need to check for the scores as well.
And then we would like to switch the player.
So f the square is true.
Felt square is true.
What it is that we want we would want to do in here.
I'm going to put in for now a comment that is we are going to handle game over and we're going to handle
it later.
For now, we have other things that we need to take care of and in the else we are going to switch the
player's turn right.
So, so far, so good.
And what I'm going to do here is I think we have created a variable called.
I don't think have we created that numb, selected?
Oh, it is inside the square class, so we have created this numb selected and and this is going to
give us the number of sites which are selected.
If they are more than if they are equal to exactly four, then we are going to fill that square.
Right.
So this is going to give us if that is if we need to fill that site so within our class.
Within the class of the square.
Let me take a look at this, should we should we do it?
Yeah, we are going to do it within this class of square.
We are going to go ahead and we are going to select the number selected and we are going to increase
it whenever any side is actually selected.
So we're in our square class where it is that we are selecting sites.
We are selecting sites right here.
OK.
So in here, hmm?
So the way that I'm doing this is going to be so here we have a switch statement and this is going to
highlight each side is going to select the highlighted side.
It is not going to highlight it.
It is going to select that side and is going to grab the owner and it is going to set it to whichever
place players turn.
It is.
And it is going to say that, yes, it is selected.
Right.
And if all of the switch statement does not return anything, what we would like to do that is in here,
as we would like to say that the highlight is not right because none of the sides have been selected.
That's why the highlight is, you know, and right after that, I'm going to grab or numb selected and
I'm going to incremented by one.
Right.
And we are going to say if if this dot, the number of selected is exactly equal to four, then we want
to basically give that the the owner who has completed four of the sites or has put on the last side.
We want to give it another turn.
So we are going to say this stud owner is going to be player's turn.
We are going to give it another turn.
Now, inside here is where we are going to handle the score.
So I'm just going to put in a comment and we are going to come back later and then we want this if statement
to return.
True.
Right.
So we wanted to return true for this.
And if this if statement does not return true, we want to return false.
It means that that a player has not completed four sides and we do not want to give it any anything,
any bonus or anything for that, for that matter.
So let's save this.
Let's come inside the browser.
So let's go ahead and let's actually test this.
So if any player completes the fourth side, they should get another turn.
So now we didn't get another turn, we should have gotten let me reload this.
And now it is not it is always switching the player from one player to the next player.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's actually check what is happening here.
So in here, what we did was we said that if it still does not return highlight, we want the highlight
to be null and we incremented the NUM selected and then we are going to save this Dunnam selected Asfour.
We want to we want to set that to the player's turn and we want to return.
True.
If it doesn't return true, we want to return false.
But we have implemented that in in our select site.
And now taking a look at this, you can see that we are iterating over this select site twice.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to get rid of that.
And I'm going to say select.
Side once, and I'm going to save it and we are going to come here and now we have to check if that
is going to work.
All right, so let's go ahead and select this, we have orange, we have green, we have orange.
Now, if I fill this, the green should get another turn.
There we go.
So I'm going to I'm going to let the orange fill this one and the orange when the orange completes the
square, the orange is going to claim another turn as well.
There we go.
It is the orange.
Just turn and then this is the orange.
And then we should get another turn and there we go.
So that is completed as well.
We have successfully handed over the turn to whoever has completed that.
The next logical thing for us to do is just to go ahead and grab that long awaited draw, fill function
and actually draw something with it.
All right.
So in here, what I would like to do first is we would like to do we would like to know if that box
is not doesn't have any owner.
If it doesn't have any owner, then we would like to return.
If it if the owner is.
No, it means it doesn't have any owner we would like to return.
All right.
So in here, let's say F.
This stud owner is not if it is, if the if there is no owner, we come on, we would like to return
from their.
All right, so I'm just going to say a return, otherwise we want to provide there a light background,
so draw a light background.
So let's grab our context and we're going to say Phil style, the film style is going to get color from
whichever players turn it is or whoever owns that sell it is going to grab it.
And we are going to say true, because we want we want to grab the light version of the color, not
the solid version.
And then we need to draw that.
So we are going to say Phil Rect.
Phil wrecked and in here, the position is going to be this dot left, plus our stroke.
And the white position is going to be this top plus the stroke.
The width is going to be this start with minus two times the strokes with two times the strokes dimension,
and we are going to have the same thing for the height as well.
But we are going to change it to this day and age.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's save it.
Let's see if it actually works out right.
There we go.
You can see that basically the stroke will allow us to you can see that the little space that there
is between this line and the starting of this box, that is going to be our stroke.
That's why we gave it a stroke.
It is just for aesthetic purposes.
The next thing that I would like to do is I would like to draw our text.
So let's go ahead and let's let's actually create the function for that.
So this is a new game.
This is select site.
We have or get color function there.
And in here, I'm going to create a function for drawing the text.
So I'm going to call it draw text function.
So let's say function, draw text.
So so far, everything is going really well in here.
We are going to pass in the text.
Now, this function is going to be called multiple times.
And whenever it is called, we are just going to call whenever we want to draw a text, we are just
going to call, this is going to have a position of X and then why the color and the size?
So they can start Phil style is going to be the color than the iconic start font is going to be our
the size.
First off, let's provide the size and then the unit, which is pixels and then the font family, which
is sans serif.
You can provide any font family that you want.
Then we have our context filled text.
We should pass in the text, the exposition and the wife is perfect.
So we have created our draw text function.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go to top and I'm going to create some variables for our text as
well.
So let's calm down our colors in here.
I'm going to say text variables.
Variables, I think, like this.
So first things first, we need a text for A.I. In this case, it is going to be player two, but I'm
just going to set it at A.I., but I'm going to give the text as player two and then I'm just going
to copy a bunch of times.
So then we are going to have a small text.
Now, keep in mind that one of the texts I'm going to I'm just going to say I smell one of the texts
is going to appear here.
The bigger text is going to appear here, like the complete name, player one, and then P1 or P2.
They're going to appear within the boxes.
So we need two versions of texts.
And it is going to be up to then we have our text player.
Which is going to be player one, then we have the text of player SML, which is going to be one.
Perfect.
So right after that, we are going to have our.
Text size, cell size cell, which is going to be equal to the cell.
Cell, our cell divided by now, you can increase this if you are divided by two, the text is going
to get increased.
If you divide it by three, the text is going to get even smaller.
So it depends on these dimensions are not hard coded.
You can change them if you want.
Then we need to have a text size top.
Which I'm just going to set it to text size top and it is going to be the margin.
Our margin that we have divided by six, we are going to have a text when it when it is a tie, not
term, it is tie and we are just going to say draw and then we are going to have a text when someone
wins and we are going to say one.
Basically, we are going to say either player won one or a player to one and then we don't need this
anymore.
So let's save that.
And let's go ahead and let's create a function that is going to give us our text and I'm going to call
that get text, so I'm just going to collapse that collapse this this one.
We have our get color right beneath there.
I'm going to grab that comment, put it right here.
We are going to call this get text.
Right.
And within this function, we want to check which players turn it this.
So we show either the small text or the object, the bigger text.
So first off, we need to check for that.
So we are going to say function, get text.
Right.
And.
And here, I'm just going to capitalize this one, and in here we're going to pass in player and we're
going to pass in small, we're going to say if it is the player, if it is the player's turn, we are
going to return and the return we are going to check for something.
If it is small, we are going to return text player small, otherwise we are going to return text player
or else it means that it is not the player's turn, it is the other players turn.
We are going to check for small.
If it is small, we are going to return the other players text, which is a small and or if a small
is not true, we are going to return the bigger text.
I became so we have created this function as well.
Now let's go ahead and let's actually.
Use this function somewhere, so inside our drawerful method that we have right here down beneath this,
what I would like to do is I would like to draw the owner's text.
So owner text and we are going to say draw a text.
Perfect, so inside the draw text, what do we have, we should pass in a text X, Y, color and size,
right?
So for the X.
Sorry for the text I'm going to pass in whichever text it is, it is going to be that get text function
that we just created and we are going to say this stud owner and we are going to set it to true.
I'm going to pass on a comment and I'm going to hit enter because we are going to have many of these.
The way that I will be creating this is going to be like exactly this, because this is a function call
of our draw text.
This is the draw text function.
We're basically calling that function down there.
But inside the function call, we are going to pass in many arguments.
So I'm just going to divide them line by line so it is easier for you to understand.
Now let's go ahead and start passing the exposition, which is going to be this star left, plus this
W time, half of this half of the width of that box.
The U.S. position is going to be the top of the box, plus half of the height of the box.
Where are we?
OK, so let's just hit enter, put in a comma there.
OK, so what is the next one we need to pass and the color.
So for the color, we are going to call in our get color function.
We are going to pass and the owner there.
And because we want to grab the.
A nice daylight color.
We are going to say false.
And finally, what is the size?
The size is going to be the text size cell.
Let's save that and let's come here.
OK, we don't see our text in here.
Oh, it should be within this.
We are basically drawing it within this box.
So let's check it out now.
It should be player, too.
There we go.
It is players, too, and we get another turn.
And at this time it should be player one.
And you can see that this is light orange and this is that dark orange.
It's not dark.
It doesn't have any opacity.
And thus this green has opacity and it doesn't have any of it.
So basically, when any of the players when the color of their text for their box is going to be the
color of their line as well as that color is going to be a.
And like it, we like sort of transparent color of their line.
So they completely match.
I'm sure you know what I mean by looking at this, so we were successful, we were able to successfully
draw the text within these boxes.
The next logical step for us is going to be drawing the scores and actually creating the players there,
drawing the scores there.
And right after that, we are going to cover handling the game over status.
So I'm not going to go ahead and I'm not going to go over the score.
And this lecture, we are going to cover score in our next lecture.
And right after that lecture, we are going to cover whenever the game is over.
What should we do then?
So see you guys in the next lecture.