Hi, everyone, in this we're going to detect the top right and left boundaries.
All right, so we have detected the bottom boundary.
What about the top one?
So for the top before actually going into the top boundary, I'm just going to go first for the right
because positive directions are easier than negative directions bottom and right there, positive directions.
And I'm going to say right boundary and you're going to say F now we are going to say we are going to
do the same thing.
So we're going to say XP is greater or equal to what?
Instead of canvas height, we are going to do canvas with minus the radius.
What do we want to do?
We want to reposition the ball and in which direction?
We want to reposition it in the extraction.
Right.
Very simple.
So the exact position of the ball is going to change to the canvas element with so what is the canvas
element that with it's going to be four hundred minus the radius, so minus the radius radius is 50.
So the exposition of the circle is going to be 350, which is right up the edge.
The circumference of the circle is going to be right at the edge of the canvas.
There we go.
So let's save it and let's come here, so if I go there, you can see that it touches the edge and it
can it can't move any any any further than that, because that is the point where we have specified
the exposition for the circle.
So the ideology for the bottom and for the right were the same and the ideology for the top and left
are going to be the same.
So Tom, boundry now before actually writing the code, let's go over the concept so hopefully I can
show it.
Why do I get that, OK?
Hopefully this is visible, so if I come to the top, so now I can see that accidentally the ball is
touching that by the.
So it's a good position for me to discuss this.
What is the radius of this ball?
So the radius of this ball is the center point.
Descender points distance all the way to the circumference of the ball because the circumference of
the ball is touching the canvas.
The canvas is top part.
I could say that the radius of the circle is from the center point all the way to the edge of this canvas,
and it is 50 pixels.
All right.
So it's 50 pixels.
We have established that.
What is the Y position for the circle?
So we know that the Y and X position for any circle is directly in the middle of that circle.
So for the X position, we can just say we can calculate a IDOT if you just put a dot here and the distance
from this dot all the way to the edge of this canvas is going to be the X position of the this circle.
But what about the Y position?
That's what we are interested in.
The Y position of this circle is the distance that the center of the circle has traveled from the top
edge of the from the top of the canvas.
What is that distance?
So this topic of the canvas all the way to the middle of the circle, we just found that out.
It's the radius.
So in this case that the ball touches the top part of the canvas, the radius becomes equal.
To the Y position of the circle, I'm going to reiterate this, what is the radius of the circle?
The radius of the circle is any line that goes from the center of the circle to any part of the circle.
In this case, we are interested in the top part of the circle.
So if the line this line comes out from goes from the center all the way to the circumference or to
the edge of the circle, that is the radius.
What is the radius?
The radius is 50 because the circle is directly touching this canvas, canvas, top edge.
We can say that the line from the center of the circle all the way to the top part of this box or this
canvas is going to be our radius.
What is the Y position?
The Y position is the distance from the canvas is, for example, top part all the way to the center.
Keep in mind to the center.
So if we have a center, a dot here, then you are going to provide it a radius and math that PI Times
two is going to draw that circle for.
So this is the Y position.
What is the Y position?
The Y position is the top part of the canvass all the way to the center of the circle.
We just calculated that that's equal to radius.
So the Y position of the circle, when it touches the top part of the canvas, is always going to be
equal to the radius.
What if it's not?
What if the top part of the what if the Y position of the ball is less than the radius?
What does that mean?
It means that the circle has moved off the canvas like this.
So you can see now the I'm going to just come down a little so you can see that the radius of the circle
is still because it goes to the edge of the circle.
The age of the circle is something right here.
It's invisible.
I know, but imagine it.
And the radius is still 50.
Right.
But what is the Y direction y position.
The Y position is the line is the distance from this canvas top part to the center.
And they you can see that the center distance has been reduced.
So the radius is no longer equal to the Y position.
The radius in fact is bigger than the Y position because the Y position was reduced by the amount of
the circle has moved off the canvas.
So whenever the circle so the circles y position is less than the radius, it means that a collision
has happened or at or to be accurate when it is equal and less than the radius, the Y position.
It means that a collision has has, has occurred, has occurred, has happened.
And the same thing goes for this one.
Just reverse that terminology instead of the radius is going to be the same, because this is a circle
in all directions, radius is the same, and in case it starts from the center and it goes to any part
of the circle, but instead of the Y position in this case, we just talk about the exposition.
And I'm going to reiterate this one time because we need to dive into code when this center the distance.
Now, this this is touching it.
So the distance from the center of the circle all the way to circumference, which is touching this
canvas canvasses left side is going to be radius and the distance from the canvas has left side to the
center of the any circle anywhere.
That's going to be the X position.
When the X position is equal to the radius of the circle, it means that some touching has been has
occurred when the radius when the X position, you can see that the X position has been reduced by maybe
like almost a third and now the radius is still 50.
We can see that it's still even though it's it has moved off the canvas, but it is still 50.
And now in this case, the X position is lower or smaller than the radius.
When it is smaller than the radius, it means that the circle has moved off this canvas.
What is the amount?
The amount is the if you subtract the exposition minus the radius, you're going to get the exact amount.
But that's not something that we want.
We were just interested in the concept.
So we are going to say if the Y position of the circle is less than or equal to the radius, we are
just converting what I said into code.
We want to reposition it in the right direction so the Y position is going to be equal to the radius.
It can no, it can't go smaller than the radius because if if the Y position is smaller, it means that
the circle has moved off the canvas.
The same thing goes for the left position.
So left.
And the reason that I'm like emphasizing on this is because in our next project I have other stuff to
explain.
I'm not going to be going over this collision detection so many times.
And I'm reiterating myself and re explaining myself and saying the same things multiple times so you
can understand it in the next project.
We have other stuff to deal with and the collision detection part is actually going to be the easiest
part of game development.
It's the most important, but at the same time it's the easiest part.
It's just very simple logic.
So in the next projects, I'm going to be focusing more on other stuff rather than this collision detection.
And another example of this is now you can see that we create functions with ease.
Why is that?
Because we have talked about functions a lot.
I'm not going to go over the syntax of how a function is created, how a function is called, because
we have already talked about it.
And that's why these lessons, they they make ideas on top of each other.
So in order to understand these lessons, you need to you need to have gone over all of the course.
So then you're going to understand what's happening here.
You can see we have statements, we have functions, we have function calls, we have game loops.
We have a lot of different stuff.
That's why those fundamentals with the intermediate and advanced level are so important, so moving
away from that discussion, if the exposition of the circle is less than or equal to the radius, the
same thing.
As for the top, we want to reposition that circle and it should never go less than the radius of it
that's come here.
So now we're going to go less than the radius.
There we go.
So our project is done.
You can move it around.
So you think of it as your character and it can never move off the canvas.
See, it moves by DHS.
All right, so with this, our projects, our project of Move the ball comes Sternin in the next project,
we are going to create a bouncy orange in which we create an orange circle, look like look alike,
and then that is going to bounce off these walls automatically and we are going to code that logic.
So in each of these projects, you can see that we get more and more familiarized with how these games
they work.
And right after that, we are going to dive into our very first game, which is pong ping pong, and
that we are going to play against a powerful A.I. or artificial intelligence.
And I'm going to show you how you can create that.
I would just one line of code, right.
That's that's going to be a very, very, very cool project.
See you guys in the next chapter.
And that's it.