Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we will be creating the everything manager function.
All right, now, this function has the job of detecting the edges, moving the ball, increasing the
ball speed in this function, we will be creating our A.I. will also playing our sound, some of them
in here.
Right.
And what I'm going to do is on the top of there, I'm just going to say the everything manager.
Function, OK, that's fine function, right, and that's going to be actually the name of that function.
So I'm going to say function everything.
Everything, manager.
So, manager, they're not going to be any parameters there, so the first thing that I want to do is
I actually want to move the ball.
So in order to move the ball, I want to I will be increasing the ball position by its velocity first.
Simple.
So ball that XP should be.
We add on to it the velocity.
Keep in mind, don't just sit like equal to velocity.
Let's see what's going to happen.
If I just do that ball dot x v, I'm going to call the everything manager inside the game in it because
we want it to be like to happen 60 times per one second.
That's why we created the game in it, because we had an everything manager in it as well.
So let's save it.
And there we go.
You can see that the ball is right there.
It's there and it's not moving again because we have set the balls, the exposition to the velocity.
But if I if I say add on to it and save and come, you can see that it is now moving.
It goes off the canvas, but it's actually moving because we are adding five pixels and then five pixels
and then five pixels, the amount that is for the velocity.
Right.
We are basically adding that amount to it.
The same thing is going to happen to the Y position, so I'm just going to do Y and now the ball should
move in both of the directions that we go.
So in X and in a combination of X and Y.
Right.
So that's done.
The next part is I want to whenever the ball hits that any wall, I want it to bounce off the walls.
So I'm going to say bouncing.
Bouncing off the top and bottom walls, right, and in here, not there, moving the ball by the amount
of acceleration.
All right, so how can we bounce it off?
We have to find out the radius and the Y position and also for the because we are only bouncing it off
from the top and the bottom, we don't need the canvas with or the exposition.
We just need the Y position because we wanted to go past the canvas so a score can happen.
So we say if the ball, if the Y position or the vertical position of the ball is greater than canvases,
canvas elements, height, it means that the ball has gone off.
How much the ball has gone off, it should go off by its full radius.
Right.
OK, so this is when the ball goes off the canvas from the top part of it, from the bottom part of
the canvas.
What if the ball goes off the top of the top part of the canvas?
So again, we are going to see a ball that wipe the vertical position when it goes less than zero bytes
for radius.
So we can just say plus baldor radius, which I'm not going to do.
I'm just going to put in minus Baudot radius so you can say zero plus ball the radius.
We have done that in our previous projects.
I'm not going to explain that anymore.
So whenever ball excuse me, whenever the ball hits either the bottom side of the canvas or the top,
it should reverse its velocity.
So Baudot why v should be equal to negative ball that y and here as well where I'm going to call our
wall play and we are going to play that.
So let's.
OK, so it comes from here, I'm going to just close that.
There we go.
So.
See, so I'm sure you can hear that it's very volume is low, but you can hear that.
There we go.
It bounces off and it plays that audio for us, OK?
And it's just doing it again and again and again.
Just going to mute that, and the next thing that I want to do here is whenever.
Now, we have detected the collision, we have detected the collision of four, the top by a wall and
the bottom wall, what is the other detection that we need to do, the other detection that we need
to do?
As for these paddles, whenever it hits one paddle, it should go to the next.
It should it should go to the other direction.
So if the ball is moving, moving, moving towards the left, it means it's moving towards the negative.
And when it hits this ball, it should reverse its velocity to move to the other part.
Right.
So what are we to do as I'm going to come on top of this everything manager function and I'm going to
say the collision.
Collision detec tion of paddles.
Function, right?
So this is going to detect the collision for the paddles and I'm going to create this function.
Pottle, I'm going to call it Padel, Kaleigh Koelie Detec Deti deti.
All right, so it's parochially deti paddle collision detection and I'm going to pass and ball and I'm
going to pass and paddle.
Right, so we have two parameters now.
There are a few computations that we need to do here.
And before doing that I'm going to zoom.
And so you really how can I get this paddle.
It doesn't matter.
We are going to get this and we are going to think that both of them are the same.
So we have this paddle right here.
This is the computer paddle, right?
It doesn't matter whose paddle this is now when the ball hits it right here in case this is the player
paddle.
So the player paddle is when the ball hits it on the right side, the computer paddle is when the ball
hits it on the left side.
Right.
So whenever we want to we want to find this one out is whenever.
The ball hits it here, the first thing that we need to do is we need to find out that the ball should
head it directly in the center, because based on that center is where we create our angle at which
the ball is going to bounce off.
So if it hits it in the center, we can see that the angle at the center is zero.
And how can we find this out?
We know how can we find the center of this powder?
Right.
It's just going to be the part, the height of the paddle.
So this is.
So the position of the panel plus the height of the panel that is going to give us the bottom of the
panel and the top part of the panel is going to be the Paros y position.
So this is the top part of the panel.
This is the bottom part of the panel.
If you want to find out the with the of the metal point, we just divide the height of the panel by
two.
And that is going to give us the center point.
And then we are going to grab that center point, which is right here.
And we are going to we are going to compare it against the center point for the ball.
Now, if I zoom out now you get what the idea is, right?
We just want to compare the ball with the circle.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to come in these two out.
So our ball is right here and I'm going to zoom in.
So this is our ball, right?
What is the center point?
The center point is right where my mouth is pointing and from the center point all the way to here.
This is the radius from the center point all the way to the left is also the radius from the center
point to the top is the radius from the center point to the bottom is also the radius.
So if this ball is to hit the apple, it should head it with its radius.
Right?
If the ball should head the R.I panel, it should hit it again with its radius.
If the ball should head the top wall, it should hit it with its radius.
Right.
So this is the radius.
If the ball should head the bottom, the bottom wall, it should head it with the radius.
So in all four cases we are going to grab the radius.
So what is the top part?
If we get the if, for example, the ball hits the top of the canvas, what is the top part?
So this is the radius.
All right.
And this is this is the type this exactly in the middle is where the Y position of this ball is.
If I grab this Y position and subtract from it the radius, we are going to grab the top position of
the ball.
And we are we are going to need that.
I'm just going to convert all this concept into code as well.
So I'm just going to come here.
So I'm going to start with the ball first and I'm going to say ball the top.
So what is the top position of the ball?
The top position of the ball is going to be ball dot.
Come on.
That's why the Y position, if we subtract from it, why subtract?
Because we are moving in the negative direction, the radius.
So you can see in all four directions we are involved with the radius.
So this is going to be the top part.
What about the bottom?
I'm sure you can, you can guess this one out if we are moving towards the bottom and we want to find
out the bottom this distance from here up until here, this is the Y position.
If I add the radius to it, we are going to get this point.
So basically we grab the ball that y position and we add it the ball, that radius.
Right.
So what about the left and right.
The left and right are going to be the same.
If it is left, it's going to be negative.
If it is right is going to be positive.
Very simple.
So I'm just going to copy these two.
I'm going to put it there.
So the first one, let's do the left as opposed to top.
And for the left we have XP.
So I'm just going to grab both of them, put the XP.
So if the X position, if we reduce from that, if we subtract from that the radius, it's going to
give us that edge of the balls exposition and for the right if we added the radius.
So when we are moving in this direction, this is the center.
If I added the radius, I'm going to get this side of the ball.
Why do we need to get these four sides?
One side belongs to the player, the r.i player Parro.
The other side belongs to the EHI player Padel.
The top side belongs to the top wall.
It should bounce off of that.
That's what I mean by it.
The bottom part belongs to the bottom wall, which it should bounce off.
We need to grab all these four edges and then we need to compare it with the paddle and then we are
going to do one logical operator, a chain of logical operators, which is going to complete this collision
detection for us.
So now we have successfully grabbed the balls four points.
What about the paddle?
So I don't know why I can see the r.i paddle.
We are going to, we can see this, I'm just going to assume that this is our eye and this is A.I. so
for the r.i what do we have.
We have this top for both of them.
We basically do the same thing.
So for the top of the paddle, what is the top of the paddle.
How can we find this edge.
It's the Y position of the paddle.
All right.
So I'm going to say paddle dart top.
Why do we need to find it, because the ball might hit that top part of the powder, right?
Right.
So it is going to be partho dot y position.
All right.
What is the Paton's bar?
So in case for it to for us to be able to get this point, we need to grab the top part and we need
to add the paddles, hide to it, and then we get the bottom part.
Very simple, right?
That Y p plus part of that height, perfect.
What about the left?
The left and right are also simple, so the left of the paddle is going to be the paddles exposition,
the left of the paddle.
I'm going to say paddle.
The left is going to be.
Paddle.
Come on, paddle dart exposition.
And what about the right of the paddle for the right of the paddle?
We need to grab the exposition and add to it the width of the paddle as opposed to height of the paddle
as opposed to the height of the paddle.
So paddle to it.
Sorry.
Ah, right.
Should be paddle.
Dart exposition, plus the width of the paddle.
Dot with.
Perfect.
Now, we have successfully grabbed all four edges of the paddle and all four outer edges of the circle
as well.
Now we need to compare it.
Comparison comparison is going to be easy.
So we are going to see a return if the ball's right position.
Right position is greater than the paddles left position, the ball should bounce off.
And so this is changing logical operators, the ball's bottom.
A position if it is greater than the the paddles.
Paddles, top position, the ball should bounce off and then we are going to say if the balls return,
if the ball is left, position is less than the paddles.
Less than the paddles, right position.
Right, and also return true, if the balls are right, position is also less than.
I think I made a mistake, we have already done that, so this is the panel's bottom.
So we did the balls, right?
Should be greater than the paddles.
The left should be greater than that.
The ball's bottom should be greater than the paddle.
Stop the balls left.
All right, the most left part of the bombs left should be less than the paddles, right?
And the ball's top we have in the top right, the box tops should be less than the paddles, but.
Let's save it.
There we go, it rearranges it better so the right hand side of the ball should be greater than the
left hand side of the paddle for it to bounce off.
What does that mean?
It means that if.
OK, come on.
So if this this side of the ball is greater than this side of the paddle, it should bounce off if it
is not greater than that.
And if we don't do it this way, what would happen this side of the ball if it gets greater than the
left side of the paddle?
And it doesn't bounce off, it would cross the paddle.
We won't have any detection, so it shouldn't cross it.
It means it shouldn't get bigger than that.
So that's the first scenario for the second scenario we have if the bonds bottom is greater than the
ball and the paddle top.
Right.
So let's say that the ball this this is the bottom.
Now the bottom of the ball is going to have the same idea for the r.i paddle and for the paddle.
So if the bottom of the ball hits the top of the paddle and the bottom of the ball is greater than that.
Right.
If it is greater, if it isn't greater than that, it is not going to bounce off.
If it is greater than that.
That's right.
At the point that we want it to bounce off.
So for example, the ball is coming from the ball.
It is coming in this way, coming, coming, coming right here and then in here.
The ball's bottom is not bigger than the paddle stop.
It should reach it and then we should compare it.
Otherwise, when it gets to here, then it would bounce off.
We need we need them to touch and to establish this relationship that says the ball bonds bottom is
going to get to is going to get to a point where it is greater than the paddle stop and then the ball
would penetrate this paddle.
And right at the point of penetration is where we want it to bounce back, bounce back.
So this top and the bottom, they basically work in the same way.
For this hour, I paddle and the paddle.
And right here, this is for the ah paddle.
We say that the ball's left should be less than the right way.
We say less than because we are moving in the negative direction.
And for this why we say bottom less than because we are moving in the negative direction.
Keep in mind the for the bottom of the ball to head the top of the paddle, the ball should come in
this direction.
The ball should come from top to bottom.
And that is positive direction for the top of the ball to head the bottom of the paddle.
The ball should move in this direction.
See, boom.
Like that.
And this is towards the negative direction.
That's why we see less than that.
And with this with very this, we can detect the ball from the edges of that as well.
And now what I'm going to do here is we need to call.
We don't have of course, this is not going to work.
And I know I know you know that as well.
We are going to make it work.
We just provided the logic, the actual know how we are going to do it in our next lecture because we
need to call this paddle collie Collie ditty inside our everything manager, because this everything
manager handles that.
And then we call the everything manager within the hour game in it, which runs 60 times per second.
So you need to keep that in mind.
Even though we have our detection, what do we do after that?
So we have detected where the ball hits the paddle.
What do we do after that?
We want to reverse the velocity.
We want to change the position.
Right.
We want to create a like a coin toss situation.
So all of that hopefully we are going to cover in our next lecture.
See you guys then.