Hi, everyone, in this letter, we are going to create the render counter function.
All right, so I'm going to come down here and I'm going to create a comment and I'm going to say a
render counter function.
Let's go ahead and let's create the function and the function is called render render a counter.
What do we want to do inside this render counter?
So to be like to be on this on the same page, this is the counter.
So now whenever we say render counter function, it is going to be responsible for this counter which
is increasing and for this bar, for this counter gauge or counter bar.
Right.
So what do I want to do?
I want to first sort of implement an if statement.
And the reason for that is I want to check for a condition.
If that condition is true, I want to run a certain code and that if that condition is not true or is
false, I want to run a different condition, a different code.
So what are the two conditions?
The first condition is whenever this counter time is less than the question time.
So the question time is 10 when the counter time is less than that, B, that whatever it whatever.
So either it is zero one or all the way to nine when it is less than that.
What do I want to do?
I want to increment it by one.
So if it is zero, I want incremented by one, if it is want incremented by two and so on and so forth.
And as I increment this, I want to, I want to increment this with this background color sorry.
This color, this purple color as well on this time gauge.
So I want to increment the number and I want increment this this segments that are coming here based
on the time.
So these are the two things that I want to do and add in the first condition.
And if the condition is true, if the condition is not true, if the condition is false, I want to
grab this counter and I want to make it zero.
When is the condition false?
The condition is false when the count and the question time are equal.
Now you can see the contestant and the question time is ten.
You can see that we go to the next question and the count starts from zero.
OK, now the next question that is a whole different story here is where the question now you can see
here, it says 10 and the question time is ten.
It means that the count and the question time, they are actually.
Equal and when it is equal, I want to I want to do something else, OK?
Well, actually, this is not accurate.
When there are equal or let me put it this way.
When the count when the count is equal to the question time or less than that, I want incremented.
Right.
But when the count gets bigger.
So when the count is 11, I just said one, it is equal.
I'm going to incremented.
All right.
And one, I increment 10, it is going to be 11.
And when it is 11, it is no more less than Question Time or equal to that.
And then our condition is going to be false when it is false.
I want to reset the counter, so let's go ahead and let's just dive into code because it is way easier
whenever we just dive into code.
So we have created our account right here.
Maybe I should like put it down here.
We have created the count and initially the value is going to be zero.
So I'm going to say if count is less than or equal to the question time, we know what the question
time is.
The question time is ten.
We have created it there.
If the count is equal less than or equal to Question Time, it means that the count is zero all the
way to nine and equal, which is ten.
So in all the scenarios, we are going to grab our counter diff from the e-mail and we are going to
say DOT enter e-mail and the e-mail is going to grab the count into consideration.
All right.
So let's come here.
We still don't see anything.
And here, because we are not actually evaluating that, we are not running the surrender of Kandahar,
so render a counter function, let's run it, check out it.
Yes, we Cesira because we because the count has a default value of zero.
If I said it to 500 and we are going to suffer, you're not going to see 500.
Why is that?
This is a cool thing that I just did.
The reason that we do not see it is because 500 is neither less than nor equal to the Question Time,
which is 10.
That's why it did not run.
So if I put it to nine and save it, we are going to see nine, even if I put it to 10.
Even if I put it to 10, we are going to see it.
That's why we we say equal to or less than or equal to Question Time.
If we just say less than we are not, we are never going to see the count turn 10.
Whenever we say we see equal, it is going to be ten.
And then after that we are going to go to we are going to get get our counter and make it zero.
So, so now that everything is established, let's make it zero once more.
When the count, whatever the counters, we want to increment the time gauge by that amount.
So let's grab our time gauge and we are going to say dot style.
Dot with.
All right, it should be equal to the Count Times, tire gauge unit gauge unit, and we are going to
add a pixel value to it.
And after this is done, it means we are at the second of zero when it when it is zero.
What do I want to do?
I want incremented by one so it becomes one.
And when it is one then I want incremented by one.
So it gets to let's save it.
Let's come here.
Well actually we don't see it yet and we get our count if this condition is true.
Question.
There is no timer.
Of course the timer.
And we should set a timer.
And because we want this render counter now this render counter, it runs only once.
We don't want it to run.
Once we want it to run as like forever, like run until the questions they are ended.
So in the else block, I'm going to explain this if statement, because I think it's a bit confusing.
So and the Alps, we are just going to get our count and we're going to make it zero.
So what does this statement do?
This statement is going to grab the value of.
So we know that inside this parenthesis we have our condition.
We have gone over that.
Excuse me if the count is equal to or less than Question Time.
So initially the count is going to be zero.
Zero is less than Question Time.
So this statement is true and this code is going to run this code.
So the count is zero.
Zero is going to come here and we are going to see underpays zero and then zero is going to be inserted
here zero times the gauge unit.
What is the gauge unit?
The gauge unit is the length of the width is the width according to the width that we want to ekrem
incremented by.
And that width has a background color.
Where is it?
This is the background color for that with which is like a sort of purple color.
All right.
And we are getting that gauge with with this with with this gauge unit that we have here.
So if I passan zero here, zero times gauge unit, we get a zero.
So the gauge is not going to be incremented.
And then because we have zero, we are going to increment it by one and then we get one and then one
is going to be passed here.
This condition is going to be evaluated to true because Question Time is ten.
Keep that in mind.
Then we are going to pass in one here and one here.
When we pass in one inside the counter that increased on the page, we are going to see one.
And when we pass in one into the time gauge that stands out with one times gauge unit gauge unit is
eighty.
It's right here.
So one times eighty we are going to get eighty, eighty plus pixels.
We are going to get eighty pixels.
So the width of the time gauge which is right here, is going to be worth what you can see that I have
given it a height, but there is no width because the width is going to be added dynamically and the
width is eighty and then the width is eighty and this background color is going to be applied.
And then we go into another iteration, another another iteration.
Then because we increment one by one, it is we are going to get two and this condition is going to
run as long as this condition is not true anymore.
So in the final iteration, we are going to get ten.
When we increment ten, we, for example, when we get ten, ten is going to be true.
We are going to get ten on the page through this code and the final segment is going to have its background
color of purple.
And then when we increment ten by one, it is going to be eleven.
Eleven is not going to be true.
So this extension is not going to run and then the else is going to run and the else says that I'm going
to grab the count and I'm going to make a zero.
Voila, that's it, very, very simple, right?
So at the end, what I'm going to do here is I'm going to grab our Taimur.
Taimyr, come on, buddy, and we are going to set we are going to set an interval and this is a very
useful function in JavaScript.
So first stuff, what is it that we want to set the interval on?
It is the ORENDER counter that we want to set the interval and how after what is the interval time that
we want this function to run?
So I want this function to run after each one second.
So I'm going to add in 1000 milliseconds.
So timer handler.
So first one is going to be handler and then the time the timer is going to be 1000 milliseconds or
one second.
So now if I come here, we can see that this counter is going to be incremented by.
By one second or 1000 milliseconds, and when it reaches to 10, it is not going to go to 11.
The reason for that is 11 is not true here.
11 is not true here.
That's why this F statement as F block is not going to run the else block runs and the S block is going
to grab the count and it is going to make it zero.
So.
Voila, the count is zero, and each time this is incremented, the gauge with which comes from here
is going to incremented by the same number because we multiply it by the same count.
So one times 80 pixels, two times 80 pixels, four times, five times eight pixels, six times, seven
times, eight times eight pixels, 10 times eight pixels.
We are going to get eight hundred pixels.
That's how simple it is.
That's it.
Well, not actually not.
I'm just going to add another because this code is very ugly sitting right here.
Why don't we add that to the start Kawase function?
This is where everything comes together.
So we are going to create I promise you, this is going to be the final function.
So we are going to grab or we are going to create a start Cui's function.
And what is it?
What is the Starquest function, the Starquest function as the event that is going to run whenever we
kaleck, whenever we click on the start are right.
So this is very, very, very cool stuff.
So start.
Colwin's.
And what do we want to do in here?
Basically, we just want to grab everything and put it right here and now, this function should be
called somewhere to be to run.
All right.
So what I'm going to do, I promise, this is the last thing.
I'm going to grab and I'm going to start.
What is that weird start button, start button event less tender.
I always write it the way it is.
I was whenever I want to write something, I just spell it the way I just pronounce it the way it is
written.
So it says listener, but it actually written listner.
That's how if English is your second language, you're not going to make any mistake.
But just make sure to keep it in you, to keep it to yourself.
Don't say it out loud or other people are going to look at you.
Very weird.
All right.
So let's say start with so everything should work perfectly fine.
So this is our application.
So whenever I click on this, Starquest, you're going to start our quiz.
The counter is starting, but the questions are not going to switch.
So we are going to wait for it until it hits 10.
Boom, it starts from zero once more.
All right, so we are getting close.
So now the interface is starting to work.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.