Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to implement the touch related events.
All right, but before actually doing that, what I want to do here is I wanted to do this in the previous
lecture, but that was almost 30 minutes.
So what happens when the ball goes off the canvas?
What what happens if it goes below?
So when it goes below, what we want to do is we want to call the new we want to call a new game.
Right.
So.
Right inside our update ball function, so right in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead
and I'm going to create an if statement.
So we are going to say and I'm going to call it out of the canvas.
Ball moves out of the canvas and you're going to say if if the ball's y velocity is greater than the
canvas is height, canvas elements, height.
Why do we want to do we want to call in out of bounds function?
All right.
So when the Y velocity y position is greater than the canvas is height, we want to call and out of
bounds function.
All right, and what I'm going to do here is I'm going to go where is our home?
Where should I put this function out of bounds?
So.
I'm going to go on top of this, said dimension's.
OK, and I want to copy this to right here, and I'm going to call this out of bounds function, so
let's create that function.
So what do we want to do here?
For now?
What I want to do here is I just want to go ahead and I want to call a new game.
Right.
So out.
Of bounds, and I'm going to call it a new game function, so let's call it right here.
Now let's see what it is going to do.
So we are going to let it go.
There you go.
So when it heads, when it goes off the canvas, you can see that our new game, which is responsible
for the new paddle, for the new ball, is going to appear.
So if I even if I bring the paddle right here.
The paddle and the ball should go to the original position, which they did, right?
So that's what I wanted to do here as well.
Next stop.
What I want to do is I want to go ahead and I want to modify the angle based on which the ball is going
to spin.
So actually it is going to happen within the same function.
So I'm going to say modify modify the angle.
The come on the angle based off based off the ball spin.
All right, so in here, what are we going to do as first off, we need to find find the current angle,
current angle?
What is the current angle at which the ball actually spins?
So for that, I'm going to create an angle, a variable, and I'm going to say math dot eight and two.
Now, this method is going to return the angle in radians from the x axis to a point so from the ball
whenever the ball is here.
So from this x axis, I want to find out at which angle this ball is going to bounce off.
So this angle, this angle, this this or this one.
That's why we are going to use this method.
So for this method, what we are going to actually do here as I'm going to grab all of this and I'm
going to put him inside our bouncing the ball off the paddle and I'm going to grab this, cut it and
I'm going to put it right here.
Right.
And actually, I'm not going to put it right like that.
First off, I'm going to pass and the balls, the the balls, negative velocity, wave velocity and
then I'm going to pass.
And the ball's positive y yv the ball's positive velocity.
All right.
So you know what?
I'm not going to because we are going to need that of y velocity.
I'm not going to delete it from there because that is responsible for that, for changing the direction
of the velocity.
We just want to find the angle at which that velocity is being changed.
So right after that, I'm going to grab the angle and I'm going to add on to it a random value, random
times, the math dot pi.
So what is the math?
Math dot pi?
We should execute this function as well.
So the math that's pi we know is going to give us 180 degrees, right.
So if I divide it by two, we are going to get 45 degrees and then from there I'm going to say math
that pi divided by four.
All right, we are going to get another 45 degrees.
Right.
And I am going to multiply all of this.
With the ball spin, so let's do that, it's multiplied with the ball spin.
There we go.
So we have created the ball spin as zero point two now, right?
So we do have our angle and I'm going to call the appli ball speed in here as well, and I'm going to
pass and the angle as well.
So let's save it.
And I'm going to go up the I'm going to go to our appli ball speed function now, and I'm going to show
you something.
So where is that function?
A fly ball speed, right?
So you know what, I'm just going to come and tell the draw functions, we don't need them for now.
We might need them.
We will need them later.
So this is going to be a new game.
I'm going to keep its curve ball dimensions and I'm going to comment tell these classes as well.
So let's go up to our appli ball speed.
And on top, what I'm going to do is I'm going to say.
So I'm going to say keeping keeping the angle between two limits and what are the two limits, it's
going to be 30 degrees and 150.
Why do we need to keep them between these two limits is because whenever it is greater than that, then
the ball is going to move very weird and it is going to be very difficult for the user to play it.
So so we are going to say if the angle and the angle is going to be this angle that we have passed there,
if the angle is less than the math, that PI varies the math.
Math darte pi, so math that PI is going to give us one hundred and eighty degrees divided by six,
we are going to get 30 degrees if it is less than 30 degrees.
We are going to say that the angle should be equal to the math that pi divided by six.
We are we want to keep it at that 30 degrees limit.
Ancef elusive angle is greater than math.
Dot pi times five divided by six is going to give us hundred and fifty degrees.
If it is greater than that, we are going to keep it at that.
So let's copy it, let's put it right here and let's change this to an equal sign, let's say.
So how can we actually test this is I'm going to put in a console clock here.
So I'm going to say.
And goal one.
Right, let's do this, so this is going to be angle one and I'm going to say.
All right, and let's grab our angle.
Angle and let's divide it by math, dot pi times 180 degrees St. 180.
So we get a something in degrees actually.
Right.
So that is going to be a council log there.
And we are going to have a council log down below.
All right, so we are going to have our angle, too, we have our angle time divided by math, this.
And for this to actually really work, what I'm going to do is I'm going to put the ball spin to something
extreme so we can actually test this.
So let's save it and let's and you can see that the angle, the spin angle was 39 for that, but now
it is 109.
Both of them are the same.
So the angle one and the angle two are the same.
All right, so let's get greater.
So now we can see that the angle is staying between 39 and 109, so you should get something that is
either less than 30.
There we go.
It is.
That was 141.
So you should get something that is less than 30 or.
There we go.
This is the point.
So you can see that our angle was one of 51, but the appli speed function actually kept the angle to
at 150.
So for this to actually work is I'm going to reiterate, this is we should either get a.
We should either get a 30 degree angle less than that, and the angle, too, should be 30 or we should
get something that is bigger than 151.
We got bigger than 150, sorry, 150.
We got bigger than that.
And it can it it kept it at 150.
So the speed was right here.
So the angle before this if statement was 151, but we kept it at 150.
So instead of a single one, I could say angle
default, default, and I could say angle intended or angle output output is better.
So now if I do this one, so you can see that both of them are the same, our if statement is not working.
There we go.
We got one fifty one point six and angle output was one fifty.
So let me see if we can grab a 30.
So again, it was one fifty point five, even by like two decimal points.
It is still going to work.
This is upwards, you can see that the spin is very, very big, the reason for that is we have put
the ball spin to one.
That's why this is the extreme amount of spin that it is going to get.
See, it is upwards or it is like in the left direction and it is completely random.
We don't have control over that, but we don't get something there.
We should get something on the other side as well.
All right.
Uh.
Hmm, let's check our code out one more time.
So if the angle is less than math that pi divided by six, we keep it up there and if it is greater
than this amount, we keep it at that amount and we have passed it here.
So if I come down here, the minimum bounce angle for us is going to be.
We have our serve ball function, so we have said that the minimum bounce angle is going to be, oh,
let me come in this one out, because we are passing the angle from there and we do not have to pass
the angle from here again.
No, we actually we needed that is for the serve ball and that is for when the ball bounces.
So we have two kinds to function calls there.
So this is working perfectly fine because whenever we serve it, that is that has a good angle that
has the angle that we want.
But when it bounces off of the ball, bouncing off the paddle, if all of these conditions are true,
we want to a turn the negative velocity and the positive.
Update the update function.
Let's see, so we have our ball and we change it, we have our balls position is going to be paddles
height and the ball height.
Perfect.
So we do have some balls.
Why?
Let's add on the balls height times zero point five.
Let's see what this is going to give us.
So 140, I mean, we do not get a bounce off the left.
Of the right, it goes top we should go to right as well.
I know it's random, but we should get it so you can see it goes to left.
It was 175 and the output is now 150.
So we should get something, think it goes there.
We should get less than 30.
And you can see it goes back there, so there is something wrong with that.
And, uh, a 10 to.
All right, minus the ball.
Oh, this is the ball's ex, sorry, this is going to be this well solved.
Now you can see there we go, we get the ball there as well.
So that was the serve the serve bowl angle was working perfectly fine.
And now this is working fine.
You can see that the default was 13, but we kept it at 30.
We kept it at 30.
So now it is going to work in both of the directions.
So we are going to keep the angle at exactly 30 now, less than that and at 150 and not more than that.
There we go.
So we it bounces on both sides.
So let's come into our appli speech and I'm going to comment about these angles, but I'm not going
to remove them because you might need them.
I know at the start of this lecture I said that we will be working with the touch and that's what I
will be doing right now.
So let's go ahead.
On top of the arrow key events in there, I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create a comment and
I'm going to say touch events.
Right.
And in here, there is actually a good article for that, which I'm going to give you as well.
But first off, we need to face the issue.
Canvas, we might not face the issue in the Firefox's, but you will definitely face it in the chrom.
So we have four different kinds of.
Touch events, we have touch events, we have touch, cancel, touch, cancel is whenever you're playing
a game in your mobile mobile device, right.
And then there is suddenly a pop up and then your game is interrupted.
Right.
Or suddenly you get a message.
The best way to play a game, by the way, is whenever you put your mobile phone on the flight mode,
when you play it, you're not going to you're not going to get any ads into your game.
That's like a good trick that you can do.
But when and some something pops up and your touch is canceled, that is the touch cancel event.
The reason that I am explaining this is because we have a similar event as well.
So I'm going to create a function for this called touch, cancel the similar event that we have.
The reason that we select canvasses because we want this touch to only work in the canvas.
The other one is touch and so touch the touch and is whenever you lift your finger off the screen.
So in both cases, the touch has canceled.
One is the kind of cancellation that you want.
The other is the kind of cancellation that you don't.
So touch cancel is that sort of cancellation that you don't want.
Touch Enda's.
Whenever you left your finger up, that is going to be the touch.
And so for that, I'm going to create a touch and.
Function, let's copy this two more times, the next one is going to be touch, move whenever you are,
your finger is on the screen and you slide it across the screen or slide it to top and bottom, that
is going to be the touch move.
It is pretty self-explanatory.
And finally, the first one is going to be touch start.
So that is when you place your finger on the screen, that is going to be the touch start.
OK, so we have created all of this and let's go ahead and let's save that and.
Oh, of course, it is going to throw all of these errors, but but in case you have, you receive another
error.
And that error is going to be in Chrom, I don't know whether or not that's going to be in Firefox because
right at this part here, I was working with Chrome and then I switched to Firefox because of that bug.
And let's go ahead and let's actually create the functions, because now we are not going to see those
bugs because the functions are not working.
You see another error.
So let's come down here.
Let's close this function.
So where is our let's close this one, this one out of bounds.
Set dimensions of date, bowl of date, paddle.
If we need them, I'm going to open them.
So right after the set dimensions, let's grab the comment and let's put it right here.
And I'm going to call it touch events, function functions.
So the first function is I'm going to create a function for each of them, we have called them now let's
go ahead and let's actually create these functions.
So I think we have created the attach X variable.
Yes, we have done that.
So we don't need to go up there, create that again.
So the first one is going to be a function, touch cancer, make sure to capitalize this, because this
is the function itself.
All right, I'm going to pass and the event in case we need it, right?
So for the touch cancel, we're going to call it touch function and I'm going to pass.
No.
So that's it for the touch cancel function.
The next function is going to be that we are is going to be touch and and for that, I'm going to pass
in the event in case we need it and we're basically going to do the same thing.
We are going to call the touch function function and we're going to pass a No.
For that, let's create the touch move function and let's grab the event.
So in the touch function to the touch function, what do we want to pass?
We want to grab our event now.
The event is going to give us an array called touches.
And from that array, we are going to grab the first item.
And that item is going to give us the first location that the that the user has touched.
OK, now we are just grabbing the X location, not the Y location.
And that's because we allow the user to touch anywhere in the Y location.
Right.
So this is going to give us the client X. that exact location.
And.
Perfect.
Let's grab the torch start function, all right, and we are going to pass in an event as well here.
OK, so.
What we are going to do is.
Let's passing the event and basically we are going to do the same thing, so we are going to say touch
IDOT Touches is right and you're going to grab the first item and from there we are going to grab the
client X..
So now on top here, I want to create the touch function.
So let's say function, touch.
And what what is going to be the parameter, the parameter is going to be X.
All right.
So X is going to be no, X is going to be no, X is going to have a position, X is going to have a
position.
So now we are going to say F.
The X is not true, so we are going to say X is not true.
What do we want to do if X is not true?
Come on.
If X is false, we want to move the we want to call them move panel function, so let's call that function,
you can see how functions are really important.
And from there, we are going to call the direction dot stop.
All right, Elsbeth Ancef, the X is greater than the paddles exposition, and it means that the X is
moving towards the right because it is greater than that.
So we are going to call the move paddle function and we are going to call the direction.
Direction dot, right?
Perfect, elusive.
House F the X is less than the paddles, paddles, exposition, we want to call the move paddle function
and let's pass in the direction Dart left.
Perfect.
So so far, we have created all these and.
OK, so let's save it, let's actually see if we have any errors, if there is something missing.
I'm going to go to our here to these phones and I'm going to it doesn't really matter.
It's just iPhone six, seven, eight, and it is in the landscape mode.
I could go to portrait and reload the page and let's serve the OK, reload the page and there we go.
So if I click, you can see that the mouse is the touch is actually moving.
OK, so you can see that.
OK, so we can actually move, we are not you can see that the panel is shaky some time because it is
trying to get to this exact client its location, but it can never get to that location, so.
See, so and and there are actually two bucks here, the first one is whenever I move it, you can see
that whenever I move to the left and for example, like right here when I click on it.
Departments, and when I keep clicking and now this clicking, I didn't say this, but this is actually
tapping.
So when you tap on the screen and hold it, it is going to move all the way to left.
But you want it to be.
Exactly.
And wherever you are holding it, the reason that you can see that pop up is just because of the browser.
The browser is going to give me that pop up and you can see that it is going to try to get to there.
So what we're going to do is we want to remove whenever the ball is first served, but we can see that
the ball is never served.
So let's go ahead and let's serve the ball as well.
So in here in the touch start, we want to say f serve ball.
We have created this function, haven't we?
So where is it?
Yeah, we have created that if Savol were our we should be down here if Savol is true.
Then we want to return, right?
Now, let's, uh, let's before actually doing this, let's serve the ball so you can see the problem
that I'm talking about.
So when I click, you can see that the paddle is moving, reload, collect, the paddle is moving.
The paddle is moving towards whichever location it is that you have topped your finger.
So for this to be really better visible, let's put it to this iPad and let's go this way and let's
reduce it to 90.
Well, it didn't make that much of a difference, did it?
Split its iPhone six, seven, eight, let's go 100.
I think this is better.
So when you click here, the paddles moving that way, even though this is the ball is just being served,
you don't want to do that.
OK, that that is going to be a bug, which we need to fix.
So we are going to say that f serve ball is true.
It means that the ball has already been served.
We don't want to do anything.
We just want to return from the function.
So.
This is still working, if Savol is true.
We want to return from the function, it shouldn't work like that.
There we go.
It's still it is still there.
So if Savol is true, why do we have any errors, you know?
So let me get out of there and let's get let's go in there.
Let's do iPhone X.
It is still when the ball is served, it is still moving.
This is the problem that I was talking about in Chrome.
I'm going to give you the solution for that.
But first, I need to know why is it still moving?
Because we have returned it and it is still moving.
All right, so.
Still, let's see if there is any other problem so that I'm just going to take care.
No, that's OK.
So if I move that, I should be able to hit the ball.
Come on.
There we go.
You can see how the paddle is like shaki jittering that sort of thing.
It's like paddle is cold, very cold.
So this is what I mean.
You can see I'm sure you can see it right now.
So what I'm going to do is before the return, I'm just going to log Eikon something to the console
and I'm going to say ball is served perfect.
It's like.
So you can see that the serve this statement is not running at all, that's why he's not returning,
because it's not running.
So let's go to the serve ball function.
So this is disserve ball function.
You can see that if the ball is already moving, do not allow serve.
Perfect.
And basically, what is this function actually doing, this function?
Is it actually doing nothing?
It's actually giving us some sort of way to change the velocity.
But so if I were to return true from this function.
That should solve the problem, right?
So if I click on it, you can see that we see the ball is served and the part was not moved when the
game started.
So so we still have that shakiness and that the paddle is nice.
So if I click here.
You can see this if I click here, the paddle is moving when I stop, the paddles of the paddle keeps
moving when I start to see.
So there are two other bugs that we need to fix here as well.
So the first stuff which is going to be we need to fix that whenever whenever the user lifts their finger
off the touch, then that is going to be where the paddle stops.
All right.
So instead of actually doing it this way now before going forward, I need to show you this as well.
I mean, if we go to the I'm not going to go to the responsive mode.
If we you can see that it says adding violation added non passive eventless listener.
You can read all about it here.
Passive event listeners.
You can read it, read all about it here.
So for that, I'm just going to copy that link and add it here inside the touch.
And the replay for that is here.
You can read about all about it there as well.
So I'm just going to paste the report as well.
And basically what it says as you need to add another item in case you're working with Chrome, you're
going to get that and it is not going to work for you.
So in case you get that, these are basically what it says is you need to add a flag.
The flag is going to be passive and you need to add the passive as to the reason that it is requesting
this from you is for better performance, for for mobility purposes, that sort of thing.
It claims that whenever you add the passive flag to true, the the error is going to go away and this
is going to be a better performance kind of thing that you do.
So if I just cut it from there and if I come here, they can see that if you come here, it says that
implement the behavior with respect to despatching passive listeners.
Listener's so calling the prevent default inside executing the callback only generates a warning to
the console can be used to dramatically improve scrolling behavior.
So it's a good thing, I guess.
So you just go ahead and added there, you should add it.
And inside the repo is it gives you the the problem.
This is the problem, how you can fix it.
This is capture truly just the passive perfect.
So I'm going to close these, this chrome and I've added that just for chrome.
I didn't get that for Firefox.
So in order to fix that problem that we have is I'm going to go ahead and say, well, actually we are
going to do it a different way this time.
So instead of calling this touch function, I'm going to come in.
This one out are not going to call the we are not going to say when I click left, go left.
When I click right, go right.
You're not going to do that.
We are going to remove this.
And instead of that, we are going to grab our touch X and we're going to initialize and we are going
to initialize it to null.
We have declared it before so and then we are going to call our remove panel function and we are going
to say direction.
Direxion dot stuff.
Perfect.
So for the touch cancel, we did that and we want to basically do the same thing for the touch and because
both of them are actually doing the same thing.
So let's remove the event.
We didn't need it here.
For the touch move, instead of grabbing the client this way, I'm going to grab it and I'm going to
stir it inside, touch X and I'm going to say each dot touches zero dot client X and let's copy that
and let's pasted right here as well.
So let's move it.
Let's save it and.
Well, did you break it?
All right, so it is not moving at all now.
Um hmm.
Which direction that stop?
So these are going to stop detractions and, uh, what else do we have to do here?
We have said touchbacks.
We should do, I think, something else with our tactics.
We have grabbed our touchbacks.
All right, and hmm.
OK, so I'm going to go to my update panel function, let's update the position, so I'm going to say
move the panel with with touch or something.
So in here, we need we still need to change this position of touch X, right.
For our panel to move.
So we are going to say if touch X is not null.
OK, if first off, we need to check if the user has touched the screen.
That is going to give us when the touch is not now, if it is not, it means that the user has not clicked
and we don't have any touch here.
We don't have any touch here.
And basically it is either touch and or whether it is touch cancel.
So first off, we need to check if it is not touch, cancel and touch.
And so after we checked for that, we are going to say that if Touch X is great on the paddles exposition,
we want to move the paddle and the direction.
The direction, the direction is going to be right and Ellos F.
Elusive, the touchbacks is it was greater than the power also, it is less than the paddle.
Come on, when I want to be quick, if it is less than the paddle, the paddles exposition, we want
to call our move paddle function and we are going to pass in the direction Dart left.
Let's say it.
Hopefully it works.
There we go and it stops there wherever the touch stops, it is going to stop there.
See, we still have that shaky kind of behavior, so I'm going to implement that, even though it is
getting closer to 40 minutes.
I know that's a lot, but I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to implement that as well, because that
is going to be basically a minor adjustment that we will be doing here.
So to be able to remove the shaky behavior, what I'm going to do is I'm going to add on to the exposition
of the paddle a small value, which is the walls with and I'm going to add it when it when it is greater
than that, it means it's moving to the right.
I'm going to add it when it is moving to the left, I'm going to remove it.
Very simple.
And also we need to we need to implement the stop as well.
I mean.
Right.
So else else move.
Paddle.
Excuse me.
A direction dot stop.
Direxion, stop, perfect, so now.
See, perfectly fine.
There we go.
So this is perfect simulation.
The ball has hit, the ball has hit, the ball hit.
And it is not shakey anymore, so there we go, boom, boys.
It's perfectly fine.
So we were able to actually do that and actually create the iTouch events in this lecture that said,
see you guys in the next one.