Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we're going to draw the text on the screen.
All right, so what is going to be the text, the text is going to either say the computer want or say
the human one or either going to say draw.
So I'm going to come on top where we have declared our variables.
And right beneath the colors, I'm going to create a comment that is going to say text.
So the first one that I want to create is going to be text underscore EHI.
So this is when the eye actually wins and it is going to say computer, computer.
Right.
And I'm just going to copy it down below and I'm going to change it to our eye and it is going to say
human.
Perfect human.
When a copy it down below and I'm going to say text tie one, it is a tie and it is going to say draw
and let's copy it one more time.
And when someone wins.
We are going to say one.
So one that's come in, the colors are right and let's create the colors for them as well.
So let me just copy that and bring it down below.
And you're going to say color for the tie is going to be dark gray.
So dark gray.
We have we are going to I'm just going to provide a space there.
So we are going to have a color for the tie and there's going to be a color for the tie that is dark.
And it should be underscore, and this is going to be black.
Block, you're going to see these colors don't work, and then we are going to have a color for when
someone wins.
So it is going to be color underscored the eye end and I'm going to set it to blue and this blue is
going to highlight the winning cells for us.
So now that these are done, let's head over.
To let's see to to our game loop, and I'm just going to call a function there.
So where is our game loop in here?
I'm going to call the draw text function.
We have not created that.
I know we are going to create it right now.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to come right here is a drug Red.
Highlight grid, create grid, draw grid, liar right here, it doesn't really matter where you put
them, I just want them to be like organized.
That's why I put it right here.
So in here, I'm going to say draw text function.
It's coming this one out.
So function draw text, and we're not going to pass in any parameters now, these texts only can be
drawn on the screen when the game is over.
So when the game is over, either it is going to be a a draw or a tie or it is going to be the in the
case that the computer has won or it is going to be the case that the that the human has won.
So we need to only draw the text whenever the game is over.
So if the game is not over, we basically we just go ahead and return from the function.
Right.
So that's the condition that we need to check first.
And now, first off, we are going to set up the text parameters.
So set of text.
Parameters.
Now, what is going to be decide, so I'm going to say the size is going to be the grid, where is our
grid, which has a these are the the zero and the zero column dots height.
So it's going to be any cells height.
The text is going to be dermo.
Now let's go ahead and provide it with the first tile.
Right now, we are dynamically drawing these texts, so it is either going to be computer one, then
it is going to or play a human one or so for the dynamic CARLETTI purposes.
I'm not going to hard code any styles for the film any like a stroke style or anything like that.
So we are just going to use a like a sort of.
General rule here, so in if any of those conditions present themselves, we would have something for
the we don't want to repeat ourselves.
I'm not going to hard code anything here.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's say it's our text is going to have a fail and it is going to
have a stroke.
And why is that?
So let's see that here.
So, for example, let's let's actually try to win this game.
So what I when you can see that I'm going to zoom in so you can see that the text has some fell and
it has stroke as well.
So we need to accommodate for the fill and the stroke.
So first off, the tile.
It's going to be the game tied.
All right, and when the game is tied, how do we know when the game is tight, if the game tied is
true, we want to show the color that is for the tie, right?
What if it is player's turn?
What if the game tied is not true?
When the game tied is not true, it means that it is the player's turn.
And how do we know which player?
So if the player's turn is true, it is going to be the player.
R.I if it is false it is going to be the player
ehi perfect.
And that is going to be it for this.
So we are going to check if the game tied is true.
We are going to show that color.
If it is false, we are going to check for player's turn.
If player's turn is true, we are going to get on all right.
Otherwise we are going to get color our.
So this is going to be the canvas Phil style that's grabbed the canvas font, which we have talked about
briefly.
Now, this this is going to be the size, that pixel size, font size.
And now we need to add on to it that pixel itself, pixel unit and the family is going to be sans serif.
Sans serif.
Perfect, and let's go ahead and let's create the line with so we are going to see a line devoted to
each.
There is an increasing line with is going to be the size of the tax divided by 10.
You could go, you could make it bigger or you can make it smaller.
Now, let's go ahead now, this is the fill of that text.
What about the stroke of the text?
So we are going to say canvas, canvas, context, stroke style, stroke style.
It should be equal to if we need to check.
This is a Turner operator.
If game tied is true, we are going to show the color tie dark.
If game tied is not true, we are going to check for the players turn.
If the players return is true, we are going to show the color dark.
R.I and if foul play stern is not true, we are going to show the color a dark.
Perfect.
So this is how dynamic reality works in this context, we are going to grab the canvas context and we're
going to say text a line, you kid a line text as well.
I mean, how cool is that?
You just have to provide it inside quotes the alignment.
We want the text to be aligned in the center.
We want to grab the baseline of the text as well.
Canvas.
Canvas, context, art, text, baseline, and I'm going to set it to metal, so the text is in the
middle.
And now let's go ahead and actually draw these texts, so I'm going to say drawing the text perfect
now we are going to provide an offset for the texts as well.
I'm going to provide it and I'm going to commented out so you can see where the offset is coming.
And I'm going to it's going to be half of the size of the text.
So let's grab or let's say let text.
So we have two different kind of texts.
Actually, three.
One is for the computer.
The other one is for the other for the human.
The other one is for the tie.
So if game tight is true, we are going to show the text for the tie.
If it is false, we are going to check which players alternatives.
If it is, the player's turn is true, it means that it is the real intelligence player's turn and we
are going to show the text for that.
Otherwise, we are going to show the text for the perfect, so we have done that as well.
Now, let's say F.
If game tied is true.
We need to draw that text, so if it is game tight now, we have stood this this turn into operator
within that text, now we need to use it, right.
So if game tied is true, what do you want to show through to the user?
We want to show the text for the tie that is drawn.
So we are going to grab the canvas context stroke.
Text.
This is going to be a function what is the text?
The text is going to be the text that we have specified there.
The you can see that it requires an exposition and then a Y position and a max with.
So what is the exposition?
The exposition is going to be the width divided by two.
It means that it should be in the center of the canvas and the height should be divided by two in the
center of the canvas vertically and horizontally.
OK, there we go.
We have specified it with so we do not need to specify the max.
And now let's go ahead and let's fill that text.
So filled text.
Uh huh.
Let's it's actually going to be the same thing.
So the text and the middle.
Perfect.
Let's put it right there or else else it means that either the computer has one or the game is not tied.
So either the computer or the human has one.
So can this context dot stroke, text, stroke text?
And we are going to provide that here as well, so the same thing, so all of the texts are going to
show in the same spot and we are going to show the text.
So this is going to be the film text, Phil text and what text should that be the we are going to show
the text when for that.
All right.
So it's either the computer or the we have talked about that a lot.
So what I'm going to do is.
It's called the canvas context, dot stroke text.
And let's provide the text when text when the position is going to be the same.
So this just copy the position, it's going to be right there.
And we are also going to have a text.
So text, text when with and directly in the center so we could go ahead and test this.
But in order to test what we have done here is now you can see we have not used the offset.
We are going to use that one.
I'm going to go where I'm going to go is let's see, where is our check game check when where did you
provide it?
So instead of returning false, I wanted to return.
True, because we want to check that text.
So let's see.
Hopefully it works.
So there we go.
So if I come here, you can see that whenever I click, it is just going to say the computer one and
you can see that the text is on top of each other.
And if I click again and you can see that it says the computer one in both cases and first off, let's
go ahead and let's take care of the this offset.
So if I provide it, let's come down.
Where is our function?
Right here, so I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to provide the offset, I'm going to subtract
the offset from the height in here.
So offset.
And I'm going to subtracted from the height here as well, offset and for the text when I'm just going
to add it so offset.
Offset Soviet, let's click on it and you can see the rest, some sort of offset, but still they are
connected to each other.
And I'm just going to go to top.
Let's check let's turn this to oh and lower case and.
Hmm.
I'm just going to increase the offset to zero point six.
And if I click, you can see there is more space there, but you can see that these spikes going out
out of that, that is because of the line join the line joints should be around.
So what we're going to do is canvass context.
Canvas context.
I believe it's line joint.
Yeah, it is, and we are going to set it to round.
So let's have it.
Let's come here.
There we go.
Now, we cannot see any more spikes in here, so we can see the computer one in both cases, we can
see it says the computer one.
All right, so just this week, ABC computer one, it's green to computer one, you can see the stroke
with and the fill with that filled text.
But there seems to be a problem in both cases.
It's this computer.
I know we should check for when the player wins or the computer wins.
So this is where actually it's happening.
This is where we're dry.
So we say if game tied is true, why is why is this in parentheses?
So let's remove the parentheses.
If game tied is true, we want to change.
We want to write the text of time otherwise that this is the problem.
This should be semicolon, this should be Colen.
Otherwise, we are going to check for the player's turn if player's return is true.
So otherwise players stern is true.
If it is true, we are going to set it to text r.i otherwise are going to set it to text ehi so let's
save it now.
This is a computer one and when you click you can see that we can still select these which we shouldn't
and we are going to fix that.
Don't worry.
Now if I click the game is now it's just a human.
There we go.
So it's just human want.
So computer one human one.
We don't see any tie.
Now that, that only happens because when we went up to the check, when whenever any of the users they
play any they put any piece, then it would be just a win for that specific user.
And OK, so I think I think with this, our lecture comes to an end to see you guys in the next one.