Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to take a look at another way of creating e-mail aliments.
All right, so we have talked about how we can create any stimulus and how we can give it some identity,
some text or content on how we can make sure that a another element adopts this element.
Right.
A parent element adopts or appends it to itself or.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm not going to comment anything out.
I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to pasted down here.
And now this is called method number six that we are going to talk about.
And this is insert before.
And you might ask, why do I have to know about another method that does this?
Whenever you use the Appen child, OK, it is always going to append it to the end of that list.
What if you wanted you wanted appended to the top or what if you want to pin that child to like to be
the second item to third, to be the third or the fourth one?
So that control comes with the insert before method, right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead through the creation of another element step by step,
and we are going to name it new item two, because I want you guys to have a bit more practice.
So we are going to say new item now.
We have created a new item.
I'm just going to call this, too, and we are going to go ahead and we are going to say document that
create element and what is the element that we want to create?
It is an ally, right.
So after the element is created, what I want to do is I should be able to grab the URL, the parent
and the item before which I want to insert this newly created item.
So where do I want to insert it?
So I'm going to come on top of it and I'm going to say const like, let's go.
Let's say we want to insert another item before this first item and I'm going to name this first item.
Let's selected document that query selector.
And here we are going to say you now take a look at this.
We have three allies here, right?
All three of them have a class of item.
How can we select the best and easiest selection is just to grab them by their Biasutto pseudo class.
And we are going to say Elai first, Dasch child, this is our first child, Suda class selecter.
Now we have selected this loyal and we can check it out as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and just very quickly for demonstration purposes, I'm going to log it
to the council first item and when I hover over it, we are going to see that the first item is highlighted.
This is one of the best use cases of console's of luck, right.
So now that we have selected our first item, the item that we want to inserted before, all right,
and we have selected our you have there as well, so we don't need to select a reviewer once more.
All right.
And we have created over Elia's.
Well, now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to give this illi some some identity.
I'm going to give it some content or text.
But before that, let's go ahead and let's consulate.
Let's log it to the council.
I was about to say consoli to the log.
New item, and we are going to see this is empty.
There is nothing inside of it and we are going to say new item to that, enter the text should be protective.
Save it, and now it has got some identity, but still we cannot see it here.
It should be should come before the loyal one.
All right.
Now for the third and the final step, well, actually, we had three steps I forgot to mention.
Now I'm mentioning it.
It is this was step.
This was second step, the creation of the element.
The first step was the selection of the element.
The first step is the selection of the element before which you wanted you wanted to insert.
The second step is a creation of the element and the third step is actually appending this.
All right.
So we are going to say list DOT.
We have the other has a variable name of list.
So we have successfully access that there.
So we don't need to really do it again.
And we are going to say that insert before.
All right, we are going to grab our item, what is the item that we want to we want we want to we want
to insert what is that item?
It is the new item to and where do we want to insert it before before the first item.
When I say that, we are going to see that protective is right here.
So even though in the e-mail we have only three allies in the what page we have five because the two
of them are fed by JavaScript.
All right.
And I'm going to call this the third step.
Very, very simple stuff.
Right.
So this is the end of this letter.
See you guys in the next lecture.