Hi, everyone, in this that year, we are going to talk about the logical end operator.
All right, so these operators, these logical operators, they modify other boolean expressions, right,
and the first logical operator that we are going to take a look at is the logical end operator for which
the symbol is.
Double ampersands, this is the symbol to ampersands, all right, and the boolean expressions or conditions
on both sides should be true for this operator to return.
True.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's take a look at an example.
All right.
So this is example number one.
And we are going to say f first off, let's create the body of our F statement.
Now, if a ten is greater than five and five is greater than four, we want to run to the console.
We want to log to the console, a message of success.
And then you guys can see we can we have successfully run that.
OK, now this what has happened, what has actually happened here?
Now you guys can say we have we have talked about the F conditions are right and the F statements.
We have a condition.
And if that condition is met, then we run a certain code.
So what is our condition?
This doesn't seem like our normal condition.
This condition actually has two parts.
So F 10 is greater than five.
And the logical end operator says five is greater than four.
Then I'm going to run this code.
And if even one side of this this logical operator, even if one of these boolean expressions are not
true, then I'm not going to run anything.
Right.
I'm not going to run anything.
So.
For instance, let's go ahead and let's say three.
Now, we know that 10 is greater than five.
Right.
We have talked about this greater than comparison operator.
And but but this is incorrect.
Three is not greater than four.
So one side of this boolean expression is correct.
The other side of the boolean expression or the boolean expression on the other side is not correct.
So this code of success should not run and let's save it.
And we don't see anything.
Right.
So this is how this logical end operators work.
Both sides should be should evaluate to true for us to be able to run our code.
So this is our first example.
In the second example, we are going to take it up a notch and we are going to check for more than one
condition that we have.
OK, so this is going to be our example to first off, I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to create a variable and I'm going to set it to number 11 by default.
Right.
And we are going to say F.
If age is greater than or equal to one, and it is an age is less than or equal to 12, then what do
I want to do?
I want to log to the console.
Minor.
All right.
I'm just going to copy this piece of code.
If age is greater than or equal to one and it is equal to 12 or less than 12, then we want to run to
the console minor.
Right now, what is the second part of this?
And the second part of this statement is going to be announced F statement because we are checking for
more than two conditions.
Right.
So what if the in the second condition, what do I want to do if H is greater than or equal to 13 and
H is less than or equal to 19?
What do I want to do?
I want to run.
I want to bring to the console teenager and I'm sure you guys have have I've got the gist of what I'm
going to do.
OK, so what in any other scenario?
In any other scenario, I just want to run an adult.
Right.
So basically we are checking for three conditions.
F the age of any person is equal to one or from one to twelve.
We want to run minor or if it is from 13 to 19, we want to run teenager or in any other scenario,
for example, if the age is 20, 21, 30, 40, 50, then we just run adult.
All right.
So now the ages 11, 11 is less than 12.
OK, so this condition is met.
That's why we we have printed to the console miner right now.
Let's go ahead and let's change it.
Let's check in at the boundaries, so the boundary is one here and 12 here.
All right.
And now you guys can see that both of the statements have been evaluated to true.
That's why this logical operator has been has run this code, because I'm just going to go ahead and
comment this one out.
This one is going to be one.
I'm going to uncommented this one because 11 is greater than one.
So this condition is met and 11 is less than 12.
So this boolean expression is also meant.
So when both of the boolean expressions are met, we printed the cost of this and we do not even go
to the rest of the condition condition that we have created.
Now it's comment that one out and let's check it out, the boundaries.
So if the age is one, it means age is equal to one and one is also less than 12.
So both sides are equal or evaluate to true.
So this code should run and now we see minor.
Let's say we are checking it at the boundaries.
All right.
Let's put it to 12.
We still should see minor.
Yes, we do.
Now, let's check it for more than 12.
All right.
Now let's check it for 13 and for 13.
Let's go ahead and save it.
We see a teenager.
And why is that?
Because 13 is greater than one.
OK, this side of the boolean expression has been evaluated to true, but 13 is nonetheless done, is
not equal, is not less than or equal to 12.
So this speed, this piece of condition is not going to run.
And then the algorithm is going to come to this one and check for this el-Fadl statement.
And this we see that the age is either greater than or equal to 13 and now this condition is met.
And in this part it says it's equal to or less than 19.
So 13 is equal to 13 and less than 19.
So this piece of logic should run.
Right.
And it works perfectly fine.
Let's put it to 14.
We still get teenager.
Let's check it at the boundary, which is 19.
We still get teenager and let's check it out, the 20.
So in any other scenario, we should get adult.
Which we do.
All right, so if it is 20, we are going to get adult, if it is, I don't know, like 35, we are
going to get adult.
I'm going to do one more.
And if even if it is like, I don't know, 68, we are going to get adult.
So that's it for this lecture and to see you guys in the next one.