Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to make our UI functional.
All right, so what do I mean by that, whenever I click this, we should get some rate, right?
So what are we going to do is I'm going to come on top.
And let's see what it is that we want to grab, so in here, inside the inputs, we have an input type
of front currency, which we need to currency, which we need, and exchange amount which we require.
And but so basically, we are going to grab from currency input to currency input exchange amount and
get right between the scrub them.
So I'm going to say consed from currency input and document.
You know what, I'm going to save you some time and I'm going to just copy paste this.
It's basically those inputs.
We have selected them by their class names.
Nothing special here.
Now where is going to be the event.
The event is going to be on the button.
When the button is clicked, then that should happen.
All right, Wendy Button is clicked.
All right.
So let's come here.
So I'm going to say get right between dot and event listener.
And now you can see that one part of this entire scenario is done that is getting the data and getting
the data or retrieving the data and now converting it into a meaningful form is remaining.
That's what we are doing here, in case you're wondering.
And one listener, we are going to listen for a click and then we are going to run a function and let's
grab the event object and now let's just save it.
And now let's come here.
You can see that whenever I click, you can see the page reloads.
Take a look at this.
You can see that the page reloads and this is the default behavior.
Either you click or you hit enter in here.
No, it doesn't.
So if I do hit enter, you can see that the the event is going to submit.
So we are going to say idot prevent default behavior.
We don't want to submit.
We want to do something else now.
Now, what do we want to do?
We want to grab the value from this currency and put the value from this or the value of this currency
and put the value of this currency input and the exchange amount so we can understand what is what and
we can convert it.
So to be able to do that, as I'm going to say consed from currency value, I'm going to call it from
currency value.
And what is this?
It is going to be our foreign currency input dout value.
All right.
So let's copy it two more times.
So this is going to be two currency value, two currency input value, and then we have our exchange
amount.
Exchange amount value, so let's copy that exchange and mount.
So it is exchange amount, there is no input there, I'm just going to add an input here as well, input
and now it is here.
So now I'm going to very quickly cancel logit.
I'm going to say from currency value to currency value exchange amount.
Exchange amount.
Exchange amount via, so let's save it.
So now if I write a friend here, right, USD here and write 1000 and Kaleck, we get all that perfect.
So what do we want to do with this data?
We want to grab this value and put it here, and then we want to grab this value to currency, put it
here and then we want to grab the input amount and put it right here.
That said, that's basically what we want to do.
So in order to do that, shouldn't we I mean, shouldn't we copy all that and remove this and paste
it here?
So instead of hard coding C++, what we can do is from currency value, from currency value is going
to be this one.
This is going to be two currency value.
And what does this amount amount is going to be exchange amount value.
So let's put it here.
All right.
So now this is going to be the same.
So if I save it, keep in mind, if I save it and if I come here and if I say if an USD 1000 and click,
we get the same result.
So now the thing the only thing remaining is just get this result and put it inside the UI.
I mean, how difficult could that be?
It's in fact, very, very, very simple, so inside here, we are returning this council log, but
I don't want to return it.
I want to say document dot.
Query selector what?
What is the element that I want to grab?
I want to grab this element.
So let's grab the class, because we are going to change the entire text of that element document that
query selector.
This is going to be the class dot in our text and our T 60.
What is the inner text.
The inner text is going to be our exchange result.
It's copy.
Let's put it right here and now.
Let's check if it works, we get a if and USD, we get 1000 and click, we get that.
Now the thing with this is that it's not going to go away.
I want it to go.
I want it to go away after exactly like maybe five seconds.
So to set time out.
And I'm going to provide an arrow function here and I'm going to say location.
Now, when you say location to reload, it is going to reload the entire page.
OK, it's it's ironic that within our asynchronous function we are reloading the page.
I mean, if you get that, it's it's kind of a joke, right?
Like a retard joke.
But this is a programming.
Do we reload the function?
We reload the page inside our asynchronous function.
That's ironic.
OK, so what is the time I could put it to, for example, six seconds.
So now if I do offend USD 1000, one, two, three, four, five, six perfect's.
I'm also a clock, right, so now we are done with this part.
Now the two major parts which are remaining is one, we need to make sure that whenever the input is
empty and we do something, we shouldn't get this error.
Not a no.
See, this is printed to this UI.
This is not something that we want to print.
So what I'm going to do here is we are going to create a basic F check.
We are going to check if if from currency value is empty or from or to currency value is empty or or
this is logical or operator or exchange amount value is empty.
Then do what?
Then go ahead and cancel log.
Error in caps alse.
And the aspart.
Come on, buddy, in the aspart, we want to run this thing.
So where is where is this going to end here?
The dot then is going to end right here.
So let's cut it.
Let's put it right here.
Save it.
So now if I click ever if I say Afan, let's remove this.
And if I click, we get error again.
If I do USD and remove this click, we get another error.
And now if I do 1000, we are not going to get any error and it should go after six seconds.
Hmm.
All right, so this is done as well, we have checked that, but the thing is, we don't want to log
this error to the console.
We want to show when the input is empty.
We want to show this stuff.
So instead of this, I'm going to call in function.
I'm going to say input, input, error.
And this input error, as is, has the responsibility to show this right now, that this is going to
be an input when or when one of these threes is empty, we certainly have an input error.
But there was another kind of error as well, which we threw right here, and that was the invalid code
error.
So instead of doing this, I'm going to say I'm going to say throw new year.
So throw new error.
And inside this error, what I'm going to do, I'm going to call the invalid code function, I'm going
to call the invalid.
Now, we are yet to create these functions.
We need to create the input error and the invalid code.
Now, we have created this error here.
How can we catch this error?
We should catch it right here.
So after the dot, then we know how we can catch it.
So if I do it, if I save it, nothing is going.
We will see some.
If I do this, we see error because input, error, they're not defined.
We are going to define them.
Don't worry about that.
We are going to catch the error here.
So to to catch the error, I'm not going to do anything.
I'm just going to call this function.
Right.
So I'm going to say invalid.
Invalid code function.
Now, keep in mind, we don't have two errors, we have three errors.
One error is the input error rate, which actually has three types.
If this is empty, if this is empty, if this is empty, which you have, which actually has three types,
I'm not talking about that.
We have an input error, but we have two different kinds of invalid code.
Why are two different kinds just go away?
The first one is whenever the from currency code is incorrect.
The second one is whenever the two currency code is incorrect.
So we actually we are throwing three errors.
So this is catching one error.
So let's save it.
Why didn't it come down?
Should have come down here.
Oh, I added it to the set time out, I should add it to here and now it's in the correct place.
So when then is done and then we add that catch.
So this is going to throw the invalid error whenever the first input is incorrect, this is going to
throw the invalid error.
When the second input is incorrect, this is going to throw an error when either of the inputs is empty.
So we are going to simulate these errors in our next selection.
See you guys then.