Hi, everyone, welcome to Part six of Matching.
All right, so in this picture, we are going to go over the first example, which actually is example
number 21.
Can you believe it?
Twenty one examples.
So we are going to match all the non-white space and the previous lecture we must all the white space.
In this lecture, we're going to match all the non-white space.
And you guessed it right.
It is going to be the lower case.
So I'm going to jump into the previous lecture, grab this, copy it and jump back in and put it right
here.
Let's grab all the 20s and turn them to twenty one and let's do CAPITALIS.
And now we get everything that is not a white space.
Right.
Very, very simple.
We can also get the length and we can see it is 90.
Right.
So it is 90 now that's come these one out.
The next one is for the next three examples.
We are going to discuss a newer like a new idea, and that is like quantity specifiers.
So example number two, we are going to specify upper and lower number of matches using quantity, quantity,
quantity specifiers.
Now, let's say we have where is a Google?
Where is it?
So we have Google.
We have, uh.
Hmm.
Whoa.
All right.
So let's put in an AI there as well.
So both of them are.
Oh, so let's go ahead and let's find something else.
Yeah, yeah, that like that, so we have it.
So now what we are going to do is we are going to go ahead and create our regular expression number
22 and inside there, I'm not going to pass anything.
And for now, so what it is that we want to do here, we want to grab all the O's that happen two to
four times.
So I'm just going to provide oh, here.
And quantity specifiers are provided inside curly braces.
So there are going to be three scenarios.
The first scenario is going to be we will have two numbers.
So the first number is going to be the minimum.
And the second number after comma, of course, is going to be the maximum range.
Think of this like a range that we have.
And the second case is we are going to talk about that.
We have when we have a minimum number, but not a maximum number.
And in the third case, we just have one number.
Right.
That is going to be the maximum number for us.
So I want to propose that a curve two to four times or like I could say one to four times or two to
four times doesn't really matter.
So let's let's grab this and let's put it right here.
I'm just going to remove the length.
We are not going to need a length anymore.
We could do the match and we could do the test.
So what I'm going to do is in this scenario, I'm just going to do the test.
So we are going to write a regular expression, number two into two here, and we are going to test
that sentence that we have.
So let's grab it and let's say sentence.
Right.
And let's come in this one and come in this one.
And and so this is one to one.
Let's change both of them to twenty two and we get through.
What does it mean?
It means that we do have oase that are at least repeated two times and a maximum of four times, not
a maximum like two to four times because there we have one, two, three and four.
We don't care about the rest of them.
That's why so strong we can go ahead and go over.
One more example and I'm going to say, Regg, 22 X.
So for this to work, I'm just going to comment about that part.
And in here we are going to write E that are repeated three to five times.
Right.
We are going to grab all of them and I'm going to put in the G flag in case we need it.
So let's stir it inside this variable.
This time we are going to grab our sentence and match it.
We're going to grab our sentence and match it to that regular expression, so rage 22 X and we are going
to store, we're going to cancel log the result, so let's save it.
So it's a sentence, that test.
OK, so this should be match.
Let's save it.
And now we get that.
So we get all the way to five and we get all the way to three.
So it means that we get e whether it is repeated three times or a maximum of five times.
So this is the minimum value and this is the maximum.
So we have got in it, which is five times and we have gotten it, which is three times.
This is how we can specify the upper and lower number of matches and the next example.
An example, number 23, we are just concerned with specifying the lower number of matches, using the
quantity specifiers.
So if I were to like, let's say Grob, this example, it right here because I'm not like so much focusing
on typing the code rather than explaining.
So in this case, I'm just going to remove the upper the upper case sorry, the upper there upper range.
I kind of lost the word there, so I just removed the upper range.
And what what does that mean?
It means that we are looking for an oh that that happens at least two times.
We don't care how many times it it has happened.
It should happen at least two times.
Right.
So let's go ahead and grab these and we are going to say 23 and we get through because we do have that
kind of oh, that happens at least two times.
But if I were to remove like Goggle, say, like Google and save it, we are going to get false.
Why do we get false?
The reason that that we get false is we don't have two consecutive O's, at least two consecutive O's
for this pattern to return trip.
Now, I'm sure you are getting the idea.
So if I were to say I'm looking for an edge that happens at least two times or for an L that happens
at least two times, then if I were to remove these two realis, then we are going to get false because
we don't have that kind of pattern inside the string and it is going to return.
False or true, because this is the test method.
You can go ahead and check it out and the match method as well.
But I'm just going to suffice to this.
So this was the second scenario where we only have one of the bands, a specified sorry, one of the
bands specified it was the lower bound.
Now, now, let's go ahead and specify the exact number it is that we are looking for.
So that is going to be our example.
Number 24, specifying the exact number of matches, using the quantity specifiers.
So we are looking for an exact number.
So let's you know what?
I'm just going to copy this, put it right here and I'm going to uncommented all of them before saving.
Let's change it to twenty four.
Now I'm just going to remove the comma.
So I'm looking for oh, that happens two times.
When I save it, we get false.
Why do we get false.
Because we don't have any.
Oh that happens exactly two times.
If I were to say Google now we get true.
Why is that.
Because Google has exactly two O's previously it did and that's why it returned.
False.
So you can do the math for this one as well.
But this test, it actually says it actually conveys the point better than matching matching.
It is going to give it is going to give it to us.
But this testing is going to say whether or not this pattern is accurate.
That's why we started with test and we ended up with match.
And again, we are working with the test.
You can go both ways that that's why I've done both ways in here.
You can go both ways.
You can you can check out if that pattern is true or if that pattern exists, and then you can extract
the pattern using the match method.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.