Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we are going to talk about the appends, the prepend, the removed child and the Remove
Dume Method's.
All right, so we have been able to successfully append two children to and you add that in our previous
lecture, but in this lecture, the Mark-Up is a bit different.
And I want to append I want to use this old order list as well.
So what if you want to add or you want to add more than one element to a Web page?
So we have we have talked about about two ways of adding only one element to a Web page.
So what if you want to add more than one element, that's where the append method comes in.
So what I'm going to do is, first off, it has the same drill.
The first step is creating the element.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and say first is going to be this is step number
one, creating the element.
So.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create a new H5 element, a new H5 element, and I'm going to say
document dot, create element, very simple.
And in here, I'm going to pass five and I'm going to create an inch six aliment as well, so I'm going
to grab this and that, I'm going to turn into six.
So now we have successfully created two new elements.
We can kick him out in the console as well.
So we can say new age five, we are going to see our age five and we can also say New Age sex.
It's 6:00 and we are going to see an on at 6:00 a.m. aliment, so this is the step number one.
The step number two is giving our elements an identity.
Well, it doesn't matter if which steps comes before which, but this this procedure makes the most
it makes the most sense, the most news.
All right.
So we are going to grab our new, not their new at 5:00.
And we are going to say that N-word text equal to cats.
All right.
And we are going to grab it the next time.
And we are going to save birds for the H six.
Let's save it.
And now it's five and six.
Both of them.
They have some identity.
All right, for the third step, we find an element to append these as the relatives of that element.
All right.
So for that, I'm going to go ahead.
I'm going to say CONSED and I'm going to grab a main heading.
It is DeMain heading and I'm going to say document that query selector, select the one, save it.
And now the final the final thing that we have to do here is Main Dot hadn't many men heading dot append.
Not a child died of pain.
What do we want to spend?
We want to open the new H5 and New Age six and let's save it.
And if we come here, we are going to see that we are going to see cats and we are going to see birds.
Now, let's let's increase this window.
Let's go into our aliments and let's come here.
So where are our acharn?
Which we can't see them.
Oh, they're here.
So they have been nested inside this one.
I mean, this might not be something that you want, but this is actually how a pen works.
We can nest elements.
All right.
And this is not something that you ever do.
So I should have probably should have come up with a better example.
But this conveys the point.
This is not something that you do.
You never nest titles.
That's I've never faced it in my entire development journey.
Work development.
All right.
So this is one way of doing it.
And this is one way of creating you could have created two allies and you could have just appended it
to a user and you know how you can do that, like as a challenge.
Go ahead and do that.
All right.
So method number eight.
Now, take a look at this.
Whenever you do append or you do a pin child, they're always going to be added to the end of that element.
What if you want to add it to the start of the element?
That's where our method number eight comes from.
It is called prepend.
Prepend, OK, and we are simply going to say mean heading.
Dot prepend, prepend, prepend, what new age five, very, very simple stuff, new age six, it's
seven.
And now cats and birds, they're on top of the ducks.
All right.
And now this has been prepend it.
That was the appendix.
This is the prepend.
This is method number eight.
Let's go ahead and let's talk about our final two methods, which are method number nine and method
number ten.
Now, we have not really talked about how we can remove elements through JavaScript, so we are going
to go ahead and we are going to say we are going to just pasted here and turn it tonight and we are
going to say remove a child.
So there are two ways of removing an element from a Web page.
The first way is remove a child.
Now, this method I'm just going to in parentheses will not in parentheses, I'm just going to do it
requires a parent note.
So if you want to remove any element through this method, you have to provide it with a parent kind
of reference.
All right, so what we are going to do is let's go ahead, let's check out our.
Our markup.
OK, so in here, what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to I'm going to select this.
Oh well.
And I'm going to remove an element from this.
Oh, well, that's why this oil has been added here.
So let's go ahead and let's select the oil.
I'm going to say consed to do list.
Right to do list document that query selector and we're going to selected by the element name which
is OEL.
We are going to select the item that we want to remove as well.
So we are going to say consed to do item document dot query selector and we are going to say oh well
elai and dash child, let's say child number three.
That's added.
The search for number three, let's save it so now, because we want to delete this, this this repeat
coffee item or a child from this webpage, what we have to do is first we have to select the parent
and then we can select the airline.
So this is what we remove child does and requires a parent.
That's why we have selected the parent as well.
And you might ask, why do why why have you selected the child itself?
Because we want to remove it.
We want to have we want to give JavaScript a way to select it and then remove it.
It's exactly like in see, assess you select an element and you say display none and that's it.
Or you say visibility hidden or you say opacity zero.
First you got a selected right to do some sort of thing on it.
OK, so we are going to say to do list, dot, remove, remove, child, what is the child that we want
to remove?
We want to remove the to do to the worries over item to do item.
And when I say yes, and here you can see that we don't have any third option in here anymore.
So the third item has been removed.
So this is one way of removing.
Elements from a Web page, the next one is even better.
All right, so I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to copy it from here to here.
Well, actually, I'm going to grab it, all of it, and I'm going to paste it here.
This is our final method, method number 10.
And it is just remove it and remove this one does not require a parent.
We can just select the item and we can just remove it.
So for that, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go ahead and comment this one out because and
common the parent out.
We have successfully selected the item number three that we want to remove and we are going to say to
do item dot remove.
And because this is a method we are going to add parentheses and save it and it is removed.
So taking a look at it, this is a way better approach than remove a child.
But sometimes you you you might want to do this.
You might want to be really, really specific.
All right.
And also, this is a newer syntax, so it may not it might not have that sort of like really outstanding
browser compatibility.
So do check before using it.
Right.
So this brings about the end of this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.