Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about the array find method.
All right, so the find method returns the value of the first element.
Keep this in mind, the first element in the provided array that satisfies the provided testing function.
So we are dealing with the testing function once more, but we are just going to grab the first element
that.
The testing function that satisfies the criteria of the testing function, so let's grab our array and
let's call the find method on it.
So it is going to only grab one of them right now.
Let's passan our.
Parameter, and that is artist name, so we want to grab an artist's name.
All right.
So the artist name, dot name.
OK, or sorry, not name, because in here we don't have a name.
We just have artist.
So we are going to say that artist should be called to, for example, Chuck Berry.
All right.
If it is equal to that, what do we want to do?
We want to print it to the console, log it to the console and oops, we have not saved this.
So let's go ahead and let's say artist name, artist artist names.
And now let's call let's print it artists names, let's save it, and we get Chuck Berry and now imagine
imagine if there were like another Chuck Berry as well, like like Chuck Berry had another song.
And I'm just going to put it right here.
So the artist's name is Chuck Berry, but the song is the the second.
Come on, second one, and it is, let's say 1959, let's save it, but we still get the artist as Chuck
Berry.
This song is Johnny B. Goode and year is 1958.
The reason that we don't get this is we just grab the first item that satisfies this condition so we
don't care how many items come come after that, we just grab the first one that satisfies this condition
that set for the array method.
See you guys in the next lecture.