Hi, everyone, in this picture, we are going to target the dynamically created to do items.
All right, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab our to do list and we are going to add an event
listener.
Now, why add an event listener on the to do list and the thing which is the parent of them or not the
parent parent of them all, but it is the parent of to do items.
Right, because we don't have any other actual way of targeting this icon for which has a status of
complete and this icon which has a status of delay.
So what we are going to do is we are going to we are going to add this event on the parent and then
we are going to do some stuff to tweak it.
I don't want to give away the surprise or the cool thing, not surprise the cool thing that we are going
to do.
I don't want to spoil it, so I'm just going to dive right in.
So we are going to create a function in the function.
We are going to grab our event or event or write.
I think we can call it evt as well.
Let's find out.
So what do we want to do when the to do list is collect?
Now, this is whenever we for example, when we create like let's say I'm sleeping.
Right.
So whenever we created to do, we can do three things with it within that year.
Well, all right.
Now, this Trijicon, this is now located inside the you.
The story of this trash icon is completely is completely different.
I'm not talking about this.
I'm talking about this.
You URL that houses these Ellyse so I can click on the circle to check it.
I can unclick to I can click to uncheck it or I can click on the trash to remove it.
But how can I if I were to write reading how can I click on this circle.
And it seems like this is an event listener and this is a click event.
All right.
So there is no other way of doing it except grabbing the to do list container and targeting where the
click happens.
So now we are inside the to do list.
So if I go ahead and if I say concertante log one, two, three, let's save it.
Let's come here.
We are inside the console.
So if I click here.
All right, so this happens when.
To Doolan's that another listener kaleck function, we are going to target cancer log, so let's let's
see why it doesn't work.
So I decided to do, for example, walking.
It's work it and now if I go ahead and if I click, we can see that it says one, two, three and it
is going to run it everywhere.
So if I click on the text, if I click on, there's anything that I click on, you can see that the
number increases.
So it is now 21 to 24 and all that.
But we want to specifically target this and transmit.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a constant call to do item right.
So constant variable to do item.
And I'm going to set it to either target, not either target.
Evt the target.
All right, and now what I'm going to do is I'm going to cancel, log this to do item to do item, let's
see, let's save it.
And for example, let's go ahead and.
Right to do.
And when I click on it, we can see that it says it's a paragraph, if I click on this, it is going
to give me an icon that has a status of complete and another icon that has a status of delete.
So now and if I click here, we see a well, if I click here, we can't lie.
So basically, we get three things.
We get ANELLI, we get a well and we get everything inside that elai.
Right.
OK, so enough with this council log, let's go ahead and let's actually implement code now what what
I want to do here is if if what I have clicked on has a status of complete, I want to run a certain
function.
And if what that I've clicked on has a status of delete, I want to run a different function.
That's what we are going to do inside this event.
Listener.
So I'm going to say to do I'm going to call it status if the to do status is to do item dot attributes.
So we are going to tap in into the attributes, attributes, dot status, dot value.
Right.
So now if I go ahead and if I say council log.
And let's go ahead and let's say to do status so this council log will only log to the console whenever
we click on to do item on any to do item that has a status and the status has a value.
And we have to to sort this to sort of icons like that.
So we have a status of complete and we have a status of delete.
So let's see that in action.
So now if I go ahead and if I create a to do one, if I click on this, we are going to get complete.
And if I click on this, we are going to get delete whenever we get a complete I want to run a certain
function and whenever we get a delete, I want to not I want to run another function.
Right.
So so far so cool.
So for now what I'm going to do is I'm going to say f to do status.
If the status is complete.
Do what?
Run the complete to do function.
Just run the complete to do function.
And as an argument we are going to person to do item.
All right, else F.
Also, remember, this is not an ounce, not like in any other scenario, we have only two scenarios,
one or the other.
So if the status is complete, we are going to run the complete to do function, which we are going
to create, of course.
And if the status is equal to to do status equals to keep in mind the strict equality.
If it is equal to delete, we are going to run another function and that is remove to do and we are
going to pass and that to do item that we want to remove.
So whatever is the to do item, which is the target, which is the one that we have collect, either
it is going to have a status of complete or it is going to have a status of delete.
If if that item that we have clicked on that to do item has a status of complete, we are going to run
this function.
If it has a status of delete, we are going to run this function.
So to do item.
Right.
And that's it.
That's it for now.
All right.
But this event listener is not going to work because we we we have to create the complete to do and
then remove to do.
Functions which you are going to complete, in which we are going to create in our next lecture.
See you guys then.