Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about higher order functions.
All right, so what are higher order functions now, higher order functions?
It is a very, very fancy term for functions which are accepted, accepting other functions as arguments
or functions, which are accepting other functions as a return values.
I mean, I know that didn't make it any simpler.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's dive into the code.
So first off, we are going to talk about functions which are accepting other functions as arguments
so we know what the function argument is.
Instead of passing a random thing there, we pass in another function.
So let's go ahead and let's create.
It's come down, so this is going to be our first scenario and let's go ahead and let's copy it and
put it here again, functions accepting other functions as arguments.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a function declaration and I'm going to call it repeat.
And I'm going to Posehn as a parameter X, because when you don't pass in a parameter, how would you
expect to pass in arguments?
Right.
And I'm going to call this X twice inside its own function.
All right.
And I'm going to create another function called NUM.
And I'm not going to pass in anything.
And I'm going to say consider log.
Two plus five.
Right, and now now none of these functions has been called we have a fun function of repeat, which
is going to repeat two times its parameter, and we have a function of norm which is going to calculate
two plus five.
Now, let's go ahead.
Let's call the repeat function.
All right.
We are going to call the repeat function, but instead of passing a value for this X, we are going
to pass on this NUM function.
So now when we're passing the NUM function, this function, this num function has been passed in as
an argument to the repeat function.
And when we say that we are going to see that this seven has been repeated twice because the repeat
function basically repeats any code two times.
And what is that code which has been repeated two times is two plus five because NUM is an argument
and when this NUM is called inside here, it says I'm going to consider the log 2.5.
And when it is passed in here, it is going to consider like two point five, which is seven.
And we are we are going to get this.
But in here the function repeats, says I'm going to repeat two times.
That's why we are going to get seven.
So this is called functions, accepting other functions as argument.
And the second part of higher order functions is functions accepting other functions as returned values.
Now, before moving forward, functions which are arguments to other functions are also called callback
functions.
Callback functions.
Right.
So this num I'm just going to add this the num.
Function is actually.
A callback function.
All right, so this is a very, very technical JavaScript term.
All right.
So the NUM function is and is actually a callback function.
So functions which are called inside another function called their callback function.
So this is a function call.
And inside the function code we call another function, that function, which is called inside another
function call is a callback function.
All right.
I hope it's not confusing because it's super simple.
Now, in this second example, we are going to create a factory function, factory function.
Right.
So now this factory function works because of the lexical scope.
Now, we had when we talked about the scope, I told you guys that we are going to talk about lexical
scope when we get to the advanced stuff.
And now is the time, actually, I wanted to talk about them in a separate chapter, but why not talk
about them here when a function is defined in another function, that function has access to its parents
variables, even if they are not defined within the child's function.
In this case, the anonymous function has access to the value of X from its parent, the sum function.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create that and let's take away all the gibberish out of this lesson.
Now we are going to create a function, we are going to call it some, and we are going to pass an X
as a as a parameter.
We are going to say return.
And now this return is going to return another function.
How cool is this?
Now, this function is going to be an anonymous function and this function is going to return X plus
Y.
Let's say that we don't see any errors.
So we are on the right track.
Right.
So what is this?
They these are higher order functions.
These are advanced JavaScript.
Right.
So this function of some, it is going to return a value.
What is that value?
That value is actually another function.
And what does that function do, that function is going to plus is going to return the sum of X plus
one and the cool thing is what now?
What is lexical scope in here?
We can see that why has been defined because why is it parameter of dysfunction?
Oops, why is a parameter of this anonymous function?
It has been defined, but what about X?
X has not been defined inside the scope of this function.
But it is still accessible by this anonymous function Y because X is has been defined inside the parent
of this function.
And when the parent has a value defined the child's function, which is the function that I've just
highlighted, has access to that variable.
And this is called lexical scope, when a function has access to variables of its parents function,
it is called lexical scope.
So simple.
All right.
And these are called functions, accepting other functions as a return values.
It works because this is a factory function.
And this works because of lexicalized coping, right?
So, so far, we have covered the global scope, the function scope, the blog scope and the lexical
scope.
All right, and everything should be clear to you.
I'm going to go over this one more time.
You can fast forward if you if you know everything here, you can just fast forward to 30 seconds.
We have a function of some this function of some has a parameter inside of it and the function of some
returns a value, the value of this, some function is actually another function and that function returns
X plus why the Y has been specified inside this anonymous function.
But what about X?
How can this function access X?
Because the X belongs to its parent.
And this, the parent, is another function, that's why it can access it, and this is called lexical
scope.
All right.
So now to see that in action.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to provide it with a series of numbers and we are going to see
the results here.
So I'm going to I'm going to call our first result.
I'm going to say let no one be equal to no.
Let's call the some function.
Now, this function is anonymous.
We cannot call it because it doesn't have a name.
How shall we call it?
I mean, shall I call it a function that you don't have a name?
Please come and calculate this.
No, it doesn't work like that.
We shall call a function that has a name and we are going to call the sum function.
And that is for for the second reason.
That is the parent.
All right, so we are going to call that, so when I pass in five for that and let's go ahead and let's
consider log num.
We have stored the results in one and we are going to see it returns.
Oops, it returns.
What does it return?
Take a look at it.
This is our anonymous function.
It says explores what and why is this happened and why in the world has this happened?
And the reason for that is we have passed in an argument of five for this X.
But what about why?
I mean, you cannot say five plus Y is five Y.
No, that doesn't work.
That is incorrect.
Whenever you pass in an argument for this anonymous function, then this entire thing is going to be
evaluated.
I mean, the sum function has been evaluated.
We have provided it with X and it has returned this function.
I mean, the sum function has done its job.
But what about this anonymous function we should pass in an argument for that as well.
So in order to pass in an argument for that, we open parentheses here and this is the cool part.
And Intellisense says No.
One and we pass in a value for Y C.
So this is actually the power of this code.
It tells you even if you're a beginner, it gives you all the tools that you need to become a very,
very, very fantastic developer.
It gives you everything.
So right away when I open parentheses, it is going to give me it is going to tell me that you are on
the right route.
You are going correctly, and now you should provide you should pass a no a number for this.
Why not number.
It could be anything.
It could be anything but because it's plus we know logically that we should provide a number and that
value is going to be a value to which parameter to the parameter of why.
And that's why we know whenever we open parentheses we have.
Accessed our anonymous function, our this function, right, and whenever I pass in for when I save
it, it says Oops, which is removed a parenthesis from here.
When I pass in four, we should get nine, which we do.
So this five is going to come all the way here and we are going to return this function and when we
pass in for five plus four, we are going to get nine.
Now, these are higher order functions.
I do not expect you to understand everything right away.
That's why I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to explain it one more time, but not in this lecture.
Actually, I wanted to cover everything as well as callback functions in this lecture.
But it's gone.
It's gone a lot.
It's gone like to 12 minutes.
And I want you guys to digest so far what we have studied.
So in the next year, we are going to pick up where we left off.
And I'm going to explain to you guys again how this factory function works because this is super important
in our projects.
All right.
I'm not going to I'm not going to say that we are going to use it all the time.
But when we do use it in our advanced projects, I want you guys to understand it right away, like
with the snap of Thanasis fingers.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.