Hi, everyone, in this election, we are going to create the clear input and the update UI functions.
All right.
So I'm going to come down here below this budget and let's come down here and in here.
I'm going to say clear input function.
All right.
So let's create that function.
Function and we are going to call it clear input now.
And the function call we have passed in an array now, even though there are two items within that array,
but this is still counts as one argument, right?
Because there are this argument.
Has not been separated by a comma, so instead of doing anything, I'm just going to pass an input as
a function parameter and in here we are going to grab our inputs and we are going to run a for each
loop on it.
When the foreach loop runs, we are going to run a function.
And each time that function runs, we are going to add a parameter of input.
Now we want this for each loop variable, which is the input.
We want that to run.
Now, officially, we have not started work talking about the for each with which is an array method
or helper methods also called or higher order functions.
We have not talked about this, but we are going to get to them.
We have talked about the array methods, but like the basic and intermediate level for each is like
more of a komaroff, an advanced kind of array method.
We are going to get to those like advanced array methods after we're done with like a like a few more
a few more projects.
And then we are going to get to like advanced JavaScript stuff.
But so far we are just diving from beginner to intermediate.
This is not advanced JavaScript.
You're going to see what advanced JavaScript is towards the middle to the end of this course.
So we are going to grab the input and we are going to grab the value from that input and we are going
to set it to an empty string chakra.
Right.
So let's say that let's come here.
So if I come here and if I say salary, salary, I'm not going to salary fifty.
And when I click, we can see that you have digitized, not defined.
It didn't work.
Why did it not work?
So if I come here, it says clear input.
We have clearly done that.
This is the clear input function.
We have grabbed our inputs, instances of data UI.
So I'm just going to go ahead and come in those ones out and I'm going to come here.
So let's project is easier to write 500.
So if when I click now we can see that because there was an error before the actual function, call
the JavaScript engine, it did not allow this to run because there was an error before it.
So now we can see that there is nothing here.
Both of them, they have been cleared and everything is printed here.
What I am going to do as well as I'm going to come here and I'm going to remove we are going to end
up with like a ton of console logs.
So it's better that we remove them after we're done with them.
So I'm going to come here on top of this clear input and I'm going to create the update UI function.
We are done with the clear input for now
function update UI and we are not going to pass and we are not going to pass in any parameter because
we are not pastan in the argument for this function.
So what do I want to do with this update?
UI Now this is, as I told you, the biggest function.
I want this update UI to change the balance, to change the outcome, to change the outcome, to change
the income tracker expense structure and all.
So we are going to go step by step on what we want to do for off.
I want to creative.
I want to initialize or redefine this redeclared, not defined functions are defined, redeclared this
variable because if I remember correctly, there we have one.
It is right here.
So this is income.
So initially the income is zero, which is this one.
And that's why we can see that it's a zero, zero and zero.
So first off, I want to grab these three variables and I want to provide them with values.
Right.
Mm hmm, let's come here, so I'm going to grab whereas so first stuff, I'm going to grab the balance.
So I'm just going to say balance.
We have initialized this variable and we have said the initial value to zero.
Now we want to redeclared.
We want to change the value.
OK, so we are going to say balance.
And when whenever we want to store any variable inside this balance, that that variable is that.
Value is going to be actually a function and that function is going to be calculate balance.
So we are going to have three functions.
The first function sorry, two functions in here.
So the first function is going to be calculate balance.
The second function is to we calculate total and calculate the total is going to be called twice, once
for the income and the other time for the outcome.
So this is the calculate balance function.
What do we want this to do?
We want to pass in as arguments, income and outcome, because balance is income minus outcomes.
So whenever we define this function, we are going to say balance income minus outcome so we can go
ahead and we can create this function right now.
So I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say calculate balance function.
You know, we could do this as well.
This way.
This way is not like confusing.
I could just create all the variables here and then define the functions, but I could define the functions
at the same time as well.
So we are going to call it calculate balance.
Now, we have two two different arguments.
They're separated by a comma.
So I'm going to grab both of the arguments and I'm going to pass them as parameters.
And I want this function to do only one thing.
I want this function to return income minus outcome.
This is going to be our balance and this is the balance.
So whatever the income, whatever is the outcome, just subtract them.
Right.
So this is our very first function that we created here, our very first variable that we have redeclared
here.
The second one is going to be income.
And on the income, what I want to do is I want to say, calculate total, calculate total, calculate
total.
And we are going to pass in our income.
All right.
And also the entry list.
And we are going to do the same thing for the expense.
So let's grab both of them and we are going to pass those in as well.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create the calculate total function as well.
I'm going to come beneath.
I'm going to come.
We could come beneath it or on top of it.
I could go on top of it and I could say I calculate total function, so function calculate total.
So we have two different kinds of two different arguments and we should pass two different arguments.
Now, there is a cool thing here.
The cool thing is the first argument is it seems like the type of the budget that we either want to
pass or we want to subtract.
So this is a type of income and this is a type of expense.
So the first parameter I'm just going to pass and type, the second parameter is going to be our enter
entry list or simply can't list.
What do we want this function to do, we want to first go ahead and create a variable called sum and
I want to make it zero, then I want to grab my list and I want to call for research on it.
Right.
And whenever the foreach loop runs, each time, I want to grab the entry, OK, and I want to check
something.
Now, if the entry type equals to the type that is written here, I want to increase that sum by the
amount that the user has entered.
So F.
Entry type equals type.
So what is this type, this entry type is going to give us either expense or income and this type is
either this income or this expense.
So if this type equals to either income or expense, what do I want to do?
I want to grab our some variable and I want to add on to it.
That's why I tacked in like a plus sign there.
I want to add on to the amount.
All right, to the entertainment, so we have an entry, that type, and we have an entry that amount,
right.
And right after that, I want to say return some.
That's it.
So I just want to sum them up.
What does it mean?
It means that whatever user passes in.
So if I were to write, for example, project.
And I would say 5000 now, this 5000 is going to be some, but like it's going to be combined with this
1000 and we are going to get 6000.
We are going to get 6000, right, so we have successfully done this.
Now let's go ahead and let's check out if the update UI is going to work.
All right.
So we are here.
Let's go ahead and let's say project.
It is not going to print it here because we have not done that.
We just want to print it here for now.
Let's see.
So if I say 100, it didn't do it because actually what we have done is we should tell the UI function,
where do we want to print it?
We just we have just provided the income, the expense with a certain value.
So if I were to say cancel the log and if I provide an array here and I could say balance income and
expense, well, this is not expense.
This is outcome because we are working in the header.
Now, this is balance income and this is outcome.
So let's go ahead and let's cancel this and let's see what we are going to get.
So I'm just going to say project and I'm going to say one 1000.
Let's save it.
We can see that expense is not defined at UI this and ADHD amount.
So if I add one hundred and six at this.
No, this is I should be sorry.
This should be the outcome.
Save it.
Let's do it one more time.
Let's go.
Oh this is rent.
Let's say project one hundred.
Click on it and we can see this so we can see that we have 100 here because we have passed all three
of them here.
Now keep in mind we can only see 100 in the middle.
What is this one hundred?
It comes from the income because the income is the second item inside.
So if I were to pass on something for the outcome, we should see this get updated as well.
So now we can see that we have 200 for the outcome, 100 for the income, 200 minus 100.
We get 100.
All right, 100 minus 200.
We get negative 100.
But we can see that because we should, like, specify the sign for that as well.
But for now, we can only see that we can see our balance for in short.
So I can go ahead and I can say, hmm, how can I how can I make this work?
You know what?
That's that's going to be it for this video.
I just wanted to do something crazy with this console, but you can see what I mean.
So if I were to go ahead and reload the page, I'm going to do it one more time and I'm going to say
project.
So don't mind the misspell.
I'm going to say project is going to be four fifty and I'm going to add it and I'm going to say rent
is going to be one fifty and I'm going to add it.
And now we can see that for fifty, OK, is going to be our income.
One fifty is going to be our outcome.
But the balance is still says 450.
Right.
And I don't know what is wrong in here.
So we have our income.
We have our outcome, income outcome.
It should work fine.
I mean, it should it should subtract them so it returns.
Where is this function?
So it says income.
We have income minus outcome.
All right.
And we have our income, so what what do I go ahead and provided down here and let's try this one more
time and let's say Project 100, you know what, 150 added.
OK, it says 150, let's say Rand, let's just say 50, just click on it, and now it is calculated
correctly, this is income, this is outcome 150, minus 50.
We are going to get 100 that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.