Hi, everyone, welcome to Matching Part seven.
All right, so an example, example, number 25, we're going to check for all or none.
Right, so this is the case of, for example, we have for example, you know what, I'm just going
to go ahead and create it so we have a sentence and I'm going to call it a sentence two.
And you know how there are like different words for different things, like in American English and
in British English, for example, in American, it is just s.L, COLB or I think this is American.
And in British we have like not we.
Yeah, of course we I'm speaking English.
So in British we have you.
So you want to match.
If the word has that extra you or it doesn't have that extra you.
So we are, we want to check for that or it doesn't matter if it, if it is there or if it is not there.
OK, I don't think this name conveys that, but I'm just going to leave it there.
You can go ahead and come up with a better name for this example.
So in case we have that COLB, you are what it is that we are going to do.
So we are going to create a regular expression, number 25.
And what it is, the pattern that we are going to insert that is going to ignore that extra you so that
it is not going to ignore it.
It is just going to say that that you is optional.
So if we find that you are inside that word, then the pattern is true.
If even if we don't find it, that then the pattern is going to be true as well.
So with a pattern found might or might not contain the letter you.
So in any case, even if it contains it, even if it doesn't contain it, we are we want to return to
you because color and color, both of them are the same.
So I'm just going to write the word here.
But when I put in the you am just going to provide it with with an optional question mark.
All right, and now let's create a result.
So this is resolved.
Now, this is a search we used to do search 25 result.
Right.
And what do we want to do?
So now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to test it because I want to see whether or not this is
actually true or false.
So I'm going to grab on a regular expression.
And upon which, upon this, I want to test it right and.
Test, I want to test that sentence.
So let's go ahead and write sentence number two and I think we should open up a live server.
So let's come here and let's check it out, says life server.
OK, let's log it to the console.
What it is, it's a search 25 result we get through, why do we get through?
Because this contains the letter you if I come in that one out and if I remove it, we still get through,
because this is the optional question mark right here.
This is the lazy.
It is just looking for that.
Whether or not we find it, we are going to get through.
But what if I go ahead and I comment that one out not there.
I'm just going to remove that question mark.
Now we get a false.
But if I come in this one in, we get through because there isn't we are just looking for this.
And if I this could be another one.
So let's come in this one and we get false for this one.
And of course, we are going to get true for this one.
So instead of doing two patterns, we can just do one and we can say that that you is actually optional.
So this is you could call it like the optional.
This is up to you.
Did you just come up with a better name for this example?
And that's it for this example.
So the next example is actually going to be our final example of this chapter sorry, this lecture.
And it is called Lookahead.
So we have two kinds of lookahead.
We have a positive lookahead and we have a negative lookahead.
Right.
And this is example number twenty six now lookahead are patterns that tell JavaScript to look ahead
and your string to check for patterns further along.
It is useful for searching for multiple patterns in the same string.
So how do how do these lookahead they work.
So first off, we are just going to go over the positive lookahead the positive lookahead is when we
are looking forward.
The negative lookahead is when we are looking backward, even though it says lookahead.
But we do have negative lookahead as well.
So if I were to create a regular expression, so I'm just going to call it a 26 X, and now let's put
in the pattern that we want to look now I'm going to look for J.
I'm going to this is how I'm going to explain this look ahead, because this is really important in
regular expressions.
That's why I'm stressing a lot on it.
And that's why there are no more examples in this lecture.
So this regular expression is going to match for the letter J.
F if this is a condition, think of it as a conditional, if that's why inside the parentheses, if
and if that J has in front of it a letter U.
If the J has in front of it a letter you then that J is the J that we are looking for and we want to
print it to the console.
All right, again, if after Jay, we have you, we want to grab that, Jay, so we are looking for
jobs which have a you in front of them.
Right.
So, you know what?
Excuse me.
I'm just going to say jumps Jarek's So we do have a Jay here as well, but it has in front of it and.
Oh, so that should not match for this one.
All right.
And you know what?
Let's copy this to spot right here.
We are going to test it.
We are not going to print it.
We're going to test it because true and false is better.
You know how you can print it through the match.
So that's completely up to you.
You know how you can do that.
And let's grab all the 20 fives and let's turn them to 26.
So this is going to be sentence the first sentence.
Now we are going to test it against this.
And when I say it, we get true.
Why do we get through?
Because we have at least one Jay that has in front of it a letter you now keep in mind, whenever you
do match, it is not going to return.
The you the you is basically a condition.
If that condition is met, we are going to print whatever comes before the condition.
So before the condition, we are going to suggest we are going to print it now, whenever.
Now in both of the lookahead, whether it is positive or negative, you're going to get this question
mark and the parentheses.
But when it has the negative lookahead, we know what the knot operator is in JavaScript.
That is the like the exclamation mark.
OK, so if you have exclamation mark in here, it is the negative lookahead.
So let's go over that as well.
Maybe like go over this like go over a few scenarios for this.
So now let's go ahead and let's put in oh we should get through.
But if I put in like, like m we should get false because we don't have any J in front of which we have
M we have js in front of which we have you or Oh we don't have M.
That's a second letter.
We don't care about that.
We care like directly after J we should have O and you.
If we have only you we get true.
If we have anything else we are going to get false.
All right, so now let's go ahead and let's talk about the negative look ahead, so let's change it
to negative lookahead and the negative loggerhead.
I'm just going to talk I'm just going to grab this example one more time.
You know what?
Only these three, and I'm going to paste him right here.
That's common to all of them, and so we have an equality sign, it means that this is a positive look
ahead.
If we have an exclamation, it means in negative look ahead.
All right.
So in the negative, look ahead.
We say that if this j if this J and I have to apologize, because at the start of this lecture, I said
that when it is positive, we are looking forward.
When it is negative, we are looking backward.
And I even joked about, even though it is a look ahead and I have to apologize for that because that
was actually not accurate, even though even if it is positive or negative, we are basically looking
ahead.
OK, it's not like we are looking backward.
We are just testing for a condition when that condition is true.
And in this case, we are testing in the case of positive lookahead, we are testing for a like a positive.
I'm just going to get positive for a positive condition to be true and for a negative look ahead.
Again, I do apologize for that misinformation and I want to correct it.
I could like we do this video, but I'm not going to do because.
Teachers, they do mistakes, they commit crimes as well.
So we are testing for a negative condition to be true, even though this is negative.
We want that negative condition to be true in order for this entire thing to return.
OK, so I hope I hope you're not getting confused.
So the results of this should be true.
If I say that we get true because we do not have any genes that have in front of them and em when we
do not have them, it means that it is a negative condition.
And when that negative condition returns, true, we are going to get through in here.
But what if what if I put a few here now before running this?
If we come here, we can see that we have a gene that has in front of it a you.
So this condition is not this negative condition is not true.
This negative condition, the condition is negative, but the status of this condition is false.
That's why it is going to return false.
Well, it did return.
True.
So we are going to get any that doesn't have that doesn't have you.
So it is going to give us true because there is true.
So let's go ahead and let's match it.
So if I were to match it, I'm just going to come and this one out and I'm going to create another variable.
You know what?
This part is going to be the same.
Let's put it here.
Let's see what it is going to give us in the console.
So let's grab our sentence and we are going to say match what it is, what it is that we're going to
match it against regular expression 26.
So we do get that even though this condition says that we want to get if after gee, there isn't any
you print.
Oh, I know why it did that, because we do have this jogs in here as well.
So for the for clarification purposes, I'm just going to remove that.
And now we get no.
And now this is working as I expected it.
We get false because we don't have any JS that there isn't a you in front of them.
We only have one Jadot in front of that.
There is a you.
So we are going to go over this one more time.
So this negative condition, it has to have a status of true for this entire regular expression to return.
True.
But it says that a J that doesn't have you in front of it.
It did say true because we had dogs and dogs had a J in front of which we had an O, and in that case
this condition was true.
Even though the condition is negative, the status is true.
But now that that I have removed that it says find a G that in front of it, it doesn't have a Q So
let's go ahead, find it.
There is nothing in here.
So this entire condition is the status of this entire condition is going to be false.
That's why this is going to return false.
And let's say that we see false.
Let's comment this one out.
That's common, this one.
And we get through.
Why?
Because we are looking for a J that in front of it.
There is not an M, so let's go ahead and check.
Yep, there it is.
And so this negative condition is going to have a status.
If true, that's why this entire thing is going to return trip that set for the negative, positive
and negative look ahead.
I hope you have understood that.
And again, apologize for the third time for that misinformation that I gave you.
It was my bad, my mistake.
And both of the look ahead, they look ahead.
But one of them is going to have a positive condition.
The other one is going to have a negative condition to be true.
Right.
So see you guys in the next lecture.