Hi, everyone, in this last year, we are going to check for a win.
All right, so we have successfully drawn the whenever the computer wins, whenever the user wins or
the R.I wins, but they were only like putting one piece when they put four pieces in a row, then they
should win.
Right.
But first things first.
Before doing that, we need to check for a tied game.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go inside the select cell.
Where is our cell.
The select sell function, where is that?
There it is.
So in here, what I'm going to do is right after we return from the when it is not highlighting, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to check for a tied game.
Now, if it is not game over, so if game over is not true, it means that we are checking for a tight
game.
So first off, what I'm going to do as I'm going to grab the game tight.
So inside the game tight, of course, we need to set it to true right.
And let's loop over that.
So we are going to save for that row of grit and then for let.
Let sell of Arrow.
We are looping over all of the cells, if the cells owner, if any cell doesn't have any owner, so
let's set it to No.
If it means that they're OK, this is not correct.
So if the cell owner is no, it means that there is a specific cell and that cell is not felt.
That cell has not been occupied by either the FBI or the R.I.
And then we are going to say that the game tied is is false because the game only is tied when all of
the board is filled, all these circles are filled and there is no winner, then the game is tied.
So in here I'm just going to say game tied is false and that's what I'm going to do as.
And here is also go ahead and I'm going to check whenever a game is is tight, so I'm going to say if
game tight is true.
We are going to grab the game over and we are going to set it to true.
All right, so when the game is not over, it means there it's not time.
And when the game is over, it means that the game is not is actually tight.
Right.
So we just said the game over and we'll run another game.
So let me just take a look at this.
So we have said for let's row off grid, let's sell Aphro.
If the sales owner is empty, then it means that it is not tight.
And then we got out of that loop and we have said that if the game tied is true, only when the game
is is over.
Right.
So to test this, I'm going to come because we have a lot of rows and columns.
I'm just going to reduce the columns to three and I'm going to reduce the rows to to let's say that
it's come here.
So draw.
You can see that it says we should not get this.
So there is something wrong in here.
All right.
OK, so we get we do get the text, you can see the text, but you can see that it is looping over that.
And I think the problem is that we are not breaking out of that loop.
So where is our whereas the logic that we just wrote.
Hmm, where is it?
Where was it?
It was inside the select cell.
So let me select.
There we go.
This is where it is.
We need to get out of this sloops, and whenever each of the iterations is answers, that's the game.
Whenever the game is not tied, we just want to get out of that iteration.
So I'm just going to reference the order in here as well.
So now we should get the game tight.
So hopes we still do not get it.
So break outer and outer.
And we have referenced the outer there as well.
OK, what what seems to be the problem, we should fill all this and then it should say game.
OK, save it once more, come here.
We should not get this text.
So we say that game tired is true, we break out of that, we say that if the cell is if the cell is
not, I'm just going to provide in one other equal sign and I'm going to say, there we go.
And now it works.
So if I click on this one, we should get this.
We should see the drawer and the drawer works only when all of the cells are filled and there is no
winner there.
So I'm going to go back to TARP and I'm going to reset the size to seven columns and six rows.
I think that was it.
Right.
Sims writes seven columns, six rows, perfect, so the next thing that I would like to do is I want
to create.
Let's see what it is that we want to create here.
I want to create the connect for function, I want to say that whenever four dots are connected in one
line or like in one row or V that row, like diagonally, vertically or horizontally, one four are
connected in a row, then we want to we want to specify a winner.
Right.
So let's see.
Hmm.
Right below our check when where is our check when the this is the dimensions, this is the check went
right here.
I'm going to create the connect now.
This is the main function that we have here.
That's why the name of the function is actually the name of the game that we are playing.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's create this function.
I'm going to say function connect for I'm going to pass as a parameter, an empty array.
Right, and first off, we are going to initial we are going to declare a variable count and we are
going to set it to zero and we are also going to declare a variable last owner.
Last owner of that cell, and we are going to initialize it to No.
Perfect.
Let's let's grab our winning cells.
Uh, what is wrong here?
Expect, uh huh, last owner equals.
No, I mean, this is correct, it should work.
Let.
Count.
That count equals zero and let last owner.
C o u a..
And last owners should be equal to, oh, there they are.
I know what the problem is.
We missed something up here.
So there is there was the parentheses missing.
Let's put it here.
OK, so mistype out there, let's grab our account and set it to zero.
And then we are going to grab the last owner and set it to No.
At first, these are what we want to do, right, and then let's grab the winning cells so we know that
we have some winning cells and I'm going to create an array for them.
And now what we are going to do is we are going to say for let's let's move over that.
So let equals zero zero zero.
Why am I doing that for zero and let the I should go all the way to cells that, um, length that length.
All right.
And we are going to increment the AI by one each time, so.
If there is no owner, right, it means that if the if there is no winner in here, what we are going
to do is we are going to reset the game.
All right.
So let's check for that as well.
So we are going to say sells the I or any item inside the cell if it doesn't have any owner.
So we are going to set it to know if it doesn't have.
Why can't it?
Right.
Zero.
OK, if it doesn't have any owner.
What do we want?
Do we want to reset the count to zero.
And the winning sells sell, there is an estimate missing it should be initialized to as an empty array.
But what if we do have an owner?
We do have like an owner.
All right.
And that owner has to be repeated again and again and again for us to win.
So four cells in a row, like one, two, three, four, four cells in a row, they should be dedicated
to one owner.
So the owner is the same owner, so same owner.
To the count, to the count.
So we are going to say alse.
Actually, this is Al-Saqqaf.
Our safety sells item does owner.
Is actually equal to the last owner.
This is why we created the last owner.
So, for example, this is our first on a cell.
This is the owner and then this is the second cell.
So this owner, this is the owner now.
And this is the lastone and the last owner and the current owner, they are equal to each other when
they're equal to each other.
What it is that we want to do, we want to grow our account and incremented by one.
And we are going to grab the winning cell's array and we are going to push to it the the item from the
cells array.
That item.
Now, let's go ahead and let's create another al statement here.
So if the owner is a new owner, so new owner, we are going to we are going to have a new count there.
So let's say else count, should we still have to increase their increment, the count by one and the
winning sales?
Of course, they're going to be empty because we have a new owner there and we are going to push that
to the winning sales in case that that player wins.
So winning sales start to push.
That's that item we are we are just pushing it to that item.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's find out the last owner.
So we are still inside this loop, right?
So this is all happening inside the loop.
So said the last owner.
So the last owner is equal to the sells item.
This is the sells item, the dog owner, so we just said that and now let's check if there are four
ducks in a row, then that is the owner sorry, that is the winner.
So we are going to safe count is equal to four.
And you can see that we are incrementing the count here.
If the owner equals the last owner, we increment the count.
And if the count goes, the counting fermentation goes all the way to four.
What do we want to do?
We want to say, let's sell off wedding sells.
And are going to say Soldat Wener equals to true cell, wener equals to true, perfect.
So what if what if we don't have four in the row, we just want to return.
True from it, when we have four in the row, we basically return true from this statement.
And in case we don't have any.
Any four in a row, we just want to return false from this entire function, so this function is created.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to inside our cell constructor.
Right, and I'm going to add the winner there.
We need to specify the winner there as well.
So let's come down here and I'm going to say this.
The start winner is equal to false.
So initially, we are not going to have any winner, right.
And if they play and there is a winner, then we are going to have a winner there.
Now, I need this winner added to this condition as well for the highlighting.
So I'm just going to add this.
Let's just provide a space.
This Dudd winner or this not highlight is not then we want the color and the color is no longer going
to be this.
We are going to change.
We are going to check for the winner as well.
So if this winner is true, we want to show the the color of the winner.
So the color eye and we want to show that.
Otherwise, we want to check if this that highlight is true.
If this is not highly it is true.
We are going to show the color for the R.I, otherwise we are going to show the color for the EHI.
Perfect.
Now, let's see now in order to actually check for any winner, we have to go to our check win function,
which is right here.
And I'm going to comment this one out instead of now.
Here is the here is where we want to provide the logic to check for any win.
So there are going to be four different conditions in case someone wins.
There is the horizontal.
There is the vertical.
There is the diagonal.
Right.
There is the diagonal left.
So we need to check for four conditions.
Now, first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to get I'm going to say getting all the cells.
From each direction, from each of the directions, so it doesn't matter.
Each direction just can provide a space.
They're going to you know what?
I'm just going to go ahead and remove that.
That's not necessary here anymore.
And let's say so.
The first one is going to I'm just going to ride diagonal left diagonal left his bottom right to top
left.
And I'm going to set it to an empty array, right, and then let's grab the diagonal.
Right, the diagonal right is going to be bottom left to top right.
We are going to have our horizontal.
Which we know what that is and we're vertical.
So there are only four directions that a win can occur, right and right after that, let's go ahead
and let's check for different scenarios and let's push to these to these arrays.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a for loop.
So for all of the eye is going to for let I saw that I equals zero, so the I's going to start from
zero and the AI is going to go all the way to less than the great arrows.
We're going to iterate over the rows and also the columns.
So this is going to be the rows.
And I'm going to say for let J equals zero.
They should go all the way to great columns, less than that, and we are going to increment Jay by
one.
So first off, let's check let's push to the horizontal horizontal array, horizontal cels.
Horizontal cells and we are going to say f the eye equals Roe then means that it is horizontal.
So we are going to grab the horizontal array and we are going to push to it.
The what do we what we are going to push we are going to push the our grid because all of the cells
are actually inside that grid.
And it is we are going to push the rose and the columns.
The next situation is vertical cells.
For the vertical says, we should say that whenever because we are talking about the vertical, it's
columns.
So we are going to grab the J because J is actually what's iterating over those columns.
So if J.
Equals call, we are going to say vertical, vertical dot push.
Let's push to that array, the same grid that we have.
So just to not repeat, just to save some time, I'm just going to grab it and put it there.
And the next thing is I'm going to go ahead to diagonal left.
So diagonal left, right and OK, so the diagonal left, if I is less than the J if the number of columns
start a number of rows is less than the number of columns when if that equals to the number of rows,
less than the number of columns, if both of them are equal to each other, it means that we are moving
in a diagonal left position.
And we want to push Bush to that array, what do we want to push?
We want to push that to that right.
And finally, we have our diagonal right.
There is a misspelling there, it doesn't really matter, but still diagonal.
Diagonal.
Is it correct?
I think yeah, it is correct.
So if the rose plus the the eye, the eye, which is the red rose iterator, plus the column columns
iterator, that equals the row plus column.
If they're the same, it means that we are moving any diagonal.
Right.
And we are going to push to the to that our grid, which has a number of columns and number of rows,
and finally what I'm going to do is I'm going to get out of that for a loop.
Yes.
The for loop.
And there so I'm going to get out of it and I'm going to say if any half, four in a row.
Return a win.
So we want to return, right, so we are going to return let's call the Connacht for a function and
we are going to pass and let's pass in diagonal left or.
Connect for.
Connect four, and it's passing the diagonal, right?
Or connect for so any of the if any of these conditions is true, we are going to return it when?
Horizontal and connect for.
Verticle.
Let's save it and hopefully we should be able to see something here.
OK, so if completed this as well, so if I come here now, if I put that there, oh, we have not automated
this, I'm just going to play the part as well.
So first off, let's check.
You can see it says human one, and we can still see our selection.
We are going to take care of that.
Don't worry.
But the important part is it checks for a vertical.
Let's see if it checks for a horizontal.
I'm just going to put it there.
Put it there.
And there we go.
Computer one horizontal.
Now let's check for a vertical sorry, diagonal.
So.
There we go.
And it's this human one.
This was diagonal, right?
I'm going to check one for the diagonal left as well.
What they are us that they are.
There we go, it's a human one, diagonal left, so our logic is perfectly fine, we have now the only
thing remaining for us is actually create that A.I., right.
And we need to call the AI inside our brain is our game loop.
This this is the game loop.
We need to call that here as well.
Right.
So what we're going to do is actually we're going to do all of that in our next lecture and see you
guys then.