Hi, everyone, in this natural working to create the clear superhero input's function.
All right, so before diving into that, I need to clean this code up a little and we created this in
the previous lecture and time ran out.
And now what we what we have to do is we have created this list container, but we need to find a parent
for it.
That's why we selected less data.
So I'm going to say less data dot append child.
What is the child that's going to be the list container, let's say.
Let's actually check that these actually works for Superman D.C. Fly.
Now, you can see that this has been created and now this superhero list class, if you go inside the
prototype, it has an ad superhero entry and now you can see that underneath the hood.
It's actually those prototypes are just the syntactic sugar sprayed on top of the prototypes.
Think of it like that.
Right.
But there was a problem here.
Whenever we are in the Superman, they're still here, but we need to clear that.
Right.
So that is the function that we are going to create now.
So I'm going to go ahead.
I'm going to I'm going to keep that there.
Now we are going to see less that the next method is going to be clear superhero in pets.
And I don't think there is not going to be any parameter here.
So let's go on top and let's create this function.
So that's common.
This one as well at Super Hero.
And in here we are going to say real clear superhero in feels just clear them.
Now, what is the function name.
The function name is this and what is this going to do?
This function is going to do very, very a very, very simple thing.
And we are going to use, again, the structuring for that.
How cool is that?
Very new features, so we are going to say document dot, query selector.
And we are going to grab the name.
That value, so what it is that I'm trying to do here, so we are going to grab this element once more,
grab it in here once more, grab it in here once more, and we are going to say that value and we are
going to set it to an empty to an empty string.
All right.
So that's basically what I am trying to do here.
Put it there.
And this is Univers.
And we are going to put it here as well, and this time this is going to be power and for all three
of them, we are just going to put empty strings when they when we call this function, oops.
When we call this function, we just want to clear that.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's check it out.
So Superman D.C. fly.
When I say that, you can see that they have been added there, but they have they have also been removed
from here.
So if I come here inside the Proteau, you can see that it's just class when we created it, but actually
it's an object.
So what is the Proteau saying?
It's an object.
That's why it's called object oriented.
Now you can see that the second method that we have added is, is this ad of the second one is clear
superhero inputs.
Right.
So we were successfully, successfully able to do that.
And with this our election comes a lecture comes to an end.
And I really hope that you'll like this kind of approach.
I may never like I may not repeat it for the for the next lecturer's sorry for the next projects, because
those projects are going to be there are crucial.
All of the projects are crucial.
But because this is a different paradigm that we are doing, I just want to make sure that you master
object oriented programming in the first.
Project that you do it and I'm just going to come here and I'm going to say form submission, event
listner.
All right, so that's it for this year.
See you guys in the next one.