Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about the ESX class word.
All right, so I've just opened up this page, I should probably copy that and pasted right here.
And let's face it here now, this is an example of how classes look like in JavaScript, but before
going over there.
Let's go over the documentation now.
It says classes are a template for creating objects.
This is where the object oriented design comes into play.
Classes are a template, a template.
They're not objects.
They are a template for creating objects.
They encapsulate data with code to work.
On that day to classes and jails are built on prototypes, which we are going to cover later, but have
some syntax and semantics that are not shared with the S5 class, like semantics.
Now, defining classes, classes are, in fact special functions.
OK, and just as you define function expressions and function declarations, the class syntax has two
components class expressions and class declarations.
But in this course, we are just going to go over the class declarations, not the class expressions.
Right.
Which are more intuitive.
So what do we have here?
We have the class keyword and then whatever name you provide that class, it's the first letter should
be capital.
This is the convention for naming that.
And then we open curly braces.
This part, which is the constructor function.
This is completely like optional.
You you can't provide it or not.
And this is the function that we have created.
Right.
And in here, we call this workshop function or workshop object with the new keyword.
Right now, this is what it looks like.
This is what actually this is a very, very small example of object oriented programming.
They are used to create objects there, a template.
But if we go ahead and check the type of the workshop, it is going to return a function.
All right.
So these classes, they can be defined with or without an extensive class, which you are going to look
at later in this lecture.
OK, here we're just defining class that doesn't extend anything.
So it is called the top level class.
You can choose to, as I said, define a constructor or not.
All right.
So now let's go over how how this is going to run and now more importantly, let's go over what the
discord is going to refer to.
So in here we have a new keyword.
And we know whenever we call a function with the new keyword, there are four things that are going
to happen.
First, the new keyword is going to create a brand new object.
The second thing, that brand new object is going to be linked to another object, which in this case
is this workshop.
This it is going to be linked to this workshop and then.
And the third thing is that what was third thing, it invokes the function, it calls it with the disk
you were pointing at the new object, we know then the new object is created, the new object is linked,
and that this keyword is going to point to this new object that that this that this new has created.
And fourth and finally, F.
And fourth, and finally, the new keyword after the function call is done, now, the function call
is done.
If the function does not return its own object, the new keyword is going to return that this keyword.
So what is this going to refer to?
The this is going to refer to this, John, because we have said that this star teacher equals a teacher.
And where is this teacher coming from?
The teacher is coming from right here where the function is called the callsign.
So this is the argument, the argument which is going to be passed inside here.
And this teacher is going to be John.
So if I were to first off, let's go ahead and let's look to the council using our type of operator,
the workshop with Capital W, and if I say it, we are going to see it says function.
And now we have just stored the results of this inside this markup.
So I'm just going to call I'm just going to log to the console that mark-up.
So Consul Locke and I'm just going to say Mark-Up.
And when I say it, we can see that we have a brand new object inside that brand new object, we have
a method.
We have a property called teacher.
And the value for that is John.
This is actually the object that this new keyword has created and has linked it to this workshop object.
All right.
So this is how classes are created.
And this is the relationship between this constructor and this workshop itself.
That's why it's optional.
You can create this constructor, but you should know that it is directly in contact with this workshop
because this argument is going to be passed inside this parameter.
Right.
So this is.
But what about this ask?
But what about this aske function?
What happens then?
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to create another variable.
I'm going to come down here and I'm going to say, let Jess be cool to.
So now we are creating another instance of the new keyword and we are going to call the workshop.
Function, OK?
And I'm just going to say, Jane, right, and now when this workshop function is is called, what is
the this keyword is going to point out, we need to go to the call side.
This is the call side.
The call side.
Says that how the function is called, how the function is called is controlled by the new Kiwa.
So all of those steps are created and we end up with another teacher for which the value is going to
be Jane.
So Jane is going to be passed here.
So this teacher is going to be equal to Jane.
And if I were to cancel log, that's you know what?
If I were to bring it down and let's change it to James, and if I said it, we are going to see that
workshop, Jane, so we can create as many instances of this workshop as we want.
OK, so this is the good thing about using classes.
But keep in mind, this is this syntactic sugar on top of the prototypes that the JavaScript is really
built on, OK, that the JavaScript is going to do.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to use were Mark-Up and Geass to do something else as well.
So I'm going to use I'm going to call the Aske function as well.
So now let's we have two instances of this workshop.
One is John, the other one is Jane.
So how can we go ahead and call this aske function?
So why don't we have to do is I'm just going to say markup dot ask.
And inside here, I'm going to pass and let's say teachers HTML, I'm just going to pass in three,
I'm just going to put in three question marks.
So it is going to say John teaches up.
So this we are going to go over this entire scenario one more time.
So this ask question this sorry, this ask function, it has it this key word.
What is this, what is going to point out.
We cannot tell that by looking at the function we need to go to the calcite.
Here is the side.
The ASC is called as a method on this mark-up.
What is the markup.
Markup is a an object and this object has a teacher of property on it.
And what is the teacher's value?
It is, John.
All right.
So this the teacher is going to be actually workshop the teacher, which is going to grab the value,
John.
And we are going to see John here and inside the question.
We are going to see teachers estimate.
And when I say that, it says John teaches HTML.
We can do the same thing for Jane as well, so I'm just going to say, James.
Teachers, yes, so again.
This aske function is a this hour function.
So what is this thing to point out?
We need to go to the call side.
Here is the inside.
The Aske function has been called as a method on this Jase's.
This J.S. is actually a an object.
So this is the context object or the implicit binding that we talked about.
All right.
And it has inside of it a teacher as a property.
Right.
So this the teacher is actually going to be workshop the teacher and the value for this is going to
be Jane.
So it's going to say, Jane in here and the question is going to be teachers, J.S. And when I say that,
it says Jane teaches us.
All right.
So with this, you know what?
I wanted to cover the extents class in this lecture, the extents and this super clause and this lecture
as well.
What the classes with the class syntax.
But it's been ten minutes and there is a lot to take in.
So go ahead.
Watch this video and just take a break and come with me to the next lecture where we will talk about
the extents and the super clause for class constructors.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.