Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to resolve the DoubleClick issue of this game.
All right, so what is the DoubleClick issue?
So if I come into the final product, if I can if I go ahead and if I double click on this card and
this card, we can see that it works perfectly fine.
So let me just do it once more.
I'm sure you are going to hear the double click.
So.
But even though if I even though I'm double clicking on one card and clicking another, I'm still not
able to click on the third card, see, so double click, click.
And then I cannot I cannot select the third card.
But what about here?
So if I double click on this card and if I click on this and this, we can see that we can flip a third
card and this stays in its own place.
So double click on this double click on this double click on this double click on this.
Now you can see all all these cards, they stay in their own place, so.
See, so this is the issue that I'm talking about and this is what we are going to fix in here.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to go here and I'm going to come right here on top
and we are going to implement another
flow control if statement in here.
So basically what we want is we want to look for the this keywords value and we are going to evaluate
it against the first car.
So we are going to say this.
So if this keywords value and we remember that this keywords value is the value of any card, who that
has been clicked.
So it is going to tell us exactly what card has been click.
So we are going to say if if it is equal to the first card, we are going to return the function.
So if we are clicking twice on one card, then this function is going to return.
It is not going to run.
Now, let's go over this one more time.
If if we are clicking, if the card that we have clicked on is the first card, it means it's our first
click.
Then this it with this condition evaluates to true and this function is going to wrap up and go and
it is going to wrap up everything.
And this logic is not going to implement it if this is true.
Now let's say we click on the second card or we click on the same card for the second time, then the
value of this keyword is not going to be the first card.
It is going to be the second card.
All right.
And this is not going to be evaluated to true.
And this is going to be evaluated to false.
Then the return keyword is not going to do anything because the condition is not true.
And then this code is going to run.
OK, to properly implement this, we need to add a function.
And I'm going to come down here.
And we are going to create a function and I'm going to call it a function.
Come on, buddy.
Function and I'm going to call it reset board, OK, we're going to take it one step further.
And in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to use the structuring, assign a restructuring assignment.
I'm going to give you a blank where you can read more about it.
You can just come here and put it right here.
So the structuring assignment syntax is a JavaScript expression that makes it possible to unpack values
from arrays.
And this is the part where we are looking for an values from arrays.
And in case you want to know what is which part of this structuring assignment we are using, it's exactly
this part.
So the value of A is going to be equal to B and the value of B is going to be equal to A.
So and you can read all about it here.
Right.
So this is the Indian doux.
I just gave you the link for that, so this is the link, this is the structuring assignment and we
are going to close it.
So if I come here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create an array and I'm going to say card is
flipped.
And also another item inside this array is going to be LOC board and I'm going to set them equal to.
So the first value that I put here, this value is going to be set to card is flipped.
And when I put in a comma and another value, the other value is going to be set for the lock board.
Right.
I'm also going to grab our first card.
And our second card.
And I'm going to set said both of them to know and not all right, so we can do.
We should provide it with semicolon so we could do it this way.
This is called structuring assignment.
This make this reduces the number of lines of code that we have.
So this thing is equal to Hoopes.
Equal to if we were to say card is flipped.
Let's set it equal to falls and then log board set it equal to falls and then let's grab the first come
on, let's grab the first card, set it to null and let's grab the second card and set it.
No.
So instead of doing all this, we did this.
So cards flipped is false.
Like board is false.
First card null.
Second call no.
So instead of doing that we could use the structuring.
This is is six syntax.
Very, very cool stuff.
So now where do we call this reset board.
So now we can see here we have a lock board, false.
And in here we also have a lock work force.
So I'm going to remove this and I'm going to call our reset board function in here.
So this is where we called it.
This is the first place that I'm going to call it.
The second place that we need to call it is actually right here.
So right here.
So it says card is flipped.
False, right.
And here we also have call it called card is flipped equal to false.
But I'm not going to pass it here because we have called the check for match function and inside the
check for match function, we have a disabled cards and inside the disabled cards is where I'm going
to call it.
And I'm going to save it.
And I'm going to remove this from here because this is the thing that I just remove.
Card is equal defaults is going to come from chick check a match and for the chick for match, it is
going to come from disable cards and from the disable cards.
It's going to come from reset board and from the reset board that is going to come from right here.
So it's like many layers, deep function call.
Right.
And let's come here.
So if I double click.
And click on this, OK, that that was a match, so let's click on something that is not a match.
So double click, click.
See, I cannot click on the third one until these two they evaluate either to true or false.
I cannot click on the third one.
So let's reset.
Let's make this thing.
I don't think we need to make it smaller because this is, I think, fully responsive.
Very cool, very cool stuff.
So double click, click.
I cannot click on a third card.
And this is the thing that this is the functionality that I wanted to cover in this video.
See you guys in the next one.