Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to detect the powerful collision.
All right, so right after that, the logic that we have implemented right here, what I'm going to
do is I'm going to come to this everything manager function.
And in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a variable and I'm going to call it player.
So I'm going to say let a player be equal to now.
How do we know which player do we want to choose?
Now, this player could be the R.I or the A.I. So why don't we, depending on where the ball is, we
can find out which player it is that we want.
So if the ball is in the room, if there was exposition is less than the canvases with, it means that
the canvas width is bigger.
The ball is in the eyes position canvases with the divided by two.
So this is the canvas with the divided by two.
This is one part of it.
This is two parts of it.
If the ball's exposition, for example, let's say this is the point of 300 pixels.
So let's say the ball is right here.
It means that the ball's exposition is 300 pixels.
Right.
And the canvas is with divided by two.
Let's say it's twelve hundred pixels so that that part is bigger than the box position.
It means that the ball is right here and otherwise the ball is going to be right there, right in here.
So if it is bigger than then the ball's exposition, it means that the ball is going to be in this side.
If it is less than that, it means that if the ball exposition is greater than the canvas with, it
means that the ball is right here.
OK, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to say if Balls X position is less than the canvas, eliminate
width divided by two.
Right.
If this is true, the ball should be in which position the ball should be in this position.
Because we know that the canvas is bigger.
The can there for example, here, the canvas is 600, the ball is 300.
So the ball is right here.
And when it is when the ball's X position is bigger, for example, the canvas right here is twelve
hundred and the ball is fourteen hundred.
It means that the ball is right here.
Right.
So we are going to say canvas element art with, keep in mind, divided by two.
If this is true, then the it is going to be player paddle.
R.I, if it is not true, it is going to be player paddle I.
OK, so right after this, what I want to do is I want to go ahead and I want to create that mouse move
as well.
So I'm going to come right here and I'm going to see I'm going to say the player Padel r.i event listener,
event listener.
This is going to be a simple event, the player panel, and we are going to grab our canvas element.
Why do we want this event to be attached to the canvas is because whenever the user goes off the canvas,
the user should not be able to move that paddle by the user I mean the r.i so out of the center.
What is the event mouse move and the move paddle function should fire.
We are going to create that function and I'm going to pass in the event and I'm going to say let canvas
erect a canvas rect right.
Should be equal to the canvas is now the canvas rect is going to store inside of it all the boundaries
of the canvas itself.
And for that we are going to use a very handy method and that is called get bounding client direct and
thus get bound and close ranks is going to give us the height the with the X position, the Y position,
all of it.
For that canvas and then we are going to say, Padel, sorry, player, paddle player, paddle.
Ah, I dot the Y position of that because we are just moving the paddle in the Y position and we are
basically concerned with that now before doing that, I just have to go ahead and show it to you.
I'm just going to say cancel the log so you can really see what I'm talking about, can restrict its
function.
What is the name of the function.
Move, paddle.
Perfect.
So if I come to inspect.
If I bring the inspector right here, I go to the so you can see that if I if I just clear that and
if I move inside the canvas, you can see that this event is being fair.
Now, let's take a look at inside one of these events.
So we have bottom.
We have to hide.
We have left, we are right.
We have TARP.
We have with we have X and we have Y now from all of this, what it is that we want to grab.
OK, so let's open this once more and.
We want to grab this why or also call the client why we can grow, so if I.
There should be a lot more in here.
So let's go into Proteau.
There we go.
Constructor.
That's everything that we have there, Read-Only.
OK, well, basically, what I want to graph from this is going to be the client, why so I'm going
to say darte client.
Client Y.
Let's see what it is going to give us.
So I'm going to give I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to grab the event itself and let's see what
that event is going to give us.
OK.
OK, so this is the event.
And then we go inside this event, we are going to grab that.
Right.
So basically, I want to grab the client y of the event.
Where is the client?
Why this is the client y right.
So I'm going to come inside the code and I'm going to say.
Let that player, panel player panel are I the y position of that should be determined by the events
client.
Why so let's say client Y minus the offset that we have, what is the offset that we have?
That is the canvasses.
You saw that canvas top and we are also subtract from it.
The player paddles height divided by two and it is going to give us the top 50 percent.
So basically what we are going to do is we are interested in grabbing this player's height from the
top because there are only three scenarios here.
One is going to be directly in the middle of this panel right here.
The other one is going to be the top.
The other one is going to be the ball.
So in the middle, the Y is going to be zero.
And the top the Y is going to be 50 and the bottom, the Y is going to be negative 50.
Why do we need all this?
Because we are going to use the we're going to use design cosine tangent to determine the angle of the
ball to about the angle at which the ball bounces off.
That's why we need to borrow.
That's why what I'm going to do is I'm basically I'm getting either a fifty, which means it's the top
or a negative fifty eight, which means the bottom.
So player paddle, ah, I don't hide, that's why we divide it by the height, by the height divided
by two, so we either get 50 or negative 50.
OK, so this is done as well.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to come down to our everything manager function.
And the next thing that I want to do is I'm going to come on top and I'm going to create our.
So I'm going to say creating the A.I. is going to be very, very simple.
The first thing that I want to create is going to be the intelligence level.
So intelligence level and I'm going to set it to zero point one and the maximum is one.
And I'm going to grab the player panel A.I. dot y position.
So what is the Y position for that?
I'm going to add on to it.
All right, I'm going to add on to it an algorithm that I'm just going to be writing here, so we are
going to say that if the ball's y position.
It's the boss y position minus the player part and the player padel idot y position.
So let's say that Webbs plus the high divided by two.
It's exactly the same thing that we did for here.
So the top position, the position of this, the vertical position of the the ah, I was the client
where it was moving in which minus the top position from there, minus the minus half of its height
working, going to do the same thing for that because we want to get a negative 50 and a 50 for that.
So player apparel, I dot height divided by two.
All right, now to be able to use our intelligence level, I'm just going to multiply it by that.
So in this case, this I will not be able to center its padel completely to head the ball to for the
ball to hit it in the center.
If it if we just remove this zero point one, if you remove the intelligence level, the I will always
be able to center the ball at its panels center and then it is always going to headed there and it's
never going to miss.
Right.
And that's exactly what we want to do as well.
We want the ball to have the paddle directly in the center.
What if it doesn't headed directly in the center?
What about then?
That's when our collision detection pattern detector data is going to come in.
So.
I'm going to say f now here is where the all of the interesting things happen, so f the if the paddle
paddle kuli ditty, let's passan or two of the arguments, one is going to be the player.
So in here we had the ball and the paddle and the reason that I pass and the player is because we have
specified a right here and the player is going to have a specific paddle.
Either that paddle is going to belong to the EHI or to the to the player or to the ah player.
Now if it hits it, we are going to play the audio.
Right.
That's that's done.
So first off, let's find out what is the point at which that it has hidden.
So that is I'm going to call it the collision.
OK, I'm going to call it the collision point now, the collision point, because we want to make sure
that it hits the center of the ball, heads the center of the paddle.
What is the center of the ball?
The center of the ball is going to be exactly the Y position or the exposition.
Why we are not using the X position because the paddles are vertical and they're moving in a vertical
direction.
We are just interested in the vertical position.
So we are going to say the ball's vertical position is going to give us that center of the ball.
So there we go.
You can see that this is moving and this is moving as well.
So if I reload, the ball is going to go away.
Let me keep this ball so it doesn't go off this.
It doesn't go off the screen.
There we go.
So this is the center of the ball, we have talked about this, I think before, that whenever you provide
a starting angle, the starting angle is going to start from here.
And we only provide coordinates for a circle.
The coordinates are going to be directly in the center of that circle as opposed to a rectangle where
when you provide a rectangle with coordinates, the coordinates are going to be at the top left corner.
And from there the rectangle is going to be drawn all the way to bottom right corner.
But for the circles, it's different.
The coordinate is in the middle.
So if I say ball that Y position, it is going to give me the center of the ball.
I want to grab the center of the ball.
And from this, let me just come in this one back in and from the center of the ball, I want to subtract
the Y position of the player so we get that 50 percent or that 50 pixels.
So the player y the player could be any player.
Right.
So I'm just going to you know what?
I'm just going to come in this one out so it is clear when the ball hits the paddle of any player.
Right.
Plus, the players height player, that height divided by two, save it.
So this is going to be a this is going to give us our collision point now.
This is the time to go to our Mathis's fun website.
So here it is.
Here we have our sine cosine and tangent.
We are basically interested in design and cosine.
So the sign of any angle is going to be the opposite side of that triangle divided by the hypotenuse.
The cosine of the angle is going to be the adjacent divided by a hypotenuse.
We know the angle, this theta angle.
We know that that's 45 degrees.
That's something that we have determined in our sole discretion.
You can determine that as ten degrees.
For example, if I were to the, let's say, open this game and zoom out and if I had it, you can see
that was 45 degrees.
So it's totally up to you.
You want to specify 45 degrees.
There we go.
Or do you want to specify 10 degrees, 100 degrees?
That's completely up to you.
There we go.
Another 45 degrees.
I want it to be 45 degrees.
So this theta is going to be 45 degrees.
And I want to find out how the ball is going to move diagonally.
I know how the ball is going to move towards the top.
That is the Y velocity.
I know how the ball is going to move to to one side or the other side.
That is the X velocity.
How is the ball going to move diagonally?
That's what we have to find out.
So if the ball is moving in this way, we are going to get we are going to get because it is moving
in this way.
We are going to get a negative angle.
And when it is moving in this way, we are going to get a positive angle because towards the bottom,
we always know that this is positive.
Towards the top it is negative.
Right.
So this is what we are going to do.
So.
The reason that in here, what I'm willing to do is I'm going to say normalization, normalization.
The reason that I'm doing normalization is to convert converting negative 50 that we have.
And 50 to what?
To negative one and one.
How can I do that?
How can I normalize that?
Because for sine and cosine to calculate the distance for us or the angle.
All right.
For them to calculate that they can calculate better if we pass in like I know we are going to pass
in 45 degrees, but they're going to return the 45 degrees, not in 50 or minus 50.
They're going to return it closer to one or closer to negative one or closer to zero.
So sine and cosine can only output one negative one or zero or in range or in this range.
So from zero to either one or from zero to either negative one, that's what sine unchosen do.
That's why you should convert them to negative one and one.
So I'm going to grab my collision point and I'm going to say the collision point should be divided by
the player's height.
We know the players height divided by two is going to be 50, the complete player.
So let me just write it so it's easier for you to understand.
Player Dotti divided by two players, height is 100, divided by two.
We get 50.
Collision point is either minus 50 or 50 or zero.
If it is minus 50, minus 50, divided by 50.
We are going to get what negative one.
If collision point is 50/50 divided by 50, we get one.
And what is the third thing that sine and cosine output that's zero.
If collision point is zero, we divided by 50 zero divided by 50, we are going to get zero.
So we are going to get our zero as well.
So this is what we need for science and closer.
So what are we going to do as I'm going to specify our bounce angle as well?
So I'm going to say calculating this is where you can manipulate the bounce angle.
You can change it to 30 degrees to 50 to 70.
That's up to you.
Calculating the angle at which.
The ball bounces back.
And the unit is going to be Irradiance Arad Radiance, so I'm going to say let bounds angle.
So what is that it is going to be math dot pi divided by four.
Why?
Because math that PI is going to return 180 degrees hundred and divided by four, we get 45 degrees.
Now, what is the direction of this?
Forty five degrees.
That's where the collision point comes in.
So collision point multiply by that.
So if the collision point is negative one, this balance angle is going to have is going to be negative
45 degrees and it is going to travel.
From here to the top right direction to this direction, that's negative 45, if the bounce of the collision
point is one, it is going to this bounce angle is going to be 45 and 45 is going to travel in this
direction.
If the collision point, this is the cool part, if the collision point is zero, the bounce angle is
going to be zero and the ball is going to travel in a straight line.
This is where it where we tie up every loose end.
So now, because we have selected everything, we need to update our velocity.
So I'm going to say updating the velocity now when I'm going to say when the ball hits any part of.
So we are going to grab the balls X velocity first and we are going to say there is one more variable
that we need to create here, but I have to first update it and then create that variable.
And so what is the we are going to grab the ball speed.
Of course we need that.
We are going to multiply it and we are going to say now what do we want to get?
We want to get this.
See, so when we provided forty five degrees, how the ball is going to travel, what is what is the
tilt that the ball is going to travel by.
So we need the hypotenuse for hypotenuse.
We know if the ball is traveling in this way, that is the Y velocity.
If the ball is moving in this way that is adjacent, that is the X velocity.
But what if the ball is moving in a combination of opposite and adjacent velocities?
How can we find this hypotenuse?
We just say if we want to find out the X direction or the Y direction for the hypotenuse.
Now, actually, we have found out the hypotenuse.
We know that the the ball is going to move in the 45 degrees.
But when the ball is moving 45 degrees, how much is it moving in the direction and how much is it moving
in the right direction?
That's why we need to find out these two, not the hypotenuse, but this time, I'm sorry for that.
I just because it's been twenty one minutes and I'm getting a little bit tired and I hope you don't
mind.
So when the ball is moving diagonally, how far it is moving in the Y direction, how far it is moving
in the direction.
So if I multiply hypotenuse by side of that angle we are going to get how much the ball is moving in
the right direction.
And if I multiply hypotenuse by the cosine of that angle, we are going to get how much the ball is
moving in the direction.
So first things first, let's get the X..
So where are we?
We are right here.
So we are going to say math dot for the X we have cosine.
So we are going to say cosine and I'm going to pass.
And the bounce angle, the best angle is going to be either forty five negative forty five or zero.
Right now we do have this, but we need to find out the direction this is going to give us how far the
ball is moving along the x axis.
And if I do this.
This is why and instead of cosign, I'm going to put inside, this is going to say how far the ball
is moving along the Y direction along the Y axis, but what is the direction it is along the Y axis
or but is it moving upward or is it moving done what?
We need to find that out as well.
So my computer is really working hard.
I'm just going to close that one and there is only one going to be open.
And for that I'm going to say calculating the direction.
The direction at which.
Which the ball bounces.
Back of the boat, not it's not that it's the one calculating the direction of the ball.
The direction of the ball when it bounces back, bounces back, what is the direction?
So when the ball hits this paddle and the angle is not zero, it means that it's not moving in a straight
line.
We know it's moving at 45 degrees, but it went which direction we need to assign that negative forty
five degrees to something.
So we want to assign that negative in 45 degrees to top and positive 45 degrees to bottom.
So for that, I'm going to say let direction this is our point.
Our Situation Room say if the ball's exposition is less than the canvas element, canvas elements with
divided by two, if this if this is true.
It means that the ball is in the endzone at the players, it could be at each side's player, it doesn't
really matter, but we want the ball to move in a positive direction and otherwise we want it to move
in a negative direction.
And I'm going to grab that direction and I'm going to multiply this by that direction as well.
So I'm going to multiply by the direction and want to say multiply by the direction.
So let's put it there as well.
And finally, when after each time the ball, I'm going to say after each bounce back, each bounce
back, what do we want to do?
We want to increase the speed of the ball.
The speed of the ball should be increased.
So we are going to grab the ball that speed and we are going to add onto it now how much you want it
to increase.
That's up to you.
I'm just going to go ahead and increase it by zero point one.
And now let's see so the ball bounces back.
There we go.
So let's see if it bounces back from here.
You can see when it hits it right at the top, it goes directly at forty five degrees.
And there we go at the bottom directly.
Forty five degrees.
If I tried to hit it in the middle it should go in a straight line.
So let's see.
There we go.
There you can see almost in a straight line.
So I'm going to try to make that no, it wasn't so the angle is going to range from zero to 45 C almost
in a straight line.
When it hits it in the middle, it goes almost in a straight line.
And when it hits it towards the bottom, it is going to come to the bottom.
When it heads towards the top, it is going to go to the top.
So so so far, we have been able to create all this.
And let's add our sounds so we should get our sense.
All right.
If I had it perfect, perfect, and now I'm going to let the computer score so we can hear that sound
as well.
OK, we did not hear that we are going to fix that, don't worry, and you can see that now we cannot
see the ball.
Where is the ball?
We did not reset the ball.
That's what we are going to do in our next lecture.
See you guys then.