Hi, everyone, in this culture, I would like to solve a bug with the responsiveness of this game.
All right, so we have come this far, and if I go ahead and if I decrease the width of the window,
you can see that this the move the position of this panel is not moving at all.
But if so, if I go ahead and if I make this model, you can see that we had this problem.
If I reload, I know that it is going to start from there.
Our walls are responsive, but not the position of the panel, nor the ball itself.
Right.
So what I would like to do first is I would like to address another issue, and that is whenever we
want to move our paddle the ball, when it is not served, it seems to stay in its place.
And when we serve it, it is going to go.
But before serving, it is not going to go anywhere.
So what I would like to do is, first off, go ahead and and fix the updatable position and then we
will go ahead and implement that responsiveness issue.
So in here, what I would like to do is I want I want to move the ball, move the ball with the paddle.
So.
The panel.
All right, so if now we only want to move the ball with the panel when it is not already moving, when
it is not moving towards the top, it means that when the ball's y velocity is equal to zero, what
do we want to do?
We want to grab the balls exposition and we want to set up to Pardo's exposition.
So that should just do it for us.
So I shouldn't serve it.
I'm just going to you can see.
So now that I move the paddle, the ball is going to move.
But whenever you hit into space and now when you move the paddle, the ball is not going to move because
the ball is only going to move with the paddle if the Y velocity zero.
All right.
So now that that problem is solved, let's go ahead and let's actually tackle the responsiveness issue
that we have.
So what I'm going to do for that is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to cut the new game function
called from the down below and let me collapse this function.
And I'm going to come to our set dimensions and I'm going to pace that function.
Where is that?
There we go.
So I'm going to post it here.
Why did I do that?
The reason for that is so if I come on top, you can see that our set dimensions function only is called
when we receive this event.
So whenever we receive the whenever the window is resized, we want to call the set dimensions as well
as the new game, which is responsible for creating a new game for us.
So it doesn't matter if you're playing, if you if I just go ahead and open up this console here.
So this is the finished game so you can see that I'm playing.
But whenever I change the size, you can see that the the game is going to reset.
That's what we are actually saying here.
So if I do that and if I change it now, you can see that the the pattern is changing with that as well.
There we go.
So I guess that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.