Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about the extents and super clauses.
All right, so first off, what is the extents clause that we have written here?
All right, so if you want to extend one class into another class, we use the extended clause.
Why do we want to do that?
So we don't have to redefine any other methods that are already defined in the workshop.
Class, right, because they can be so-called inherited using the extends clause so we can inherit this
method and we can inherit the this method if we do.
And so this another workshop.
This is another workshop.
Hence this.
The first letter is capital for the classroom.
And we say that we want to extend the workshop.
So whenever we do extend, we get access to all the data that's inside the workshop.
And in here we have a method or a function that is speak up and a message as Pastan as a parameter.
Right.
And it says this don't ask.
So we are invoking this function.
So now if I run this code, what is the this keyword is going to point out?
First off, we have two different kinds of discourse.
One of the discourse is right here.
The other one is inside this class.
So we have two different this keywords.
So let's first off talk about that, this key word, which is right here.
So if we go ahead and call this workshop and we can see that we have not called it, we just we have
just called the another workshop.
All right.
So but what happens here is this.
Another workshop extends the workshop.
So we need to go inside this, another workshop.
First off, where is the workshop called?
It's called online number 16.
This is the call site.
So we want to find out what this is referring to.
All right.
So this is going to bring us to line number 69 from the line number 16.
We are going to go inside this.
In here, we can see that we have another this, so we can see that this this is going to reverse this,
this and what is this this referring to?
So we need to go to where this functions.
Speak up has been invoked.
The function speak up has been invoked in here.
So the function speak up has been invoked as a method on this python, which is an object which has
been created.
But the new keyword, which is right here.
All right.
So this python, it should have this key word on it, which comes from the new object which has been
created when we call this another workshop.
All right.
And we say that that is due and we passed as an argument, which is Julian.
All right, so what happens is when we say that speak up, this is the teaches by Python message is
going to be teach us Python.
But what about this, Julia?
Because we are extending the workshop, it means that we are grabbing this constructor and we are grabbing
this aske function.
This Julian is going to be passed in here instead of this teacher and also passed in here.
So we are going to get that this teacher is going to be equal to Julie, right.
Because we don't have any any other method in here.
Whenever we call, whenever we extend the workshop to this another workshop, it it means like this.
So I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to pass it right here.
So now it makes more sense.
Right.
So we are going to pass on this, another workshop inside the constructor.
So this Julie-Anne is going to pass past in here and then ultimately passed here.
So this of this constructor is going to refer to Jullian.
So this is done.
I'm just going to remove it from here so we know what this is.
So this is going to be Julian, this star teacher is going to be Julian.
And then the question, so where is the question coming from?
The question?
We are asking the question right here.
So the question is this argument.
So this argument is going to be passed inside this perimeter and this parameter is going to pass.
It has an argument in here to this ask so we know the question is going to be teachers by thought,
and I'm just going to remove that as well.
So what about this?
What is the this key word in here, inside this another workshop, what inside the speaker function
is going to refer to?
So we need to go to where it is called.
It is called on line number 17.
And we can say that it has been called on the python.
OK, and Python is a new object that has been created by the new keyword.
And that object has one method in it sorry, one property in it, and that is teacher.
So we are going to grab that teacher and we are going to pass it right here.
So this ask is going to be Teacher Dot ask.
All right.
And what is the teacher asking?
The teacher asking this this argument.
I hope you're not getting confused.
This is how classes work in OLP pattern.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is whenever I save it, whenever I run this code, we are going to see first
off, Julian, because that is the first argument in here, OK?
Because this is the only council that we have.
OK, so this is going to log it to the console.
So this the teacher is going to be juliann the question.
Where is the question?
The question is teachers python, because this is passed right here and then pass right here and then
right here.
This task is going to refer to this aske, which is right here.
Right.
So if I say it, we are going to see Julieann teaches Python and we can see that Julieann teaches Python.
It is a bit complicated, but once you get the hang of this, you will know, OK, that you are going
to go up and down until you find what the this refers to.
And when you find one that this refers to, basically you can master object oriented programming, like
very easily.
So this is the extents clause.
The next example that I want to talk about is going to be the super class.
So I'm just going to say extend extends and then we have super and I'm going to also tell you what is
the difference.
So I'm just going to go ahead and come in this code out and I'm going to go over this code.
I'm just going to copy it and I'm going to paste right here.
I am going to come in this one out and we are not going to run anything for now.
OK, so what do we have here is now when do we when do we use the extent?
So in the class system, we also have this this sorry, when we use the super.
So in the class system we also have the super and we use it whenever we want to, whenever we want to
do relative polymorphism.
What is the what is relative polymorphism.
Relative polymorphism is if you have a child class like another workshop that defines a method of the
same name, which is ask OK, as a parent class, as this class.
So this workshop has a method ask, which is the parent of this another workshop, because this is this
is going to extend it so you can see that super works with extents.
And now we have this we have a method that is had that has the same name as this one.
OK, this is also called shadowing, and we can refer now what is this super going to allow us?
We can refer to the parent from the child by saying Souper Dout.
So this is the method which is called Inside Another Workshop.
I'm just going to bring it up.
And whenever we say super dot, it means that the parent of this, another workshop has a method called
Aske.
And the argument for that method is going to come from this aske.
So we grab the message and we say to uppercase, I could just remove this to uppercase just to remove
the confusion and assist Trever teachers react apart from the super that it is going to just point to
the method which is defined on its parent.
Apart from this, everything works in the same way.
And I'm going to go over this one more time, OK?
And before going over this, I just want to say that this is an example of extension beyond syntactic
sugar, because prior to E is six classes, there was there was essentially no way to do relative Molefe,
relative polymorphism, very, very difficult word.
There was no equivalent of the super keyword.
And whenever we get to the prototypes, we can see that we can only extend classes or prototypes.
In that case, we cannot do the super.
We cannot, like, do the same class names in both of the prototypes.
Right.
So we are going to go over this one more time.
So in here we have a class that is called workshop inside.
There we have a constructor and we have a method called Aske.
We do have this teacher.
Right.
And then we have another class of workshop that extends the class workshop.
And we have a method that has the same name.
That is that that a method on the parent has.
So basically here we have a naming collision, but this is not a name in college.
So what do we want to do is we want to we want to run.
We want to call this another workshop class, which is actually a function.
And we want to pass in the TREVER.
So whenever we extend it means that we grab all of these and we put them right here, OK, we extend
all the classes here.
So this way, I know this is not like literally this is literally this is not something that is happening,
but a runtime this is actually what's happening.
OK, we are not rearranging the code.
I'm just showing you how this actually works.
So what I pass in Trever, let's go one level up.
So when I pass in Trever, this driver is going to be passed inside this constructor, the inside this
parameter and then is going to be passed here.
So this DOT teacher is going to be equal to Trever.
So this line is done.
You know what that this is going to refer to?
And because that this the teacher is equal to Trever, we know that the first argument inside this,
the first part of this argument is going of this log for this log function is going to be.
Trever, what is the second argument, which is this question?
OK, so let's go ahead and let's see where this function is called.
Where is this function?
Ask this call.
The function asked is called right here.
So which one of these two asks is actually this function of call?
We can see that this is a function declaration and this is a function call because both of them have
the same name we tag on a super dot.
It means that we can use the same names for classes as we have in the parent and the same name for the
child as well.
So so if I pass in a program an argument to this parameter for this function declaration, that argument,
which is now a parameter in here, is going to be passed again, as an argument for this ask question,
where is this coming from?
So how can I how can I pass it then pass a parameter here.
OK, sorry.
Pass an argument here.
I hope you're not getting confused.
So an argument is passed into a parameter.
So in order to find that argument, we need to go to where that function is called.
The function is called right here.
So we are going to grab this.
Teachers react.
We are going to pass it here.
Oops, teachers react.
Let's grab it.
It is going to be passed there and it is going to be passed there.
So now we know that this the teacher is Trever and question is going to be teachers react.
Right.
I'm just going to go one level back and now so this one is done as well.
So now this one is done.
We know what this is referring to.
It is referring to Trever.
We just go to the call site where it is called.
And this when we find it, we know that this is Dreaver.
And where is the question?
We go to the call side.
The call center is here.
Then it is inside this function for this function ask we go to the call side, which is right here.
OK, so it is going to be Superdad ask, so what is super?
It is going to grab this class right here, this method from the workshop class.
And we know that this method is going to return council log teacher Trever and the question which is
teachers react.
So at the end react ask is going to say, Trever, teachers react and it is going to come from line
number twenty seven because this is our cancela.
But we call this function online number 33 and we call the ask function on line thirty eight.
So this is how all of these they are linked together.
That's it for the extents and super clauses.
We are technically we are done with the with the sugar layer of this object oriented programming section
of our course.
Now this is the sugary part.
What is what is actually happening in JavaScript whenever you create classes or what what are these
classes are created based upon?
That is the prototype, OK, which are starting from our next lecture up until the end of this chapter,
we are going to talk about the prototypes.
So, you know, the two sides of this object oriented programming that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.