Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to go over the first case.
All right, so in case one, we are working with restricting usernames now, this is the case, one,
we have some requirements.
The first requirement, these requirements are going to be implemented using our regular expressions,
knowledge.
Now, the there should be at least two letters.
All right.
Numbers should be at the end.
If there are any in any numbers, they should be at the end.
Letters can be either lowercase or uppercase.
Now, these are the requirements that we as developers implement so that the user has to follow these
requirements of of creating his user name.
OK, excuse me.
And for if there are two letters, they cannot contain numbers.
So if you have like a two letter like let's say fo efo, then they are like one of these letters.
It cannot be like a number like EF1.
All right.
So both of them should be like actual letters.
If there are more than that, then they could contain numbers.
So we need to have like we are going to end up with a pretty int..
I would say I wouldn't I wouldn't say advanced, but an intermediate level kind of regular expression.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create the regular expression first and then we are going to
create our user name and we are going to test it tested.
OK, we are just going to test that set.
So let's open the console.
All right, so we are going to say username check, username check, this is a regular expression.
So everything comes in here.
Now we want now let's go over the requirements one more time.
So we want to have at least two letters.
OK, the numbers should be at the end.
So it means that the letters should be at the start.
What is the character that we use to make sure that we are working with the beginning of string patterns?
I'm sure you remember.
So if I if I just come here.
So Carrott matches the start of this of the string, so I'm just going to put in a carrot.
It means that whatever comes after the carrot is going to be at the start.
So at the start, we want to have letters and letters.
They could be uppercase and lowercase.
So I'm going to say all the uppercase letters and all the lowercase letters, they could be at the start,
so the start part is done.
So this part is done.
OK, these two parts, actually, both of them, they are done, and now what we want to do is we want
to make sure that we have at least two letters, OK, because that is the minimum.
You cannot have like a blank username.
You should at least write something.
So we need to have at least two.
That's why we are going to use quantities, specifiers, because we are implementing the quantity,
the number of times something should be there.
So it should be at least two and it could be like 10, 15 to an infinity number.
It could be like 50, like 100 or 1000.
We don't care about that, but there should be at least two.
So we provided the minimum range.
The maximum range could be specified by the user.
You could go ahead and say like the maximum range for a user name could be like 140 characters, but
I'm not going to do that.
That's why we just specified the lower bound.
The upper bound is up to the user.
We want to provide the user with some flexibility as well.
Now, after now, these are the letter of parts.
What about the numbers?
So we want to grab numbers as well.
Right now we want to which we have to provide the pattern that allows for the numbers and that is this
D it is going to grab all numbers.
If we provided with a capital D, it is going to grab all the numbers.
Right.
And we want to grab the numbers that have zero or more occurrences.
And you might ask, OK, why zero and more occurrences?
Why not one or more occurrences or to be accurate, why asterisk.
Why not?
Plus because at the beginning we said at least two letters.
If there are two, I'm not like my throat is closing up and I'm not sure what's happening and I apologize
for that.
At the beginning we said that we want at least two letters and if there are only two letters, they
cannot contain numbers.
So when they cannot contain numbers, it means that we have is zero occurrence of numbers.
OK, so what is the zero occurrence?
That's asterisk if you provide plus you should have at least one because plus is one or more matches.
But Asterisk says zero because we have given the user of flexibility to not include any numbers if the
user wants.
But in that case, the user must have at least two letters.
So if there are only two letters, they cannot contain numbers.
So we don't have any occurrence of any number.
That's why we are going to use the asterisk.
I'm sure you got the point.
So we are going to grab the asterisk and we are going to put it there.
And now a cool thing is the other thing that the numbers should be at the end because the letters are
at the start, the numbers, they should be at the end and let's put on the dollar sign.
So this is a regular expression.
Very, very simple.
Now, let's check it out.
So we have our user name.
First off, I'm just going to say SDK software development kit.
I mean, why not?
That's cool.
So let's say check status.
We are checking for the status, whether it is true or false.
So we are going to grab our user name check and which is a regular expression and we are going to test
the user name.
And we are going to log to the console, the checked status, so if I save it, we get through.
Why why do we get through?
Because we have at least two characters and then we have a number.
We have like a third character, which is a number.
So we have it sorry.
We have at least two characters, which are letters and a third one is optional.
The user can provide because we have specified the range so the user can provide two or more.
So even if I were to come and this one out and to just provide SD or ČESKÉ software kit, we should
see true as well, because this is the minimum requirement.
But if I were to say, OK, we should get false because this is not we should have at least to see.
So the lower bound can only be two.
It cannot be one.
We cannot go less than two.
We can go above that like cattle.
We can't go above that, but we cannot go below that, right, so we have tested it for the.
There is yeah, we have tested it for the letters, let's test it for the numbers.
So if I put in canine and we have said that at least two letters, there should be at least two letters.
And one, there are two letters, they cannot contain numbers.
That's why inside these brackets, we just have letters.
And if I save it, we get a false.
So whenever you're creating a regular expression, you should test it on all of the possible scenarios.
I know it takes time, but this is how you, like, remove the issues from your software or your application
or your webapp in case there are any.
So your application should work perfectly fine in all 100 percent of scenarios.
It doesn't matter what the scenario is, you shouldn't provide loopholes for users to exploit.
So this works as well.
Now let's do K K nine.
We should get through because we have at least two letters and then we have a number and that number
is at the end.
If this number is by any means in the front, we get we should do this.
We get a false because we have said that numbers, they appear at the end s..
So so far everything is working perfectly fine and.
And I'm just going to say Java script.
Rux, so now this is everything that we have done, rocks like.
3000, if you know what I mean, Servet, and we get true because all of the conditions, all of the
conditions are met.
So now we are done with this.
We are done with this.
But because I really care about you, I'm going to give you another comment and I'm going to just sit
right here and it says it breaks down this regular expression.
This is because I really care about your learning, about you learning every part of it.
And that's why, in case you forget, you can come back and you can see which part actually does what.
I just did this and I've inserted it.
And good luck.
See you guys in the next case.