Hi, everyone, in this letter, we will handle game over our ride along with when the game is over,
we will like to print a text as well to just show which player has won and Tulsa restarted the game.
Also show whether if there is a tie or not and all these sort of things.
So first off, we have created over time and right here.
So what are we going to do as I'm going to keep that one open and we are going to go to our new game
and inside our new game right down here, I'm going to grab our time in and I'm going to set it to zero.
So initially it is going to be zero and.
What we are going to do is where did we handle that logic?
So in our select site, we we put something think handle game over.
So in here, what we would like to do is.
We would like to check F now f the score, r.i, plus the score I.
If Score II, if both of them are equal to the grid size times, the grid size now grid size, it means
that the number of rows, number of columns score score, it means that the game is over.
Like the both of the scores.
They are equal to the size of the grid.
There is no more score for any of them to grab.
Then we are going to say the time end is going to be equal to math.
Dot, dot, seal.
So it is going to give us a whole integer returns, the smallest integer greater than or equal to its
numeric argument.
And we are going to pass an hour delay and in here times the FPS.
So if the FPS is thirty, it is going to take two seconds.
If the FBI says 60, it is still going to take two seconds because the FBI should be based on frames
per second of your refresh rate screen.
So go ahead and check that out first and then pass.
And for me, it's 60.
So I'm just going to go ahead.
I'm going to pass in 60 in here.
And basically we want to do that.
So next stop, let's go ahead and let's actually draw this.
So I'm going to collapse this square thing, the entire thing.
I'm going to collapse this site and I'm going to collapse the new game.
And here is where we are going to do our logic, so we are going to say game over text, we need to
show that right.
So we are going to say if time end is greater than zero, it means that the time is not ended.
We are going to decrement it by one.
Right.
It means that we are in the game over.
Now, first off, let's go ahead and let's handle a tie when there is a tie there.
Right.
And.
If when do we have a tie when this core of R.I equals the score of A.I., very simple, right?
When when these two scores, they are the same, it means that it is a tie.
All right.
So for that, which one should I grow?
I could either of those.
I'm just going to put it right here and I'm going to save it.
So what is the text?
The text is going to be text Ty.
Perfect, what is going to be the with the with is going to be zero point five, the exposition, the
Y position is going to be margin zero point six, the color is going to be colored tie.
So we do have a color for that as well.
And the text size is going to be that.
So this is going to handle a tie for us.
So let's go ahead and let's check it out.
All right, so if I put in that there and I should give the other user the edge of, I don't think I
can, so I'm just going to put it there for there.
So this is not going to be a tie.
So let's try this again.
Right.
So this is that user and then it's this user.
Put one there and one here.
It is this user and this should be there we go.
It says draw.
Right.
And you can see that the draw went away after exactly two seconds, but our game did not our game did
not restart.
We are going to handle that as well.
So if it is a tie, what if it is not a tie?
If it is not a tie?
We need to make sure.
We need to find out which player.
Players when which player has one player's player wins?
Right player wins if they score.
Of the first player is greater than the score of the second player.
Let's go ahead and let's check the color as well.
This is going to return a boolean if then if you hover over it, you can see that it says Boolean and.
And if this boolean is true, it means that player one is one, if this boolean is not true, it means
that players two has one.
Let's grab the color as well based on that boolean.
So we are going to say if players turn, if Flair's wins, it's true.
It means that the first player has won.
Right.
And we need to show the color for that.
So color of player, if it is not true, if player wins is false, it means that the A.I. has won.
So we are going to show the color for the.
A perfect.
And what about the text should I mean, we should show the text as well, right?
So we are going to say if player wins is true, it means that the player won, a.k.a. r.i has won and
we are going to show the text player.
Otherwise it means that the RIAA, a.k.a. player one has not won and the AK player too has won.
And we are going to show the text for that.
Perfect.
And finally, let's actually draw this so we could grab any of these.
I'm going to grab this one and I'm going to put it right here.
Save it.
So what is going to be the text?
The text is going to be the text.
The weather is going to be zero point five margin is going to be zero point seven, the color is going
to be the color that we have just passed, we have just created there.
The text size is going to be text size top.
So this is going to be the text and let's actually grab and pass.
And the text went as well.
So where is text when the with the same the margin for this.
I'm going to put it a five.
This is going to show us which player it is, but we need to say that PLAYER one, this is going to
give us that one one text and it should be below this.
That's why the margin is bigger.
The color is the color.
The size is that.
So if.
And also after this, we are handling it and and the statement we are handling, whichever which player
has won, we need to reset the game as well.
So start a new game, so start a new game.
And with this, hopefully our project is going to work and it is going to come to an end.
Now, if it is equal to zero, it means that the game has ended, it is greater than zero.
We are going to decrease it until the game ends.
And when the game ends, we are going to call a new game.
All right, so I'm going to play it with this player once, and you could go ahead and you could play
it with the great size 10.
I'm just going to check it here.
And PLAYER one.
First off, let's check for a draw that's player two, and this is going to be.
Oh, this is going to be so it says player one one and you can see the game reset.
So now let's give player to the win.
Right and pleasure to.
So it says player to one and the score was three.
Let's let's try to grab a draw.
So I'm going to try to do this randomly, so.
This is going to be a draw.
OK, so oh, so if I put it here, I can grab that and that and it's going to say draw and then the
game is going to restart.
And each time you can see that it is random, which players turn, it is the player's turn is always
going to be right.
So it is player one.
Players to.
Player one again, one, two, one, one, one, two, and basically it's random.
So the final thing that I would like to do is I would like to set the grid size to turn.
So everything looks cool here.
I'm going to close this game that we have.
So this is the game that we built.
Just refresh the page and start playing.
So now you can play with another player.
So player one.
Player two.
In our next game, we will be changing the text to A.I. and our computer, what we had and we will be
automating the computer.
Right.
So whenever I put a line here, the computer will think and will come up with another line, for example,
here or here.
And then we will have, like I think I can call it, like a smart AI that is going to be smart AI and
it is going to be a little bit challenging to play against that A.I. It's going to be somewhat like
the A.I. that we created for a Kinect for game, but way smarter than the one that we created for the
Pong.
I mean, the Pong II was really smart, but we had to dumb it down.
So that's it for this chapter and for this project.
See you guys in the next one.