Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to create the complete to do and remove to do functions.
All right, so what we have done is we have targeted the dynamically created to do items and I'm going
to show you one more time.
So like.
Hmm, like drinking, OK, drinking.
OK, so if I just click on this, we can see it right here.
So if I click here, it is going to say complete to do is not defined.
And if I click here it is going to say remove to do is not define.
Now these two errors, they are pretty normal because we don't have those functions defined yet.
But there is another error that I'm worried about.
It's this one that it says uncute type error cannot read property value of undefined.
And if we click on this, it is going to bring us to where it is going to bring us to this to do status.
And I'm going to explain to you why we see this error.
So when we have specified a word to do status, we said to do item, which is the item that we have
clicked on, and then we go inside the attributes of that item.
And from there we grab the status attribute and we get the value for the status attribute.
Now, this is fine, but where is the problem?
The problem is right here inside this dynamically created element.
Now this I icon, this icon, this one has a status.
This one also has a status, but what about this paragraph, it doesn't have a status attribute, so
let's come into our e-mail.
What about this year?
Well, it doesn't have a status attribute.
So let's go back to our JavaScript.
What about this elai?
It doesn't have a status attribute, so it doesn't matter what we click on, as long as it is.
As long as it's not.
The icon, as long as it's not these two icons, is going to throw an error.
How do we know that?
I'm going to show you how we know that.
So for simplification purposes, I'm going to come and tell these two and I'm going to hear cancel that
log.
All right.
To do item.
Let's go ahead and cancel the log to do item and let's see if it is going to throw anything.
So I'm just going to put in one, two, three.
If I click on this, we can see that we have clicked on an icon.
Let's refresh.
OK, just maybe like print something real.
So if I click on this trash, we have clicked on the trash icon.
What if I click on this?
So this is our paragraph and I've just clicked on it and it shows that cannot read property value of
undefined.
It does not tell me where I have clicked.
So for that to work because this consider log happens after the error, it's not executed.
So I'm going to bring it here.
I'm going to bring it here.
And now this concept, the log has no idea what this to do item.
So I'm just going to grab this and I'm going to put in put it right here.
If it a target.
All right.
Let's save it now, let's create a writing center, click on this, we are going to get our icon, of
course, which has a status of complete.
This one should have a status of delete.
But when I click on this paragraph, we do get the paragraph which says writing, but we still see this
error.
So clicking on the paragraph, we see an error.
Let's remove it.
If I click on the ally, it gives me an ally and we still see that error because the ally doesn't have
a status attribute and therefore there is no value for that.
That's why the value is undefined, right?
If I click here, it is going to give me a user because we have clicked inside the user.
We have not clicked on any elai, any icons or any paragraphs.
And and the UN doesn't have an attribute of status.
Hence the value is undefined because there is no status.
There is no value for that.
So what do we have to do is we have to make sure that we cover this corner corner, we cover this.
We like let's say we debug it, OK?
We remove this book from our application.
So for that one, I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to implement an if statement.
I mean, what is better than an if statement to be able to control the flow of our application?
So before even like doing this if statement, I'm going to show you something very, very cool that
you can do with events.
But what the exact event object did working with.
So I'm just going to consider log given.
I'm not going to say target, I'm just going to consider log the event itself.
So I'm going to say walking.
And when I click on this, we do get an error.
But that's not the point.
The point is we get all this information from this all this information.
What I found out was what I found out to be the most exciting was this path for this specific bug that
we have in our application.
So we get this path.
So whenever inside this event, we want to grab some property of that event, we can access that through
the dot notation so we can just say path, dot path, hence the evt.
The target target is a property of this event object event.
As an object.
Each object has a specific set of methods and properties.
You can access them through the dot notation or through the back bracket notation.
We have talked about this, right?
So I want to target the path.
I want to grab the path.
So I'm just going to say Evett dark path.
This is the same as the E or as the event that we have used before.
So here we have set it to event.
It doesn't matter if you write event, if you write evt or if you write it is going to work.
Right.
I don't think we have used E in this application.
Of course, in our previous applications we have used E a ton.
So it's it is going to work the same way.
So now if I create another one and if I click on this, it is going to give me the path, the path that
I showed you.
Now you guys can see that this seems like indices.
These seem like indices as says zero, one, two, three, whatever.
But the zero index is where is what is when I have her on it, it is going to highlight this paragraph.
So let me show you one other cool thing.
So if I click inside the user and if I come hover over this, well, it is going to highlight this entire
area.
So through this path, ensure through this path, we can know for sure.
What is it?
Was it what is it exactly that we are clicking on or that the user has clicked on?
So if I click on this, we are going to get the exact icon that we have clicked on.
I mean, this works like path, but in a much better way in my opinion.
So if I click on this trash, we are going to get the trash well, with a lot more info.
Now, this info is the tree, the the parent tree or the ancestor tree for this element.
So the first parent is going to be alive.
The second one is going to be well then content and container, then body, then HTML, then document.
Right.
So these are the ancestral tree of this element which we don't want to do.
We don't have any thing to do with those.
We just want the first this one, the index of zero, the exact item that we have collected.
How does this help us and helps us in in and writing in our logic, so we are going to say if now here
we are going to use our logical operators.
So I hope you have practiced them a lot.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say Evett Dutt if event dot path now how to how we can access
index through the bracket rotation notation.
I'm just going to put in zero because as I told you guys, we are interested in the first item.
The first item has an index of zero and from there we are going to grab the local name.
I should have shown you the local name as well, which I'm going to show you in a sec.
So I'm just going to come in this one out.
I just want to show you all our.
All of the like like the route that we are going to go through and then apply that, so we were up to
her path and then we are going to grab the first item.
And from there, I'm going to show you, you know what I'm just going to show you here it's not going
to take long.
What cooking?
Still the same thing, instead of removing one, I even added one, so.
OK, so if I come here now, you can see that we get our paragraph, which is the element that we have
clicked on.
So if I click on this, we get an I click on this, we get another, I click on this, we get our ally
click on this, we get our viewer if I remove this.
And come here and right, walking properly this time and click on this, we can see that we get all
the information that we talked about.
So now let's click on this and the first items index, which is zero.
And if we come down, we are going to see something very, very interesting.
And that is the local name.
So the local name is actually the aliment name that we are looking for.
So the way that we are going to implement this logic is that if the local name is a paragraph.
So let's try this.
Let's click on this.
Let's come here.
Now, you guys can see we get errors in three situations.
One, when the local name is a paragraph, two when the local name is lie right here, and three, when
the local name is you.
Well, so in these three scenarios, we get an error, but when the local name is an icon or another
icon, we don't get an error.
So we need to take these three out of this equation through an IF statement.
That's how simple it is.
So for the paragraph, we should be able to see a local name, whereas l come buddy.
So the local name is the element tag.
This is what we can use to our advantage that's collapsed this.
Let's expand this one.
So for this, the local name should be illi.
And a local name.
Yes, the local name is Elide, the Element name, and I'm going to show you the U.S. so your mind is
at rest.
All right.
Where is the local name, the local name as you are?
So what we are going to do, we are going to say is if so, now let's delete this so that local names.
So let's come in this back.
And so we are going to say if the local name equals P or I'm just going to copy this for F or if the
local name equals Elai or if the local name is person or logical operators, or you will.
What do we want to do?
We want to return from the function and this return key is a very, very interesting one, because if
even one of these three conditions is true, then it is going to return and none of the following code
is going to run.
This is this is how we can control the flow of logic so the logical operators can also be changed as
well.
So you can use like technological logical operators in one sentence and one has not signed and in one
line of code.
So this logical operator says that if either of these three is true, then if the condition of this
if statement is going to evaluate to true, hence we are going to return from this function, meaning
none of this code is going to run, none of them.
So let's see that in action.
So I'm just going to consider log one, two, three.
So if one of these if statement if one of the logic, one of the sides of this logical operator is expression
is true, the condition of the statement is going to evaluate to true and we are going to return from
the function.
It means that this constant lock should not.
Like run, if this condition is true, the council should not run, this kind of luck only runs when
these conditions, all three of them are false, even if one of them is not true.
Sorry, even if one of them is true, this consular should not run.
All right, so this is the most difficult part.
So if I click on this, we can see that the console log runs.
If I click on the reading, we don't see the console log run.
So let's click on the reading.
The console log doesn't run.
Click on the like.
Click on the URL.
The console doesn't run.
We want we wanted to run in only two situations.
One, this one and then this one.
So you can see that we have run it for two times so we can say this and then trash it.
And if I click on this and we are going to trash it.
So through this statement, we were able to remove those errors that we used to see.
I don't I mean, those errors, they didn't have a negative effect on the applications overall performance.
It is not it's not like a good thing to have in the background there.
I don't want to have any errors there.
So I know I called this lecture to create the room complete to do and remove to do functions, but this
was actually to remove a bug.
So in the next lecture, we are going to create our complete to do and remove to do functions.
See you guys in the next lecture.