Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to create a correct answer function and incorrect answer
function.
All right, so we know why and by now we know what the user has clicked on.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's implement some logic based on that.
So we are going to say if the answer equals if the answer equals questions.
Now we want to evaluate the user's answer against the correct answer, that the correct answers, key
value pair inside the object, which is an item of an array of questions.
Right.
So right away when I write these questions, we are we have access to this to this object, which is
inside this array.
So inside this object, we have a question that is a string question, a string.
Everything is basically a string.
But what is inside this entire list that is really useful for us?
It is the correct answer.
But before going to the correct answer, we should know what is the answer that the user is currently
is currently working on?
What is the question that the user is currently working on?
So, for example, if the question is question number five, we need to check this answer and yes,
against the correct answer for the question number five.
So before even accessing that array, we need to know what is the active question that the user is actively
trying to answer.
So after we have found out the index of that question from there, we are going to grab our correct
answer.
So if the answer that we pass on inside this parameter that that is going to be passed and instead of
this parameter, which is going to come from right here, which we know how we got it.
If that is accurate, sorry if that is equal to the correct answer for that specific question, we want
to grab our Oscar and we want to incremented by one right now, we have we have created the score and
the initial value for the score is zero.
This is this.
Where is the score?
I don't think we have created it.
So let's go ahead and let's create it down here.
So let's say let's score be equal to
zero.
Now, this score is the score that we are going to show when all the questions are done.
So first off, we want to increment that score because the score has a value of zero.
When the user answers one question correctly, the score is going to be one.
This is how we add it behind the scenes.
Beats are right.
And the next thing that I want to do here is I want to call two functions here.
So the first function is going to be answer.
Insur is correct.
I want to call in dysfunction, if the answer is correct, we are going to call the answer is correct
function or else we are going to what is this Lisse else?
Else we are going to call the answer.
Is incorrect function, all right, so we know that we should call this function.
So why do we want to call these functions?
Because because each of these functions is responsible for providing this box with a different color.
So answer is correct.
Is going to change the background of that box to green and answer is incorrect, is going to change
the background of that box to red.
So now let's go ahead and let's say the answer is correct function.
Let's create this function, let's say function answer is correct.
And sir is correct.
All right, so what do we want to do, we want to grab that element, so we are going to say document
dot, get element by I.D. and I'm going to tell you why.
Get Element by Biden.
And in here, I'm going to pass on the active question.
Dot styled, dot background color.
Where is the background color and let's change it to very solid green, so why not go and buy it?
If you remember correctly, this is where we created those 10 boxes.
They have a class of progress box which we styled and see assess, which should be right here.
This is that.
And they have an I.D., which is a number.
Now, the number of that IED starts from zero, goes all the way to question index less than the last
question or equal to it, and then it increments it by one.
All right, so if the last question is, for example, of course, the last question is nine or eight,
it has an index of nine, which we have created right here.
Last question.
It was the first necessary variable that we created.
So it is nine.
So first off, the question index is going to have a value of zero.
Then this condition is going to run, which is true, and then this code is going to run.
So when this code runs inside this IED, we are going to pass and what we are just going to pass in
zero.
So the idea of this entire thing is going to be zero.
All right.
And this is a div.
So what we do here is we say that we want to find an element whose ID is the active question.
And whenever we are talking about the first progress box, it means that we are talking about the first
active question, because if I come here, the active question by default has a value of zero.
And then we increment that active question right here.
We get the active question in here, which is zero.
All right.
And let's come down here.
Where is the active question?
Where else we have?
We used it.
So last question, active question is going to be zero, we we set the active question to be the index
of the array items inside the questions, right.
So let's just highlighted and check for it.
I'm just going to do this.
And here is the active question, the correct answer.
All right.
And then we get the active question that started that background color green.
Right.
And we are going to do the same thing for answer is incorrect.
And sir is incorrect, so let's call that function and let's create the function answer is incorrect,
and when the answer is incorrect, we simply change it back to read.
Let's save it.
Let's check it out.
So if I click if I click on this, this is red because of course, 150 is incorrect.
The correct is 100 and now it is red.
Sorry, it is green.
So red, red, green, red, green, red, green.
All right.
Now there are a lot of a lot more things that are still remaining.
Right.
And we are going to do them in like one after the other.
So for example, whenever we click on either the correct answer or they're incorrect answer, we want
to go to the next question.
And the next question is going to be a function that we have not created yet.
So what I'm going to do is to be able for us, for our active question to make even more sense.
We are going to go to our next lecture in which I'm going to create finally the next question function,
which is going to like some everything to like it is going to summarize everything that we have done
so far.
Well, not everything like 95 percent of what we have done so far is based put on the shoulders of the
next question.
See you guys in the next lecture.