Hi, everyone.
In this letter, we are going to write the algorithm for the eye of this game.
All right, so I'm going to try to wrap this game up in this lecture so it might become like a longer
lecture than than usual.
So let's see the first things that I would like to do as I'm going to I've come here to this new game
function.
All right.
And.
All right, before going that, I've come to this click function and we have said that if it is not
the player's turn, the other player should not be able to click.
And if that's why we have returned from this.
And the other thing that I would like to do is, all right, so I would like to come down, let's see
where I would like to go.
I just want to get rid of that selection.
So let's go to the highlight grid, which is the highlight grid.
So Selex, this is draw text, this is drug read, this is the create create Kleck.
Oh, there it is.
And I want to return from this as well.
If it is not the player's turn or the game is over.
Just returned from that.
We do not want to highlight the crit.
So you can see that it is not my turn.
That's why you can see you can't see any highlighting.
No, not my turn.
Not it's not my turn, and now it is my turn.
It only highlights when it is my turn right.
It is the Eastern and when I click, you can see nothing else is being highlighted because now it is
the computer's turn.
OK, so what we are going to do is we are going to code the computer and in this lecture and I'm going
to name it the go A.I. or I think that makes more sense.
So let's come here, I'm going to go to a game loop, where is the game loop?
There it is.
This is the game loop.
And right here I'm going to say I and I'm going to create an R and I function.
It gives me a text.
I'm going to say just I.
And inside here, I'm going to pass an hour time difference.
Right, so now let's go ahead and let's actually create this EHI.
All right, and I'm going to go down here, so where is our let's see where I do I want to put this.
Or should I put this function, doesn't really matter, just going to go ahead and select cells on top
of these, so I'm just going to put in the A.I. function.
Perfect.
So let's create this function.
So let's say function A.I. and this is going to take in a difference as a parameter.
And in here, first stuff we need to check if if it is the player's turn or if it is the game over.
We do not want to run anything.
So if it is the player's turn, it means it is the our eyes turn we or if it is the if game is over,
we want to return from this function.
That is the first thing that we want to do.
Now, first off, let's go ahead and let's put in a comment here.
So I'm going to say count down, I'm going to create a countdown and this is going to be the delay.
DeLay the A.I. until it makes a selection, it makes its selection.
It's sort of like we we want the A.I. to think for like half a second or four, like less than that.
And then we want it to, like, actually return something to actually, like make its its selection.
So I'm going to say if.
The I'm going to call this time is greater than zero.
We are going to say time, a time I is we are going to reduce from that or subtract from it.
The time difference that we have.
So in this case, it is the parameter of difference.
Right now, if the time I want of my writing, if the time I.
Is less than or equal to zero.
So it is equal to zero.
We want the A.I. to make it smooth, so we are going to call these select cell function and right after
that we are going to return from this investment return.
We don't want this if statement to do anything else and we will be actually returning from the function
as well.
So we just want to return.
The next thing that I would like to do as.
Huh?
All right, I want to create that time for our A.I..
All right, so let's go to the top.
Let's create the time delay.
So if I come here, it doesn't really matter where I put it, I'm just going to put it here and I'm
going to call this.
Delaying the Ehi, so delay underscore ehi and we are going to set it.
So I want to, I want the AI to be delayed by half a second and I'm going to put in a comment for this
as well.
So it's going to be seconds for the AI to make or to take its turn to take its turn right.
So now let's go ahead and let's actually code the A.I..
OK, so what do we have here?
So I'm going to go to the ice function, where is the ice function?
It was, I think, down below.
So where is the iSelect cell?
This is the kaleck.
I kind of actually lost it, so I'm just going to search for it.
I am going to search for it, I.
Come on, ay, ay.
So it is there and right after it is right, it's right there.
OK, so.
What do we want?
What do I want to do here first?
First off, I want to check for the I want to highlight the selected cell.
So before actually making its choice, the eye has to highlight the cell.
So I'm going to say highlight the selected cell.
Basically, the way that we are coding this is as if it was an actual human.
So for that, we are going to call the highlights cell function.
The highlights of function is going to grab the X position and the Y position.
The X position is going to be the great zero row because it can select the first row first and the column
could be any column it could select from any column.
And we are going to pass in the center X, we are going to do the same thing, but for the center Y
so grid.
Come on.
What am I right in here?
I'm getting tired, so I'm putting it at the.
It can select only from the first row at first and it can select from any column that it want and the
set and the position for that is going to be the center.
Why?
OK, so this is the first thing that we are going to do for the.
The next thing that I want to do is I want to actually go ahead and set up the algorithm.
So for this, I'm going to create a different comment and I'm going to say setting up the AI.
Algorithm.
All right, so let's go ahead and set up the algorithm, the first part of the algorithm is going to
be creating the an options array for the A.I. So what are the options of this A.I.?
So I'm going to say creating the options array.
So there are actually going to be four options, so I'm just going to say options, right?
And I'm going to initialize it as an empty array.
And then so the first option that the A's going to have.
So this is going to be the item zero in that array.
I'm going to put it to.
We are going to put all of them to empty arrays.
The first option is when the A.I. wins.
Right, this I'm just going to copy, you know, what this is like takes a lot of time to write it out.
I'm just going to put it here.
The second item inside that array is going to be the second option the A.I. has.
The second option is going to be just block the player.
I'm just going to put in block the r.i.
This is the second option for the A.I..
The third option, the third option for the eye is whenever the eye makes, well, not an important
move.
For example, I'm selecting a cell important and the eyes casually selecting a cell, and that's really
not that big of a deal.
The fourth option is actually as is an important option.
And this is when the eye.
Yeah.
Lets the r.i win.
I mean, it cannot actually block the r.i and it cannot make a significant move and it cannot win.
So the final option is to let the RIAA win.
OK, so in the second it blocks the DRC, it makes not an not an important move and then it lets the
DRC win.
All right, so.
What I'm going to do down below is I'm going to say randomly select a column.
In a in a priority order, in a priority order.
OK, so let's say let's first initialize our column and we're going to say if if options.
The first, if it is the first option that the ATO has and the length in that option is great and that
options array is greater than zero, it means that the AIA is making his first move.
We're going to say that the column could be, whichever it is that the AIU, whichever that the AIA
wants to choose.
All right.
And whichever is going to be actually a random number.
So we are going to say that the options, the first item can be any number.
So we are going to use the math, that floor, the math, that floor is going to give us a whole integer.
And this random is going to take a look at any random column.
And select it now, we need to multiply it by the options length and whichever the options length is
that which is going to be like only one.
So the eye can only select one of the columns at one time.
All right.
So we need to multiply it by the length as well.
So we need to tell the eye that you can only Celenk select one one length one of the options or one
of the columns.
So the columns that the eye select is going to be pushed inside this.
The first option that we have and we are going to get a a whole integer by saying that floor and made
that random is going to be a random column, and then we are going to multiply it by the length.
All right.
So we're going to say l f.
al-Assaf, basically, it's going to be the same thing, but for the second one, so I'm just going
to pass it right here and the length stretch.
Make sure you do not misspell anything for the second one.
We go do the second option, which is it blocks the dry.
If it blocks the right, what it should do.
I'm going to grab that column.
I'm going to put it right here.
It is going to the column should be whichever column that the eight blocks.
All right, so the rest of the Ellsworth's are going to be almost the same, so I'm going to put it
there.
So I'm just going to grab these and I'm going to put it to two and.
Right.
Where is the curly brace?
There it is.
So this is the Ancef, and for that we need a curly brace as well.
So this is zero.
This is one.
This says this Ancef is one, this else if is to and finally this LGF is going to be three.
So now we have we have taught the A.I. to randomly select a column in a priority order.
The next thing that I would like to do here is I want to loop through each of the columns to check for
a win.
Right.
Based on the priorities on I'm going to say loop through.
Though through.
Each column, each column.
So let's say we have a variable of sell and we are going to say four let I equals zero.
I is less than the grade columns.
I is less than the number of columns.
And each time we are going to increment the design, so we are going to say sell is equal to the highlights
of functions and now we need to pass in the actual position for that.
We have done that right here.
So I'm just going to copy.
This is going to be a bit different.
I do not want to type that out.
So the column is going to be I because the ace is we are looping through the columns.
I'm just going to pass and put it in there as well.
So if the column is full.
The I should go to the next column.
Right.
That's why we are looping over that, of course, if a cell is equal to now, if there is no cell,
we want the A.I. to continue.
With its search.
And continue in this case means it means I'm not going to write it.
It means that the A.I. is going to break out of this iteration of this, the first iteration, and then
it is going to go to the next iteration.
Right.
Right after that, we are going to say so the first priority, what was the first priority?
When the A.I. wins, perfect, so when the AI wins, it means that the owner of the cell, so cell owner
is going to be the player's turn.
Perfect it is.
Now, keep in mind that whenever we're using this player's turn, we're actually talking about in some
contexts we talk about whenever, for example, where is the player's turn if I come down here?
In this context, the player turned could be either Ehi or R.I or was what is the other context that
we talked about?
So if I come here.
No, not there.
This is the EHI function.
I'm going to show you a context in which the player's turn is actually the the, our eyes turn.
It's never going to be the eyes turn in this context.
It's still if it is going to be either the ah I ordered the eye.
So in which context can we find that they're here.
So this highlight great function, it says that if it is the players, if it is not the player's turn
or if the game is true, then return.
It means that in this context the player's turn is going to be the turn for the are I not I.
So we are using this term interchangeably depending on the context that we have.
So in this case, it is going to be I'm just going to write, I turn so so you understand really what's
happening.
So in here, what we need to do is we need to check for a win.
So I'm going to say check when Chegwidden is going to grab the cell, the and the column.
So I'm going to say cell row and cell dot com.
When we check for that, what do we want to do, because this is the first priority, we are going to
grab the first item and we are going to push this loop variable to that.
And we are going to say Owles.
This is going to be the second priority, second priority, and that is I blocks the hour, I am just
going to put in r.i in this case the cells owner is not DCI, so it is not player's turn.
It means that the cells owner is.
Are I right.
So it is the cells owner is r.i.
And we are going to check if the check when function, lets pass the arguments there, so sell dot roll
and sell dot com.
We are going to push to the second option.
Right.
So options, let's grab the second item and we are going to push Bush to that.
The I the loof variable.
And then inside of here, we are going to say alse, if sell that owner, if soldat owner is the player's
turn as the players turn.
What do we want to do that we want to check the cell above, right, so I'm going to say check the cell
above.
If there is no cell underneath the air, I can select the above cell.
So we are going to say if cell Dutrow is greater than zero, it means the bottom row has been the bottom
row of the cell has been felt.
We need this to go up one level.
All right, but we need to check if that is which, if that is the ice turn or not, we need to check
for that as well.
So we are going to say if cell when row minus one.
We are going to go one level up and these cells call them.
That owner is not the player's turn.
It's not the player's turn.
And so this is going to be we are checking for the above self and and now let's go ahead and check for
our fourth priority.
Now, you can see that all these if statements are being nested here.
So you have to keep that in mind as well.
So I'm going to say fourth priority.
This is a bit complicated.
I know.
And that's what I meant, that this is going to be JavaScript advanced to expert if you're not feeling
comfortable with any of these concepts, the array pushing to that, the last item, negative one,
you could you have to go back to those chapters and you have to polish your knowledge.
All right.
So we are going to say, do not let the player one, let the player right now in the fourth priority,
the A.I. gives a when, but we don't.
We are telling it, do not do it.
All right.
So we are going to grab the check one function one more time.
And we are going to sell Dutrow minus one for the this is going to be the row and the column is going
to be Soldat column.
We are basically grabbing the wrong column from there.
And now we are going to push to the fourth array, push the eye to the fourth array.
And finally, after this statement, we are going to pass in our alts and that is going to be the third
priority.
Now, the third priority is when the A.I. makes not an important move, when it makes not an important
move.
And we are going to say else.
Anything in any other scenario, just push it to the third options array.
All right, so and finally, what after it does all of these calculations, what I want to do is I want
the I want to deselect all these cells, right?
Because whenever the A.I. selects one cell, I want to deselect any cell that the IAEA has not selected.
So let's grab the cell, Dutrow.
If we do not deselected, then with one selection, the air will be able to select all of these cells
and that is not something that we want.
So that honor is equal to.
No, we just say that I'm just going to put in a common deselect the cell above.
Above.
Right, right after that.
OK, I just want to put in this here as well, if there is no Rosabeth, if there is no rule above,
it means that the column has filled up.
We are going to go to our third priority priority, which is not making an important move.
So if there is no cell in that row, sorry, if there is no cell in that column, it could go to either
of the other columns.
So it's not that big of a deal.
We're going to say else options.
So we are going to push it to the second to the third array.
And once the aid is done, we are going to cancel the highlight and this election, so we are going
to say cancel the highlight and this election.
All right and OK, so we are going to grab these soldat that highlight, so where is the highlight cell
that highlighted should be no cell darte owner should be.
No.
And finally, the final piece of this game is going to be we need to clear the winning cells whenever
we click there for the next iteration, for the next time that the request animation frames comes.
And we need to clear that.
So I'm just going to say clear.
Clear the.
The winning sells.
Right, and this is going to be the end of the game, so for that row of gret for Lietzau of a row,
all of them are going to sell Dot Wener is going to be equal to.
So now hopefully this is completed and we are finally able to play this game.
So let's go ahead and let's actually play this, we can see that it says four hundred and thirty we
have we are missing a bracket, so 430, whereas line for 30.
Oh, else there is a typo there.
Center X cannot re type error for sixty.
So we do have some typos there.
So if I go to four sixty we have highlights.
So grid zero column and center X and center Y.
Why is it throwing an error there should not throw an error there?
OK, so it's hmm, we have our we are getting our DNA.
That's correct.
The highlight highlights cell function we have called the highlight cell function and we are getting
the we are getting our grid the column from the grid and the center X, also the grid center of why.
I mean, is there something wrong with the highlights?
It says that there is 460 and let's play game 111.
Let's go to line 100 and 11.
And a time difference.
One, when when oh, this is when the function was called, right?
So.
Hmm.
Now, before actually solving that problem, what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to this, I remember
that we created a delay for the A.I. and that was half a second, but we never used it.
So we can see if I just control D there is no other we have not actually used.
So if I come to four hundred, were the A.I. functions at the end of this, I'm just going to call the
time I is going to be equal to the delay I.
The delay, not delay, noad delay, so let's save it.
Let's come here, and it is still saying that there is a problem there.
We have successfully specified that there.
OK, do we have that problem here?
That's network.
This is the council.
We don't have that problem here.
So let's take a look at that.
So what I'm going to do actually here is I'm going to collapse first all of these functions that we
have created.
I think there is something wrong with the order of these functions, because I believe that we have
used the highlights.
So before the syntax is familiar, let's see where we have used it.
OK, I'm just collapsing them.
I'm looking for the highlights, so.
And we have used the highlight cell here, and you can see that it doesn't throw an error.
For that, we had this is the function itself.
This is going to be the connect for and this is the check when this is the game loop.
I'm not going to touch the game loop that's collapsed.
This one collapsed the set dimensions.
So the way that I'm going to reorder this is I'm going to first put our check one function, then the
connect for then I'm going to grab the kaleck, I'm going to cut it.
And right after the connect for I'm going to put in the click.
And right after the break, we are going to put in the create grid, you know what, actually these
are the highlights cell and highlight grid.
I'm just going to cut this from right here and I'm going to put them after the EHI.
So after the I'm just going to put them right here.
So I'm just going to come in this one collapse.
That collapse, this one.
So we have after the click, what do we have.
So I'm just going to remove the space.
Remove the space after the click.
We have the create.
Great.
I'm just going to cut this one as well.
The create grid.
Then we have the drawback ground.
Draw a grid, draw text A.I. and highlight cell highlight grid.
Right after the highlight grid.
I'm going to put in the new game function and then we have our select cell and said dimensions.
So let's save it.
Now you can see that the error was basically just we had to reorder some things.
Why is it coming back?
OK, so.
OK, there we go.
So I'm just going to you know what, I'm just going to close this.
Do we have that same order for this?
No, we don't.
So I'm just going to go ahead and open this one live server one more time and we still get that error
and I have no idea why do we get that error?
411.
So it says that cannot read property of this highlight, sell a grid zero column is going to be zero
that Senator X and Grid zero column that Senator Y kind of read this.
And I actually I have no idea why is this happening.
All right, so on this on second thought, I would like to try to debug this error using this sources,
using the call stack.
We have talked about this, but we have not really used it in a real world scenario.
So this is a good use case for the call stack.
And you can see that the error is right here.
And it says uncute type error cannot read property of undefined.
So it means that it's a type error.
It means that we have certainly mis typed something.
So if I click here, you can see that we have created a brand new breakpoint and after I collect, I'm
just going to go ahead and I'm going to reload the page.
And you can see that we get all these things here, that all these calculations based on this highlight
grid.
And you can see that it says column is undefined.
This is undefined, undefined, undefined, undefined.
So all of these are undefined.
The computer is doing nothing.
So if I come to the play game, which is this right here, we don't have any errors here.
But you can see that we have all of our calculations inside here.
But now what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to the A.I. itself.
And in here we can see that we have all these undefined.
So the cell is undefined, even though if I am if I am right, we have we have defined the cell.
You can see it is going to say that it is paused inside debugger.
Right.
But that doesn't matter.
We have specified the cell to to this.
So it says the cell is undefined and.
What is this?
We have said that the cells should be equal to the highlights, so this is I mean, this is if I change
it to an equal sign into a cell minus the highlight, it means that we have never actually defined our
cell.
So now if I put it back there and.
Let me go ahead.
Let me come down here.
Let's grab this, reload the page.
Let's grab it.
And I'm going to go ahead and reload the page.
We should see all the errors.
It's reloaded one more time.
Let's actually click and reload and.
Come on, show it to me.
So this is where the error was.
Perfect.
So we don't see the errors anymore, even though this is incorrect.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go out of it.
We can see our error was gone.
So I'm just going to go ahead and still says undefined.
I'm just going to reload.
And you can see it automatically comes to where I was before.
So now I can see that this cell the problem is that this cell is undefined, even though.
We have we have declared the cell, we have initialized it, and we this is actually a declaration,
we declared it, but we didn't initialize it.
So in here we we did initialize it to this value.
So instead of that, if I just put in a plus sign soon here you can see that it is negative.
This was a basic typo, if I put it to that.
And if I refresh this page, we shouldn't see any errors here.
Now you can see that the cell actually has a value.
This is the left.
This is the right.
This is all the computer that the computer is actually calculating this.
So this is our algorithm kicking into motion.
So the cell, all of them, because it's not doing any move, it's actually doing that.
So I'm going to reload the page.
This is our project.
Let's remove that.
Let's play against this computer.
And I could play it in this lecture or I could play it in the next one.
But what I'm going to do, actually, is I'm going to play like for a minute or two with the computer
and this lecture and we are going to wrap this entire project up.
I'm sorry for that.
But actually I'm not, because that actually showed us how we can debug our code, using the console,
using the sources and using the call stack.
It was it the sources think it was sources.
Yeah, using the sources and the call stack, so the FBI makes that move, I'm just going to create
a one there.
I'm going to create one here.
You can see that these are insignificant moves by the A.I. So the because this roll was felt, the moved
to another one and the air's trying to block me.
Just going to put one there and I'm going to put one here, the air is going for two.
And so either this one or that one, I'm going to block the A.I. So I'm going to block it there as well.
Let's see who wins.
All right.
I'm going to put.
So I'm going to put one here, the I put.
OK, so if I if I don't put it there is going to block me there.
So they just locked me here.
I'm just going to block it here and all right, I'm going to block the oh, the computer one to see
the Iowa.
So now let's play it again.
I'm going to try to win against the EHI.
Uh huh.
Hmm.
Oh, okay, so now if I put it right here, the eye puts it there.
Let's place it here and let's try to actually win.
OK, so is there any four in a row you can see that the air is making significant moves, it is blocking
me and it is making an insignificant move and it is actually trying to win.
Uh, no one is the one well, I give that three, so it's OK.
So if I put one here, there's going to score, I'm not going to do it.
So this is going to stand.
Hmm, that's on here.
Let's put it here, this is going to put it there.
That's place one dot there.
And we are going to see eventually who is going to put one here.
So let's do that.
Let me try to put one here.
And.
You can see that the air had to put one here and now I blocked it there and I'm going to put one right
here.
It doesn't matter if there are three, you have to connect four.
So if I put.
One right here.
They are.
There and you can see the blocked me again here.
And that's, you know, this place there and then here it's now you can see it says so it's good we
checked for that as well.
So let's check for this.
Let's put one here and now.
If I put one here, I'm going to win from the air.
So the I block me there, but they cannot block me here.
That's the only case that you're going to beat this year.
So it's a pretty powerful I know it is my turn.
And when it is my turn, the I cannot when they cannot take and make a move and when it is very stern,
I cannot make a move.
And the only thing that I want to check for is, for example, going to let the I win.
So just go ahead and put forward their.
And the air one can see the selection doesn't work, so that's it for this project and for this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.