Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to reset the ball to start from the center.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is if if our ball goes off the R.I side, it means that the A.I. has scored
and the score should increase by one.
If the ball goes off the ice side, it means that the RBA has scored and this zero should should should
be incremented by one.
We just want incremented by one.
We also want to add the audio as well.
And also whenever any of the players they score the ball should be reset, it means it should start
from the center.
So let's do that.
And I'm going to say updating the scores.
First off, let's update the scores.
And for that, we need we need if statements.
Of course, if the ball ball's exposition is less than zero, it means that it has gone off the left
side of the screen.
What is the left side of the screen assigned to its assigned to the arrow.
But we need to account for the radius as well.
So I'm just going to say Baldor radius, we need to account for the radius as well.
If it goes the left side of the screen, it means that the A.I. has scored.
See, so the AI scores are scored and we need to grab the paddle player and sorry, the player paddle
player paddle away.
And from there we are going to grab the score and we are going to incremented by one and we are going
to grab the ice core idea and we are going to play it as well.
And when the ice cores, we want to reset the ball to start from the center.
Now, what is the elusive.
al-Assaf now al-assaf the ball dot, the exposition of the ball is greater than the canvases with canvas
element with it means that the ball has gone off the right side of the screen.
If it goes off the right side of the screen, the right side of the screen is associated with the player
ehi.
It means that the player r.i has scored so the player.
I couldn't catch it.
So it was score.
Right and we need to accommodate for the radius as well.
So I'm just going to say Baudot radius.
All right, and what do we want to do that when the our eyes cause we we can say that they are I scored
when it goes off the left side, the way I scored the right side, I scored very simple logic.
So we are going to say player Padel, our idot score just incremented by one.
We are going to play the r.i score ordeal and we are going to call in our reset ball function now to
be able to create the reset ball function.
What I'm going to do as I'm going to come on top of everything manager and I'm going to say the reset
ball function function perfect.
So function reset ball, there are going to be any parameters basically we just want to reset the ball.
What are what is it that we want to reset the ball.
The first thing that we want to reset the ball, ask the ball is X and Y position.
So ball dot exposition should be canvas elements with divided by two.
That's exactly what we did before.
Right.
So what about the Y position?
The Y position should be the canvas where Kanavis elements high divided by two.
Also, I'm going to reset the speed so the speed is going to be reset.
So originally I'm going to just collapse this.
Uh huh.
OK, so it's the run game, so originally we can see that the ball has a speed of 10.
So whenever we reset it, we should reset it to that speed of ten, because when the players they're
playing, the speed increases.
And when one score is the speed, the speed, the speed, the speed should start again at that's that
point.
And I'm going to save that.
And let's come here.
Let's check this one out.
So I'm going to increase the audio.
So we do.
There we go, it bounces back, I'm going to play for like a couple of minutes, so either so there
we go, it's scored and now we can see that when it when when the when computer scores, the ball is
coming towards me and let me score.
So let's see where the ball is going to go.
OK.
You can see that the ball is getting speed.
OK, and the audio is working perfectly fine.
Oh, boy.
There we go.
That was a mistake I wanted to do like a hard angle, but it didn't work, so I'm not going to do anything
fancy again.
So let's see.
Boom, there we go.
Well, the only way that I can beat the computer is just to wait until this the speed of the ball increases,
there is no other way of beating it.
It doesn't matter how.
What is the angle that you hit it with?
It's always going to get there.
That was a straight line, by the way.
There we go when tensions at the top, it's going to go at an angle of 45 degrees, it should come right
there.
OK, come on.
I know the speed is slow, you could go faster, but and now the speed is getting faster.
I'm going to give it like try to give it a hard angle.
Come on.
Not that good.
Maybe like 30 degrees.
That was 30 degrees.
Let's do more.
Ah, right.
Oh, come on, man.
So anyway, what I'm going to do is I'm going to come in here, I'm going to set the speed.
The speed, let's set it to 15 and I'm going to reset the speed whenever it happens, I'm going to set
it to 15.
So if I save it whenever one hits it, it's going to go 50.
So you can see how fast it is.
OK.
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Let me score one.
There we go.
So either of the players who score it is going to go to the next player.
It's just going to the computer.
So whichever player scores, the other player gets to start with the next one.
And you can see that now the A.I. is not strong and is not powerful enough to get the ball.
It is just moving in that direction.
See, the AA is not powerful enough.
See, there is not it cannot even get to there, but let's say for the sake of fun, I'm just going
to increase the ICE intelligence level.
Intelligence, I'm going to put it to zero point four, let's save it, let's see.
Now, let's check check this out.
S..
The area is getting it, it's trying to get it at the middle of the ball, so it was going to get it
at the middle.
So it's adjusting its metal there we go to for the eye and I'm going to increase the intelligence level.
You cannot score now, I mean, you should be, like, really expert to score against this, I, I could
increase it to point seven and now and I'm going to increase the speed to thirty.
I'm sure I cannot keep up, but just for fun.
So I'm going to increase this to 30.
Let's save it.
Oh, boy, oh, boy, see, the eye keeps keeps going.
Yeah, there we go.
I cannot even follow it with my eyes.
All right, there we go.
There we see the eyes getting it, you cannot score now.
That's why we need to dumb it down.
So I'm going to set this speed to seven.
The reset speed is going to be seven as well.
And the intelligence level better be one, only a 10 percent capacity.
If you set it to even like above four or five, you will never be able to beat the eye.
So with this, our logic comes to an end.
And I think we are done here.
And this was fun.
I know it was a longer project than usual, but creating is was creating.
It was a lot of fun.
Even more fun was teaching it.
And I hope you learned a lot.
And at the end, I just want to grab this and I want to I'm just going to decrease the volume.
I'm going to put it right here in case you want to learn more about it.
It's going to sound cosine and all of that.
So go ahead and play with this.
Play with the code, play with different levels, different speeds, different paddle with and height.
So you really, really get the idea of how this game is created and see you guys in the next one.