Hi, everyone, this lecture we're going to talk about the object keys method.
All right, so the Object Keys method is going to return all of the keys from an object.
So this is an object specific method.
So now let's go ahead and let's see what we're going to do as we are going to create an element, create
a variable, not an element.
And we're going to call it Kei's because in here, here is where we are going to save all of our kids
now to grab all of the keys from any object we call the object d'art keys.
All right.
And we passing the object name that we have.
So the object name is FAF Colors.
Right.
And now let's go ahead and let's say cancel the lock keys and we should be able to get all the keys
and notice that it returns all of them inside an array.
All right.
So we can access each of these keys individually as well through a for each loop.
So we are going to say keys dot foreach first stuff.
We grabbed all the keys of this object and we started inside this keys, which returns an array, even
though the keys, they belong to an object.
But when you extract him from the object, they're going to be returned in an array because arrays are
so, so useful.
All right.
So and then we are going we can call the array for each method because it is an array.
So what are we going to do as I'm going to create the parameter and I'm going to call it key and we
are going to run this function.
Now, what is the function is going to do?
The function is simply going to log to the console our key.
And when I say that, we can see that we have caller one, we have color, too, and we have color three
that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.