Hi, everyone, this lecture, I want to remove a bug in the responsiveness of this game.
All right, so you might have noticed that whenever whenever you go to inspect and so let's say let's
go to the responsiveness part and let's, for example, make this window big.
So at some point you can see that the game is responsive and it is reacting very well.
But if I decrease it, for example, like let's reload it, you can see that below 718, it is going
to it is going to be buggy.
But when I decrease the with the height, it is going to go back and now I'm just going to go ahead
and decrease it.
So whenever.
So let's go ahead and increase the whenever the width is going to be decreased less than the width of
the game that we can see.
You can see that we have this kind of problem.
The reason for that is that we have in the create grid function where I have by mistake, I have multiplied
the width with the margin, but we need to subtract the margin on both sides from the width.
So if I save it now and if I come here, you can see that the game goes back.
So it doesn't matter what the screen size is, you can still you can play the game.
For example, this is an iPhone six, seven, eight.
I know these are pretty outdated devices, but this is the list that I have.
So iPhone six, seven, eight plus.
So you can play the game against the computer.
All right, and it is going to be working fine, so I'm just going to go ahead and play that for a while.
So I'm going to put one here and I'm going to put one right here.
OK, so let's put one there and human one perfect, so it works with that.
It is.
It should work with the iPhone X, just going to reload that page so it adjusts itself.
iPad, perfect, iPad pro very well.
And Surface duo and everything seems to be working perfectly fine.
Just go ahead.
And just that with minus margin with the Times margin that was actually minus margin.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.