Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to fix a small bog in the angled determination for the paddle.
All right, so our application has been effectively completed, but after I played this game, I found
out that there is actually a bug in our application and you can see that whenever the A.I. hits it towards
the top of the paddle instead of the ball going to the top of the screen you just saw it came towards
the bottom of the screen.
The case should be whenever the ice paddle hits it towards the bottom of the paddle, then it should
come down and toward the top of the paddle.
It should go up.
I'm just going to redo this so you can see.
So now you can see it came down, but the ball has to go up.
So bottom of the paddle ball moves towards the top and at an angle of 45 degrees or it is going to try
to move at that angle and bottom of the paddle.
The ball should move towards the bottom of the screen at at an angle like that.
Like this one.
So the our eyes paddle is OK, but the ice paddle clearly has a problem.
So what I'm going to do is this is where we have determined the direction.
So this is the velocity and this is the way velocity.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to grab the direction and I'm going to remove it from the Y velocity.
And now let's go ahead and check it out.
There we go.
Now I can see that the ball moved towards the top, moved, and this one also moves towards the top.
So let me just take a look at the eye to head towards the bottom of the paddle.
Let's see what the is going to do there, it is going to headed towards the top as well and let's make
sure it does headed there.
There we go, and it came down so that problem is solved.
The other thing that I would like to do here is I forgot to add some Borodai here.
So for this, I'm just going to grab the radius of the ball and I'm going to add it to the direction.
And I'm just going to go ahead and clean up the code a little and I'm going to grab the the collision
point and then I'm going to then grab it out of the parentheses and then multiplied with that.
And let's see.
So what else do we have here in here?
I'm going to add the ball radius as well.
All right.
So I'm just going to say ball dot radius.
Let's save it.
Let's check it out here.
I'm just going to reload the page.
I'm going to increase the volume, and I'm going to play for like a couple of minutes just to make sure
that there are no further bugs here.
All right.
So let's see.
OK, so the angle for the arrows paddle is perfect and as well as the ice paddle, let's leave that
to the score is working perfectly fine.
Perfect.
I'm going to try to get it to headed toward the bottom of the paddle.
There we go, it is coming towards the bottom and this is coming towards the bottom as well as well,
this is going to go top.
There we go.
So this is a more realistic kind of scenario that we have here.
And the speed is going to increase gradually.
There we go.
And I'm going to try to score like at least one against the sky.
And then I'm going to wrap up this video as well.
I just want to take I just want to look for any other bugs that we might end up having now before actually
doing that.
I'm just going to go into a console and I'm going to take a look at the console as well.
We don't have any error here, so that's a good thing.
Now, let's go ahead and score one against this A.I., at least one.
All right, so I have to wait for, like a few rounds of this ball, like the ball should travel for
for some time until the ball speed is going to increase.
And then we will be able to basically score against this EHI.
And if you feel like this is like dumb and stupid and you want to, like, increase the intelligence
level, you can go ahead and do that, but make sure to never put it at one, because that way it is
not going to be fun at all and you're going to lose all the time.
So my suggestion is never increase said do not increase it.
Be on point four.
I mean, point point four is going to be pretty advanced as well.
But still, you might have a chance of winning.
There we go, the bone speed is increasing and.
And we should be able to score something against this guy that was close.
There we go.
I can see it travels in a straight line when it hits it in the center and then forty five degrees.
The ball speed is gradually increasing, so this is a game whenever you're playing a game, of course,
you want to take your time, right.
And you want to enjoy that.
Now, it is pretty visible that this bull is fast, faster than before.
I know it is taking some time, but the good thing is that whenever you play any game that you create,
you'll be able to understand, OK, what are the issues that are going to arise when you, for example,
you apply or deploy that game to the Internet and the users, they're actually going to go ahead and
play that game.
OK, so the ball is pretty fast now I'm trying I'm going to try to keep up with the speed of the ball,
not to give away any point.
There we go, there is another one, so let's wait for it until it gets to seven.
So now you can see that this is basically well, it is it cannot do anything else.
So that's why my suggestion is that if you increase the I'm just going to mute it.
It's very irritating.
So my suggestion is that if you want to increase the intelligence level, go ahead and increase it to
four or maybe like 2.5 or three, then you are going to have a good time.
That's why I've used it as an independent variable, because I want you guys to have control over this
game.
So if you want to increase the intelligence level, decrease it, that is going to be based on your
own choice.
Everyone is different.
Some some people like to play it really, really difficult.
Some people like myself like to play it lazy.
So that's it for this application.
See you guys in the next one.