Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to talk about prototypes and prototype of class.
All right, so before diving into prototypes, I just want to talk about instant's and instantiating.
All right.
So, for example, let's say we have a class of workshop workshop.
Right.
And in here, let's say we have let's just say we have a funt a function that is ASC and it is going
to get a question.
It is going to get questioned as a parameter and it is going to do something.
I'm just going to right here do something right.
It doesn't matter what it does.
What matters is that we have a class of workshop right now.
What is an instance now?
An instance is when an instance is something that is created by the new keyword.
Right, so the new if I were to say new workshop.
And open and close parentheses, this would mean that this is an instance of the workshop class right
now, what is this instance?
This instance is actually an object we know because we have talked about.
Right.
So.
This object is an empty object that can grab the its of its properties and its methods, it can copy
them or it can link the properties and methods from the workshop class itself.
Right.
So it can copy the features of the workshop class.
All right.
So the new keyword is actually what's instantiating the class in JavaScript?
All right, and this entire thing is called an instance, I'm just going to write an instance of the
class work of the workshop class or workshop class just like this.
This is an instance of the workshop class and what is instantiating a workshop class that is the new
operator.
I just I just wanted to talk about this.
So this thing is instantiating this thing.
And this entire thing is called an instance of a workshop class.
It is an instance of anything that has been created there.
So if this were to be like anything else, for example, get posts or a like like post images, whatever,
whatever this class is, this is an instance of that class.
OK, this is just an example here.
So I'm just going to comment this one out and we are going to come in here and I'm just going to come
and this back end.
All right.
So we have talked about this sugar layer in our previous lectures.
We know what the syntactic sugar is and what is the extension beyond the syntactic sugar, which is
the super cure.
We know that.
We have talked about it and we know where we can use them and we know what the this key word is going
to point at because we know how the function is going to be called.
Now, this prototypes that we have used here, this is exactly the same as the class system that we
have used.
Right.
So this is called the like the layer underneath the sugar.
This this is what's actually happening.
OK, this is what the code will look like.
And you have to keep in mind that this is the old school way of doing a prototype or prototyping class.
And you can notice that we have a workshop function right here, OK, which is doing which is doing
the same thing as the class of the workshop class.
Right.
It has the same purpose as this constructor.
And then we start adding methods to this workshop by saying workshop that prototype that as soon here
we added it directly inside of it.
But here we just said that prototype that ask.
Right.
And we call the new operator right here on that on that specific function that we have created.
So you see some of the underpinnings of classes, but this is the system underneath and what's happening
in the class, sugar, it's not that you would really write this code anymore, because if you wanted
to do classes at all, you would almost certainly be using the class syntax.
You wouldn't write this prototypical code anymore.
But I think it is important for you to understand how this system actually works.
You have to understand what are what are what are the relationships, where are all these relationships
are coming from since they're not a copy paste operation, but they are a linkage operation?
OK, we need to understand how this code actually works.
The reason that we need to understand is because when the code breaks, we need to know why did it break?
Why did it do something different than we expected?
That's why we first we talked about the sugar layer, which was this classes, and now we are talking
about what makes up that class syntax.
And when we know both of them, we will be able to master object oriented programming and we will know
if if our code breaks, if there are bugs, we will know why.
Why are there bugs?
Right.
So what I'm going to do is we are just going to go ahead and I'm going to call the ask function.
On the jazz, and I'm going to call the ask function on Jank so we know that whenever we say new workshop,
this is an instance of the workshop class.
OK, so when we said this new operator, it instantiates.
Right, a class instance.
So if I were to say Jayce dot ask here we have this key word inside this anonymous function, we want
to know what did this key word is going to point out.
So I'm going to say just ask and I'm just going to pass and is a great teacher.
Right now, before saving this, before saving it and coming in here, we need to take a look at this
closely and we need to find out whether this key word is going to point it.
So in order to find out whether this key word is going to point out, we need to go to the call site.
So here we have a function, which is ask let's go and let's find where the concert is for this function,
it's right here.
And from the call side, we will understand, OK, what the this keyword is going to point out.
So the call cites says that this ask is actually being called on a gess object.
So we know that the new keyword is going to create a brand new object.
So this is our this is our implicit binding method, which is also called the context object.
All right.
So this is the context object.
And if I come and if I see what's inside this context object, we can see that it is a an instance of
the new of the workshop class or in this case, function that has Teddy inside of it.
Right.
As an argument.
So this study is going to be passed where you're right and I'm going to change this question to I'm
just going to change it to DC, DC.
I'm just going to say description.
Right.
The see.
All right.
So whenever we grab this right, it means that this is actually what the this keyword is going to be
pointing it.
So this teacher will actually be because Jesus is going to create a brand new object.
And inside of it, we are going to have a teacher.
Right.
This is where the teacher is coming from.
So this argument is going to be passed in here and then passed in here.
So this teacher is going to be a property of this new brand new object that we have.
All right.
And we know that this teacher is going to be referring to this teacher.
And when I say it, we are going to see that this study is a great teacher.
And if I come down here and say, concer log, let's take a look at the type of.
Type of J.S., we are going to see an object because this is an object and it is the same object that
links OK, people use people.
Some people say coppice, but because JavaScript doesn't do copy pasting, it actually links.
There is a linkage relationship.
So this object is actually linked to the constructor that is creating this right to the instance to
which it belongs.
What is the instance in this case?
It is the workshop class instance that this object belongs to.
In this case, this just belongs to this workshop function.
Right.
So this is not actually a copy paste relationship.
This is a linkage relationship.
Right.
So if I were to go ahead and do the same thing for Jianguo, I would say let's call the Aske function
right.
And I'm going to say it is also a great teacher.
Right.
And now here we have this teacher and here we have this keyword as well.
Now the this keyword of this workshop has been called.
This workshop has been called in here and in here.
But now we are talking about the Jianguo part.
So whenever I call the workshop here and now A and DeJohn John is an argument which is going to be passed
inside this parameter and then we are going to pass it inside whatever the function needs to do.
So this teacher is going to be John.
So we know what this teacher is going to be, because when we if we want to find out that this key word,
what it points out, we need to go to the call side.
This is the calcite or this doesn't really matter.
But because we are talking about Jianguo, so this is the calcite.
And when we called the ask function, they ask also has this key word, what it is pointing out, we
need to go to the call side, which is right here.
So it is it has been called on the Jango object.
So the Janger object has a workshop function in this in this case or class.
You could call it class, a workshop class.
And this workshop class says this DOT teacher equals Stojan so that this key word is going to point
to John.
So we are going to see John is also a great teacher.
If I were to say that we can see that John is also a great teacher.
And if I were to say.
What is the type of Django we're going to get an object as well?
So now we know how this prototype system works and when we know how the prototype system works, we
know how the class syntax works.
All right.
So this is going to be paid for the prototypes and prototype class, right?
See you guys in the next lecture.