Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about capture groups.
All right, so what are capital groups now, capital groups that allow us to group patterns that we
are looking for now in our first example in here?
What do we want to do?
Is that so let's let me go ahead and let's create the sentence.
So I'm just going to say book and I'm going to say book one more time on buck book.
And in this case, we are looking for the word book that appears to eyes in a stronger line, in this
case, strength.
And there is a space between the two occurrences of the word book.
Right.
So how would you use capture groups now, the syntax for a capture group and.
Well, I should provide our example.
So this is example 27.
All right.
And these are capture groups.
OK, so capital groups are just try this, the syntax for them is a parenthesis, a set of parentheses.
So I want to say I want to grab all of the characters, all of the characters.
Right.
And that have one or more occurrences, hence the plus.
And then we are going to say there is a space there.
Right.
So this cultural group is going to grab this book.
Then we have a space.
That's why I provided the space there.
And then what I want to do is I want to repeat this entire thing one more time.
That's why there is one.
This is not L, this is L, but this is actually the number one on the keyboard.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and let's now I've created it here.
Now, there are two ways that we can work with this.
The first one is we are going to test it.
So let me go ahead and create a regex test result.
So this is regular expression test and this should be capitalized test results.
And I'm going to grab a regular expression, number 27.
Right.
And we are going to test the sentence.
Sentence and after that, we are going to log it to the council, so if this pattern is correct, we
should be able to which we should, which we do not do.
We should we do it means that what does this actually mean?
So for this to make sense says, I'm going to explain this one more time and I'm going to say that this
Capital Group is going to be applied on this book.
It is going to find this book within the strength, because this says all all the characters and zero
more or occurrences occurrence of them, which we have four occurrences of that.
But this space says space.
And this one, it basically repeats this capture.
So there is no difference between that and this that I'm about to ride in here.
So if you're writing like this or if you write it like this, there are not there is no difference.
We still get through.
But instead of repeating ourselves.
In case we have a culture group that we want to repeat it, we just provide one.
OK, so it is going to work like this.
So this is the testing.
Let's go ahead and let's talk about the matching.
So I'm just going to copy it below and common these one out.
So now we are going to grab our sentence and we are going to say match match to match it to the regular
expression that we have created number 27.
And this is going to be this is not going to be the test result, this is going to be the match results,
let's save it.
And we get this now, you might ask, OK, why do we get, like, book, book?
And then one other book?
The reason for that is.
Well, this should be marching well, there was I shouldn't have, like, copy pasted that I should
have written it.
I'm just going to paste this for you as a reference here that this is a shorthand is a shorthand way
for this is for repeating what is inside the parentheses.
So this book book is repeated by this and we have this as well.
So this parentheses is repeated once with this and then we have the parentheses themselves.
That's why we have another book in here.
So this is a reference for you.
So we have four capture groups.
We have talked about the testing and we have talked about the matching.
Now, what I am going to do is I'm going to give you another example.
So this is very, very clear.
So for that, I'm going to comment everything out and I'm going to provide some space here.
OK, and in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create some digits, so the digits are going
to be three, two, one, three, two, one, one, two, three.
So three occurrences of three digits, three digit numbers.
Right.
And now let's create our regular expression, which is twenty seven X.
So what do we want to do here?
We want to find out the same pattern.
So for this pattern, how would we write a regular expression?
So we would write that we have a number in the beginning, a number in the beginning, and this is our
culture group inside this.
So we are going to grab all numbers.
Keep in mind, D is all digits or all numbers, zero or more occurrences of them, and then we are looking
for a space.
After that, we want to repeat this entire search and then we look for space and then we repeat this
entire search.
OK, and also we have numbers at the end as well.
So we have numbers at the start.
We have numbers at the end.
Only this regular expression is going to return.
True.
So let's first off, let's talk about the testing part.
So I'm just going to say testing.
And in the testing, I'm going to say let.
You know what, I'm just going to copy this from here, it's easier, so regular expression test, it
should be digits, digits and let's copy this, put it right here and oops, put it right here and commented
and and now we get false.
So we have regular expression test.
It is regular expression number 27 and we test the digits.
OK, so we have this we have space, we are repeated once and when we have space, we repeated it one
more time and then we have the dollar sign, which says that it is at the end.
And when I save it, we get a OK, maybe like because this is one, two, three.
We should and this is three to one and now we get two.
So it has to be the same thing.
So it has to be that's why because when we say repeated it, it should be the same thing.
This was a mistake and I'm sorry for that.
When we say repeat, it should be the same thing.
So this is like the short the short hand way we could go ahead with the long way as well.
So I'm just going to copy this.
I'm going to grab this one and I'm going to basted like that.
So both of them is going to return.
True, because both of them are looking for a pattern of three digits, three digits, three numbers
that have three digits inside of them.
Now, why did we do the dollar sign at the end?
For example, if I remove the dollar sign, it should say true again.
But if I were to add like four or five secs, like six, five, four, sorry, we are going to get through
as well because we haven't specified what the end results should be.
So it is looking for three copies of the same number and after that it doesn't care what comes inside
this pattern.
But when we provide the dollar sign, we say that this pattern should be the starting thing and also
the ending thing.
And when I say it, we get false.
All right.
So this is going to be the testing part.
Let's go ahead and let's talk about the matching.
Matching, right, and for the matching.
I'm just going to copy, you know what, I'm just going to write it.
So I'm going to say let Reg X match the result.
So we are going to grab our digits.
All right, so in the digits, what do we want to do?
We want to match it.
Match it with what with the regular expression number twenty seven, so a regular expression, number
27 and right after that we want to console logit, it is regular expression match result.
So let's come in this one out.
Let's save it.
We get that.
So why do we get three, three, two once and then we get three to one once more?
The reason for that is this.
This thing is going to run first, which is going to give us this.
And finally, we are going to run this parentheses one more time.
That's in another iteration.
You can think of it like that.
That's not completely accurate, but you can think of it like that.
So you understand how it works.
And then this parentheses is going to run one more time.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to give you another comment in here as well as a resource.
All right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.