Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to persist our data to local storage.
All right, so first off, what I'm going to do is we are going to grab a V. to do items that are printed
on the screen.
For example, if I come here and if I add, like, read that book.
Read the book that you didn't read, read that book.
OK, why do I say save should click on this?
So this is our data right now.
We need to grab this data and we need to store it inside the what is the name, the local storage.
So it is inside the application.
And if we just expand it to right to our application does not break.
And if we come here, we don't see anything in here.
Right.
We see there is something here, but we don't see anything inside the first application inside here.
So we need to save it here.
And why do we need to save it?
Because whenever we relook, reload the page and when it is saved here, it is going to stay here.
So the first step is to save it to the local storage.
The second step is to retrieve it from the local storage to in technical terms, the first step is to
persist to local storage.
The second step is to retrieve it or to grab it from the local storage.
OK, so we are going to add it to local storage wherever we updater to do item.
So the first the first place that we are actually a to do item is whenever we call an event listener
on the key app sorry, on the enter key and on the R to do add button.
So this is where we add our input also.
This is where we update that input.
This is whether we are whether we say that it are the what do I say about what do I want to say, whether
it is a completed task or whether it should be removed.
So we are going to persist at the local storage in two places.
All right.
And I'm going to say persisting to local storage or updating the local storage array.
So did it is it correct?
Yes.
So what we are going to do is we're going to call a method called Jason that string ify.
And I'm going to tell you why.
So we are going to say for a setting, for providing something to local storage, you are going to call
that local storage and we are going to set item.
OK, so this is the method for that.
And it says the first value, the first one is key is string.
The second one is value string.
So we have a key and we have a value.
So we have a key value pair like an object.
OK, now it says sets the value of pair identified by key to value creating a new key value pair if
nonexistent.
None existed for the key previously.
Right.
Just forget the rest of them in here.
What is the key that we want to provide it with?
The key is a brand new key that I'm just going to create here.
It is the to do item and now it says the next thing we should provide it with the value.
The value is going to be Jason or AJ.
So on that string of Afie and what is Gesang?
That string of I, you know, actually I'm not really sure how this is spelled.
Sorry how this is pronounced.
Some people, they call it Jason, some people call it Jason.
All right.
So feel free to call it whatever you want as long as you understand what this, Jason, that if I does,
I think Jason has a better string to it than has a better ring to it than Jason.
All right.
So like like think of it like this.
Maybe like you have a name.
An English name that is Jason now, this is called Jason, you never see Jason.
Hey, Jason, come over.
You say Jason.
So keeping in mind like this terminology, you should say, Jason, you like this methodology of pronunciation.
Pronunciation.
So what what does Jason, Jason or Jason does?
If I do, it grabs a JavaScript object or value and it converts it into adjacent string.
And whenever it converts it to that, then we can store it somewhere.
Right.
Either that is a database or a very simple basic local storage of the browser.
So before saving it, we need to convert it to a language that the local storage understands, and that
is the adjacent string.
All right.
So whenever we want to store it to the local storage, we need to convert it to the Jason language.
And whenever we want to grab it from the local storage, we need to convert it to the JavaScript language.
Think of it like this.
So we are going to say to do content or what is it that we want to persist to our local storage?
It is going to be our to do container.
I'm going to copy this line.
Right.
And I'm going to come down here and I want to add it to here as well outside the if statement, of course.
So we're going to add it here, because this is where we update our ally as well.
So technically, you know what?
And I'm going to grab this.
You are.
And where is the first place?
Hmm.
Excuse me.
So sometimes I do this.
So let's face it right here.
And this is in case you are a very, very serious developer.
I'm just getting this is for your reference.
You can go to it.
So let's come here now, we are inside this local storage, let's say hi, local storage.
Save it while we see that we have a key and we have a value.
So it is a set of key value pairs.
Keep that in mind.
And when I click on it, it says name is high local storage idea zero because we want it to be zero.
And if I click on this, we get exactly our object.
Whereas this object located inside our code, I'm going to tell you where.
It is going to return to us this because this is the object that we have pushed to this to do container's
array and if you remember correctly, to do container is an array inside which we have pushed in object.
So it is it's like this one.
So if I copy that and if I put it inside here, so inside our local storage, we see the same result
as I've just done here.
All right.
So we have an array and inside the array we have an object and the object has a set of key and value
pairs.
So we we have exactly done that.
Local storage.
Very, very simple.
Right.
So we can see that the done is false and OK, the done is false and our high local high local storage
is gone.
So if I click on the.
And this one we can see that Al's idea zero done is false.
If I click on this to do complete and it says that done is true because we have just clicked on it and
if I click on the trash it is going to say trash Asatru.
So it automatically is updating that.
And where is this update coming from?
It is the last place where we add it.
So if I just do this and if we come here and that's how can we remove it like that?
So if I say hi L.
S and if I click on and click here.
So this is what we have.
If I click on this, we can see that the done is still false because we have not added the local storage
there.
We did added, but we commented out.
So it's not updating the local storage in this point.
So if you do this and save it and come here and do hey, let's not hi.
It's Hey.
So it says hey.
Ls it, is it zero done is false.
True is sorry.
Trash is false.
Click done is true.
Click trash is true.
Very very cool stuff.
I know.
All right, so there is another issue here as well, so we can see that we have won one key and one
value, and it's if I click on it in here, we have only one and one idea, and that is the idea of
zero.
So if I had to do one.
We are going to see that here, it says To do one, if I had to do two, are going to see that.
It says to do to so.
The problem is when I reload our our page, the the items, they are still the to do items, they're
still inside this local storage, but they have been removed from our.
Let me just reduce this.
They have been removed from this browser.
So how can we retrieve this data from the local storage back to our browser?
How can we do that now?
We have updated the local stories.
Now it's time to grab that update and update our browser once more.
So for that, what I'm trying to do is I'm going to come on top.
And we are going to do things differently now.
OK, so in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to comment both of them out and I'm going to initialize
them.
I'm not going to set them to any value.
I'm going to initialize them.
Right.
And I'm going to say let to do container and I'd be initialized.
They don't have any value as of yet, but they are initialized.
Right.
And what we are going to do is in here, in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a variable
at the variable is going to say to do data, to be able to retrieve data from from the local storage.
You are going to say local storage data, get item.
Now, we said set item when we updated the local storage.
And we are going to say get item.
Get item is just asking us for the key.
What is the key?
The key is to do to dash do dash item.
We know what the key is.
The key is this where it returns the current value associated with the given key.
So we know what the key is.
The key is to do item.
Where is it coming from?
It is coming from right here.
Whenever we sit the item to the local storage, we added a key for it so we can we can get it back.
Right.
So set item, we give it a key and we gave it a to do container.
So whenever we inside our get item method we say give me the value associated with this, with this
specific key.
What is that specifically?
It is the to do item.
So it is going to go inside the local storage and it is going to retrieve the value associated with
this to do item.
Now let's go ahead and let's see that in action.
So I'm going to first off, I'm going to add an if statement because I want to make sure that that our
local storage is not empty.
So I'm going to say to do data.
OK, so f to do data is true, it means that it is not empty, OK, if it is empty, I do not want anything
from the local storage because there is nothing to grab from the local storage for that.
For this to work, we need to add an F because we want to check.
OK, so if it is true, it means that there is something inside the local storage.
If there is something we want to gravois to do container.
Remember we have initialized our to do container right here, but we have not added, we have not specified
any any value to it.
So what is going to be the value.
The value is going to be Jason that pass.
Not paranoid pass, and what does it have to pass, it should pass the to do data because to do data
why?
To do data.
To do data is the variable that stores the items value that we have that we want to retrieve from the
local storage.
So this part of this this entire variable is going to give us a value and we have stored that value
to this to do data.
And now because that value is in Jason's language, we need to convert it back to JavaScript.
And for that we use a pass method and the pass method is right here.
So, Jason, that pass method passes adjacent string const constructing the JavaScript value or object
described by this string.
So to round everything up, we had a.
We had an era in which we had like a set of like we had an array of objects, right?
We converted, we were on we wanted to save that inside our local storage.
So we converted that to Jason language.
And now we have lost our array.
All right.
We have lost it.
And we are asking Jason, please give me my array back and the Jason.
And in order for me to understand Marrara, because my array has been converted, my object has been
converted to the Jason language, Jason first has to convert it back to my language and give it to me.
So this is what this in the past does in simplest terms.
OK, so we're going to do this.
And what about the idea?
The idea is going to come from our to do container that length?
And what does it mean?
It means that we are going to set the idea to the last one, to the last item inside or to do container.
So the idea is going to be to that and we are going to add another function.
It is load to do container.
Now, we have successfully grabbed it from the from the local storage.
What do we do then?
Now I do have my data back.
I need to show it to the user.
For that, I'm going to create a function that says load to do container.
Right.
And what is it that I want to show to user?
It has to do container.
Very simple, right?
And now this load to do function is going to show this to do container to the interface and this to
do container has its data from the local storage.
Right.
That's it.
And OK, so this is in case the to do data is true, this is in case we do have something inside our
local stories.
But in the case that we do not have anything inside our local storage, what do we want to do that then?
We want our to do container to be sent to a simple empty array and our I.D..
Come on, buddy, or it should start from zero, right?
So in this case, the idea came dynamically from our local storage, but in this case, we set it back.
So this is very, very similar to this one.
Right.
So this we have basically changed it and we have brought it here.
And this is a good thing.
Whenever whenever you create an variable and you just initialize it, you did not give it a specific
value.
Now then you can change that value.
And the reason that we have used let here is because you are changing the value dynamically.
If you use const here and here, you're going to see an error, right?
Hopefully.
So let's change it to const.
Let's see if I'm right.
Save it and let's come here.
And it says Oncotype are missing out on fire and the const declaration missing identifier because you
cannot initialize you cannot initialize variables using const.
You cannot do that you cnr right.
And this is what I'm talking about because whenever you initialize that variable with the constant variable,
it means that you're going to change the value and const does not let you do that.
Let is going to let you but const is not going to let you.
So we should be good so far.
All right.
So.
Now, the final thing that I want to do is in this lecture, I'm not going to wrap it up, even if it
gets to 20 minutes.
I want to create my load to do container function.
I want to do something useful in this lecture so loath to do container function.
And we have passed an hour to do container as an argument and the function call.
So what is the to do container to do container is basically an array.
So when it is an array we can add, we can apply the for each method on that array.
So remove that from there so you guys can see that it uses an arrow function.
We are going to remove that.
We're going to use our very regular overused function and we're going to say item we are just so this
item is a function parameter or the array or the for each lupe's variable, which is going to loop over
and in here we are going to call our add to do function.
What is the add to do function.
The add to do function is the first function that we are the recreated and inside the add to do a function.
We have created our dynamic element.
Whenever we call that function, it has four parameters.
So we need to add four.
I like respective.
Arguments, so the first argument is going to be item Dutney, the second one is going to be item DOUT
I.D. The third one is going to be item dot done.
And the fourth one is going to be item trash.
We are not going to hard code anything, they're not going to give it a name.
And I'd done any trash because that is going to come for that is going to come or that is going to be
retrieved from the local storage.
So doing this, we should be good.
We should be able to do something useful.
So let's reload.
That's how can I remove these?
Let's remove them.
Let's reload the page.
Let's let's go into our local storage.
We do have some stuff here.
So let's clear everything.
So everything's clear I'm going to say to do you know what I'm going to say?
Watch.
John WEC.
Right.
So it was John Wick, we can see that our local storage has been added, has been updated accordingly.
Now I think it's delayed, selected clear all now everything's cleared.
So let's clear this one as well.
All right.
So I'm going to say watch John Weck say that this is our why are the rest of them there anyway?
Refresh.
It's, uh, scrub this.
Deleted and her options deleted.
Come on, buddy, don't do this.
Hey, Ali, we still get it and oops, everything is removed from here.
Gosh, what should I do?
The way that we can select them again, we can grab them from our local storage is.
Um hmm.
We should be able to see them.
I mean, I don't know what's wrong here.
So let's come back into our ad to do we have added the name ID item items done item array.
This is going to push this into this load container.
The load container is going to be from here.
And hmm.
All right, so, uh.
Oh, because we have we have removed everything from here, that's why we cannot see them.
So now the trash is true, that's why they're not coming back, because it says the trash is true.
So let's clear everything.
Let's do something else.
Let's do to do is to save it.
I know we can see the rest of them.
And in here, if I click on this, it's done.
It's true.
We will be able to remove this in one way or another.
So it says done is true, trash is false.
If I trash it, then it is going to go away.
The thing is, I should be able to reload the page and this should stay here.
So if I reload the page, it is still it is still here.
I'm going to close this page.
I'm going to come I'm going to come into my e-mail open of a life server because it is saved inside
a database.
We can see that to do is cool.
And if I click this and then remove it, reload once more, we can see that it is off, obviously persisted
accurately to this local storage because it doesn't matter what we do, it is going to give us this.
OK, now it doesn't matter how many times you reloaded, you can use it as a mini application for yourself.
You can create a to do list, you can add twenty items.
And when you cross them and when you close the application, turn off your computer.
If you come back and just open it, there are always going to be inside this local storage.
You can use it as a mini web like like a webapp sort of thing.
It is a web app, of course.
And the final thing that we need to do is just go ahead and add the clear functionality, which I'm
going to do in this lecture as well.
So I'm going to say clear the local storage.
So for the clearing that I want to target this button.
So whenever I click on this trash, this cloud trash, I need to be able to create clear everything.
So we have already selected that inside our clear button.
So I'm going to grab it and I'm going to add it here.
And I'm going to say that add event listener and the event that we are listening for is a click event.
And when the click event happens, we are going to run a function, the function.
So what is going to be the function?
The function is going to grab our local storage and it is going to clear it.
We're going to use the clear method.
We also want to reload our Web page.
So for doing that, we are going to say location, reload.
So now we should be able to do what we want, so if I come here and if I click on it now, everything
is gone.
So if I add one to three and if I come here, you can see that we only have one, two, three, we don't
have anything else.
So if I click, everything is gone.
So let's go ahead and let's close everything up.
Let's reload our Web page.
And I could say a reload or I could just close this.
This is the finished project right here.
It's just finished project.
I could double click on the index and we should see our project.
So now let's test it out.
This is the first to do.
Created by a wonderful person, save it, so it says this is it to do.
This is the first to do created by a one created two to a wonderful person.
Anyway, OK, so let's go ahead and let's inspect it inside our local storage at the same time so we
know it works properly.
So in here, what we have is this is our local storage and it says that this is the name.
The name is very long.
I mean, let's remove everything and let's say to do first or one or initial set.
Good.
We should be good.
Still long, but OK.
So to do first or one of initial we have an idea of zero done is false.
Trashiest false.
If I click on this done is true and let's say this is the to do that I wanted to do today.
Let's save it, let's close it, close this, let's open it up again.
Let's open this one again.
And if we come here we see that our to do is still completed and it is not removed.
And if we come to application, we can see that the data is still right here.
So let's say for this is the second day that you're using this application.
Excuse me.
And just give me one sec.
All right, so let's say this is the second day that you are using this application and in the second
day you say clean the pool, right?
Don't know, like clean the pool, water the flowers.
And then the second day you get a little bit lazy.
You do not clean the pool, which is difficult.
You just water the flowers and that's it.
And this is the third day you come back in.
And whenever you open up your application, your to do list, you can see, oh, I did not water the
flowers.
No, sorry I did for water the flowers.
I did not clean the pool.
I should probably do it today.
So you're going to do it and you still get to do first.
This is something that I did two did two days ago.
Let's clean, let's try it.
And then you close it and then you open it up again and you can see that the trash is trashed clean.
The pool is clean.
The water, the flowers are water or the water is a flower and everything is done.
Then you go ahead and clear everything when you come to inspect and you check it out.
Nothing is inside the local storage.
So this is going to be it for our application.
I hope you have enjoyed it.
It was a longer one, but again, you should get used to it because we are in the territory of intermediate
JavaScript projects and when we get to the advanced, we are going to get even longer and longer projects.
See you guys in the next chapter.