Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we will handle score and lives.
All right, so first off, I'm going to go up there to our game parameters and I'm going to create a
constant and I'm going to call it game lives and I'm going to set it to three cliche and then we are
going to have a key.
Score, which is going to be safe, Towra, local storage, and it is going to be called high score.
Perfect.
All right.
And next up.
I would like to create the text for the color, for the text, so I'm going to say color text to 60
and I'm going to just set it to white.
You can change it to whatever color you like.
And right after that, I'm going to create another bunch of text property.
So I'm going to say I'm going to call them text properties.
So in the text properties, what we have is first things first, we have our text font.
So I'm going to say text font.
The text font is going to be sans serif, sans serif.
And then just going to copy it a bunch of times, we are going to have the text level.
Then we are going to have the text for the lives.
Should just grab this one, so lives, then we will have the text fourscore.
Perfect, after that, we are going to have the text for high score, which I'm just going to call a
score high, then we will have a text for game over.
So let's just grab that and let's say game over.
Over and finally, we are going to have a text for when?
Now, let's let's grab this.
So this one is going to be level this one, the lives is going to say just ball, the score is going
to say score and the high score is going to say best or you can change it to high score.
I'm just going to capitalize it.
The game over is going to say game over.
So game over and Cabral's and the win is going to say you won.
So we have created this
next stop.
I would like to go ahead and I would like to create our levels live score, score high on all of that
as well.
All right.
So in here.
Right in here, what I would like to do is I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to.
So here we have our panel, then we have the ball.
Then we have the I'm going to remove the touch from here.
All right.
And then we have our bricks.
Then we have the level, which I'm just going to go ahead and remove it from here as well.
And down below, what I would like to do is why do we have an error?
Because this is coming, right?
Yep.
There we go.
So I'm going to create I'm going to create a variable left.
It's going to be game over for our game over.
And then we are going to have, you know, what the power up.
So I'm just going to create them here.
Of course, we are going to talk about them in our upcoming lectures.
I just want to make sure that they are created so sticky why we are here.
So we are going to have the power up for extension, another one for sticky, another one for Super
Bowl.
And then we are going to have our win text.
Right after that.
I'm going to create a real level.
And then the lives score score high.
OK, this is a score and score high, perfect after that, let's create the number of bricks perfect.
And let's create the text size.
And in here, I'm going to also add our touch X, so let's save that.
Let's come here.
We don't have any error.
We have not messed anything up.
Perfect.
Now, what I would like to do is I would like to go to our set dimensions function.
All right, so where is our said dimension's function?
And here, what I would like to do is I would like to create a context for the alignment, for the baseline
of our text.
Right.
And.
I'm going to say con eckstut, text, baseline text, not that text baseline, and I'm going to set
it to middle.
All right, so we have done that as well.
And after that, what I would like to do is I want to create a new ball, a function, and then where
is our new game function?
Right on top of there.
So I'm going to grab this and I'm going to put it right here.
Now, you could call this a little bit of refactoring that we do here.
I just want to tidy up some loose ends.
So I'm going to say function.
Kneubuhl This is going to be in charge of creating a new ball for us.
And in here, what I would like to do is I would like to cut everything from there and I would like
to put him here.
I'm not going to save it.
Keep that in mind.
I will.
I'm not going to save it.
And then I'm going to come to our new game.
Let's remove all the space so we have our level.
Let's initially the game over is going to be equal to force.
The score is going to be zero.
The when whoever has won is going to be false because no one has won and the lives amount of the lives
is going to be the game lives that we have.
Right.
And in here is.
Right after this, what I would like to do is I want to create another function that is going to be
called new level.
Right, and I'm going to call it beneath this function.
OK, so I'm going to call I'm going to create it there.
So on top of the out of bounds, in case you're wondering why the out of bounds was here, I think it
was below the set dimensions and I brought it here.
This is the correct place for it.
So just go ahead and copy it and bring it here out of bounds.
So in here, what I would like to call create is a new level function and let's say function, new level.
This is going to be responsible for creating a new level for us and in here is where I would like to
go ahead and grab our touch and set it to no.
All right.
And I'm going to call in the new ball function here and I'm going to call in to create bricks.
Excuse me.
I would like to call in the create bricks.
OK, so just make this.
Correct.
Let's put it here.
So this is going to be our new ball function.
Why is it not why is it throwing an error here?
Oh, because of these.
I see what you say.
So let's remove this.
And in here, I'm going to call our create bricks.
Create bricks function as well.
We're basically calling it here and then.
All right, so inside our new game function.
I no longer want to call the create bricks here, I just want to call the new level function here I
would like because inside the new level function, we already called the new the create bricks and also
the new ball.
Function, so where is our touch X, I think we have we are we have never provided it here.
So the touch X is right here.
It is going to be null and ah, right.
So from now inside this new game function, I also would like to do our local storage and we are going
to say getting the high score from the local.
Storage perfect.
Now we are going to say score a star or score string is going to be equal to local storage, not get
item.
We have not said it, but we are going to set it somewhere and it is going to be key score.
Right.
And we are going to say F score string is null.
If it is empty, if there is nothing there, it means that the score high is going to be equal to zero
else.
Else our score high score high is going to be equal to where is the score high coming from, let's click
on it.
Yes, it is coming from there, so we should be good.
So otherwise, where is our.
No game, where are we?
We are here, we are here, otherwise the score high is going to be let's grab the pass and function,
right?
And it is going to convert.
It is going to give us when we pass in a string, it is going to convert it to a number and that is
going to be the score strength.
Perfect.
So we are done with that as well.
Next up, I want to go to my create bricks, whereas I will create bricks function.
Um.
Create it, break color word, oh, there we go.
So inside the create bricks function, I would like to create our text the size of our text that we
are going to show by the text, I mean this that we have here.
So this is going to be like based on the height of the bricks that we have and I'm going to say text
size.
Now, the text size that we have declared there is going to be the height of the row times, the margin
that we have times zero point four or five.
This is going to be the height of our text.
And now it is time for us to go ahead and actually draw our text, so on top of the drop ball, I'm
going to call a function, draw a text.
I'm not going to save anything because it might throw an error.
And for that's it.
Well, and it is going to keep throwing that on.
My computer is going to overwork itself.
Perfect, so let's go ahead and let's actually draw our text, create the variables, the dimensions,
there is going to be a lot of things that we need to do there for for our text to really work.
So what I'm what I am going to do is I'm going to go let's see where I want to put the draw text.
So where is our draw parallels?
So let's collapse this one.
This one.
This is a redraw panel and I want to put it there on top of the draw walls.
So let's copy that and let's put it here.
And I'm going to say draw.
Text, so let's go ahead and let's create that function, draw text.
Yes, we have called it they're perfect, so in here, what I would like to do is first I want to grab
our canvas context and I want to say Phil style.
Phil style, and we are going to set it to the color of the text that we have and then let's create
the dimensions perfect.
So we are going to have a label size Soulet label size is going to be equal to a derivative of our text
size.
So there's going to be time zero point five.
We are going to have a margin, which is going to be four times the wall, times two.
That is the margin.
We are going to have a maximum with a lot for our text, and that is going to be the width of the canvas,
minus the margin on each side, which is going to be margin times to then we are going to have a because
we have four columns, one, two, three, four.
We are going to have max widths for each of those columns.
So I'm going to say Max with one and this is going to be our Max with time zero point two seven.
So this is going to be the width of the width of the first half of the column of text one.
Let's copy it three more times.
And in here, this is going to be two and I'm going to set it to zero point two.
Then we have three this all these are the center of columns, and I'm going to set it to zero point
two as well, and this is going to be four.
And I'm going to set it to zero point two seven zero point two seven is actually correct.
So we have created the withes and now let's create the position.
So we need four positions as well.
So I'm going to say X1 is going to be.
So the first one is going to be the position is going to be the margin.
So it's going to be position.
Of the call them one and let's do this.
So for these second columns position.
I would like to grab our with and I'm going to multiply by zero point four.
So at this point, the width times zero point four at that pixel point is going to be the position of
the second column.
The position of the third column is going to be.
With time zero point six, so these two are going to be relatively closer to each other, let's grab
the position number four and position number four is going to be our with minus the margin.
So it's up against the wall on the right.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a Y label here as well.
And that is going to be wall plus the label size, and we are going to create a Y value here as well,
and that is going to be the Y label plus.
Plus, the text size.
And to and I want to reduce it a little, so I'm just going to multiply it by zero point nine so our
dimensions are done, we are going to go ahead and we are going to say drawing labels.
So Conex start phonte the set up the fund first and let's open our tactics, we are going to pass in
a reliable size.
Roman writing.
So let's grab our legal size and we need to toss in there the pixel and then let's passan what is the
text font that we have or the font family?
So it is going to be text font.
Right after that, we are going to grab our text line and we are going to set it to left.
And then we are going to grab the full text.
Con.
Phil, text or original text and in the full text.
First off, we need to pass in the text.
So on the left side we have score and let me show it to you.
So here we have score, then we have ball, then we have level, then we have best.
So in this order, we are going to pass in the full text properties here.
So first one is going to be text score, this is the text, the position is going to be X1 the after
the position, the Y position is going to be Y label and the width is going to be max with one.
Perfect.
So this is going to be the text of the score.
I'm going to copy this one more time.
And I'm going to copy this one one more time, so then we should provide them with the center.
So in the center we have our lives or ball and then we have our live level.
All right.
So here I need to pass and text live.
Perfect, so the position is going to be x2 and the width is going to be matched with two.
This is going to be three and the position is going to be X three, x two.
And this is going to be.
Text level.
Perfect, and for the last time, I'm just going to grab that, put it right here, and this is going
to be for this to the right and this is the best text score high.
Text, I'm just going to say hi, perfect, and this is going to be four, so now these are our text.
So if I save that, have we call the draw text?
And so there we go.
This is our text score board level and best.
Now let's draw the values as well.
So before actually going out of the function, we are going to say drawing the values.
I'm just going to say, drawing values, we don't know what the values are.
So first off, it's you know what?
It's actually going to be very similar to this one.
So I'm just going to grab it and put it here.
So for the text, we are going to have text size and then the font is going to be the same thing.
The alignment for the first one is left for the second and third one.
It is going to be center for the fourth one.
It is going to be right.
Then we are going to have X1 and then x2, x3 and X four.
This is no longer Y label.
So this is going to be Y value perfect.
The max widths are going to be the same as well and we need to change this text.
So for the first one it is going to say score, this is going to be the text of the score.
For the second one, we are going to grab our tactics and I'm going to grab the dollar sign and curly
braces.
So we have our number of lives that we have and then we have the the remaining lives are here.
The maximum number of lives that we have is going to be here.
So Max Lives is like this.
So this is remaining lives.
This is the maximum lives that that you can have.
For the level we are just going to pass some level now, this level is going to be zero and then one
and then two and then three.
So this is going to change dynamically.
And for the for this, we are going to pass in the score high.
So let's save that and let's come here.
There we go.
So whenever we start the game, you can see that we have three out of three balls.
The level is zero.
The best is zero.
Everything is zero.
But if I were to go to our new game, set the score like I know this is this is not going to be like
very practical, but I just want to show you, you can see the score is one hundred and the level is
five.
Perfect.
So let's reset them back.
Now that that is done, let's see what else do we want to do?
I'm going to go to our cruciate bricks function.
So where is that where it should be towards the top, if I remember correctly.
So draw bricks, create bricks, function.
And in here, I want to grab our score and I want to provide it here as well, so the score, whenever
the user hits the green, we are going to have score of one.
When it when it goes up one rank, we are going to add two to it.
So it's going to be one three and then this is five.
And I think the red one is going to be seven.
So let's see where we would like to provide this.
So this is our rank.
So right below there, I'm going to write a score and the score is going to be based on the rank high
minus the rank, and it is going to be two.
And then we are going to add one to it because we are going one level up.
When the user hits each of the upper ranks, we are going to add like two scores to that, two consecutive
scores to that.
All right, that is done as well.
The next thing that I would like to do is let's go into our update Brooks function.
So where is our update?
I'm just going to close this for now.
This is the new ball.
This is the new game.
This is the new level of date breaks.
And I am going to you know what?
Now I'm going to leave it there for you.
Update.
This is our update.
Bricks function.
So inside this function right after that, I would like to call a method that is going to be update
score.
And inside there, we are going to pass in our bricks, each of each of individual bricks, individual
bricks is core, right?
And.
And then let's go ahead and let's create this, so where should we put it?
So we have our update panel right here and right below the update panel.
I'm going to create our update score function.
So score.
Now, this function is going to accept a parameter, so we are going to set up a date score and it is
going to call it the break score.
Right.
So first off, what we would like to do is we would like to add on to the score that we have by the
BRICS score and then we are going to check.
Check for a high score.
Now, f score is greater than score high.
What is it that we want to do now?
You remember that we have grabbed an item from the local storage.
And we did not actually set an item to local storage.
This is where we will sit at the item to local storage.
So if the score is greater than the high score, it means that we have another high score.
So the high score is going to be equal to that score that we have.
Just have we have just scored right or right and we are going to grab our local storage.
Locals, come on.
Local storage, and we are going to say set item.
The items are going to require a case for which we have, which is the key score and the value is going
to be the score high.
All right, so let's save that as well, and what I'm going to do is let's go to our out of bounds function.
And I told you that I think I told you that in here what we are going to do is we're basically testing.
So this was basically a test.
This is not we do want our new game to run.
Right.
But we don't want it to run like this.
Whenever I would out of my function is going to call whenever the ball hits the brake and we cannot
get it and it is going to go down, then the out-of-band function function is going to be cut.
Right.
So what I would like to do here, as in the out of bounds function.
I'm going to say first stuff, when when it is out of the band, I'm going to reduce it by one life
and then we are going to say if lives is equal to zero, it means we don't have any more lives.
That means that the game is over.
Right.
So game over is going to be true.
And finally.
Game over is true, and finally, we are going to call the new ball function here.
So what I would like to do now is go ahead on this, test it.
comScore says, and not a number.
OK, so.
Where is our score, where have we specified that the score said dimension's pinball?
I'm just going to collapse these functions that we are not going to need?
Serve all of that one as well.
So this this this this one as well.
So in here, this is where we are updating your bricks.
And this is the update score and this is somehow it is it's returning now and this update breaks.
So let's go to top to or create bricks, because the score is actually coming from our brick class and
the score is right here and we have passed it inside the constructor as well.
But as far as calling this is concerned, there we go.
We can see that we don't have any score.
So whenever when we created the score right here, we need to pass it here as well.
I'm going to pass and the speed mult as well.
So in case we don't have any problems with that.
So let's try this one more time.
So there we go.
You can see that the score is one and the best is one.
The score is going to be two.
I'm going to play it for a while.
All right, so there we go.
And.
Why is the angle so extreme?
I think we put it, too, that this is random, so you can see that our score is we just lost the ball.
The ball is the score of the ball is reduced, the number of the balls is reduced and the score is for
the best.
As for if I reload the page, this score is going to come from the local stories.
That's why it doesn't matter if you refresh, it is going to stay there.
So let me just check the ball speed and the angle.
So let's go.
There we have the ball speed is zero point the zero point four or five ball spin.
Let's just increase it to zero point seven.
So now you know what?
I'm not going to increase it because it should increase, I think.
Did we do the speed as well, the speed increment?
I don't think we have done that.
I'm not sure about that.
I don't remember.
So let's check it.
A fly ball speed.
Yeah, we did that.
So the speed should be increasing.
As well.
So so I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to check it, so our score is three, best is four.
If the score is above the high score, like right here, then the high score is going to be equal to
the score and it is going to be committed to local storage.
That's what we did.
So the higher ranks, there we go, they have a higher score.
So we have a score of 19.
This is going to be 20.
And this is going to be 21.
So let's see.
This one is 26, so that was five.
This should be three.
Yes, the other one should be seven.
So the red one has to be seven.
I'm just going to keep playing until we hit the red one.
I could increase the speed.
But we are we are getting close.
So you can see how the best score is also changing, so hopefully we are going to hit an orange.
We have done that.
So let's go ahead and let's wait.
There we go.
It didn't.
OK, so the best score is 60 and we are getting closer, so we don't have to wait for a long maybe like
in the next minute or so, we should hit a red one as well.
There go, come on.
So, uh.
Let's wait for it.
We are getting closer, I know.
Just bear with me.
I just want to check what is the score?
It should be seven, because that's the logic that we have implemented in order.
And I told you that you have to check it.
It's there is no other way.
You got to, like, go ahead and check this to make sure that it is working properly.
I mean, this is just a small game.
Like if it were like a bigger one, like like a really huge game, like 3D game, then that would have
taken longer.
This is just like a very basic, simple 2D game.
So the next time it bounces up there, we should hit a red one or this way.
So it should we should hit.
That so let's see now, um.
OK, it didn't.
Hopefully this time we are going to hit one.
So there we go.
Oh, it didn't.
So we are going to keep track of our score from this point onwards, 146 159 and.
165, come on.
There we go, 172, so it is going to increase, each rank is going to be increased by two.
And I think this is going to be it for the for this lecture and see you guys in the next one.