Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we we're going to call the show entry function.
All right, so we're do we want to actually call this function, we want to call it inside the update
UI, because this update UI is the function which is responsible for updating the balance, the income,
the outcome, the chart, the expense income tracker, the other tracker, the other all list.
So what we are going to do is we are going to grab our entry list and I'm going to explain it very,
very thoroughly.
And we are going to run a for each on it.
So the for each what it is going to grab is it is going to require a callback function, which we have
done a lot.
Right.
But why foreach.
Because decentralised at this point, it has something in it and because this interest is actually in
an array we can call the foreach because we want to apply a certain logic on each of those items.
We want to classify those items either as being inside the contractor or expense structure or being
inside the all or whatever.
Right.
And something like that.
So what we are going to do is we are going to say function lets pass and the loop variables which are
which we are going to pass and the entry and also the index.
So the index is what is going to define our IDE because our ID for first item is going to be one zero
one.
For the second one, it is going to be one.
Right.
And then after that we are going to open the declaration sorry, the execution context of this function.
We are going to say, if not, we are going to have three different to actually two different conditions.
And before writing it, let's just go into the theory.
I mean, like everyone loves theory, right?
So what is what what are these two conditions?
So the first condition is that we want to check if the entry that the user has inserted has a type of
expense.
We want to add it here.
And when we add it to this, we want to add this show entry.
You know, I'm going to try I'm going to start over.
So we have an ally here right now.
This allai has a class which is tie.
All right.
If what the user has inserted is inside the expense structure, it means that this class is going to
be.
The idea is going to be zero.
And what do we want to do?
We want to graph from that what you have, what the user has inserted from there.
We want to grab the title and we want to grab the amount.
Right.
And we want to show it here.
So in here, we are going to see, for example, if I say rent 50, so we are going to see title amount
and two icons.
I want to show it here and they will receive a style automatically.
Now, where is this style coming from?
If I come to my expense structure, you can see that the less the less has a color of tomato and for
the income tracker, it has a color of long green.
That's where the color is coming from.
So if I come here, so the first situation that I want to check is if entry door type equals what expense?
Because we have two different types.
One is expense, the other one is income as well as in here.
So we have specified one is income and one is expense.
OK, so if the entry type is expense, we also have them specified here as well because it says income.
Basically we are grabbing it from here.
So we say because this object is within this array, we select this object using this for each method.
And we want to grab this entry is going to go inside this entry list and it is going to grab a type
right.
And the index is going to be dependent on the index of the item that the user has inserted, the item
that the user has inserted.
So if the entry type equals expense, we want to call our show into a function.
But this is not the important part.
The important part is these are like inserting all of these arguments.
So it says, first we should insert the list.
What is the list?
When the entry type is expense, which the list does it belong to?
It belongs to the expense list.
I'm just going to pass an expense list and I'm going to head and you can see right away when I do comma,
the underline is going to shift to Type C. It has shifted to what is the type?
The type is very simple.
Now here is the trick.
We are not going to add the type to expense because we have already specified that right here we are
going to say the type is going to be entry doctype duct tape.
And after that it says, what is the title?
The title is going to be whatever the user has inserted.
That's why we are going to go in now.
This entry is going to get us that specific object and from there we are going to grab either the title
or the type or next stop the amount entries, that amount, which is the most important of them all.
And finally, we are going to pass in our index.
Now, the index is going to be start from zero and go all the way to as many budget indices.
We have, for example, budget like entries we have.
So if we have five entries for the incoming like 15 entries for the expense, the index is going to
be fourteen because it is going to start from zero.
This is it.
That's it.
Now, this is when the entry has a type of expense, FLC elusive.
The entry F the entry has what if the entry has a type of income?
What do we want to do then?
Now, why do we want to do then, as we are going to call our show into a function and we are going
to pass the list.
So in case this is income, which less does it belong to?
It is going to belong to the income list.
So what is going to be the type?
The type is going to be entry type.
And tree type, what is the what is the third one is the title, it is going to be in the title and
then what is the amount?
It is going to be in tree that amount.
Ampere, unpunched amant And finally, we are going to pass in the index, so now this is created,
but we and we have inserted items to our expense list and income list.
But there is one major thing remaining.
What is that?
That is the whole list.
Now, I'm going to give you five seconds here, OK?
I'm going to give you five seconds.
And in these five seconds, what you what you have to do is think about this.
Do we have to create another LaFalce block to enter our all list or we should just throw it casually
there or we need another function for that.
So we need three situations.
I'm going to give you five seconds and the clock starts now.
All right, so what do you think?
I'm sure you know the answer.
The answer is we do not need another function for that and we do not need another ounce of luck.
And why is that?
Because no matter the tracker, either if it is the income tracker or if it is the like, let's say
the expense structure, it doesn't matter which track it is, where our ally is inserted, we want to
insert it inside the oil so we do not care about any conditions in every condition.
We want to insert the show at the entry inside overall list.
So in that case that we want to run a code any way.
In any case.
In all cases.
We do not need an if statement for that, right, because we are going to run it anyway, it doesn't
matter what the cases, it doesn't matter what the condition is.
So when the condition doesn't matter, what is the point of a statement?
So outside this if statement, this elusive block, but remember, inside our for each loop, because
all this is part of this for each loop as well.
It is.
We are going to append a list sorry, an object to it, and we are going to grab that object from the
entry list.
If we go outside this for each, the whole list will have no idea, will have no connection to this
list and it will have no way of grabbing its objects.
So in here, I'm just going to call the show entry.
And now what is the list?
The list is all list and it is going to be entry type.
The type is entry that.
Type the title is entry, the title and the amount of entry that amount and we are going to pass in
our index a right.
So no errors here.
Let's go ahead and check out our application numbers here.
Thank goodness.
So let's say salary.
I don't know.
I keep saying Brading Salal salary.
Funny.
So if not 15, I'm going to say 11, 23.
OK, when I added here, of course it is added to the income tracker and we can see we see a lawn green
color because it is inside the correct tracker.
And lets let's go ahead and check out the expense structure.
There is no income there and this value is is updated.
The balance is updated.
The input is clear.
So let's go ahead and let's like I don't know, like brunch.
And let's turn to five, let's add it, and now this is working properly as well.
This has been updated.
The outcome, the balance has been updated.
You don't need to worry about the math.
JavaScript does that.
So you should be cool.
And it is inside the expense structure.
It is in the correct spot.
And now for the final thing, inside the oil and now inside the oil, we can see we have our salary
and we have our seventy five dollars for the branch.
OK, so we have successfully added in added items to our income tracker expense structure and to the
list.
And we have successfully updated the UI like the balance, the income and the outcome.
So what is actually remaining here?
The first thing that's still remaining, that this application is still missing as this chart, which
we are going to start creating from our next lectures and then the local storage, the LS because when
I reload this page, everything is going to go away.
All right.
But we don't want it to go away.
So we are going to use your see you guys in the next one.