Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we're going to talk about the object entry's method.
All right, so the object entries method is going to return the key value pairs from an object.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's create our variable, which we are going to call in this case, entries.
Let's grab our object, which provides us with this functionality.
And we're going to call in the entries method and let's pass.
And the favorite colors object.
And finally, let's get to the console entries.
Let's save it.
And we get through.
We get three items and each of them is an array.
So we get color one.
So so you can see that how this array how this method is useful because it is going to convert all the
keys, all the key value pairs of this array into string of this object into arrays.
Right.
And it is going to return them as array items.
So they're no longer key value pairs, they're just array items that we can access through the for each
loop.
So I'm just going to say entries that are for each where is it.
So entries for each today misspell anything because it should show it.
So entries dot for each.
It doesn't.
So I guess it should work.
And we're going to say entry and what do we want to do?
We just want to consider log that entry.
So save it.
And we get this first array and this is the first key value pair.
And then we get the second array, which is the second key value pair, and then we get the third array,
which is the third value pair.
OK, and we can get, for example, the index of them as well.
For example, just index the zero indices.
We can get the first index index.
All right.
And and I think this is going to be it for this year.
So let's give it one more time.
And that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.