Hi, everyone, in this letter, we're going to delete listed superheros.
All right, so this is the part where I'm going to tell you, if you don't want to use font awesome
icons and if you if you wanna use anything else, how you can still make it work and how you can still
make the deletion process complete.
Right.
So first off, for example, if you want to use a simple anchor tag or if you want to use anything,
just make sure you add it here and give it like a class to because we are going to grab it by the class
and then do some dumb traversing and then we are going to delete it.
All right.
So make sure you give it a specific class as far as the eye, the item, the e-mail element itself is
concerned.
It doesn't really matter what you use.
So just put it right here.
Just make sure it's in the correct format.
And once that happens, what we are going to do is we are going to now because we want to grab the listed
item.
So if I just go ahead and take a look at that, what that is.
So let me grab this.
Let's just click here.
So now we are in here.
All right.
So now you can see that inside this class, which we have created in inside this div, we have a will
and inside the other we have this icon.
All right.
And excuse me.
And this icon is generated dynamically.
So this is going to make our work a little bit trickier to grab it, because if it were directly inside
the HTML, that would have been easier.
But because it isn't done that way, it makes our work a little bit trickier.
So first off, we are going to grab the parent, which is which we are just going to call it less data.
And if you remember, we have also selected that.
So this is actually the parent.
So I could just grab it from there and put it right here.
Right.
And we are going to sell this data that add event listeners that add a wellness center.
We are listening for a click and when the click happens, we want to run a certain function.
Now, first off, let's go ahead and let's take a look at that e that event object associated with this
click.
So now if I add superheros here and if I go to the console and if I click, you can see that we get
all this information.
Now we want to trace back to this trash.
So if I were to go inside the target and from Target, if I go inside the class name, you can see that
we get that specific class name.
That's why I told you guys give it a specific class name.
You can provided a specific IED name.
You can't do it that way as well.
But I'm going to do it.
So we are going to grab this.
So it was inside Iida Target that Klausner ads copy this class name.
Let's come here.
So f if the thing that you know what, I'm just going to store it inside of inside a variable.
So we are going to say f the thing.
Which is e that we have hopes if the thing that we have clicked on, come on, we have clicked on has
a class.
Name, which is equal to this, what do we want to do so we want to implement this whenever we have
specifically clicked on that icon, we don't want to remove that entire list.
When that entire superheroine we click on the for example, the name of the superhero or the universe,
we want to remove it whenever we have clicked on it.
So if the thing that we have clicked on has a class of this that we have inserted, then let's go ahead
and let's store this class because we are going to use it.
So consed, I'm just going to call it trash and I'm going to put it.
Now what is that.
OK, so we have so the thing that we have clicked on, if it has a class of trash this class, if has,
if it has this class, what do we want to do with it now before doing anything with that, I want to
consult something.
Now I know I told you guys that we are going to keep it under five minutes, but for this particular
situation, I'm not I don't think that it's a good idea because we are actually in the middle of something
and it's not finished.
And I don't want to interrupt the I don't want to ruin the continuity of this lecture.
So we are going to keep going.
So now what I want to do is.
Actually go over the idea.
So now we have successfully grabbed that Troche icon, and when we click on that Troche icon, what
is it that we really what is it that we want to delete?
So let's let's take a closer look at that.
So when I click on it, you know what?
We are going to go and check it out here.
So inside the e-mail, it's my way better.
So what is it that we want to click?
Sorry, we want to remove for that to work perfectly fine.
We need to have more than one variable, more than one item.
So now we can see that each item actually is housed within one year.
Well, that's how I intended it to be.
So if I want to remove this superhero Superman, I need to remove the entire well, if I want to remove
Rockit, I need to remove the you for the rocket.
So I hope you're following this is how we intended to create it.
So this is the icon we have successfully traced our icon to here.
So when I click on this, I want to go one level up and I want to remove that level up.
That level off is either called parent node or parent element.
Either way, it works fine.
But I'm going to use Paran note.
I think it sounds cooler.
So if I were to now click on it.
So if I come here and if I click on it, let's remove this and let's click on it.
We get this event fire.
So when this event fires, so we want to grab the target's parent.
So either target.
This is the target.
What is the parent node of that target?
And we want to remove that.
So if I come into here so you can see that we get the you see, so it doesn't matter if you say that
parent element or dot parent note, both of them return the same thing.
And if you open them, they are going to have the same almost the same properties and functions on them.
So if I say e da target, dot parent node, what do you think it is going to give us?
It is going to give us the USA.
And that's exactly what we want to delete.
See.
So in order to delete a complete superhero, because all these list items are actually housed within
this, well, we need to delete that specific user.
Right, so things are getting easy, so now I'm going to grab this and I'm going to delete this console
log and I'm going to say const trash.
This very simple, we want to trust that, and now we are going to say trash, there is a method called
remove.
Simple, very, very simple stuff here.
So now let's say Superman, DC and fly, let's save it.
So now when I click on this, so if I click here, nothing happens, right.
And I'm going to log to the console something.
Oops.
Uh.
Deletion success, I want to log this to the council as well.
So now let's create our SUPAMAN.
And so it doesn't matter where you click, as long as you click on something that has a class of ASFA
trash.
So when you click on it, you can see that the superhero is deleted.
It no longer exists in here.
And it says deletion success.
And if you come to the HTML.
And if we come to the last to the less detail, you can see that it is empty.
There is no arrow next to it.
It's empty because that superhero was deleted.
Now.
As far as the deletion of the superheros are concerned, we are done all right.
So we are done with the process of deleting them.
However, we are going to come back to this code because when we implement our local storage, we want
when we delete that, when we head that trash icon not only deleted from the UI, but also deleted from
the local storage and also update the local storage, tell the local storage.
I just deleted this item.
So go ahead, delete it from there as well.
So.
That's what we are going to do in the next few lectures as far as the application itself is concerned,
if you're not really if you don't really care about their local storage, we are done with this application.
But I do care about local storage.
And I think we need to at least have some idea of how we can store something somewhere.
Right, until we get to, like, complicated stuff.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is starting our next series of lectures because we are effectively done with
this.
We are going to start working with the local storage and the store superhero class.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.