Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to talk about the key event events and the event object.
All right.
So we have talked about the click of the mouse events, like when the user clicks, user double clicks,
user mouse over, mouse is out.
What about keyboard?
So these events, they're related to the keyboard.
When the key is pressed, we have an event for that.
That is the key down.
When the key is released and key comes towards the top, that is key up.
We have an event for that.
And when the key is is like is like pressed, just like it's pressed, we have an event for that as
well.
So we have a key down.
When the key is pressed down, we have a key up when the key comes towards the top.
When you release the key and when the key is pressed, simply pressed, we have an event for all three
of them.
So first first things first.
Let's talk about the first keyboard event, which is key down.
All right, so for this, what I'm going to do is I have created in the HTML and put element because
we are working with the keyboard, what are what better way than creating an input element?
So what I'm going to do is, first off, I'm going to grab our element, our input for element.
So we are going to say text input.
This is the name of the variable and we are going to say document that query selector and we are going
to say now we can.
There are a number of ways that we can grab that element.
The the way that I am going to grab it is going to be by its attribute and we are going to say grab
an element that has an attribute of type which is equal to.
It has type of text, save it and we can consider log it.
Text input.
Let's save it and voila, we have successfully implemented that, we have successfully selected that.
Now we have, if you remember right in the first lecturer's of the donc, we talked about how if you
want to do something with the dome, first we have to select and then we have to manipulate it.
Now, the selection part is done, the manipulation part is still remain.
So we are going to say to extend that at Eventless in the event this time is going to be key down.
And when the key is pressed down, we don't care if the key is released or not.
We just care when the user presses the key.
That's when the user presses the key towards the down key is pressed down.
That's when the event is going to fire, because for a key up when the key is released, we have another
event.
We are going to say console dat lock, we are just going to simply say ke down.
Key down, simple, so when I click here and when I press one, we're going to say.
And if I hold it, you guys aren't going to see that this is actually increasing because I'm keep on
keeping I kept pressing down.
The key I'm in the grammar is really difficult with this event listeners.
So let's let's go ahead and reload the page.
And in here, when I press any key, when I press it towards the bottom, it is going to fire that event.
Right.
The event is going to fire.
And this is the key down event.
Right.
I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to cancel comment that one out.
And now let's go ahead and let's talk about the key up now.
The key event only works when the key is released.
So let's go ahead and let's change it up and let's change this one two up as well.
All right.
So let's save it and let's click here.
So if I press it, nothing is going to change, even though we can see a lot of ones there.
But when I release it, it says press key up.
So I'm just going to reload.
So when I press it, nothing changes when I release it as this key up, key up, key up, key up.
So key up only works when the key is released.
Key down works when the key is pressed down, when the key is down, key up works when the key is up.
That's how simple it is.
So but the cool thing about these two events is it doesn't matter which key you press.
So even if I if I hit shift and if I release it, it is going to say that it is going to fire an event.
So I'm grabbing the assault on my keyboard and I'm pressing it down.
And when they release it, I'm just going to have to click somewhere.
So when I proceed down and when I release, it is going to say keep right.
And if I come this far out and come in this part and and now I am pressing the art and it is going to
say key down, key down is click the key down the second time, click their key down.
Key click there, because it happens only on the input, so I should be clicked in inside then.
Now I'm pressing the function key on the keyboard.
It doesn't work the control.
It does work.
That's why you can say this to anyone.
It is a counter, the alt.
It goes somewhere else.
The control works.
The arrow keys also work.
The shift key also works.
The function key I think also works.
It is increasing or decreasing the volume on the left.
It is increasing and decreasing the brightness.
They also work.
Now this one doesn't work.
So this is key down.
It doesn't.
It also works whenever you're not actually pressing a you're not actually typing something.
But what if you want only to capture the user input when the user has typed something, that's when
the key press comes into play.
So let's grab this one.
Let's put it here and let's grab the key up.
And you're going to say keep press, let's save it.
And it's like this in coming this end.
And now when I say MusclePharm, we are going to say we are going to see six key presses.
And when I when I just go ahead and reload it, when I hit control, it doesn't do anything.
It's not firing.
It's not firing what I do, comma.
It is going to fire when I do that.
It is going to fire when I do.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
It is going to fire.
But when I do control, it's not going to fire because control is not something real time inside the
input field.
This is the difference between these three.
And finally, I want to talk about the event object itself for which the comment is this.
Now we have an event object.
We do have events and we have an event object.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to take a look at what is the event object.
And for that, we need a very, very big window for our.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to do an event listener.
So, for example, let's grab I'm just going to copy and paste it here and and in this part.
And we are going to listen for a click inside the input and it's going to say click and the console.
But this time the function is going to have a parameter.
So let me like go ahead and reduce the width of this window a little and increase this one.
So this time this function is going to have a parameter of E and now when I click, it is going to say
click.
But I don't want to say in the console, I don't want to say click.
I just want to return the key itself.
So when I click, this is the mouse event, see, so this is the event object.
It is going to give us a lot of useful information which we are going to use in our project is going
to give you a client X, client Y, where client X and Y give you the exact coordinates where you collect
inside that input.
So if I click somewhere, right.
If I click on the start, OK, we should have another client.
So Client X is ten and client Y is nineteen.
If I click at the end, Client X is 174 and client Y is seventeen.
All right.
So it's going to give you direct, like real and exact place where you have clicked.
We have path.
Let's see, we have timestamp, we have Target, which is a really, really, really important one,
which we are going to use a la target, especially in our gallery carousel project.
We're going to use Target.
And it is impressive and it's always it's even going to tell you what event, what event does it classify
as.
So if I go ahead and if I say target, let's save it and let's collect it is going to give us what is
the target that we have clicked on?
It is the target is the target is going to return the element.
So if we come here and if we take a look at the target, the target, the input, because some because
we want to find out what is exactly that we have clicked on.
Is it an element?
Is it something else?
What is it that we have clicked on and we want to grab that element.
So this element, we want to grab it and we want to apply some sort of logic on it.
All right, and we could also go ahead and take a look at the key, so the key when I click the key
is undefined.
We don't have any key for this one.
So let's come here and see if we can find the key.
And we can look for Client X. So I'm just going to copy it and I'm going to paste it right here and
I'm going to save it.
So Client X is 80.
We can look for client Y as well.
So we are going to get one one, one, two and two one.
So this is actually the event object, we could also call it event itself, and we can just grab it
from here.
You know what?
I'm just going to click here, hold and click here, here and here.
And it is event.
And it should still work.
Yes, it does work.
We could call it evt.
That is a common convention as well.
And if you click it, everything is going to work.
But I usually just go ahead and I just call it.
You just call it E e.
S shoulder, and it's not a mouthful like event or event, and it looks better.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.