Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to talk about Dundar, Protoje.
All right, so what is Dundar Protoje before getting there, so here on line number 10?
I have a console lock that says is dot constructor equals triple equal, which is district equality.
Operator equals the workshop function.
Now, before asking before answering this, let's go ahead and let's take a look at the prototype chain.
So this is our largest object and we have said that constructor so does this JS object has a constructor
property on it now.
So when we don't find a property on an object, what do we do?
We go one level up the prototype chain, we go to the Aske object.
Does this one have a constructor property on it?
Yes.
And what is it pointing at?
It is pointing at the workshop.
So Jayce object actually has a constructor prototype constructor property.
It comes from, it comes, it went one level up the prototype chain to find it the same way as the ASC
method.
But there is one constructor and that what is that constructor.
That constructor is going to be our workshop function.
So if I were to come here and to save this, that is just that constructor equals workshop we should
get through.
So if I save it, we are going to get through.
And it comes from line number 10.
Right.
So let's come to line number 11.
Here we have I'm not going to save it.
I'm just going to come commented.
And here we have Geass dot, dot, underscore, underscore, Proteau underscore, underscore.
This is very long.
It's a very long name.
Right.
So what we could do is we could say double underscore Proteau and then underscore or we could shorten
it to double under or we could say Dundar.
OK, so double under some cool developers, they call it Dundar Protozoan.
Guess you see it somewhere.
They're basically referring to this GETER function.
OK, so if I were to save this line number 12, we are going to get true as well.
And why is that?
Let's take a look at this one more time.
So this is our JavaScript.
Sorry, this is our religious object.
Now, I hope you're not getting confused.
This is the the newly created object.
This is not like JavaScript.
This is just like I'm just going to you know what?
I'm just going to grab it and I'm going to say just class.
So it is not confused with the language itself.
I'm just going to suggest class and I'm going to say.
We are going to get through, but if I come here and let's assess, why do we get through?
So this this should be just class as well.
I should I don't know if I can edit this.
I created this in paint, so I should go back and I recreate it.
But you get the idea.
This is deejay's class object.
So this J.s class object, does it have a Dundar proud on it, a go getter function on?
No.
So what it what it is going to do, it is going to go one level up the prototype chain.
Does this workshop prototype have it, Dundar Proteau?
No, it doesn't.
So it is going to go one level up one more time to the main JavaScript object.
Now keep in mind this the object function on the left and this main JavaScript object object, they
are available to us.
It doesn't matter if you run the code or not.
That's why they're called line zero environment.
They are available to us.
Right.
Does this mean that GS have a Dundar Proteau on it?
Yes, it does.
And if we come here, I've provided you with the link.
You can see that we have our object, which is in capital o object dot prototype.
So this is object dot prototype then what it is referring to.
It is referring to this object.
It has a prototype property, but it is actually deprecated, but it is still used in JavaScript.
I'm going to show you where it is used.
All right.
And this is even though it's a prop., it is actually a GETER function.
So if we come here and I told you that the prototype and the spec is Brocket bracket prototype.
Right.
So where can we find it?
OK, is a GETER function and a setter function.
So this main object does have this property on it, which is actually an a function, even though there
are no parentheses, but it is a function.
So unlike no.
What is 12.
If I suggest class dot Dundar Proteau, we are actually invoking this GETER function and when we invoke
that GETER function, why is it equal to the work of that prototype for that?
We need to come in this to align and so we can see why is it equal to that.
So just Dundar Proteau.
It is going to.
OK, so this one should be just class as well.
Class.
Let's say that we get an ask function which is inside this object.
What is this object?
This object has been created by the new keyword.
We have talked about that a lot.
But if I click here, you can see that the Dundar Proteau is or the prototype is the object.
So this is actually an object.
Right.
And if I were and you can see that it is the constructor of function, ask is also a function.
Constructor is also a function.
And if we can if we come here, we can see that we have our aske function, which is right here, and
then we have our constructor, which is the workshop.
And if I click, all the information is going to be is going to be inserted here.
So now it comes from line number 14.
If I were to say workshop that prototype now for first stuff, what is workshop that prototype.
So this is workshop.
This is a prototype.
We know whenever we say something that prototype, we are referring to this main JavaScript object.
And does this mean JavaScript object?
Have an ask method on it?
Yes, it does.
So we are going to get the same results as this one.
And if I say it, we get exactly the same result in is an object.
We have an ask method and we have the constructor workshop.
And why do we get the same thing for JS classes?
Because when this Jayce class, it goes wonderful up.
What do we get?
We get the Aske method.
That's why both of them are equal.
All right, and now there is actually another property on the object function that is going to give
us the prototype of whatever we pass.
So if I save it, we can see that the prototype of the jazz class is actually the same function, the
same thing that we have done here.
So Prototype and Dundar Proteau are actually the same thing.
And if I were to do this, we are going to get through once more.
All right.
So I just wanted to go over this Proteau as well.
You have the link.
You can go ahead and read more about it, even though it is deprecated, but it is still used in JavaScript.
You can see it right here.
It is going to give us the prototype.
If you have seen it before and you don't know why is it written like this weird thing that is this is
Proteau underscore, underscore, Proteau underscore, underscore.
What is it now?
You know what it is?
It is.
It is actually the prototype of whatever it is that we are going to pass inside of it.
Right.
And the prototype is actually referring to the main JavaScript object.
That's why we are going to get an object in here.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.