Hi, everyone, in this picture, we are going to clean up our code using promises.
All right, so this is the code that we had from our callback.
Hell, where are you?
This code that we had and I've just copied and pasted it right here.
Right.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to use promises to take a look at how this callback can
be resolved.
So let's look where this actually ends.
It ends right here.
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to delete all that.
You're going to save it.
All right.
So now what are we going to do?
Is inside this get questions function?
We are going to instantiate a new promise.
But in this case, we are going to return the new promise.
So return new promise to keywords are made available to us, and that is resolve and reject.
And then we are going to run this function.
So now everything in here.
I mean, like everything is going to come right here.
That's it.
All right, why do we have errors?
OK, so we have worries there, Arakan state, oh, this area is missing, perfect, so now everything's
right here.
Now we are not using callbacks anymore, so I'm going to get rid of the callback from here and in here
instead of passing a callback.
Now, this is where the request is successful, right?
So instead of passing a callback, we are going to pass on the resolve function.
So resolve what do we want to do?
We want to grab our questions retrieved.
And in here, instead of passing again the same callback, we are going to pass and reject.
So this is where the where the HDP request is resolved.
This is where it is rejected.
So in here, we are going to do reject and I'm just going to say the same thing.
Error, fetching data.
Right.
So everything else works in the same way we have been able to clean up our code a little bit now what
we are going to do is we need to call our get questions.
So I'm going to go outside of it, which is right here.
Right.
And we are going to call them.
So I'm going to do this in two steps.
So you really understand what we are doing here.
So first off, let's go ahead and let's say get questions.
All right.
So inside here, because this question has one parameter.
It requires an argument, which is the value of that parameter.
So this parameter is actually the question source for which is actually the request.
You are a source.
What is the source?
The source is going to be the same thing.
We go into the questions folder.
Questions folder.
And from there, we are going to grab the six questions come, by the way, to respond that questions
one dash to dot Jason, Jason.
All right.
So we grab that.
So now we are done with this.
After that, I'm just going to toss in a dot then in here.
Now, this dot then is going to be resolved or is going to be used when the process started, when they
promised, not the process, when the promise is either resolved or rejected.
So what we are going to do here is.
First off, I'm just going to make a request to this single file, to the single file, and then we
are going to resolve and reject it, and then I'm going to show you how you can make requests to multiple
API endpoints.
So in here, we are just going to pass on the questions.
Come on, so we are going to pass on the questions data if the promise is resolved and what do we want
to do with that?
We want to say, Consul Locke, we want to grab our questions data now because we are going to have
five different data for our questions we have because we have five different files.
I'm going to try to keep up with them.
So I'm going to say I'm going to print a string as well.
Which six questions?
One, one, two, three, one to two.
And then we are going to print the questions data, questions date.
So this one is done right now.
What we are going to do is we are going to tag on the data catch as well.
So we are going to say that catch this is going to take this is going to be called this function is
called whenever this elusive block.
It runs whenever we get an error.
Right.
So if I were to go ahead and complete this, I would just write error.
And what do we want to do with this error?
We just want to say we just want to log it to the console.
So console the log and I'm going to print a little message as well.
I'm just going to say rejected.
And then we are going to pass and our error should probably put in a comma here, so let's save it and
let's make the smaller.
OK, so let's.
Keep the smaller as well.
Scared to console.
Now, if I click on this, you can see that we get I should shouldn't make this zoom zoom out.
I'm not sure if you can see it clearly.
And that is not a good thing that the teachers do when they zoom out.
So I'm just going to do this.
But you know what I mean?
Like, if I zoom out, this is what we get.
So we get questions wanted to do and we also get our questions.
So we were able to do to make this request using promises.
We can see we can see that we have used promises, but there is something missing.
We have five files or we have five API endpoints.
What if you want to make a request to those now before doing that, let's for example, let's say we
have questions.
We have a file that is questions one to five.
We don't have that sort of file.
So let's say, well, let's see what we get.
So if I click on this, we can see that we get our error error.
We rejected error, fetching data error, fetching data because the reddest state was four, but the
HTTP status is four or four.
See, that's why we get this error.
So it's nice that we can see that this reject and resolve without commenting them out, like in a previous
lecture they work.
So I'm just going to go ahead and remove this one to five.
Just put it back to one to two.
And when I click, we make this request.
So now let's go ahead and let's implement the second step.
So the first step was just to warm you up so as to what we are going to do here that's going to come
in that one.
So this was the warm up state in step step and this step, we are going to make requests to all five
of those files.
All right.
So now you know how these actually work.
So I'm just going to breeze over them.
So we have get questions for this.
We are going to pass in a path to our questions, which I'm just going to grab it from there and I'm
going to put it right here.
And then we are going to add the dot.
Then dot then is going to be added when we want to resolve the promise.
I'm just going to grab the questions data and put it right here.
Now, there is only there is going to be only like two things different.
And I'm going to explain to you what those two things are and basically the rest of the stuff they are
going to be like this, only two things.
So we are going to.
Uh.
Questions.
This is incorrect, misspelled, I just misspelled.
Just ignore that I'm going to correct it in here and say questions, questions.
All right, so we are going to say consult, log.
And what do we want to log to the council?
We want to log almost the same message.
We are going to say question one to two and then we're going to grab our questions data.
All right.
So now so we have selected our first API endpoint in this case or our first U.
URL.
What?
How can we select the second?
So we are going to do it a different way.
So in here, the way that we do it with promises is we are going to return the other promises.
So the promise, they get questions, they get questions which should handle question number three and
four or the second file that is going to be returned.
All right.
So we are going to say return.
Return what?
Now, keep in mind that we are still inside this dot then, right?
We are.
We are still inside this.
Right.
I'm going to explain to you why we are still inside.
So we are going to grab our questions.
And in here, I'm going to pass in the path for the second file that we want to grab or the second API
endpoint.
And I'm going to change it to three and to four.
Right.
So this is the second file and we are basically just returning this now.
When we return this this quest get questions function when we call it and when we return it, it is
going to return a promise.
Right.
And when this returns, I promise this entire thing all the way to here, it is going to return a promise.
And when this entire thing returns a promise, we can we can put another dot and at the end of the initial
dot and so does then.
So not that end.
We can put another dot then at the end of the initial one.
So I'm just going to say that the reason that this is going to work is because this entire block is
going to is going to return.
I promise.
This then only works when we have returned a promise like in this case.
So we have returned a promise.
That's why the original DOT then worked and now we are returning.
And again, another promise.
That's why the second Dudin is going to work.
And in here, we're going to add questions, data.
Right, and let's create the error function.
What is this error function going to do?
The error function is going to do basically the same things.
So it is going to grab our question is going to print question three and four and then print the questions
as well.
Now we are going to create we are going to return this, get questions once more.
But instead of looking for for the same API endpoint, we are going to look for a different API input.
This is how we make requests to multiple files using promises.
Now, we saw how callback, how they worked.
Now this is how promises and this is also called promise chaining.
Now, whenever I say return, get questions, six questions, five and six.
This is going to return a promise and in and resulting in this entire thing, return and give promise
so I can add another dot then as well.
So now you know how this works, right?
So questions we have questions.
Data are going to create our error function.
We are going to do the same thing in here until we are done.
So this time I'm going to call it questions five and six.
Because this is going to return questions five and six and just going to remove I'm just going to cut
this because this is going to return questions five and six.
And when it returns that, what do we want to do with that?
So you can see that first the promise is returned, then we say what we want to do with that.
Don't be confused with this, like in the first case.
So if I were to like, I don't know, what should I do here?
So I'm just going to create a comment, put the code that I you know what?
I don't need to put this code here.
So I'm I'm going to grab this.
I'm going to grab all this right, I know it's going to throw an error, but I'm just going to put it
here.
Because I want to explain something now, keep this only this in mind and I'm going to zoom in, I guess
that's a lot.
Increase the largest.
So what happens here now, this gett questions, this part that I've highlighted, it is going to return
a promise.
That's why we can add a dot then method on it when we return.
Get questions.
Aren't we stating the same thing?
We are saying return another promise.
That's why we can add a dot.
Then after that, promises return.
Keep in mind the dot then or dot catch they are added when the promise has already been returned.
So the dot then relating this promise comes after the promise in the same case that we had a promise
here and the dot then came after it.
So this is the promise and the dot then came after.
It works in the same way we have a promise, then comes after it.
So in this this way, you're not confused, right?
So in here what we have is now we are we are returning another promise.
And this time it is going to be questions seven and eight while zooming is really cool, zooming in.
So when that returns a promise, this entire thing is going to return the promise.
So we are we can just say dot then and in here we can graph questions, data.
And what what do we do with questions, data, while we can't allow it right?
So in this case, we are going to say seven and eight and we logged the console to the council.
Now, what do we want to do is we want to return yet another promise.
And that promise is going to be the last one questions.
Number nine and 10.
We are making requests to this.
You are out.
So this is a are we are again making requests to multiple earths.
And what is this going to do?
It is going to when we do return, they promise this is going to be return as a promise so we can add
a dot then method to it and we are going to run and grab the questions data.
And finally, we can say cancer lock in here.
All right.
So we are just going to say console this time.
It is going to be questions nine and 10.
So you might be asking where are I'm just going to zoom out to this level.
I'm sure this is still readable because we need to work in two different windows.
All right, so like this so what is what is the catch, where do we grab where do we catch our error?
So the good thing about promise chaining is whenever you whenever you chain all these promises, you
just go ahead and add a dart catch at the end.
And this error is going to catch any error, whether that is in the first API endpoint, in the second
opinion point in the third one and the fourth one or in the fifth one.
So this dot catch is going to work for all of them.
So we don't have to specify error and catch error and data all the time, we can just specified once.
What do we want this to do?
We just want to log it to the council at this stage.
Grab our air.
What is there going to be, the air is going to be this.
All right, so what else do we have here?
So I think we are done here, let's save it.
So the the format rearranges it, which is very helpful.
So we have Doug, then Doug and Doug, then we are we are having as many then as many.
You are requests that we are making.
So if I click on this, we can see that we are grabbing all of them.
So I'm just going to increase this.
We have questions.
One, two questions, three, four questions.
Five, six, seven, eight, nine and ten.
And if you click on any of them, you are going to get the data inside them.
So this is an array of objects.
The Proteau, it says array and all these array methods are right.
And it's, for example, inside this, we have our choices and then we have the question itself.
So this is actually how we would use promises to clean up code.
All right, so I think I think we are done here.
So this was step one.
This is not really necessary for you to do this was necessary for me to do so.
I could, like, convey the point of promises better.
But this is actually what we done, what we have done.
This is a much cleaner code, a much clearer, cleaner syntax.
Of course, there are other ways of doing even better than this, which we are going to dive into.
But for now, this is the best way that we have so far learned when it comes to callbacks and when it
comes to promises.
That's it for this lecture.
And see you in the next one.