Hi, everyone.
In this next year, we are going to create our chart.
All right, so let's go ahead and let's dive into this chart.
So what is the XHTML element that is involved with that?
There is only one d'Hiv, which has a class of chart, but there is nothing inside of it.
So we are going to create a canvas element dynamically and we are going to appended to this chart element
chart diff.
All right.
So I'm going to say CONSED chart should be equal to let's grab our dif our very, very lonely diff.
So we are going to say query selecter.
What is the class.
The class name is Chart.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to say consed.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a canvas element.
So I'm going to say document dot, create element.
So we are creating an element.
And what is the element name.
The element.
Name is canvas now that we have created the canvas.
Let's go ahead and let's give it dimensions.
Dimensions.
Right.
You're going to say canvas dust height should be equal to 120 pixels and canvas dot with it should be
equal to 120 pixels because we need to grab a like.
Like, Square kind of lost the war, and I'm sure you remember that we had a canvas inside the success
and the canvas had a border of one pixel, white and solid.
The reason that I did that was to visualize our canvas.
I know we cannot still see it.
We cannot still see it because we don't know where the canvas is.
Actually, right now.
We should appended the canvas has been created inside the JavaScript, but it has no physical actual
relationship with any HTML element.
So we are going to grab our chart and we're going to say append child, please adopt this child.
What is the name of the child canvas without quotes.
So because canvas, this is a valid JavaScript identifier within it, we don't need quotes, so this
is where our canvas is going to be present, is going to come.
This is where it is going to look like it is going to be created.
And that's why I did a border, because I just wanted to visualize where the canvas is and how I can
create a circle inside the canvas.
So what I'm going to do here, as I'm going to I know we have not officially started talking about Kashima
five canvas.
I'm I will make sure towards the end of this course that I will include chapters four or five canvas
like drawing and animating so we can create like awesome games in this course, which we are, because
in case you're like interested in game development, then you can go ahead and go down that route with
JavaScript as well.
So I want to I want to do that.
But for now, we are just focusing on the project at hand, which is the budget app, not the canvas
aspect of it.
Of course, I'm going to be explaining it, but officially we will be starting a later initializing
a 2D context.
Now, whenever we say canvas, we can only draw 2D and canvas.
So a height and a width.
I know using those two dimensions we can like.
Elusively, we can create 3D objects, but the actual context is going to be 2D like a height and and
width, so we need to initialize that.
So we are going to say const.
And I'm going to call it context.
I could call it like a context.
Usually it is called Sirtex, but I think this is not correct because it starts with a number.
So you know what I'm going to say context to.
All right.
Let's see if it works.
So canvas, does it get context?
So we have talked about this method.
Get context.
What is the method?
I've also given you the the resources for this.
So it says the identifier idea of the type of canvas to create Internacional or whatever 2D context
using canvas that give context to.
Right.
It gives you a lot of information that you do not need.
So now we have created this context.
Let's go ahead and let's grab the context and let's provided with a line with.
So what is the line with the line with is going to be ten pixels.
What is going to be the radius of the circle?
The radius of the circle is going to be 50, not pixels, just 50.
All right, let's provide some space there and now let's actually draw our.
Circle draw, circle function.
All right, so we are going to create a function, we are going to call draw a circle called a draw
circle.
So we are going to pass in a parameter as an argument.
Color as a parameter.
A ratio.
Because the circle is going to be divided between the income and the outcome, we need some sort of
a ratio there and there is another another what should I call it?
Another key word with the ARC method that we have.
And that is going to tell us what there was, whether the circle should move clockwise or counterclockwise.
Right.
So antique clock.
Anti clock.
Why so it says anticlockwise.
If anticlockwise is true, it is going to start going like from right.
All the way to like bottom like top left.
So, so if I come here.
So it is going to start from here and is going to go there this way.
This is anticlockwise.
And if it is clockwise, if anticlockwise is false it is going to go clockwise of course.
And it's going to start from here and go like this.
Be like that.
All right.
So in here, first off, you're going to grab our context and we are going to say stroke style.
What is the stroke style?
The stroke style is going to be the color.
Where is the color coming from?
The color is actually these colors because we have specified a certain color for income and a certain
color for expense.
So we are going to use these colors and these colors.
They're going to be universal.
So you can see that this is green.
This is tomato.
Tomato.
All right, so this is the stroke style for this circle to work or to start drawing, we should tell
it to begin path, right?
And now we should provide it with the information, with the actual coordinates.
Where do we want to start?
How big should it be?
What what is the radius size?
What is the line with?
What is the starting angle?
The ending angle, everything.
So the arc first off, we need the X and we need the Y.
OK, so the X, the the X should be 60 half of the canvas dimensions.
The Y coordinates should also be 60.
Next we have radius, we have specified the radius there up top and then we have start angle, start
angle is angle is going to be zero and then we have the end angle.
The angle is going to be math dot pi times two, which is going to give us 360 degrees and we are going
to multiply it by ratio.
Now ratio is going to specify which amount of the circle should be a should be adjusted for the income
and which amount should be adjusted for the outcome.
We are going to define the ratio.
Don't worry about it.
And we are going to pass in the anticlockwise, all right, so this this is going to create a circle
for us, but we need to tell it to start creating as well.
That's why we're going to say stroke as well.
So you know what?
Before doing anything else, I want to call this draw circle function.
Now, I'm going to pass in three arguments.
So the first argument is going to be color.
So let's pass and read.
The second argument is going to be ratio and I'm going to pass in zero point five.
The third argument is going to be anticlockwise, which is a boolean expression.
Right anticlockwise is a boolean expression, either true or false.
So if I say false, it means that anticlockwise is not true, meaning that we are moving clockwise like
this.
Like that.
I know you can't see it, but, you know, I'm basically showing it to myself.
So if I come here, we can see this.
So this movement is actually clockwise and the color is red and this is the line with which is 10 pixels.
And this this is the start angle is is going to be right here.
This is the radius.
And then we are going to have a 360 degree rotation, which is the math that PI two and the ratio is
going to say how much ratios should be specified for the income and how much for the outcome, because
ratio is point five.
We have 360 degrees here.
Times point five, we are going to get 180.
That's why we see half a circle.
So if I if I set it to point to five, we should see a quarter of a circle.
We see a quarter of a circle, like a half of half of a circle, right.
So this is going to be a ratio and I'm going to show you if the anticlockwise is true.
So if this is true and you know what?
I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to give it a green.
So they are really distinguishable.
So this is anticlockwise.
This is true.
And you can see that it comes here.
So it doesn't matter what the ratio I've specified here, it is going to grab all of the circle because
we need a circle.
At the end of the day, we are going to create a circle.
So, of course, this was just for experimentation purposes.
What I'm going to do here is I'm going to create another function and I'm going to call it up date chart
y update chart, because we are going to call this function inside.
This Abduh file.
And we want to call it whenever we update the UI so that I'm going to do in the next lecture.
See you guys then.