Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we will handle the game over and the speed multiplication.
All right, so first things first that made me collapse all these functions, so there is none of them
open here.
Because they take a lot of space.
So first things first in here, what I would like to do is I want to add a game over conditional and
I'm going to add their.
So it is going to be the game over conditional, so just just game over.
So if the game.
If the game over is not true, it means that the game is not over, then I would like to call all these
functions.
So let's grab all of them and let's put them there.
Let's see if the game over is true.
We do not want to call all of them.
We just want to say, like, game over and that's it, right.
And right after that.
Let's go over the drawing, drawing the game over, right, and that is going to be handled by our draw
text function.
So in here, right beneath everything.
OK, I'm going to say drawing the just destroying game over.
So if game over is true, so if game over is true, what it is that we want to do.
First off, we need to decide which text, if the game is over, which text do we want to show?
We want to show the text of when or the text of the game over.
So for that, I'm going to say let text.
We are going to say if when is true, we are going to show the text when, if, if, when is false,
we are going to show the text of game over.
Is that.
There we go.
We will be testing this as well.
So don't worry about it.
And just in just a moment and in here, we are going to grab our context.
We're going to say Phonte, and it's something like this.
So I'm just going to copy it from here and I'm going to put it right here.
So it is going to be these text size times, too.
So a little bit bigger of a text.
Then we will have our text, a line of center.
We want it to be in the center of the page horizontally.
And now we're is actually the position.
So we are going to say context fell.
Phil text.
So what is going to be the text, the strength, it is going to be text that we have specified up there,
what what is going to be the exposition?
The exposition is going to be right in the middle of the page horizontally.
So that's where we've put it.
So we want it to be on top of the panel.
So why am I going there?
So if I come here, if I had the ball, if I leave it to go down, if I had it one more time, leave
it to go down.
You can see that this is this is game over and I exactly wanted to be right here.
So the horizontal part is taken care of.
The vertical is going to be on top of the paddle.
So the paddles y position minus the text size times, too, right.
So that's the position.
And the width is going to be Max with.
Perfect.
Let's save it and I don't think we we are going to be able to see it, so let's wait for it.
And Ms.
Let's just leave it.
Let's see what we get.
There we go.
We can see this is now this is game over.
When the game is over, you can see that we get the game over text and the breaks.
They stayed the same way.
We do not want to recreate the bricks, but when you hit space, you can see that it is not like calling
or serving another game.
So there is no way to actually.
But for the final application when you had space, you're going to get another excuse me, another round
of like play.
All right, so.
We got that as well out of the way, so there it is, our game over.
So what I would like to do next is let's go ahead and let's actually be able to press, enter and see
something happen.
So what I would like to do is, first off, I want to go to my key down event.
So in here we have a key of 32.
This is going to be the space responsible for serving the ball after checking after running disserve
ball function.
I would love to check if game over is true, then called the new game function.
So now we should be able to do something here.
So let me go over there, Servet, again.
And servlet again.
There we go, and now when I press space, it's just started a new game for us, so that is done there
as well.
We need to implement the same thing for the touch as well.
We shouldn't forget that.
So I'm going to go to my touch starts.
So that is complete.
Where have we?
OK, so they're right here.
So in the touch start when the ball is served, it says that the ball is served.
All right.
So in here in our touch start, instead of doing a console log, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
check for game over.
And if it is game over, then we would like to call a new game.
OK, so we should probably go ahead and test this as well.
All right, so in here, what I would like to do is I'm going to go to the mobile and I'm going to click
here.
Let's reload the page.
Why is it not working?
That's open up a life server one more time and let's check it out there.
So in here, let's go to the responsive design mode.
O Touch simulation is off.
So if I click, it should serve the ball.
When it doesn't, it doesn't even move.
I don't know what the problem is.
There is no problem here.
So.
Oh, there we go.
It just required so that was the first one you can see that the score is being updated as well.
So let's put it to something that is better visible.
So like maybe iPhone six, seven, eight, click, let's move away.
We have two lives are lost.
One, life is lost and we have two remaining.
Perfect.
And then the final one remaining.
There we go.
It says, game over and when I click, it is going to create it is going to call the new game function
perfect.
So it is working in the mobile as well.
Next up, what we would like to do is let's go ahead and let's count the we have created this variable,
haven't we?
It is the number six, right, so it is going to give us the number of bricks that we have.
So what I what I would like to do is inside our create bricks function.
So let's go to the create bricks function.
And in here, I would like to find out the number of bricks that we are dealing with.
Right.
And down here I'm going to say no bricks.
So the number of bricks is going to be equal to.
Our columns times rose.
So that is going to give us the number of bricks and then we are going to reduce our number of bricks
by one.
All right.
Each time the user destroys one of them.
So inside our update, bricks function down here.
Close that update, Brooks function, what I would like to do is we are going to grab our SO right after
here in here, what I would like to do is I want to grab our bricks and I'm going to subtract it by
one each time the ball hits it.
And I think you saw whenever the ball hit it, it it destroyed more than one brick at one hit.
But we want to destroy only one brick when there is one hit.
And that's basically what we are doing here.
All right, so we are we also would like to test for the next level.
So what I'm going to do is inside the same function, I'm going to create an if statement and we are
going to level up as well.
Whenever the user destroys all the bricks, we have to level up.
So where should I put this statement?
So out of this loop in here, I'm going to say test for a for the next level.
For the next level.
Now, we know that this is not we don't have an index level.
And I'm just going to go ahead and I'm going to increase the speed of the ball to maybe like seven five
and I'm going to decrease the brick columns to.
Two, one, only, just one, so let's save it.
So if I if I click on it now, you can see that we only have one column.
And if I try to destroy all of the breaks in that one column, let's see if we go ahead.
If we go to a next call.
A next level.
You can see that and you can see here that even though all of the bricks are destroyed, we are not
going to the next level.
So we need we need to go to the next level whenever I'm going to keep it of this.
But then we are going to change it back.
So in here, we should test for the next level f the number of bricks is equal to zero.
What what is it that we want to do?
We want to check if the level first stuff we need to check if we are not already at the maximum level,
if the level is less than the maximum level.
Right, then we are going to grab our level and incremented by one and we are going to call the new
level function as well here, and you can see how handy these functions can get.
All right, and else and what is the asking to do when we are when the number of Bruxner, both of these
conditions are only going to apply when the number of bricks are equal to zero?
We don't have any more bricks.
So if the level is less than the maximum level, we are going to increment it by one.
If the level is going to be either equal to or above that, that is going to be the LS when it is not
less than the maximum level.
So it is either equal to that.
Then we are going to show the game over or and we have to say the when whoever has and we have to say
that the win is true as well and the user has won and then we are going to call in Dinubile function.
So with this.
All right, so what I'm going to do, as if we go off to our draw text function.
Here we go.
We have already drawn the game over is true.
What do we want to do if when is true?
We are going to show this text.
If it is not, we are going to show this text.
We have done all of this.
Now we need to test everything.
So for us to be able to test it better, I'm going to grab the minimum balance angle and I'm going to
set it to 90.
So it's always going to go 90, hopefully.
And now let's set it so 90.
There we go.
I don't have to, like, switch to right and left go.
I don't have to move this anymore.
Now, let's see.
Now we are clearing everything so we should see a win is true and we should see the win text.
Now you can see that we went to the next level.
So this is level one that was zero and this is level one.
Now, if we go ahead and destroy all the breaks we should get, let me put it to one, we should get
OK.
So now this is level zero.
We should get a taste of when.
And I'm going to check for that.
It is going to take some time, of course, but you know what?
Let's go ahead and let's decrease the number of rows to one.
So we are only going to have one row.
So and in the next one, of course, we are going to have to rush.
This is level three already perfect.
There we go.
I could do something else if I don't know if that is possible.
I'm just going to put it to five ball speed, because if you increase it, like, a lot, then then
the frame the frame per second is not going to handle it.
And the ball is just going to go straight through the panel, OK?
And that is in there, you see, this is it's going to be jumping because the screen refresh rate cannot
handle it.
So I'm just going to put it to that, the column and I guess you could fast forward and from now on,
I'm just going to leave it so it does its work.
And you could fast forward.
Or or just as a as I thought, I can decrease the number of levels, so the maximum level is going to
be like, let's say two.
If I do that, that is going to decrease it as well.
What did we did the max level to perfect?
So.
Everything is bigger and you one see, so we get the new one text and losing should be easier than winning.
It always is.
So if I just move away, just do that.
Move away.
That's one loss.
Two losses.
And three losses, we get the game over perfect, so everything seems to work perfectly fine, we are
going to set it to 14.
We are going to set the ball speed zero point four or five.
So we have successfully implemented the game over and the game, what was then the other one, the game
when we have implemented both of them.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a constant and I'm going to call it both speed, max,
ball speed.
OK, this should be capital and Max.
And I'm going to set it to two.
And this is going to be the ball speed.
Max is going to be a multiple of the starting speed.
So now what we are going to do is we are going to go to our we have create I think we have created that
in our class.
So in the ball now, in the break, I think, yeah, we have our speed multiplier.
We already have created it.
But what I would like to do is because whenever we hit any of any row of the breaks, any higher ranking
row of the breaks, we are going to get a speed multiplication.
So for that, what I would like to do is let's go to our create bricks function.
So let's clops that one.
This is draw text.
This should be the create bricks function inside our create bricks function.
All right.
So what I would like to do were should we put it I'm going to put it right here in here.
What I would like to do is I'm going to say speed is speed, multispeed mount.
And you can see that we have already passed it inside the brick.
And we are going to and now we are going to set it.
So we are going to one plus.
Rank high minus the rank, right, and we are going to divide this by the rank high.
Also, we are going to let's put this entire thing inside parentheses, oh, not this one as well.
And we are going to multiply this by the ball speed, Max, minus one.
Now, what does this mean?
It means that I'm going to I'm going to create a comment here so you can really understand what this
means.
So I'm going to say that the red rank is going to be equal to zero.
Then we are going to have the orange, yeah, the second one is orange, the orange rank is going to
be one.
Then we have the yellow, the yellow rank is going to be equal to Sweida, provide rank.
It is going to be equal to two.
It's let us reduce the space there, and finally, the green rank is going to be three and you know
that, right?
So as we come down the ranks, they get higher and the rank high is going to be equal to three.
So it is going to be three for our first level.
As the levels they keep progressing, the rank is going to get higher.
So we say that if the let's say for the green, what is the speed that we are going to have the speed
and speed if I pass through here for the Ranchi, what is the rank?
The rank is three.
So three minus three, we are going to get zero zero divided by rank, high zero divided by anything
is going to be zero and zero multiplied by the max ball speed is going to be zero.
So we are going to have one plus zero.
Basically we are going to have one and one times the speed, the current speed that we have, which
is zero point five.
We are just going to get what we are going to get zero point four five.
Right.
So for the green, we do not change the speed.
It is going to be a multiplier of one.
What about the yellow?
So if I put yellow here, that is the rank.
The high rank is three three minus two.
That is one one divided by the higher rank, which is three.
Right.
And that is like three minus two.
That is one one divided by three.
We are going to get zero point three three and then we multiplied by this, which is one.
So we are going to get one plus zero point three three.
So for this we are just increasing the speed by zero point three three.
Right.
Very like by 30 percent of that.
So if the speed is 300 originally, we are going to incremented by almost 100 because 100 is almost
one third of that.
Right.
So you can see that here we have it is these are like very it's not like very fixed numbers.
So we have three hundred and thirty seven.
Our initial speed, the second speed is going to be 450.
So let's go ahead and let's grab our calculator.
And in here I'm going to say 450 minus three, thirty seven point five, we get one twelve.
So three three seven one 12 100.
How much.
So I'm going to multiply this by 100 and then I'm going to divide it by three thirty seven point five.
So you can see that we get thirty three point three percent of that.
I just did the ratio and that is very simple.
We have done it a lot.
So each time the speed is going to get increased by thirty three point three percent from one rank to
the next rung in case it is level one, otherwise the speed is going to adjust itself.
We are just providing it with a mathematical operation so it can do the rest itself.
We don't want to worry about it anymore.
So now that that is done, let's go to our update.
Bricks function.
So which is way down here.
Update bricks function.
And in here right after the update score, what I would like to do is I'm going to grab the ball and
I'm going to call a method which is set speed.
And I'm going to pass in our bricks, whichever brick that is, and from there we are going to grab
the speed that you can see how all of these methods are interconnected.
After we have created that, we should go to our ball class and actually set this function, so let's
come down here, where's our ball class?
It is right here and down below.
I'm going to say set speed and this is going to be an Arab function.
Because it has an argument you are going to pass in a parameter, and that is speed.
So what do we want this to do?
We want this first off, let's grab this start speed, which is right here.
Right.
So we are going to say this, that speed is going to be equal to the max math that Max.
So the max function is going to return the larger of a set of supplied numeric expressions.
So I'm going to pass in two arguments in here and the math that Max is going to return the biggest of
those and it is going to set it to this speed.
Right.
So the first one is going to be the speed, the current speed that we have.
The second one is going to be that speed multiplier.
So ball underscore speed times the height, because whenever the height is getting smaller, the speed
is going to get slower.
If the height is getting bigger because we have more distance, we are going to increase the speed so
that distance is covered faster.
Very simple stuff, and now what I would like to do at this point is I want to log it to the council
as well so we can see it.
So I'm going to say speed equal to dollar sign curly braces this start speed.
In both cases, this speed is going to decide a speed.
But what this Max Max is going to do is if this is bigger than this, speed is going to be equal to
this speed, if this part is bigger than this, speed is going to be equal to this one.
Right.
And in here, what what we what we are going to do is we are going to play through the next level.
So you can't really see what's happening here.
And after that, we are done here.
And in the next lecture, we will be implementing the audio.
Right.
So this is where we are.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to play that.
So let's see, we get three thirty seven point five in case you get a different number.
Well, I'm expecting that you have to get a different number because the screen height is different
for you and for me.
For me, it is.
This is a you you should screen.
So it is seven thirty something and the width is different as well, which shouldn't matter.
But if the height, if you get any number, which is not this or this, you shouldn't, you shouldn't
have to worry about it.
And in case you're wondering about this, why it is going just upwards, it is because that our bounce
angle is set to 90.
That is a good thing.
I'm not going to change it.
So you can see that our first rank, we had three three seven, then increase it by thirty three point
three percent, four fifty.
Increase it by thirty three point three, fifty five sixty two.
And then the maximum is going to be six seventy five.
So let's now go ahead and reduce the number of columns to one once more and let's check out the different
speeds that we are going to get.
I don't want to waste too much time.
So the first rank is three thirty seven, a multiplier of one.
The second rank is a multiplier of one point three three.
So we get four fifty, then we get one point six something, then we get 550 to.
And for this one we get six seventy five.
So now we are our in our next level.
So in here now, you can see that we still start, so the starting point is going to be the same and
the ending point, the range is going to be different because that speed multiplier, where did we added?
I'm sure we added here this dysfunction, this equation, this equation is going to take care of the
remaining rows, the extra rows that we are going to add.
All right.
When the level goes up so you can see that the starting is still three thirty seven.
The ending is still six, seven to five, even though in between the range is different because we have
an extra row.
And if I do it here as well, you can see that the starting at three three seven.
Each one has to be done two times because there are two rows in that specific rank, each rank has two
rows in it, you can see that we have different ones here and we have 540 because it has to count for
another rank that has been added.
And finally, we should yeah, there we go, we have our six seventy five, so this is how we set the
speed speed multiplier.
Let me put these back to 14 columns.
The bounce angle should be 30.
Let's save everything and everything should go back to normal.
And now you can see that as you go up, as the levels progress, it is going to get significantly difficult
for the user to play.
Even at the second and third level, especially in mobile devices.
It is going to be like pretty difficult for the users to play.
For example, at this level, you're going to get this.
So you have to really like run.
And there we go.
I'm just going to play it for a minute and embarrass myself.
So there we go.
Come on.
OK, let's try to keep up.
The bounce is real.
You can see that the speed is already at 360 389.
There we go.
It is going up.
Go up, go up.
It is.
The speed is four nine.
I was looking at the council.
That's why I lost it.
It's three, three seven, and there we go.
It is increasing.
Come on.
Oops, I lost it there, so you get the idea, you get the point what we are doing here.
So let me put it back to zero.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.