Hi, everyone, in this lecture, we are going to talk about the replace method, Auri, so the replace
method is going to search and replace patterns within strings.
So how do I mean, so what I'm going to do is I'm going to say twenty eight point one.
So this is this example has two parts.
So example, twenty eight point one.
Now, let's go ahead.
We have let's say we have a sentence and I'm going to call it, you know what, just sentence.
And I'm going to say my I don't know, like dog meows my dog Max.
And let's create the regular expression Reg Rage twenty eight point one.
I don't think point one works.
I'm just going to say Rage X, I'm just going to say rejects.
Right.
And now let's say I'm searching for miaows.
And I want to replace it with barks.
So I'm just going to say replace text.
So the replace text replacement text replacement text is going to be Bachs.
And now let's do the replacement, so I'm going to store it and I'm going to say replace result, right.
So we are going to grab our sentence because that's where we are looking and we are going to call the
replace method on it.
And whenever we call it, it says an object can search for and replace matches within a string.
So we are looking for something.
What is what it is that we are looking for?
First off, we need to provide that.
So I'm just going to say projects.
So we are looking for the regular expression and the regular expression is going to match a pattern
within that string and it is going to match.
Miaows So we are looking for that.
What do we want to replace it with?
And it says replace value right here.
So what do we want to replace it with?
We want to replace it with the replacement.
Replacement.
Text, so let's go ahead and let's say Consul Deathlok very, very straightforward replies.
Results, and when I say it, it says my dog barks, even though it's in here, it says my dog meows.
We've got the meow and we change it with the bark.
And we did the method and we logged it to the console.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to give you another example.
We can do it another way as well.
So this is twenty eight point two.
And for this to work, I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to you know what?
We don't need any of these.
So I'm just going to call them out and I'm going to say let replace.
Replacement, I'm just going to call it this time, replacement, nothing else.
OK, so a replacement be equal to now we insert our sentence here.
So I'm just going to say my cat barks.
I'm going to say so this is our sentence.
Now, this is like a sure way of doing it.
And we are going to call a replace method on it.
Now, here we call the replace by its variable name.
But in here we call the the sentence itself.
We are going to say that to replace.
So what what is what is it that we want to we are looking to replace, we are looking to replace Bachs
and what do we want to replace it with?
We want to replace it with MIAOWS.
So let's go ahead and let's say Kansa log replacement Servet and it says, my.
Cat meows So this is the end of our chapter for regular expressions.
There could be like a ton more that if you wanted to really get in depth with this.
But I am not going to because I just give you like the necessary tools to create awesome regular expressions.
We are just focusing on forum validation and because we are going to have two projects in this area.
One of the projects is going to give you a strength for the password.
So it's going to be a password strengthened.
It is going to be an application.
And the other one is going to be like whenever you're typing something inside the password, you're
going to get like life feedback like it is going to give you on this like on the spot.
When you're writing, while you're writing, you're going to get whether an error or not.
So we are going to do that with regular expressions as well.
So this is it for this lecture and this chapter.
See you guys in the next one.