Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we will be implementing the sound effects.
OK, so so far, we do have a working game in case you want to play.
So it is completely playable on imagine every device available and you can go ahead and play it.
And now what I would like to do here is I'm going to point you towards this folder.
So we do have a sound folder, brick paddle, power up and wall.
And right after this video, we will be working with the power ups.
All right.
So after the canvas, what I would like to do here is I'm going to create variables.
So the first one is going to be audio brick.
So I'm going to say mudbrick.
It is going to be new audio, new audio.
And let's provide the path for that.
So it is in the sounds folder.
And from there it is going to be brick dot com for a let's copy this a few more times here.
And so the first one is going to be the brick, the second one, and that's our paddle.
And it is going to be the paddle dart.
And for a.
OK, right after that, we have the power up, power up, which we are going to implement.
So don't worry about it and it is going to be power up.
It's add an O there and finally, we have the war.
And this is going to be one.
Now let's see where we should implement them, so we should implement them wherever we have hit those,
we had either the break, any break.
So I'm just going to collapse this whatever we had a break or any, for example.
The wall or the paddle or when we eat any power up, so first things first whenever we serve the ball.
I want that I want the sound to to play, all right, and that is going to be the panel sound.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come to the service function and right before returning something
and hear what I'm going to do is I'm going to say audio panel that play.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
So this is our game.
There we go.
So that audio is being played each time we serve the ball.
So the idea is being played.
Next stop, let's play the sound effects for the wall, and so where should we apply that?
So what I'm going to do is let's go to our updatable function, which I assume is down here.
So inside the updatable function.
What do we want to do here?
So whenever we hit a ball, sorry, we hit a wall, so this is where we are bouncing off the walls.
So this is if we had the left, right and top, we have to call the idea here as well.
So we are going to say audio wall.
Don't play, so this is going to play it for the left wall and this is going to play it for the right.
We need to play it for the top ball as well.
All right, so now let's save it.
Let's check it out.
There we go.
So on the left, it does play right about the sorry and right.
What about the left?
And I assume it is going to play for the top as well.
OK, so next up, what I would like to do is, let's see, I want to apply this whenever it hits the
paddle as well.
So in here, when it hits the paddle, we are going to apply the paddles audio.
So where is it so bouncing of the paddle?
There we go.
Right here.
We are going to say audio paddle.
Ops dot play, let's save it.
So apart from the bricks, it should play, it should work everywhere.
I'm just going to increase the idea.
And I'm sure you can hear that.
Perfect.
So it is working fine.
Next stop, we need to implement that for our bricks as well.
All right, so we are going to go inside our update Brooks function, so I'm just going to close this
one.
And in here, let's see where we should play that.
I'm going to play it right after we decrease the number of bricks.
And I'm going to say Ardeo Brick.
And itude, I did it again, fly when to calling the plane, called the plane with it.
There we go.
So we are done effectively with this idea.
I'm just going to play it one more time.
You know what?
I'm going to go into this responsive and let's see if it plays here.
So when you when you tap it is going to play that and now it is playing it.
There we go.
Let's get a wall.
Oops.
Oh, there we go.
That is the wall.
So it is playing off all the sides.
It's really difficult with this mouse simulating the touch, OK?
That was very.
OK, so you saw how we played with the mobile phone and the speed was 300, the starting speed.
That is because the height is different, right, for the mobile phone.
So we are basically in the touch simulation.
We are basically on a different device.
That's why it is 300.
But for browser, I assume that for all of my browser it is going to be three three seven.
So that's it for this lecture.
In the next lecture, we are going to start creating the power ups and we will go through them.
Hopefully they are going to take not that many lectures and there they are going to be really, really
fun.
So see you guys then.