Hi, everyone, in this next year, we're going to talk about the Fetch API.
All right, so we know how the XIKAR object worked, we know how we we created we made HTP requests,
how we handled the data received, and we know how all that stuff works.
But that is like the old school way of doing it with the exciter object.
Now we have newer standards.
We have newer methods like the API, like async await that we will be using in our projects.
Now, keep in mind, there is this there is one thing that I want to mention first, and that is there
is nothing wrong with using XIKAR object.
In fact, like there are many developers that still prefer that way of doing it, that old school way
of doing it.
But you need to know that.
And then what we talked about was the callbacks.
So how we used callbacks and then how we used promises, now promises topic was really important.
Important because the API actually returns a promise, the FETCH API returns a promise.
And so what we can do with that, we can use the dart then method to get the data and we can use the
dart catch method to catch the errors.
Now the Fetch API implements promises under the hood.
So we are going to get a response which is going to be an object and we are going to get an error,
which is going to be another object.
All right, so what I'm going to do is we are going to go over a much simpler syntax, a a way easier
syntax and a way less of a headache kind of syntax.
But if you want to use XY char, that's going to be it for you.
You don't want to learn API, which is like which is not a good idea.
You should learn API should learn, async, await.
But as far as the XIKAR object is concerned, we are done with that.
We are diving into modern JavaScript asynchronous programming.
Right.
And the methods and functions that are made available to us.
So first off, what I'm going to do is I'm going to.
I have the API endpoint and the other screen, so I'm just going to copy paste it.
So first off, I'm going to go ahead through a simpler example and then we are going to take it up a
notch and we are going to cover a more intermediate kind of example.
So the first one is like a beginner one.
So I'm just going to say example one right in here.
What do I want to do is I'm going to make a request request to two groups to get the users.
So we are going to make a request to get the users.
Where is the API endpoint?
The API endpoint is going to be that specific.
Jason Placeholder website.
The fact that we talked about.
So I'm going to say fetch.
You just have to say fetch and open up that set.
So in here, what we have is we are going to provide the API endpoint.
So I'm just going to copy it from the screen and I'm going to paste it right here.
So this is the API endpoint.
Now, you could go ahead and create a variable and stored this API endpoint inside that variable and
then put the variable here.
I mean, that that is going to work as well, but I'm just going to do it directly.
So when when we run this, this is going to return a promise.
So let's take a look at it.
What this is going to return.
So I am going to store it inside a let variable and I'm going to say.
What I'm just going to say what that's it.
So let's save it, let's say consult the log scra what and let's save it, we can see that it is going
to return a promise.
Now the promise it has the Proteau is promise.
We know what this Proteau is.
We have talked a lot about it.
Now, when it returns, they promise some methods are made available to us.
One of them is done then right Dudd.
Then we use it with the dart cache then is used when we want to grab the data.
So in this case, I'm going to say a response because we are going to have response and then we are
going to have error when it comes to that which sorry, the API.
So in here, what do I want to do?
What I want to do is I want to grab that response and I want to log it to the console.
So we are going to say cancel the log, let's grab the response.
Let's see what the response is going to give us now the if we have an error along the way.
Now here, it says, attaches a callback for only the rejection of the promise because they implement
promises under the hood, we can use these methods.
So I'm going to say, oops.
To say reject.
And what do I want to do when the promise is rejected?
I just want to log it to the consul.
Oh, I'm not going to say reject, this should be error, so error and I'm going to do better inside
the console, let's say.
So now we can see that we get our response.
We don't get the reject because they're the promise has been successful.
But if I were to add another is there and save it, we can see we get four or four, but we still get
the response.
Now, this is something that is that is, well, not that helpful.
We should make our way around this, which we are.
So we get the error, which is four or four, but we still get their response.
But their response, what is the response going to say now before diving into this?
What are we going to do is I'm going to remove the extras.
First off, let's talk about it when the this method is called.
So what do we have here?
We have a status of 200 these statistics.
It is empty.
All right.
And this is the euro to which we have made the request.
And this is the prototype of this response, which is actually a response.
Right.
And our right.
Is there anything else that I want to cover here now?
So if I add another is here, it means that we have made a mistake and now we have a status of 404.
All right.
So this is how Fetch API works.
Now you can see how similar this is.
I know we we get something really weird with this one.
Very, very, very weird.
Right.
And there is no response text.
We don't get our users.
We are going to dive into that.
And the second example.
Right.
So in the second example, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to come and run out.
I'm going to grab this comment and I'm going to paste it here.
And we are going to say example to make a request to get users.
Now, we have made the request.
The request was successful, but how can we extract the information that we want?
We made the request to fetch some data, to retrieve some data, in this case, its users.
But still, we want to grab our data.
Where is our data?
We can see it here.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to go over this example one more time.
So I'm going to say fetch, right.
And I'm going to pass on the same API endpoint, which is right here.
And because this returns a promise, we can say it does then on it.
Now in here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab the response.
Right.
Well, it's.
Smaller case, I ah, and when I grabbed that response, I want to do something with their response,
so let me just make this smaller so it makes more sense.
Yeah, like that.
So come here, buddy.
And OK, so what do I want to do with that response?
I want to return.
I want to return response dart, Jason, right now, what is that, Jason Dott Jason, what is this?
Now here is a page.
Now basically you can go ahead and read more about it.
So I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to r pasted right here.
I'm going to save it, make some way.
Right.
So basically what this does Jason Method is going to allow us to do is it is going to grab our response.
It is going to read it is going to convert it to a Jason file.
This this method, it is going to convert it to a Jason and then it is going to read it and then pass
it so we can use it inside JavaScript.
So it is going to do three things.
The response first, the response is convert it to Jason file, then it is right there and then it is
passed into a readable code by JavaScript.
All right.
But what happens in the process is this return response to Jason.
It actually returns a promise as well.
So this entire thing is going to return the promise so we can just add a thin method.
And why is this done then, method necessary, because when we grab our data, when the data is passed,
we want to grab that data and do something with it.
I know in this case, we want to just log it to the console.
But think of think of think of it as a like real world application application.
When you when the data is passed, you need to get the data.
You want to grab the data, you want to have the data.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to say in this case, because we are phishing users, I'm
just going to say users and we are going to run an error function here.
And what do I want to do?
I simply want to log to the console users and now when we said that, then, all right, we can do the
catch as well.
So we need to do that for the error as well.
So error.
And just consider the log error, let's save it, and now we get our data, see, so this data is going
to give us users now because the JSON placeholder is actually.
By default, it is going to for users as far as users are concerned, it is going to give us 10 users.
OK.
So if I come here, you can see that by default you are going to get 10 users.
We can we can get 200 to Duse, 5000 photos and all this information.
Right.
So we have gotten 10 users.
And now keep in mind that all of these they are valid JavaScript.
We can this is an array of objects.
This is no longer a Jason object.
So a decent object or adjacent string.
So you can see ID is not surrounded by its name, is not strong.
User name is Nazran.
When it gets users from the adjacent API, it is going to give you an address company email.
Of course these are all fake.
And the good thing is this.
These objects are also nested.
So we have object within an object, within an object like three levels nested.
So you can extract all kind of information that you want.
And you can see that with only like a few lines of code, we were able to prove we were able to do the
same kind of request to this server with only like with like with five times fewer lines of code and
not having to deal with all that with the four steps like instantiating and X, which are object and
then creating the request, like deciding what to do when we get a successful response and then sending
the request.
So all of that is implemented by promises under the hood when you use the fetch API.
So this by far is the best method, right?
So before this lecture, we had another best method and that method was promises.
But now we know that is even better than promises.
But actually this is promising.
This is a different syntax for promises.
It uses promises.
And I'm not going to repeat myself anymore.
So that's it for this lecture.
And the next lecture, we are going to talk about the async await, which is the final technology that
we are going to cover in this chapter for now.
See you guys then.