Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we are going to update the chart based on the updated UI function.
All right, so we are going to call the update chart function inside this update UI function, but there
is something that we need to consider that whenever we we are traveling from one file to another file.
First off, you need to make sure that the file arrangement is accurate, that we want our charges to
run first and then the object file.
So this is the first thing.
The second thing is we need to pass in the correct parameters, the correct parameters.
So we are going to pass an income, an outcome because we do have income, an outcome inside our update
UI.
So first we are going to grab our context to D and we are going to clear our rectangle or our you know,
it's funny because it's a circle, but if you want to clear the canvas, you should call the clear rectangle
method zero for the X coordinate, zero for the Y coordinate and we are going to grab the canvas dot
with and we are going to grab the canvas dot.
Height, right, and then now let's go ahead and let's define the ratio now, the ratio might seem a
bit weird, but I'm going to explain it.
So the ratio is going to be income divided by income plus plus outcome.
So I'm going to tell you why.
So imagine the income is, too, and the outcome is one.
OK, so we are going to have to divided by two plus one.
OK, so two divided by two.
OK, let's grab our calculator.
I know it's point seventy five but still so too divided by two plus one which is three.
So we get, we get two point six six not point seventy five point six says we get one third, we don't
get one fourth of it.
OK, if the income is three and the outcome is I mean I should have told you, you know what, let's
start over.
Let's say the income is three and let's say the outcome is one.
So three plus one, we are going to get four.
And in here we have three.
So three divided by four.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's divide it.
We have three divided by four.
We get we get three quarters.
OK, so when the income is four and the outcome is one, it means that we actually have four quarters
of final quarter means like four parts of that pie.
Think of a circle like like divided into four parts.
Then one of those parts is going to be the outcome.
And three of those parts is going to be the income.
But what is the ratio of this?
The ratio is going to be point seven, five or three by four.
So I'm just going to comment it three by four, OK, because actually the whole pie or the whole circle
that we have is divided into four parts and the ratio drops three parts of that.
So what are the other what is the other part dedicated to that is dedicated to the outcome?
All right.
I hope you're not getting confused, so I'm going to go again.
So if the income is 100, like let's say the income is 100, the outcome is one.
This ratio is always going to be less than one.
It is always going to be less than one because the bigger number should be accommodated, should be
dedicated to the income.
And these the smaller number should be accommodated to the outcome or vice versa.
Doesn't matter.
What matters is one of these incomes or outcomes should get a bigger number than the other one in case
both of them are equal.
Then we will get like a sort of like like an equal ratio for both of them.
OK, like a point five that we saw there.
OK, so let's go ahead and we are going to complete this and then we are going to play around with it
so we can understand it.
Now, inside here, I want to call the draw circle function twice.
First one, I'm going to call in the line green.
Lorne, green color for the income, OK, and the ratio, whichever value comes out of this excuse me,
and the anticlockwise is going to be true because whenever we are working with the ratio, we go from
here to here.
So this is anticlockwise whenever we working sorry with income, but whenever we're working with the
outcome, it is going to be clockwise.
So.
From here all the way to here like that, so it is going to be true and a next time where we are going
to grab it and we are going to set it to false right.
And we are going to change the color to tomato.
Now, keep in mind here that we do have a ratio of, for example, zero point seven five.
This is going to be the ratio, but we are going to say one minus zero point seventy five.
So one minus zero point seventy five is going to give us zero point two five.
OK, so zero point two five is our ratio.
OK, and we have said that three is the income and one is the outcome and point seventy five is going
to be divided between the income and the outcome.
Let's just go ahead and implement it.
I feel like the more I explain it, the more confused you get.
So I'm going to come in here and say the update UI function and I'm going to call the update chart.
You can see that it's.
It can.
Detected and we are going to call in the end, come and come and out, say it, let's come here.
Let's just see it for ourselves.
Let's close this.
So if I were to person project for the project, let's say I have three add added.
We can see whenever the expense is zero, all of the circle is going to be dedicated for one of the
trackers, whichever is present and let's say dinner.
Let's put it to one, OK, now, this is the problem here, you can see that because dinner is one and
well, actually this is this it should and shouldn't do this.
I think we have done a mistake here.
We should see a whole circle here.
Everything else is correct and is three outcomes.
One balances two dollars.
But we should see this expense come all the way here.
Get the one third of it.
So we have income and then we have the outcome, if we come inside the update chart, we have the one
minus ratio and draw a circle.
Let's go ahead and let's add a negative sign to the ratio.
We still see that it's OK, we don't see it anymore, let's say Project South, let's add three and
come into expense, let's say dinner one and now it is working, right.
So you can see that the entire circle has been divided into four parts, one of the parts is dedicated
to this expense.
You can see that this is one fourth of the circle, three other fourths of the circle, three quarters,
not forts.
Of course, three quarters of this circle has been dedicated to this three.
So what this is going to do is this is going to grab all of our incomes and all of our expenses.
It is going to sum them up and it is going to create a circle and the circle is going to have segments.
Each segment is going to be equal to one of the dollars that we have inserted here.
So if I reload this page, the circle is going to go away.
Now, let's go ahead and let's say project.
I'm going to say 1000.
OK, so now the circle has 1000 segments and let's say dinner and I'm going to pass in five and now
it means that this five is actually five of those 1000 segments.
OK, so 995 segments are dedicated to the incoming five segments are dedicated to the outcome.
That's why you can see them very, very small.
Let's go ahead and let's say Birrarung.
Brunch and let's say 1994, OK?
And if we do that, you can see that now because we had five here, you know, what can I deleted now?
I cannot delete it.
Can I edited nine, cannot edit it.
So I'm just going to reload the page and I'm going to explain it one more time.
So let's say we have a project here and it is you know what, 100 is better than 1000.
Let's say we have dinner.
And for dinner, we have five, but then we have brunch, and for the brunch we have 90, you can see
that 90 plus five, we get ninety five.
And the it's this income is going to be 100.
That's why if you pay attention, the income is a little bit bigger than the expense.
So if I were to add five more for the expense, lunch is going to be five.
Now both of them are equal.
The reason for that is we have 100 inside the project, 100 inside the expense, I'm sorry, 100 inside
the contractor, 100 inside the expense structure.
That's 200.
So this circle is made up of 200 because both of these segments are equal.
Equal spaces of this circle have been has been dedicated to each of these incomes and outcomes.
So this is how we create that.
The reason that we say minus one, because the result of this ratio is going to be a decimal, we basically
change through this.
We mimic changing it to like a like a ratio.
That's why it's a ratio.
All right.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
I think there are only two things remaining here at this point.
The first thing is that.
Actually, three things, the first thing is we need to be able to delete the items.
The second is edit the items and the third is add them to the local storage.
See you guys in the next lecture.