Hi, everyone.
In this nature, we are going to display superheroes from the local stories to the UI.
All right, so now you can see we have our superheroes inside this local stories, but they're not showing
on the UI.
So what we are going to do is are going to create a function, display superheroes from L.A. and are
going to put static.
And we are going to say display super heroes, display superhero.
Right.
There is not going to be any parameter.
So first off, where how can we grab superheroes from the local storage?
The method and the function responsible for that is the get superhero.
This is adding it.
This is getting so we need to call this method.
So for that, what we are going to do is we are going to say CONSED Superheroes list.
So superheroes list.
So let's create this.
Now keep in mind, this variable is different than this because we are using CONSED.
This variable is code to this function.
And we are going to say the same thing, so store superheroes don't get superheroes, so we are going
to get the superhero when we get it.
OK, there might be more than one.
We are getting an array of superheroes so we can call superhero.
Let's start for each for each method on it.
So let's remove the array.
And for each time we are going to call superhero.
What do we want to do when this array runs, when this array is iterating over, that we are going to
instantiate our superhero list class and we want to add the super we want to grab the add superhero
method from there.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to set instantiating the superhero.
OK, not upper superhero lest class.
So for that, we are going to say CONSED list is going to be new superhero last and not that one, that's
incorrect superhero lest it's instantiated and when we instantiate it, then we can call a method from
it.
So this is the difference between static and non static in non static.
You need to instantiate it first to be able to grab the superheroes and we're going to add superhero.
Let's add the entry.
So we just called the ad superhero and we just called the entry on it.
OK, sorry, not the entry, but the superhero.
OK, so and I'm going to come down here.
We are going to create a you know what?
I'm just going to because this is an event I'm going to created here.
Now, this event is actually going to fire when the page reloads.
So that's why I've opened this up.
This is Dom Cont'd Loaded event.
It fires when the initial e-mail document has been completely loaded and passed without waiting for
stylesheets, images of friends to finish loading.
You can read all about it here.
OK, so I'm just going to this is dumb content loaded, right?
So we are going to say document.
Document DOT at Evenflo Center, and we are going to say Dham content loaded when the DOMS content is
loaded fully.
What do we want to load?
We want to load the store superhero store superhero darte.
Sorry, Dad, display the display superhero.
OK, so when the dom loads at that moment I want to load this method right.
This, I want to, I want to grab the superhero and from there I just want to call it whenever the dom
loads and when I call it what it is going to do, it is going to go into the superhero lists class and
from there it is going to call the ad superhero.
And what is the ad superhero going to do?
So if we come up here, the ad superhero is going to do all this.
It is going to create a you'll create an ally, create an icon appended to the less data and it is going
to do all that stuff.
So now let's come here.
So now you can see we already have all of our stuff here.
So if I remove everything from there and remove from here, let's add Superman, DC, fly, click,
everything is added and add it here as well.
Now, if I remove it from here, it's removed from here.
But if I reload, it is going to come back.
Now keep this in mind that we are not getting items from the local storage.
I mean that you could call this like a trick that we are doing here because we are not actually getting
items, because it's tricky to get items from the local storage and put it inside the UI.
For that, you need to create all this process once more.
So when you grab the item, you need to pass it and you need to grab the ID, grab the last grab, you
create a UL for it and create the inner HTML and then append it to that superhero less data div that
we have in the e-mail file.
So instead of doing all that, all that stuff, what we do is anything that's inside the local storage.
So where is it, anything that's inside the local storage, we just want to grab that local storage.
And so for example, if we have only Superman inside the local storage because inside the local storage,
we only have an object adjacent adjacent strength.
So let me bring this over here.
So we have only this Jason strain, this Jason's shrink.
The resume does not resemble this data that we have in order to, you know, grab it and pass it into
this data.
We need to run this function.
So we get that data, then we get the parent for that data.
This is the parent.
We create a UL for that data.
We create the inner e-mail for that data.
And then from that data, we grab the superhero name superhero universe and superhero power and then
we add it to the screen.
So this is how we are actually doing it.
That's why I'm telling you that it's you could think of it as a trick that we are doing here, because
this trick actually allows us not to repeat ourselves.
So you could go ahead and do this trick here or instead of this, you could do all this.
So which one is better?
This one is better, right?
Just call the function.
Instead of doing all this, you could just go ahead and call.
And in order to call that function, you need to instantiate that class and then call it and pass in
the superhero.
OK, so this is how we completed this application will not actually complete it.
When I click remove from here, we need to remove that item from this from the local storage as well.
And that is going to be the ultimate thing that we want to do in this chapter.
I just want to go over this line one more time when the document receives an event and this event says
when the document is loaded completely.
We want to call this display superhero.
Function, the display superhero function is going to get all the items from the local storage and convert
them into the kind of data that we would want to display on our web, see.
So it's just grabbed it and converted it into this.
That's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.