Hi, everyone.
In this lecture, we're going to take a look at Aira handling with a syncopate.
All right, so first off, let's open this with live server, and I'm just going to go into the console,
right?
And I'm going to remove this now.
I've kept this one open.
This is the previous lecture because I want to show you something when we are almost done with this
lecture.
So what I'm going to do is we are going to grab we are going to create a customer and we are going to
grab the this data.
Where is it?
Where is this data?
So we are going to grab this 10 ten questions and we're going to create our customer as well.
So first off, let's ride the async keyword async and let's create the function.
What is the function identifier is going to be get questions right and there is going to be no parameter.
And what do we want to do?
We want to say a weight fetch.
What is the fetch going to fetch.
The fetch is going to grab six start.
What is the name of the file questions Dot Jason.
So we are basically now this inside this, this is the API endpoint or the source for that HTP.
You are our request and this is the source six that questions the sources like any other source that
we do with e-mails here, says JavaScript.
So it works in the same way and we are going to store it inside a variable and I'm going to call it
questions response.
So what what is this going to do as it is going to await this entire line until this fetch grabs all
the data, fetches all the data, and then it is going to assign it to this questions response.
Now, let's go ahead and let's log it to the console questions response.
And now before I know it is not going to work because we are we have to call the function.
So we are going to say get questions, let's just call it, let's save it.
And we get this response.
And if I come here, we can say that the status code, A code is 200, but there is no way that we know
what's inside this response.
Where are our data?
Right.
Where is our data?
So the way that we grab that data is that I'm just going to get rid of this cancer log as we are going
to do the same way.
But actually, we're not going to do it.
We could say, like posts data and then we could return posts data and then we could run this get posts,
which is dysfunction, and we would get our data.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to do it a different way.
So I'm going to say return.
Questions, data, so we have questions, I'm going to create this variable now you can do it in this
way.
This is why I've kept it open.
You can do it.
You can create the variable and assign it and then return it.
Or you can simplify this into one line of code.
You can return and assign the value with one with one line of code.
So when I say return questions, data equal to await, what is it going to await?
It is going to await questions.
Response Dot.
Jason.
When you say this, what it is going to do, it is going to assign this value to questions, data and
then return it.
So I think this syntax is easier and simpler than doing doing it this way.
And this looks more professional as well.
So if I save it.
We get questions, data, and we get Jawaid questions, response dot Jason.
All right, so I await questions, response.
Jason, we say return.
And now when we return this, it means that this entire thing is going to be a promise.
So when it is a promise, we can do a thing.
And I'm just going to say data in here.
All right, and what do we want to do, we want to log it to the console, right?
So let's save it.
We get all of our data and you can see that it is in JavaScript format.
So instead of this line is actually equal to these two lines, instead of a sign creating the variable,
declaring the variable and then returning it, we did both of them in one line with just the return.
So you could do that as well.
And that's why that's what I wanted to show you there.
And now where is our custom error?
So what I'm going to do is if I comment this one out and paste it down here and we don't have any file
by the name of one, two, three questions three.
So we get an error.
This is 404, not found and uncaught in promised syntax error, unexpected token.
So we get all kinds of crazy errors.
So how can we throw our own custom error?
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab this.
You can see that the status is not 200 anymore.
The status is 404 inside this console.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say that if this DOT questions data sorry, sorry, not question
is data.
If this DOT status is not if it is not 200, throw a new error.
So we are going to literally say throw new error.
All right, and what is that you're going to say they are going to error fetching data and when I say
it, we still get this one because we need to we need to catch that error.
Now, we have thrown the error here.
We need to catch it here as well.
That's why the name of this method is catch.
Catch the error, buddy.
So we are going to say catch.
We are going to log it to the console error.
Let's save it.
And now we get this error error fetching data.
So I'm going to I'm going to remove that.
Let's make this window smarter.
We don't need it to be big.
So let's save this, just bring a of OK, let's save it, and now what do we get?
We get error, error fetching data, right.
And where is it coming from?
It is coming from line number two on from this council.
Look, so this is how we can create a custom error.
All right.
And if the file was correct, we still see that error, which we should not see it.
So if this star status is not 200 return questions, so this doesn't have, why do we still get that
error?
OK, so our catch the error, so here we have Dot then get questions, dot then and then we have data,
we are going to log the data.
We should we should have logged the data.
And in here, you know what, before doing before finding out what the problem is, we can make this
line even shorter, because whenever you work with arrow functions and you have only one line, you
can just remove the curly braces and put all of them on one liners.
So if I say that missing oops, this remove that we still get this error, which is which comes from
throe new error, error fetching data.
If this that status is I think this this is not actually pointing to this question's response.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to remove this and I'm going to say questions, response and
save it.
And now we do get it.
So this is not actually a good idea to be used here.
And you saw how it didn't work.
If throw it through an error, I'm going to go over this code one more time and then we are going to
wrap up this lecture.
All right.
So we basically created an async function.
The thing that we did differently was we did the variable declaration and returning of that variable
in one line and we just grabbed the questions response and we did Jason Method, which is going to do
three things.
One, it is going to convert their response to Jason file two, it is going to read it.
Three, it is going to pass it to a format that is.
Common to JavaScript.
Right.
So this is what we did here in case there is an error like there is if you URL that is not valid.
What we did was we said if questions response, that status is not 200 throe new error.
We literally said throw new error.
Very simple.
That's why JavaScript is simple.
OK.
And what was the error?
The error set error fetching data.
All right.
And we resolved the promise here and we caught the error here.
So you can go ahead and you can say error message.
There is a property on the error, which is error message.
And if you click on it and save it, you can see we only get the error date, the error message.
So this is the message.
This property is available to you when you create this when you instantiate a new object object function.
All right.
So I think I think we are done here.
So this is going to be it for this lecture.
And I hope you have learned a lot.
I hope there isn't any problem because I try to reiterate stuff as many times as I could.
So that's it for this lecture.
See you guys in the next one.