Hi, everyone, welcome to the second part of implementing our power cuts.
All right, so first off, what we need to do as we we have created the power ups, they are coming
down, we need to collect them.
So in order to collect them, we are going to go into our update padel function right here.
And this function function, what we're going to do is a.
So this is the wall collision for the panel.
Right underneath this, I'm going to say collect collecting, collecting the pups.
All right, so what we need now, we are going to loop over backward because we collect them and when
we collect them, we are going to delete them.
That's why we are going to loop over it backwards.
So we are going to say for I is equal to the pups length.
It should start at that point and length minus one, of course.
And the eye is going to go is going to be equal or greater than zero and each time are going to decrement
the eye by one.
Perfect.
Now if now we need to provide some conditions.
So this these conditions are actually collision detection of the part of the pop and the paddle.
So we are going to see if the pups I am just going to say I'm going to copy this because we are going
to have a lot of that.
If the pups exposition plus the pups with half of the pups with is greater than the paddles exposition,
minus half of the paddles with the W time, zero point five, if it is greater than that.
And we are going to say and the pups exposition.
So X minus the pups, minus the pups with half of the pups with is less than the paddles.
Exposition plus the paddles, half of the paddles with so zero point five, let's save this.
Oh, it didn't rearrange it.
I thought it would.
So let's save this.
It doesn't rearrange it.
So let's add the other one.
I'm just going to hit enter there.
So we have said that if the Pops exposition plus half of the width is greater than the panel six position,
minus half of it's with and then the exposition minus the pops half of the pops width is less than the
paddles exposition plus the paddles with a right.
So what is the third condition now we have checked for the X positions.
We need to check in for Y positions as well.
So I'm going to pass in our pops that if the Y position of the pop plus half of its off of its height,
not with this time.
If that is greater than the paddles y position paddleboat y minus half of the paddles height the tight
time, zero point five.
And finally we are going to check for our final condition, and that is if the pups y position minus
the pups height times minus half of the pups height, if that is less than the paddles.
Why position plus half of the paddles hide, so paddle Dotti times zero point five, if all of that
is true, what do we want to do?
It means that's a collision has occurred and this is prettier.
All right.
So I'm going to go over this one more time.
So X half of that is greater than the paddles with and then smaller.
Right.
So we should be good.
We should be good.
So what do we want to do here?
We are going to create a we are going to check for whichever type it is that has been passed because
whichever type it is, that is going to specify for us what we should do with the paddle.
If that is the extension type, we want the paddle to get bigger.
If that is the sticky, we want the paddle to the ball to stick to the paddle.
If it is life, we want increase the life.
So we have to check for whichever time it is that that has just that has just been devoured by the paddle.
So I'm going to do switch.
Switch and and here we are going to grab our pups, right, and we are going to grow from there the
type, so now we are going to create cases.
So the first case is going to be case.
Puppy type is extension.
So let's parcelling if it is extension.
If it is extension, we want to double double the the width of the panel, the width of the paddle.
How do we do that?
So first off, we need to check that if it is true, it means that it has already been consumed by the
paddle, then we do not want to double it, because each time if the user, like, grabs an extension
and doubles the width, then we are going to end up eventually with the kind of with that is going to
grab all of the screen.
And that is going to be a bug.
We don't want to do that.
So if.
If the user has already gotten a pop extension, if the extension is true, we just want to grab our
score and add onto it the pop bonus that I showed you otherwise, which is alse, what do we want to
do?
We want to grab our public's attention.
Otherwise, it means that public attention is false.
If it is false, we want to make it to true.
We want to set it to true.
And let's grab the paddles with and we are going to multiply on it to perfect and then we are going
to break from this.
So this is going to be our very first condition, our very first case.
We need four of these bad boys.
So this is case.
I'm just going to provide some space, provide some space.
Be very careful when you are like copy pasting like this, because a lot of errors may arise from this
if you're not careful.
So the second one is going to be pop life.
If it is pop life, we want to add at a life.
But first, if the user has already gotten a pop life, well, we don't really are.
We are not going to check for that here.
We are basically going to grab our lives because if the user has gotten a life before or not, we are
basically just going to go ahead and increase the life.
It could go to 100 even there are only three.
That's what we that's what I would like to do.
You could go ahead and implement this situation and you could say that you can't you will increase the
life only by one in each level.
If you do this, then that is going to do it only because in each level, if you, for example, get
three lives, only the first one will increase the count.
The second two on the second to this condition is going to apply and they are just going to increase
the score to buy to 100 and buy 50 each time.
But each time the user grabs a life, I just want to increase the life for the next step.
We have pop sticky and this is going to make the paddle sticky.
So make the paddle sticky.
And we say that if pup pup sticky is true, we just want to add to the score or else if it is not true,
we want to grab our pup sticky and we want to set it to true.
Right.
And that's it.
That's what we want to do here.
We just want to set it to true.
We are going to handle that stickiness as well, but later and finally, we have our Super Bowl, this
is going to be pop super and I'm going to call it Super Shutz.
Super shots, right, if pop super, if pop super.
If it is pop, if pop superstar is are ready, we just want to increase the count score count by 50,
you can increase it to 100 or ten, whichever you like.
Otherwise, we are going to grab our I'm just going to remove this because we are not going to need
that, otherwise we are going to grab our super.
And said it true, and then we are going to break out of that as well.
So this is where our
our switch is going to end.
So.
There we go, it ends there and then I'm going to grab our pops and I'm going to splice the I want one,
right.
And now here I'm going to play the audio for the power up as well.
So it was the audio power up.
Um, a oh, this one, this is it, this is the one, so let's save it.
Let's come here.
Let's see how far have we come.
There we go, so you can see that the life works, so that's a good thing and it is just one to five.
There we go there with also works.
What about the super?
Now, it doesn't this bounce it off.
You can see they don't work, the super doesn't work the stick, it doesn't work, we increase the count.
And if I grab another extension, you can see that we basically increase the count.
It's 162 by 100.
It should be two something now.
It should be three three, three, 13.
Right.
So if you have something and if you are ready and if you get something that you already have, again,
counts is going to increase by four for 16.
Perfect.
So the extension and the other one, which was that the life they do work, we need to implement the
first stuff.
I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to implement the color of the ball.
So if it is super, we are going to change the color of the ball.
So for that, let's go to our drawable function, so I'm I'm going to be keeping I'm going to be keeping
collapsing, I'm going to be keep class, what is the word I'm going to be keeping collapsing it.
That is the perfect form and grammar.
So for a second I was worried, like I forgot I've forgotten English.
So what we are going to do is no longer we want to only implement the ball color.
We want to check if it is a pop super, if it is a pop super, we are going to provide it with the pop
superstar color.
Otherwise you are just going to go ahead and show the color of the ball.
So first off, we need to check for Pop Super.
If Pop Super is true, if it is true, we are going to grab we are going to go to our pop type adult
super that color perfect.
We are going to grab the color.
Otherwise, if that is not true, we are going to just show the simple color of the ball.
So we have done that and you should see that we are going to be implementing this step by step.
So now the color of the ball should change.
There we go.
It changes.
So what do we have next?
Next, I'm going to apply
to a right.
So now you can see that I'm going to shoot first.
I'm going to show it to.
So if it is pop super, when we hit any brick, we don't want to bounce off that brick.
We want the ball to keep on collapsing the bricks.
That is what is the meaning of a super shot or a Super Bowl like with one like ball.
You will be able to to destroy so many like rows and so many bricks.
But you can see now with only with one, it is super.
We only destroy one brick.
That is not something that we want.
We want to destroy so many of them.
So let's see where we should implement that, so I'm going to go to our update bricks function.
So where is our update?
Bricks should be down here.
This is our update.
Bricks function.
So inside here, what I would like to do here is.
We are going to check we are going to say that this velocity is going to change direction whenever it
is not pop super, if it is pop super, we do not want to change the velocity.
We do not want to change the direction of the velocity.
So if it is not pop super.
Perhaps super, then we want to change, if it is pop super, we don't want to change the velocity,
velocity, direction.
So let's check that out.
I'm not going to grab it.
We are looking for a super.
Oh, lost it kind of there anyway.
Let's just do it one more time.
Let's see.
Let's grab the sticky.
Nothing should change.
Nasution should happen.
Scrub the extension.
We should check for the other ones as well.
So if I grab extension again, you can see that it went to 56 and now it should go once 107.
There we go.
It is 107 and it should be 158.
Our life should increase to three.
It is three.
And now it should increase to four.
We should get another 50 here.
There we go.
It should we should get another 50 here.
And our lives should increase to five, why we are not it is random, completely random that these power
ups that you get, they are completely random and now you can see that the speed of the ball has increased
and it's not allowing me to grab these lives.
There we go.
This is the super one, sir.
So if I headed back, it should not bounce back.
There we go.
You can see it is not bouncing back.
And this is called the super shot.
So we have successfully there we go.
That's why I call it the Super Bowl, right.
It might not be accurate, especially I'm not going to continue talking about this.
Let's destroy all of them.
So we go to the next level.
And all of these like balls, everything should be the balls.
They're not reset, but the power ups are we are not going to get any power.
See, we had an extension.
The extension is gone and the ball color is come on, the ball color is reversed as well.
You can see that all of them are set to fall, but we still have our 12 balls there.
All right.
So we have done that as well.
The next thing that I would like to do is I would like to implement.
The functionality for the pup as sticky as well, so we are going to go to whenever we grab the sticky,
let's grab one and I have to show it to you.
So I'm just going to grab the sticky one.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, there we go.
So when we grab it, the color changes to dark green and the bounce angle is going to be there we go.
You can see it's sticky.
The bounce angle is going to be directly 90 degrees.
There we go.
So sticky, I would say, is the most powerful of them because it is going to allow you to do everything
that you want to eat, all of this and it when even when it's double in size, the color is still going
to be that.
So first off, let's go into a redraw panel, draw power of function in here.
We are going to check if it is sticky.
So if it is pop sticky, pop sticky, if it is that if pop stick is true, we are going to grab our
pop type dot sticky.
That sticky, that color, we are going to grab the color, otherwise it is going to be our normal panel,
so let's save it.
Let's come here.
If it is sticky, the color should change.
Come on.
Give me a stick.
We are waiting for a sticky one.
There we go.
So bounce it off.
The color changes.
And if I get it a second time, 556, and this time it's going to be 107.
There we go.
And then one, 58 nerika.
Then 209.
There we go.
So if I increase the width, we should still have stick.
We haven't implemented that as well.
Now let's make this sticky.
Actually sticky.
Right now, before actually doing that, what I would like to do is let's go to our reserve board function.
I want to make the angle 90 degrees when it is sticky, so instead of passing the angle here, we are
going to check if pop is sticky.
Now, this we have never done before inside a function call implementing a ternary operator.
We have never done this, I believe, and this is really cool that you can see all these different possibilities
with JavaScript.
So if it is sticky, we grab my third pie, which is one eighty divided by two, which is going to give
us ninety degrees.
We want the bounce angle to be 90 degrees, otherwise we just pass the angle.
So whatever the outcome of this argument is, that is going to be our main bounce angle.
So and I would like to say this, that whenever the more projects you create, the more the logic of
programming is going to develop inside your head.
OK, and you will be able to better understand, OK, what should I do when and if you're if you have
that question all the time with you, you just go ahead and create more projects.
That is the idea behind adding 50 projects to discourse in the first run.
Of course, in one hour, update the course.
I'm going to add even more than that.
Right, because each of these projects is going to teach you a unique thing like this.
All right.
And it is going to open a unique door of opportunities that you can do with G.S..
Right.
So we are done with that one as well.
So whenever we grab it, we should go straight up.
Now, let's go ahead and let's I'm going to implement this stickiness as well.
So we are going to make it sticky and we are going to go to our updatable function.
Of date ball.
All right, right here.
So in the update, both function right towards the end, what I want to do is I want to make the the.
Make the ball stick to paddle, if
sticky true, if stick is true, just make it stick to the paddle for this.
What we are going to do is.
So where is our Smain Ball function and, hmm, what I would like to do actually is I'm just going to
cut this comment and we are doing all of that inside this cell statement, bouncing the ball off the
panel.
We are not doing it inside the ball itself just in here.
So I'm going to paste it here and I'm going to get rid of, you know what for stuff.
I'm going to create the if statement.
So basically, we are checking if pop stick is true.
If a stick is true, then we are going to grab the X velocity of the ball X V and we are going to set
a zero and we are going to grab the Y velocity of the ball.
And instead of zero, basically we are going to make the ball static and then we else else of the paddle
is not sticky.
This is if the paddle is not sticky, then we want to spend the ball and we want the velocity to be
reversed as well.
If we are going to check when the ball hits the paddle, then we are going to check for a condition.
If pop stick is to make the ball static, if it is not true, then basically just bounce it off the
paddle and spin it.
That's what we did here.
Right, and we should be able to do this right now, so if I come here until our game, let's check
it out.
It is super, we know that this works, the rest of them work.
And if I do super, we are going to get get that easier sooner.
So there we go.
There it is, our sticky.
So it is sticky.
And there we go.
You can see that it's stuck to the to the power.
All right, but, uh.
Why is it moving towards the center?
Is it the same thing and now it is not?
So there is something actually missing here?
Right.
But first, what I would like to do here, we are going to fix that.
Don't worry about it.
What I would like to do is I'm going to cut this part.
And we are going to put it inside the update padel function, so this is the update ball function and
this is the update, a function in the update panel function.
We are going to put that right here.
So before collecting the pups, I'm going to put that here.
And we are going to say, if the ball's a why velocity is zero balls exposition, we are going to add
on to it the paddles exposition minus.
And I think you remember that we created a variable here and that was the last position.
So let last paddle X.
So the exposition, the last part, the last position of the paddle in the X direction to be more accurate.
So it should be paddle that X and in here we are going to subtract that position as well from there.
So this is going to be move the ball with the paddle.
So let's save it.
Let's come here.
Oh, this is our game in here, this this is where we are working, so if I grab this sticky.
Now, let's try to see now that is perfect because we want to subtract which wherever the parallel was
from there, from the from the exposition of the paddle itself, and we are going to give the ball that
position, which basically what it means is we want the ball to stick to wherever sided was, wherever
wherever is the point where the ball is heading.
It should stick there.
It should not go to the center.
We just displace the center of the ball here.
And congratulations with this hour, a game comes to an end.
So what I'm going to do now is we are we have one more thing to check with the sticky.
And I'm going to check it first and then we are going to wrap this up.
So I'm going to check all of the pups.
So with this sticky, when it sticks, it should go 90 degrees up.
So let's grab this.
There we go.
It goes exactly 90 degrees up.
And if we get super, then we get this cool magic.
And if I eat all of them, all the lives are increased.
Here we go.
Because the chance is 100 percent.
So there are like high chance.
They're like 100 percent chance.
If you hit a break, you're going to get a pop.
We should not lose it.
OK.
And just going to try to clear this round and I'm going to play the next round and then I'm going to
wrap this letter up.
There we go.
So everything should work perfectly fine.
Let's eat all of this.
And the high score is increasing.
You can see that.
And whenever we eat the power, the power ups, the best is not going to increase because the best is
going to increase off of this the brick.
So the next time you hit, the best is going to increase.
And at the end of the lamp, you're going to see that both of them are equal.
So I'm going to play through this and I'm not going to play another round.
Now, this is the ball, this is the super shot.
And the speed is increasing.
You can see the speed on the right and the console, you can't see that that is open.
That's why I didn't comment that one out in the original game as well, because I want to I want you
guys to really see what what's happening here from this start, from the start of that.
So I'm going to try to eat all of them.
So I'm going to try to losable that we have 60 of them, so that shouldn't be a problem.
And you can see that when we lose basically what we are going to do, what we actually lost is not only
alive, but all of our pups, all of our power ups and all of the speed.
Everything is lost to the wind.
OK, so there we go.
Come on, give me the spin is also random, and I'm going to as I told you, I'm going to play through
this level and this taking a little longer than expected.
So you should be able.
Yeah, there we go.
Give me a pop.
That is the extension.
And I may not be able to grab it.
Now, I didn't.
So there we go.
We should see a couple of more.
And the speed is increased.
Oh, right, all right.
Right, let's grab all of them.
This is super boom.
And everything is back to normal.
Everything is good with the world again, so the last thing that I would like to do here is I want to
check.
We have Rose.
We have we'll both spend four or five paddle speed.
We could put the paddle speed equal to the ball speed.
You could do that as well.
Game Lives is three.
You can the max level.
No, that is not.
Where is our max level?
That is ten.
I just want to check our game parameters if they're correct.
So.
Puff Chance is going to be zero point one and the score, because it is so unique and you know what?
I'm just going to stick to 50.
I guess that's OK.
Pop speed is zero point one five.
You could go ahead and increase it or decrease it if you won.
If you want if you want to play the game easier, then you would decrease the speed of the pump and
you would get it definitely and break a number of columns.
No Afroz and.
There we go.
So a lot of lines of code, I know, but and I just want to go ahead and collapse everything.
I'm not sure when I when you get the code, it is going to be collapsed or not.
But I like to think that it is collapsed.
It is minimized and everything is perfectly fine.
So with that, with all of that, our game comes to an end.
Feel free to modify to your own well and add extra layers, extra levels, add extra pops.
You could increase the number of rows, you could increase the number of columns.
The original is eight by 14.
But of course you can always go crazy with it.
So if you if I added 20, you can see that we have 20 columns.
If you are 200, you are going to get 200 columns.
I think it looks good.
Yeah, and then you would have to bounce the ball like four a thousand times.
There we go.
And you can see the pop as well.
The reason for that is the size of the pop is of the size of the columns.
So everything is interrelated.
In case you want to change anything, make sure that you check it for all of the situations and you
do not break anything in the code that set for this lecture.
See you guys in the next game, which is going to be as awesome as this one.