Hi, everyone, in this that we are going to pick up where we left off in regard of implementing the
edit and the delete functionalities for the entries.
OK, so we know what the idea is going to be for that target that we click on it.
I don't need to really console it because at this point you are very familiar with that.
OK, so we need all this, we have all that now let's create our investment so we set if target but
we know Target.
Putin has a class, OK, because we selected the class right here and there are two classes because
there isn't any third class.
If there is a third class, this function is going to return and it is not going to run anything.
The function is going to return.
We just we are just interested for the classes of the icons, the icons.
There are two icons, hence two classes.
So if the target button, the icon that we have clicked on has you know what I'm just going to say one
equal to if the target button is equal to it icon.
IT icon for which the value is this, we have just stored it like a better practice.
If it is the Tikhon, what do we want to do?
We want to call the Idit entry function.
And whenever we call the edit entry function, we want to target that.
We want to grab the target ID because if I have like let's say, a salary of 1000 inside the income
and let's say I have a project 500, whenever I want to edit the salary, I should be able to that the
salary.
When I click on the edit icon for the salary, I should not be able to edit the project, I should add,
at that specific target idea that I have clicked on, OK?
That's why we have pastored there.
So this is our first scenario.
What is the other one so elusive?
What if the target button target Beaton is equal to delete icon?
So if it is the delete icon, we want to run the delete entry function and again, we will pass in the
target idea because again, I have a salary and I have a project in the income tracker.
So when I click on the salary, I should not delete the project.
Right.
I should delete the salary.
That's how we can track the ID and we are done with this event listener.
So now let's dive in and let's create the edit entry and delete entry functions.
So first off, I'm going to create the delete entry function, which is because this is easier than
the other one.
So let's create the function, delete delete entry.
OK, so we are going to pass in as the parameter target ID.
So what is the target?
We need to feed this function with a target ID, whereas the target ID going to come from we know where
is it going to come from from here, but where is it going to come from inside this function?
It is going to come from our entry list because when I when I completed, I'm going to tell you why
we are going to call our splice method, which we have talked about.
So the splice method either removes or replaces or adds to an item, item to array.
So that's what the splice method does.
So in this case, we wanted to remove.
So we are going to pass in the target ID.
What is the idea that we have clicked on and we want to remove one item of that array?
Because when I click on the salary salaries, what item and when I click it, I want to remove that
specific one item.
I do not want to remove the project as well with the salary.
In that case, I should provide two.
If I if you want to remove two items with one, click on the trash.
You just passed two.
But that is not how things work in the budget and in the budget.
And when you click on that one icon, that one ally should be deleted and the target ID from for that
ally is going to be passed from here.
We know what the target ID is.
It is the one that we have clicked on and we pass it right here.
So let's say the item has a target idea of zero.
When we pass the zero here, it means it is the first item inside that array.
And we want to this is the delete count.
The lead count is one.
So we want to delete the first item.
By one count, it means we only want to delete one item and then we want to update our UI.
Don't forget the parentheses this time.
All right, that was very, very energizing, so they delete entry is completed, completed its go ahead
and it's tested out in here.
So I'm just going to click on it and it says the editor is not defined.
So let's go ahead and define that.
So we are going to define the edit entry.
So we are going to say function.
No, no, no, no, no, we're going to edit entry function.
So
function edit entry.
What do we want to pass in as the parameter is the target idea based on the idea we delete it, we get
rid of it.
So let's go ahead and let's do a bunch of console logs.
So I'm going to grab your entry list at this point.
What is the entry list?
Let's go ahead and let's take a look at it.
So if I click on this edit, we can see our interest inside the entry list.
We have two specific objects.
The first one has an idea of zero.
The second one has an idea of one.
So what it is that I've clicked on, let's go ahead and let's find out.
And in here I am going to pass in the Target ID.
So the target ID should tell me what is what it is that I've clicked on.
So we are inside the expense and I click on this, we can see that we have clicked on the expense.
You can see this is the rent rent two and three from here.
So now we know what we have clicked on.
All right.
What do we want to do with that?
We know what we have clicked on.
What do we want to do with that whenever we click on the edit icon?
So when we click on the edit icon, we want to edit the title and the amount not set so that and you
know what?
I'm just going to keep it there and replicated here.
Dot image
and come on, buddy.
So if I click on this we should get the amount two, one, three.
And this is blue.
It means it's a number we don't need to do.
Jason, sorry, pass integer anymore.
So we need to grab the amount and we need to grab the title.
So that title.
So if I click on this salary and the amount is thirteen 64.
All right, so we need we have successfully selected these.
Why is that the reason that we have selected these as we are going to store these values?
So we are going to say let's target Type B equal to what is the type?
So the type you know what?
I'm going to create another console as well.
I might as well do.
Where is our cursor?
Oh, it's right here.
So let's see what is the type when I click on it.
So for this we should get income.
For this, we should get expense.
Perfect.
So now we are going to store all these console logs inside variables.
So the target type is going to be this one.
And then we have a target amount amount, the target amount is going is going to be this whatever is
be that the the expense or the income, I am running out of fuel.
So target title should be the title that we have here.
So entry dot v.
So this is going to give us our target.
So to the most important part, if if the target type.
Equals income.
What do we want to do?
We want to grab the income amount we're raised the income amount, so income amount, come on.
But we want to grab the income amount, income amounts, value, and we want to sell it to our target
amount.
So target amount is the amount that we just passed.
And there you just saw it.
And because whenever we want to edit an entry, basically we want to edit the amount and we want to
edit the title because that's the only two information that we have inside these inputs.
We don't we cannot edit anything else.
We cannot edit the type.
We have specified the type.
We just edit the amount and the title title that value.
So the value should be equal to target title.
Very, very simple.
So if the target type is income, do this else.
The target type is equal to expense, then do what they can, then do exactly the same thing, grab
the expense amount, amount's value and set it to target amount.
Now we set it to target Taman because target amount, as you just saw, could be the income amount or
could be the expense amount.
So this is targeted.
Doesn't matter what the says, as long as this is correct here.
And the title expense title value should be target title.
Do we have anything else here?
No, but yes, one more thing, we want to delete our entry.
Why delete our entry?
Everything is correct.
The application is done.
So whenever I click on the edit, when I click on it, you can see that the entry has been deleted.
Oh, gosh, where is the entry?
The entry is right here.
And if I add it to 2004 and now you can see it is 2004 if I come here and if I said rent is very, very
expensive, 1000 dollars, if I click on the edit at the end, we want to remove that I that item,
that entry, because we want to update it with another one like one oh one enter and this is it.
So let's go ahead.
We don't see any errors.
I'm just going to leave it right here in case there are any errors.
Let's delete yeb delete.
Yep.
Delete.
Everything is updated.
So oops.
What is this.
Let's reload the page.
Oops.
So let's say salary is very good.
Fifteen hundred let's add.
So no no no no no.
Salary is three thousand.
Just added it.
Very good expenses.
A lot of expenses.
Rent is like crazy.
150.
No no no no no.
Rent is actually 550.
Perfect.
It works.
Woops, what was that when I clicked on it, it said five fifty.
Yeah, so let's delete it.
Excuse me.
Let's try one more time.
It is that let's say 1500.
Yipes.
It is ipse.
It is deleted.
Everything is there.
And where is the income.
Did we delete the income.
12.
Reload the page.
OK, everything is right here, 12 is very insignificant to.
What is happening here, what is happening?
OK, so let's go ahead, do it one more time project.
Project 1000, that's it, and let's add the expense, rent 500, that's added.
So if I click on this, everything is right here, this ad 5000, it is 5000.
Everything is in the all I can delete it from the all everything is here.
So now nothing is here.
Right.
And our local.
Why doesn't it call the clear?
Inputs, what is happening with the clear inputs?
Hmm, OK, this is delete entry oh, whoops, we should say targeted as well.
That's why it was like a bit buggy there.
So let's go ahead and let's say one more time.
I should be I should make sure that this is working properly.
So twelve hundred, let's admit it to like twenty thousand.
I'm very rich getting rent.
Well I couldn't be rent rich because French because they pay nineteen thousand of that for rent.
So if I delete both of them from here.
It is still here.
Did I click on the edit, it is still here.
Oh, right, so what is going on here?
So we say update UI, we update the UI by one, we grab the target ID pass and the target ID, Target
ID, Edad ID if type is income, we want the amount value target amount, income title, target title
income target type is expense expense amount value target amount title target title home if target button
is added to icon.
Run the data entry, otherwise run the delete entry if target beats.
If Target Beacon is that.
It attack on the daily Tikhon target button.
Where is the entry?
The entry.
And that parent out, so if I come here into this target IED to that target, specifically that IED,
I mean, shouldn't be seeing that here.
So let's let's see if we can see them here.
So if I delete them from there, I can't see them here.
So, you know, in the final application, let's say project twelve hundred, let's edit it to 1500,
add an expensive front like one 20, that's Editta to 150.
And now if I remove it from here and from here, it is not here, it is not here and it is not here.
So it should be the same for this one as well.
So project that say 1500 Editta to 2500.
And let's add expensive rent, 750, oh, no, that's added to do that.
Let's click on this and click on this.
Oh see, everything is cool because we added the triple equality.
This is why I always tell you guys use the triple equality.
Always.
All right.
So I think I think our application is done.
We can't afford to look.
So now nothing should be inside the local.
Of course, we can delete the entries from here as well.
Delete them from there.
It is going to be deleted from the all.
So if I added, if I deleted from here, the URL is going to be updated accordingly.
So now if I go into my local storage, into application, local service, we see and only we can see
there is like this empty array.
And we can see that in here as well, that if I go ahead and if I cancel our entry list, entry list
is this should be an interior as well.
And let's wait for it.
Come on.
OK, so this is an empty array as well, length zero, this is it for this project.
I'm super, super excited that you have come this far and I'm really happy for you.
Good luck on your journey to the end of this course, because there is a lot like like literally a ton.
Not literally.
They don't teach us grammar here.
So my back there is a lot there is a lot still remaining.
But I really commend you on your perseverance and hard work.
You are a wonderful person for doing all this for you because you want a better life.
You want like more more money or whatever it is, you're going to get it, I'm sure, and keep working
hard.
You're going to achieve all the milestones.
You're going to, you know, like the cliche, sky's the limit.
See you guys in the next chapter.