Welcome to your very first section for the class.
The first video for each and every section is a little section introduction.
That's where we come together face to face for just a minute or two to talk about what exactly we're
going to cover in the section and how that's going to fit into the bigger picture goal of the class
which is to get to the point where we can build and launch our own no J.S. applications.
So here's an example in this section section 2 you'll be getting your machine set up for the rest of
the class.
We'll start by installing no J.S. on your computer.
And I'll set you up with a text editor that works really well with note.
We're also going to talk about what exactly know James is and why it's something you should spend your
time learning we're about to invest a significant amount of time learning something new.
And it's always a good idea to know what exactly you're getting yourself into.
All right let's jump right into the section.