In this video you're going to learn how to get input from the user into your node j s application.
And this is going to be essential for creating anything meaningful.
So think about the notes application.
If I'm the user and I'm trying to use the notes app to add a new note as an example I need to provide
some information about that new note such as a title and a body.
The same would be true with I'm trying to use this notes application to remove a note.
I have 15 different notes I need to provide some information about which note I want to remove.
Now for the moment we're going to handle getting input from the user via a command line arguments later
on in the class as we get into node j s with web servers.
You'll learn how to get input into your node application from a client such as a browser.
For now though let's go ahead and get started with the fundamentals of getting input into your app with
command line arguments.
Let's go ahead and get started in the terminal.
So down below I'm going gonna use clear to clear the terminal output and over going to do is run our
script through the node command with one slight modification.
So node space app dot J asked.
We know exactly what this does.
We get our your notes message and our blue success message.
Let's go ahead and run that same command.
This time though after we're done we're gonna type A another space followed by a value.
So for the moment let's just use something like our first name.
I'll type mine in Andrew.
Now we're gonna run the program again and what do we get.
The program still works.
We get the exact same output.
The only difference is that we've now provided additional information that our program could choose
to use to do something dynamic like print a greeting with that name inside of the message that prints.
Now the question is where exactly do we access those command line arguments.
And the answer is that they're on that process.
Global variable we explored in Section 2 in Section 2 if you remember we took a little time to illustrate
some of the differences between JavaScript in the browser and JavaScript running in node j s I talked
about how the browser has window and document and how node has global and process well on process.
There is a property and that's where we can access all of the command line arguments passed in to our
app.
Let's start by dumping them to the console.
So right here console dot log process Dot.
Remember process is a big object with dozens of different methods and properties.
We're looking for one specific one.
It's called ARG V and that's an all lower case r v stands for argument vector and in the case of node
j asked.
It's just an array that contains all of the arguments provided.
Right here I'm going to save apt J S just dumping all of the arguments to the console.
Then we're going to rerun our script with Andrew appended.
So right here I'm going to rerun the script and what do I get I get my two pieces of output that were
expected and I get my one new Array.
This is the value for ARG V and what do we have.
We have three strings inside of there.
Now there are three strings and two are always provided.
The first one is the path to the node j s executable on your machine.
Now this is obviously going to be different for each and every user.
The second is the path to our app dot J S file.
Once again this path is also gonna be slightly different depending on where exactly the file lives on
your machine.
But both of them should be paths to those two locations.
The third is the value that we actually provided.
Right here we have the string Andrew which means that we could take advantage of that in our program
to do something meaningful.
Let's go ahead and extract the individual value out of that array.
So process dot ARG V is the array we want to grab an item from the array by its index.
So I'll use javascript bracket notation to get that done and we put the index right inside where 0 is
the first one.
One would be the second one and two would be the third item right here.
This is exactly what we want.
Now if I were to save the script and rerun things we wouldn't get this long array with a lot of useless
information.
We just get our one piece of useful information we have the string Andrew and we can now use that to
customize our program.
Now in the case of the notes application we're gonna use this first value after the script name to actually
determine what action we want to take.
This will be known as our command.
Am I trying to add a note.
Am I trying to read a note or remove a note.
What sort of action am I trying to take when running the program.
So for example right here node space app dot J S space I could do something like ADD which would let
the program know my intention is to add a new note right here I can see that ad now Prince and I could
use this to run the write code.
Let's see what that would look like.
So up above I'm going to remove all of the code except for r to require calls.
Those are going to stay as we'll continue to use them and all we're going to do for the moment is create
a variable called command and we're gonna get its value from what we just printed to the console.
That's a process dot ARG v grabbing the third item by index.
Now we could actually use an if statement to conditionally run some code if the user who's running the
app provided ad we could run the code necessary to add a note.
Otherwise we won't try to add a note right here.
If we'll set up our condition and the code block to run if that condition passes.
And we're just going to check if command equals using triple equality.
The string ad if it does we know the user is trying to add a new note and we could run the code necessary
to create the note and save it to our data store for the moment.
We're just going to console dot log a little message letting us know this code actually ran.
I'll say something like adding notes now if I save the program and rerun what do I get I get adding
note printing which is fantastic.
Now we could also run this with a different command for example node space app dot J S space.
Let's go ahead and use something like remove to remove a note.
If I run this you'll notice I'm not getting any output because I haven't set up the program to actually
do anything when that's the provided command value.
I could always address that by setting up an else if statement checking if command equals the string
right here.
Remove if it does equal remove.
That's great.
We'll go ahead and run all of the code to get the removal done.
Console that log right here.
Removing note as a temporary placeholder.
Now we could save the program we could rerun things again and there we go.
We now support that second command allowing users of way to add notes and to remove notes from here.
Let's figure out how to get even more information for each command.
So knowing that the user is trying to add or remove a note is a good start but if someone is trying
to add a note I need the notes title and I need the body.
If someone is trying to remove a note I need the title as an example of the note that should be removed.
So how are we going to get that done.
Well once again we're going to start with the command we've been using throughout this section.
So right here node act J s ad then we're going to provide command line options like you've probably
seen with other command line tools so hyphen hyphen title could be where we set the title.
I'll set that equal to inside of double quotes the following.
This is my title I could run the program and now we're passing in even more information.
It might not look like it but if we were to dump our V to the console once again we would see it console
dialogue process dot ARG v just dumping the entire array of you on the program exactly as we had it
with titles set up and now I'm getting as the third argument ad which we already had and as the fourth
one I am getting title.
Now one thing you'll notice here is that it's not something that gets passed for us.
We have the exact text typed out over here as we do here minus the double quotes.
We need to now add some code to manually pass that we have to figure out for example if title was actually
provided.
If we do see that title was provided we have to get the value.
Now sure we could go ahead and write all of the code necessary to pass those arguments.
It would result in maybe 12 of the most on interesting videos in this course where we didn't talk about
no JSA at all but just talked about string passing.
Now we're not going to do that and for a couple very good reasons one we would have to write test and
maintain all of this code and that code it doesn't do anything unique passing command line arguments
is not unique to our application so it would be best to look for it NPM package that can take care of
that for us so we can get back to the task of writing what does make our application interesting which
is in this case its ability to manage your notes.
So in the next video we're going to look at how we can use a tool to pass.
Process dot ARG v making it much easier to set up our arguments for our node j s applications.
I'm excited to get to that and that video will include a challenge.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.