In the last video you learned how to get input from the user via a command line arguments in your note
J.S. application.
We saw that all of the arguments provided to node are passed through into our application and we can
access them via a process dot ARG V.
Now as we were exploring this we also saw that we don't necessarily get these values in the most useful
way possible.
Node doesn't provide any argument passing it's a very bare bones utility allowing us to just access
the raw arguments.
So when I provided this title option with the value things to buy it wasn't passed in a way that's particularly
useful.
I would need to write some code to extract the key and the value from this string something we're not
going to do because most node j s applications use command line arguments in some way and there are
a ton of great NPM packages out there that are gonna make it really easy to set up our commands and
options as we want.
And in this video we're going to explore one of them called yards.
That is why a r g s Let's head over to the browser.
Here I have my one tab on NPM J S dot com.
I'm gonna go ahead and search for that yard's package and right here it is the first one yards is a
pirate themed application which is where the y in args comes from and it is a fantastic utility with
about twenty one million weekly downloads so it is a widely used well tested tool that we can easily
integrate into our application.
Now you might be saying Hey I thought this was a node course and it seems like we're using a lot of
packages.
We already saw that node doesn't provide a ton of argument passing and at this point that is intentional
node has left it up to the community to create various packages each with their own way to solve the
passing problem.
You can then go out and pick the package right for you and args is one of my favorite and it happens
to also be one of the most popular.
So let's go ahead and install it into our project so we can make use of it from the notes app directory
npm install.
I'll be using AI which is the same thing.
It is an alias.
Then the module name yards and the latest version that is at twelve point zero point two.
So we're gonna go ahead and install this into our application then we'll be able to use it to better
pass our command line arguments.
All right.
Everything was installed down below and I'm just gonna take a quick moment to clear the terminal output.
Now let's take advantage of this in app dot J S instead of manually looking at process dot ARG V on
our own.
The first thing we have to do is require it.
And once again I like to go core modules first.
We have none.
Then NPM packages and then our own files.
So right here I'm gonna load in another NPM package alongside of Chuck we're gonna call this variable
yards and we are going to get it from the return value of using require to load in the Yas library.
Now we can actually take advantage of it and that process is super easy.
What I'd like to do is do a little comparing and contrasting.
So to keep the output simple I'm gonna remove this command variable for the moment and I'm going to
remove our if conditions down below and all we're going to do is print out process not ARG V.
Then down below that we're also going to log out something from yards it's yards dot ARG V.
So this is the version of process dot ARG V that yards has passed.
Now we can see exactly how the two are gonna differ.
So let's go ahead and start by running our script node space app dot J S and we're gonna run it with
nothing additional.
What do we get.
We get a lot of information for the first version.
The one that node provides and Jago provides almost nothing.
Here we have an object with two properties.
We have an underscore property which will get populated with various arguments in a little bit.
Once we actually add them and we have dollar sign 0 which is the name of the file that we it.
So let's go ahead and actually add some arguments into the mix and see how Jago is going to help us.
Right here I'm gonna set up the ad command and I'm also going to set up that option once again.
So hyphen hyphen title equals inside of double quotes a name for some note let's use things to buy things
to buy.
Maybe it's some sort of grocery list.
And if I go ahead and run this now we're really going to start to see some of the advantages.
So the first array from node itself contains what we've already seen before.
We have information that's not too useful.
We have our command and we have some unpassable option down below what you args provides us is much
more useful.
Our command shows up in the underscore property right here ad and we have an actual title property on
this object that contains the string value so yards did all the heavy lifting of passing our options
and putting them on this object.
So they're easy to access.
I can access the title property to do something with it like a create a new note and save it to our
data store.
Now this is the most barebones way to use yards since we haven't configured it to do anything special
by default though we actually get some pretty useful behavior to explore that.
Let's go to the terminal down below and clear the terminal output.
We're going to run our script so node space app dot J S and we're going to do that with the help option
something we haven't done anything to create and actually comes by default with yards and it displays
some helpful information about what's going on with our little app.
Now this first part.
This is still coming from our console log on line 5 which we can go ahead and delete it is the second
part we're interested in.
This is what's coming from yards itself so it's printing a little cheat sheet about how to use our tool.
It's showing two options that are available help which shows the help.
That's what we're seeing right here.
And hyphen hyphen version which shows the version number of the tool we're using.
That means we can actually run node app dot J S with that version option.
And what do I get.
I get one point zero point zero.
So by default yards it starts you off on that version and you can always customize it to fit your needs.
Let's go ahead and do that up above I'll leave a little comment customize Yahoo's version and we do
this by accessing yards and calling the version method.
This takes to it a string as its one and only argument and we provide our new version no.
So maybe I'm ready to move on to one point one point zero.
As an example.
Now if we were to save the program and do rerun in that version and command what do we get we get our
new version no showing up.
So yea.
Was it comes with a ton of useful passing and features on its own but it can be configured to do pretty
much anything you want and that's what we're gonna start to get into down below.
I'm going to clear the output and we're going to focus on setting up yards to work with the commands.
We need it to work with for example in the notes application.
People should be able to add notes remove notes read individual notes and list out all their notes.
These are four distinct commands we want to set up and customize.
I want to display help options for each.
I want options so I can pass in data all sorts of things and yards supports all of that.
Let's start by working through one command together the ad command.
So right here create ad command.
And this starts by calling the command method on your ARGs that is yards dot command and we pass to
it an object.
This is our options object where we can customize exactly how this command should work.
Now the first thing we have to provide is a name for the command.
Does it add as it read.
What is it.
Right here we do that by setting up a command property setting its value equal to a string name.
Now I'm gonna start with the ad command so I'll setup ad as the value.
From there we can also add a description to describe exactly what this does.
That happens via the describe property.
This is also a string value and I could have something like add a new note as a way to describe exactly
what this command is supposed to do.
Now we can also set up a third property called handler.
That's the code that's actually going to run when someone uses the ad command.
So down below comma the next property handler.
This needs to be set up with a function value and that function gets executed if the command ever gets
used.
So right here a brand new function.
And for the moment we're gonna have a little place holder console dot log call and we'll just say something
like adding a new note.
Excellent.
Now let's go ahead and see how all of this is going to change our application by running it from the
command line to start.
Let's go ahead and use that help option right here.
I'm gonna run the file using the help option like we did previously and we're going to notice that because
we've registered a new command.
We have a new commands section in apt and J S I have access to the ad command which adds a new note.
Now let's go ahead and actually use it.
So node app dot J s ad and when we run it what do we get.
We get our little message printing to the screen adding a new note is showing up.
So this proves that our handler is indeed running when someone runs our application trying to perform
that ad command which is a fantastic step in the right direction.
Now let's go ahead and add a second command into the mix down below.
We're going to add a remove command so create remove command and once again we are going to use yards
dot command to set that up right here.
Passing in the options object and we'll configure these same three properties.
We need a command name.
I'm gonna call this one remove.
We have to describe our command.
Well we actually don't have to describe it but it is a good idea to describe it.
I'll say something simple like remove a note.
Then we're going to set up our handler function.
So right here setting that function up and providing some code to run when someone uses remove right
here.
Console dialogue removing the note perfect.
Now we can use this second command from our program as well.
And it's also gonna get ended up listed in our help options.
So I'll rerun the command I ran two commands ago to use the help option.
Right here I see remove showing up below add.
Now let's use a remove node app.
J S remove and when I do I can see that removing the note is printing which is great.
That is exactly what we were hoping for.
Now it's gonna be up to you to add two more commands for read and list.
Let's go ahead and talk about what I'd like you to do right here.
I'm going to paste in some challenged comments.
There are three steps for getting this one done.
The big picture goal add two new commands and you can do that right here below the remove command.
Step 1 you're going to set up the list command and for now you can just print a place holder message
saying something like listing out all the notes you want to use list as the name and then you can pick
a description that makes sense something like.
List the notes the other command you're going to create is the read command.
Once again you want to set up the command name you want to give it a description and for the moment
you're going to continue to print some sort of place holder message until we actually wire up the functionality.
Now once you have both of those commands created using the command method I want you to test your work
by running both of them from the terminal and ensuring that you get the correct output.
All right take some time to knock that out when you're done come back and click play
how'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by working with step 1.
Right here we are going to create that list command so create list command.
We're going to call a yards dot command to register a brand new one and passing in our options object
and we'll start by setting up that command property the name list.
Then we'll set up a describe value something like list your notes or anything similar would have worked
and last up we have to set up a handler.
So I will do just that providing a function value.
And once again I mentioned you can just use a placeholder message for now.
So console dot log something like listing out all notes.
Perfect.
Next up.
Step two we have to create the read command.
So let's go ahead and do that as well.
Create read command with a call to your args dot command.
Down below passing in that same options object and setting up those same three properties.
We're gonna have our command property the name for this one being read.
I'm going to set up describe and right here we'll pick a description read a note and then finally we're
going to set up handler because we want to do something when someone runs that command right here.
A place holder console dot log reading a note.
Excellent.
Now that we have that in place it's time to move on to the most important step.
Step three which is to make sure that the code we wrote actually works as expected and this is a very
important part of every challenge.
Let's go ahead and do just that down below.
To start I'll clear the terminal output and we'll start with the list command.
So node app dot J s list right here listing out all notes shows up.
I misspoke because I spelt things wrong.
It should be listing out all notes.
Excellent.
Then we're gonna go ahead and move on to the read command.
So node app J.S. read.
And what do I get.
Reading a note shows up which is great.
And there we go.
We now have a basic configuration with four commands set up to run code when the command is actually
used in the next video.
We're going to wrap up our discussion of command line arguments by exploring how we can provide additional
options for each of these commands.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.