In this video we're going to wire up the ad command together and in the next video you're going to wire
up the removed command on your own as a challenge.
So let's go ahead and jump in.
The first thing I'm going to do is change directories and the last video we were using that playground
folder I'll be using C.D. dot dot to get out of that directory.
Then forward slash notes hyphen app to get into the notes app project folder.
From there I'll use clear to clear the output and up above.
I'm going to close all open editors and switch over to the notes app directory.
Now we are going to use app dot J.S. and notes dot J as in this video notes that t x t that was created
as an example file of the file that we're going to store our data in as we learned about in the last
video is going to be a Jason File.
So let's take a quick moment to delete that notes dot text file.
Now like we did previously notes dot and J asked is going to define a function that gets called an app
dot J S so let's start there.
Right here.
We're gonna go ahead and define a another function const I'm going to call this ad note and this is
going to be the function responsible for adding a note.
It's going to take in the title for the note as the first argument and it's going to take in the body
of the note as the second argument and its job is to actually get the note saved to the data store.
Now how are we going to do this.
Well we'll talk about that in a second.
The first important thing to discuss is how are we going to export more than one thing from notes dot
J.
And the answer is simple Instead of setting module exports equal to a single function we're going to
set it equal to an object and we'll define multiple properties on there for the multiple functions we
end up creating.
Let's set up both of those properties the first being get notes whose value is going to come from the
get notes function defined up above.
So we have a property of the same name as our function then we're going to do the same thing for ADD
note setting up an add note property and getting its value from the add note variable defined up above.
So now in effect we are exporting an object with two properties one for each function meaning that they're
both getting exported and they can both be used by another file like apt at J S now over in Apt.
J Yes we do indeed require that file we just edit it no longer does it return a single function to the
name and get notes is misleading we should rename that to something like notes utilities or just notes.
This is now an object with two properties we have a guest notes property and we have an add note property
both of which we can now take advantage of in this file and we're gonna start by calling add note in
our handler for the ad command down below right here.
Currently we're just logging the title and the body to the council we're gonna go ahead and instead
call our new method.
So right here that's going to be note dot add note and we're going to pass in the two arguments it expects.
We just defined it the first one is the title The second one is the body.
So the title lives on our v dot title then comma space the second argument that's the body which lives
on Argh the DOT body.
Perfect.
Now the handler is all done.
It's passed the information off to add note and it's up to add note to actually do the job of adding
the note to the data store.
Now currently there is no data file and we don't have any code to read or write from the file system
either.
So we're gonna have to add all of that.
The first thing we have to do is load in the existing notes.
We don't want add note to override any data.
We want to load in the existing ones stored as Jason.
We're gonna pass them we're going to add something new onto the array and then save them back to the
file system.
Now we'll be loading in our notes from multiple functions for example.
We'll need to load in our notes when someone wants to remove a note.
So I'm going to create a little reusable function that just gets that done const load notes equals a
new function.
It does not take in any arguments and it's going to return an array of notes.
So in the end of the day the goal is to be able to use it like this const notes equals and then we'll
just call load notes and get the notes back.
So hopefully we can make this API actually work and we can.
Let's go ahead and move into load notes and get this done.
Now we are going to use f asked to read from the file.
So let's make sure to load that in before we try to use it const F as equals.
We are going to require the file system module.
Now we can actually take advantage of it and we are going to read from the file.
Now we don't have a file yet and that's OK.
So right here const I'm going to call this something like data buffer equals I'll be using F S dot read
file sync to load in a file and we can pick whatever name we like for this.
I'm gonna call it notes dot Jason.
So this is the file we will be reading and writing to from here we can convert that buffer into a string.
So const data Jason equals we'll use data buffer dot to string then finally we're gonna go ahead and
pass it.
So right here I can go ahead and return the following I am going to return the past data by calling
Jason dot pass and passing in the data Jason value.
Now this code is kind of work really well.
If there is a file and it contains Jason but it's actually going to fail.
If there is no file or the file does not contain Jason let's go ahead and prove that by running the
program I'm going to run the program using that app command.
So from the terminal that would be node app.
J.S. ad we'll provide a title.
I'll just stick with the letter T and we'll provide a body.
I'll just stick with the letter B and if we run that command what do we get.
We get a really long error message and if we scroll up I can see that the English readable version is
no such file or directory to open and then it's talking about our notes not Jason File which we're trying
to load.
So clearly that's a problem.
Now we have a couple of options.
We could one create that file or two we could write defensive code that knows how to work.
Even if that file doesn't exist.
And that's the approach that we are going to take to do this.
We're gonna use java scripts try catch statement.
So right here try with a code block.
So we open and close a set of curly braces.
Then after the closing braces we set up our catch block and we define our error which I'll just call
E.
And we set up our catch code block.
Now if any of the code inside of try throws an error that code is immediately gonna stop and it's going
to run the catch block instead.
So that means we can take these three lines cut them out and move them in to try.
So if either of these three lines throws an error the code will immediately stop and it will run catch
instead.
If they all work that's great we will get the past data back as expected.
Now what do we want to do.
If one of these things fails well if there is no file and that throws an error this code is going to
run.
So all we're going to do is return an empty array.
This is basically what would happen if we had an empty file.
So we don't have to worry about overriding data because this code is running we know there is no data.
So we'll just start add note off with an empty array.
It can then add the first item to that array and later on it'll be saved to the file.
So we'll file will actually exist and it can be loaded the next time around.
So let's go ahead and test this out right here console log printing notes I'm gonna save notes dot J
S I'm going to rerun it the exact same command I ran before by using the up arrow key and enter and
this time around what do I get I get my empty array showing up which is great now that we are at least
getting an empty array we can start the process of adding our new note on to the list.
Now how are we going to do that.
Well we're going to use the push method on arrays.
So right here notes dot push and we are going to push on what I'm going to push on an object so we'll
be representing each note as an object with title and body properties.
So right here I'll set the title property equal to whatever value is stored on that title argument and
I'll do the same thing with body down below.
Setting up a body property whose value comes from the body argument up above defined on line 7.
So now we've loaded in the data we've added something to the array.
The next thing we're gonna go ahead and do is save that data.
Now once again we'll be saving data from multiple places in our application as well.
So we're going to create a little reusable function for that down below right before load notes though
the order is not important.
We're going to create a new constant and I'll call this one something like save notes now save notes
is going to be a very simple function but it is indeed going to take an argument it's going to take
in the array.
So remember when we want to save data we take the object or an array we use Jason string ify and then
we write it to the file system.
That's exactly what we're gonna do with whatever data is passed.
And so right here let's use save notes up above I'm going to call save notes.
I'm going to pass in the notes array which has been changed since it was originally loaded in.
So we're going to end up saving that new note and then all we're going to do is string ify the data
and save it to the file system right here.
I'll create a constant for that string a file.
Jason I could call it something like data.
Jason that would work just fine and we'll use the Jason dot string a fine method which we've used plenty
of times before.
And we're going to pass in notes.
Now we have our Jason data and we need to write it to the same file we were loading from.
So we have a note Scott.
Jason File.
Well we don't have it yet but we'll have it shortly.
F S dot right file sync.
Writing two notes Dot.
Jason and what are we writing.
We are writing whatever is stored in that data.
Jason variable above and there we go.
We load in the notes.
We change them and we save them.
This is essentially what you did for your challenge in the last video with just a little more complexity.
Adding a little error handling to make sure that things always work smoothly.
Let's go ahead and test this out.
Now the program should indeed create that file.
I'm going to rerun the same command we were using before.
And what do I get.
I get no output.
That's okay.
There is no console dialogue statement running but I do have my notes that Jason File and if I crack
that open it looks like an array with a single object inside that object has a title property with the
value of t and a body property with the value of b both coming from the options we provided to the command
line down below.
And this is a fantastic step towards creating the notes application.
Now let's go ahead and add one more note right here.
I am going to load in the previous command and just use the arrow keys to change the data so I'll remove
the T for a title and I'll use something like list as the title then for a body.
I'm just going to list out some stuff maybe that I need to buy.
It's getting cold out so let's go ahead and put in sweater and I'll also put in some new pants.
Not plants.
Perfect.
Now if we run this hopefully we don't override the existing data but we just append to it.
I'm going to run the script and what happens well hopefully in just a second we see our refreshed data
and there it is.
We have our existing note from earlier and we have our brand new note with the correct title and body
values.
So this proves that both of the cases for low notes are working the first time around when there was
no file this did indeed throw an error.
So we started off with an empty array giving us a barebones way to actually create that file the next
time we ran it.
This didn't throw an error.
It correctly passed the existing data and then added onto that existing data and saved it.
And in the end of the day we are seeing the correct results over here.
Now let's wrap up this video by adding one more small feature to our function.
We're going to make it so that add note checks if that title is already in use.
So if I'm trying to add a note with a title and that title is already taken the application won't let
you add it again.
So we're gonna prevent duplicate notes from being added.
Let's go ahead and knock this out.
First up I am going to clear the output down below.
Then we're gonna make some changes to the ADD note function.
The first thing we need to do is look through the notes array and see if any of those notes have this
title and to do that we're going to use the array filter method.
And the reason I'm doing this now is because in the next video you're gonna have to use the array filter
method for your challenge as well.
Now let's go ahead and actually knock this out right here.
That's going to be const we are going to create a new array called duplicate notes in here will store
all of the duplicate notes we find if we find none.
Great.
We'll go ahead and run this code if we find some.
That's obviously a problem and we won't add the new one because it would be a duplicate.
Let's go ahead and use the method.
That's an array method.
We'll call it on the notes array it is filter.
This is going to return a subset of the notes array.
So if there's 40 items in here duplicate notes will be either 40 items or less depending on how many
match our criteria and we define that criteria by setting up a function and this function gets called
one time for each note.
So in our current case it would get called two times once with this object then once with this object
and we access the object via that first argument right here we can call this whatever we like.
I have an array of notes.
We have individual items over here so I'll call it singular note.
Now the goal is to return either true or false.
If we return it true filter is going to keep that individual note in the new Array calling it a duplicate.
If we return false filter is not going to keep that in the array saying it's not a duplicate.
Now we don't want to type out the boolean explicitly.
Instead we're gonna use a little conditional logic we're going to use the equality operator to check
if note dot title equals the title argument from up above.
So this function is going to run twice the first time that's going to see if our title equals this.
If it does it's going to return true meaning we have a duplicate.
If it doesn't it's going to return false leaving the duplicate notes or write empty it's then going
to call this function again with the second object.
We're going to compare that title and go through the same process.
So this array is going to have zero items if no duplicates were found.
And now we can use that to conditionally run some code down below.
If a condition and a code block to run the condition.
We're going to look at the duplicate notes array if its length is zero.
We know we didn't find any duplicates which means that we can safely add this note so down below I can
take these two statements I can cut them out and I can paste them inside of the code block and we can
even print a little message console log something like new note added.
Perfect.
Now we could also add on an else clause to this if statement and then here we could run some code if
duplicate notes dot length is not equal to zero in which case we have found a duplicate console log
I can say something along the lines of note title taken.
Perfect.
Now that we have this in place let's go ahead and see it work in action.
I'm gonna try to add a duplicate.
Make sure that fails then I'll try to add a new one and make sure that works from the terminal.
Let's go ahead and cycle through our previous commands looking for one of the ones we've already executed
right here.
This is the command where we added the list.
Note now that already exists in the data that should be caught as a duplicate.
Let's run the program and see what happens right here.
No title taken which is great.
You'll notice that no new note was added because the title was already in use.
So the duplicate notes array had a single item the first time it ran our callback it ran it with the
note object being this one right here.
Now the title t did not match up with the one provided which was list so that returned false and nothing
was in duplicates or right.
The next time it ran used this object seeing if this one was in the array already and it was it compared
note dot title which is this value with the value provided.
And those are identical which means that this returned true which means that item was kept in the duplicate
notes array bringing the length to one.
So this condition did not pass this code was the code that ran.
Now let's load in that same command and change the title.
I'll create a new list called the list to I'll run the command.
And now we can see new note added.
And over in the Jason we have our third note added onto the list.
So now that we have this in place we have one of our commands knocked out in the next video.
It's going to be up to you to wire up the remove functionality.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.