Welcome to section number five in this section.
You're gonna learn how to debug your know J.S. applications.
So as you might have already seen when you run your program things don't always work as expected.
You might introduce a typo into your program causing your app to crash or you might misuse a function
causing strange and unexpected behavior.
The goal in this section is to give you the tools needed to actually fix these problems so you're going
to learn how to debug and inspect your app as it's running so you can figure out exactly where your
program is going wrong and why that's going to give you the information needed to fix the mistake in
the code and get back on track.
Now in the beginning all of this is going to be a little frustrating as it's going to take a lot of
time to debug your issues.
It might take 10 or 15 minutes to figure out what's going wrong and to solve it.
The good news is that as you make mistakes which you will it's only going to get easier to fix them
over time by the end of the class.
What might have taken you 10 minutes to debug will only take 10 or 20 seconds to fix.
You'll notice you start to see a lot of the same issues and patterns over time.
So what we're going to focus on in this section is not perfection.
Perfection isn't a realistic goal.
Anyone who's writing software is making mistakes.
The real goal is to be able to recover from them quickly and get back on track so we can continue to
be productive.
All right let's jump right in and learn how to debug our note apps.