WELCOME TO SECTION NUMBER 8 where you're going to learn how to create your own API endpoints and you're
going to learn how to access them from the browser.
So right now we have these two distinct applications on the back end.
We know how to take an address and convert that into a forecast.
And on the front end we know how to get our web application up and running in the browser.
The real question is how do we integrate these two together.
What we need is for the browser to be able to communicate with the server passing and address along
then the server needs to convert that address into a forecast and pass it back to the browser.
So the browser can actually render forecast data to the screen to get that done.
You're going to learn how to create your own H TTP Jason end points with Express.
I'm excited to get to it.
So let's jump right in.