In this video you're going to explore the two tools we'll be using throughout this section to deploy
our node j s applications.
The first is get hub end.
The second is Heroku.
Get hub is the very popular software development platform which gives us all of the tools necessary
to manage software development projects whether we're working by ourselves or whether we're working
with others and Heroku gives us all of the tools and infrastructure needed to actually deploy our node
j s applications to a production ready server to get started.
Let's explore both tools in the browser and we'll also create accounts for each over in the browser.
I'm gonna crack open a brand new tab and navigate over to get hub dot com GitHub.
As I mentioned is a development platform making it easy to manage our projects.
This is going to make it easy to track code changes over time to collaborate with others and to track
bugs issues and feature requests.
Now all of those NPM modules we installed all of their code is actually hosted on GitHub with get hub.
You can host a public or private projects depending on whether or not you want to share that particular
code with the outside world.
Let's go ahead and get started by looking at an example.
What I'm gonna do is just google NPM Express.
This is gonna bring us over to the Express package page on NPM J.S. dot com.
This is a place we have been before.
On the right hand side bar near the bottom of this little stats panel is a repository link and this
actually links over to the github project page for express.
If we visit this we can see we have all sorts of interesting information about the project.
We have issues.
We have projects documentation and pull requests a pull request is just a feature suggestion and if
we scroll down we can learn more about the project.
We have all of the files and folders that make up this project and then down below that we have documentation
for how to get started.
So when we create a get Hub project we are essentially creating one of these.
It can be public or private and we're going to use GitHub to track our project code.
So let's go ahead and get started by creating a new account or signing into our existing one.
If you need a new account you can use the sign up form on the home page or you can click sign up right
here.
If you have an existing one that's fine too.
There's no need to create a new account.
I already have one so I'm going to take a quick moment to log in to my existing one.
Now what we see here is information specific to our accounts.
So you're going to see different information than what I have here.
I have all of my code projects on the left hand side.
I have my feed right in the middle and on the right.
I have some discovery suggestions which I typically ignore.
So now we have a get how the account created.
We don't know how to use it but that's OK.
The goal here is to just get everything set up for the rest of the section.
And now what I'd like to do is do the same thing for the other tool.
We're gonna be using which is Heroku.
You can find Heroku on the web by heading over to her Roku dot com her Roku is an application deployment
platform.
It's gonna give us all of the tools and infrastructure necessary to take our application code.
No J.S. applications and deploy them to their production servers.
Now Heroku isn't no J.S. specific you can use Heroku with P HP Ruby on Rails Python Java and other languages.
In this case though we are indeed trying to use Heroku with node now in the end of the day both get
hub and Heroku are businesses which means they do have paid offerings.
That's how they stay in business but both also have generous free tiers allowing you to get started
without needing to pay any money or provide any credit card details and their free tiers are gonna be
more than enough for us to explore both tools and for us to actually get our applications deployed to
production.
Now once again we're gonna need to either log into our existing accounts or sign up for a new one.
If you don't have a Heroku account you can go ahead and click that sign up button.
The account is completely free.
They just need a few basic pieces of information which they ask for down below.
If you already have an account you can log into your existing one.
There is no need to create a new one for this class.
I already have one so I'll take a quick moment to log in.
Now what we see when we actually log in will indeed be different depending on the particular account
here.
I have a bunch of different projects I've created for clients as well as many test projects which I've
used with my various Udemy classes.
So once again you're going to see something completely different to start.
They're likely going to show you some sort of onboarding or welcome screen.
That's OK we'll work the process of creating and setting up a new project in just a few videos.
For now the goal is to just have an account for get hub and for Heroku and to be logged in for each.
The last thing I want to do in this video is install Heroku whose command line tools these are gonna
give us access to various commands we can use from the terminal to do things like deploy our latest
code changes to the production server allowing users to see the latest changes to the application.
The tools can be accessed by heading over to a new tab and Googling Heroku.
S.L. I this is gonna bring us over to an article that the Heroku Dev center.
So here I'm at Dev center dot Heroku dot com.
This is the U.R.L. that we want.
And once we're here at the Heroku Seelye article the first thing they talk about is how to install the
tools.
There are installers for Mac OS and for Windows and down below there are various commands you can run
to install it on a boon to or other Linux distributions.
In my case I am indeed running on a Mac so I'm gonna take a quick moment to grab the installer take
a quick moment to grab the installer for your operating system and get the tools installed.
I'm gonna download the installer and this is one of those very easy to use click next to type installers
for Mac and Windows users.
All we have to do is continue through the little installation wizard.
There is no need to customize any of the options and once it actually goes through the entire process
we're gonna have a new set of commands that we can access from the terminal before we wrap up the video.
We will take a few moments to explore some of those commands and actually test things out to make sure
the Heroku CLIA was installed correctly.
Right here the installer has completed I'm going to close it and trash the installer and now it's time
to test out our new commands.
Now to actually use these we are going to need to restart our terminal.
So from Visual Studio code we can use controls C to shut down node mod then I can use this little trash
can to close the terminal.
Now we can open it up again essentially restarting it right here.
Terminal new terminal.
Or note the keyboard shortcut become familiar with it as it's super useful.
And from here we can test out our new commands the Heroku CLIA gives us access to the new Heroku command
and we can use this to do all sorts of interesting things for the moment.
I'm just gonna use it with the V flag to print the version of the tools we have installed.
Now if you get an error when you run this you know that things didn't install correctly.
You can always crack open a new question in the course Q and A.
And we'll work with you to fix that.
Otherwise you should see something similar to what I have here.
It starts off with the Heroku version.
Then there's some additional information about our OS and our node version.
The things I have highlighted now are gonna look different for you.
You should see some sort of Heroku version upfront.
If you're seeing that.
That means her Roku was installed successfully and the last command we're going to use is Heroku log
in.
This is going to link the commands we run from the terminal with our Heroku account so we can actually
manage our projects from right here in visual studio code.
Now when we run her Roku log in it it's going to ask us to open up a new tab in the browser by pressing
a key.
Pretty much any key but the Q key I'll press space that's going to crack open a brand new tab in the
browser asking us to log in to the Heroku S.L. eye and since I'm already logged into my Heroku account
we just did that a few minutes ago.
All I need to do is click the log in button I can see that I have successfully logged in and it's telling
me I can close that tab.
And from the terminal I'm getting some brand new output right here.
I can see logging in is done and I can see I am logged in as followed by my Heroku account email.
Right here you should be seeing a similar message with your email address showing up if you're seeing
that.
That means that you're done for the video.
You have a github account you have a Heroku account and you have access to the Heroku command line tools
to create and deploy your node projects.
That's where we're going to stop.
For this video we're not quite sure how to deploy our projects just yet but we now at least know what
tools we're going to use to get that done in the next couple of videos.
We're going to talk about how we'll put all of this together by using version control.
I'm really excited to get to that.
So stay tuned and I'll see you in the next one.