In this video we're going to continue to work with the get tasks request allowing the client making
the request to sort the data in a specific order.
So now that we have timestamps enabled they could sort by when the task was last created or last updated
or they could sort by the completed value putting the complete tasks first or putting the incomplete
tasks first.
So let's go ahead and start by looking at that you are L structure and then we'll actually worry about
implementing this into the javascript code below.
Right here it's still get forward slash tasks and the option we're gonna be setting up support for could
be called something like sought or sought by.
This is going to allow someone to specify these sorting criteria.
And there are typically two pieces to the value.
The first is the field we're trying to sort by.
And the second is the order.
So do I want to sort.
In an ascending fashion which would be something like 0 through 10 with numbers or a descending fashion
which would be 10 through 0.
So we can specify that using the following.
Right here.
Let's say we want to sort by the created at field.
So I want to sort my tasks by when they were created.
Now this alone isn't enough.
Do you want to sort them with the newest first or the oldest first.
So the next thing we provide is whether it's in an ascending sort or a descending sort.
There are a few different ways you can do this the most common is to use a character like the underscore
to separate the two.
So right here created at underscore a S C for ascending or created at underscore D E S C for descending.
Now if you're someone who likes to use underscores in your field names you could always switch this
up to a colon.
Any special character in there would get the job done.
Later on we'll be splitting this string on that special character to break it up into its two component
pieces so we can set up these sorting correctly.
So in this case I would be sorting my tasks by when they were created in a descending fashion.
Now let's see what this is actually going to look like by modifying the populate call below.
We'll do this with a hardcoded value then we'll actually accept and pass sort by as an option down below
we specify our sorting criteria by setting up a another property on that options object.
This one appropriately enough is called sort and in here we can pick the field we want to sort by.
So let's say I do want to sort by created and I would simply list that field out then I provide the
order in which I want to sort ascending would be one excuse me right here has one and descending would
be minus one.
So this is how we're actually going to set things up in terms of the call to populate.
So let's go ahead and see this in action.
I'm just going to hard to code us sorting created at.
In a descending fashion we'll head over to postmen and see what we get.
Right here.
I'll remove everything related to Paget nations so all four come back and what am I getting I'm getting
the tasks in the reverse order.
Fourth third second and then first at the bottom because this is them sorted by created at.
In a descending fashion we have the newest ones first and we have the oldest ones last.
Now if I wanted to reverse that I could sort by.
Created at setting it equal to 1.
And in this case I would see them in the order in which we created them.
So I have first up top.
Then second third and fourth.
Now I could also sort by something else.
So let's go ahead and remove created at and instead sort by complete it.
Right here I'm gonna start by sorting in a descending fashion using minus 1.
Now if I fire this off and post man what are we gonna get.
Well right here we can see we have our complete tasks showing up top end our incomplete ones down below.
If I wanted to see my incomplete tasks first I could go ahead and sort in an ascending fashion by setting
completed equal to one right here we'll fire off a request for the last time for the moment and post
man and I can see that I have my incomplete tasks up top.
So this is the basic behavior we'll be using.
The only thing we need to do is allow the user to customize it by actually providing that in the you
are out.
So let's go ahead and start with this.
We'll try to sort by created at in a descending fashion.
So over here we'll set that up the query string sought by setting an equal to.
We're going to sort by created at that our special character whether it's an underscore a colon or anything
else followed by the order either ascending or descending I'll use D E S C for descending.
Now if I fire that off the data isn't being used but we're gonna go ahead and change that.
Now once again this is a situation similar to how we set up complete it.
There's a chance they might want to sort.
In ascending or descending there's also a chance they don't specify sort by at all.
So we can't actually provide any information right here.
Instead we're going to do what we did with match.
We'll create the empty object and we'll use it down below.
And there's a chance we'll actually customize it.
So right here what we're gonna do is create an empty sort object we're then going to use that sort of
object as the value for this right here.
I'll remove the hardcoded version and use the shorthand syntax to set sort equal to these sorts variables
value.
Now we can see if sought by was actually provided and if it was we'll set something up on these sort
objects.
So if request dot query dot sought by if that is defined what do we need to do.
Well we need to go ahead and break up the value which would be all of this.
What I want to do is split it by that special character so I can get the two individual pieces right
here.
Let's go ahead and knock that out now to do this.
Let's start by creating a variable a concept called parts.
And what we're going to do is get its value from the following.
We're gonna use request dot query dot sort by.
So this is the string value provided and we know it's provided because we have our if statement right
here and we're going to split it.
We'll be using these string split method to split it up by the colon or the underscore whatever special
character you're choosing to work with.
Now down below.
Let's use those two parts to set up something on these sort object.
So down below when we had manually done it sort had the field we were trying to sort by as the only
property on that object.
Right here we have to do the same thing.
Now we don't have a static name like sort.
Dot completed at sense it's not hardcoded that user is providing the name of the property we need to
set.
So what we do is we use the bracket notation and the value comes from a variable.
It's in the parts array it is the first one.
So here I'm grabbing the first item in the parts array and I'm using it as the name of the property
we're setting on sort.
Now with that in place we have to set that property value equal to either 1 or minus 1 as we just saw
when we set up our populate call with static data.
Now we don't have one or minus one.
We have descending or a sending a S C or D E S C we're going to convert that to either 1 or minus 1
using the ternary operator down below.
So we start off with our condition.
Right here I want to look at that second part right here.
I want to see if it is equal to the following string.
D e S C is this person trying to sort in a descending fashion.
Now what the ternary operator the resolved value is one of two things if this is true it's whatever
we put after the question mark which we know is minus one for descending if this is not true if it's
false then the value would be whatever is after the colon.
So here the ternary operator is called the ternary operator because there are three pieces we have our
condition we have the value for when the condition is true and the value for when the condition is false.
So this is going to make sure that these sort of object gets set up correctly.
Now with this in place we're actually done and we can test things out to make sure we can indeed sort.
So over in postmen we have created at in a descending fashion I'm going to go ahead and fire that off
and down below what do I get.
That's exactly what I get.
I have four third second and then way at the bottom.
I have first now I could swap out ascending excuse me descending for ascending and if I fire that off
what do I get.
I can see I have first up top followed by second third and fourth.
Now we can string together all of the available options to do multiple things at the same time.
For example I could get all of my incomplete tasks sort them by when they were created and then I could
use Paget nation to get the first ten followed by the second 10.
So with these options in place what we're giving the client the ability to do is really customize the
data that comes back without these options.
They would always get back all of their tasks.
And as I mentioned that can get out of hand really quickly as more and more documents get added to the
database.
This can slow down your server and it's also definitely going to slow down the client device whether
it's a desktop laptop or mobile phone.
It's gonna have to request a huge unnecessary amount of data by providing a few simple options and adding
maybe what 13 lines of code to our router we were able to give that client complete control over the
data they're getting back that's gonna make sure their app can stay nice and fast and snappy and it's
also going to make sure that our server isn't constantly querying and sending back thousands of records
which is going to take more time than it otherwise would need to.
Now as always if you have questions about anything covered here just crack open a new question in the
course Q and A and we'll get back to you right away.
That's where we're going to stop for this video end for this section in the next section.
We're going to dive into a very exciting topic which is file upload so we'll figure out how we could
upload something like a profile picture for a user account.
Let's go ahead and jump into the section introduction for that one.