In this lesson you're going to learn about the Web socket protocol of the web socket.
Protocol is what we're going to use to create real time applications with node j s now web sockets are
not specific to node J.S..
You could use web sockets with other programming languages as well.
But in this case we'll be using web sockets with no JSA to create our real time chat application.
So what I want to do in this video is just talk about exactly what web sockets are and how they're going
to help us achieve our goal the goal of a real time application.
Now like with the TTP protocol of the web socket protocol is going to allow us to set up communication.
Let's go ahead and see what this is going to look like.
So we'll start off with our server.
In this case it'll be a node J.S. application that starts up a server and we'll learn how to actually
do this with web sockets in the next lesson.
And from here clients can connect to that server.
So I might have one client connect then I might have a few others as well.
For this example let's go ahead and add four clients into the mix.
Now here we have four clients connected to our server using web sockets.
So what exactly is this going to allow us to do.
The first thing we're going to be able to do with the Web socket protocol is achieve what's known as
full duplex communication.
Now that's just a fancy term for bi directional communication which means that the client can initiate
communication with the server and the server can initiate communication with the client.
This is not something we had with each TTP requests with an H TTP request.
It was the client's job to initiate the request asking for data from the server and then the server
would go ahead and respond.
But at any point in time the server couldn't just send data to the client if the client didn't make
an HD TTP request the server had no way of communicating with it.
All of that changes with web sockets with a web socket.
We have a persistent connection which means that the client connects to the server and it stays connected
for as long as it needs to.
So if I'm creating a chat application I can connect to the client which in this case would be a browser
to the server and then the client could send messages to the server and the server whenever it wanted
to could send messages to a client.
So first up very important we have full duplex communication.
Next up Lulu web socket protocol.
It's a separate protocol from each TTP.
That is why we are seeing very different behavior.
And then what we get is a persistent connection between the client and the server which I already talked
about.
So right here the two important things to note is that one we have a persistent connection and two.
We have bi directional communication.
If you understand that then you understand everything necessary to actually create a real time application.
Let's go ahead and see how all of this would work.
In an example to get started let's go ahead and ignore three of our clients focusing on just this one
right here and its connection and communication with these server.
Now in this example we're going to talk about what it would look like if we were creating a chat application
which is exactly what we're going to do.
So right here at the client end and the server are going to communicate and to the communication remember
could be bi directional.
So it goes from either client to server or from server to client.
In this case we're going from client to the server and we're sending a new message across.
So this particular user has typed something in the input field they've clicked the submit button to
post the message to the chat room and that message goes from the client to the server.
Now when the server gets the message it could do nothing.
It could just print it to the terminal or do something else like dump it to a file on the file system.
But what we really want to do is bring our other three clients into the mix.
So the client has sent a message to the server.
We're done with this component.
The next thing we're gonna do is make sure that everyone else connected to that chatroom actually sees
the message that this person typed.
So right here we'll go ahead and bring those three clients into the mix.
And this time we're also going to send some data around this time though it's going to go from the server
to the client something we were not able to do in the past.
So right here the server has said to this client I have a message from another user.
It's going to send that message across to the client and the client can it in the browser the exact
same thing is going to happen with our other two clients as well.
So in this case we have client server communication.
When someone types a message and hits enter and we have server to client communication.
When that message needs to get sent to all other connected users and this is what allows for a real
time application this client over here can get the chat data in real time as soon as the server gets
it it sends it off to the other client and in reality for us it's going to look like it shows up instantly.
So this is what we're working towards.
We're going to work towards implementing the web socket protocol allowing for all of our clients to
stay connected to the server and allowing for the clients and the server to communicate in both directions
which as we've just seen is going to be really important client to server and server to client.
Now we're gonna get that done using these socket dot I O library which we'll be setting up in the very
next lesson.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's jump right in to the next video.