In this lesson as promised it's going to be a challenge.
Video in this one you'll be using what you learned about socket it done.
I owe to set up the events necessary for the chat application now to get started.
What we're gonna do is comment out all of the code for the little count app we built in the last lesson.
I'll leave that code around though so you can use it as a reference for the stuff you'll be creating
in this one.
So in chat dot Jay asked on the client what I'm going to do is comment out everything except for that
very first line and then over in index dot Jay asked on the server what I'm going to do is comment out
my two calls to socket methods inside of the connection callback.
Now the only thing that runs when someone connects is my log method call up above.
I'm gonna make sure to remove that count variable which is no longer being used.
And right here this is where I'll paste in the challenge comments for the first of the two challenges
you'll be completing.
The goal here is to send a welcome message to new users.
So you're gonna have the server emit a message event when a new client connects.
This is going to send some data back which will be a string.
The message that the client should receive and in this case you could just send something like welcome.
So that would be similar to Down below where we emit count updated and pass in the count.
Here you're emitting message and passing in a string with your welcome message.
Now once the server is correctly emitting that event you want to make sure the client has the code set
up to actually receive it.
So you're gonna have the client listen for the message event and then you're going to print the message
to the console.
So when a new message comes in it should show up down below in the console.
Similar to how our count was showing up before.
Next up test your work.
If you save all of your files and refresh the browser you should see welcome printing in the console.
The Chrome developer tools so take some time to knock that out using what you learned in the last lesson.
When you're done test your work and then come back and click play
how that go.
Let's get to it by first omitting the correct event from the server.
So right here when we do get a new connection we'll use a socket that is meant to send a message to
that particular connection.
Right here the event message followed by the message to send.
And in this case anything would have worked.
I'll go ahead and use welcome.
Next up we want to make sure that the client is actually listening for this event and doing something
when it occurs.
Let's go ahead and move over to chat Dot.
Jay s in here.
We're going to use a socket dot on to listen for message and we know we're going to get access to that
message data as the first argument to this function.
Now down below we can go ahead and do something like print it to the terminal right here.
I'm just going to dump the message variable.
Now I can save chat dot and J.S. and I can save index dot J Yes and we can test our work.
So I'm going to switch over to Chrome from here I'll refresh both of my clients and I would expect both
of them to get that welcome message and that is exactly what's happening.
I have welcome for client 1 and welcome for client 2.
Now from here what we want to do is provide the user with an interface where they can type in a message
submit that message and have that message sent to the server.
The server is then going to relay that message to all connected clients.
So I type something over here and click a button and I should see it show up over here.
As a new message for them to read let's go ahead and talk about how we're going to get that done over
inside of index Dot.
Jay asked what I'm going to do is replace the current challenge comments with a new set right here.
Your goal is to allow clients to send messages to one another.
So the first step is to create a form with a text input and a button.
Now this is similar to what you did with the weather search form previously in the class.
So if you forget how to get that done you can always dig into the code for that project to jog your
memory and you're going to add that form into index dot H2 UML.
Now once you have the form in place in chat dot J.S. Yes you want to add an event listener waiting for
that form to be submitted once the form is submitted.
You're going to emit an event from the client to the server with that data.
So when someone submits the form and you're gonna get the input text value you're then going to emit
send a message and you're going to provide the string message that the user typed as the data.
Next up on the server you're going to listen for send message.
So once that event actually occurs you'll relay that message to all connected clients.
And this is very similar to what we did with increment down below right here.
We relayed the updated count to all connected clients.
You'll simply be relaying the provided message.
Now there's a lot to do here.
So the best way to approach this is to not try to write every single line of code then save the program
and hope it all works.
It's best to move one step at a time get the forum up and running and make sure it renders correctly
add a form this submit event handler then run your project and make sure that triggers from there start
to omit the events and test each step of the way.
There's no need to write all of the code because when it fails it's gonna be really hard to figure out
what failed.
If you write just the code for Step 1 and it fails then you know step 1 failed.
So take some time to move through this one.
There's quite a bit here.
When you're done test your work you should see a form for each client in the browser.
When you type something in that form and click the button you should see the message show up in the
console for all connected clients.
All right knock that out.
Test your work and when you're done come back and click play
how'd that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by first creating our form.
So like we did with the weather search form earlier in the class.
We'll be adding something into our HDMI file.
No I didn't tell you to remove the button but you can indeed remove it.
So if you didn't remove it as part of the challenge just take a moment to remove it right now inside
of here we'll be setting up a form exactly like we did with the weather search application.
And right here we're gonna go ahead and provide an input.
So I'm going to set up my text input and I'm gonna provide a placeholder like we did before as well.
And the place holder could just be something like message perfect.
From here we also want to set up a button and I will have the button text to be something like send
though the exact text you use isn't particularly important.
Now when it comes to setting up the form submit event listener we could choose to target it by tag or
you could add an I.D. on right here.
Either way would get the job done.
I'll go ahead and add an I.D. on and I'll call this one something like a message form perfect.
Now with this in place I can go ahead and refresh the browser to make sure that it's actually showing
up correctly.
And right here I'm seeing it which is a great step in the right direction.
With this in place we've actually finished.
Step number one.
Now let's move on to Step number two.
I want to make sure that when the form is submitted we actually do something.
So over in chat dot J Yes let's go ahead and kick that off by targeting the form that is document not
query selector grabbing it by its I.D..
And in this case the idea we just picked is message form and then we're going to use add event listener
and we're going to listen for that submit event.
Now from here we'll go ahead and set up our function.
And if you remember when we listen for form submissions we get access to that e event argument and we
want to use E dot prevent default to prevent that default behavior where the browser goes through a
full page refresh.
This is exactly what we did with the weather web application.
Next up what we want to do is emit an event.
So right here we want to emit send a message with the actual text that the user typed in.
Now currently we're not doing any sort of validation.
So you could have an empty message that is perfectly fine for now.
Let's go ahead and knock this out over inside of our callback function right here.
Let's go ahead and grab the message.
Storing it in something like a message variable.
And I'm going to target that input so document dot query selector.
I'm going to select by tag name in this case input and I will use value to grab the value for the input.
Next up we're going to use socket dot image to emit the event send a message and we're going to provide
the one piece of data I wanted you to provide which was the message.
So I'll go ahead and provide that right here.
Now with this in place the client is actually done.
We can save this and the next thing we need to do is make sure that the server is doing something when
send a message is received.
So over in index dot J.S. that means we'll be setting up a another call to socket dot on right here.
And this time on the server we are listening for send a message.
We have our callback function that runs when a new message is sent and we get access to that message
data right here.
So remember the first argument is the name of the event that we're emitting and everything after that
is provided to the callback function.
On the other end.
So in this case we're providing message to the callback function on the server.
Now once again I could call this variable anything like S G.
That would work just as fine though I will stick with message.
Perfect.
Now down below what do we want to do when I get a new message I want to send it to every single connected
client right here.
That is I O dot omit omitting the message event and sending the message data.
So right here it's very similar to what we did when someone joins and we send them our welcome message
though in this case the text for that message comes from another user.
Now with this in place we can make sure to save both the server and the client and we can go ahead and
test our work.
So what I'm going to do is move over to the browser and I'll just give both of my browser tabs a quick
refresh.
Right here we have the welcome message for both which is great for this first browser tab.
What I'm going to do is type from first client I'll hit enter or click the send button.
And what do I see down below.
I have that message up showing in real time for both clients.
Now if I type something in for the second client this is a test and hit enter.
We can see that in real time all clients have access to that data.
Now currently once again we're not validating that any message is typed and we're not clearing the input
after the message is sent.
This is OK.
We'll work on focusing on those UI improvements throughout the section.
For now the big picture goal was to make sure that we're able to send messages between the clients connected
to our server and we are now over inside a visual studio code.
We can remove all of the code we had for that count application.
I'm gonna remove the commented out code in chat dot J.S. and save this file.
Now it only contains stuff before the chat app and over in index dot J Yes I'll do the same thing.
I'm gonna remove the commented out code in our connection callback end up above.
I'm also going to remove the challenge comments right here since they're no longer necessary.
That challenge is completed and we've tested our work making sure it's functioning as expected.
Now before we go there's one more small tweak I want to make together.
And this is not related to socket dot I.
Oh it's actually related to the input.
We're creating an index dot H2 UML.
Right here we're creating an input and then in chat dot J.S. we are selecting it by its name.
Now if there was another input on the page that could mess up our code breaking it.
So what we're going to do is make a small change when we have element inside of a forum we can setup
the name attribute for them.
For example I can provide this with a name whatever makes sense for what the field is storing.
It could be name before a user's name it could be age or location.
In this case something like message makes a lot of sense.
Now we can actually access this forms element by its name from inside of chat dot J s making sure that
if there was another input on the page it didn't break our application.
So right here we have name set to message.
I'll save the file over here.
All we're going to do is change how we get access to the element in the end.
We're still going to pull the value property off of there.
What we're going to do is remove everything after the equals sign and we're going to access e now E
has something on it called Target.
Target represents the target that we're listening for the event on and in this case that's our form.
So right here we have access to the form from there on our form elements.
We have access to an elements property and we can access any of our inputs by their name.
So that is e dot target to get the form then dot elements dot followed by message which is the value
we picked.
So this is just an alternative way to get our input.
And this one is less likely to break as the H2 UML for the page changes from here.
We're gonna go ahead and grab the value property on the input exactly like we were doing before.
Now if we go ahead and refresh things inside of Google Chrome we should see the exact same functionality
right here.
I could type a message in like test.
I can send it off and it shows up for both.
So now our application is still working as expected.
It's just a little more foolproof preventing changes to the HDL from breaking our javascript code.
Now that we have this in place we'll continue on in the next lesson.
So stay tuned and I'll see you soon.