In this lesson you're going to learn how to broadcast your socket.
Dot Iowa events.
Now this is going to lead us to two practical features for our chat application.
The first one when a new user joins all other connected users are gonna have a little message show up
saying that a new user has entered the chat room and when a user leaves the chat room all connected
users will see a message saying something like a user has left the chat room.
Now for the moment there are no user names for the individual connected clients though that's something
we'll fix a bit later on in the section.
For now the goal is to just get those messages showing up.
One when a user joins and a another when a user leaves.
So let's go ahead and figure out how we're gonna do this by heading over to index dot J S as we're going
to make some changes to the callback function for the connection event.
Now when it comes to omitting events we have two ways to get that done.
The first is to use the socket dammit.
We know that amidst the event to these single client that we're referring to and we also have I O dot
omit and we know this amidst the event to every single connected client when we broadcast an event we
send it to everybody except the current client.
So that's going to allow us to send a message saying something like a new user has joined to everybody
except the new user who's joining.
So right here what we're going to do is use the following that is socket dot broadcast dot emit now
emit works here just like it works anywhere else.
The only difference is that it's going to send it to everybody except this particular socket.
So right here what I can do is emit a message and I can say something like the following a new user
has joined.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and actually test this out.
What I'm going to do is navigate over to Chrome and we have our two tabs opened up.
I'm going to close down the second tab though I'll create a new tab first.
So the whole browser window doesn't close then I'm going to refresh the first tab over here.
As expected I see my welcome message now from the second browser window.
What I'm gonna do is open up new developer tools.
One more time and I'm going to navigate over to local host on port three thousand.
Now when I do so I would expect to see just to the welcome message here.
And that is exactly what I'm getting.
And over here I would expect to see a message saying a new user has joined and I'm getting that as well.
So now we have three ways that the server can emit an event I can use socket data emit to emit it to
that particular connection I can use socket dot broadcast data emit to emit it to everybody but that
particular connection.
And finally I O dot omit to send it to everyone.
So there are cases where you want to use all three it's not like one is better than the other.
They just do different things and they're going to be used in different situations depending on who
should be notified about what's going on.
Now one more thing we're gonna do is make sure that all connected clients also get a message when a
user leaves.
Now to get that done we have to figure out how we can run some code when a user gets disconnected.
For example when they close their browser tab.
Now there are two main built in events and one we already explored.
That was I O dot on connection which allowed us to run some code when a given client connected.
We also have a another event that allows us to run some code when a given client gets disconnected.
Now this can be a little confusing because it does not use I O dot on.
We're only ever going to use I O dot on for connection if I want to run some code when a given socket
gets disconnected we use socket dot on inside of our connection callback.
Now in this case we're also using a built in event so the name and needs to match up exactly.
That is disconnect.
Now there's no need to omit either the connection event or the disconnect event from the client.
These are built in events so the socket dot Io library takes control over actually emitting these all
we have to do is setup the listener right here.
Now we're going to run some code and this code is going to run whenever a client gets disconnected.
Now in this case we actually don't need to use broadcast because the client has already been disconnected
so there's no chance that they get the message.
Now what we're going to do is send this message to every single client who is still connected.
That is I O dot MIT right here emitting message and saying something like a user has left.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and see if this actually works as expected.
What I'm going to do is save the file and over inside of the browser I'm going to take this second browser
window once again create a new tab and close the old one then I'll refresh just the one page which is
open at local host three thousand as expected.
It's the first user and we get our welcome message from here.
Let's bring that second one into the mix.
That is a local host on port three thousand.
Now when I join I can see a new user has joined and if I go ahead and close that browser window I see
a user has left.
So by adding just what four lines of code we're able to set up messages for when users join and leave
our chat application.
Now this is going to allow us to build all of the features you'd expect from a chat app.
And we're going to continue to use socket dot Io to get that done.
That's where we're going to stop for this one.
I'll see you in the next lesson.