In this lesson you'll be adding a new feature to the chat application which is going to allow users
to share their exact location with one another.
Now to actually get the user's location we'll be running a little client side JavaScript code using
the browsers geo location API that gives us a way to fetch the location for a given user assuming of
course they consent to sharing their location.
We'll be using that from client side JavaScript to fetch their latitude and longitude and once we have
those coordinates we'll share them with the server who will share them with all other connected clients.
So it's similar to how we share a message though instead of the user typing a message and sharing that
we'll be fetching coordinates using this browser API and sharing those.
Now the exact API we're going to use can be found by cracking open a new browser tab right here.
We're going to Google M.D. end geo location M.D. and standing for the Mozilla Developer Network.
It is a great set of documentation for everything browser based.
Right here we can view the API documentation which is going to show us how we can fetch that location.
Now I'm only pulling this up show you so you know where it lives.
Of course we're going to go through all of this together in the lesson.
So let's go ahead and get started.
And the first thing we need to do is make a change to the user interface.
What we're gonna do is show them a another button which they can click to share their location and that
will show up for other users like a regular chat message.
Now let's go ahead and get that done by moving over to index dot HDL.
We're going to create a new button just outside of the form so right down below I'll create a new button
with the text of send location or something similar and you can use whatever you'd like.
And we're also going to set up an I.D. so we can easily target this button from javascript right here.
Let's go ahead and use something like send location.
Perfect.
Now we can go ahead and save the file and actually wire up a click event for this button over in chat
dot J S when the button is clicked then we'll use that geo location API to actually fetch the user's
location over in chat Dot.
J Yes all of that is going to happen at the very bottom of the file.
Right here we'll kick this off with code.
We already know about.
I'm just going to use document dot query selector to grab that button by its I.D. and the I.D. we picked
was send location and from there I'll use add event listener and we are going to add the Click event
listener and we'll run at the following function when the button is clicked.
Now not every browser supports this geo location API.
Most modern browsers do.
But if they're using an older operating system and an older browser we want to make sure to show them
a message if they're not going to be able to perform this operation.
Now everything we need for geo location lives on navigator dot geo location.
Now if this exists that means they have support for it.
If this does not exist that means they don't have support for it.
So what we're going to do is use this inside of an if statement to check if they don't have support
right here.
If we're going to look at that property once again that is navigator dot geo location and then we're
going to use the logical not operator to check if it does not exist.
If it does not exist we're going to run the following code.
I'm gonna use a return to stop the function execution and we're just going to stick with an old school
alert function call to print a little message.
You could use a modal if you wanted to but for now an alert will get the job done right here.
Something like geo location is not supported by your browser.
Perfect.
Now down below we'll run some code for a wind geo location is supported and the first and only thing
we're going to do is get their location so we can share it.
The location can be fetched.
Using navigator dot geo location dot get current position.
Now get current position is indeed a synchronous it takes a little time to get the location but unfortunately
it currently does not support the promised API so we can't use promises or async await.
Instead we'll be calling this function passing to it a single callback function.
This could be a standard function or an arrow function.
I'll stick with an arrow function.
Now this function will eventually get called with an object called position and this contains the information
we want to share.
Now before we actually share it let's go ahead and long get to the console to see what exactly we have
access to.
So right here all I'm going to do is log out the position object.
Now we can save chat dot J.S. and actually test things out.
I'll make sure all my files are saved and I'll refresh the browser.
Right here we have our send location button.
Now when I click that I'm gonna have to consent to sharing my location right here.
Chrome is letting me know that local host three thousand wants to know my location.
I'll click allow and it's going to take maybe a couple of seconds for the location to get fetched and
once it is we'll see the object down below.
Now if I expand it we can see we have a timestamp property showing when the location was actually fetched
and then we have courts.
If I crack that open we can see we have the latitude and longitude and that is exactly what we want
access to.
Those are the two values we're going to share with the server as this is enough information to determine
your location.
Now getting the rest of this done is something that you already know how to do so we're not going to
do it together instead.
It'll be your challenge for the lesson.
So down below I'm going to paste in the challenge comments describing what I'd like you to do.
The big picture goal is to share those coordinates with the other users.
Now later on in the section we'll learn how to share a link that links to a Google API map with your
location pinned.
But for now we're just going to share the latitude and longitude as a text.
So step one you're going to have the client emit a new event called Send location and the data is going
to be a single object with the following properties.
The object should contain the latitude and longitude properties with the correct values off of the position
object and you're going to emit that event right here.
Now once the event is emitted from chat dot J asked.
That's the only change you'll need to make to this file.
The other change is going to be on the server since you're emitting this new event from the client.
The server needs to listen for it.
So set up the server to listen for send location when the server receives that it should fire off a
message event to all connected clients a string in the following format location colon space then the
actual longitude comma followed by the actual latitude.
Actually I believe that's reversed.
It should be the latitude followed by the long etude.
Perfect.
So once again you want to replace lat and long with the actual values that the server received.
You're gonna send all of this as a string message like we're already sending our messages from server
to client then you're going to test your work when you click send location.
The result is that you should see a new message in the terminal with those coordinates showing up.
If you had two users user one should be able to share the location and user 2 should see the coordinates.
So take some time to knock that out test your work and when you're done come back and click play
all right.
How'd you do.
Let's go ahead and kick things off by sending the location from the client to the server.
So right here what do we want to do I want to use socket data emit to emit a new event.
I said the name should be send location so I'll provide that as the first argument.
And I said the only piece of data we need to send is an object so I'll provide that as the second argument.
Now on here we want to get access to the latitude and longitude.
So we'll go ahead and set up both of those properties grabbing them off of the position object we had
dumped to the terminal earlier.
So right here.
Let's go ahead and start with the latitude we're going to grab that off of position now.
That is position dot chords as we saw over here in the terminal for the Chrome developer tools.
Then that is chords dot latitude.
Perfect.
Next up is the longitude.
So right here we'll go ahead and list that one out.
And once again position dot coords dot right here longitude excellent.
And there we go.
That's the only thing we need to do from the client.
Everything else is going to go ahead and happen on the server.
So we have latitude and latitude and longitude and longitude.
Now we can go ahead and remove AUST COUNCIL dialoguing that position.
There is no longer any need to actually do that.
If you still have that in place just go ahead and remove it now.
And next up we're going to receive this event on the server and make sure it gets shared correctly.
So over here in index dot J s what I'm going to do is set up a new listener.
So right here we have on send a message.
This is where we send our messages out to all connected clients.
We're going to set up a nother socket dot on call this time listening for send a location.
And when that happens we're going to get access to our object.
The one that we just set up and we could call that whatever we wanted to such as courts.
Perfect.
Next up we want to make sure we share that data with all connected clients and we know that when we
want to do that we use I O dot emit.
And right here we are going to emit the message event and we are going to provide our string and I'll
use an E S6 template string to generate what we want to generate.
Now I outlined that right over here in the challenge comments.
So let's go ahead and knock that one out.
We start off with location colon space followed by the latitude.
So I will interpolate cords dot latitude then after latitude a comma and a space followed by right here
coords dot longitude.
Perfect.
And with this in place we are all done.
If the location gets shared from client to server and then the server shares it with everyone else let's
go ahead and make sure we've saved all of our files and over in the browser.
I'm going to give things a quick refresh.
Now let's go ahead and create a second browser window as well.
Right here I'll navigate over to local host on port three thousand and I'm also gonna open up the Chrome
developer tools for this one.
Now when we share the location again we're not going to have to tell the browser that we want to allow
the site to access it.
As we've already consented to it.
So right here I'm gonna have user to share their location and I can see that we have the coordinate
pair showing up for everyone.
That means the location was fetched it was shared with the server and the server shared it with everyone
else.
Now to wrap up the lesson.
Oh we're going to do is change the message we're sending back.
So over in Visual Studio code we're going to send a link to google maps instead.
This is going to show the exact location for these coordinates.
So let's see what the U are L structure for this looks like.
It is h TTP s followed by a colon forward slash forward slash.
Then it is Google dot com forward slash maps.
Right here we set up the question mark for our query string and we set up Q setting it equal to the
latitude which I'll just set to zero followed by a comma followed by the longitude.
So this is the U R L structure we want to use now when we visit that it's going to bring us over to
Google Maps and right here I can see that it's dropped a pin at that exact location.
Now in this case that is in the middle of the ocean.
But once we actually change it to work with our real coordinates it should be pretty accurate as to
where we are in the world.
So let's go ahead and get that done.
I'm going to close down this tab over inside a visual studio code I can remove these challenge comments
as we're all done with the challenge.
I'll save the file and in index dot J Yes we're going to change the string we're sending back now right
here.
We do still want the latitude followed by the longitude.
So we can keep that in place but I'm gonna do though is remove this space from there.
What we're going to do is change what's up front.
We'll remove location colon space and this is where we'll put the rest of the U.R.L..
So once again H TTP s colon forward slash forward slash Google dot com forward slash maps then question
mark Q equals perfect.
Now when we send the actual geo location information it's in a much more useful form.
So right here I've saved the file restarting the server.
I'm gonna head over to Google Chrome and just give both of those browser windows a quick refresh and
we're going to share the location from one with the other when the location does show up we'll see it's
now a clickable link and once again we'll be integrating all of this into the user interface up above.
And if we actually click it it's going to open up Google Maps and it's going to put a pin at that exact
location right here.
This isn't exactly where I am but it's close enough so now that we have this in place we have the ability
to share a user's location providing useful information to everyone else.
That's where we're going to stop for this one in the next lesson we'll continue on with our chat application.
So stay tuned and I'll see you soon.