In this lesson you'll be integrating styles into the chat application.
Now much like we did for the weather web application I have these styles pre created and in this lesson
we'll be downloading them and integrating them into our existing HDMI l document.
Now for the moment we only have one page for the chat application.
A bit later we'll be adding a second one where a user can provide the name of the chat room they're
trying to join and their own personal user name.
But for now we'll focus on just styling the actual chat page.
The content shown here you can download all of the assets we're going to need for this one over at links
dot Mead dot I O forward slash chat assets when you visit this link it's going to redirect you over
to a different U.R.L. and this is where you'll be able to grab the zip download that is chat assets
dot zip.
So I'm going to take a quick moment to actually download it to my machine then we'll navigate over to
the finder and integrate this into our project.
So navigate to your finder or your file explorer depending on your operating system on one window.
I have the chat app project folder on another I have my downloads directory right here what I'm gonna
do is expand chat assets and in there we have two folders.
We have a CSX directory this contains a style sheet for the chat application as well as a Minnifield
version which is the same thing.
Just not meant to be read or edited by humans.
It's a little smaller and runs a little faster and the other directory we have is an image directory.
In here we have a fave icon that's going to show up in the browser tab right here.
So let's go ahead and take both of these directories and we're going to bring them over to the public
folder of our chat app.
So I have the chat app with the public directory.
I'm just gonna grab these and move them over there.
Now in public we have both of those directories and we're done with the finder.
We can go ahead and close things down and focus on actually integrating these assets into our project.
So I'm going to close this tab and close down the little downloads panel at the bottom.
I'll navigate back over to the chat window and we're going to spend the rest of our time in index dot
H2 UML.
We're gonna work through this file from top to bottom making the changes necessary and the first set
of changes will happen right here inside of the head tag.
First up let's go ahead and use title to set up a title for this document.
And I'm going to use something like a chat app.
This will show up in the browser tab instead of what currently shows up which is local hosted three
thousand and then from here.
We're gonna go ahead and link the five icon as well as our style sheet exactly like we've already done
before.
So I'll use link for both to link in the icon the relationship the real attribute has a value of icon
then the H ref attribute is the path to the icon that is forward slash image forward slash right here.
The only file we have is fave icon dot PMG.
Perfect.
Next up we'll take a quick moment to load in the style sheet.
Also using link this time though the relationship is that of a style sheet.
So right here.
Style sheet and then a draft will be the path to that file.
Now you could go ahead and load in either of the files inside of there if you want to add new features
to the app and customize these styles later you could always switch to this file the unmodified version.
But for now let's go ahead and load in the Minnifield version as it'll load a little faster.
So right here H ref forward slash C Ss but words slash styles dot Min don't see ISIS.
Perfect.
Now with this in place we should see some pretty drastic changes to our application.
So far.
I would expect the title and the icon to show up as well as some styles.
Now the styles aren't gonna look great just yet because we'll have to alter the structure of our document
and add some classes into the mix but we should at least noticed some change over in the browser.
Let's give things a quick refresh and right here what do we see.
1 I see my icon too I see my page title and three things definitely look different now.
Once again things aren't completely styled although there are some styles being applied.
For example if I send my location I can see the disabled style makes the button look different until
the location is actually sent.
But now what we're going to do is integrate the classes that these style sheet uses to make all of this
look like it's actually supposed to look so over inside of index dot HDL.
That means we'll be making changes to what's right here inside of body.
We're gonna add classes and do a little bit of restructuring adding a few elements into the mix strictly
to get the layout we're looking for.
The first thing we're gonna do is add a couple of new divs just to create the layout we want.
We're gonna have a side bar on the left and the main chat content on the right.
So the first thing we're gonna do is create a div element with a given class right here.
Let's go ahead and set that up.
The class for this one which is used in that style sheet is called Chat.
Now inside of here we're going to add two new divs one for the side bar and one for the main chat content.
So right here let's go ahead and create both of those.
The first one is not going to have any content for the moment we'll focus on populating that sidebar
a little bit later in the course.
So right here we set up the class chat underscore underscore sidebar for that.
And once again no content inside.
Down below the last div we're going to put in this chat layout is for the main content.
Class equals chat underscore underscore Main and what's going to go inside of here.
Well everything that we have down below not our templates but our messages div our form and the button
for sending the location.
Now these things will change a little bit too but for the moment let's take these three elements.
The div the form and the button we're going to cut them out of their current location and paste them
right here inside of chat Main.
Then we can go ahead and just in-depth them to the proper level and down below we're going to remove
our little chat app title we'll bring a page title back in a little bit later that'll end up showing
up in the sidebar.
Now the only thing we have is our chat div and its contents.
Then down below that are templates and the scripts where loading in from here.
We're going to focus on adjusting what's inside of chat Main.
Now before we do that we can actually see where we've gotten so far with these styles.
So over here in the browser I can give things a quick refresh and we can see the page is starting to
come together.
We're gonna have this dark side bar on the left with the main content on the right.
Now the next style is we're going to apply will ensure that everything related to composing messages
is sitting down below and the messages take up most of the screen which is currently not what's happening.
So right here we're gonna make a few small adjustments to what we just put inside of chat.
Main first up the message is div.
This has an I.D. allowing us to easily target it from javascript.
We're also setting up a class for this one that is chat underscore underscore messages.
That's going to make sure it takes up the necessary space.
And down below what we have is our form and our button.
And obviously the forms contents all of this is going to go in one more new element we'll be creating
right here another div just to make sure that we can set up the layout as needed.
And this one right here is going to have a class of compose sense everything inside of it is specific
to composing new messages.
We're going to take this we're going to copy it and paste it right inside of that new div adjusting
the levels as needed.
So there we go.
This is the final setup we need for index dot HDL.
As of now we have the main chat area.
We then have our sidebar right here we have the right hand side here we have our messages up top followed
by the composition elements down below.
Now let's make sure that we saved our mark up and from the browser we're going to refresh things one
more time and we should see some major changes so far so good.
We now have our messages down below.
We can send those off and they show up up here as you might expect.
Now there are a couple of more adjustments we're going to make to wrap this video up.
I've also provided you with some styles for the actual messages and to the markup for those lives in
the templates down below.
So let's make a few small adjustments to these as well.
Right here we have the root div all we're going to do for this one is add a class onto that and the
class for the message is called appropriately enough.
Message.
Now in the paragraph right here is going to stay as is but it's no longer going to contain the timestamp
that's going to live just above in a separate paragraph.
So right here it will create that separate paragraph setting up the opening and closing tag and inside
of there we're going to add to span elements which will be styling.
The first one is going to be for the user's name.
Now currently there's no way for a user to set their name.
We'll fix that in a few videos.
And the other is going to be the date which we already have.
So right here I'll go ahead and set up the first one and we can just put a dummy name inside some user
name as an example just to make sure we see some content showing up.
This will be dynamic later and then we'll create a second one down below for created at right here adding
it in exactly like we had it up above.
Excuse me down below.
Now we can go ahead and close the span tag.
Perfect from here.
Oh we need to do is set up classes on both of these right here for the first one.
That is a class equal to message underscore underscore name and down below for the second one.
That is class.
Message underscore underscore Metta.
Now with this in place are text based messages should be completely styled and we can give that a test
before continuing on.
So I'll refresh the page.
We can see our styles showing up.
I'll type something else and try that perfect.
Now here I was able to send a message with no content.
We'll fix that a bit later.
Before the final version of the application now we haven't had any styles before the location messages.
So if I send my location it's gonna look exactly like it looked before.
We're going to adjust to that as well.
Right here we'll take the paragraph from up above for our regular message and paste it in the div down
below for our messages that are location based.
Next up for this div we're going to set up the class message once again and inside of this paragraph.
All we're gonna do is remove created at with the hyphen.
We have the paragraph with the link right inside.
Now let's go ahead and test our location styles out.
I'm going to refresh things in the browser.
I'm going to click send location and my location shows up styled right here I have the link I could
click that and it still cracks open Google Maps in a brand new tab right here with my location pinned
to the map.
Now that we have this in place we have our basic styles in place for the chat page.
Now don't worry we are going to add something over here in the sidebar a bit later in the class we'll
show the chat room name as well as a list of all of the users currently in the room.
Right now we don't have any of that wired up though which is why we have the empty content over here.
We're gonna start to address that in the next lesson by allowing users to join a specific chatroom providing
a user name and a room name.
I'm excited to get that mark up created.
So let's jump right in to the next one.