You know how they join page in place and when you submit that form with a name and a room it brings
you over to the chat page with that data.
Now currently that data is not being used at all in this lesson we're going to fix that.
You'll learn how to get access to this data from our client side JavaScript and we'll also talk about
rooms in socket don't I.
Oh that's going to allow us to omit events to a specific set of connections.
So just people in the South Philly room.
So we'll be able to have separate chat rooms for any topic you'd want to talk about.
No the query string component in the you are around can be accessed via javascript using the following.
I'm just going to crack open the dev tools real quick and we'll explore that from the console before
integrating it into our code.
So right here we have the console for this page.
What we have access to is location which is a global made available to you.
Dot right here.
Search.
This contains the query string for the U.R.L. and right here we're seeing exactly what we have up above.
So what we're gonna do from our client side JavaScript is pass this string to get access to the individual
pieces of data for user name and room.
And we're going to send those off to the server now to get this done and we'll be using that third library.
We included in our HDL file.
So over in chat dot HDL near the bottom we've already used mustache for rendering templates and to moment
for formatting time.
It's now time to use Q S which is short for query string to pass our query strings.
So this library makes it easy to pass this into an object with a user name and room property.
Let's go ahead and get that done inside of chat Dot.
J.
And up top we're gonna go ahead and get that done right here where we're creating our templates.
So just below that I'll create a new section for options and what we're going to do is use the following
It is capital Q S dot pass.
Now this takes the query string and we just saw we have access to that on location dot search.
Now by default it's not going to remove that question mark.
So it's actually going to create an object with two properties.
One would be room.
And the other would be a question mark user name.
So there is a option we can use to make sure the question mark goes away.
Right here we provide that option on the options object which is the second and final argument we'll
be passing to pass that is ignore query prefix by default that is false.
We're just going to set it to true.
So all that's going to do is make sure the question mark goes away now.
But we get back as mentioned is an object that object has all of the keys as properties and the value
for those properties is the value.
So we have the user name property the string.
Andrew is the value and the room property the string South Philly being the value for that.
So we could go ahead and do one of two things I could create a variable to store that object or I could
go ahead and destructor those individual properties off of the object and that's the approach I'm gonna
take.
So right here I am de structuring the object that comes back from Q S dot pass.
I'm gonna grab the user name and the room and we are going to use those sending them off to the server.
Now we can go ahead and send this data off to the server by adding an image to call down below at the
bottom of the file.
The last thing we're going to do is use socket emit to emit a brand new event that the server is going
to listen for and this is done to be called Join or something similar join is going to accept the user
name you want to use and the room you're trying to join then on the back end it will attempt to get
that done.
Now later on we'll add some validation.
So you can't use a name if someone in that chat room is already using that name.
But for now let's just get the basics in place.
So the second argument is going to be an object and we are going to add the user name and the room on
to it.
So we're sending that data off to the server.
We can save this file and it's now these servers job to set up a listener for join and to do what it
needs to do when that event actually occurs.
So in index dot and J.S. we're going to set up a listener for join.
So we have listeners for disconnect send location and send a message just above the 1 4 Send message.
We'll be using socket dot on for a fourth time in this file and we're setting up a listener for join.
Now we're gonna get access to that data right here in the callback function.
And we're going to use it to set up those separate chat rooms right here.
The object we get back is going to be d structured.
So we have access to user name and room as individual variables.
And then from here what we're going to do is use the socket dot Io features given to us to actually
join these individual rooms.
So to do that we use a method we can only use on the server that is socket dot joint socket dot join
allows us to join a given chat room and we pass to the name of the room we're trying to join.
So right here what we're going to do is pass in the room string as the value to join.
Now what this is going to give us access to is a whole nother way to omit events where we're specifically
emitting events to just that room.
So only others in that room would actually see that whether they're messages or anything else we might
be sending from server to client.
Now so far we've sent events from a server to client using three methods.
We had socket dammit that sends an event to a specific client.
We then had I O dot omit which sends an event to every connected client.
And finally we had socket dot broadcast dot emit which sends an event to every connected client except
for this one.
Now with the introduction of rooms we're going to have two new setups we'll be using for emitting messages.
One is a variation of this and the other is a variation of this.
So the first is the following I O dot to dot emit.
Now two is indeed a function and we'll learn how to call it shortly.
But essentially what this does is it emits an event to everybody in a specific room.
So that's going to allow us to send a message to everyone in a room without sending it to people in
other rooms.
The other option we have is a variation on this that is socket dot broadcast dot to dot emit.
So similar to above.
This is sending an event to everyone except for the specific client but it's limiting it to a specific
chat room.
So these two approaches are how we're going to communicate with members of a specific room and we're
going to start to incorporate those right now.
So the first thing we're gonna do is take these two statements up above we send our welcome message
and an alert that someone new has joined.
These are not things we're going to send on connection any more.
Now we're only going to send them when join fires because that's where we get access to the user name
and the room name.
So right here let's cut those two statements out of their current location remove those extra empty
lines and we'll be pasting them down below in the callback function.
Now this line right here is still perfectly fine.
It's emitting the event to a specific socket and that's great.
Down below what we have is our new user message.
This is currently emitting the event to everyone but that specific client regardless of what room they're
in.
And that's a problem.
We want to go ahead and limit it to just the room that was just joined.
So right here we'll be using socket dot broadcast dot too.
So right after the T in broadcast that is dot two.
That's a function so we set up our parentheses and we pass to it this string name of the room that we're
trying to emit that event to in this case it is stored in that variable.
So we join the room right here then we emit the message to that same room.
Now the message is a new user has joined.
We could include the user name as well in that message since we now have access to it.
Let's go ahead and remove the entire string and replace it with a template string.
And right here what we're going to do is use the following.
I'll start off with their user name followed by a space followed by the rest of the message.
So something like Andrew has joined.
And that's going to show up whenever a new user joins the specific room.
Now that we have all of this in place.
What I want to do is actually test out this behavior in the browser so you can see how it's going to
play a pretty important role when it comes to us creating separate chat rooms for the individual users.
Right here.
Let's go ahead and narrow that browser window so we can open up our application twice side by side and
over here we're just going to crack open local host three thousand a another time.
This time we're gonna have a another user like Jess join that exact same room.
So right here I'm gonna have her join South Philly typed out exactly like I had done for Andrew earlier
and when she joins Andrew gets that message saying Jess has joined because she's joined the room that
he is currently in.
Now if she were to leave the room or send a message currently that functionality isn't using the two
method so it would still get sent to everyone but at least this portion is working.
So let's go ahead and prove that Andrew would not see the join message if Jess joined a different room.
So right here what I'm going to do is open a new browser tab and close the old one right here I'm going
to open up local host three thousand again.
The name is still going to be Jess.
The room will change though.
I'll use a different neighborhood in Philadelphia like center city.
And this time when Jess joins that chat room we don't see any message over here saying Jess has joined
and that is correct.
Now unfortunately that's the only place we're using the two method.
So if I send messages from one of those rooms both rooms still get it.
So for example if I send test from Center City the South Philly room is still getting that text message.
This is something that we're definitely going to want to clean up but at least two is working in the
one place we've wired up that welcome message.
Now if we head back to visual studio code you'll notice that down below this is where we have our other
amid calls that need to change.
Here we're sending a message to every connected client instead of just those connected clients in the
room.
We do the same thing down below for location messages and for disconnection messages.
So these are all things that need to change.
The problem is that we don't have access to the necessary data inside of these functions.
For example we need room.
Room is scoped to this function.
It's not accessible outside of it.
So what we're gonna need to do in the long run is keep track of which users are in which rooms when
we're tracking that data.
It's going to allow us to use it anywhere in our application such as with new messages are sent.
Now that'll be the topic of the next video for now just to show you what we're working towards.
We're going to take these send message callback listener and tweak it down below.
We have I.
Oh dammit what we're gonna do is use I O dot to calling that then dot emit.
Now once again we don't have access to the room variable right here.
We'll fix that for now though let's just provide a string and type out one of the two rooms we're using.
So right here I'm gonna type out center city.
You should be typing out one of those two rooms that you're using over inside of the browser.
Now the end result of this is that all text messages are going to go to that one room.
That's not what we want long term but it will at least allow us to see this behavior in action.
So I'm gonna save index dot J S we'll head over to the browser and we'll give things a refresh.
I'm gonna refresh both of my clients so both reconnect.
And now I'm going to send a text message from South Philly.
I'll use from Andrew.
This should only show up over here.
Since this is the center city room and it does.
And if I send a message from the center city room it should only show up here as well.
So right now our server is emitting all of those messages to a single static room.
That is not what we want long term but using two is going to allow us to achieve that behavior assuming
we track the users who are joining.
Since we have the data right here it is something we're able to track and that's what we're going to
focus on in the next lesson.
So what did we do in this one in this lesson we learned about the two method allowing us to target a
specific room.
Now how does someone join a room.
Well we use socket dot join.
So the client gets the user name and her room name it passes it off to the server and the server sets
all of that room behavior up.
We're going to continue on in the next lesson so stay tuned and I'll see you then.