In this lesson as promised it's going to be up to you to add it to new functions to users downtown J
S one get user and a another get users in room.
So right here what I'm going to do is remove everything below our 1 call to add a user we'll leave that
in place and then I'm going to paste in the challenge comments.
So right here the goal is to create those two new functions.
The first one get user this accepts the I.D. of the user and it returns the user object.
If there's a match otherwise you can just return undefined.
Now in this case you can use the array find method to get that done down below.
The other function you're going to create is get users in room.
This is going to accept the room name and it's going to return an array of users that are in that room
or an empty array.
If no users are in that room and for this you could use the array filter method.
Last up you're going to test your work.
So let's go ahead and together add a another call to add user down below for this one.
I'll change the I.D. to something like forty two and I will go ahead and add Mike to the south Philly
chatroom.
Then I'm going to add just one more user below that I'll change this idea to something like 32.
And this person's name will be Andrew.
But we'll put them in a different room like center city.
So now we have some interesting data we can test with.
I should be able to fetch any of these users by their I.D. And if I look for all of the users in Center
City it should just be one.
If I look for all of the users in South Philly I should get to back.
So take some time to create those functions and then call them to test your work when you're done come
back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and kick things off.
Up above.
By creating our first of those two functions we'll test that out and then we'll move on to the other
one.
So right here this one is gonna be get user which I mentioned should accept the idea of the user.
And it should return the match if any.
Now I mentioned you could use find to get this done.
Sure there are other ways as well.
For us though.
Well we're going to do is return a call to users dot find.
Now remember find returns the match.
If there is one.
Otherwise it'll return undefined if there is no match.
So this actually works out really well.
We can directly return the result of the find method.
Now we want to supply our function.
So right here we'll go ahead and get that done.
We get access to the user and we're looking for a user whose I.D. matches and I'll use the shorthand
syntax.
So right here that is user dot I.D. equaling the I.D. We are looking for.
Now let's test this out before moving on to the second and slightly more complex one right here.
We're gonna go ahead and get that done down below where our users are created.
So I'll create a concept called a user and then I'll use get user with one of these three ideas I'll
use forty two.
So right here that is forty two and then we'll log the user out to make sure we actually get them back
and let's go ahead and run the program to test this one out right here.
I have that object returning which is excellent.
Now if I change the I.D. to something like a four twenty one and save the program and rerun it we can
see we do get undefined which is also what we want.
Next up we're going to create the get users in Room function so up above.
Let's go ahead and get that done right here constant get users in room.
Remember this is what's going to allow us to show that users list in the sidebar in the browser.
We are going to accept the name of the room that you're trying to look for and down below.
We'll use the array filter method to get that done.
So I'm going to return the result from calling users dot filter.
We are going to get access to the individual user in the callback function.
Now remember with filter we want to return true if the item should be considered something that gets
returned and false if it should be filtered out and should not be returned.
In this case we want to keep all of the users where the users room equals the room we're looking for.
We want to return true.
Keeping that as a match and sending it back in the array.
Now with this in place let's go ahead and test our work here as well.
Down below.
We're going to go ahead and look for both rooms but we'll start with South Philly.
So right here a new constant I can just create a list called User List setting and equal to I'll use
get users in a room and we're going to provide one of our room names.
Now right here we didn't do any sort of sanitization for this data because this data isn't going to
be coming from the user.
It's going to be all on the server.
Now you could have added that code in there if you wanted to if you wanted to do that.
It would look a little like this.
That is room equals the existing room we're using trim and then we're using something like two lower
case.
This is not something you needed to do but you could add it if you wanted to.
Now down below we're going to search for those rooms.
I'll start with South Philly and then I'll go ahead and print that user list out to see what exactly
we get back since there are two members in that room I would expect to see two showing up.
I'll rerun the script right here we get our array with both Andrew and Mike which is great.
Next up we'll look in Center City.
So right here we have Center City.
I'll save the program rerun things and we get just that one member.
And if I were to type something else entirely let's go ahead and use a different neighborhood like Fairmount
and rerun the program this time I would expect to see an empty list as there are no users in that room.
And it's exactly what I'm getting.
So now that we have this in place we have a really great system of for managing our users.
We have four functions allowing us to keep track of them over time.
Now we're just going to clean this file up a little bit.
I'm going to remove my one comment up above.
We then have our array our four methods and down below that we have the usage we just set up we're going
to go ahead and remove all of that as well.
As long as your code was working this is no longer necessary.
So right after we create the final function we're going to export all of these from the file.
So module dot exports equals an object.
We have add user then we have remove user.
We have get user.
And finally we have get users in room.
So here we're exporting all four.
And then the next lesson we're going to take advantage of these in index dot J.
S to wire up this room feature.
Now I know the last two videos were in real time application or socket dot I O specific but they're
just as necessary for building out a useful application now that we have this in place.
Let's jump into the next one.