In this lesson you'll be taking the functions you created in the last video and actually integrating
them into index.
J.S. remember the whole point of tracking the users was to make sure we had access to things like the
user name and room name throughout our other event listeners as well.
So we're going to alter these making sure that they do only emit messages to the correct chat room.
We're also going to include Users User names along with their messages so we can render those to the
screen as well.
Now to get started the first thing we need to do is load those functions in.
So up top I'm going to do just that and I'll go ahead and grab all four using a little bit of D structuring.
We have an object coming back when we require that file that's dot forward slash utilize a forward slash
users.
And right here we're gonna get all of them.
So we have add user we have remove user.
We have a get user.
And finally we have get users in room.
So we want to make sure we have access to all four of these functions now that we do.
We're going to go ahead and edit on join right here.
The user is indeed joining the room using socket not join.
This is where we want to use add user to start keeping track of them.
Now I mentioned that every single connection has a unique I.D. associated with it.
So we're going to learn where that lives as well right here.
The first thing we're going to do is to try to use that function.
I'm going to try to use ad user to add the user to that users array providing their socket I.D. the
user name and the room name.
Now I'm going to call this providing the options object setting up I.D. user name in Rome.
Now the only one we don't know how to set is high deep.
The value for this comes actually on the socket object itself.
It is a socket dot I.D. That is the unique identifier for that particular connection.
Now notice this is in the parent scope for all of our event listeners which means that inside of send
a message I'm gonna be able to use get user to get the user by its socket I.D..
They don't have access to their room name and their user name which I can use throughout.
And that's exactly what we'll end up doing up above.
So we have to finish off this function call.
So we have the I.D. set then it is the user name and the room.
Now we know we get back an object with either the error property if something went wrong or the user
property if things went well.
Right here what I'm gonna do is dish structure that object storing both in individual variables.
So I potentially have an error or I have user only 1.
No down below we can use a little conditional logic if the person was not able to successfully join
then we're going to want to notify them of that saying something like that user names already taken
or that they need to provide a user name and a room name right here.
Let's go ahead and actually get that done a little conditional logic will allow us to get this done.
We're going to see if there is an error and if there is we're going to send that back to the client
using an acknowledgement now.
Currently there is no acknowledgment setup for the join event.
So right here when we admit it we're not providing a function that's going to run when it's been acknowledged.
This is something we're doing for other events we admit like send location we provide our acknowledgement
function right here.
So all we need to do is provide a function as the final argument to omit this function is going to get
called with an error if there is any.
Otherwise it'll get called with no error.
And that's just going to let the client know what exactly is going on.
If something does go wrong the client will be able to use that information to show the message to the
user.
So over inside of index dot J S we now get access to that as the final argument to our event listener
function.
So right here I'm going to call this callback.
This is the exact same pattern we used for send a message right here and force send location down below
that and we call the callback whenever we want to.
It's up to us to determine how we're going to use it.
Right here I'm going to call the callback with the error if there is one letting the client know what
exactly went wrong.
And I'm going to use return it to stop the function execution.
So none of the code down below runs I could alternatively not use return and use it.
Else block instead either way gets the job done.
So at this point the code down below is only running if the user was indeed added and we're going to
end up doing some stuff pretty similar to what we're already doing right here we are still going to
have them join the room and using socket dot join we're still going to emit that welcome message.
And down below we are already correctly broadcasting that welcome message which is great.
The only new thing we're going to do is we're going to call that callback function after all of this
is complete.
So down below right here I'm just going to call the callback letting the client know that they were
able to join here I'm calling it without any arguments which means without an error down below I'll
remove the comments from the previous video and there we go.
We now have a joint event listener that is actually tracking the user.
Actually there is one more change we need to make right here we have user name and the room name.
Remember that these are going to be trimmed and converted by ad user.
That means what we really want to do is use the output from AD user.
The stuff that lives on the user object itself as that is the correct version.
So down below instead of room that would be something like user dot room and the same would be true
down here for our other instance of room and for our instance of user name.
So that would be user dot user name.
Now we're just making sure that we use the version that add user is actually storing in our little array
of users.
Now with this in place you could do a bit of restructuring of the arguments.
It's really up to you to determine how you want to set things up.
So obviously this approach works fine as an alternative approach maybe you don't de structure this first
object and you just call it something like options then you could use the rest operator which we explored
earlier in the class to put all of those on this object alongside of I.D. so no longer do we have user
name and room as variables.
Instead I would use the spread operator spreading out the options object like this.
That would be a fine approach as well.
Now before we can actually test out this functionality we should probably also clean up the user when
they disconnect otherwise those user names are never going to be cleared out of the users array and
will become unavailable for ever so.
Down below inside of socket dot on disconnect.
We're going to do something similar to what we did above though instead of using add user we'll be using
remove user.
Now we're still removing them by their I.D. That is socket dot I.D. exactly like we had used before
and we know that remove user which we created will return one of two things.
We either get back the user that was removed as an object or undefined if no user was removed.
So right here I am removing the user and storing it in a user variable.
Now down below we actually want to use a little conditional logic before sending this message.
There's a chance that the person who's disconnecting was never actually part of a room.
For example if they fire join from the client with invalid data and then saw the error and closed the
browser.
There and actually no one who needs to see this message as they never joined the room and no one needs
to be notified.
Right here though if we do have a user they were part of a room.
So if there is a user then and only then are we going to send a message saying that the user has left.
So I'll cut that out of its current location put it inside of our if code block and remove those extra
empty lines.
Now from here we could also choose to include the user's name since we have access to that data.
I have user dot user name and I have user dot room so right here we're gonna go ahead and use the two
method to make sure we're only sending this message to folks in the same room.
That is I O dot to providing the name of the room user dot room.
Then we emit the message and here we're just going to use a template string instead of our current static
string.
So I'll start off with the user name user dot user name followed by a space and then I could just say
something like has left.
So Andrew has left or Mike has left now with this in place we are adding users and removing users when
we're supposed to.
And we can now go ahead and test things out make sure to save all of your files including chat dot J.S.
even though we're not doing anything in this callback just yet.
And down below we're going to start up our chat app once again using NPM run Dev.
I'm gonna start up that dev server and in the Chrome browser I'll refresh both of those tabs.
Now if you remember we have two users in different chat rooms.
So over here if I look at the U.R.L. Andrew is in South Philly then over here I have Jess in Center
City now in the past when a user left from any room.
Every other user was notified whether or not they were in the same room with the code.
We just put in place that should have been fixed since we changed the image event inside of on disconnect.
To use that to method sending it to a specific room.
So over here what I'm going to do is open up a new tab and then close the old one and we can see that
we're not notified over here which is correct.
Then I'll head open to local host three thousand.
Again I should have said head over but head open is a nice shorthand for what I was doing.
And right here we're gonna have just joined the same room.
Andrew is in.
So that would be South Philly.
Now when she joins I would expect to see the welcome message and once again sending those text messages.
That's still going to everyone will focus on adjusting that shortly.
But this time when Jess leaves I would expect to see the message since Jess is in the same room so I'm
going to crack open that new tab and close the old one and I can see Jess has the left is printing.
So now that we're tracking users were able to use that data to do what we want to do which is share
the events with just people who should be notified.
Just people in that same room now with this in place.
What I want to do to wrap up the video is to actually handle errors that occur on the client.
So right here if there is an error message that means someone wasn't able to join.
Maybe the user name is already taken or there's no required data provided such as the user name or room
name.
In that case we'll show them a message and we'll redirect them back to the original page where they
typed that information in so they could try again.
If there is an error then and only then do we want to actually do something and we'll start by using
alert to alert the error message.
Now if you're using a different UI framework you could also choose to show this error inside of a modal
window instead and then down below.
We're just going to redirect them to the home page.
Now for this we use the location global.
Remember we read off of location dot search to get our query string that we passed if we want to redirect
them.
We set location dot H RAF equal to in this case forward slash to send them to the route of the site.
That is the join page.
Now let's try to generate an error.
I'm gonna have two users with the same name join the same Roma.
So over here in Google Chrome for this first tab I'll be heading over to local host three thousand.
As Andrew I'm going to join a J.S. Rome.
Now this person can join correctly which is good.
Then I'm gonna open up local host three thousand in another tab and I'll have Andrew join the J.S. room
and this time it should fail.
Right here we can see our message.
User name is in use.
We click the OK button to accept and then it redirects us back to this page to try again.
I could go ahead and use something like a different name.
Let's say I use a nickname followed by J.S..
And this time I should join.
And now I see that joined message and they could communicate.
So with this in place we have the very basics of user tracking all set up.
We're able to track when a user joins inside of socket dot on join.
And when they leave inside of socket dot on disconnect.
Now we still want to use this information for our other events as well and we'll focus on doing that
in the following videos.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.