In this lesson you'll be deploying the chat application alive to a production server.
Now this is gonna allow anyone with an internet connection to open up the app in the browser and start
chatting with others.
Now we've already gone through this deployment process twice in the course once for the weather web
application and a second time for the task manager API.
Doing it this third time is going to be a challenge for you to make sure you actually know how to deploy
your node j s apps.
So let's go ahead and get to it by heading over to chat dot in J.
S right here up top.
What I'm going to do is paste in the challenge comments outlining what I'd like you to do.
So once again the big picture goal is to deploy the chat application.
Step 1 is going to be a setup.
Get in the chat app project and also commit your files.
Now we want to commit every single file in the chat app project except for the contents of the node
modules folder.
So you're going to want to set up the ignore file like we've done before.
Next up.
Once you have that commit in place you're going to create a repository and then push your code up to
that repository and you'll also create a Heroku application and push the code up to that as well.
Now our code is already looking for process dot EMV dot port over here in index dot J S so there's actually
no need to change any of our code to get this done.
Now once you have the code deployed to Heroku the last thing you want to do is open up the live app
and test your work.
Try to join a chat room with a few different browser windows or share the you are with a friend and
have them try to join and make sure you can actually chat on the production version of the app.
All right take some time to knock that out and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Let's go ahead and get to it.
By first shutting down the dev server from the terminal we're going to run and get in it to initialize
the chat app folder as a get repository.
Now from there we do want to set up our get ignore file to ignore the node modules folder.
So in the chat after rectory you needed to create a new file Dot.
Get ignore right here.
The only thing we're going to Noor is the node modules folder.
Perfect.
Everything else is going to be committed including everything in the public and source directories.
Now that we have the get ignore file created we can go ahead and use get add dot to add all files to
the staging area and we can run get status just to make sure things look correct here if I scroll up
through the list of things I'm about to add.
I have my 3 files in the root of the project.
Then I have a few different ones in public followed by a few others in the source directory.
That all looks great so I can go ahead and move on to the final part of Step 1 which is to actually
commit those files get commit with the M flag for my message and in it commit will be a good start here.
Now that we have the comet in place we want to create a github repository and push our code up that's
going to allow us to backup our code collaborate with others track issues and more so to do that we're
gonna head over to the browser and go over to get hub dot com from here.
What we want to do is create a new GitHub repository so in the top right that is new repository here
we can create this as a public or private repo and we just need to provide a name.
I could use something like node v 3 chat app as an example.
Then I'll go ahead and actually create it.
And like we've done before of the options we have available it is this second option that we want to
take.
We have an existing repository and we want to push our code up so I'll run this line to set up the remote
correctly.
Then I'll run this line to actually push that code up for the very first time.
Once that's done we should be able to refresh the website and see our code showing up right here.
I give things a refresh and what do we have.
We have our project available which is great.
Now the next thing we needed to do was also get our project up on her Roku so people can actually use
the application to do that if you remember what you need to do is run Heroku create from the terminal.
Now remember you can also choose to provide a name.
Otherwise a name will be randomly generated for you.
I'm going to use Mead node the 3 chat app for mine.
Now I can go ahead and actually create that Heroku application and from there what I'm gonna do is push
it up to the new remote.
That's been added that is get push Heroku master.
Now this is going to take all of our code.
It's gonna get it up on the Heroku servers and Heroku is going to attempt to install those NPM modules
and actually start up the application now in package dock.
Jason.
We already have our start script so all of that should go pretty well and in a few moments I should
be given the U.R.L. I can visit in the browser right here.
I can see that it is launching our app and I have my U.R.L. right here.
I can alter click that or I can copy it to the clipboard and head over to the browser and all we're
going to do is move on to Step 4.
I want to visit it and make sure I can actually chat.
So right here I visit the U.R.L. and what do I get.
I get my join page which is great.
I'm gonna go ahead and open up the production U.R.L. in a another window as well.
Right here we have open in both and then I'm going to go ahead and try to join.
So I will join over here as Jake to the room.
Let's go ahead and join a room like Philly then in this window.
I'm going to have someone else let's go ahead and have just joined that same room and right here I can
see that both do have the names showing up and I should be able to share data so I could say hey and
that shows up for both Windows and I should also be able to share my location.
Now yes I do have to allow that but once I confirm after a few seconds I should see the location being
shared and it is over here Jake.
Got the location that just shared I can click on the link and it brings me over to Google Maps once
again with my location.
So now that we have this in place we have our chat application deployed to Heroku.
Anyone with the U.R.L. l can go ahead and visit the chat application to actually use it.
Now over inside of chat dot J s what I'm going to do is remove those challenge comments.
Save the file and that's where we're gonna stop for this one.
That is it for the end of this video.
And that's also it for the end of this section in this section.
You learned how to create a brand new type of application a real time application with web sockets and
socket.
Dot I O.
This allowed us to setup an application with real time bi directional communication where the client
can send information to the server and the server can send information to the client over this persistent
connection.
All right.
That's it for this one.
I'll see you in the next lesson.