Let's talk about AWS EKS.
AWS EKS, the Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service,
is a fully managed Kubernetes service on Amazon.
Unlike Kops, EKS will fully manage your master nodes,
which includes that Kubernetes apiserver and etcd.
So, it also manages the state of your cluster,
by managing etcd for you.
You pay a fee for every cluster that you spin up,
to pay for the master nodes and then you pay
per EC2 worker that you attach to you cluster.
It is a great alternative for kops
if you want to have a fully managed cluster
and not deal with the master nodes yourself.
Depending on your cluster setup,
EKS might be more expensive than running a kops cluster,
so you might still opt to use Kops for cost reasons.
EKS is a popular AWS service
and supports lots of handy features.
AWS created its own VPC CNI,
Container networking interface, for EKS, which means
that you get VPC-writable addresses within your cluster.
AWS can even manage you workers to ensure
updates are applied to your workers.
So, if you don't want to manage the AMIs, yourself,
of your workers, then you can use managed node groups in AWS
and that AWS will role out the updates
on your workers for you.
Cluster authentication is using IAM, so you don't need
to setup your own users within the cluster,
this can be done using IAM users and roles.
So, there's an major benefit that you don't have to work
with the certificates and the API server, yourself.
It is completely integrated with IAM.
So, you can create IAM users or roles
and the use those to log into your cluster.
Kubernetes Service Accounts can be tied to IAM roles,
to use IAM roles on an pod-level.
So, you can have permissions on a pod-level
by using IAM roles on the Service Accounts,
and it also integrates with many other AWS services,
like CloudWatch for logging and other ones.
There is a command line tool, eksctl, available
to manage eks clusters, which I'll use in the demos.
You can find the documentation at eksctl.io,
where you will also find the download instructions.
You can use command line arguments
to quickly setup a cluster and you can also
pass a yaml based configuration file,
if you want to set your own configuration, like VPC subnets,
otherwise it'll create the VPC and subnets for you.
So, easiest way to get started, is,
that it creates the VPC subnets for you, but then, later on,
when you want to use your eks cluster
within an existing setup,
then you probably have to use this yaml configuration
to specify the VPC subnets to have this cluster
running in your existing infrastructure.
So, in the next demo, I'm going to use this tool
to set up a Kubernetes cluster, using EKS.