The next coming lectures are part of the advance topics.
So, now you have covered all of the Kubernetes basics and now we can start with advanced topics.
The first topic is a Service Discovery using DNS as of Kubernetes 1.3.
DNS is a built-in service launched adamantly using the addon manager
before 1.3 you had to enter some commands.
Now it is already launched automatically.
The addons the Kubernetes are in the "/etc/kubernetes/addons" directory on the master node.
You might want to take a look there if you're interested in other addons.
The DNS service can be used within pods to find other services running on the same cluster
Multiple containers within one pod
don't need this service, as they can contact each other directly. A container in the same pod can
connect to the port of the other container directly using "localhost: port".
So if you have a web service and a database service then the web service can just connect localhost, and
then the port of a database, and it will be able to access the database within the same pod.
If you want to connect from a web service in one pod to a database in another pod, then you need Service Discovery
because you cannot just access this other pod,
you don't know the IP address or port. To make the network
a port will always need a service definition, so only when you create a service for a pod, then the pod
really becomes accessible, and Service Discovery will work.
So, this is an example of how one app could reach another app using DNS. on the left you have "Application 1",
we have a container in a pod, and a service for that pod. A service is at "1" and has IP address
10.0.0.1
Then on the right we have "Application 2",
we you also have a container in a pod, and this has another IP address,
The IP address is 10.0.0.2 for "Service: app2".
If you would execute commands on the container of pod one for instance host of one service, the name
of the service, then you would get the IP address back
10.0.0.1
This is the Service Discovery in action.
You only need the name of the service to find the IP address of that service.
If "app1" wants to contact "app2"
It can do a DNS look up on "app2-service" and it will get an IP address
10.0.0.2
This is only going to work if both applications are in the same namespace.
The standard namespace that we have been launching in is the default namespace, because we haven't really
specified a namespace.
What does it mean.
Default stands for default namespace. Pods and services can be launched in different namespaces to logically
separate your cluster.
You can have different namespaces to just logically separate your cluster.
Default is a "default1".
There's also a kube system where the Kubernetes services run in.
If you'd want specify a namespace then you just do a DNS lookup of "app2-service.default", where default
is a namespace.
If you want to do a lookup on the full hostname, the full hostname is actually the [name of the service].[namespace].[svc].[cluster].[local]
and this whole hostname is also 10.0.0.2.
This how one application in one pod can access another application in another pod. These requests
here are always on the "A" type, which is resolving from a host to an IP address.
There's also an "SRV" type if you want to know the port number.
So, here we just have the IP address, but it's also possible to get the port number.
So, how does it really work?
How does this DNS really work?
So, let's say that we have a pod, so we have a pod on the left with a container, we can start this container
using "kubectl run" on "busybox", I am going to run the image busybox, which is just going to give us a shell.
And if you use "cat" to show the contents of a file.
Here we are going to show the contents of "busybox".
Then you can see that the name server points to 10.0.0.10, which is the DNS server. And the DNS server is
"Kube-dns" running in another pod, exposed as a service, with the IP address 10.0.0.10.
And the reason why I didn't see it, when you did "kubectl get pods" is because it runs in another namespace.
If you would do "--namespace" equals "kube-system", with "kubectl get pods", you would see that
there are pods running anytime when the Kubernetes is running.
The reason why we can use the service name, or servicename.default, or servicename.svc.cluster.local
you can see here in the line with the search in Linux
when you look up a DNS name this can be automatically added.
So, if you just do a lookup of the service name then actually it will do a
DNS request of servicename.default.svc.cluster.local
So, this is how it works under the hood, DNS resolving can help you to do service discovery.
In the next demo, I'm going to run a deployment, which is a lab app, and I'm going to run a separate service, and then you
will see that just using DNS names, our lab app will be able to find the database which is the other
service.
So, we can continue with next lecture which is the demo.