You just finished the advanced topics section and this is going to be the next section the Administration Section
where I will explain the Kubernetes administration topics.
The first topic is going to be the master services, I've been talking a lot about the node itself.
Now, let's have a look at what is running on the master nodes.
This is architectural overview of the Kubernetes master services. On the right
you have not one and all the nodes that you can have in a cluster.
I already discussed those in previous lectures.
Let's focus now on the master components. To communicate with you cluster,
you have been using "kubectl". Here on top, "kubectl" is going to communicate to the "REST" interface.
First, before it can pauses the "REST" interface it needs to do "Authorization".
"kubectl" needs first archive and can then only execute commands to the REST interface.
Every time you sense new resources new objects to this "REST" interface using "kubectl" these objects are going to be saved.
And Kubernetes uses "etcd" as a back end.
That's what you see here at the bottom right.
When you sense a new object let's see a new pod definition.
Then the pod definition will be stored in "etcd".
"Etcd" is a separate technology and it's just a cluster, a distributed data store, that exist often
in three or five nodes.
You can also have one then,
but then it's not running in high availability, so typically we would have three or five. Three for smaller clusters, five for bigger clusters.
Because, all your your data in kubernetes, the definitions are going to be stored
in distributed data storage. So, the "REST" interface is communicating with "etcd".
This REST api, is called the kube-api server.
Then you also have a scheduler that communicates with this "REST" interface.
This scheduler is scheduling pods that are not scheduled yet,
and this will become pluggable, so that you can use whatever scheduler that you want.
You can use a default Kubernetes scheduler or you will be able to plug in some other schedulers.
You also have the "Controller Manager" and the "Controller Manager" exists of multiple controllers.
You can have a node controller, which is responsible to discover new nodes, and then manage those nodes,
or you have the "Replication Controller", which is managing the replicas of pods
if you have those defined. This "REST" interface then communicate with "kubelets". "Kubelets" are found on the nodes,
the "REST" interface communicates with those on every separate node. From a 10,000 foot overview
This is the architecture of view. In the next coming lectures we will go into more details about how
Kubernetes works and how the administration of it works.