So you can go to github.com/kubernetes/kops
here there is downloaded the latest release
and you can download the kops-linux-amd64.
Copy link address
and then I can download this
kops-linux-amd64 to this machine.
This is downloaded, I can do change mod kops-linux-amd64,
plus executable flag, so that I can execute it,
and I can move this to /usr/local/bin,
I have to use a sudo.
And then I'm going to download python-pip
because python-pip will allow me to install AWS,
the AWS command line utility, which I will also need
before I can set up this cluster on AWS.
So, this is installed, so I should be able to do pip install
aws command line utility.
And this is gonna give me the command line utility
called aws, that I'll then be able to use.
So then I'll type aws, I can now execute commands with aws.
If you don't have an AWS account yet, you have to open one.
AWS.Amazon.com, create an AWS account and,
when you create a new account,
you will automatically get the free tier.
Once you create a new AWS account, you will see this screen,
the AWS Management Console.
You can go to Services,
and then go to IAM,
to manage access to AWS resources.
On the left you can click Users, and then Add user,
to add a new user that will be used by us to configure,
so that kops can access our AWS account.
User name can be kops, it can be really anything
that you want, and we're going to select
Programmatic access, so we get an access key ID
and secret key, that we then can configure
using the AWS command line utility.
Now we can add this user to a group.
So, for example, you can create a new group administrator,
or attach existing permissions.
Probably the easiest is to add existing permissions,
this Administrator Access, that you can then give this user.
You can also choose to create an admin group
and then give that group Administrator Access
and assign that group to this user.
And that you can do in the first step Add user to group,
here we are just attaching the policy directly.
We're not going to add tags, at this point,
and then we can review our user.
So user name's gonna be kops, for Programmatic access,
and it's going to have administrative access.
We can create this user.
This user was successfully created,
so now we have the AWS access key ID.
And then, when you click here on Show,
then it will show the Secret access key,
which we need to configure the AWS command line utility.
Those need to copy/paste.
We go into the shell, of our VM, where we installed AWS
the command line utility,
and we're going to type aws configure.
It asks for the AWS Access Key
and for the AWS secret access key,
both are printed when you were creating this user.
You can specify a default region, or an output format,
but that's not necessary.
So that's it, now, what the AWS utility did actually
created these files in .aws.
And our credentials are now configured so,
we can now use AWS.
Next, I'm gonna go back to the Welcome screen
and I'm gonna go to S3.
S3 is an object storage, you can compare it with Google
Drive, or a DropBox.
And we're going to create a new Bucket.
And this Bucket is going to be used for our kops-state.
And I'm just going to add some random string at the end,
which you also should do and you also should make it random,
because this Bucket Name needs to be unique in Amazon,
in that region.
This region, that you specify here,
is going to be the region
where you want to deploy your cluster.
So, if you want to deploy your cluster in Ireland,
you should choose the Ireland region.
So, depending on where you are,
you can choose a different Bucket.
If you don't know what region to choose,
there's a tool cloudping.info you do with HTTP Ping.
And, for me Europe and Frankfurt are the closest ones.
I'm gonna go with Ireland,
you're going to do this from a different location so,
you're going to see different results.
I'm going to choose Ireland, I'm going to click Create,
and now I have my kops Bucket.
Next is the DNS, so kops is also going to set up DNS
for us but, we need to set up a domain for that,
a sub domain.
You can use Route 53 for that.
Route 53 allows you to do DNS management.
Kops expect you to enter a sub domain and kops will manage
that sub domain for you but, you already need to create
this zone in Route 53, so that kops can manage this for you.
You can either register a new domain name, here on Amazon,
or even somewhere cheap, where you can get one
for a couple of bucks.
There are also free solutions, so you don't spend money
for a domain name, there's a .tk and there's also a provider
that give you sub domains,
that you then can use in Route 53.
So, you don't need to spend money if you don't want,
if you don't have a domain name
it's probably the easiest way
to just go for something free.
Have a look at the procedure document,
I have listed some free solutions there.
And I have my own domain name so, I am going to get start
here with DNS Management and we'll create a Hosted Zone.
So, even if you have your own domain name, or if you opt
for one of the free solutions, you still need to create
this Hosted Zone.
And this is actually gonna cost you some money,
right now this cost you half a dollar per month,
to create a Hosted Zone.
So, if you don't want to spend any money at all,
you might just wanna run MiniKube,
maybe kops is not the solution for you.
So, I'm going to click Create Hosted Zone
and I'm going to use kubernetes.newtech.academy.
I have a domain in newtech.academy so, what I will do is,
I will make sure that kubernetes.newtech.academy
is going to forward to Route 53.
And, to make it forward, I need to specify these values
here, and those are going to be different for you,
as nameservers for this sub domain.
My domain is host.namecheap so, I have to go to namecheap,
tell namecheap kubernetes.newtech.academy
is hosted by Route 53, these are the nameservers.
You will easily find it if you're buying a domain name,
it's quite straightforward to make those changes.
Just to show you how it works with namecheap,
you have something called Advanced DNS,
and here I added four new records for kubernetes,
for this domain name, so that I have sub domain
kubernetes.newtech.academy and they point
to the Route 53 nameservers.
So, I did Add New record, NS Records, kubernetes as a host,
and then whatever nameserver that you will see.
So, if you do this yourself,
don't take these nameservers but, take the ones that you see
when you add a hosted record in Amazon.
If you use something else than namecheap,
for instance a free .tk domain name,
then this will look a little bit different but,
it's the same principle.
You will have to add an NS record for a domain,
or a subdomain, to be able to make this work.
Once we set up the DNS, kops is going to manage the DNS
for us, using Route 53.
So now, we have done all the preparation and we can finally
start launching our cluster, using kops,
and that I will show you in the next demo.