The Readiness Probe.
Besides livenessProbes you can also use
the readinessProbes on a container within a Pod.
livenessProbes indicate whether a container is running.
If the check fails, the container will be restarted.
readinessProbes, on the other hand,
indicate whether the container is ready
to serve requests.
If the check fails, the container
will not be restarted, but the Pod's IP address
will be removed from the service,
so it will not serve any requests anymore.
The readiness test will make sure
that at startup the pod will only receive
traffic when the test succeeds.
You can use these probes in conjunction,
and you can configure different tests for them.
If your container always exits when something
goes wrong you don't really need the livenessProbe.
But in general, you configure both
the livenessProbe and the readinessProbe.