In this demo, I will show you
end-user authentication using a JWT token.
I have again an empty Kubernetes cluster with Istio enabled,
and I'm going to use helloworld-jwt.yaml in this demo.
This will spin up exactly the services
that I've shown you in the previous lecture.
So we're going to use a gateway, a helloworld gateway.
We're going to create a virtual service,
and the difference is that I'm not going to use
the example.com domain name,
I'm going to use a real host name
because this host name need to exist
for our sidecar to be able to retrieve this jwks.json.
So this is a virtual service and this will go to the host
auth.default.svc.cluster.local
which is defined a little bit lower.
Then I will have a second virtual service.
I'll have the hello.kubernetes.newtech.academy
and this will go to the hello service.
So this is the service that we'll use to authenticate
and this is the service that I need to be authenticated for.
Then we have a deployment of our authentication service.
It's still http-echo. I all wrote this in one app.
Text is showing this is the authentication service.
I have a service for this and then I have second deployment.
And this says hello, you can only reach this service
when authenticated, and this also has a service.
You're going to enable MTLS still.
So your ARR MTLS rules, which is the same
as the previous ones that we did in the previous MTLS demos.
I'm going to execute this. Kubectl apply
of helloworld-jwt.yaml. This will spin up the pods.
And what I need to do is now I need to log in
to my AWS account and I need to create this.
Auth.kubernetes.newtech.academy
because our sidecar will try to connect to this one.
So I'm logged into my AWS account.
I'm going to route 53. I have here one hosted zone.
Kubernetes.newtech.academy. I will create a new record.
This is gonna be auth.kubernetes.newtech.academy,
domain alias, and I only have one ELB classic load balancer
and this is the Istio English load balancer.
So I'm just going to pick this one.
I'm going to click create, and now I have
auth.kubernetes.newtech.academy,
which goes to the load balancer.
You also can create one for hello,
but it's not really necessary as we can just pause
the header with our curl commands.
We just have to wait a few seconds
until this DNS is propagated.
These changes need to be made,
otherwise it might not work.
This only takes a few seconds before it propagates.
You just have to make sure that you do this
before enabling the end-user authentication.
Back to our terminal, let's have a look again at our pods.
They're both running. I haven't enabled
end-user authentication, so I should be able
to access my hello pod still
because there's no posse enabled on it.
So let's try it. I'm going to use curl for that.
Let's have look what the load balancer host name is.
This is the load balancer host name.
So I'm going to curl this host name,
host: hello.kubernetes.newtech.academy.
Hello, you can only reach this service when authenticated.
Well, I didn't put authentication on,
so I can just readjust now. Let's try to put it on now.
Helloworld-jwt-enable, we'll put it on.
So this is the policy,
that I showed you in the previous lecture.
We have this jwt configuration here.
Make sure you also enable MTLS,
because MTLS is enabled in our croster.
Targets is hello. This is the name of the service.
The issuer that we looking for,
is http-echo@http-echo.kubernetes.newtech.academy
and the jwksUrl is auth.kubernetes.academy/
.well-known/jwks.json. Let's first get the token.
Let's enable this and then get the token.
So I'll just enable this. How to get this token.
Login and then I'm going to poss my username.
So if I just do login, it will say no login supplied.
This is written in the code. If I do minus d,
I can add some data. It's expecting a json.
Login, and my login's Edward.
And I'll just submit it like that.
So then I get a token, and now I need this token
to access this other service.
So let's try to exit this hello service without
tossing his token. Origin authentication failed.
So this works because I enabled the posse,
and the posse says you need to be authenticated
and if you're not authenticated,
then I will give you a permission
in Iotin origin authentication failed.
So now we need to pause this token,
so we'll do token equals. It's easier to pause like that.
And this is my token. And then pause this token
using the header. The header is authorization bearer
and then the token. So I'm doing this manually now,
but this is typically incorporated in the app.
Either pause the header or pause it using a cookie.
And then if everything goes right,
we shouldn't get an error anymore, of no origin.
But, we should get this sentence again.
And this works. It says hello,
you can only reach this service when authenticated.
So what happened in the background?
Let's have a look at this token.
Has to go to jwt.io.
We can just put our encoded JWT token here
and then we'll see the headers, the payload,
and we can verify the signature.
The header's algorithm that I'm using
is RS256, using asymmetric encryption.
So it has a private key and a public key.
I have a kid, this is mykey.
And I have a typ JWT. In this JWT token,
I have an expiration time. I have groups,
which I have hide myself, issued at the issuer.
So we'll create an iss token, the login, and the subject.
It's only this issuer that's going to be used.
My Istio to check whether the issuer
is this http-echo.kubernetes.newtech.academy.
Let's have a look again at configuration
and let's have at then how that Istio
could verify this signature
because I cannot verify it right now
because I don't have the public key, right?
So it says it's an invalid signature right now
because I have this token, but I don't have the public key
to verify the signature. This is token.
Let's have a look again at configuration.
Jwt-enable.yaml. Issuer, we've seen this in the token.
It had the key iss, so this issuer is something
that was created by the authentication app.
It's just something that has to be there.
So that we are sure that this is a token
that is issued by our authentication server.
Then we need to verify it. And we are telling Istio,
you can verify it using this jwks.json.
So the sidecar will actually go to this url.
So our hello sidecar will curl this url.
That's why we need this TNS. And this json,
will list our keys. It will also have the kid.
It will have a type, which is RSA,
and it will have the public key.
And this is an encoded public key,
that we can use, or that Istio can use
to verify a signature of this JWT token.
So this token, sidecar will receive.
It needs to first validate it.
It will use this public key to validate the signature.
The signature is going to be the last part of the key.
So this is the last part. This is the signature.
And when it's valid, then it can use the data
that is in this key. Data contains the issuer.
It will compare the issuer. If this issuer is correct,
then it will allow access
to hello.kubernetes.newtech.academy.
You can also validate this token using jwt.io,
but then you a public key. This is the public key,
but it's not in a format that jwt.io will recognize.
You need to convert it, but if you want to get
the public key, you can actually login
to this authentication port and then here you have
the private key, the private pem
that's supposed to use to generate this token.
You also have the public key and the public pem.
So this public pem is the one that you need.
This is in a pem format, and if you copy this,
go to jwt.io, paste it here, and it says signature verified.
Cause now it was able to verify the signature
and that is what the Istio sidecar does.
It verifies this signature, looks up some of the data in it,
and then it says we have a valid signature
now we can exit this service. So this is a very nice system
that Istio provides, that you can enable authentication
on services, using this end-user authentication
using JWT tokens. If anything goes wrong
when you're trying out this demo yourself,
then the best chance to debug this
is by getting the logs of this hello pod.
So if you do kubectl logs of this hello pod,
then it'll say we have two containers
that you will have to choose from.
You have the hello container
and we have the Istio proxy container.
Kubectl logs of this pod name, Istio proxy
will give you the logs of the sidecar.
So this is envoy, this is a logs of envoy
trying to connect to it. So if something goes wrong,
then it will be in here. For example,
if you cannot reach the url of the jwks token,
then you'll find the error here
and then you can remediate it.