I will now be talking about StatefulSets.
Stateful distributed apps on a Kubernetes cluster.
Pet Sets was a new feature starting from Kubernetes 1.3,
and got renamed to StatefulSets which is now
a stable since Kurbernetes 1.9.
It is introduced to be able to run stateful applications,
that need a stable pod hostname
instead of a podname-randomstring,
as you see when you run, for instance, deployments.
They have a randomstring after the podname
so they don't really have a stable hostname
you always need to go over the service
to then get access to one of the pods you are running.
Your podname, in StatefulSets, will have a sticky identity
using an index, for example, podname-0,
podname-1, and podname-2, and when a pod gets rescheduled
it'll keep that identity.
So if podname-1 gets rescheduled it will still be podname-1.
StatefulSets allow stateful apps stable storage
with volumes based on their ordinal number.
So if our podname-1 gets rescheduled,
it will keep the storage because it's stable storage.
It will not have to be reinitialized.
And then deleting and/or scaling a StatefulSet down
will not delete the volumes associated
with the StatefulSets, preserving the data.
So if you go from three to two,
then it will not delete the volume
you will have to clean it up yourself.
This is to preserve the data.
A StatefulSet will allow your stateful app
to use DNS to find other peers.
Cassandra clusters, ElasticSearch clusters,
use DNS to find other members of the cluster.
For example, you can use the DNS name
cassandra-0.cassandra for all the pods to reach
the first node in the Cassandra cluster.
So if you have, let's say, five nodes,
all those five nodes can use the same DNS name
to reach the first pod which is cassandra-0.
So they will then contact, in Cassandra it's called
the seed node, this is the way they find each other.
So in this case you need a stable hostname
for all the pods, for all the nodes, that are running
to find each other.
Using StatefulSets you can run, for instance,
three Cassandra nodes on Kubernetes
named cassandra-0 until cassandra-2.
So then you will have cassandra-0,
cassandra-1 and cassandra-2.
If you wouldn't use StatefulSet
you would get a dynamic hostname,
which you wouldn't be able to use
in your configuration files as the name can always change.
A StatefulSet will also allow your stateful app
to order the startup and teardown.
Instead of randomly terminating one pod,
one instance of your app, you will know
which one that will go.
When scaling up it goes from zero to n minus one,
where n is replication factor.
If you have three nodes you have zero, one, and two,
if you create another node then your n will be four.
When scaling down it starts
with the highest number, so n minus one.
So replicate if you have four nodes,
it will tear down number three,
then two, then one, then zero.
This is useful if you first need to drain the data
from a node before it can be shut down,
because then you know that the highest number
will be scaled down first so you can drain
that node if necessary.