This lecture is about Daemons Sets. Daemons Sets ensure that every single node in the Kubernetes cluster runs the same pod resource.
This is useful if you want to ensure that a certain pod that is running on every
single Kubernetes node goes unnoticed.
When a node is added to the cluster, a new pod will be started automatically.
Same when the node is removed the pod will not be rescheduled on another node.
You have four nodes.
You will run four pods one on each node.
You remove one node.
You will then run triples instead of four. That fourth pod will not be rescheduled.
So you always have the same amount of pods as you have
the amount of nodes. The typical use cases, logging aggregators,
so when you want to have one logging aggregator per node, where our pods send their logs.
Monitoring, again,
if you want a monitor per node then typically only want one pod that is going to do the monitoring
for physical nodes.
Load Balancers, Reverse Proxies, API Gateways.
There are third party API gateways, like linkerd, that also use daemon sets to run just one pod per node
that you have in your kubernetes cluster and in general running a daemon that only need one pot instance
per physical instance, then you're going to use daemon sets. This is an example of a Daemon Set specification, which is very simple.
You're going to use the API version extensions if you want beta.
And the kind is DaemonSet and all the rest is exactly the same as the previous definitions
that you are used.
You have other data and then you have the spec. In the spec
you define a template where you have your pod specifications. I am not going to do a daemon now or daemon sets,
it will come back later on in the course.