In this lecture, I'll be talking about "Secrets". Secrets provides a way in Kubernetes to distribute credentials,
Key, passwords, or secret data to the pods, even Kubernetes itself uses this Secrets mechanism to provide
the credentials to access the internal API.
That means that pods have access to secrets and those secrets must be distributed using this Secrets mechanism.
In the demo I am going to show exactly how it looks like.
You can also use the same mechanism to provide secrets to your application.
If you have an application that needs credentials,
you can use this same mechanism.
Secrets could be, for instance, a database looking at passwords or anything that needs to be kept secret.
Secrets is one way to provide secrets native to Kubernetes.
There are still other ways your container can get its secrets
if you don't want to use the secrets in Kubernetes.
For instance, you could be using an external vault service in your app.
There are external vault services that you can use, that your app might be contacting.
So, you can write that completely in the app layer.
You don't really need kubernetes for that.
I'll be explaining this native Kubernetes secrets in the next coming slides.
Secrets can be used in the following ways you can use secrets as environment variables.
So, in your application you will just have to read the environment variables
and that's where the app will then find the secrets.
You can also use secrets as a file in a pod.
This set up use volumes to be mounted in a container. In this volume
you have files.
So, in your container you're going to have a volume.
It means, it's just a directory that you can access, that contains and all secrets. It can be used, for
instance, for "dotenv" files, if you are familiar with those or your app can just read this file.
So, on your app you can just write some code that says you need to go and look in the specific directory
for the secrets that you need, for instance, to connect to a database.
You can also use an external image to pull the secrets. Obviously, from a private image registry,
you cannot put your secret in a public image registry.
In that case, it would mean that you will have a second docker image and that that image would be pulled and
your app would then read the data that contains the secrets from that image.
First, you need to generate the secrets.
So, we have a login and a password, and it put that in Kubernetes. To generate secrets using files,
you can use these commands.
So, first we're going to create those files,
if you don't have them already, you are just going to create a file "username.txt", put "root" in that file,
and I am going to create a file "password.txt", and we are going to put the string password in that file.
Then you can say, "Kubectl", or "kubecontrol create secret generic", it's in generic secrets,
give the name, and then you say "--from-file", use "username.txt", and for "--from-file=./password.txt",
and then you have the secret database user pass that has been created
that later you can use. A secret can also be an SSH key or an SSL certificate.
Here you say, "kubectl create secret generic", username again as the SSL certificate and the "--from-file"
is a key rather than the user name or password.
So, that's a way to distribute keys for instance.
If you want to generate secrets using the YAML definitions, previously we all learned to use the YAML files,
you're going to create a file secrets secrets-db-secret.yml
And this definition is going to be of "kind: secret".
You'll give a name, a type, and then you will supply the data. Here you're going to supply base64 strings.
On the right you see how you can generate those base64 strings.
So, you need a Linux or Mac machine, or you can search online for base64 generation tool.
You say I have the string root or you have a string password
and you generate a base64 string for that,
then you use that in your YAML file.
After creating the YAML file you can just use, "kubectl" to create the database secret.
Once the secrets are created, then you can use them. At that point you have the three options.
I will show you the two most common ones, which is the finance and environment variables.
If you going to use environment variables you can create a pod that exposes the secrets
as environment variables.
Here we have the pod definition that we always have been using and what are you going to do is you going
to add "env".
You going to give your environment variable a name and then you're going to say that you want
to have the value from another source.
The source is going to be the secrets and you're going to say that
the name in the secret is database-secret,
and the key that you want is username. Database-secret is the name of the object,
in Kubernetes the key is username,
the value will be the secret value that you store stored in Kubernetes.
You can do the same with other environment variables that you want to have in your pod.
Alternatively, you can provide the secrets in a file.
Here, we have a "volumeMount" within our container that you want a volume. VolumeMount, we give it a name,
we give the path,
so this is the path that your app will have to use.
It's easy "/etc/creds", "readOnly: true", app that is running in this container can not change this,
it can only read this, and I'm going to have a volume definition and in this volume definition you're also going
to define a name, "credvolume".
So, this name practically must be equal to the "volumeMount", because in the "volumeMount" you're referring
to a volume here that you are creating. This volume exists off secrets.
So, we don't see secret with a secret name database-secrets. So all the keys and values of data secrets will
now be inserted, will not be put in this "/etc/creds" folder and the secrets will be stored in "db-secrets",
the name of the secret and the keys.  Get the key username and password, so you will
have two files, username and password, that the application can then read.
The only thing that the application needs to do is read those files and it can then use the secrets within the
application. Using volumes and using environment variables,
using these two ways,
I will show you in the next demo.