In this demo, I'm going to show you how to run your first app on Kubernetes using pods.
First of all you will need to clone my git repository.
So, again you can usually git clone commands or you can go to this website and you can download a zip file.
So, this repository is called "kubernetes-course"
On this machine I have my mini kube-cluster running
Just as I explained in one of the previous demos, so I can immediately use kubectl
So, "kubectl get node" is showing me that's my mini kube is running.
Though, I have here under "fist-app", I have the "helloworld.yml" file
And this file I am going to use to create the pod.
So, I am going to use "kubectl create -f fist-app/helloworld.yml"
Kubernetes came back to me
"pod 'nodehelloworld.example.com' created"
So, then now use "kubectl get pod", then you can see the pod that was previously running
which is the pod that I started when I installed this cluster, which is already running
And then, I have another pod "nodehelloworld.example.com"
So, let's have a look at this one using "describe pod" and then the name.
At the bottom you see the events and you see one of the evens is that it's now pulling
the image, so it is pulling this image
it's downloading the image and then [it] will start the pod. So here I see some info about container, my labels,
State is "Pending"
If you don't have a very fast internet connection it can take some time to pull this image.
So, now it's started the container with the Docker ID and then the ID. Our pod is now running.
There are now multiple ways to get to this pod.
The first way is to use port-forwarding
We can use kubectl to port-forward and then we just use the name. We can port-forward the pod, which is 3000
And we can listen locally on port 8081.
So then, again locally, on this machine connect to 8081 and then kubectl is going to make sure that
all this traffic is redirected to port 3000.
So this stays open,
I just have to open a new shell and I can just do, "curl localhost:8081", and then I get the "Hello World".
This is one way to quickly test whether it is working.
The second way is to create a service.
In the next lecture hour, I will explain how to create a service for AWS.
If you are running a class on AWS that's going to be interesting for you, if you are using
minikube you can just expose the port and then connect directly.
You can do the same on your AWS cluster, but on AWS you have the possibility to use Load Balancer.
So, Load Balancer is always going to be better for you.
Let me first show you how to expose this port.
Go to "kubectl expose", we are going to expose "pod", and our pod name is "nodehelloworld.example.com" and
and our pod name is "nodehelloworld.example.com" and we are going to use type "NodePort"
which means that we can directly access Port 3000 on the Kubernetes
and it will redirect to this pod
And actually in this case we also need to provide a name for this service.
So we will just say "nodehelloworld-service"
because you cannot use this as a name for a service. So, "service 'nodehelloworld-service' exposed
Now, we just need to know the IP address of the Kubernetes cluster to connect to.
If you're an AWS you can just use your Master Node.
You will have to change your security groups though.
If you're a minikube, "minikube service nodehelloworld-service --url"
and this gives us the correct mapping.
So this port-forwards to Port 3000
So if you do "kubectl get service", we see the newly created service that exposes Port 3000. With minikube
we can use this port to connect to the service, because this is an IP address that I can use for my whole
system, for my Mac. These IP addresses here are IP addresses within our cluster.
So, those are two different things.
So, I'm going to use my browser and "Hello World"
It is working.