In this lecture, I'm going to talk about ETCD.
ETCD is used by Kubernetes as data backend.
ETCD is a distributed and reliable key-value store
for the most critical data of a distributed system.
It's meant to be simple and it has a well-defined,
user facing API using gRPC,
which is a communication protocol
that is more efficient that normal HTTP.
It is secure, with automatic TLS
and optional client certificate authorization.
It is fast, it is benchmarked with 10,000 writes per second.
And it is reliable,
it is using the Raft Consensus Algorithm.
All Kubernetes objects that you create
are persisted to the ETCD backend,
and this backend is typically running inside your cluster.
If you have a one-master Kops cluster or a minikube setup,
you'll typically have a one-node ETCD cluster.
ETCD uses consensus to persist writes,
so you need to have three or five ETCD nodes
to allow for one or two nodes, respectively to fail.
You have three nodes, you can have one node failure.
You have five nodes, you can have two node failures.
The latency between your nodes should be low,
as heartbeats are sent between the nodes.
If you have a cluster spanning multiple Data Center's,
you will need to tune your heartbeat timeouts
in the ETCD cluster,
otherwise your heartbeats will timeout
and you will hit some issues.
A write to ETCD can only happen by the leader,
which is elected by an election algorithm
as part of the Raft Algorithm.
Which I will explain in a separate lecture.
If a write goes to one of the other ETCD nodes,
the write will be routed through the leader,
because each node also knows who the leader node is.
ETCD will only persist the write if
a quorum agrees on the write.
For example, when you have three nodes,
a quorum will be two nodes.
When you have five nodes,
then you will need three nodes for a quorum.
This is to have consistency of the data,
for example, when a network split occurs.
All Kubernetes object data
is stored within the ETCD cluster,
so you'll want to have a backup of this data
when running a production cluster.
ETCD supports snapshots,
to take a backup of your ETCD cluster,
which can store all the data into a snapshot file.
So here's an example, you can use ETCDCTL,
you have to pass endpoints
and you can then execute snapshot save to snapshotdb
or you can then also use restore to restore snapshots.
So these are commands that you could enter
to communicate with the ETCD cluster
and take a snapshot for backup or restore one.
Then in the next lecture I will explain
a bit more about the Raft Algorithm.