In this demo, I am going to show you how to set up a WordPress using the secrets. It's not a fully working Wordpress yet.
The more features of Kubernetes you will see, the more and will changes set up a little bit, and at the
end of the course you will actually have a Wordpress that is working.
We don't know how to use stateful containers yet, that's why whenever you can to put data in this WordPress,
it's not going to be persistent, whatever your pod shuts down that it is gone.
But that doesn't stop me of showing you already what we can do now using those secrets.
WordPress files are in a directory called WordPress.
In my git repository of the "Kubernetes-course". The first file I want to show you
is the "wordpress-secrets".
This "wordpress-secrets" has a one secret, the database password.
You can change the database password into something more secure,
but this is just the passwords.
Then we are going to need a deployment.
So, I have a file called, "single-deployment-no-volumes",
because we're not using any volumes to persist data yet.
That's why I called it that way.
It only has one replica.
It's just one deployment of our app WordPress.
This deployment has two containers.
Wordpress is a blog software.
In case you didn't know yet, this has a container that is referring to an image,
"Wordpress:4-php7.0"
This container is one of the official Wordpress images and it comes with PHP and Apache which is the webserver.
So, its websites is blog software, all bundled within one image,
and that's why they're going to pull from a repository. It's going to expose Port 80,
and we need to provide some of the environment variables, we need to provide a password of the database.
And that's why we're going to use this "WORDPRESS_DB_PASSWORDS",
and if you're wondering how do I know the name of this environment variable.
This is all explained on the website a "http://help.docker.com" of Wordpress, and I will show you that,
this is the official repository for wordpress.
It's rich content management system and can utilize plug in switches and teams and then here you have
how to use this image and you can see we have a "WORDPRESS_DB_HOST", "WORDPRESS_DB_USER",
default "root", that we are not going to change, because it's fine for us,
and "WORDPRESS_DB_PASSWORDS", which we are going to set. You can also change the database name with table prefix.
You can set some other settings like an authentication key and so on, but if you dont set those then
it will be generated, which is fine for us for now.
We also have different images.
We are going to use the one with PHP7 and Apache, but you can also use the one without Apache.
You can put an nginx in front of it if you want, but that would make it a little more complicated.
So we're just going to keep it relatively simple for now.
So, that's how I found out about these wordPress database passwords and the value for these key,
for the environment variables
it is going to come from the "wordpress-secrets", and I am going to use the database password for this.
The next environment variable that I am going to try is the "WORDPRESS_DATABASE_HOSTS".
And I'm going to use 127.0.0.1, which is basically localhost,
because this is going to refer to another container.
The second container that I have in this pod. I have mysql container which is a database.
Mysql version is 5.7.
This is also an official image from docker help.
So you can also take a look at docker help how to read instructions.
It exposes the standard.
My secret Port 3306.
And we are also going to define an environment variable with the mysql "root" password and this magic
root password is going to have the same value as this one which is the password that comes from our
"Wordpress-secrets".
So, the password needs to be the same, because our database will be set up with this password to login
and all need to be "root".
And, we also want to let our application know that it can login using the same password.
You can set some more environment variables but this will do.
We have one pod, two containers, and only one replica because if you would increase it to two, it's going to run two databases
and it isn't going to make sense.
You only want one database and one wordpress in front of it.
So, that's a long one, "kubecontrol create -f wordpress/" secrets first, "wordpress-secrets". "Secrets 'wordpress-secrets' created",
and now we can create that deployment.
"'Wordpress-deployment' created"
So, let's have a look at the pods,
I still have my "helloworld" from the previous demo and then here I have the wordpress deployments running,
Two containers this time.
"Kubectl gets" or "describe pod"
And here we have two containers running
using our secret. To reach this WordPress,
I need to make a service.
So, I also have a "wordpress-service" that is going to target my HTTP port for my pod.
It's the service for the app Wordpress and is going to expose this port as a "NodePort", "type: NodePort"
"Kubecontrol creates -f", and then, "minikube service wordpress-service", and then the URL.
And then, I should be able to access our wordpress.
I'm going to do this in a web browser and then here we have our WordPress.
So we just need to do some set up.
Is going to be my blog, my username.
I can use this password.
My email address can discourage, "Discourage search engines indexing this website".
It's not online, it's just on my PC.
And then you can say install and then it is installed.
Goes very quick and you can log in.
I can now log in and then welcome to WordPress, so I have my dashboard.
It's all working and if I click on "Visit Website" I can actually visit my blog website.
So it was that simple to set up a blog, but it's not fully working yet, because this container is still
going to write some data to the local image.
If I'm going to upload media like images then those images will be written on the container,
if that container restarts all my images will be gone.
So, we will have to find a solution for that and I will show you what happens when the pod gets killed.
"Kubectl get pods"
So let's say that our pod gets killed, "kubectl"--
I'm just going to delete my photos, which will be launched again by the deployment.
So my book is deleted and your pod is launched.
But what's going to happen now, because we launched and mysql that contains all the data.
The installation that we have done now.
The main login and password that I filled out,
but like I said earlier those images they boot up.
You can find some data to that image, but when you restart a pod it's nowhere saved because there are
no data mounted and no volumes that we are using yet to keep the data saved somewhere.
It's just, if a container restarts the data will be gone.
So, what happens if our vault gets rescheduled or it is killed.
Well, I will just refresh this page and all the data is gone, and I can just reinstall WordPress, because my
database is completely wiped, it is reinstalled, because the data was not saved.
This is still something that we have to find a solution for and I will explain the solution in the volumes
lecture later on.
But for now it's already a very interesting elab, because this already touches a lot of things,
we had a deployment of service, secrets, and environment variables, and multiple images in our pod.