In this demo, I'm going to show you how Service Discovery works.
I have here a folder services discovery.
I'm going to create a few resources again or let me first show you what's in it.
I'm going to use "cat service-discovery/credentials/",
the credentials are "secrets.yml"
I've got in secrets username, password, rootPassword, and the database. I'm only using rootPassword at the database actually.
I'm going to use a rootPassword rather than using a separate username and password,
because that needs extra set up and I want to keep it as simple as possible for this demo just to show you
Service Discovery.
"kubectl create" and I'm going to create a pod and it's going to be my database pod, so I have here
the database again. The name of the database container is "mysql:5.7",
runs on 3306, specify root passwords, a user, and a password, and a database.
I also have a service is going to expose a node port, a random node port.
"Kubectl creates -f service-discovery/database.yml" and service.
Then I have a "helloworld-db.yml" and a service.
This one is interesting
It's a deployment, three replicas, off my "k8s-demo",
I also call it "helloworld-db", it is the same image, but this image also has an "index-db.js"
in the same folder.
You might have noticed that when you did the docker built,
that there was also an "index-db.js".
If you specify command "node" in the "index-db.js" rather than using NPM start, which is executing
node "index-db.js", I can override this in my YAML files, so I can execute different commands on my image.
For us it's all the same,
nodejs-port 3000, but then and I am also adding environment variables here.
Host, mysql host, mysql user, passwords, from the root password and a database from the secrets and
key database, which is going to run in a database.
And this is going to connect to our database and is going to use the host "database-service".
So, this will only work if the DNS resolving works, because
my database service is called "database-service".
This value of mysql host needs to resolve to the IP address of this service database-service
and then my app will be able to connect to the database.
Let's try it out.
I'm going to do a create of this "helloworld-db.yml" and this "helloworld-db-service.yml".
So, this service is very generic and just going to also expose my "helloworld-db"
"Minikupe service helloworld-db-service --url",
So, that's going to be the URL that I am going to connect to
Let's first check whether everything is running.
So, "kubeclt get pods"
We have one database which is just a pod and then we have three pods for deployment.
All of them are running.
Let's check the locks of this pod to see whether we are able to connect that to the database.
It says, "Connection to the database established".
So, index-db.js was able to connect using these credentials to the database.
The only thing that this database index-db.js does is going to create a table and there is going
to be one column that is going to initialize a value at zero,
and every time I'm going to do a hit, it's going to do a plus one.
Just instead of the "Hello World", it is going to do a plus one.
So, "Hello World, you are visitor number 1".
"You are visitor number 2"
"You are visitor number 3"
and so on.
So, this is stored in the database. So, it actually works,
this "helloworld-deployment", this pod connects to the database service, and inserts data in the database.
How can I check this?
Well, let me do "kubectl exec database", I am going to log into the database, I am going to execute something on the database, "-i -t",
and the command I am going to execute is "mysql"
I am going to log in as "root" and I'm going to give a password.
Password is a root password, those are found in secrets.
Database, so show databases.
The database is "helloworld",
I am going to use
"Helloworld".
Show the tables here.
And "select * from visits;"
So, this was created by my app.
There are four records, four visits, and this is just a timestamp.
So this works,
my app was able to discover the service, and connect to the database.
And this because DNS resolving works,
which I could also test, opening a shell on one of the nodes, and
actually in a "busybox", because I need to resolve settings.
So, I'm going to do "kubectl run", "busybox", and "busybox" has "nslookup".
And then, with "nslookup" I can then check whether my service works, my service can resolve.
So I'm going to do "helloworld-db-service"
I am going to do "nslookup",
and yes that works.
"Kube-dns" answers with "helloworld-db-service"
is at 10.0.0.52,
and this is the full hostname.
So, let me do this and then "nslookup" again, because here we have an overview of our cluster IP addresses.
So, it will be easier to show you, which one is which, because these names are quite confusing.
So, if you want to find out which one is the database service,
I can do "nslookup database-service". If I want to do a "nslookup" on the service, which is app layer in our case,
then I can do a "nslookup" on this one.
So, I don't have "curl" here,
so I actually use the telnet to this service,
and then it gets "/", "You are visitor number 5"
So, if I just want to connect to the app layer, I can use "helloworld-db-service". If I want to connect
to the database-service, the mysql, the database,  then I can use this hostname.
This database-services resolves to this IP
and these other services resolves to that IP and whenever the service would be recreated,
the DNS within them would also be updated.
That's it for the DNS Discovery
It is also going to be part of our WordPress later on.
So, I will come back to this. Service discovery is a very important part of running a cluster with lots of services
"Control+D" if you want to exit and the delete the pod "busybox", if you want to delete the "busybox"
and you obviously have to delete all the running services on pods  and deployments.