In this demo,
I will show you how to set up a cluster on AWS using EKS.
This is eksctl.io, the official command-line utility
for Amazon EKS and is the website.
You will find the introduction here, getting started,
the basic commands that we are going to execute
in this demo, and also the installation
on how you install it on Linux or Mac, with Brew,
Brew is the easiest if you have macOS, or on Windows.
So on Windows, you can download Chocolatey,
the package manager, then just run this command.
You will need to have your AWS API credentials configured.
They say, "What works for AWS command-line utility
"or any other tool,"
for example, if you use Kops, that should be sufficient.
So if you used AWS configure at some point,
to then configure the AWS credentials file
in .aws/credentials, then it will be okay.
You can also use environment variables,
but running AWS configure is the easiest way
to have your AWS credentials configured.
So if you haven't done that yet,
you will have to download the AWS command-line utility
from the AWS website and then run AWS configure
to configure the credentials,
for your AWS user that can spin up a cluster.
You will also need the AWS IAM Authenticator for Kubernetes,
so this makes sure that you can
log in to the cluster using IAM.
So either follow this link,
or if you are using a package manager,
the package manager is going to
automatically install this for you,
because then the authenticator will be
a dependency of eksctl.
You will be able to spin up a cluster without this tool,
but then, when you run kubectl, if you cannot authenticate,
then there is something wrong with this IAM Authenticator.
Most likely, at that point,
you are missing the authenticator,
and you need to still download it.
I am going to run the install on macOS,
so I need those two lines to install eksctl.
Let's do that first, and let's then start a cluster.
Let's first install eksctl,
and let's then create our cluster using EKS.
You can use eksctl create cluster, with the name cluster-1.
For example, two nodes, so these are the two worker nodes.
The master node, you will not see.
In a specific region, I am specifying eu-west-1,
and if you want, you can also specify managed,
and if you specify managed,
it will also manage your worker nodes.
If you don't specify it, it will still be a managed cluster,
but it will only manage the master nodes.
If you also want to have the worker nodes managed,
automatically updated, then you can specify this flag,
and this will enable the managed nodegroups in EKS.
If you get this error, here,
then your AWS credentials are not configured,
so let me just configure my AWS credentials
in another window, and then execute the command again.
So I'm going to execute it again,
now I have my credentials configured.
Basically, I run AWS configure again
to configure my credentials.
Now, it can connect to Amazon over the API,
and then create the necessary infrastructure.
Let's have a look what it is doing.
This is eksctl version 0.11.1,
using region eu-west-1, three availability zones,
so I need to create three subnets
for those availability zones.
It's going to create a public subnet
and a private subnet for each availability zone.
It's using Kubernetes version 1.14,
which is currently the latest one, in Amazon, available,
but they bring out newer versions,
so there are already newer Kubernetes versions,
just not in EKS.
So at some point, Amazon will bring out a new version,
and then the default version will be 1.15, 1.16, 1.17,
whatever the latest version is.
It is then create a cluster with the name cluster-1,
in eu-west-1, with managed nodes.
And it's going to create two separate CloudFormation stacks
for the cluster and for the managed nodegroup.
If you have any issues,
then you can check the CloudFormation console.
Then you can use this command or go into the UI
to describe the CloudFormation stacks.
CloudWatch logging will not be enabled,
but you can enable it using this command,
so you can enable, afterwards, some more configuration.
This will be a public endpoint,
so we have publicAccess, true,
and privateAccess, false,
so that means we can connect to our EKS cluster
without using a VPN or without having to use a jump host.
If you want to create a production cluster,
it's actually advised to create a private cluster,
so that the API is not available to the whole world,
and then you would choose private access true,
then you need a VPN or a jump host, a bastion,
to be able to connect to your cluster.
So it's then, first, building the cluster,
and then it's going to deploy it.
This might take some time, so I'm going to pause the video,
and then, when it's finished,
I'm going to deploy our test application.
After waiting a couple of minutes, your cluster will be up,
and your worker nodes will have started.
So we left here, "Deploying stack."
Then, all the EKS cluster resources have been created,
so that means the EKS cluster is up.
And then, it is starting the nodes,
the EC2 nodes in the managed nodegroup,
so we have here the managed nodegroup.
And it's waiting for the two nodes to come up,
and after they are ready, then we can use our cluster.
It wrote a Kube config file,
so if you first have a look at this config file,
we will see that we have the minikube configuration
from when I, earlier, started a minikube cluster,
but we also have the EKS configuration.
So clusters, we have two clusters.
This is the minikube one, and here's the EKS one.
So it has a name, cluster-1.eu-west-1.eksctl.io.
Here's a certificate authority.
This is to connect to the Kube API server
and to verify a certificate.
But authentication itself is now done by
the AWS IAM authenticator.
So here, this is just a command that needs to be available
on your machine.
So you will have to download it
if you don't have this command available.
So when we execute kubectl,
it will execute this command using the argument token,
i, cluster-1,
and it is then going to retrieve the token
that we can use to log in to this cluster.
So that is then using IAM, rather than using certificates.
So here, for example, we have certificates
to connect to our minikube cluster.
We are not using that.
We are not using the client certificate and the client key.
We are using IAM as an authenticator
to log in to our EKS cluster.
Let's type kubectl get nodes.
Here, we have two nodes available,
so they are the EC2 instances that are now ready.
So, here, we didn't really configure the instance family,
the instance size, but you can configure that if you want.
By default here, now, it is an M5 Large that is configured.
1.14.7, we are running.
So let's try to deploy something in this cluster.
Just like the minikube demo and the Kops demo,
I can deploy the echo server.
So hello-deployment created.
Now, let's expose this deployment by adding a service.
I'm going to use kubectl expose deployment.
Type=LoadBalancer.
Port=80.
That's the port I want to use on my LoadBalancer,
and the target port is going to be 8080
because the echo server is running on 8080.
Let's have a look.
Kubectl get pods.
So we have one hello-deployment.
If you use -o wide,
we also see that it has assigned an IP address.
So this is a VPC routable IP address.
You see 192.168 is in the same VPC.
So if you do kubectl get svc,
then we get the services.
So then, here, we have the hello-deployment,
which is of type LoadBalancer,
and this is the URL that we can use
to connect to our LoadBalancer.
It is best to wait a couple of minutes
before going to this URL.
Otherwise, you will probably catch a non-response,
and then it will take time before the cache clears.
So after you waited a couple of minutes,
run curl on macOS or Linux,
or just type this in your browser,
and then the echo service will respond.
So this is the echo service responding.
So now we set up an EKS cluster with a deployment,
with a service, service of type LoadBalancer,
connects to our application, which is running in a pod,
and then, if you go to the URL on port 80,
it goes to our echo service.
So this is basically how easy it is to set up EKS,
which is now just a normal Kubernetes cluster
that you can use.
So you can start launching pods, deployments,
DaemonSets, and so on, on this cluster.
Some configuration is different,
so it's best to also have a look at the documentation of EKS
on the Amazon website.
Where there are differences in this cluster setup,
it will be documented.
For example, how to setup CloudWatch and so on.
It will all be documented.
But with this eksctl,
you will often find and easy way to configure it.
So also have a look at the eksctl.io website,
if you want to change your configuration on your cluster.
If it is supported by the tool, it is, most of the time,
very easy to set that up.
So that is it for the demo.
Let me quickly show you how to delete your cluster,
because once you don't need it anymore,
you want to delete it.
Eksctl delete cluster, you can use,
and then it says, "Name must be set."
So then you can use --name cluster-1,
was the name that we gave our cluster, --region eu-west-1,
and then it is going to delete our EKS cluster,
delete our LoadBalancer, so it says,
"Cleaning up LoadBalancer services."
so it's going to delete any dependencies,
including LoadBalancer, delete the EC2 instances,
and delete the EKS cluster
so that you don't have to pay for it anymore.
You are billed by the time that you are using it,
so it's best to delete it when you are doing the demos,
or you are just testing out.
After you did your test, you don't need it anymore.
It's best to delete it.
So this will now run for a couple of minutes
to then delete our EKS cluster.