In this demo, I will show you
how to set up Flux
and to use a deployment and a service
that will automatically be deployed
to our Kubernetes cluster.
In my Kubernetes course,
I have a directory flux.
And here I have a README.
First thing that we need to do
is to install Flux.
So here I have the commands available to install Flux.
You will need to install fluxctl first.
So depending on what operating system you are,
you have different installation methods.
So let's have a look on the website first.
So this is the Flux documentation.
They're currently on version 1.17.1.
They probably are going to be at a newer version
when you are following this lecture.
So make sure to go to the Flux URL
and have a look in the documentation yourself
when you are following this lecture.
We need to first install fluxctl so on macOS,
it's very simple.
Brew install fluxctl.
On Linux, you can use snap.
And on Windows, you have the Chocolatey package manager
that you can use.
First, you need to install this package manager
and then you can execute this command
and this will install fluxctl.
You can also download the binary releases yourself
from the GitHub release page.
So once you have done this,
let's start with the installation.
Kubectl create namespace flux.
We're going to create a namespace for Flux.
I have already a Kubernetes cluster running.
You can use Minikube or Kops
or whatever Kubernetes cluster you have running.
Whatever's easiest for you.
Then I'm going to use a Git repository.
So I'm going to install Flux
and currently it only supports one Git repository.
So when you install Flux,
you're going to pass a Git repository
where your manifest files are located.
I have in my Git repository,
the flux-demo repository.
So the best thing that you can do
if you wanna do this demo
is to go to my GitHub repository,
flux-demo, and you fork this
which makes a copy of this repository
under your own GitHub user
and then you can export your own username here
and then it'll install Flux
using a Git repository that you have write access to,
the flux-demo on your own GitHub repository.
So I'm going to do export and it's gonna be my user.
So the URL of this flux-demo repo is GitHub.com,
my username and then /flux-demo.
I'll go over the code in a minute.
I'm just going to install it first.
Fluxctl install.
So this created a serviceaccount, clusterrole,
clusterrolebinding, the deployment,
a secret, the memcache and the service/memcache.
Let's have a look.
It's still rolling out.
So it's downloading the images now
and then once this command is complete,
we can start using Flux.
The deployment Flux has been rolled out.
Let's have a look at this flux-demo folder.
So this is my repository, flux-demo
and then we have two folders.
So it's only going to look at those two folders.
That's an argument that we passed during the installation.
We're only going to look at the namespaces
and the workloads directory,
so you can still add your application
to this repository, any other folders will just be ignored.
So we have the namespaces.
Here we have the definition
to create a new namespace called demo.
That's the only file in namespaces.
And then we have the workloads and in workloads,
we have hello.yaml.
And we just have a simple deployment here
of a docker-nodejs-demo.
We specified annotations so that we can use Flux.
So we have fluxcd/io/automated is true
and we're also going to say use
from this docker-nodejs-demo,
the tag that corresponds with sematic version 1.0.0.
So whenever we push a new version to our Docker Hub,
then the Flux will make sure that when it's still
within the major version of one
that that latest version is deployed.
So I have in this repo version 1.0.1 and 1.0.2.
So what I'm going to do is lemme just edit this file
and make sure that it is 1.0.1
which is an older version,
so then you'll immediately see this happening
because then it's going to deploy 1.0.2.
So I'll just roll this back to 1.0.1.
So we are going to deploy the image docker-nodejs-demo
version 1.0.1 but we're using
semantic versioning here with fluxcd.
Fluxcd will see that there's a 1.0.2
and then it's going to deploy the 1.0.2.
All the rest is pretty default stuff.
We have a strategy, rollingUpdates,
we want the max unavailability zero.
We have a selector, a template,
the containers and the ports.
The port is 3000.
So then we also have a service.
And the service is just a NodePort.
Depending on what kind of cluster you are,
you can change this to a different port.
What do we still need to do?
We need to here go to Settings.
Deployment keys and we need to configure a deployment key
for Flux so that Flux has access to this repository.
So we can add a deployment key.
Going to call it flux.
And then we can execute a command
to retrieve the correct key.
Setup SSH key in the README.
Fluxctl identity.
And this is the key.
This is a public key.
Flux has a private key.
And we are going to set up the public key in Git.
You have to allow write access
because Flux can also make changes.
The key is added
and now Flux will see that it has now access
to this repository.
It is a fluxctl install.
My git-user, the email, the url.
This is what I was talking about.
The git-path is namespaces, workloads.
So you need to make sure these two directories exist
and Flux will only look in those paths.
The namespace is flux
so let's have a look at the ports
in the namespace flux.
So I have the flux and the memchached
and let's have a look at the logs.
So what happened here?
Git repository was not ready
because a clone still was giving permission denied.
This was at 11:56
and then at 11:57,
it retried and it could actually fetch the master branch.
Then it goes into our Git repository,
figures out that there is a namespace, YAML file
and a deployment YAML file.
So here then it does a kubectl apply,
namespace/demo-created, service created
and it started the deployment.
Let's have a look.
Get pods in the demo namespace.
And then this one is running.
Let's try to reach it
on this NodePort.
I'm using Minikube here.
But you can really use whatever you want.
If you're using Kops, your probably want
to put this on a load balancer
to make it easy.
So this returns Hello World
which we typically return.
And we also have version 1.2.2.
So what happened here is that Flux did a sync
of our repo but also,
went to Docker Hub, checked what is the last version
that I can use taking this semantic version into account
and then I can use 1.0.2
because there's a newer version.
So it switches from 1.0.1 to 1.0.2.
So we have a look again in our flux-demo.
We see there was a commit two minutes ago
from Flux where Flux changed the 1.0.1 in 1.0.2.
And then it also pushed this image to Kubernetes
instead of the 1.0.1.
So Flux will continue to monitor this repo.
So if there now is a 1.0.3 released,
it will also automatically bump it to 1.0.3.
And that's what you will see here in the logs.
It will keep on syncing this repo.
Even if we make a change,
and we commit something,
then it will also pick it up
and then immediately apply it to our Kubernetes cluster.
The only real downside that I find now
is that we can only have one Git repository
but I'm sure that in the future, it will change.
What they that you can do now
is run just another flux daemon in another namespace
if you want to have multiple repositories.
And then you can use then RBAC rules
to make sure that Flux can only access that namespace
so that there is no overlap.
So that is it for this Flux demo.
It looks very simple
but it's actually a very powerful tool
because now you can put all your manifest files
in your Git repository
and then Flux will automatically monitor it
and apply it to the Kubernetes cluster
allowing you to do GitOps.