In this demo,
I will show you how to use Skaffold.
First, you will need to install Skaffold, which is binary.
So for Linux, you can execute these commands.
For macOS, you can use
brew install skaffold in a terminal.
And if you are on Windows,
you can use choco install skaffold,
which means you need Chocolatey,
which is a package manager for Windows.
If you don't have this package manager yet, chocolatey.org,
you can go to this website and here click install now.
Once you have installed this package manager,
then you can run this command from a powershell
or a CMD to install Skaffold.
Alternatively, if you don't want
to use this package manager,
you can download the latest release from here.
But as they say here,
it needs to be in your path to be able to use it.
So either you need to change environment variable path
or you put it in the directory
and can only use it in that directory.
The easiest way is to actually use a package manager.
So once it is installed,
you can start using it.
In my kubernetes-course directory,
I have a directory skaffold-demo,
and here I will show you how to use Skaffold.
I have a main.go file here,
so it's a Golang project.
And in this main.go,
I am just going to start a web server,
ListenAndServe on port 8080,
and when somebody goes to this website
I will say "Hello world".
When the server starts,
I will also print out to the terminal, to the logs,
"Listening on port 8080".
You don't need to have Golang installed,
because we will use Docker to build it.
What we need is, to have it deployed,
we need a skaffold.yaml
So let's have a look at this skaffold.yaml
API version skaffold/V1,
this is a configuration,
and we're going to use an image artifact,
and we're going to say
this is going to be the image URI,
and this is a Docker Hub URL.
So I have my login/staffold-demo
that I'm going to use.
You don't even need to create a repository,
it all happens for you.
So this is the build phase,
and then we have the deploy phase.
Skaffold is going to deploy using kubectl,
and then we have a manifest file for that,
the manifest files start with k8s.
k8s, and then you have one file:
kubernetes pod.yaml right here.
So if you have a look here,
then we have a pod,
skaffold-demo with the same image,
and then we're also going to use a service
of type LoadBalancer.
You don't really need to use the type LoadBalancer,
it's actually easier to use LoadBalancer
if you didn't want it also to have public,
but you can also use port-forwarding.
Skaffold also supports port-forwarding
if you don't wanna have LoadBalancer,
and then you can just go to a local IP and port.
If you have a look here,
we'd also then have a Dockerfile,
you also then have a go.mod,
which is just a definition of the modules
we are going to use in Golang.
So this is important.
We have here the Dockerfile then.
In the docker file we are going to build this main.go;
go build main.go in /app,
and then we are going to have a runtime container
using alpine, very small.
You're going to execute app,
and we're gonna copy our binary from this build container.
So, we say copy from builder, from /app
to our current directory,
and then we will be able to run this application
when we run this container.
So the typical developer will not use Vim,
the typical developer will use something like VS Code.
You can use Vim, you can use VS Code,
you can use another IDE.
I'm going to show you this demo with VS Code.
So this is my Visual Studio Code
and I already have my skaffold-demo open.
So here I have my main.go
and I'm gonna open a terminal, new terminal.
And then here I'm just gonna check
whether my kubernetes cluster is up and running:
kubectl get nodes.
Just gonna make it a little bit bigger.
kubectl get nodes,
our nodes are up and running.
And then we can type skaffold dev,
cause we are developing.
And then it's going to start building this container,
pushing this container.
And then I'm gonna open a second shell
because I wanna see when the deployment happens.
So now it is tagging it,
and now it's starting to deploy.
The pod is created,
and the service is created.
Waiting for changes now,
and it says "Listening on port 8080".
kubectl get pods,
skaffold-demo is now running.
kubectl get svc,
we have a LoadBalencer running.
And then we should be able to curl it,
it might still take a couple of minutes
before this LoadBalancer gets up the first time,
because of DNS, it takes some time
so we might have to wait a little bit before it works.
But then what we should see
when we go to this LoadBalancer URL
is that it says "Hello world".
So one simple command to deploy our pod
on our, I would say, development cluster
because this becomes then our development cluster
where we can, with multiple developers,
push our code on and see whether it is working.
So if you try again, it says "Hello world".
So our LoadBalancer is now setup
and if we try a few times we get hello world.
Now let's say that I wanna make a few changes,
so I'm saying "Hello world, I'm making a few changes",
and then I'm just going to hit the save button here,
the shortcut to save,
So I'm now saving,
and what's happening here?
Skaffold immediately sees that there has been a change.
It's going to rebuild the Docker image, push it again,
push the changes to Docker Hub,
and then it's going to the pod with the latest version.
You see now it is tagging it, pushing it,
and now is listening again on port 8080.
Let's curl again.
"Hello world, I am making a few changes."
So you see, it automatically builds, tags, push,
and then I have my new pod running.
My pod is updated
because it says pod configured,
so it puts a new image in place.
It puts this image, skaffold-demo
and then the tagged version,
the one that they tagged here.
And then it restarts the container with this new image,
and then when I do the curl, then I see that I am getting
the new version.
So this lets you rapidly iterate over changes
and test them immediately on your Kubernetes cluster.
So this is a really nice piece of software
to use by developers,
to then build their software
on Kubernetes using Docker containers.
And you can even do this demo
without having Golang installed on your local PC
because it's all running in a Docker container.
And like I said in the theory,
Skaffold is also very plugable.
You can change the way it builds,
you can change the way it pushes,
you can change the way it deploys,
so it's a very interesting piece of software
that you or your developers should definitely try out.
And then when we hit Control + C,
it is actually also going to clean up
the pods and the service,
so if we then do kubectl get pods,
there are no pods found any more.
So then it's nicely cleaned up,
the service and the pods are gone,
and the next time you are going to use Skaffold
then it will bring it all up again.