This is the end of
the section Introduction to Kubernetes.
Let me recap this section using a few diagrams
to make sure you understood the concepts.
I showed you how to deploy a first application
to the Kubernetes Cluster.
First, I show you how to create a container image
using the Docker command line.
So, we created, locally, an image,
we tagged it, and then we uploaded the container image
using the Docker push command to Docker Hub.
So, this point, Docker Hub,
has a container image called Kubernetes example.
Next, I create a first pod, Kubernetes example,
and this is the definition of this first pod.
What's important here is that you defined a container.
We can define one or more containers in a pod
that will run on the Kubernetes Cluster.
This container image uses the port 3,000.
That's why I defined the ports with the name nodejs-port,
and the container port to contact the server is Port 3,000.
This launched our first pod on the Kubernetes Cluster.
We used the command, kubectl create,
to send this yml file to the Kubernetes Cluster
and Kubernetes Launch Spot.
What Kubernetes is going to do now is
going to pull the image from Docker Hub,
because we defined that image in the yml file,
so it pulls this container image,
and it starts running the container
in its pod in Kubernetes.
Next, we want to contact the pod.
And because we don't have service yet,
we need to use another way to contact it.
One way that you can use to contact the pod
from your local machine is using port-forward.
So, using kubectl port-forward,
and then the name of the pod,
and then the ports that you want to use.
The first port is a local port
in your machine that you want to open,
and the second port is the port of the pod.
In this case, 3,000.
Once we enter this command, we can use our browser
on our local machine or a curl command to contact our pod.
And, we can do that on port 8081.
Port-forward is not the regular way
that you would contact an app.
It's just a way for us to contact an app locally,
because we are administrators of our Kubernetes Cluster.
The real way to contact a pod is to create a service,
so that's what we did next.
We created a service.
We defined the yml definitions,
and used kubectl create to create
the service on the Kubernetes Cluster.
And this, for example, is the yml definition for a service
for the helloworld-service that is of type LoadBalancer.
If you are on the Cloud on the ALUs on Google, on Azure,
you can use type LoadBalancer to
put a LoadBalancer in front of your service.
So, this will launch,
this will spin-up LoadBalancer on ALUs,
and then you can contact this LoadBalancer on port 80,
cause port 80 is defined here.
You just extend an HDP port on
the LoadBalancer host to contact your app.
This is the normal way to contact your app, because then,
it exposes your app to the internet.
Everyone can contact it.
LoadBalancer is not the only way to expose a service.
There's also another way to expose
a service using a node port.
If you'll just open a port that you defined
or when you don't define a node port,
it'll choose a random port, and to open that port on
every single node of your cluster, except the master node.
So that way, it doesn't create a LoadBalancer,
but it opens a port on your Kubernetes Cluster nodes,
so that you can contact your app.
This can be useful, for example,
if you're going to deploy on-prem,
where you don't have a LoadBalancer.
Then, you can use a node port.
There are different ways to contact your app.
And you will see in the next lectures, in the next sections,
different ways that you can contact your app.
These are just two ways that I just showed you.
Now you might ask yourself, "Why do we need the service
and why don't we just contact the pod directly?
Like, I mean I'll just put
a LoadBalancer in front of a pod."
Well, now we have only one pod,
but you might have more than one pod.
You might have five pods, so the service that we create
make sure that we don't LoadBalance the request over
the multiple nodes, in case that we have multiple nodes.
In Kubernetes, we'll always have pods,
and we'll always put services in front of them.
And from outside, we'll always contact the service first,
and the service will make sure that your requests
are rooted to one of the pods that you are running.
Let's say that your pod is malfunctioning.
Pod One is malfunctioning.
There are ways that you can use to debug the problem.
First of all, you can use kubectl attach
to attach to the pod to see what is happening.
You can maybe see some output that
will help you debug your problem.
You can execute a command, for example,
if you execute the command bash or sh, it will open a shell,
and you can type more commands to debug your problem.
Or, you can also use kubectl logs
to show you the logs of the pod.
Maybe there is something in the logs that can help you.
So, these commands are very helpful
to debug issues with your pod.
Then there's another possibility.
You can also launch a new pod, for example,
you can use kubectl run to launch a pod buxybox,
that is using the image busybox,
to then pull the image busybox
from Docker Hub and launches in a pod.
You will then execute the command sh in a pod,
and then that will then open a shell,
and that allows you to execute
more commands to debug a problem.
You could, for instance,
connect from this busybox pod to the Kubernetes example.
So, that's it for the recap.
I hope I made it a little bit more clear
what we tried to achieve in the first lectures.
In the next lectures, I will go into more details
on how you deploy applications on the Kubernetes,
and how the architecture of Kubernetes really looks like.