I will now be talking about ConfigMaps. Configuration parameters that are not secret, not like credentials
can be put in a ConfigMap.
The input is again a key value pair just like credentials.
You have username and password.
Here we have another key value pair.
The ConfigMap key value pair can be read by the app using environment variables again.
Also you can use container commandline arguments in the pod configuration or using volumes.
A ConfigMap can also contain full configuration files where the value is actually a configuration file
and not just a short string.
For instance a full configuration file can be a web server configuration file.
This file can then be mounted using volumes where the application expects it's config file.
This way you can inject configuration settings into containers without changing the container itself.
Just imagine that you want to use the nginx container and you of course want to change the configuration
and then you inject that configuration file as a volume in that image.
You didn't change the image at all just the confirmation file is different and you can run any container
with the configuration that you want.
To generate a ConfigMap using files where you first put your data in a file
you can use the following commands.
This command will just get the data that you write on terminal and then put it in "app.properties" until you
write the letters "EOF".
So, here we have "driver" equals "jdbc", "database" equals "Postgres",
this is a property file, key value pairs, and this file we going to read using "kubectl create configmap"
We are going to call the "app.config", and I am going to say, "--from-file=app.properties"
and then you have a ConfigMap
These is a very simple ConfigMap, where you just have very short strings.
You don't really have a configuration file, but we could also use configuration file.
And that's what I'm going to show you during the demo. How to use the configuration, so that we can create a pod that
exposes a ConfigMap that uses a volume.
Here we have a pod.
Still our "k8s-demo", still "containerPort: 3000".
We have volume months.
The name is "config-volume" and the mountPath is "/etc/config". So, we come to mount volume in "/etc/config".
The volume itself is just referring to this ConfigMap that we used earlier and then the content values
will be stored in files.
You will have, for instance, from the previous one,
"/etc/config/driver" and then the value will be in the file.
You can also use hierarchy if you would use dots in a name,
then you can have "param.with.hierarchy", then that translates into param as a directory with a
directory and hierarchy as a file with the value in.
So, you can also create hierarchy in your ConfigMap.
Here is a seam example of a pod that exposes the ConfigMap as an environment variables.
You can use, "env: name", you can say, for instance, "DRIVER",
"valueFrom", so this is exactly the same as what we did with credentials.
But then you have ConfigMap key reference rather than the reference from our credentials.
You posit a name and a key and then the value of the environment variable driver will be the value of
the ConfigMap of the key driver.
In the next demo I'm going to show you how this works.
Using a configuration file, you're going to run an nginx in front of our pod-demo.
We are basically going to run a reverse proxy and we need to update the configuration file for that.
That's why we need ConfigMap.