In this demo, I will show you
how to install Kubeless on your Kubernetes cluster
and I will show you how to create your first function.
If you go to Github dot com to Kubeless slash Kubeless
then you will end up at this page
and this is the Github product page for Kubeless
and here you can find the releases.
They have 36 releases.
Still in alpha, this is version one, alpha eight,
released nine days ago, so it will be very likely
that there will be a new version when try this out
and because they keep on releasing versions very often.
You can download your verion for MacOS.
There is a Darwin version, or for Linux or for Windows.
I'll run this on my Vagrant Box so I'm going
to use a Linux version.
So let's open the terminal.
In my Kubernetes course, I have a directory Kubeless
and in Kubeless I have readme.
All the commands that you will need in this demo
and in the next demo are listed in this readme
so you can just easily copy paste them from the readme.
This is the commands to download the Linux version,
version eight, and then we go to unzip it
and then we go to move the Kubeless binary to
user local bin so that we can execute a
Kubeless binary anywhere in our Linux system
and then we're just going to remove
bundles which was the directory
that was created by unzipping Kubeless.
So I'm going execute this first.
This will then download Kubeless, unzip it
and then put it in the correct place.
So I have now Kubeless, command works now,
Kubeless Serverless Framework for Kubernetes.
This is the command line utility.
Now we need to install Kubeless
on Kubernetes cluster.
Let's have a look again at the readme.
First, we create a new namespace
and then we can create using the YAML file
from the release we can us kubectl create
and this will create all the resources necessary.
So we have a config map.
We have deployments.
These will be created in the Kubeless namespace,
a service account, RBAC roles and then we have
the custom resource definitions, functions,
HTTP triggers and chronjobs triggers.
So these will give us this extra functionality
within the Kubernetes cluster.
To see whether it's spun up correctly,
we can do kubectl get pods of the kubeless namespace.
We have three containers in this
kubeless controller manager.
So they all look fine.
Let's have a look at the first function
that we're going to deploy.
I have a Python example here and NodeJS example.
So these should both work.
Let's just deploy those.
This is the Python function
and then you have a NodeJS function.
So what is the difference here?
You do a Kubeless function deploy,
the name of the function.
You specify the runtime.
So this runtime is python two point seven,
and here we use the runtime node js six.
From file python example example py.
This is a file that exists here on my file system
and then the handler is test dot hello.
This is the function that will be used.
With the node js example we also have dependencies.
We can use package dot json which is part of NodeJS
or we can find dependencies when they are necessary.
You also have a handler and a from file.
So you see, it's very similar whether you deploy
a Python function or a NodeJS function.
Let's have a look at both those functions.
Let's have a look at the Python example, example dot py.
We just defined a hello function, event context,
print event, return event data.
Then we have NodeJS example, example js, very similar.
This means that we are going to a export function.
This is the my function
which is a function with the arguments
event and context just like here.
You're also going to log the event
and we're going to return here hello world.
Those examples are very simple
and we can deploy them with a simple command.
The node example also has a package dot json
where we can define dependencies.
We don't have any defined here
but we could define some dependencies
if we would need some Excel libraries
within our NodeJS program.
Let's have a look, Kubeless function ls for example.
Will show us the functions that are available.
Kubeless, not kubectl, Kubeless.
So we have hello and my function in the default namespace,
handler is test dot hello, test dot my function
runtime Python, runtime NodeJS,
no dependencies and they are both ready.
So do kubectl get pods.
We then see that for every function it has spun up a pods.
We can call this function,
for example using Kubeless function call my function
which is the NodeJS function
and we can pass data to it.
This is some data and then
if you pass some data you can use
this data within your function.
In our NodeJS function we are not really
using this data so it will always just reply hello world.
So you can see here return hello world.
It also logged the event
so we can do kubectl logs of this pods's my function.
There's a pod name here and
then we'll be able to see the output here
of this console log of the event variable
and then we see here the health checks that have been done
and this is the start of the output of our event
and we see event type, time, ID, time,
namespace and here's our data.
This is some data.
This data in the event variable,
If you have a look again at the node example.
So we have here event is an object.
In this object we have data.
We could use this object data to then
do something with the data and then return something.
In the next demo I will show you how to use
some of this data with Kafka.
In this example is just going to show you hello world.
I will now just show you how to connect this
to a HTTP endpoint that will then show hello world
that will then show the output of this my function
which is in this case hello world.
So let's have another look at our readme.
We started the functions.
We listed the functions.
We called one function manually,
but now we are going to expose a function
and if you expose a function then
we can trigger it from external.
Kubeless uses the ingress functionality
in Kubernetes so we first need to launch
an ingress controller.
So if you use this ingress controller with ELB
it will launch ingress controller with
a load balancer in front of it,
so they can just go to this load balancer.
Then secondly, we need to make sure that there
is an ingress rule that is created
that will point to this function
and you can use Kubeless for that.
So Kubeless trigger HTTP create my function
the function name is my function and the host name
that we are going to use is my function dot
kubernetes new tech academy.
So let's execute this.
So here I have the nginx ingress controller with ELB.
You can have a look at the ingress lecture
if you need some more information on ingress.
I'm just going to create this nginx ingress controller.
This will then create an ingress and a service
in the ingress nginx namespace.
So we are going to do minus O wide.
This is the URL of the
load balancer so they can use,
it will then point to the ingress controller.
Let's have a look at the ingress rules.
Currently, there are no ingress rules present
because I need to first enter this Kubeless trigger command
which will create an ingress rule
that will use this my function as a backend if the
host name my function kubernetes new tech academy matches.
So I'll do that.
It's created.
You do a new kubectl get ingress
then my function will be triggered
if the host is my function kubernetes new tech academy.
I can now go to Route 53 and add this load balancer
for this host name my function kubernetes new tech academy.
So let's try that.
So I'm now logged in to my AWS account.
I'll go to Route 53.
I have one host that's on,
kubernetes new tech academy is the host that's on
and I'll create a new record set.
I will create a new record for my function
which will be of type Alias
and I can point to this ELB Classic load balancer,
which the only load balancer in my account.
I can click create and now I have
my function kubernetes new tech academy
which points to the load balancer.
My load balancer points to the ingress,
to the nginx ingress controller
and I have a ingress rule that if this host matches
then it will point to my function.
It's best to wait a couple of minutes because
it will take some time before these changes are made
and if you do it too early it might be cached
and then it's not gonna work again.
So it's better to just wait a few minutes before using it.
What happens if you go straight to the load balancer
and you don't use this host name,
then you will hit the default backend.
This is the default backend.
It's a 404 error.
So the default backend is defined
in this nginx ingress controller here.
Let's check whether the host name resolves.
This resolves to two IP addresses
and those two IP addresses should be the same
as this load balancer which is correct.
I only see one IP address here, but these IP matches.
These are two IP addresses, one for each availability zone.
So if I then curl this
my function kubernetes new tech academy
I will get hello world and
I can do the same in a browser.
So if I do curl my function kubernetes new tech academy
it will resolve to one of these IP addresses.
It will go to this load balancer here.
This load balancer will send it
to the nginx ingress controller,
nginx ingress controller has its rule.
Its rule matches and then it will go
to the backend, the my function pod
and this pod will return hello world,
it executes this function and
it will be returned to the client
which is this case was curl.
So this is how you can create a function,
a Serverless function in Kubernetes
and then create an HTTP rule for it
so that an ingress rule is created.
If you then have another look at
logs of this my function,
we will then also see that now the event is different.
It is a request and then here we have an incoming message
and from this incoming message you can get
some more information like the URL that was requested,
the method that was used because now
we are using HTTP, rather than calling
the object directly using the Kubeless commands.
So depending on how you trigger the Serverless function,
your event object will look different.
So this was here our request.
In the next demo I will show you then
how to use PubSub with Kafka.