In this demo I'm going to show you how to horizontally scale a pod with the Replication Controller.
I've just started my minikube Kubernetes cluster again.
So, if I type, "kubectl get nodes", "get pod" or "get node"
Then I can see minikube is ready
I have the YAML file in the "Kubernetes-course/Replication Controller/helloworld-repl-controller.yml"
I'm going to create this
"replicationcontroller 'helloworld-controller' created". So, let's have a look "kubectl get pods".
You can now see that this replication controller created 2 pods.
Now we have a "helloworld-controller-[randomstring]"
because a name should be unique.
And then a second one also with a unique name.
So, these ones are now creating, it needs to pull the image again, so they can take some time.
So, let's describe one of them, so we need to use now this name.
"kubeclt describe pod"
and then the name
So, this uses the replication controller and it's still the same demo.
Let's just wait a few seconds now until the image is pulled.
Now, the image has been pulled and I have the two pods running.
You can see that now a horizontally scaled my pod, I have multiple instances running.
If I have multiple nodes those instances could be running over multiple nodes and we could put a service.
In front of that, a load balancer, that will make these multiple pods accessible
to other software or customers.
If one of those pods crashes if one of those underlying nodes crashes, then the controller will automatically
reschedule the pods.
So, let me just remove one of those pods and then we're going to see that the replication controller is
just going to create a new pod.
It will see that this pod is gone and it will reschedule a new one.
So you can see here now this pod is terminating and 11 seconds ago a new pod is already running.
The controller will always make sure that the correct amount of pods is running.
I can also scale those pods just using the "kubectl" command.
I can do "kubectl scale" and I can save replicas equal to four instead of two and it can again pass the
YAML file or I can just specify the full name of this replication controller.
I'm just going to show it first with the file name.
"replicationcontroller 'helloworld-controller' scaled".
Now, you can see it is creating four pods because we did the scaling operation and under way to use
"kubectl scale"-- First let's get the name of the replicator controller, we can abbreviate this by "rc"
It is the "helloworld-controller" and we can say, "kubectl scale --replicas=1" only, maybe, 1 replica
and then we can say, "rc/helloworld-controller" and then it's going to scale it again.
So, if you do again "kubectl get pods", you will see now, three of them have been terminated and only one of them is
now running. Again, to reiterate what I said during the theory,
this you can only horizontally scale.
So, this is horizontal scaling.
You can only horizontally scale when your pod is stateless.
If you have stateful pods then you will not be able to do this.
If you want to know how to create stateless applications have a look at the 12factor app.
Have a look at my other courses. If you are really sure that you have a stateful application, you will just
have to be a little bit more patient, because I would be explaining stateful pods
later on in the course. If you want just to delete this controller, "kubectl delete  rc/helloworld-controller"
and then the controller is deleted.
And the last pod is not terminating. These scaling operations are all saved in Kubernetes itself
as a backend ETCD where it saves all those settings, like number of replicas.
You don't always need to have those in the YAML files.
It's easy to have them in YAML,
because then you'll have your state easily available to you in files.
And you can do testing and you can put those things in version control but it's not a necessity.