In this short lecture I'll be talking about
Custom Resource Definitions.
Custom resource definitions lets you extend
the Kubernetes API.
Resources are the endpoints in the Kubernetes API
that store collections of API objects.
For example, there is the built-in Deployment resource,
that you can use to deploy applications.
So I showed this one in the previous lectures,
you would create the yaml file, you would use
kind to deployment to deploy an application.
In the yaml files you describe the object,
using the Deployment resource type.
You create the object on the cluster by using kubectl.
So resource is like a Deployment resource,
you create the yaml file using the resource to describe
the object, then you put that object on the cluster
and you have, for example,
a Deployment running on the cluster.
A Custom Resource is a resource that you might add
to your cluster, it's not available on every cluster.
It's an extention of the Kubernetes API.
Custom Resources are also described in yaml files.
As an administrator you can dynamically add CRD's,
the Custom Resource Definitions,
to add extra functionality to your cluster.
Operators, explained in the next lecture,
use these CRD's to extend the Kubernetes API
with their own functionality.
So in a nutshell, anyone can create CRD's,
those CRD's you would have to add to your cluster,
and then you can use, you can create yaml files
with these Custom Resources.
So you could, for example,
rewrite a Deployment object as a Custom Resource,
then you could deploy your own Custom Deployment object
that might do something different
than the standard deployment.
And what it does different, that's all up to you
because you can write it, we are not going to write
the CRD's ourself, we are going to use operators
which are going to use those CRD's that are then going
to extend the functionality of your Kubernetes cluster
of your Kubernetes API.