In this demo, I will show you
how to do traffic routing with Istio.
I'm going to create a v2, version two,
of my hello world app.
So we still have the Istio-ingress controller,
and the Istio-ingress controller will redirect
to the version one of my hello pod,
and this hello pod will connect to world and world-2.
I'm going to add a new pod, hello (v2).
It will be a new deployment,
but the app label will be the same,
so the service for hello will route to hello and hello (v2).
The distinction between the apps
is going to be in the label version.
The first pod has version v1,
and the new pod will have version v2.
In the Istio rules, I will then have to define
some new rules to route to traffic not to both pods,
but depending on the version number,
I want to route all the traffic to the first one,
and only when it matters some specific rule,
I want to send it to hello (v2).
So in this demo, I will change the virtual service rules,
and I will say that if the host is hello.example.com,
then route it to version one.
If the host is hello.example.com
and the header end-user is equal to john,
then send it to v2.
And this is actually quite powerful
that Istio can do these advanced routing rules
because you could make your app in a way that,
if users logged in, that you pass a header or a cookie,
or something that identifies
that a specific user is logged in,
and only when this user is logged in,
then you will show the new version of the app.
That way, you can test your app on the cluster with Istio,
but no users will see it,
only this specific user is end-user john
will be able to see the new version.
So that's what I'm going to show you now.
So I have a helloworld-v2.yaml.
This is deployment.
This deployment is called hello-v2, still three replicas.
The label is still app hello,
but here, the version is v2.
This app will output hello, this is v2,
and it will add the content from world-2,
so these are the three exclamation marks.
So let's have a look at our first deployment
to see the difference.
So we have helloworld.yaml,
and here we have metadata name hello.
This is different because now we have v2,
but here we have the same app label.
The label app is hello and is version one.
So what will happen is that,
if you wouldn't use Istio,
then you would have a service that selects app hello,
so it would route it to both the earlier hello deployment
and both the new v2 deployment.
So that's not what we want.
We want to create some rules to distinguish between those,
and those rules I have in helloworld-v2-routing.yaml.
This is a kind of destination rule of the Istio API.
I will call this hello.
And I say if the destination host is
hello.default.svc.cluster.local,
so this is our hello service within our cluster,
then we're gonna have two subsets.
We're gonna have subset name v1,
and that will be routed to the pods
with the labels version v1,
and then we will have a v2,
and these will be routed to the pods with the labels v2.
I just have to update my virtual service now.
So this is the same virtual service I created earlier.
I will now overwrite it.
I'm going to specify a host, hello.example.com,
so I'll have to pass this.
Still my helloworld-gateway,
and then I will have default route here at the bottom,
so if nothing matches, then this route will be used.
So this will be the host hello.default.svc.cluster.local,
but it will use subset v1.
Then I have a matching rule here.
With this matching rule, I have headers right here, headers.
End-user, exact: john, so this header end-user is a key.
john is the value this needs to match.
If this matches, then I'll route this
to the destination hello, but subset v2.
Let's test this out.
I'll have to add my v2.yaml,
and I'll apply my helloworld-v2-routing.yaml.
I destroyed and spun up my cluster again between the demo,
so let's have another look at the service of,
at the service of Istio-system.
This is my load balancer.
So if I do curl /hello, it's not gonna work anymore.
Because I applied different routing rules,
I still have only one virtual service.
I just have overwritten it with my v2 yaml file.
So this actually gives a 404 Not Found.
If I want to reach my hello world app,
I need to pass a host name now,
so host: hello.example.com,
and then I get my hello world.
So this is the URL that normal users use.
People will get the hello world URL.
Now I want to reach v2,
and the header that I can use is end-user: john,
and if this header is set, by example,
this can be set by your login code on your website,
then I'm going to get hello, this is v2.
So this is hello, this is v2,
comes from the hello app,
and these three exclamation marks
come from still the world two app.
So this is how you can direct traffic
and put advanced routing rules within Istio
to redirect traffic to one app or the other app.