Let's set up Kubernetes locally using minikube. Minikube is a tool that makes it easy to run Kubernetes locally.
Minikube runs a single-node Kubernetes cluster inside Linux VM.
It's aimed on users, who want to test it out, or use it for development.
It cannot spin up a production cluster.
It's a one node machine with no high availability.
Now the good news, it works on Windows, Linux, and Mac OS. So, you can use it on your PC whatever you're running.
You will need visualization software installed to run minikube.
For instance, you can use Virtual Box, which is free and can be downloaded from "http://virtualbox.org".
You can download minikube from this URL, you can just copy paste from the procedure documents,
or you could just type it on from this video.
To launch a cluster you just need to enter in a shell in Linux, in a terminal on Mac OS, or in power shell, or CMD in the windows, and minikube starts.
If you are using Windows, you first have to go into the directory where you download minikube and
then you can start a minikube, with this minikube start command.
I will show you that in a demo in the next lecture.