Now that I have showed you an example of how
to do traffic routing, let's continue with this,
and let's now explore how to canary deployments.
I still have the same pods running.
The hello and hello v2 example.
And rather than using a header to identify how
to route traffic, I want to use a canary deployment.
That means that's for the host example that come,
I want to route most of the traffic to my first version.
So I'm going to give it a wait.
The first version of the deployment, the v1,
will get a 90% wait.
And the version two will get a 10% wait.
So everyone who visits helloexample.com,
most of time they will get the first version.
Only 10% will get the second version.
This way we can test our new release
and see whether it still has issues.
If there are issues only 10% of our users are impacted
and not the full 100%.
We want to run this canary deployment
for at least a couple of hours
to see whether our deployment is stable.
If it is stable, we could then deploy it
to our full population, the 100%.
Let me show you how to do this.
I still have my hello v2, worlds 2, and worlds deployed.
So I'm just going to override the virtual service
to change the waitings.
So I have this defined in my helloworld v2,
canary.yaml so in the previous lecture I used routing,
now I will us canary.yaml.
I have destination rule, this hasn't changed.
I have the virtual service, this has changed.
And I have two routes, one destination for v1,
and one destination for v2.
And I give them waits.
So the first version has wait 90,
the second version has wait ten.
So I'm just going to apply this
to route 90% to v1 and route 10% to v2.
We're gonna do kubectl apply helloworld-v2-canary.yaml
and this will reconfigure my virtual service.
Just gonna do get virtualservice.
This still has helloworld.
Let me describe this.
So my previous compilation has been overridden.
And now I have the waits.
Let me now hit this end point at least ten times
to see that I get approximately nine times v1
and then one time v2.
You can just execute curl ten times
or you can use a for loop if you are Linux or Mac
to run it ten times after each other.
I run it ten times.
You see nine times we have hello world.
And then one time you have v2.
If you have ten visitors,
there will be one visitor seeing v2.
So this is a very handy way to test your new deployments
rather than deploying them to your whole population
you can first try them out,
test them with a substitute population,
and then see if everything works fine.