One of the great features of Istio is retries.
If one of your pods stops working,
Istio can redirect traffic to another pod
without the client seeing an impact.
In this demo, I will deploy version three
of our hello world app.
Version three will be two deployments.
We'll have two pods in the first deployment
and the one pod in the second deployment.
The difference is that the pod is the second deployment
will have a pod latency of five seconds.
So the boss and arrival variable
to tell our application that it has to wait
five seconds before excluding the codes.
In our virtual service, we want a timeout of 10 seconds.
So within 10 seconds, we need to see a reply.
Otherwise, we just give up on the request.
Within those 10 seconds, we're going to retry
two times, so we're going to define two retry items
and the per retry timeout is two seconds.
So if a pod doesn't reply within two seconds,
then Istio will try using another pod.
So our pod latency is five seconds.
Our hello v3 will never make it within
this retries amount and we should only get
the request from the first two pods.
Let's try this out.
Let's have a look at hello world v3.yaml.
This is my first deployment.
Hello v3 is the name of it.
Two replicas and I'm just going to echo hello,
this is my pod name so that I know what pod
I am reaching.
This defines my pod name, so it comes from the metadata.
These will then just reply the name of the pod.
My second deployment is called hello v3 latency.
It's only one replica and it's also going to reply
hello, this is and the pod name.
But it will introduce a latency of five seconds.
This pod will still show text but only after five seconds.
We're then going to define a new destination rule
or change the current one.
We're going to add v3 to it.
We're then going to define a new virtual service.
Hello world v3 with the host hello v3 example.com.
In this hello v3, we'll write everything to the v3
version of our pods, so it's routed to the
two deployments but we are going to say here
timeout 10 seconds, retries attempts two,
and per try timeout is two seconds.
Let's apply this kube C-T-L apply hello world v3.yaml.
This will create two new deployments.
It will reconfigure our hello destination rule.
We have a look at this destination rule.
Destination rule, so we have the hello destination rule.
So describe this one.
Now we have v1, v2, and v3.
If you do get virtual service,
you'll now have a virtual service for hello world
from our previous example and now we have
the hello world v3.
Let's have a look at the pods.
These are our v3 pods, hello world v3,
v3, and v3 latency.
Let's take this end point, hello v3 example.com
is our host in this case, so this is going to
then give us the
hello, this hello v3 c5, so it's our first deployment.
And it's this pod that is replying.
We'll need to do it a couple of times
so let's use our for loop again.
Hello world v3 for the for loop and let's
also add time, so do time curl.
If you do time, then we'll see the time
that it needs to execute this curl command.
Because what's gonna happen is that if
we first hit this v3 latency, then our request
will take two seconds longer because the retry
timeout for this pod is two seconds.
And because this pod only answers after five seconds,
after two seconds, it still will retry one of those pods.
So our time should be a little bit more than
two seconds if we hit this one, but if we directly
one of these two, then it should be immediately.
So let's execute this and let's look for that result.
Here we immediately see it happening.
First of all, we never see these latency pods here.
So the only pods that can give us output
are the pods from the first deployment.
Then, if we immediately hit the first deployment,
then you see that the real time to execute
is very low.
You see here and here and here is 0.0 something.
If we hit the latency pod, then you see
that there is a two second timeout that is added.
So for two seconds, it's trying to get a reply
from this pod.
It gave up, it went to another pod,
which is a pod from the first deployment
and then this replied very fast within less than a second
and this gives us two seconds and just something
where the two seconds comes from the latency pod
and your time comes from doing the request itself
and also the execution of hello v3 and then this pod.
If we wouldn't have retry, we would always have
to wait five seconds, so I can change the retry
or I can remove the retry
to show you what would then happen.
Hello world v3.yaml.
Just remove the retry altogether, so I'll just
come at it for now.
Let's apply this again, hello world v3.yaml
and now the retry is gone.
So what are we going to see now is that
we will get the request from our latency pod
and it will not be retried but the latency
will be a lot higher.
Let's do time curl on this hello v3 host.
Hello, this is v3 and is not a latency pod.
This one's really quick.
Now I do it again and you see now we are waiting
and it is now five seconds, more than five seconds.
And the reply comes from this hello latency pod.
Using retries, you can make sure that you
regress our retries and route it to a pod
that can answer within the retry latency.
This can avoid that an end user has to wait
a long time for one pod to respond to its request.
If the pod doesn't respond, then it can be retried
using another pod that doesn't have this latency.
That is maybe not handling as many requests as
the other pod and therefore, it can respond much quicker.
So this is something very useful to implement
if your applications support it.