In this lecture,
I'll be talking about security
and mutual TLS to secure the communications
between your microservices.
The goals of Istio security are:
Security by default.
No changes are needed for
application code and infrastructure.
This is in general, in Istio
you get all the features
and you shouldn't have to change your obligation.
That is running on your cluster.
Defense in depth.
Integrate with existing security systems
to provide multiple layers of defense.
One of these layers is the mutual TLS
that I will be explaining in this lecture.
Zero-trust network.
Build security solutions on entrusted networks.
You cannot trust that your network is secure.
That's why you want to encrypt the correct communication
between your services, using mutual TLS.
Istio provides two types of authentication.
Transport authentication,
service to service authentication,
using Mutual TLS.
We also have origin authentication
and that is end to end authentication.
Verifying the end-user using a JSON Web Token.
I'll be talking more about the first one
transport authentication, service to service authentication
and were going to use Mutual TLS for that.
Mutual TLS in Istio can be turned on without having
to change the code of applications.
Because of the sidecar deployment.
Once you enable Mutual TLS the sidecars
will have TLS enabled between them.
Your traffic will be encrypted and the Mutual TLS
authentication will be enabled.
If you don't have a certificate
then you cannot reach the service anymore.
Its only Istio that can issue the certificates.
It provides each service with a strong identity.
So, once Istio starts issuing certificates
then a service has an identity.
And that identity can be verified
because a certificate with a particular name
will only belong to a particular service.
Attacks like impersonation by rerouting
DNS records will then fail.
Because a fake application can't prove its identity
using the certificate mechanism.
If you would have a fake application within your cluster
it still cannot impersonate a real service,
even though, it would manage to change
the DNS records and point it to that service.
The certificates will never match.
This rogue service will not have the certificates
that the real service has.
That's why it provides you with strong identity.
If the identity doesn't match
the communication will not work.
That's why it provides excellent security
using a strong identity.
It also secures, encrypts, service-to-service
and end-user to service communication.
That comes with it.
Istio also provides key and certification management
to manage generation, distribution, and rotation.
You don't need to manage any of those certificates.
Istio will manage that for you.
For the next example, I will show you how to activate
Mutual TLS on a cluster that doesn't
have Mutual TLS enabled yet.
I'm going to launch all these services that you see here.
We'll have namespace one and two and legacy.
The legacy namespace will just have applications
that are not deployed with a sidecar.
They are not Istio enabled.
You're going to have the hello world
and the three exclamation marks.
That are going to be executed across namespaces.
Then we have another hello world
and three exclamation marks that are being executed
but in the reverse order.
You'll have a service that starts from namespace one
and will have a service that starts from legacy.
(Mumbles) depending on where the service starts
how it will communicate once we enable Mutual TLS.
Not having a sidecar that has
a certificate will have implications.
This is what I'm going to show you in the next demo.