Let's talk a little bit about networking. The approach to networking is quite different than a default Docker set up.
In this course, I already covered container to continue communication within a pod that
goes through localhost and the port number, I covered Pod-To-Service communication, using nodePort using DNS discovery,
using the cluster IP, External-To-Service, using the load balancer, like the external
load balancer on the cloud, Ingress Controller is also an example, or just the NodePort.
In Kubernetes, the pod itself should always be routable .
This is Pod-To-Pod communications, Kubernetes assumes that pods should be able to communicate to other
pods regardless of which node they are running.
Every pod has therefore its own IP address, pods on different need to be able to communicate to each other
using those IP addresses.
This is implemented differently depending on your networking set up. On AWS: it's kubenet networking (kops default)
everybody can get an IP address that is routable using the
AWS Virtual Private Network (VPC)
The Kubernetes master allocates a "/24" subnet for each node, a "/24" consists of 254 IP addresses.
This subnet is added to the VPCs route table using the SDK.
There is a limit of 50 entries which means you cannot have more than 50 nodes in a single AWS cluster,
although AWS can raise its limit to 100, but it might have performance impact.
Not every cloud provider has VPC-technology, although Google Cloud and Azure do have something similar.
So, we can use something very similar on those cloud providers. For cloud providers or even on premise
there are alternatives available.
You can use something called content network interface (CNI).
That is a software that provides libraries and plugins for network interfaces within containers.
Popular solutions are Calico and Weave. Weave can be used stand alone, or with CNI. Or there is another solution
called an Overlay Network,
and here Flannel is an easy and popular way.
There are also other solutions that I didn't put on this  slide.
So, if you want to have a full list, have a look on the Kubernetes networking page, or just google for
CNI or an overlay network, and you get all of them.
Let me just discuss Flannel in a little bit more detail, so that you have an idea what it actually does.
So, here is a Flannel overview diagram.
The problem that Flannel tries to solve is that, let's say you use Digital Ocean, you have a public IP and get
a private IP, but it stops there.
You cannot allocate more IP addresses, but within one node you still need more IP addresses to allocate
to your pod, because your part wants to
communicate to another pod on another node.
So, basically you're going to create some fake network.
This is what they call the Overlay Network.
You can lay a network over the network you already have. So, we have two host IP addresses here
"192.168.0.2" and "192.168.0.3",
and that's how our nodes can communicate with each other.
Our pod also needs an IP address,
and here we are going to use some virtual IP address that is going to be managed by Flannel.
Flannel also uses "etcd" as a backend to store its networking information, so "10.3.1.2" the IP address of our pod of "Node 1"
is going to go to Docker0, which is the gateway, which is going to go to Flannel,
and then to the host IP,
and if you would take a look at the packet that is transmitted between Host IP 1 and Host IP 2, so the
one with ".2" and the one with ".3".
is that the packet is encapsulated, because the source destination always needs to be
the "192.169.0.2" and "192.169.0.3" IP addresses.
If you want to send a packet from point "2" to point "3", you cannot communicate
the IP addresses "10.3.1.2" or "10.3.2.2"
over this real network.
So, those are encapsulated within these packets. The encapsulated packet goes then to the Host IP final "0",
and it actually gets to a normal packet again, and goes all the way to the other pod.
So, if Flannel acts as a network gateway between the nodes, so you are going to have an overlay network,
so that you can assign each pod with a unique IP address
That is not really known by a real network.
That's it in a nutshell.
So, if you're going to deploy your Kubernetes cluster on premise, on cloud, but not AWS, Azure, or Google cloud,
then you might need Flannel. If only for Digital Ocean, you need an overlay network,
You can use a CNI like Calico or something simple like Flannel.
Often when you are using some launch scripts that are going to deploy you a Kubernetes cluster for you.
Those large groups will include the configuration for software like Flannel, but it's very good to know that
this exists and that you might have to implement it yourself,
if you're doing let's say a manual setup.