In the demo apps we built thus far in this course, whenever we changed something, so whenever our user
interface changed and for example we showed a new box or anything like that, that always happened instantly.
So we clicked somewhere and something popped up or popped into the screen
and the same of course for removing stuff,
it suddenly disappeared, it suddenly was gone.
Whilst we can of course do that and build the user interface like this and whilst the app technically
will work correctly, it often provides a better user experience
if you animate your things, if you transition between different widget states and with state here I
mean the thing you see on the UI, so if you transition between the different output so to say
and that's exactly what we'll have a look at in this section. You'll learn about different ways of animating
widgets and animating different things with widgets and we'll have a look at both custom animations
where you have more control and using some built-in animations or some built-in helpers, helper widgets
that help you with certain common transition and animation patterns that are looking good out
of the box and require only minimal or no consideration to work as intended.
So let's have a look at what we can do there.