So let's make sure we can fetch data and for that in the db helper class,
I'll add another static method which will return a future and
for now, I'll say that this will resolve to void but actually later, it will return something different
and I'll name this method get data and the name is up to you.
Now it would be nice to get the table name here
so that we know from which table to return data
and now we need to get access to the database. Now for that, we can of course copy that code which gives
us access to database but that would be a bit redundant.
So I'll add yet another method here which returns a future which eventually yields the database, database
is a type provided by the SQFLite package and I'll name this database and all that should happen
in here is in the end that I want to have my code here for creating or getting access to the database
in that database method.
Now important is just that I don't await for this open database call to complete but I simply return
it
and therefore overall here, since this returns a future which yields a database and I return this future,
here we'll yield that future thereafter.
So here, I returned that database access and now here where I need the database,
for example when we insert something, we can just call db helper, so the class name, .database. We have
to repeat the class name here because this is a static method,
so just database like this won't work because that would look for a global function outside of the class,
not inside of the class because all these static methods are not scoped to the class since these are
all static methods,
so we have to repeat dbHelper.database to get access to the database.
However, keep in mind that database here returns a future and not the database itself,
so actually we can store that in a new constant, db, with the help of the await keyboard, we get the
result of this database call which is the database in the end
and then here, we can call db.insert in the next line, just like this.
And now we can just repeat this code here in the get data method to get access to our database, turn
this into async function for that to work
and now here, we can run our command to retrieve data. Now for insert, that was the insert method, for getting
data,
that's the query method and that takes the table from which you want to fetch the data and it will then
return all the data in the table.
Now you also have methods for filtering data or for retrieving only some of the fields of the table
in case you don't need all and the official docs of the SQFLite package are the place to go
to learn more about all these different configurations,
also about updating and deleting and all these other operations you can do with the database, here
I'll focus on getting all the data. Now query unsurprisingly of course returns a future which in the
end yields us a list of maps and that makes sense because we inserted a map here in the end,
right,
data is a map and that's what we inserted,
so it makes sense that if we get all the data of a table, we get back multiple maps and therefore a list
of maps.
So here, I just want to return the result of that query as part of get data so that we can use that data
which is returned in whichever place we call get data
but of course therefore here, we don't return a future or we don't get back a future which returns nothing
in the end but we get a future which returns that lists, that list of maps.
So here, we actually return a list which itself is a generic type because it will hold multiple maps
and that again is a generic type,
so a lot of angled brackets here because in that map, we'll have a string key and then dynamic or object
but I'll go with dynamic, here dynamic data types in there,
so that's what we get back. Now we have the get data method and now we can add a new method in great places
to leverage this method. So in there, in great places in the great places class here, I'll add a new method
which in the end will yield a future which will return nothing though
and I'll name this fetch and set places and it will be an async function, so let's use that correct syntax
here and in there, I want to reach out to the db helper, get my data from there,
initialize the data here in my items list with that data and be done with that.
So here, I'll of course use the db helper and call get data for the places table which is the table I used
up there for inserting data,
so obviously you have to use the same table down there, that returns a future with that list of data
thereafter.
So here I'll get my data list by awaiting for that result and now we can transform that data list to
a list that is actually a list of places because
that's
what we need here.
Now there are various ways of doing that and one way of course is that we take our data list which is
a list, so we can call map on it to transform every element in there into a different element and call
to list in the end to get back a list and then set items equal to that mapped list.
So in map, we get every element,
so here we get our item or whatever you want to call it
and now we have to return a place object in the end.
Now a place object of course takes a couple of pieces of information. We need to set the ID but on
item, we of course will have an ID key because in our database, we will have an ID field. So the fields
we configured up there will be the keys we can now access on the data we're fetching here
and obviously therefore,
these are also the keys which you should use for inserting, so ID, title and image here because these
are the keys we configured here and these are the keys by which we can now retrieve our data. So the
ID on the ID key, the title of course unsurprisingly on the title key and the image now should be
a file and we only stored the path.
Now we'll come back to the image in a second,
the location will be null for now because we have no location at the moment.
So what about the image though? What should be stored for the image now
because I don't need the path, I need the full image instead, the file?
Well for that, we can use the file class which is provided by dart:io.
which we do import up there and before we only used this as a type but we can actually instantiate this
to create a new file
and this now simply takes path of the file which we want to create.
So here, we just pass in item and then image and that is the path to the file,
so this will create a new file based on that path and will actually load that file into memory so to
say and that's all. That should give us a list of places,
store that in items and therefore the remaining piece is that here we call notifyListeners, like this, to
inform all places in the app that are interested in the data about the newly loaded data. Now I want
to use the data here in the places list screen of course and for that in here,
in the body, we can wrap the consumer with a different widget and there, I want to use the good old future
builder because with the future builder, I can now point at a future and there, I want to use the provider
package of great places and then pass in the context and call fetch and set places because that of course
returns a future and it should,
so that's the future at which I'll point. Here,
I'll set up listen: false because I don't want to rerun the entire build method when that updates and
that is what would happen if I use provider of like this,
I only want to update the part of consumer and that's what the consumer will do automatically and besides
a future, here on the future builder, I don't need to provide a child but actually a builder argument
and there, we get a context and a snapshot of the result
our future returns and in the end here, I will then return my consumer or actually not always the consumer,
I want to check my snapshot and there, the connection state
and if that is equal to ConnectionState.waiting, so if we are waiting for the resolve,
then as before, I want to show a spinner. So I only show the consumer and the loaded data in the else
case,
otherwise I'll show a centered CircularProgressIndicator, like this. So we have the future builder, load
the data here
with that future, whilst we're waiting I load the centered progress indicator,
if we're done waiting, I use consumer here to either show the info that I have no places or to build my
places. With that, we should be able to load data from the database when we visit this first page.
So now is the time to test this all
and for that, I'll now not use my real device here anymore but instead, my Android emulator and I'll restart
the app on that.
So let's do a full restart there, full rebuild and then see whether that all works as it should.
So let's go back to this application,
got no places here initially,
of course if I do a full refresh, we can see that loading spinner again real short
I think, yes
there it was, of course accessing this local database is super fast so we don't see the loading spinner
for very long
but we also get no error which is good because that tells us that connecting to the database worked,
we just get a log that no places table was found and that makes sense because I named the table user
places here,
obviously we should also name it user places when we access it
here and here.
So make sure to do that in both the insert and the get data
call here,
so that's a tiny improvement or tiny fix
we should implement and now let's do a restart here and now we don't get that warning anymore because
now we can access the table
but of course it's empty which is why we don't see anything here.
Now let's add a new place, a test place here and take a picture,
here it is. Confirm that
and click add place now and here it is, here in the debug console, I see no error
so that's looking good
and now let's actually do a hot refresh with this green arrow here
and once this app reloads now, we should still see our data here.
So here's the spinner and here's the data again,
so it was able to store that in the database and fetch it from there and that's of course exactly what
should happen.
So with that we're taking images, we're storing the image files on our local device hard drive and we're storing
the overall data in our local device database.
Now the missing piece in the same module is that we also work with Google Maps and also with the user
location.