To make sure that the products belong to a user, the journey starts at the place where we add a product
because that is what we created initially,
that is where we should therefore store the user ID of the logged in user as part of our product data.
Now you could change your product model here in Dart, in the product.dart file to include a new user
ID value here but we don't really need
that. The userId is more something that we want to store on the server,
so it should suffice for now
if we send our data here to the server and there we add a new key which is only stored on a server, not
in our local model, which you could name userId or creator ID to make it really clear what's in
there
and that points at the userId property which we already have in the products.dart file which is set
to the user who's logged in.
So now we're also storing this on a server when a new product is created.
Let's first of all try that before we adjust the fetching logic,
so let's create a new product, some book for 29.99 here,
this is an amazing book,
let me use the image I used before,
save that and on Firebase,
now on this new book, we see a new entry,
we see the creator ID and that's the id of the user who's currently logged in.
The other two products right now have no creator ID entry but we can manually cheat one in there and for that,
let's first of all go to the authentication section and let's actually take the ID of the other
user, so simply create a second user
if you don't have a second user yet. So I take the user of the second user, the one who's currently not
logged in, the one which I just didn't use for creating that product
and now back in the database here on the products, you can click the plus button here if you hover over
a product ID and add a new key-value pair and there,
I'll add creator ID, make sure to spell it as you spell it down there and enter that ID as a value,
click add thereafter and do that on the other product too
and with that, we cheated a bit and
we made sure that the products belonged to the other user.
So we have three products,
one belongs to the second user with whom I'm currently logged in, the other two belong to the other user.
Now let's work on fetching and let's make sure we only fetch the products for the user who's logged in. For
that in fetch and set products,
we need to filter the products we're fetching and this is now a server-side task.
You do that filtering on the server-side because you don't want to fetch all products and then filter
by ID on the client,
you could do that but that would be a lot of work on the client that should rather happen on the
server, otherwise you are hitting your server, fetching hundreds of entries from the database just to
filter out one entry on the client. You would transfer loads of data would slow down your server, would
slow down your client just to get one product, that's not what you want to do.
Instead you want to make sure that the filtering happens on the server best before the database is hit
or when the database is hit and then you only get back what you really need.
Thankfully, Firebase has a built-in filtering mechanism,
the service you're using might also have that and if you're building your own back-end, you might want
to add such a service or such a capability if you need it.
So how do we tell Firebase to filter though? You can add another query parameter before or after that
token thing with an ampersand, so you only have the question mark before you add all your optional query
parameters at the end, thereafter
you separate them with ampersand symbols and there, you add orderBy, written like this with a capital
B and then between double quotes or single quotes if you used double quotes to surround your string, the
key by which you want to filter which in our case is creator ID. So here I want to filter by
creator ID and then you add another key-value pair,
so one more ampersand and then you add equalTo and these are of course special commands which Firebase
understands, you can't use them with any server,
these are Firebase specific. You set equalTo double quotes and now between the double quotes, your user
ID which you can inject with string interpolation like that but you need surrounding double quotes
around that.
Now this tells Firebase that you essentially want to filter by creator ID and only where it's equal to
your userId,
only these entries should be returned. Now important, for this to work,
you also need to change something on Firebase side, here under rules,
you need to configure a so-called index which simply is required by Firebase to optimize the way it
interacts with the database and to support such filtering.
Again, this is now Firebase specific here.
You set such an index simply here after read and write by specifying the name of the node which you want
to index and that is the products node here, then a colon and then the curly braces
and then in there, you add double quotes and then .indexOn which is a keyword understood by Firebase,
then a colon and then in an array or in a list,
so between square brackets, the fields by which you want to be able to filter in and in our case, between
double quotes,
that's just the creator ID or whatever you name the field. You can then publish that and with that, you should
be able to save all of that and now when you reload this screen, you only see one entry here
and if I refresh
and login with the other user, we should only see the two products that belong to that other user,
in my case the test@test.com, so let's login here. On the shop page, we also only see these
two,
we'll have to fix that
but under managed products too.
Now on the shop page, I of course want to see all and the fix could be that we make this method a bit more
flexible,
we could add a boolean argument, filter by user and the default here and for that, we can wrap this into
square brackets to have an optional positional argument,
the default could be false,
you don't have to set a default but you can and therefore
if this argument isn't provided and you also learn this at the beginning of the course, square brackets
around the positional argument make it optional but then you should provide a default value,
so if this is not provided, we'll have that available but it's set to false or we do pass in a value for
this argument and then we could set it to true.
Now we can use that to determine whether we want to add this or not.
So here we can actually add another runtime constant variable, filter string or whatever you want to
name it and there we check filter by user
and if that is true, then we want to set this to this string here,
so cut that,
this is then the value between single quotes, this is then the value and otherwise, we'll have an empty
string here because otherwise we'll not filter
and then here we simply inject filter string with string interpolation, the ampersand is in between the
two string interpolations here.
So with that, we should now only attach this filter string
if this is set to true. By default it's not, so on the user product screen where we want to filter by
user, we should set it to true. Now there,
here is where we call fetch and set products,
so here I want to pass in true to filter by user.
So now if you save all files and maybe do a full refresh, you should see that if you now login on the
products overview screen, you actually do see all products, so all free products in my case here but on
the managed products screen, you only see two.
So here we have three,
please note that the favorite status is also detected correctly and on managed products,
if we reload, we only have two. Now the problem is when I first visit this, we don't fetch the data and
therefore when I first visit this page, I actually see all my products.
Now that of course is also not something we want, so the solution here would be to simply also fetch
products when this page first loads.
Previously in the app, we didn't need that because we always fetch the same products in both pages,
so there was no need to fetch products when we visit the managed products page but now since we actually
want to fetch different data, we should definitely also fetch data
when we first load that. So back here since we have a stateless widget, we could convert this to a stateful
widget or use the future builder
you learned about earlier and as a side note because I just see it, we can also set listen to false here,
doesn't matter too much because we're having a listener here anyways but we can still do it to be clear
that we here only dispatch but back to the original point I had or what I wanted to do.
We can now wrap this entire page or actually at least the body with a new widget and that should be
that future builder here in the end, that future builder will of course get a builder here, not a child
and that builder is a function which receives a context and that the data
our future will resolve to or that snapshot and go back to the HTTP section if it's unclear how that
works, I showed it there and the future builder
also, besides the builder, needs a future to which it should listen or for which it should wait and that's
of course the future returned by refresh products.
So here, I can simply call _refreshProducts and here I do execute this right away because
I want to call it right when this first gets parsed, when this page gets loaded. Forward my context to
there because I need it in refresh products and we should be good.
Now this will build that and in here, we can now check if we're currently in a connection state or we're
waiting, by comparing this to the connection state enum here and checking whether this is waiting,
in which case we could return a centered CircularProgressIndicator
and only otherwise, return our main content with the refresh indicator in our list view.
Now one problem we'll have here, we've rebuilt the entire page thanks to that listener whenever
our products change
and currently that would trigger an infinite loop because here with the future builder, I'm calling refresh
products which goes ahead and fetches products, this will update the products,
this will retrigger build, this will retrigger the future builder, not what I want. It would be better if
only a part of this screen would rebuild, only the part down there
if we have new products, that's something we can do of course with the help of a consumer. So we can wrap
this padding here
with a new widget and that would be the consumer pointing at products and the consumer as you learned
also takes a builder and that builder gives you or wants a function which gets the context which gets
that products data
and maybe a child which you don't have to use though, I don't need it, so I'll just add a blank here, just
an underscore
and now with this, we have a setup where we should, thanks to the future builder, fetch data when this
first loads, when this first builds and then whenever it rebuilds but it shouldn't rebuild here, then
we either show the progress indicator or once that's done,
our main page with the surrounding refresh and indicator, there we can refresh products
and now it's really important that you have listen false here,
otherwise you will get an infinite loop I described earlier and once you refresh or once the initial
loading is done in the end thanks to that consumer, that list here will be built and rebuilt.
So let's give that a try and let's see whether it works, let me also print something here to rule out
that we have an infinite loop.
So let's do a full refresh and then login here with test@test.com and testers here login and
we go to the shop page of course.
Let's now go to managed products,
we see the loading spinner,
we see our products and we were only rebuilding once, if I refresh here,
we didn't rebuild again,
so that's great.
So this works, if I go back to the shop, we load the data there and we have three products here but only
two products there on managed products.
So this is now working as it should
and now we're making sure that we can really only work with the products we own.