Now another problem we're facing in this app is here, our little modal here where we can enter text. On smaller
screens and in landscape mode,
we can't really type here and we constantly have to close the keyboard to get to the other inputs.
Now thankfully, Flutter provides us with the tool to work around that issue and find out how much space
is occupied by that soft keyboard and actually move that entire box up by that space, so that we can
still type in there. For that,
let's go to the new transaction widget here,
the new transaction file and in that file, we can now add some padding to that container inside of our
card here
and actually we're already doing that but we can now change this to the only constructor of EdgeInsets
so we can target each side individually because there, I want to assign a default padding of 10
to all sides, left, top and right
but for bottom which is where our keyboard appears, I actually want to be more flexible and that's why
I need to control every side separately.
There, we can again use our good old media query which gives us some information about our sizing
and about our device in general as you've already learned by now
and there, we can get access to the viewInsets property and that gives us information about anything
that's lapping into our view
and typically, that's the soft keyboard and then we get a bottom property which tells us how much space
is occupied by that keyboard
and I want to adjust the bottom padding of that card by that space plus my 10 which should always be
there to lift upwards, to move up my entire input area.
So with that, if I now tap in there, you see now we have that bottom overflow problem
and that simply happens because that general modal sheet has the height it has. Now to work around that, we can
simply wrap this entire card here into a SingeChildScrollView, so that if we are in that mode where
we have some overlapping content and that should be a SingeChildScrollView, not overview, then we
can simply scroll.
So now if I tap in there, now we can scroll everything into view here and that's certainly better than
the solution we had before where this was pretty unusable.
Now you can actually go more fancy than that, the modal bottom sheet which we're using simply is restricted,
at the moment at least, such that you can't change its height like this, otherwise it would be easy to
simply ramp up its height and therefore avoid having to add that scrolling view which still might not
be optimal and you can build more elaborate solutions if you basically replace that built-in modal bottom
sheet with your own implementation
and in case you're interested, you'll find a link to the code snippet of a custom built bottom
sheet which has more set up options and which is a bit more flexible but this also is way more advanced
than what we covered thus far which is for now, this solution will do
and it shows you how you can work with a combination of SingeChildScrollView and the media query
in conjunction with the information about how much space is taken up by the bottom keyboard to still
move everything such that users can interact with your application and reach all the inputs.