That was a lot of error handling,
let me now fix that error again
and in the meantime behind the scenes, I also cleared up my Firebase storage here and I only have two
products in there which I added - a book and a shirt.
I deleted all the other dummy records we added in the meantime and now I want to fetch these products.
Now we could fetch them here on this user products page but I think the most important page to fetch
the products is the shop page,
this product overview screen here. There, when this screen loads, I went to fetch my products because the
app simply doesn't work if I can't get my products from the server there
and I always want to have my latest products there as well because whenever we reload that page, I simply
want to see what's in the shop.
So therefore here in products overview, which is that widget that renders that screen, I want to fetch
products when that screen loads.
Now how can we do that?
Well generally, initState would be a great place here.
We're having a stateful widget here anyways,
we have a state object and initState would run when this first gets rendered
and it would only run once and that's the perfect scenario for fetching data.
So here, we could absolutely use our HTTP package and due to get request and fetch the data and then store
that in our provided container, in our provided object and so on.
The only downside with that is that we don't want to have too much logic in our widget,
so putting that HTTP fetching code in this which it would technically work but it's not the
best way of doing that, we want to keep that widget lean.
So the better approach is to actually move that fetching code into our class here, into our provided class
and therefore hide it from the widget and in the widget, we can then just call a method to do the fetching.
So here in the products.dart file in the providers folder, I'll add a future which will yield nothing
in the end and I'll name it fetch and set products but the name is of course totally up to you but that's
what this method should do.
Now I want to use async await in there, hence I'll add the async keyword between the parameter list and
the function body and now in here, the goal is to reach out to that URL, hence I'll copy it because
of course the products are stored on that URL and we want to fetch the products from exactly the URL
we used for storing them and then in there, we used the HTTP package which I prefixed here, hence
http. which I use here, to fetch the products,
so here I can now use a get request. We used post for storing, for adding a product,
now I can use get for fetching a product. So here I send a get request to this URL and now
for get request, you need no extra configuration, unlike a post request, you don't have to append data,
a get request works like that.
So it justs get data and we're good.
Now since I use async here, I can await this, wait for the response and of course I'm interested in the
response because the response will contain my data.
Now this might of course fail, so we can wrap this into try catch again, to do something with that error
we might be getting here and we can of course then also throw that error again in case we get one
so that we could handle it in our widget if we wanted to do that there.
Now I'll keep that leaner here and I'll not add error handling logic in the widget, simply to not bloat this
course module too much but you learned how error handling logic would work
and you're absolutely free to experiment with that and see how you might want to handle possible errors
in this case here, I'll focus on the success case now.
So here, we're trying to get this response
and if we succeeded,
so if we have a response, let's see what's in there right and
let's see what we get this so that we can then determine how we can actually get that response data
into our list of products up there, which is of course the ultimate goal.
So right now, I'm just printing the response,
let's now make sure we call fetch and set products.
The goal is to call that from inside products overview and of course, initState would be great here.
We can use provider in here, so make sure you have provider imported,
also make sure you have your products imported,
so from the providers folder, the products.dart file because that's the class which has the method we
want to call
and then of, for the products class, context, context is available everywhere here in our state in the
end, in our state class just like widget and then call fetch and set products.
Now let's save that and do a hot refresh here and now what we actually see is that we get an error here.
We get an error here for a reason we already saw earlier in the course, in initState, all these of context
things don't work, like ModalRoute.of context, right,
That also didn't work here simply because the widget is not fully wired up with everything here.
So therefore we can't do that here,
this won't work
and otherwise it would be great if we wouldn't reach out to our provider of context here,
this would be a great solution and a great place for fetching our products.
Now there are two ways around that,
one is that you use future delayed here, which is a helper constructor, to build a new future, there you
add a duration and I'll use duration zero to basically add no delay
and then you can add a then block and in that function here, you could now actually reach out to your
provider and do that fetching, so you could do that here, know the value we're getting and you would be
fine
and even though it is technically also executes immediately because we have zero duration until this
code runs,
so this is simply a helper constructor which creates a future which executes then after this duration
passed, now this will execute immediately but technically, this is still registered as a to-do action by
Dart and we will first continue initializing the class here in the widget before it then comes back
and executes this and this will all happen immensely fast but it orders this differently than when you
directly call this code here.
So this would work but it's kind of a hack, though you can absolutely also use this approach.
The other approach is an approach we used earlier already and that is that you add the didChangeDependencies
lifecycle method Flutter knows and this will now run after the widget has been fully initialized so
to say but before build ran for the first time. It will
however, unlike initState, run more often multiple times and not just when this gets created.
So when using this approach, you should have another helper variable or property, like isInit, where
you check if you're running this for the first time basically and only execute some code if that is
true and set isInit to false thereafter, so that this never runs again and then you can put your code
for fetching products in here and then this will only run when this page first loads. So that is the
alternative, both approaches work, both are kind of work arounds but both are fine to use, use whichever
you prefer.
By the way, this future delayed syntax of course would have also worked for ModalRoute.of or for
any code which depends on this of context pattern in initState. With that,
if I now do hot refresh, this loads, I still see my dummy shorts here,
these are not the shirts from Firebase but the dummy shorts and I see instance of response and that's
of course coming from this print statement.
So with that, we're printing that. To see what's in there,
let's actually decode the body with json.decode response.body because that's the interesting
part now,
otherwise we just print the entire response object,
I'm interested in the body though.
So let's do a full refresh here and this will now reload that page and with that reloaded, here we actually
see what Firebase returns us and that's a very useful output here.