To wrap up this responsiveness part, one additional note. Whenever you're using media
query a lot like you're doing it here multiple times in the same widget tree,
it's actually recommended that you don't use it like this but that instead, you simply store
that media
query object in a variable.
So here at the start of your build method, you can simply add a new variable up here,
media query and then simply store the result of MediaQuery.of(context) in there and in all the places
below that variable where you use MediaQuery.of(context), like here in the isLandscape variable calculation
or here for defining that transaction list widget or then of course also down there where we calculate
the size of this container and then of this container, in all these places and I selected them all together
with the help of my IDE,
so in all these places, you then just want to use your media query variable. So that way, you still use
that media query but you don't recreate that object and tap into it and tap into a new object all the
time which simply costs more performance and can lead to unnecessary re-render cycles,
instead you set up one connection, get the media query data once and store that in one object and then
you reuse that object throughout your widget tree or throughout your build method here which is more
efficient and since you're in one and the same build method, this will never change whilst you're running
in that build method.
So getting the value upfront at the start of the build method makes a lot of sense
and whenever this is rebuilt because the orientation changed for example, then build will run again
and therefore, you will create a new variable with a new value.
So defining it here at the beginning makes sense
if you're using it multiple times throughout the build method. Of course as you will see, if we save this,
everything still works as before.
So it's really just a more efficient way of getting, storing and managing your media query data.