You see in the end here,
the decoded JSON gives us a map
and in that map here, we have these IDs keys and as a value for the ID key, we have another nested
map
and then here is the other ID key with its nested map and the nested map has the actual product data
where we have more key-value pairs, like description and its value or price and its value.
So we have a map with another map inside of it and that's of course useful to know because that now
allows us to transform that data.
So here we have our extracted data
so to say, you can name this however you want, which is equal to json.decode response
body and that's that map with a map inside of it.
So the type here is map, we will have string keys,
right, these cryptic things here, these are strings and then the value is another map
but actually, we can just say object or dynamic here,
otherwise Dart will give us an error here because it's basically doesn't understand this nested map
in a map structure here on that response
body object.
So this tells Dart that we have a map where the values are dynamic,
we know that the values actually are also maps but Dart would give us an error if we tell it that
this is a map.
So let's just say dynamic here and with that, we have extracted data which is definitely a map, right
here,
it's a map and hence we can call forEach on it and forEach will now execute a function on every entry
in that map,
so on that outer map,
so on every unique ID we have here. That function will get two arguments, a key and a value that's in
that map.
The key as we know is the ID of our products,
so I can also name this prodID, you can name your arguments here however you want and I think that's
clear
and the value will be our prodData, our product data.
Now I want to convert that data into product objects based on our product class because I need product
objects for my items here.
I will comment out all these dummy products here by the way
so that we now really only work with the data we're loading from the server
and with that down there, here in forEach, I want to build these product objects
now . We'll also need a new list here, a temporary list and I'll name this loaded products and initially,
it's an empty list
and to tell Dart which kind of data will be in there eventually, I'll add a type annotation,
this will be a list which eventually will hold a couple of product items,
so single product elements.
And now here in forEach, I want to add new elements to that list and I'll use add here,
you could of course also use insert
with index 0 to insert an element at the beginning instead of at the end, what add does but I'm fine
with the end and here, I want to add a new product, so I'll create a new product object and now the ID for
that product will be on prodID, right, because prodID is that key here in my map and that is just
that ID Firebase generated.
Now the other values can be taken from that inner map,
so title can be taking from prodData and prodData is simply just that map inside of the map and
there, we have a title key. So I can simply access prodData title like this to get the title and the same
for the description. There we have prodData description and the same for the price, there we have
prodData price and this should actually already be a double and not a string because we store that
as a double on Firebase. As you can see, there are no quotes around it, so Firebase recognized that this
is a number and stored it as such.
Now I also of course want to get my favorite status, so I'll also access prodData isFavorite
and of course also the imageUrl,
so here we take prodData imageUrl.
With that we're creating a brand new product,
we're doing that for every product we have in our extracted data,
we're adding that to loaded products,
so the only thing that's left to do is that after this forEach loop here, where we go through all our
extracted data, I set items equal to my loaded products
and that's also why my items up there is not final because I'm now replacing it with my new products,
so with the products I just fetched and of course important, I now call NotifyListeners to update all
places in my app that are interested in that
and one place that is definitely interested is the products overview because here, I'm kicking off the
fetching of the products, down there in the build method,
I of course listen to my products, in my products grid to be precise,
I do listen to my products.
So with that, we should have code that actually fetches our products when this loads,
so let's do a hot refresh and this refreshes and after a while, we see the products and that's of course
not too bad but it would be nice if we show some feedback to the user that tells the user that something
is happening whilst we don't see the products and for that of course, we can show a loading spinner again.
So in the products overview, we again might want to add a new property here to our state, isLoading, which
initially is false and then when we're starting to load,
so right here before we call fetch and set products, we set isLoading equal to true
and now here we shouldn't use async await here
for didChangeDependencies or for initState because these are not methods which return futures
normally and since you override the built-in methods, you shouldn't change what they return.
So using async here would change what they return because an async method always returns a future and
therefore, don't use async await here but here, I will use the old approach with then and then I have
a function which eventually executes where I don't care about the value this yields me because that
will be empty, it will be void anyways
and here I will set isLoading to false again now because here I know I'm done with fetching the products
because fetch and set products returns a future once it's done
and therefore here, I can set this back.
Now obviously, this should be set inside of set state though, so that we also update the UI with that,
otherwise we just change the property but we don't reflect that on the user interface
and now that we do rebuild the UI when this changes, we can use isLoading in the build method to show
something else.
So there for our body, instead of showing the products grid, I want to show the loading spinner if we
are loading.
So here I'll check isLoading and if we are loading, I'll again use a centered widget with the built-in
center widget and then use the built-in CircularProgressIndicator here to show that centered loading
spinner whilst we are loading and only if we are not loading, I'll show a grid. With that if I do a full refresh
here,
this app will restart.
Here it is, here's the spinner and after a while, the spinner disappears and we see the products and I
think that is now a better user experience and that now allows us to load the products.