Let's now come back to that auto login and also to the logout functionality. You just saw that I was logged
out automatically when I tried to go somewhere when my token expired and that happened because in the
main.dart file, I'm already checking isAuth to decide which home screen to render and this simply returned
false
when I tried to switch my page because the home screen is always something which is checked when you
navigate somewhere, it always checks whether you want to go to the no home screen and if it then finds
that you're going to a named route in the routes table, it will go there
but the home screen is always checked as well and that is why the AuthScreen was actually rendered.
This is not entirely the flow I want though.
I don't want to go to a different page when I try to navigate, when my token expired, I should immediately
be logged out and the auth page should pop up in my screen basically instead of waiting for me to navigate
somewhere.
In addition, I want to have a logout button here in the drawer so that I can manually logout
and then of course on the other hand, we want to make sure that when the app restarts, we actually automatically
log the user in as well.
With all that, let's go to the auth.dart file and let's add a logout method as a first step maybe.
So here, I'll add a new method which will not return anything which I'll just name logout and have a
very simple setup here. I'll basically reset the token to null, I'll reset the userId to null and I'll
also set the expiry date to null, everything is reset and thereafter we call notify listeners.
Now we can trigger that logout method from inside our side drawer. So here in the app drawer, we can add
a new entry for logging out and for that, I'll just scroll to the end,
copy that divider list tile set up here and add one more of that and here the icon I want to use is
exit to app which is this exit icon as a text, we can display logout.
And then here of course, I'll not use the navigator like that and instead here, we can simply use provider
of and
now I want to reach out to my auth class,
so therefore we need to import providers of the dart here and with that imported,
I also need the provider package to use my provider here and get access to the auth object.
So here, package/provider/provider.dart also needs to be added and with that app both added, down there I
can reach out. Don't set up a listener, I'm not interested in listening, I just want to be able to call
the logout method there to clear all my data. Let's give that a try, let's refresh and then let's login
and give logout a test run.
So here, quickly login like that,
here I am
and now let's open that drawer and let's click logout and we're back on that screen, which looks good
to me. So that's working but if you have a look at the debug console, we also get an error there and that
error here is coming from a modal scope.
Essentially the problem here is that the drawer was still open and this hard switch of widgets led us
to this error. The solution is simple,
you simply also call navigator of context pop here to close that drawer and if we do that, do a full
restart and therefore the debug console is also cleared, let's try that again,
let's login here and then open the drawer, logout and we have no error.
So that's an important change here that we close the drawer as well. With that we can logout,
now the next step is to make sure that we automatically logout if our token expires instead of waiting
for the next navigation to then accidentally logout.