So we're fetching products here on our shop page
and what about managed products now?
The good thing is, in this app, we technically can't really get to manage products without having been
to the shop page first. Since we fetch our products here and we then store them in items in our products
class here,
when we reach managed products which uses the same items, we are guaranteed to have products.
So we don't really need to fetch products when we reach this page, though of course theoretically you
could do that, here on the user products page,
you could turn this into a stateful widget as well
and then also use didChangeDependencies here or the initState hack to load products here as well
but as I said, I don't need that here
but there is one other thing which we could add here.
It would be nice to have a pull to refresh logic here where we can pull the screen down to fetch the
latest set of products or the latest values from the web and such a pull to refresh pattern is relatively
easy to implement in Flutter. All you have to do is you have to go to the widget where you want to have
that pattern,
then to your body there in the scaffold
and then here in this case around the padding, you wrap this with a new widget and that new widget here
is a refresh indicator, another widget that's built into Flutter. The refresh indicator takes a child
around which you wrap it and then you need to define an onRefresh function.
So this takes a function, a function which gets no arguments but which has to return a future
and that's important
and this function has to return a future, so that the refresh indicator widget knows when you're done
fetching data because it will show a spinner automatically in the meantime and it needs to know when to
dismiss this.
So here, you can either use a named function and point at that and actually I'll do that or use an anonymous
function
but here I'll use a named function which has to return a future which yields nothing in the end,
that's important and I'll turn this into a private function which is only available inside of this class
and I'll name this refresh products, the name is totally up to you of course
and in there, you now have to return a future. Now that can be done by turning it into an async function,
then you learned this will always return a future
but of course I want to return a meaningful future that really does something for that
and for that, we can use provider for which you need to have the provider package imported, of and then connect
it to products of context and then also called fetch and set products of course.
Now to have the context here, since I'm not in a state class here, I don't have it available everywhere,
so here I need to now get this as an input, as an argument here in the refresh product.
So now here, I can call fetch and set products and then we simply await for this to finish and therefore
this overall method will only be done once this is done
and only then this future which is automatically returned will yield, will resolve
and with that we're fetching our new product here.
So now down there, we could now point at refresh, products was the name but actually, since I
need my context there, I need to pass that in
and therefore I will wrap this in an anonymous function which reference is now stored in onRefresh
and inside of that anonymous function,
I return a call to refresh products where I can now forward the context, the context I'm getting here
in the build method automatically. That should already be everything.
If I save this, here our products are lost because due to this hot reload, our state gets cleared
but that's good actually because that allows me to demonstrate that fetching. Here I can now pull down
and you see that indicator up here here
and if you pull down long enough or far enough, you see that starts loading and as soon as the data is
there, that spinner disappears.
So that's the refresh indicator and that pull to refresh pattern which as we see is pretty easy to implement.