What about other things like the appBar or the general look of this page? By default, we have the material
design look here because what we're using here in our main.dart file, in the build method is this scaffold
widget and the scaffold widget here by default gives us a page for material design widgets.
Now there also is a Cupertino and iOS version of that and this is another good place to point at the Flutter
widget catalog again because in case you haven't noticed it yet, there also is a Cupertino iOS-style
widgets section and that gives you an overview of all the widgets that are built into Flutter that have
that Cupertino look and which you can use in conjunction with that platform is check to render either
the Cupertino widget or the default material widget
and for example here we have the CupertinoPageScaffold and that's pretty interesting here.
Instead of that scaffold, we could render the different one by again using Platform.isIOS
and if that is not true,
so in the else case after the colon, I'll use the material design scaffold, otherwise I'll use
the CupertinoPageScaffold which is kind of the replacement for that. Now important, to use any Cupertino
widgets, you need to add an import to package:flutter/cupertino.dart just as we used material.dart
before,
now in addition to that and I say in addition because we still use a couple of features from the material.dart
package because it contains more than just material styled widgets
but in addition to that, you now also need to import the cupertino.dart file. It has less options
than the material design scaffold but it allows us to define a body which here is named child,
that's a bit of an inconsistency which unfortunately or deliberately, I don't know but which was introduced
but this is essentially what you have in body and then you can set the background color of the page,
you can also add a navigation bar
So here, the body of course should be the same,
so I'll actually grab the entire body content, this entire SingeChildScrollView and cut it out of
there and store it in a new variable, again so that I can reuse it.
So here, I'll have a page
body variable, you can name it whatever you want,
the value is our page body
and now I can enter this here as a body for scaffold but also as a child for CupertinoPageScaffold
because the thing which I change or which I want to change here is not the page body but actually, the
navigation bar. There, instead of appBar, I want to use a specific appBar for Cupertino because here,
we actually can use the CupertinoNavigationBar.
However, it's best if I don't add it here but if I do add it up there where I already created that appBar
variable to now again check the platform,
so if platform is iOS, I want to render something different and only render the appBar if I'm on Android
and here, I want to use my CupertinoNavigationBar and that means that the appBar variable now holds
either the CupertinoNavigationBar or the material appBar and hence I can use appBar down there in my
CupertinoPageScaffold, just as well as in the scaffold down here and I'm doing this because I use my preferred
size here and that actually is taken from the appBar and of course, I want to calculate the preferred
size for both my CupertinoNavigationBar as well as for this appBar. Now small problem we have here though
is that I'm getting an error that preferred size is not defined on widget. The reason for that is actually
that appBar is inferred to be of type widget here. Now that simply happens because Dart is not able to find
out that CupertinoNavigationBar and appBar both have a preferred size property but actually, if we
add a dot here after CupertinoNavigationBar, we see there is a preferred size property. So this also,
if we click on it, is in the end implementing some kind of preferred size widget. So we should tell
Dart that this is the case by adding the type here
and that's one of the cases where it makes sense to explicitly set the type
if you know what the type is
but Dart can't find out and set this to preferred size widget, like this.
Now you get rid of these type errors down there because you know hey this will be available at a point
of time Dart is not able to find out.
So with that, we now have a setup where we render a different navigation bar,
of course we now also want to set a title,
however not with a title property here but here instead, you target the middle property and space control
is your friend here to find out what you can set on the CupertinoNavigationBar. Middle here takes
a widget just like title does,
it's just a different name.
Again, some inconsistency here but you can set your text there.
Now of course, you typically also want to add some actions here, though here you have no actions property
but instead you'll have a trailing property to add some content at the end of the bar and that could
be a row with your actions
and now here important, IconButton also would be a material icon
and if you try to use that in a CupertinoNavigationBar, you would get an error
and now when you save that though, you'll get an error
where we see that an IconButton widget requires a material widget ancestor.
The problem here in the end is that we added an IconButton widget which is defined for material
design inside of our CupertinoNavigationBar, inside
in the end of our CupertinoPageScaffold and as the error message tells us, material widgets and the
IconButton is one of them
look for some parent widgets somewhere which implements material design and that's missing here. Now since
at the point of time I'm recording this,
there is no Cupertino IconButton,
one thing we can do here is we can build our own button. We can add a GestureDetector where I wire up
onTap to start add new transactions, so to the same code I had down there for onPressed, like this
and where the child then is our custom button content and our child here can be an icon widget which
is not a material design limited icon and now we could use icons add but actually to have that full
iOS look, we might want to use CupertinoIcons which exists at.
So that's a collection of CupertinoIcons
and again just as with material icons with a dot here, you can go through them and find out which icons
are included,
unfortunately without a visual preview, at least for now but still with a short description and it's a
pretty good list,
pretty good mix of CupertinoIcons. With that if we save that and we restart our application here, we
now have that plus icon up there and it also opens that modal. Now what's clearly missing however is
that title, the middle here and that happens because I used a row here and by default, trailing has no
boundaries in how big it may be and therefore row is pretty large. That's fairly easy to fix though, on
the row here in our trailing part of the CupertinoNavigationBar, there's one extra property you can
set on row and column which I haven't shown you before but which is really useful now
and that's the MainAxisSize. By default, it takes all the width it can get as a row and column takes
all the height it can get. You can restrict this and set it to MainAxisSize.min.
So MainAxisSize here really is just an enum with a max and a min value,
the default is max but if you set it to min, the row will shrink along its main axis,
so from left to right, to be only as big as its children need to be and therefore now, we have the plus
icon and our text here
and as you can tell of course, this is now the default iOS look and it's not that purple appBar we would
normally have.
Now as you also can tell however is that now, that's not really looking that good, the chart is now below
our navigation bar.
So somehow, this calculation of the navigation bar height is not working out correctly.