To have a text and below the text, a couple of buttons, we now need an invisible, a layout widget
and there we can use the column widget. Column, as the name suggests, is there to render widgets in a column
because the difference to text and so on is that this has a children named argument which actually takes
a list of widgets.
Now there are a couple of new things,
this thing here between the angled brackets, that's new and the square brackets here are also new.
What does this all mean?
Let's start with the square brackets, Dart
like many other programming languages, has the concept of lists.
Thus far we learned about strings, about integers, doubles and objects and everything is an object in the end.
Now lists are another type of data,
a list is basically a group of data,
so you can have a list of strings, for example here we could add a variable, questions and that could now
be a list of text, the list of text questions, like what is your favorite color. By the way, if you would
want to write what's here and you use single quotes to enclose the string, then this single quote would
quit the string which is an error and you can escape this by adding a backwards slash in front of
this.
Now what happens is that this single quote here is not treated as a quote that ends string but instead
as the quote character that should be part of this string,
so that backward slash in front of it achieves that.
So now we would have a question, what's your favorite color
and also
what's
your favorite animal for example. Let's also add a trailing comma here
and now questions actually would be a list of string data.
Now the idea behind lists is simply that we can group related data together because in so many scenarios
of programming but also in real life actually, you work with lists of data. You have, on your phone, on your
real phone
if we take a real life example, you have a list of contacts, your friends,
that's a list of persons, a list of people and therefore lists are also something that exists in programming.
and basically in any programming language you can find
and of course also in Dart therefore. Lists are created with square brackets,
that's also what I did up here,
I created it with square brackets and therefore, lists are also created down there where we have
a list of widgets and that's the angled bracket widget thing.
This is a so-called generic type and so a little annotation, which we could also drop here because of
type inference,
this tells Dart that this list here will hold a list of widgets because a list can of course hold
anything.
This for example is a list of strings,
if I hover over questions, we see that Dart was able to automatically infer this list and then again
this angled bracket thing but here with string. A generic type is basically an annotation which you
can have on some types that allow Dart to understand that this is not just a list but a list of a specific
data type
here for example and it's the same thing down there,
this is a list of widgets. Now because of type inference, we can remove that as soon as we start adding
widgets here and there,
I would want to have my text widget with the question and I'll add some real text soon and below
that, a couple of buttons.
Now there are different kinds of buttons in Flutter,
one of them is the RaisedButton which is a button with a background color and the little hover effect.
Now the RaisedButton here is again a widget which we create by instantiating our class here
and it typically has a child, which is basically the content inside of the button, that could be
an image, that could be an icon but often, it's also just some text,
so the text which is displayed on the button. Again, this is a widget, not just some string,
the child here is a widget instead
and therefore here, we could have answer 1 and then I can copy that line and add it again
so that we also have answer 2 and maybe also answer 3. Now each button, besides having a child
also needs an onPressed argument and onPressed will be a function that should be executed when
this button is pressed. For the moment, since we haven't really learned how to wire that up, let's
add null here. Null is a special value in Dart, it basically means nothing,
the difference to void is that void is a type,
so here we say the type of data main returns is empty, is nothing and null is not a type but a concrete
value, just like one is a value,
the number one or like this here is a value, null is a value which says nothing but we need to add that
to avoid errors.
So here, I add onPressed to all my buttons and for all buttons, I then add null. And with that, again I hit my
code formatting shortcut so that this gets formatted in a bit of a nicer way. And again, if we add trailing
commas like here, after null in my first button, then this gets formatted in a bit of a more readable
way.
So now I added my column widget, which has a couple of child widgets where we have the text widget and
then the RaisedButton and if we save that, now we see our text up here and then we see the three buttons
and they are currently all disabled because onPressed is null and that means if we press this button
right now, nothing happens and Flutter automatically detects this and then disables the button, which
sometimes can be nice if you have a user input form where you gather the email address and the password
of the user, then you would want to disable the button as long as nothing valid has been entered, here
however of course, I want to enable them. And for that, we have to understand how we wire up the button
here to some function that does something or how we make sure that something happens when the buttons
is tapped.
Of course, we can also improve the styling and how this is laid out here on the screen but we'll
do this in a second step,
for now it was important to understand how we can have more than one widget next to each other with
the help of column for ordering widgets from top to bottom.
If we would want to have them sit next to each other left to right, you would have used row instead
but we'll see column and row and all these other invisible and visible widgets throughout the course.