So just as before in earlier sections, let's plan the app we're about to build in this module.
Now the app we'll be building will not be too complex, it won't have too many widgets because I really want
to focus on these native device features. So we will have one screen of course where in the end, I want
to output a list of places because the entire app we'll build in this module
will be all about managing great places we found.
Now what makes up a place? A place should be defined as basically a title but then most importantly, an
image and also, the location, a snapshot on the map
so to say. So in this list of places, we'll have a couple of list elements of course,
let's say here with an image preview of the image we took, here of the title and then here of the
address of the place so that we have all that here.
Of course we can tap such an item here to be taken to a detail screen where we maybe also show the
image, also show the title and the address and also give the user a show on map button here,
something like that which simply opens up a full screen map where we can then see the place on, something
like that.
So this is the idea here for the detail section,
of course we also need to be able to add places and for that here of course, we'll have a plus icon in
our appBar which takes us to a brand new screen of course
and on this screen here, we have a title input, not too fancy,
that's of course something we saw before but then, we'll have an image preview and next to that, a button,
take picture, maybe a bit more beautiful than here but we'll have such a button next to this preview
here and we'll also have a preview of the map snapshot or of the part of the map that shows our place
because we'll have two buttons here where we have a pick place button which allows us to pick a place
on the map that opens and a user location button which will auto-locate the user and take that location
as the place then,
so two different ways of choosing a place.
Now the app will be a bit more beautiful than what I drew here but in the end, we'll learn or you'll
learn how to work with the camera and with maps and what you don't directly see here, of course we'll
also store the data,
so the images are stored on the file system of our device for example so that they survive reloads of
the app and our place data in general, that will be stored in a SQL database, SQLite database
here on our device so that all the data is stored on the device and not on a web service.
I showed you how to send data to a web service, how to make HTTP requests,
now we'll focus entirely on working with on device features.
So let's dive in.