To receive our transactions in the transaction list file in the transaction list widget here, we can
first of all add a new final property here which is a list of transactions,
so this doesn't change, which I'll name transactions, of course you can use a different name here.
So we have that final list of transactions and that should be set
with the help of the constructor now because the constructor is how we can pass data from the parent
widget into a child widget, so into this widget here. For that, I'll use the shortcut and expect to get
the transactions as my first and only positional argument.
So now incoming transactions are saved here and instead of _userTransactions, we again now use
just transactions here, referring to this list. Now in user transactions where I do instantiate that transaction
list widget,
we now have to pass our list of transactions and that here simply is _userTransactions.
So thus far, we just did a lot of reorganization without actually getting closer to the point where we
can add a new transaction
but this will change now.
Now in the user transaction file where we manage our list of transactions, we can add a new method, a method
that doesn't need to return anything and therefore will have a return tab of void and which I will
then name add new transaction.
The name is up to you, though it should start with an underscore to mark this as part or as private and
as part of that private class here. In here,
I expect to get two pieces of information, I expect to get my title which will be a string and I expect
to get my amount which actually should not be a string but a double let's say. So here I get my title
and my amount and I then want to create a new transaction here. So I'll create a new variable which
I'll call newTx maybe, it's final because here I create it with the values that are passed into this
method,
so it is create based on values which I don't know at the point of time I'm writing the code,
hence const can't be used here but I can use final because once that transaction has been created with
these dynamic values, it will not change again.
So here, I will create a new transaction by using the transaction constructor and for my title, I pass
the title. Now to avoid confusion,
I'll name this txTitle here, you don't have to rename it, you can use the same argument name here as
you expect here but to avoid confusion on what's what,
txTitle is what I pass as a value because I get it here as an input to this method and I pass this
as a value for the named title argument on my transaction constructor. For the amount argument, I pass
txAmount. Again
you could have named txTitle just title and txAmount just amount, that would have been okay.
Now we also need to pass an ID and a date. For the moment, we have no way of selecting the date,
we have no date picker
the user could use,
so why don't we again use datetime now to use the current date? And now for the ID,
I want to have a value which is kind of generated automatically and unique and therefore I'll also use
datetime
now to string here.
It's not perfectly unique,
theoretically we could add two transactions at the exact same timestamp
but here for this app, it will do for now
and it will be a string
and it is generated automatically so we can treat this as a kind of unique ID for now.
This is the new transaction
and this new transaction should now be added to the user transactions list.
For that, since I also want to update the user interface because build should run again to rebuild our
transaction list and then also rebuild new transaction, that's the side effect, since I want to update
that,
I have to call set state now which I can call because we're inside of a state class, extending state,
so we can call set state in here and inside of that function you pass to set state,
I will use my user transactions which is that property up here and now, I want to add a new transaction.
Now of course, that is marked as final
but remember what I explained earlier when we talked about final and const? I mentioned that Dart stores
objects in memory and only stores the pointer at these objects, the address in your variables.
So _userTransactions holds a pointer at this list, the pointer, the address itself is final,
we can't do user transactions equals something, that would not be allowed because then we would try to
assign a new value to user transactions and user transactions is a final variable.
What we can do however is we can interact with that list because that doesn't change the pointer,
the object stays the same,
we just manipulate the object and that can be done with the help of add. Add is a method we can call on
a list to add a new element to that list, so that will change the existing list but it will not generate
a new pointer or a new address and therefore we don't violate this being final,
we just added the object that's stored in this final variable.
So here, I add a value and that value of course is my new transaction.
Now thanks to set state, that should be reflected on the user interface and a new transaction should
be added to our list. To now see that all come together,
let's go back to the main.dart file and there,
let's now add our user transactions widget, on which we worked, below our chart container here and for that,
as always, you need to add an import which should be ./widgets/user_transaction.dart, then that's
added here below the container.
Now last but not least, we have to make sure that when a user now presses this button, the add transaction
but we don't just print the text of that transaction but that we actually trigger that add transaction,
that add new transaction function in user transactions.
Here's your chance to wire that up on your own,
we'll of course do it together in the next lecture.