For this application, I again have a brand new application which is pretty empty, which you find attached
to this main.dart file,
that's what you find attached,
you can simply drag and drop this into a brand new Flutter project.
I haven't set up anything here and this main.dart file is pretty lean,
it only has the MyApp stateless widget and the MyHomePage
stateless widget which just shows some center text here.
Now this is our starting point and of course, there are many places where we could start in this app.
We could start with the feature of adding products, so that users can add new products. That would make
sense because without products, there is little we can display.
However, I will start with the ProductsOverviewScreen instead and simply start with some dummy products
and then later we'll replace that with products that we actually added ourselves with the
add a new product screen in the app.
Now what we'll definitely need is a couple of different screens and also normal widgets and therefore
I will already create a screens subfolder and a widgets subfolder here and that's simply something
we did before
in an earlier module, it allows us to keep our files more organized and understand what's inside our
files. Now in the screens folder here,
we can add a new file to hold a new widget and that should be the products_overview_screen.dart
file because in there, I want to create a products overview widget which is the widget
that should present that grid of products we have in our application
and that's simply my choice here to start with this
widget because I think that's one of the easiest ways of getting something useful onto the
screen which then soon also allows us to dive into state management. For the moment, let's start with
a stateless widget in there,
create a new stateless widget which I'll name ProductsOverviewScreen and as before, of course we need
to import material.dart from the Flutter package here to unlock stateless widget, build context widget
container, all these types and classes.
Now in the ProductsOverviewScreen, I want to render a grid of products and therefore, we need two things,
we need products and we need the grid. Now a product in this application will be of course an important
model, an important thing and therefore I'll create a new folder, models
and in there, I want to have a product.dart file to define how a product should look like in this
application, so that we can build products based on this definition which simply helps us then use
this product in a uniform way throughout our application.
So in there, we can define a product class
and it's again a normal class, not a widget, it's just a class because I just want to use this as a blueprint
to create objects based on and how could a product look like?
Now of course, you are free to structure and model this in whichever way you want it
but for this application, a product definitely should have an ID and I'll mark this as final for now
because I expect to get that ID when the product is created. Later down in the course for example, we'll
get that ID because we'll create a product on a server and then we'll store that server-side generated
product here in our application. So we'll have that ID when we create the product,
we also probably will have a title and I think a description also makes sense on a product and other
than that, probably also a price right
which should be of type double, to allow for decimal places too
and also an imageUrl, again here
I'll have an image which is stored on a server which we then display in the application.
We don't store it as an asset that's baked into our application bundle because if we would do that, then
we would have to ship a new app version with every new product that was added and then that's of course
not feasible at all.
So we'll have a network image here and there is one last field which I want to have and that's a boolean,
isFavorite and this is not final because this actually will be changeable after the product has been
created and it allows us to track whether the user of this application has this product as a favorite
product or not and later, we'll still be able to save different favorite statuses for different users
of our app
but that's simply something we'll worry about later,
for now we just have this changeable, this mutable boolean property here, isFavorite, in this app.
Now we need a constructor to initialize a product,
so let's repeat the class name here to add such a constructor and as always, it's up to you whether you
want to use named or positional arguments.
Since we have a couple of arguments here, I think it's easier to work with this class if we use named
arguments, so I'll use curly braces here around my argument list to add these arguments as named arguments
and then I want to be able to set the ID, I want to be able to set the title, the description, the price
and the imageUrl
and of course, also isFavorite.
Now there are a couple of fields, a couple of properties which I want to mark as required so that we
can't create a product without them
and for that, we can use the required decorator which we can import from the Flutter package and there,
the foundation.dart file. With this import added at the top
here, we can add required in front of the ID because that ID will be required, in front of the title,
in front of the description, the price and the imageUrl but isFavorite is not necessarily required.
We can simply initialize that with a default value of false by assigning a default value here. With that,
the product class is finished,
looks quite good to me
and with it, we can move back to the product overview widget to start our work on the products overview
grid.