There are a couple of core phases when it comes to building an app.
Now of course, this here now is just my view, it's not the single correct way of building an app but it
is a way that worked for me and that I think makes a lot of sense. When you're building an app,
the first phase always is the idea phase.
Now maybe you already have an idea
but even then as you will see, I'll dive deeper into this in a second,
you'll have to check a couple of things to ensure that you're really building an app that your users
want.
The next step is the planning phase,
you got an idea,
now it's time to plan the app, plan some general things but also sketch the app and model your data.
These are crucial parts, sketching the app means that you decide which screens you want to have, which
main widgets you'll need
and that you also come up with a design idea for colors and fonts and images you want to use and modelling
the app means that you plan which kind of data your app will use,
that also is important because you'll have to decide whether you need to store that on a database,
how that data should look like, how it should flow through your application and so on.
Once all of that planning is done, it's of course time to develop
and typically, that will be the largest chunk of the time you allocate to this of course. You write your
code and that's an iterative process, which means no matter how well you planned it, you will probably
change some things there,
you will write code and then you always should test it
and based on your testing results, you will change code, fix bugs, add new features, maybe implement something
differently than you planned it because during testing, you'll find out that you're not liking it.
So this here, developing and testing, that's a super important part obviously.
Now once you're done with that, it's time to optimize your app and
with that I mean that you explore optimization strategies,
so scan your code for possibilities of improving it, for example by extracting widgets, by using const
constructors, things I covered in this course and also beyond that, things which you'll learn about in
the official docs and other blog posts,
certain patterns other developers are sharing, things like that, of course always test your optimizations
though to make sure you're not breaking the app and they really have an impact.
Then it's time to publish the app and that also involves a couple of things, it's not just a technical
process of publishing as you will learn
and last but not least, maintenance.
Once your app is published, you're not done,
now you need to listen to user feedback, improve the app, release patches and so on.
Now let's have a closer look at all these phases therefore. The idea and planning phase is kind of combined,
there you should decide what you want to build.
Now maybe you already have an idea but then you should still check what the market is,
which competitors do you have?
What are other apps doing?
What could your app do better?
Who are your users?
What are your users expecting?
What's their budget?
Where do they live?
Because all these things influence the app you want to build.
It influences how you monetize it,
if you plan on monetizing it, the region where your users live
also influences whether you want to localize your app, how important the size of the app is, how
fast the mobile phones or the
devices your app will run on will probably be.
So plan all of that carefully because it's super important that you build the app for your audience
and not an app just for your own personal phone.
Also decide on the core features you want or you need to offer based on the market and the audience
you're targeting and more.
These are the core questions you should answer and on Google again, you can find a lot of discussions
there, a lot of resources that help you do that planning and there is not a single right path.
It always is something that takes some experience and where you might need to check something for app
A but not for app B
but these are some rough thoughts you should definitely have.
Now thereafter, it's time to sketch your application and
that means that you should sign it,
build a wireframe model, which means that's kind of a technical layout, it's not so much about colors
and fonts, it's more about which screens do you have,
how are they connected,
what are your main widgets and so on.
But all of course work on the design and the graphics, the look and feel of your app - Which colors do
you want to use? Which fonts? Which font sizes? Which images?
How should the app be structured? And sketch the screens and the main widgets of your app
so that you have an idea of how the screen should look like, which are the core widgets you will need to
build and how all of these are connected. Also consider the navigation,
so how users get around in your app and how data should flow through your app, which data you need on
which screen and that's of course tightly connected to the data modeling phase then. What are your main
data models?
Do you have products, users, shopping carts, orders, whatever it is,
think about that and think about the structure of these models, which fields, which properties do you
need in there? Plan your main classes and properties and methods
you want to have and how you want to interact between these models.
So think about data dependencies, dependencies between your data and also data sources,
where is your data coming from?
Do you want to store it in a database?
Which data do you want to store? All of it or just some data?
Which structure should it have in the database?
Which kind of database? Do you use your own REST API backend or do you use a service like Firebase?
These are all the things you have to answer here
so that your app, if it needs it, also uses a backend that suits your needs
and of course even if you need no backend, you will still probably work with some data on your app and
you should make sure that you have an idea of how that data is structured.
Now you can certainly also plan all of that perfectly and that really depends on your nature, what you
personally prefer and also if you're working in a bigger team and on a bigger app maybe. If you're
working on your own project alone, you probably need to do less planning because you can often switch
strategies and spontaneously implement something. If you're working in a bigger team, more planning needs
to be done but then you typically also don't do all the planning alone.
Still, even if you're working alone, you should have a rough idea,
it's absolutely okay if things changed thereafter but you should have a basic plan.
Well and then you can enter the developing phase. There you need to implement your planned layout, your widgets,
your screens, navigation, your data models, all of that but also as I mentioned, deviate from the plan,
it's absolutely normal to do so. When I plan applications,
I have nice plans but then when I start working on it, I decide that something would look better if I
would build it like this or that this data should actually be connected to some other data
even though I didn't plan that initially. So definitely deviate, your plan should be something to build
up on, not the final structure you absolutely have to adhere to.
Also consider creating a prototype
first, a dirty first version, a version which works, which has all the core features but which maybe is
ugly or not battle tested which still might have bugs and then improve your app
step-by-step.
The cool thing about development is that you can always work on your code, so you don't need to think
about every single widget for five days and then write the code once and you may never change it,
start writing code and improve it over time because that will make sure that you get something on the
screen,
you stay motivated and you find bugs faster actually
and that of course goes hand-in-hand with the testing phase,
that's not a phase after development but whilst you're developing. Test your code manually and on different
devices and certainly test it whenever you change something big.
Test it on different devices, different emulators, real devices and emulators
and as many devices of different screen sizes and performance as possible, also explore automated tests.
I didn't cover them here but automated tests are basically tests where you write code which then runs
to test your code.
That can sound strange and it doesn't replace manual testing but it can help you,
It is simply a way of quickly running a bunch of tests which you have pre-written whenever you change
something to quickly evaluate if that change breaks something immediately.
The official docs get you started with that automated testing and it's certainly something you should
dive into once you're a bit more advanced and you're feeling good writing Flutter applications.
Now we enter the publishing phase,
we're done with the app, we're happy with it,
we also optimized it,
I left that out here, goes hand in hand with testing but as I mentioned before, optimize your app, so make
sure you're following best practices, you're using const constructors, you're splitting your app and
widgets,
you're making sure that build doesn't run too often and so on, so do all that optimization and then you
can start publishing.
That means that you should add icons and make your splash screens look good, that you want to polish your
app so again do some final testing, some final optimizations, make sure that the app is fun to use and
it looks good and then set up the store page in the Google Play store or the Apple App Store and that
will take a lot of work.
You need to add images there that make people want your app, you need to add description text that
really make your app look good.
It's like a shelf in your supermarket,
you want your product, your app, to look attractive,
so definitely put a lot of work into that.
It's too easy to be exhausted by the development time and then you just quickly throw some images in there
and quickly add some text.
That's bad because if your app doesn't look great in the stores, people might not use it,
so definitely spend time on that.
Also again, think about your audience when you set up the store pages.
What does your audience want to hear?
Who is your audience?
How do you best target them with images and texts you use there? Now and after publishing as mentioned,
you enter the maintenance phase. Listen to user feedback and improve your app, fix bugs and fix them
quickly and transparently. Communicate with your users, have clear and understandable patch notes where
people understand what you changed, why you changed it and that they get a feeling that you're caring
and that you're working on fixing issues quickly and that you're maybe also adding new features people
are requesting and keep an eye on analytics and potential crashes which are reported to you, for example
through the basic App Store analytics or also with dedicated analytics packages which you can pack into
your app.
Now there are a lot of concepts in here which will make more and more sense the more advanced you are
and they are easier to use if you're more advanced,
I'm just throwing some thoughts out there which hopefully helps you build amazing apps
and if you have an amazing app, don't hesitate to share it with me, share it with us here,
I'm super interested in seeing what you're building.