So back in the project we worked on over the last modules and attached you find that snapshot in case
you didn't follow along or you just want to make sure you're using the same version I'm using, this is the
shop we build in the last modules and there we can view our details,
we can place orders
and the problem with the orders for example is that right now whilst they are replaced and whilst we can
fetch them,
they're anonymous or our user is anonymous.
So these orders here don't belong to a specific user and that's one of the problems we'll solve
and in addition in general, a shop app only really makes sense if we have a user.
So therefore, we'll make sure that we can login and sign up
and that requires two things. In our app here,
it requires an authentication screen which shows us this login sign up form and on Firebase, it
will also have to tune something. There,
there are two things you have to set up -
the first thing is that we need to lock down our database.
Right now it's open to everyone
and that was good for the last module
but now that we'll add authentication,
we want to lock down that database to only allow access by authenticated users
and you do that by going to the rules tab here in your database section on Firebase and there instead
of having read and write access set to true, which means everyone can read and write,
you should set this to a string where you say auth unequal to null and do the same for writing
and that's a special syntax which is understood by Firebase which basically tells Firebase if the user
is not authenticated, then the user does not have read or write access.
You have to publish these rules thereafter and the warning you were getting here about these rules not
being secure actually just means whilst the API is now locked down, as soon as you are authenticated,
you can actually read and write all data,
so even orders that don't belong to you specifically as a user.
This is fine for this demo because if we would want to change this, we'd have to dive deeper into how
to configure Firebase rules,
that has nothing to do with Flutter though and it also won't help you if you're using a different back-end.
In case you plan on using Firebase however, you'll find some resources attached, some links to the official
docs that help you with understanding the rules so that you could configure them in more detail.
These rules will do for us and what they will do is they ensure that unauthenticated access is not possible
and I can prove that if I go back and I load the shop page, now we have a spinner which won't stop and
because I haven't added error handling here, we're also not seeing some error message,
you could of course implement that to show some error text or anything like that,
this fails now because here we're getting an error because now basically that HTTP request doesn't succeed,
we get back an error response because the API is locked down and currently we are not logged in,
so this works as intended.
Now we need to change one more thing on Firebase and that's here under authentication,
you need to set up a sign in method.
So there, you need to unlock e-mail password sign in because that will allow us to create users with an
e-mail password combination and then also log users in with that combination.
So once this is enabled, we can continue with the steps we'll implement throughout this module to sign users
up and sign users in and get that token by Firebase.
So for now, our Firebase work is done and we can go back to Flutter.