Now let's say our code is finished and we're happy with the code,
now it's time to finalize our metadata so to say, let's start with Android.
There in the app folder, in the src folder, you have your AndroidManifest. In there, you set the
Android label for example and that's the name of the app which users see on their home screen or in
the app drawer.
So for example, I will name this great places and you can pick any name you want here,
this is what your user sees,
so pick a nice name here.
This Android name here is nothing you should change,
that's an internal identifier.
Now another thing you want to make sure in the AndroidManifest is that you're setting the right permissions,
I showed this throughout this course. Certain packages need certain permissions, for example when we're working
with the user location, we need to get the permission to get the user location.
Now there's one tricky permission actually in Flutter apps, you might notice that in your app src
folder, in the Android folder, you also have a debug folder with another AndroidManifest file.
Now this is a very short file which has only one permission,
the internet permission. In the end, this file is merged with your main AndroidManifest file automatically
by Flutter whilst you are working on your app in development mode.
The Internet permission is required by Flutter to talk to your development server which is running on
your machine
and that's in the end
the setup that enables this hot reloading, hot refresh stuff that's all managed through behind the scenes
internet connection between your app and your machine so to say.
That's why every Flutter app needs the Internet permission during development but not necessarily in
production.
If your app does need internet access in production and for example this app does need it because we
have that location helper where we're sending a HTTP request,
if your app needs that, you need to copy that permission line from the AndroidManifest in the debug
folder into your main AndroidManifest,
so here, right next to the location permission,
otherwise your app will work during development but not after you published it or once you build it for
production,
so really make sure you're setting this up correctly.
You can also change your package identifier here.
The idea behind this identifier is that it's unique across the entire App Store,
that's why you typically use your own domain if you own one of your own website in a reverse way,
so for example for me since I own academind.com, I could use com.academind
great_places.
Now if you have no domain, you can come up with one,
this doesn't have to exist but you should of course take one that probably really doesn't exist and
isn't owned by anyone
so that you ensure that you really have a unique identifier for your app when you then publish it to
the app stores because that's in the end the idea, have a unique identifier here.
Now if you're changing your ID here, you should change it in all the places where it's referenced, for
example also here in the debug AndroidManifest and also in your MainActivity.java file where
we're also importing from it because this will be used everywhere to tie your app together thereafter.
Another place where it's getting used is the build.gradle file in your app folder in the Android folder.
There we're also referring to that application ID and here, you should adjust it as well.
Now whilst we are in that file, let's also see what else we can set there,
for example you can set your mini SDK version or your target SDK version for this project.
Now these are some Android specifics, the mini SDK version defines the minimum Android version expressed
as a number which your app supports and on older versions, it won't be installable
and this target SDK version simply normally targets the latest stable Android version.
You can read more about the configuration here also in an attached link to this lecture, the default
settings here normally should be
all right.
So really just make sure you adjusted this application ID. Let's now do the same for iOS,
so let's go to the iOS folder and there, it's the runner folder in which we work. There in the info
plist file,
you should check that all your permissions are set up correctly
but unlike as we did it for Android, here you don't need to set a specific Internet permission, so nothing
to do regarding that and the identifier is also not set directly here
but we will set it somewhere else instead. The somewhere else is Xcode,
so let's fire up Xcode now and there simply open your iOS folder in your project folder and then
the runner.xcworkspace file,
SO not the Xcode project file but the xcworkspace file. Open that
and then here make sure you got your projects selected here in this project folder view
and then under targets, here you can set the display name, like great places which is shown on your screen
and then here you can also set up your own unique identifier which doesn't have to be the same one as
for Android
but the idea is the same, it's unique across the entire App Store and therefore you want to use a reverse
domain. If you own one, use that, otherwise come up with one which probably isn't owned by someone else
and then here, simply create such an identifier. One tiny difference compared to Android is that instead
of having great_places, for iOS you typically use the camel case notation here which means
you start with a lowercase character but then the next word inside of the word starts with a capital
character,
so greatPlaces with a capital P. With that, we have a unique bundle identifier here,
we have a display name and that's it for now.
Now let's move on to the next step.