We're nearing the end of this module,
the missing piece is that this order item here should be expandable.
Now it's gone because I changed something on the screen
but if I place an order here with order now and I go to orders, this button here should actually expand
this order
and show us detailed information about which products were part of that order.
That means that in the order item which is that element we're rendering here in that list, I want to
change what I display depending on whether that icon was clicked or not
and that screams for a stateful widget
and that's important for a stateful widget, not for something we want to manage inside of a class we
provide with the provider package because we're again back to that slide
and whereas orders and the cart and the products are all on the left side here, app-wide state or at
least state that affects multiple widgets,
the question whether we are viewing the details or not is definitely a local state thing.
Our shop page, our cart page doesn't care a bit about whether we expanded the state or expanded the information
for a single order or not.
So that's something we want to manage inside of a single widget and therefore, we use the default widget
state management tool which is using a stateful widget.
So here in the order item, we can use the refactoring tool to convert this to a stateful widget and
in the state class here, we can now manage or add a new property, expanded, which initially is false and
which should be set true when we click this button here.
So here we can call set state and in there, set expanded actually to what it's currently not, with the
exclamation mark in front of that value.
So if it's currently true, we set it to false, if it is false, we set it to true and set state of course
so that the UI updates. That icon should also change based on it,
here we can check expanded and if it is true, then I actually want to show the icons expand_less icon
to shrink it again and only show the expand_more icon if we would see more details,
so if we haven't expanded yet. And now we can use expanded here because remember, we're in a column.
Thus far I only added one element to the column,
well this is exactly the reason why I did this because now, I want to be able to show more details by
simply adding another element below that ListTile. For that,
I use this in list if statement which Dart 2.2.2 added, by using an if statement here right
inside of my list, which either adds nothing to the list if it is false, if the condition yields false
or which adds an item I have to return inside of the if statement to the outer list,
so to the list of column widgets and the condition I want to check here is simply expanded. So if expanded
is true, then it will add a new widget to that column list of widgets,
otherwise it will not. The widget I want to add conditionally here is simply a container with a height that
depends on the amount of items we have in the list, up to a certain point. For that, I'll first of all
import another package that's actually built into Dart and that's dath:math because that gives us a
min function which I can use here to use the minimum height out of two values - either widget.order,
we have to use widget now because we're in the state object,
this gives us access to the connected widget and in that connected widget, we have that order. So widget
order gives me access to the order and there, I want to get the amount of products, which I get with products
length.
So the amount of products that were registered in there and then I multiply that with let's say 20 and
add a base height of maybe 100, yes, maybe 100. So that's the first possible value, that ensures that we
never add a too big container, a too high container
if we only have one product for example but if we have 10 different products in there, I also don't want
to expand this infinitely and have a super big container and therefore, the other value is let's say
180.
So now min will pick either of these two values here.
It will calculate this and if this is smaller, then we'll take that or if that gets very large and this
is smaller, it will take 180 as a height here for our container.
Now important, min requires doubles here, so let's simply add .0 here after 20 which I multiply with
the length.
So this entire container will be attached
if we're in the expanded mode. Of course I then also want to have something in the container.
So let's add a child here
and the part inside of the container.
Well that will be a ListView because it should be scrollable in case we have many items and we take
this value here as a height for the container,
then not all items will fit into the container
hence they need to be scrollable
and since we don't know how many that are, I will use the builder here.
However, we probably won't have that many,
so using children would probably also be fine and to mix it up again,
I will use ListView children here but you could definitely also use the builder. Here we need a list
of widgets and actually what we have here of course is a list of products which I want to render but
you learn that you can of course map the list of data here into a list of widgets.
That's something we did a couple of times in this course already,
just need to convert this to a list again with to list. Map takes a function that runs on every item
in that list here, so on every product
and now here, we need to return a widget which is then used in our ListView here, in that children list
in the end.
Now of course, it's up to you how you define a single product you want to render here,
I will use a row there because I want to have two elements, two widgets side by side.
I will add a text widget here which holds my title,
so here on that product for which I'm rendering this, I get the title of the product and maybe also add
a little bit of text style here and give this a font size of 18 and a font weight of FontWeight.bold, of
course, this is always up to you
and next to that, I'll add another text widget where I want to output the quantity and the price side by side.
So here I'll use string interpolation, use prod quantity, then a times symbol, an X simply, then a dollar
sign which I want to print
hence we need to escape it and then more string interpolation where I output prod.price and there,
I'll also assign some style,
little bit of a different style however, set the font size to 18 and the color maybe to
color.grey.
Now these are the two text pieces
and on that row, I want to add spaceBetween which we can do with main axis alignment and then
MainAxisAlignment.spaceBetween as you learned. This is how I want to output my list items or the
data about the products if we expand that. So let's do a full restart here and now add a couple of items
to the cart, here we should probably fix that now that I see it in the cart screen here where
I output my total, total amount,
we should use to string as fixed and use two fraction digits here to avoid
issues like this.
So now let's re-add cart items here
and now if I click order now and I go to orders and I click this expand icon, this gets expanded,
we see our data here and we can close this.
We can improve the look of that a little bit. For one, in order item, I think that is a little bit too
big here and one error was
I don't want to add +100 here, just +10
and actually also add some padding of course with EdgeInsets.symmetric and maybe have a horizontal
padding of 15 and vertical of 4, horizontal 15, vertical 4. So that's one thing, that we add some padding
here and the max size also should be just 100 maybe.
So now let's give this one more try, add a couple of items here to our cart, click order now, go to the
orders, go to the orders, expand this and now this looks better. You can see, we can scroll here if that gets
cut off which is indeed what I want to have as an effect here
and with that, that looks quite nice.
We can see what we ordered here,
we see the date and we can see more information if we want to.
So that's always a nice feature we add to this application,
it also emphasizes when you should use stateful widgets and when you should use provided classes and
hopefully also makes it clear what the difference is and with that, I'd say we have a decent shop here.
Definitely not finished, we can't add our own products yet, we'll do that in the next section once we also
work more with user interaction, fetch user input, give users different feedback and so on and there are
other nice features which we can add, like saving data in the Internet, on a server and these are all
things we will add but hopefully with this module, it got a bit clearer how you may manage your state
and bigger applications and why we're doing it like this and how it generally works.