The next step is that you ensure that your third-party APIs and services are configured correctly.
So if you're using something like Firebase, make sure your security rules are set up correctly there
or when working with Google APIs like we're doing it here,
you can search for the Google Cloud Platform console or just the Google Cloud console and then log into
there with your Google account and then under credentials here, you will see the API keys your app use.
So this is the API key we are using here in the location helper for example.
Now I will delete this key here once I'm done recording, so you won't be able to use this one but for
your own key, you can,
you don't have to but you can restrict it,
for example you could restricted to only work on Android apps if you wanted to and then you'll find
out which instructions you should follow here on the right.
You can also restrict your API in different ways and whilst you might not need to do that, you should
at least be aware of that,
read through that and see if you want to change something there, if you want to change the APIs for
which this key can be used
or if you want to restrict it in any other way.
And whichever third-party service you are using,
make sure you're using it such that it's secure and your users can only do what you want them to do.