Let's actually start by adding a couple of products and for that, I'll import from my models folder and
there, my products.dart file to unlock that product class here in this ProductsOverview widget
and then here in our ProductsOverviewScreen widget class, I want to add, since it's some dummy data for
now, a
final property which will hold a list of products which I'll name loaded products or whatever you want
to name it
and that will be a list of products as I already said. Now
for this, I prepared some products which you'll find attached and
you can simply add them here or replace your existing products list with these products, simply some
dummy products which you can of course change, you can add more products if you want to,
so that we have some products to start with in this widget and these products satisfy my product definition
defined here in the product class. With the products loaded, here in the build method, I of course don't
want to return a container but actually, a scaffold because remember that this widget here, the products
overview screen widget will be used as a screen in this app, which means that it will fill the entire
screen here and therefore, it should also provide an appBar, a background color and so on
and that's all something scaffold does.
So I'll use a scaffold widget here and add the appBar argument which is simply a widget created with
the appBar class and there, we can set up a title like my shop if that would be the name of our
brand, of our shop,
of course should be a text widget though, so that's something we can add here, like this.
And besides the appBar, obviously we want to have a body and a scaffold and that should be the grid
view and therefore I'll use GridView but now not in the way we used it before
by instantiating like this and providing a children argument but instead, I'll use the builder method
which works in the same way as ListView.builder,
it simply optimizes longer grid views with multiple items or where we don't know how many items we'll
have by simply only rendering the items that are on the screen and not rendering the items that are
not on the screen
and this helps us with performance for very long grid views which our list of products potentially could
be.
So that's the GridView.builder here and the GridView.builder now takes a couple of arguments.
Now one of them is the padding which we can add and I want to add some padding here with EdgeInsets.all
10.0, to make sure there's some padding around the grid
and now you learned earlier in the course that you can turn this into a const here, use a const keyword
in front of this to make sure that this does not rebuild when this whole build method is called which
can save you some performance
and that is true and definitely add const at all places where you can add it.
I will not focus on it in this module here because I want to focus on the new widgets and then
on the state management part which is the heart of this module.
Now of course, feel free to add const in all the places where you can add it, as you learned, it's never a
bad practice for applications and can help you with performance but with that, back to filling this grid
view, padding to have some padding around the grid and then we also need three other items here,
three other arguments.
One is the item count which simply tells the GridView how many grid items to build and that of course
should be our loaded products and there, the length,
so how many loaded products do we have.
Then we need the item builder which is a function or which holds a builder function which receives the
context and the index of the item it's currently building a cell for, that should return the widget that
gets built for every grid item we have.
So this is actually what we'll see on the screen. Now
I'll come back to this in a second because there is another argument which we have to provide and that's
the gridDelegate.
The item builder defines how every grid item is built, how every grid cell should be built,
the gridDelegate allows us to define how the grid generally should be structured, so how many columns
it should have
most importantly and we set that by providing a SliverGridDelegate
and then here, I'll use with FixedCrossAxisCount which means I can define that I want to have a certain
amount of columns and it will simply squeeze the items onto the screen so that this criteria is met.
The alternative would be the SliverGridDelegateWithFixedExtent which we used earlier
in the course where we can define how wide every grid item should be and it will then create as many
columns as it can for the given device size.
It simply depends on your app requirements, what you want,
I simply want to show both and therefore here, I'll not set a fixed width of all the grid items but
instead say I want to have at least a certain amount of grid items on the screen.
Now for that, we have to configure this SliverGridDelegateWithFixedAxisCount class
which is really a cool class name and one thing we have to configure here is the crossAxisCount which
is exactly that amount of columns I want to have
and here let's say I want to have two columns and then you can set the child aspect ratio and there
I want to have 3 / 2,
so this should be a bit higher than they are wide, a bit taller than they are wide and then you can set
up the crossAxisSpacing which is simply the width, the spacing between the columns and I'll set 10 here,
10 pixels
and the mainAxisSpacing which is the space between the rows and I'll set the same spacing there.
So with that, we defined the structure of the grid,
now we can go back to the grid items that we want to render.
Now we could definitely add the widget subtree for each item here but since this is a perfect scenario
for outsourcing something into a separate widget to keep this widget tree of this widget here smaller,
I'll create a new widget in the widgets folder and I'll name it product_item.dart and
in there, a stateless widget which is also named product item and this will be the grid item which
gets rendered for every product.
Now of course here, we have to import material.dart and now we simply have to define how a product, how
a grid item should look like.
Here, we could return a container which we now style ourselves,
we could return a card but I am always a fan of showing you new widgets which we haven't seen before
and therefore here, I'll return a GridTile, that's a widget built into Flutter. You might remember
ListTile which we also used in the ListView but also for example in the side drawer.
Now GridTile is simply a built-in widget which can be used anywhere but which works particularly well
inside of grids.
Now a GridTile takes a child and that will be the main content of the grid.
Now here, I want to have an image as the main content and that will be the image of the product we're rendering.
So here, I'll use image.network to create an image widget that takes a network source and here, we
could enter a URL
but of course I don't want to have a hardcoded widget but I want to get that data from outside,
so from the place where I use the product item widget.
So we'll need to accept a couple of properties in this product item to display a product.
Either we have only one property which is our product of type product or the separate things that we
need from the product as separate properties
and that's the approach I'll take here,
so I expect to get the ID let's say, I expect to get the title because I'll probably need that,
I expect to get the imageUrl and yes, that should be it for now.
Now of course to really get values for these properties,
we need to provide the constructor here and then again, it's up to you whether you want to use positional
or named arguments, I'll use positional arguments,
so I'll simply add these three property assignments here as arguments in the constructor of the product
item
and with that, we get access to the imageUrl down there. This allows us to render such product
items, let's now use that widget in the ProductsOverviewScreen widget.
So in there, let's import from the widgets folder, the product_item.dart file and with that import
added, down there in our item builder of the GridView,
we use product item and now we simply have to forward the data.
So since we go through all our loaded products here or since the GridView.builder does that for us, we
want to forward loaded products for the index
we're currently building our item for and then here, the ID,
then the second argument product item takes as the title.
So let's access load products i.title and then also loaded products
i.imageUrl
These are the three arguments we forward to product item and therefore product item will now work correctly.
Now one important note, of course in this module, we'll have a look at other state management solutions
and one goal there will be that we don't manage all our state in the main.dart file and pass all the
state as arguments to other widgets. Passing data into a widget like this however is and will always be
normal.
You want to have reusable widgets which you could drop anywhere into your application and we should
then simply configure through or via arguments which you pass to them.
So a product item that receives the data it needs to display the content correctly as arguments,
that's something we'll always use in our applications.
The things we'll later take care of are the unnecessary arguments where we pass something to a widget
just because we then need to forward it to another widget and so on which we also had earlier
but I'll come back to that once we do dive deeper into the state management part.
So for now, let's simply pass the data here to product item which should render it
and with that let's save it and do a full restart here and see whether that works.
However for that of course, in main.dart, I first of all have to make sure that I delete MyHomePage
class here and that we actually do render the ProductsOverviewScreen here as our main screen. So I
can import from the
screens folder and there, from the products_overview_screen.dart file and with that import added here,
down there,
I want to of course use my ProductsOverviewScreen widget as the main widget.
Now with that, we can save this and now indeed here,
I see these four items, which are my four images for the four products I provided.
It's a start,
obviously not the prettiest application we ever saw but it is a start and it's something we can build
up on.
So let's now fine tune the product items here a bit and for that, let's not just return a boring
GridTile with only an image but let's add more to that than just the image.
First however, I want to configure that image with the fit argument which we can now provide to take up
all the available space it can get
and I do this with BoxFit.cover which is the setting I want to use here
and if we do that, then this already looks a bit better because now these images at least are equally
sized. By the way, this list of course would be scrollable here if we had more products that would exceed
the boundaries here of this screen.
Now on the images, of course it would be useful to also display the title of the product because that's
certainly an important piece of information.
For that, besides the child on the GridTile here, we can also add a footer and that will add a bar or a part
at the bottom of the GridTile and there, there is another widget which helps us with nicely displaying
content there,
you don't have to use it but you can use it
and that's the GridTileBar. Now the GridTileBar can be configured of course in various ways and for example,
you can add the title argument here.
The title argument takes a widget and typically that of course is a text widget but you could add anything
which suits your requirements and in there, I want to display the title of our product.
So I'll use that title property which we are receiving here and which we do store in the title property.
So we'll use that
and on that text, I also want to make sure that we center this with text align and then
text align.center which is an enum value to tell Flutter to center this text in its widget.
And with that, if we now save this, we got that title down there as well which is quite nice.
Now of course, for example here for the trousers, this title is a bit hard to read and therefore, a good
thing is that on the GridTileBar, we can also set a background color. Now here,
let's try colors gray as a hardcoded color and we could work with something like this but I rather
have a color which has some opacity to it.
For that, we can of course use something like black54 which is a black color that is a bit opaque where
you can still see the image and I think that looks a bit nicer,
so I'll go with that.
So with that, we now have the title and we can also read the title. Now on this header or on this footer
here to be precise,
I want to have more than just the title though, there also should be buttons to favorite this or to add
it to the cart.
So in the footer here, we can also add a leading argument to define a widget that should be placed at
the start of this bar.
Now the title is always in the center,
we can also add items here on the left and on the right to it. So here with leading, I want to add an
IconButton here because it should be pressable and it should only display an icon, hence it's an IconButton
and the icon I'll use here is is an icon widget and there, I want to use icons.favorite
and also add onPressed and set this to an empty or to a function that does nothing at the moment.
With this, we add this heart icon here on the left which is quite nice,
let's now also add an icon on the right here with trailing still on the GridTileBar and there, another icon
button where the icon is an icon widget where we can use the shopping cart icon and then also add onPressed
on the icon button which for now is a function that does nothing
and if you save that, you see also the card icon here. Now with that, it's taking shape,
let's next worry about our theme and some styling for this application.