In our application here, there's also one thing I want to improve. If I have a transaction with a pretty
big amount here,
so if we enter a big number, then we of course know that we would have grown our bar here without
the fixes we applied earlier.
One thing we can still see is that now, these weekday shortcuts here are not really aligned
and in addition, we also see that the bar here, the first bar is actually starting a bit earlier than
the other ones, it's not in line with the other bars.
The reason for that of course is that we shrank our text and therefore the height of this text
also changed and hence this whole bar is moved up a bit.
Obviously, that's not a behavior I want here. Now to fix that behavior,
we can go to our chart bar widget here and simply wrap a container around our FittedBox here and
in that container here, we can give this a height of let's say 20.
Now the text here at the top will always have a height of 20 no matter how much height it needs
and therefore the text is now aligned,
the bars are aligned and the text here at the bottom is also aligned
and that of course looks better than bars jumping randomly around.
Now one other thing we can improve on this chart here is the order of days.
It's a pure cosmetic thing and you might not even want this but at the moment, the current day, toay
is here on the left and the oldest date is on the right.
To me it's more natural that the day one week ago should be on the left and today should be all the
way on the right.
Now again, it's totally up to you if that's what you want but if you want that, it's relatively easy to
achieve,
all you have to do is you go to your chart.dart file where you derive your grouped transaction values
and there, we build this list for our weekdays.
In the end, the way we have our algorithm here means that we generate today as the first day in
line
and it's hard to change that.
The easiest way to change the resulting list however is to simply add something on the list which is
generated here, we can call reversed here and reverse gives us a new iterable so we can then call to
list on that
and now we get a reversed list.
So now we build a list, then we reverse it
with the help of reverse which gives us our list, just in the opposite order
and it doesn't give us a list but actually an iterable
and therefore just as for map and so on, we have to call to list.
And if you do that and you save this,
now you see the bars switched order and we have the oldest date or the oldest day on the left and
today on the right.
Again it's up to you if you want that behavior, here I do want that and therefore this is the change that
I think makes sense here.