So how do we tell Flutter that we want to load this categories screen as the starting screen of our
application? You do that in the main.dart file, there in your root app where you set up that material
app or that Cupertino app, whatever it is, you have
that home argument which you provide and that points at the widget which should be loaded as the first
screen in your application.
So home here is a super important argument.
Now you will later learn that there are other arguments on the MaterialApp which also help you with
loading screens
but home always marks the entry point of your application, the root screen of your app
and therefore here, we now can point at our categories screen widget
and for that you need to make sure that you also import those categories screen widget here.
So make sure you add an import path at the top of your main.dart file.
Now since I added this, we can also get rid of my home page of this class and its state,
we didn't need the state anyways but now also the entire home page is not needed anymore because we load
a different widget as our starting widget in our app.
Now one important note though before we see that in action, what's missing in the categories screen widget?
If you have a look at it, there is something missing which I mentioned would be important in every widget
you want to use as a screen
and that's the scaffold. Here
we're returning the GridView but in the end, that would be the content of our screen. The screen itself
also typically has an appBar and maybe some other things like some tabs
and therefore here, we should actually return a scaffold widget and that scaffold widget should have
our GridView as a body.
So let's grab this entire GridView here,
cut it and add it as a body or as a value for body here on scaffold, like this.
Now we can also add an appBar here and that can be a simple appBar where I for now only set the title
to deli meal or whatever you want to name your app, should be a text widget though
and since we're building it here, of course this can be a const text widget which never will have to
update when the app rebuilds because the text in there is constant,
this widget will never be different than it is initially.
Now with all of that, restart your app and do it with that green icon here because hot reloading will
not work,
you need to do a full restart and now you should see this here
and this doesn't look too bad.
We have a scrollable grid of categories here.
Now a couple of things can be improved though,
this text here doesn't look the way it does,
the overall theme in general doesn't look the way I want it,
maybe we want to bring our own fonts and some spacing around the grid would also be nice.
So let's work on these visuals next before we then focus on making these categories tappable so that
we can see the recipes for a single category.