Let's start with the product detail screen where we can tap on a product and we see more information
about it, like for example its price and its description.
Now obviously, you might want to show the price here on the starting page as well,
you could for example also go to your product item and besides a footer, there on the GridTile, you can
also add a header so that you could have the title of the item up there and the price down there.
These are all changes you can of course implement,
I will simply also for demo purposes shows some of the information here on the main screen and then
some on the detail screen,
you learned all the tools it takes to fine tune this to your personal likings and requirements.
So my goal now is that we can tap onto a GridTile here and then we're taken
to that detail screen and for that, we need to add a new screen of course, add a new file therefore and that's
the
product_detail_screen.dart file which will hold the stateless widget which is the product detail
screen widget
and therefore of course as always, we should import material.dart from the Flutter package up there. Now
since this widget here will in the end render a screen, so it will control the full page,
I want to use a scaffold widget here to add an appBar and a background color and here in the
appBar, I of course want to render appBar widget and there, I want to output a title with the name of
the product.
Now we got two ways of managing this now and that is now already getting closer to that state management
idea. You learned in the section where we also focused on navigation and different screens and so on
that there are two important ways of going to a new screen. Here in the ProductsOverviewScreen, when
we tap one of our product items there or therefore here in product item where we can register such a
tap, we can either use navigator push and then create a MaterialPageRoute on-the-fly and create the
widget we want to go to on-the-fly and pass all the data we need to it in place or we push a named
route.
Now let's start with pushing on-the-fly so to say, which is relatively easy to implement in this app
here
and for that, let's say whenever we tap on the image, we want to go to that new screen,
we want to go to the details and therefore we can wrap this here with a GestureDetector.
The image here is wrapped with this widget because that allows us to add an onTap listener to this image.
The image itself has no onTap argument but we can easily add one by wrapping the invisible
GestureDetector widget around it.
So onTap should now push this new page and therefore here in this function which we define, in this
anonymous function which we define for onTap, we can use navigator of context push, not pushNamed but
just push and there, you learned in the navigation section that you create a MaterialPageRoute which
is a widget built into Flutter, which takes a builder method which gives you a new context, an object and
which has to return a widget you want to go to. So here, we might want to go to the product detail
page, to the product detail screen.
So for that, let's import from the screens folder the product detail screen and now we have
that widget available here,
so here, we can then create a product detail screen like this.
Now this is one way of doing it
and when the product detail screen now requires data like the title, then we can simply expect the title
here as a property and therefore as an argument in the constructor where we then simply store it in
the property and then we can reference this title property here in our widgets and that should of course
be a text widget with the title as a content.
So now, we can use the title property here in this text widget as a title for the appBar because we're
getting the title in the constructor of the product detail screen because when we push, we do it here
on-the-fly in the place where the user tapped on something, like in this case
here on the image and here, since we're in the product item widget, we already know the title of
the product and we can now forward this here as an argument to the product detail screen.
And with this approach, if we do that, now we can tap on these images and we load these different screens
with the correct title in the appBar as you can tell.
Now this approach has some benefits,
it's relatively easy.
We've forwarded the data we already have and we're good to go.
Downsides of this approach are that we create this route on-the-fly here in this anonymous method
and therefore if this application gets bigger and bigger and we have multiple such on-the-fly route
creations, it can be hard to understand which different routes and screens our app has
if we're new to this app, if we're a new developer. Named routs which are all registered here in the
main.dart file are much easier to understand because there, we have that routes table and we simply see
which routes our app has and that's simply easier than if we have to manually go through all the files
to find all these on-the-fly route creations. Another downside is that of course it's convenient
to pass the data we already have here to the product detail screen but what if we also need the price
here, which we actually do need here? Then I also expect to get the price
and now all of a sudden, we request some information, we need some information which we don't have here
in our product item widget. We don't have the price of the product here.
Now obviously, we could expect it here as the argument and then we could pass it into the product item
widget from inside our products overview widget where we of course have all the products including their
price.
The downside about this approach is that we then pass data into product item, which we don't directly
use there, which we don't display there, which we only need because we want to create a new screen in here,
we want to create that on-the-fly route in here.
So we're in that scenario where we pass data as arguments which we don't really need in the widget but
which we need in another widget where we want to forward it
and that's exactly what we typically want to avoid.
So here we already see a problem with this approach.
It would be nicer to have a named route and therefore here in the product item,
we could simply use pushNamed and simply pass in the name of our route here and therefore on the
product detail screen, instead of getting this as arguments, I would rather extract that value here from
my routing arguments as you learned it in the navigation section and for now, I don't have that,
so that I can still compile, I'll turn this into some hardcoded text just so that I don't get errors
whilst this compiles, we'll turn this back into a dynamic title later.
So instead of getting or having properties which we get as arguments in the constructor, it would be
nicer to retrieve arguments from our routing action
so to say and use this page here, this screen, this widget as a named route and therefore, we can of course
have a static const routeName or routePath here which could be product detail so that we can use this
in our main.dart file here in the route table because then here, we can import from the screens folder
the product_detail_screen.dart file and then register this as a named route here, use the product
detail screen and there, the routeName, this static const which is a string as a key in this map and
then the value is this builder function where we get the context. We get that by Flutter when it calls
the builder function, when we call pushNamed
and here, we built the product detail screen and now we have a clean way of seeing which routes we
have. We have the overview screen and we have the detail screen. And now when we call pushNamed here,
we refer to the product detail screen route name and now we can set some arguments and the argument
here should of course now not be an object or a map with the price,
the title and so on because then we would still need all that data in the product item widget which is
exactly what I want to avoid
but instead we could for example only forward the ID, so that we can fetch all the data we need in
the product detail widget inside of the product detail widget.
So here in the product item widget, which is that grid item, there I only forward the ID here which
is a property which I do have, I forward that ID here to my named route,
not all the data I need there
and now in that named route, I want to extract that ID which we can do with ModalRoute of
context.settings.arguments
.
This will in the end give us the ID
because I forward the ID as my argument, as my only argument here and now here, I want to get all my
product data for that ID and that of course won't work if we always pass data just through constructors,
instead now we need a central state management solution.