So we're taking an image,
we're saving the file,
now let's make sure we actually create a place which we add to great places here,
for now only in memory, so only working with the features here without storing this in any database
but we'll add this later as well.
So here in add place,
we of course have our text field with the title controller.
Now we also want to get some information by the image input
once an image was taken and for that, we can simply pass in a reference to a method which we have here
in add place screen which should be triggered from inside image input when an image was taken.
So I'll add a new method here to the add place screen widget which will not return anything which I'll
just name _selectImage and there,
I expect to get a file and therefore, we of course have to import dart:io up there to use that type of
file,
my picked image in the end. That's what I expect here and then we can store this in a property of this
class here, of this state class.
So here, we can have our file type property, picked image or whatever you can name it, _pickedImage
here.
It's undefined initially but here, I'll then set picked image equal to the picked image I get here as
an argument,
so picked image on the right without underscore is the argument, with the underscore it's referring to
our property here.
Now I'm not using set state here because I don't really need to re-render this widget here, I don't want
to call build again just because we pick that image because regarding the preview of that image, we are
managing this in the image input which is also a stateful widget,
so we don't need to manage this in the add place screen and other than that, there is nothing in the add place screen
that would need to update just because we picked an image.
So now with picked image saved here, which we only need so that we can submit our form later, now we need
to make sure that select image, this method, is triggered from inside image input and therefore, I'll simply
pass a pointer to the select image method to image input and in the image input class in the widget
there, we can now expect this function.
So up there in the widget itself, I expect to get a function type data which I'll name onSelectImage
maybe to follow the onPressed and so on naming the Flutter widgets use and add a constructor of course
to accept a value for this
and now we have our function which we expect to get,
so a pointer at the function which we expect to get from outside, registered as a property, the image
input widget, we can now use it in the state down there once an image was picked.
So here I will refer to widget,
this is the global property which is available in state objects, giving us access to our widget class
here, widget.onSelectImage and now execute this function because onSelectImage is a pointer at
a function, here I want to execute it and I want to forward that saved image because remember, in the
end, we do expect an image here in the add place screen.
With that, we get the image here, we're storing it in this property,
now we can also add a method for submitting that form and therefore for adding a new place and I'll
name this save place, the name is up to you,
it's a new method, _savePlace, doesn't return anything and in there, first of all let's check
if _titleController.text, if that is empty or if pickedImage
is equal to null. If either of that is the case, then we have invalid input
and even though I won't add super complex validation with error messages and so on, I'll at least return
here to not continue execution so that we can't hit the add place button and add an invalid place but
I'm also not showing any error messages, that of course would be an improvement
you might want to add in your app or as I just said, use a form right from the start
so that at least for the title, you can add a validator and show an error message. Here of course, you
could show a dialogue and so on but I don't want to spend too much time on that,
we worked with all of that before,
let's instead continue with that place and for that, I want to add the place here to my list of items
in the great places class which we then provide in the end.
So here in great places, let's add a new method, add place which won't return anything which should store
a place and there I expect to get a title which is a string of course and I expect to get a file which
is my image and to use file in here, we have to import dart:io. So we get the file, the image and we
get the title,
later we'll also get the location data
of course. In here, we can therefore
now create a new place by using the place constructor provided from the place model we're importing and
now a place needs a couple of things.
It needs an ID
and here since we're not using any web service, I'll just use the good old datetime
now to string dummy ID here.
We'll need to set an image and that should be the image we're getting here,
the image we're getting here,
can also name this here picked image to make it really clear what's what
down there.
So here we have the image which we store and then of course we also need to provide a location and a
title.
Now we're getting the title as an argument and you could of course also rename this here picked title to
avoid confusion regarding the names down there and also the location and for now, I'll set this to
null because for the moment, we have no location, we're not yet able to pick a location on the map or
by getting the user location. With that, let's go to the items list up there, _items and call
add and then add this new place to this list and thereafter call notifyListeners so that everyone
listening will get informed about that changed data and will get the new data
of course. That's add place in the great places class, back to the add place screen,
I want to use that and therefore we need to import the provider package of course, the provider.dart
file and we need to import our provided/great_places.dart file here.
So with these two imports added, in save place, we can use provider of and then refer to great places to
get access to the nearest provided data of that type which of course is provided here in the main.dart
file of and pass the context and then call add place and there, forward the title which we can
of course get from the titleController.text and the picked image which is of course stored here
in the _pickedImage variable.
So let's forward that to this add place method because these are the arguments this method needs and of
course, make sure you don't listen here because we're not interested in updates in this place,
I just want to dispatch this action here. With that, we're adding a new place,
we can also go back thereafter with navigator of context pop to leave this page and now on the places
list screen,
I of course want to output the places now because that's something we're missing at the moment. So here
instead of always showing this CircularProgressIndicator, now I instead want to rather show my places,
so I'll replace this with a consumer here and consumer is a widget provided by the provider package
as you learned to listen to a provider and then update this part of the widget tree when it changes,
so import the provider package up there,
have your consumer here,
let the consumer know to which data should listen with that generic type here.
So import providers/
great_places.dart as well because we need the great places
class down there, here
great places and now the consumer as you learned gets a builder and the builder gets a context and then
the data the provider gave us,
so our great places data here in the end.
In addition, we also get a static child here which we can also set up, maybe here before we add the builder
and that's the part which can then be used inside of the built widget which is built with the help of
the builder which will not update even if the data changes and here, I actually want to have some centered
text where I say got no places yet, start adding some
and then you could even use a column here and show a button right below it to navigate to the
add place screen if you wanted to.
I'll keep this simple,
this is a text which I might want to show because here on the right side of this builder or as a return
value for the builder to be precise,
there I want to check whether great places.items length is smaller or equal than zero which means we
have no places and if that is the case, then I want to output this child.
So here, that's the child we defined up here, I want output that if we have no places, otherwise I want to
render a list view of places.
So this now our builder either showing the child we're getting here which is this child which won't
be re-rendered if places change because there is nothing to re-render there
and of course, you could even use a const constructor here and leverage even more optimizations if you
want to
but if we do have places, then I want to return a ListView, with the builder constructor though because
we don't know how many places we'll have,
so to get performance improvements, let's use ListView.builder here and there, we'll have a certain item
count and that item count simply is greatPlaces.items.length of course and then
we'll have our item builder which is a builder function which gets a context and the index or just i
of the item we're currently building
and then here, we have to return what should be built for each place
and here, I'll simply build a ListTile widget for every place. And then in there for every place, I want
to have a leading widget, a CircleAvatar which is that rounded element at the beginning of the ListTile
here where I want to set a background, not color but a background image where we now can provide
an image provider, so not an image widget but an image provider which is basically Flutter's way of resolving
the pixels for an image
so to say and here, I want to use a file image and you might remember that earlier in the course, we used
asset image and network image,
now we're using file image because we're working with a file stored in our device and here, I want to
use the greatPlaces.items for the item we're working with,
so for the index, we're rendering this ListTile and then there, the image which of course is such a file. So
that's the leading element in the ListTile
here, I also want to have a title and that of course should be greatPlaces.items for the item we're
working with and there,
the title and shouldn't just be a text but instead be a text widget
of course. Upon a tap of this ListTile here, I later also want to go to the detail page, go to detail page
but we'll implement this later.
So for the moment, this should be all we need to render a list of places on the places lists screen, on
the add place screen,
we now have to make sure that we triggeer the save place method,
the _savePlace method
when we hit this button here at the bottom, this RaisedButton.
So here for onPressed, I want to point at save place, without parentheses to not execute this immediately
but to tell Flutter that this should be executed when the user presses the button.
With that, we should have everything in place,
let's enter a title, a
test and then take a picture there with the emulator camera and on the emulator,
this can be a bit slow,
in reality, this will be fast, no worries and click add place and that didn't work.
Why did it not work?
We're getting an error here, yes
path provider not found, it's the same issue as before, we're tapping into native device features
here,
so if you added a plugin that uses such features, you might want to restart your app entirely, restart
the build process.
So here, I'll quit my entire running process and do a full restart, a full rebuild of the app so that
we can include all these plugins that tap into native device features. So let's wait for that to
finish and
let's then test it again. So the app restarted,
let's go to the add place screen and again have a test here,
then open that camera,
here we go.
Take this picture here, confirm it and then click add place and now this looks good.
We're going back to the list and we're seeing our place here
and if I add another place, obviously always with the same image here because that is what the emulator
gives us here. So
let's take this image here,
confirm and click add place and we see that as well.
So we have our places here,
that is great.
Feel free to fine tune the look of this list if you want to have a different look,
my next step will be to test this on real devices,
also on iOS device there and thereafter, we'll continue with storing the data we're getting here,
so the path to the image, the title and so on in a database on the device, so that the data survives a restart
because right now if I do a full refresh and therefore I restart my app, of course all our places will
be lost,
here they are, they're gone.
So that's the next thing we'll work on after testing this on real devices.