So you learned how to publish your app to Android,
let's now do the same for iOS and again, in the official docs, you find detailed instructions which I strongly
recommend that you check out to have a written a step-by-step guide.
Now for publishing iOS apps, you need an Apple developer account
and here, you actually now need a paid account which costs $99 a year.
This is in place to make sure that only people who are a bit serious about it release apps to the App
Store and there is no way around it,
so to publish to the App Store, you need such a paid account. With that account,
once you enrolled there into the Apple Developer program and links can be found here in the official
docs, you can go to App Store Connect which is the first step for setting up your app in the end. You can
also Google for App Store connect to find a direct link and then log in with your Apple ID which is
connected to that Apple Developer account for which you're paying.
Once you did sign in there, as you can see there, you should open the app ID's page and click on plus
to create a new bundle ID. You can simply click on the app ID's link here of course to be taken to
the right page and there, go to identifiers,
click on the plus here and register new app ID. So click continue here, choose the platform which should
be iOS and then give it a description like great places and choose an explicit bundle ID
and now here, use that same bundle ID you're using here in Xcode.
So this bundle identifier,
make sure you're using this here as well.
Check any capabilities your app uses
and in my case, no special capabilities are required here but if you're using any of these features,
make sure you check it and then click continue and thereafter, register and that's now step number one.
With that out of the way, go back to App Store Connect where we've been before and click on my apps here
and take on the plus icon here and new app, choose iOS as a platform and give it a name which is the
name that is displayed in the Apple App Store as well, as you can see here, so make sure this is a good
name which gets users to click on it. Choose your primary language which in my case is English here and
then choose a bundle ID here and it can take a while until your newly created ID shows up here,
so once it does, choose it here. You can give this an internal identifier here if you wanted to, like great
places and then click create here in the end.
Now this name is unsurprisingly already used, so I'll name it great places course, of course you want to
find a name here which is not in use already and which describes your app
well and with that, we created the app here. Now here again, you can fill out the details on this page to edit
how the app is listed in the App Store and how it looks like there, however we will now continue in
Xcode.
You'll also find this in the official docs, there
you should now open your Xcode project, make sure that your display name and bundle identifier is set
up correctly. So click on your project name here,
make sure this is setup correctly and under
signing, make sure that you'll have automatically manage signing checked and regarding the
build number here, go back to your project code and there in the pubspec.yaml file,
make sure you set your version here.
The part in front of the plus is the version number that will be visible to your users,
so when they go to the App Store,
that's the version
of the app
they will see. This should of course be a version that makes sense to your users,
so for example if you publish a new version where you have a minor bug fix in there, maybe change this
to 1.0.1, this doesn't look like a huge breaking change and your users will simply see that there
is a new version which probably just fixed something minor.
You have a bigger change,
maybe change that middle number and if you have a large new version, maybe change that front
number because version 2.0 certainly looks more important that 1.0.1. So really just change a number
that makes sense for the size of the change your update brings. The number after the plus here is your
internal number and you should simply increment this with every new version you're releasing.
This should be an integer and simply use a new number here whenever you publish a
new version into the App Store,
that is how you should manage these versions. With all the versions set up correctly here and all the other
settings also being correct up here,
you can go back to your project, open the terminal there and run flutter build
ios and this will now build your production ready iOS application and it will automatically optimize your
code, shrink it to be as small as possible and sign your app for production. Once this is done, close and
restart Xcode,
so that same project in Xcode of course and now in there, as you see in the official docs, go to product
scheme runner and select product destination generic iOS device.
So here, product scheme runner, make sure that this is set and also make sure that product destination
generic iOS device is set here and with that configured, go to product and then archive which in the
end also now bundles up your iOS application into an app bundle which can be deployed to the App
Store and wait for this process to finish and now in that new window which opens up here, select your
project and you can now validate your app or distribute your app to upload it to the App Store and then
continue from there and publish it from there as well.
Now I will not do that here but that's the next step that you can thereafter publish your app from inside
App Store Connect which we worked in earlier and
that's how you published your iOS app.