So let's make sure we see the shop screen after we logged in.
Now there are two possible routes we could take,
one route is that if you did login or did sign up successfully,
so basically here inside the try block, you actually use navigator of context and then maybe pushReplacement
and then you go to your products overview screen
which right now isn't registered as a route but of course we could add it here to our routes table.
We could add our product overview screen here to the table and then navigate to it with pushReplacement
named so that we live the AuthScreen
and we're in the shop. Would work,
no problem with that
but it has one major downside, it would mean that we always start on the auth page when we open the app
and we have to login so that we are then forwarded to the shop page and
that's not really what I want to do.
So the better approach might be to change the home page we have here in the main.dart file.
Now that might sound strange but keep in mind that MaterialApp is also a widget and that in the my
app here, we're also in a widget with a build method.
So we could say that if we login, this build method should maybe rerun because logging in and logging
out is a big change that should affect the entire app,
so this will then rerun and if it reruns, it will rebuild the MaterialApp
and if we then switch the home screen and switch that from AuthScreen to products overview screen, then
for that rebuild after the login, we would automatically render a new screen without navigation simply
because this was rebuilt and now renders a different screen into our face
so to say and that's actually the approach I want to use here because that will later allow us to implement
a check here when the app starts for whether the user is authenticated or not
and then always send us to the right screen right from the start.
So the goal is to switch this home screen we render, either our home screen is the products overview
screen if we are authenticated or it's the AuthScreen
if we are not and if we initially are not authenticated and then we do authenticate, that's no problem,
we just have to ensure that this build method runs again
and then here we use some if condition to switch the screen we're showing,
that's the idea.
So how does this work in detail then?
Well since we set up our auth provider here and that is in the end managing the object where we do manage
that whole login stuff and so on, since we're doing that here, it would make sense that we actually don't
rebuild this entire method here maybe
but this part of the tree and for that, we can of course use the consumer which is part of the provider
package and which I showed you in the state management module of the course. So we'll not entirely rebuild
the entire widget tree but we will rebuild the MaterialApp and that of course is what counts here.
So here, we have our consumer and we consume our auth class or the nearest auth object we can find which
is of course the object provided here and consumer now takes a builder here and that builder receives
a context which is given to the built object in there and gets your auth object, your AuthData,
whatever you want to name it,
I'll just name it auth and you'll also get this child widget if you had some static part which you don't
want to rebuild.
Now here however, I have no child, so
I'll just add a blank here, to indicate that there is nothing I would want to pass in as a fixed widget
so to say.
Now the thing I want to return here is my MaterialApp, so let's grab the MaterialApp here and move it
into this builder function right here.
So now this ensures that the MaterialApp is rebuilt whenever auth changes, whenever that auth object changes
and whenever we call notify listeners in there which we right now by the way are never doing but we'll
soon add that.
So whenever that changes, this builder runs again and gives us a new MaterialApp, in there we get access
to the latest auth object and therefore we can use that down here when we decide what our home page, our
home route should be
and here we can therefore check auth
and now what.
Now we need some gather or some property on the auth object and therefore in the auth class that tells
us whether the user is authenticated or not.
So let's go to the auth.dart file and up there, I'll add a new getter which should return a
boolean, which I'll simply name isAuth because that is what I want to return here and we can have a very
simple rule here. If we have a token and the token didn't expire, then the user is authenticated. So here
we can add our logic for checking the expiry date and comparing it to the current date and see if the
current date is still behind the expiry date,
so the expiry date hasn't passed yet
and if the token is set. Since we'll also later also need the token itself, I'll create another getter here which
actually returns the token,
so here token without an underscore, here it is with an underscore and there I check if
_expiryDate is not
null,
if it's null, then we can't have a valid token
and if it's not null, if expiry date and now the cool thing is on date here, we can call isAfter
and here want to check if it's after
now because if it's after now, then it's valid.
So if we have an expiry date and it hasn't parsed yet, so it's in the future, then I will return
_token
and actually we should also add one other check here,
we should check if token is not null because if the token is null, we also have a problem
but if the expiry date is not null and it's in the future and the token is not null, then we return
the token otherwise
and please keep in mind that with return, you finish this execution, you won't reach the next line if
you return here,
so we only reach that line if we don't make it into if,
so otherwise I'll return null as a token.
Now here in isAuth,
we can now use our token getter and find out if that is null because we have all the validation logic
in here,
the local validation logic I should say. So if this here returns null, we know we're not authenticated
because we have no token or a token that already expired.
So here we return token unequal to null
only if it's not equal to null,
we are authenticated,
if the token is equal to null, then we are not authenticated.
So this is the getter and now we can use that getter in the main.dart file here, on auth,
we can now call isAuth,
use that getter and if that is true, I of course want to render the product overview screen.
If it's false and we're not authenticated, then I want to allow the user to login or to sign up with
the AuthScreen, that's the logic there.
Now of course we'll have to do some work in the auth.dart file, in the providers folder though because
right now, we're never setting the token or the expiry date
and of course we have to set this,
otherwise this will always be false,
we never will have a token.
We have to set this here in _authenticate, in this method.
There we get our response and here we have the response data and
we're checking the response data for errors.
What we're not doing is when there is no error in the response data,
so if we're not throwing an exception here,
then of course I want to log my userId and I want to set my token and store the token here in memory and
so on.
So here, I want to set _token equal to response data and then ID token because remember
that on the Firebase response, you actually would get back an ID token field which contains that token,
so we're extracting the ID token from the response we're getting here.
We also want to set our userId, so _userId should be equal to response data and then
it's the local ID field here and you can see that in the official docs too, local ID is the ID of
the user. Now the expiry date is also something I want to set, the expiry date here of course has to be calculated
because the only thing we get back is expiresIn which only contains a string but in that string, we have
the number of seconds.
So we'll have to parse that string and turn it into a number
but then after turning it into a number, we have to derive a date from that. So expiry date should be
a datetime object
and there we can take the current timestamp
and now we only have to add this amount of seconds it takes until the token expires,
right
because current time plus amount of seconds until it expires gives us the timestamp when it will have
expired.
So we take the current timestamp and then we can call the add method which the datetime object conveniently
gives us and pass a duration into that, duration is a class provided by Dart to express durations
and here we want to set a duration in seconds because we're getting a duration in seconds and the duration
in seconds now is response
data expiresIn with a capital I,
so this key here
but keep in mind that's a string. Here
however, seconds takes an integer.
So we need to transform that into an integer,
otherwise we'll get an error later.
So here, we should call int.parse and wrap response data expiresIn into that int.parse call here. With
that, we're now setting this duration here with our parsed seconds and add this to the current timestamp
to derive the expiry date
and with that, we're storing that data which we need.
Now with all of that, we can call notify listeners here to update our user interface which we of course
have to do to for example trigger that consumer here. Let's give it a try,
let's do a full refresh here
and now let's try logging in with one of the users we created earlier.
So here, I'll reuse my dummy data like this, press login, see the spinner and that's looking good, we're
in the shop. We still can't load the products and that's normal because we know now that we're logged
in, we know that in our app here but we're not telling the server, we're not attaching the token to the
requests we're sending to the server.
So that's of course the next step,
make sure that we use that token which we do manage here in our auth.dart file, that we use that token
to also send it to the server
so that we're not the only one who knows that we're logged in.