Now of course it would be nice if we had some information in that CategoryMealsScreen, which is coming
up, about which category was loaded so that in here, we can actually display the right recipes for that
category.
So we would want to get that information about which category the user visited in that or on that page.
For that
in here, we can add a property,
category ID maybe which should be a string and another final property, category title
and of course, you can give these any names you want.
Then let's add a constructor by repeating the class name as you learned it
and there, let's assign values to this category ID and the category title.
So now when we create the category meal screen, we need to forward that information to that created screen.
So in category item thankfully, we can get that information.
We have the title already and the ID is also something we can expect there by simply adding it as another
argument here
we want to have in the constructor and another property we manage here and now in the place where
we create our category items,
so in the categories screen we simply have to forward that ID and thankfully, that is available here
in our catData,
so it's no problem to forward that. So now we have that in category item and there, we create that category
meals screen which now wants that ID and title.
Well since we have it here in the category item widget, it's no problem to forward it,
we can simply forward ID and title like this because since the select category method runs inside
of a single category item, we only have one clearly defined ID and title inside of this widget.
So now in the CategoryMealsScreen, we can use that and for example instead of showing the recipes here,
we could output the category title here which seems more appropriate. So if we save that and we go back
and I click on Italian, now we see Italian here in the appBar instead of just the recipes and if I go
to a different category, we see that different categories name here.
So that is how we can pass data into a new page if we load it like this, by using navigator push.
Now since I'm saying it like this, it already sounds like there also is a different way of loading pages,
right?
Let's have a look at that way too.