Besides the hero animation, there's another kind of animation or behavior you might know from some applications
and that is that you don't always have an appBar like this right from the start but only once you scroll
down on the screen,
the let's say image here becomes the app bar, so there's a nice animation between the image and the app bar
and that's also something which is fairly simple to implement with Flutter and I want to implement it
here on the product detail page. For that, let's go through the product detail page and in there,
the first step is that you replace your SingleChildScrollView here with a custom scroll view because
you basically need more control over how scrolling is handled because different things will now be scrolling
or we need to do different things when we scroll,
we need to change that image into the app bar, so kind of transform the image to the app bar and of course
that should be smoothly animated.
Now that sounds super complex but again, Flutter has got you covered.
We don't set up an appBar anymore because instead, we'll now manually animate a widget from our body
into the appBar over time and the custom scroll view here actually doesn't take a child but our list
of slivers.
Now that's a strange word, in the end slivers are just scrollable areas on the screen, so parts on the
screen that can scroll.
Now here, we need different slivers,
we need a sliver app bar which is a widget built into Flutter and we need a sliver list, sliver
list is basically your list view as a part of multiple slivers,
so in case your list view is a part of multiple scrollable things on a screen which should scroll
independently and where you want to have some special tricks when they scroll, then you will use sliver
list here.
Now let's start with the sliver list,
the sliver list needs a delegate that tells it how to render the content of the list. Now
please note that here, of course we have no list view but in the end that we'll just replace the column
here with all but the image.
So let's grab the size box, this text, this size box and this container.
Let's cut it all from that column and then here on the delegate of the sliver list, you should use the
sliver child list delegate which you instantiate and which simply takes a list of the items that should
be part of the sliver list
and these are the items I just copied. So let's paste them in there, into this delegate object and that's
already all for the sliver list.
Now for the sliver app bar,
that's the thing which should dynamically change into the app bar,
for that you need to configure it. You give it an expanded height which is the height that should have
if it's not the app bar but the image. Now previously there, we used the height of 300, so maybe
we stick to that, use a height of 300
here. I'll set pinned to true which means that the app bar will always be visible when we scroll,
it will not scroll out of view but instead it will simply change to an app bar and then stick at the top
and the rest of the content can scroll beneath that and we need to define the flexible space and that's
in the end
what should be inside of that app bar
but since it's a flexible space, also how it may change. For the flexible space, you should use a flexible
space bar
here and now there, we can set up a title and that would be our app bar title,
so what we had in the app bar title up there,
let's move it down there
and also the background and
that's the part which you'll not always see,
that's the part which you'll see if this is expanded
and here, I want to have my image. So it's here where we use this hero widget with the image inside of
it
and with that, we can get rid of that part down there, of that child with the column and use that hero
widget here as a background because that is what should be visible if this app bar is expanded.
Now let's have a look at this, this is already all.
Let's do a full restart and let's wait for that to reload
therefore and now let's go to that page here and now at the moment, we can't scroll this page.
What you do see is of course that you see your image here and here is the title, kind of difficult to
read, of course you could wrap this into a container and give this a background color or things like that,
for now here
it will do.
I want to make sure that this page is scrollable and of course it would be scrollable if we had a longer
product description which we might have in reality, here a little hack just for us to
test this is that I add a sized box with a height of let's say 800, that will add a sufficiently
high box at the bottom so that we can scroll this and as I scroll this, you see that this image changes
to the app bar and that's this nice effect which you get out of the box because it's built into Flutter.
And one thing here's the price,
I'm not happy with that look of course, there I want to add text align and set this to text align center.
I need to do this now,
didn't have to do it before because before we had the column which centered everything,
now we're not having that anymore
so I need to do it manually.
So this is this effect which is quite nice in my opinion and which gives us a nice look here,
again with only a few lines of code that had to be added.