Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, Let's Talk in the course,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
Okay, let's get started with this very insightful quote.
Here's a quote from John Baldoni: "The words a leader speaks are important,
of course.
But how they are delivered can make all the difference.
" So what we're saying is, the words that leaders speak are important.
That is, the content, that is what you say is important,
but how they are delivered can make all the difference.
Don't forget about the how.
The what and the how are wrapped together in your message.
So improving verbal communication skills is typically more
challenging than improving your written skills.
With written skills, you may have a little more time to think and plan.
So as much as possible, also apply that approach to the verbal side of things.
Think and plan before you speak.
For an upcoming presentation, you may have a week or two to think and plan,
the what and the how you will say something.
In an impromptu meeting,
you have maybe 3 seconds to think and plan about
how and what you're going to say.
Okay, we're going to help you in both of those categories.
Now let's check out the overview of this module.
So the bottom line of this module is how you can improve your verbal skills and
speak with impact and influence in your business settings.
Okay, now let's see the key topics we will cover.
First, some general effective communication tips in the verbal arena.
Next, the 5 C's and how they apply to the verbal concepts.
Then five key areas that are essential to your new leadership role: The first
being presentations because you'll be giving a lot those.
Meetings, you'll probably be having more meetings as well.
Stand-ups, that's the impromptu get-together with your team.
Walk-arounds, that's the casual walking around,
getting to know people and talking to them and
understanding them from a more impromptu approach.
Interviews, hiring new people.
All these are critical and essential and the core elements that I
think are important for your new role as a leader.
So this module will focus on the verbal communications,
hence "Let's Talk, " but also the interpersonal aspect of verbal communication.
Such things as body language, class, style, finesse, personality, humor even.
So this module will be the touchy-feely module.
So certainly the emphasis will be verbal communication skills,
but let's face it.
If you only spoke in monotone and never smiled,
had poor manners, and was not available to your team,
do you think anyone would listen to any message that you spoke?
Uh, no!
These will all be described and presented following
the theme of the software engineer, you,
in your new role as delegated from your manager to lead and build a team.
I will first describe the topic or concept and then may also show specific
poor (things not to do) and good (things to do) examples,
so you can see the differences.
Another important thing I want to emphasize is that
when you are being verbal (talking), there is also the visual side of it as well.
That is, people are observing and watching you,
whether it is conscious or subconscious in the observers.
Therefore I will also be addressing the visual aspects
of you speaking or talking as well. Alright, let's get started.