To lead off this course,
I'd like to start with this section that contains basic and
helpful tips on verbal communication that you can begin using with
your team and your projects right away.
Okay, let's see what they are.
You may think that content is king,
but your audiences need more than content and by audience,
I mean anyone you are speaking with or to.
A single person, group, your team, and even a whole auditorium.
You may believe that the content of your speeches and presentations,
what you think of as your message, creates the influence you are aiming for,
but I have a different point of view.
But I believe you are the one who's creating the influence, not the content.
And the reason is simple.
You are the message.
Okay, here is what I want you not to do.
For example, read the whole memo, word by word, and then say, any questions?
That just does not work.
Here is what I would like you to do.
Be clear and concise, summarize and crystallize the message,
and present it with passion and confidence.
So here's a tip.
Your audiences usually cannot separate the message
or content from the messenger, hence the messenger,
that is you, must be on point, professional,
and prepared.
Now let's make the complex simple.
Always make the complex simple.
Your employees and customers are being bombarded 24/7 by information,
making it hard for them to hear, listen,
and retain information from you.
In the busy and hectic world today,
simplicity has never been more powerful or necessary.
Now effective leaders distill complex thoughts and strategies into simple,
memorable terms that colleagues and customers can grasp and act upon.
If you're having trouble distilling something to its essence,
it may be that you don't understand it.
So dig deeper, understand it, simplify.
Also, look out for technical jargon and business speak.
These add complexity to your message and make it harder for others
to really understand what you're trying to say.
Okay, here is what not to do.
"We will soon have the user-defined functions and other stored
procedures ready by the end of the week.
" Even though that's true and even thought that's the real details,
that's not what I really want you to say to your customers.
Here is what I'd like you to do.
"The customer will have the month-end report on Thursday, 12/10.
" So we went from 17 to 11 words, we used the customer's terminology,
and made the message very clear.
Okay, here's a tip.
Say you mean in as few words as possible.
After you write a memo or a status report or a presentation,
take a look at it and actually think, can I make this a little shorter and a little more simple?