Okay, the first is clear.
Remember, that's transparent and able to see through.
So here is an example of what I do not want you to do.
You might write,
"I think last week we talked about adding some things or ideas
to the agenda that we need to talk about.
But then Joe brought up something that I don't
remember about improving the agenda…, " etc.
Too much.
Too much chitchat.
What are we really trying to say?
Here is how it should read: "The purpose of this note is to
define a new process for creating meeting agendas.
" It's that simple.
It's very clear.
Remember, clear communication always has a clear purpose.
So what is the purpose?
Whenever you sit down to write a document,
take a few seconds to ask yourself, why am I writing this?
What do I need from the reader?
Okay, that's the purpose.
Okay, let's go on to the next 5 C.
Concise.
That's using as few words as possible to give the necessary
information or compressed in order to be brief.
As you read and review your written documents,
see if there is a way you can shorten them.
Remove words or sentences or even paragraphs.
Leave nothing but the essential message you're trying to communicate.
Okay, again, here is an example of what not to do.
"We think that by the time the team finishes migrating
to the new version of Bootstrap, and we believe it will be right,
it should be November 1st.
" Well, here is how it should read.
"Bootstrap task target completion date: November 1st.
" That's it.
That is the date that we're going to be complete.
Clear and concise.
Okay.
So we've covered clear and concise.
Because of the volume of emails and other materials we send and receive,
and because emails are often misinterpreted,
it's important to write emails clearly and concisely.
It may take you just as long to write short emails as
it took you to write long emails, quite frankly; however,
even if this is the case, you will help your coworkers,
clients,
or employees to be more productive because you'll be
adding less clutter to their inboxes,
making it easier for them to respond to you.
Okay, now let's see how to be polite and to write diplomatically.
Be courteous.
That is,
be polite in a way that shows consideration of others and/or good manners.
Be polite and write diplomatically; even in a declaration of war,
one observes the rules of politeness.
That's a quote by Bismarck, okay?
Okay, so here is an example again of what not to do.
"Did you really delete that stuff?
That is just not what you should have done at all!
" And here is how it should read.
"I understand that the4 files were removed.
Do we have an options of recovering those files?
Can we meet later?
" There is no blame, there is no your fault,
or whatever; it's very,
very diplomatic and very courteous and it also talks about the problem.
They've been removed, but no blame, as well as,
can we meet later and figure out how to solve it.
Well written. Okay, on to the next.