You have heard term, "I am all ears, " but that's easier said than done.
It seems we humans like to talk a lot so we need to
think and plan in order to listen more.
Listen with your eyes as well as your ears.
The ears is the easy part, but when you listen with your eyes,
you are listening, or should I say watching,
for visual cues--that is body language,
to get a read on how they are feeling and/or reacting to your conversation.
Stop, look, and listen.
Take a pause for a minute.
It is almost like you want to be a bystander,
watching and listening to your own conversation.
Think about what is being said and how it is being said.
This takes some practice,
but also gives you a lot of insight into the conversation and the message.
Remember that effective communication is two-way.
Good leaders know how to ask good questions and then
listen with both their eyes and their ears.
It's easy to be focused on getting your message out,
or persuading others, that you don't tune in to what you see and hear.
Because you're in a position of authority,
the stakes are even higher because you won't always get direct feedback.
You need to read between the lines, listen and hear what is coming back to you.
Here is what I'd like you not to do.
Of course, do all the talking and I see people do this all the time.
It's a turnoff.
What I would like you to do is initiate dialog and then just
sit back and listen; you'll learn a lot.
Okay, here's a tip.
Look for the nonverbal cues.
Sometimes a person's body language may tell you everything you need to know.
Your voice counts and I don't mean politically.
There are several things that can literally affect your voice quality.
So to improve your voice, you have to minimize the tension in your body.
The first thing you need to realize is that fear or nervousness
of speaking can really affect your voice.
So maybe before an important talk or presentation,
do something that for you is relaxing.
Maybe a short walk, meditation, or something like that.
Start with your posture.
Undesirable posture habits shorten, narrow and twist your sound box.
Be sure you are distributing your weight between your left and your right
foot and balancing from heel to the ball of your foot.
Have a nice, comfortable stance with good posture and you'll breathe better,
which supports the voice and how it will carry.
Your breathing,
and you should stand upright so that your lungs can expand freely.
This might sound silly, but it's not.
As I walk to my presentations,
I stop and I stretch my arms way over my head and I stretch my body.
It not only feels good, but I feel a little taller, so to speak.
It's interesting.
I feel better and I think my lungs work better.
Here's what I'd like you not to do.
Be stressed, tired or have slumped shoulders.
Visually it doesn't look good and it also will affect the quality of your voice.
Here is what I'd like you to do.
Look tall, look straight, have good posture, and breathe easy.
Okay, here's a tip.
Be rested and relaxed before a big presentation.
Maybe get a little more sleep, you know,
maybe have some fluids, just get relaxed,
do some meditation and your voice will be better and
therefore your presentation will be better.
There is great power in your voice and speech.
If you get up in front of others with the aim of delivering information,
you could fail, not realizing the power of your voice and speech.
If, however, in addition to your great content,
you focus on using your voice, body language,
and other tools of performance we discussed,
this will get listeners on your wave length concerning your
content and you'll be well on your way to success.
As ideas and the urgency of your message emerge and you paint
what you're saying with a broad or fine stroke,
your vocal skills will give you both power and subtlety.
Speech is the vital external expression of what you think, know, and intend.
Use your voice and your passion to convince others to
enrich your connection with them and you'll be well on your
way to a successful presentation. Alright, now let's check out Michael's 5 C's.