Consistent.
Able to maintain a particular standard or repeat a particular
activity or artifact with minimal variation.
Okay, here is an example of what not to do, okay?
Each status email you send out say on project X, is a different format.
It may even have a different subject, there may be different headings,
etc., and not easily recognizable by the recipient or the reader,
and here is what I want you to do, okay?
Each status email sent out to the team is a consistent and
standard format so the reader knows exactly what to expect and
it's easy to read and comprehend.
Okay,
we're going to go into great detail on email format
and structure later in this module.
Okay, let's go on to the last one, compelling.
The last of Michael's 5 C's is compelling.
That's attracting strong interest and attention in
the material that you've written.
Okay, here is an example of what not to do.
I have a couple subject lines, say, for an email for example.
One is status report.
Well, what does that mean?
Whose status report?
What is it about?
What project?
Unclear, not compelling, I might delete it.
Next example, OMS.
What does that mean?
What's OMS?
Maybe I'm even on the OMS project, but it is a status report?
What is it?
I do not know.
Not clear, not compelling, probably not going to open it.
Now here is another example,
as a subject in an email: Windows Uplift Project: Status and Actions for 11/21.
It gives me a lot of information.
I know it's the Windows Uplift project, I know it has to do with the status,
oh, and there's actions.
I wonder if I have actions, and it's for 11/21; I know the date.
Much better and I'm sure you can get creative and
write them even better than I can.
Now part of writing effective email copy is nailing down that subject line.
The subject line is like the gatekeeper of your email.
No one gets to read your email if they're not interested or
compelled to read and that interest is determined almost wholly
by the subject line of the email.
Now of course, the sender name can play a role as well.
For example,
if you got an email from the president of your company and the
subject line just had some gobbledygook in it,
my guess is you would still open it.
So the sender does have some cache if you will in the compelling
argument here of whether you should open or not,
but I'm really focusing on the subject and how important
it is to write great subject lines, and again,
we'll have a whole section devoted to emails and
writing emails later in this module.
Now let's summarize Michael's 5 C's.
Here's a tip.
Make a little post-it, yep, let's go old school.
You can put it next to you.
I put it on my computer monitor or maybe you put it somewhere on your desk,
so you can easily glance over to it to be sure
you're always following the 5 C's.
You will write many emails every day, documents every day,
presentations; all of them should follow the 5 C's.
It's very easy and takes very little time to do.
Remember, you need to be clear, concise,
courteous, consistent, and compelling in your communications.
They will lead to enhanced credibility resulting in your success. Now let's see what's in store for the remaining portions of this module.