So to this point in the module,
we have covered general tips and guidance for improving your verbal,
speech, and interpersonal skills.
Remember, you are now leading a team, working with customers,
spending more time with your management,
so I see that you need to have a set of rock-solid,
let's-talk skills in the following areas or scenarios.
The first is presentations, meetings, stand-ups, walk-arounds, and interviews.
These are the five key areas that I think are vital and important
to your success in your new role as leader.
Okay, and of course, they're all supported by my 5 C's.
Okay, now let's dive into presentations.
Here is the section on effective presentations.
Now what you don't want to hear from your audience after you present is,
can I bring a pillow and blanket to your next presentation?
And what you do want to hear when you complete your presentation is,
wow, that was really great!
Can you tell me more about?
For me,
it took a few years to get from attendees bringing pillows to my
presentations to where attendees felt that their time was well spent, so be patient and follow these simple guidelines that will speed you to success.