The 4 P's to successful presentations.
We touched on these in the previous module.
Plan, prepare, practice, and present.
Now the first two relate to writing of the presentation.
That was in Know Your ABC's, in the lsat module.
Practice and present, those are related to delivering your presentation.
The verbal and interpersonal part, and those two we'll cover now in detail.
Practice, practice, practice, and yes, practice makes perfect.
Stand in front of the mirror and watch yourself.
Are your hands at your sides?
Well, they shouldn't be.
Hands should be moving, not all over the place, either.
Pretend you are holding a basketball.
Your hand should be placed something like that when you move.
So before a presentation,
I will stand in front of a mirror in my hotel room or home and present.
I can see myself, I can hear myself speak.
This provides great real-time feedback.
So hear yourself speak.
Yes, actually listen to yourself speak.
You will be amazed at how you sound and how you can make corrections to improve.
You may even consider recording yourself and listening to that.
Project your voice loud enough and clear enough and even consider a
microphone based on the size of the audience and the room.
Try to not memorize written texts,
otherwise your verbal cadence will be stiff and monotone.
Try to understand the topic to the best of your ability so you can communicate
it well during the presentation and meet the time limit.
Now you can memorize things,
but just memorize high-level topics or concepts that
later you can provide more detail.
Okay, let's do it one more time.
Practice for a coworker or manager and get their feedback
on your presentation skills and yes, practice does make perfect.
Here's a tip.
Remember,
you take classes on technical topics to be better engineers so
putting time into learning how to better communicate will be
well worth your investment; trust me.
Alright, are you feeling confident? Let's see.