Believe or not, meetings are a wealth of potential productivity.
I mean, why is that people don't want to go to meetings?
Are they long, boring, even stupid?
Nothing seems to get done?
Well, yes, those are all true at times, but if you follow my simple process,
you will have productive and effective meetings,
maximizing the progress of your projects,
improving your team's morale,
and having your customers feeling that their time was well spent,
and maybe even have your attendees actually looking
forward to attending your next meeting.
Imagine that!
Contrary to popular belief,
you don't just show up and expect a meeting to be productive.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm all for stand-ups and quick meetings as needed,
but for important, productive,
and critical meetings with key members of your company or your customer,
I recommend the following steps.
Plan, prepare, lead, and the follow-up.
Now the first two relate to writing and that's,
of course, as part of this module for know your ABC's.
The next two, they have to do with leading your meeting,
the lead part and the follow and those will be covered in
the communication module coming next, the verbal communication.
Okay,
so in this section we will focus on the planning and preparing for your meeting,
since they have an emphasis of course, on writing skills,
and in the Let's Talk module we will focus on your
leadership skills necessary for the leading of the meeting
and the followup of the meeting.
Okay, now let's plan our first meeting as a leader.
Now here are your actions as a leader for planning a meeting.
What is the purpose of your meeting?
Be sure you really need the meeting in the first place.
Could I solve this problem with a phone call, a standup or a casual drop-in?
What do you want out of the meeting?
Know your expected outcome.
Make sure your agenda reflects exactly what you want out of the
meeting and we'll have more on the agenda later.
So what do you want accomplished?
So develop a preliminary agenda,
jot down the topics you feel need to be covered and we'll talk
more on the agenda in the next few slides.
Who should attend?
Determine who needs to be there and how they would contribute.
Don't leave out key subject matter experts or stakeholders that you will need.
Also, think about what are the roles you need as opposed to the person?
Sometimes thinking of the roles you need will help identify the people.
For example, I need some architectural inputs regarding our application stack.
I think I might need to invite Harper since she is a key
architect with the experience I need.
What is the best date and time for the best attendance?
There is usually one or two really key people that need to
attend so be sure their calendars are free.
Use your calendar system or make a call to them or
their admin to double check beforehand.
How far in advance will you send the meeting request?
Also maybe, send out a preliminary agenda with the meeting invite.
Note I said preliminary.
You may certainly add,
change or delete agenda items or attendees since business is dynamic.
You may also inform the attendees what they need to prepare for.
Maybe some additional reading material or additional handouts that
you may have attached to the meeting request.
Who is required to attend and who is optional?
Not everyone you want to invite may be required and if your
calendar system enables optional attendees,
please use it and where is the best location for the meeting?
Be sure to confirm your location, that is reserve it,
prior to sending out the invite.
Be sure to secure any additional equipment,
computers, overhead, whiteboards, etc., prior to the meeting.
And will the meeting be virtual or be part in-person and part virtual?
Again,
some meetings are totally virtual and some are part physical and
maybe you have some remote sites that will call in.
I suggest you first set up a web conference,
get all the relevant information, phone number,
URL links, etc., and then when you send out the meeting request,
include those.
You may also do them separately,
but what happens is that you have two meetings on the same time,
one for the normal meeting invite,
maybe through your email system and the other for the web conference invite.
I don't two at one time; it may be confusing to the
attendees and maybe even yourself.
So discover how all that works and I suggest only one meeting invite
with all the relevant information and here's a tip.
The more people you have in the meeting that are not critical to its success,
the greater likelihood that you would not achieve your
purpose or you may require another meeting,
so don't over invite. Okay, now let's take a look at the importance of an agenda.