Hi everyone.
My name is Michael Krasowski and welcome to my course,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
Here is a quick fact for you.
A survey of corporate recruiters reported that 86% of recruiters said
that strong communication skills were a priority.
They didn't say required or even nice to have; they said, a priority.
So you've come to the right place.
This course is for you.
In this course we're going to cover the following major topic and themes.
We will explore why leadership and communication are interconnected,
intertwined, interwoven,
and that your potential as a leader will be dependent upon your
ability to effectively communicate with others.
We will discuss just what does leadership mean and
the qualities of great leaders.
Next,
we'll discuss why writing skills are critical to your success and we
will focus on the following key areas: presentations,
meetings, status reports, emails, and interviews.
We'll also examine why verbal and interpersonal skills are
essential for your success as well and we will focus on the
following key areas such as presentations,
meetings, stand-ups, walk-arounds, and interviews.
By the end of this course,
you will know how to begin your journey as a leader or manager with
the confidence in skills necessary for your success.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to improving your
skills with my Pluralsight course, Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.