Now let's see how we can align the team skills to the
projects and the business goals.
Well, first of course, we need requirements.
So what do the team members actually need?
You'll want to ask them, what do you think you need to get your job done?
Next, we want to look a little closer at the projects themselves.
The projects may show to us certain technologies and skills
we may need to accomplish that project.
And third, we want to take a broader, longer-term look.
Where is the industry going?
Maybe we have some long-term skills that we're going to need to keep up on.
Okay, so the skill needs for what the members need.
So interview team members as to what they think they need to learn.
We want to review the entire list with the team.
You know, maybe some examples of things like Visual Studio,
SQL Server, HTML5, etc.
What are all the skills or tools the team thinks
they need to accomplish the goals?
They've already sat with the team,
they understand the tasks and they understand the projects
and the alignment to the business as well.
Now what do we think the projects might need?
Okay,
we want to determine what technical skills will be
needed for the priority projects.
For example, maybe a certain project is really going to need Bootstrap and HTML5,
MVC, etc.
Maybe we even need some presentation skills.
You know, so we put those skill lists together as well.
And lastly, we want to look at the longer term.
We want to stay abreast as to where the industry is moving
and what new technologies look promising.
Maybe there are some new IDEs for developing native mobile apps.
Maybe Oracle, maybe other things like that.
Those would be longer term, less priority, but we still want them on our radar.
Okay, so now that we have the team skills requirements that we think we need,
let's see how we can make that happen.
Now that we know the requirements,
we want to go about actually building those team skills.
Okay, so we want to review the project based skills list.
We want to review the team members skills list,
and we also want to review the longer term skills that we might need downstream.
We will want to integrate those lists, put them together.
There may be some overlap, there may be some gaps.
We want to prioritize those skills.
Typically they're going to be prioritized based on the priority projects.
We may want to develop a training plan, okay?
What are the training tasks we need to do?
What's the schedule?
We want to look at the budget, and of course,
we want Pluralsight as part of your plan; of course!
Maybe we want to implement the plan, just work the plan!
And repeat.
Maybe you want to repeat this process of looking at the skills
and readjusting your training plan quarterly,
or what makes best sense for your organization.
Now it may only take about an hour or two of a meeting
with your team to update your plan,
so once your plan is in place and you've gathered the skills,
the ongoing maintenance of this is really not very much
and besides the training benefits, of course,
you are showing your team that you care about them.
You're showing you want the best for the team, and this results in inspiring motivation.