Now I'll talk about the verbal and interpersonal side of meetings.
In one sense, leading a meeting is a little bit like giving a presentation.
That is, all eyes are on you and you are responsible for its success.
So, how are you presenting yourself?
Have a positive attitude and come ready for work.
How do you hold yourself?
Again,
have good posture and try and sit in a spot so you
can see and observe all attendees.
What should you wear?
Well, as with presentations, what you wear is important.
Maintain good eye contact.
This creates a connection with your attendees.
Remember, you're the focus when you are leading the meeting.
They are watching and learning from you,
and make a point to actively engage attendees.
Be inclusive.
They will either participate by being on the agenda,
maybe through discussions, and lastly through questions.
Make sure everyone has had a chance to say something.
And leverage their attendance.
I mean,
why would you invite them if you didn't want them to participate in some way?
Make sure they have all been involved, and how are the attendees feeling?
Check for body language and other visual cues to determine how
the meeting is going and make corrections.
A correction might mean an impromptu question to someone, things like that.
And here's a tip.
No matter how interesting you think your agenda is,
they will be watching you because you are the message.
Now let's see what I don't want you to do as a meeting leader.
So here is the bad and the ugly.
These are the things I don't want you to do when leading a meeting.
First off, never arrive late.
You want everyone to arrive on time and be punctual,
so if you're late, that sets the wrong precedence.
Not introducing everyone.
So always introduce everyone.
Everyone wants to feel included and others will know who to
ask when different questions come up.
Some people avoid eye contact.
Boy!
I cannot stand that, so always good eye contact.
And also not speaking with commitment.
People will pick up on that and think the meeting is kind of
soft and easy and maybe they won't want to stand up and pick
up commitments themselves.
Not being courteous.
Even if you disagree, be strong, be a leader, and always be courteous.
And focusing on the person.
What I mean by that is, if something goes wrong,
focus on the problem and how you're going to solve it,
not the person or what they did wrong.
And lastly, not confirming commitments.
You always must confirm commitments; they are very, very important.
Speaking of commitments,
commitments may be one of the most important elements or outcomes of a meeting. Let's see an example.