Now you will need to use your verbal and leadership skills to ensure
proper actions or determine the right persons are assigned and are
committed to the completion of the task and of course,
by a certain date.
It all gets written down during the meeting,
published in the meeting notes, and tracked by you as a meeting leader.
Okay, okay, time for a pop quiz.
Are you ready?
Alright.
Five frogs are sitting on a log.
Four decide to jump off.
How many are left?
Well, what do you think?
One?
That's what I thought, too, but it's five.
Because deciding is different than doing.
So the moral of the story: decisions are worthless
unless you turn them into commitments.
So, what's a commitment?
Let's break one down.
A commitment is made up of three parts.
The first is who owns the commitment, also known as the owner.
Next, what the commitment is.
That is, what task they will do, also known as the deliverable.
And lastly, by when?
The due date.
And what I like to add to the due date is just how,
that is what context will the delivery of the test take place?
For example,
will the owner send an email with the results or maybe be on
the agenda for the next time with the answer,
or what?
Now let's go through a detailed example.
I think we need to back up the database nightly, says Joe.
That sounds reasonable; anyone have any other suggestions, says the leader?
Silence, so I guess not.
Okay, so Joe, can you perform the backups nightly, says the leader?
That's the what.
That's the deliverable that's being asked.
Yes, says Joe.
Okay, now we know who the owner is.
Okay, great.
Joe what date will have that in place, says the leader?
November 20, and add me to the agenda, says Joe.
So now we have the when and the delivery.
In other words,
it will be delivered in the next meeting by way of an agenda item.
And of course, thank you, Joe.
I will note your action in the notes.
Okay, so that was a simple example of how you get the what--the deliverable,
the who--the owner, and when and how that will be delivered.
Alright, now let's discuss meeting commitment guidelines.
Here are some simple guidelines to help you with getting the
commitments you need to be successful in your meetings.
At the end of each topic in a meeting,
pause to agree on the next steps and establish specific
commitments with clear deadlines.
Let people know they can negotiate at the time they make the commitments,
especially with regard to due dates.
They may have other things on their plate,
other things going on and so it's a good time to talk,
decide hey, this will be the good time when I can deliver.
And don't use automatic by the next meeting as the due date.
Be thoughtful about what timing makes the most sense.
Make clear that you expect each commitment will be fulfilled
as agreed upon and if something comes up,
you expect they'll reach out to discuss the change.
So how I do it in my meetings is,
absolutely with no exception we will fulfill the commitment.
But of course!
Life happens!
Call or email with any changes so we can make notes and move forward.
And lastly,
assign someone to check in at appropriate intervals to ensure
the commitments will be kept as promised or reevaluated if
something unexpectedly comes up.
Now if the commitment dates are pretty short,
you may not need this, but if commitment dates are pretty long,
two, three, four weeks or even longer,
you're going to need to keep track of each of those and see how they're doing. Okay, now let's drill in on ownership and what that means.