The interview.
Coming to an office near you.
So continuing with our theme of this course,
you are now responsible to hire and build your team.
Before you hire anyone,
you will likely have to interview candidates to join your team.
They may come from other departments or outside your company.
It is very important to get the right people for the job.
So let's see how you can improve your interviewing process.
Let's face it.
Knowing how to interview can be a challenge.
Conducting an interview isn't always fun and it doesn't
come all that naturally to people.
Why?
Well, most interviewers are unprepared with the appropriate interview questions.
In fact, unprepared or at least uncomfortable with the entire process.
Actually,
I love it and I look forward to it because I'm prepared and I
can't wait to add new people to my team.
So don't take this lightly because the stakes are high in terms of building
your team and furthering your own and your team's success.
This section will give you the basics so you can find and keep the best.
"Great vision without great people is irrelevant,
" by Jim Collins and his book, Good to Great.
You might add this book to your professional improvement reading list,
by the way; it's a great read.
After all, a company is only as good as the people it keeps and in your new role,
now you have this responsibility on your shoulders. I believe that people and only people is what makes the world go around.