Here are some simple rules of thumb to think about
prior to doing your walk-arounds.
Make walking around just part of your normal routine.
Dropping in on employees' work spaces for an informal chat is most
effective if you don't do it on some sort of fixed schedule since
you'll realize the greatest returns by seeing what's going on when
people aren't prepared for you.
But do plan for a bit of walking around on your own calendar every day,
if you can possibly do that for maybe, you know,
a few minutes here and a few minutes there.
The more often you do it, the more benefits you'll realize.
Certainly, don't bring a committee.
This is just about you personally.
Walking around works best as a continual stream of one-on-one
conversations with individual employees over a series of time.
Bringing aides or assistants with you would probably just inhibit the
discussion by making people feel more self-conscious,
or worse, make them feel your ganging up on them.
If you really do need a meeting with several people, then go call a meeting.
Include everybody.
We have talked a lot about inclusion and that notion
that makes great leaders even greater.
So in all aspects of leadership and here is just
another example of using inclusion.
As anyone might guess who is familiar with how office rumor mills get spinning,
dropping in on some folks more often than others is likely
to create the wrong kind of impression.
Try to spend roughly the same amount of time,
not necessarily all the same day or the same week,
but over the long run with each person who reports to you.
And follow up with answers.
You may get some questions.
So if you can't answer an employee's question off the top of your head,
that's fine.
Don't forget to get back to him or her with the answer later;
it's just common courtesy and it builds trust,
and it also shows you listen and care and if the question
and the answer were of great importance,
you might even send out an email saying,
oh by the way.
Mary had this great question and I answered it and
thought I should share that with everyone.
It shows you another level of inclusion of that person's question.
Next, don't criticize.
Don't be critical.
Remember, you're kind of on a fact-finding mission to get a pulse,
so with the secondary purpose of building rapport.
So to avoid undermining those names,
if you find that an employee isn't performing his or her job correctly,
don't attempt to change the behavior on the spot.
Just make a note of it and address the problem at a later time.
Maybe if you have one-on-one meetings or in a private setting, okay?
Next, don't overdo it.
Don't leave people feeling that you're always looking over their shoulders.
Wander around often enough to get a good feel for what's going on,
but not too often or it becomes a distraction.
You'll get the feel for it.
You'll figure it out.
Here's a tip.
The higher up you are in the organization,
the more flattered you will feel when you poke your head in and say hi.
So again,
in our scenario you're basically the team leader and there is just one level up,
but you can imagine that if the CEO of your company popped
his or head into your office and said, hey,
you got a second to talk about something?
You'd say, wow, who me?
So you feel really good about that when people come to you and say,
hey, let's talk.
So again,
that org chart and later in your career when you're higher up the org chart,
don't forget this technique.
It makes people feel good and included and special.
Now here are some rules of thumb related to the
actual execution of walking around.
First of course, relax.
People will sense your genuineness and casualness
and they'll respond accordingly.
Stiff or formal conversation will probably lead to
equally rigid and stiff responses.
Listen and observe more than you talk.
Use more of an active listening approach with your team.
When people feel you are hearing them,
they'll probably seem to be more sincere and tell you more.
Ask for feedback and suggestions and recognize good ideas.
Ask each employee for his or her thoughts about how
to improve products or processes, sales,
service, whatever.
Then if someone's idea leads to a positive result,
make it known whose suggestion it was and show you're
ready to give credit where credit is due.
Let everyone know that you want ideas to make things
better and as a leader in your new role,
people may think that your opinions and ideas are right,
so hold back from saying what you think all the time.
The goal is to see what others think and what others have to say.
Use the time for spontaneous or just-in-time recognition.
If you see something good, compliment the person.
This is a perfect way to show your gratitude.
So maybe the walk-around is simply poking your head in the office and saying,
hey, Joe, thanks for fixing that stored proc that didn't work the other day; boy,
that really saved us a lot of time.
Hey, have a good day, and you move on.
20 seconds of your time and that person feels good,
recognized, included, and motivated.
This is not for serious issues.
Don't use this time to judge or critique.
This may make people nervous when you're around and you don't want that.
If you see something that concerns you, talk to the person later in private,
maybe one on one in your office or a conference room.
Answer questions openly and honestly,
but you won't have all the answers and if you don't know,
no worry.
Find out and then follow up and if you can't share something, say so.
Hey, that's a little private right now,
corporate is still deciding it; I'm unable to share that,
but when I know, I will tell you.
So telling half-truths can break down trust, so don't do that.
Communicate.
Share company goals or philosophies, values,
or vision or whatever you need to share when you're walking around.
You have many opportunities to mutually share information that
helps everyone understand and do their jobs better.
Chat.
Effective organizations aren't all about work, work, work.
They're also about building relationships.
Maybe you want to learn the names of your staff's kids,
find out what they love to do or where they're going on vacation.
Maybe even joke or laugh or have fun.
I really like joking, laughing, and having fun with my teammates.
You may be surprised at how great it feels to relate on a
personal level with the people in your office.
Now here's a tip.
This make take some practice, but give it a try.
It is so worthwhile.
Alright, now let's move on to the next section on the verbal skills of interviewing.