Now let's talk about why interviewing is such an important
skill and likely a new skill that you need.
You have been tasked to build or grow your team and only with your
personal involvement can you really build a better team.
Do not rely on HR to do it for you.
You need to be part of the process.
The last thing you want is for your HR or boss to force someone on you.
Yes, that may happen, but if you have a process,
you are more likely to be in control or be prepared to
participate as much as possible in other processes.
You want to be sure the new person meets your requirements.
There is no point in hiring someone who does not meet your requirements.
That just means more work and more headaches.
You want to build your interviewing skills.
The better your skills at interviewing,
the better quality people you will be hiring.
Better for you, your team, and your company and the new hire.
It's also a career builder as well.
The better interviewing skills you have may help you downstream when you
are being interviewed yourself for the next new job.
Okay, now let's cover a simple interviewing process to get you started.
If you don't think about what you need in a new employee ahead of time,
you will have a much harder time knowing when you find him or her,
so follow this simple process.
In preparation for the interviewing process,
you must follow company HR standards and policy.
I'm never going to suggest that you work around those or ignore those,
so check with your manager and/or your HR department and be sure
you understand your company's process first.
Maybe HR is responsible for posting open positions.
Maybe they want to hire from within first and then from the outside.
All that is good and you must follow your company's process.
Just be sure at some point you are part of the interview process and
many times HR will ask you for the new- hire skill requirements and
we're going to talk about that later.
Okay, so step 1, document and post.
So document and post your new-hire skill requirements and we will go
through an example of documenting on the next slide,
so hold on there.
Then post your requirements either through existing company practices or
say on Indeed or LinkedIn or other social or business portals that your
company has approved or that you can go use.
Next, screen and phone.
Okay, in this step,
your responses are starting to come in from where you posted them.
Rank them against your requirements.
Believe me,
you may get some that aren't even close to what you need
and you may get dozens or hundreds.
No worries.
That's expected.
Now when you find candidates that come close,
remember, no one walks on water, so don't look for the perfect response.
Then you're going to put them in the pile for the phone interview,
which will be the next step.
Some people jump right to face to face and I think
that's basically a waste of time, not only for you,
but to the candidate as well.
And what do you ask on the phone?
Well, that's coming up on the next couple slides as well.
Step 3.
In-person interview and test.
If they satisfy your phone interview,
then set up a time for them to come into your office
for the face-to-face interview.
You might need to coordinate schedules with not
only yourself and the interviewee,
but also with one or more of your team members if you want
them involved as well and I suggest that.
For the in-person interview, we provide a written test at our company.
This allows us to have an objective score based on their answers.
We also score on soft skills such as team work,
personality, attitude, motivation, and things like that.
This is certainly subjective, but in my opinion,
actually more important than the objective attributes that we test on.
The next step, follow-on interviews.
Usually one interview is not enough.
After you have interviewed your first round of candidates,
I suggest you narrow that down to two or three,
and then high a second interview with each.
Now the candidate is more relaxed usually and you can discuss job duties and
expectations in more detail and/or drill in on some of their answers from the
first interview to better understand the candidate.
Next comes selection.
Okay, you need to pick one.
Now you could rank each person with the scores,
technical scores and soft skills scores.
I suggest though that you pull your team together and
delegate the selection to the team.
Remember, we talked about delegation?
Now that takes some guts here on your part, but give it a try if you can.
Step 6 is what I call just paperwork.
HR or company paperwork that must get done.
So you need that to actually probably make this happen in
terms of really getting that person hired in.
Also, you need to have an offer letter extended to the number 1 candidate.
After they reply with "I accept,
" then you can inform the other candidates that they did not make it,
but you will keep them on file since they did so great.
Now if the person turns you down,
then pull the team together again and pick the next best candidate.
Now we're going to go into some of these steps in
more detail in the following slides.
So now let's prepare for our first interview.
Now let's drill into the document and post step.
So first, we're going to come up with all of our new-hire requirements,
what are all the things we need this person to fulfill.
Next,
we're going to come up with our list of interview
questions for the phone conversation.
This won't be a very long list.
You're just trying to vet them.
You have their resume and you're just trying to vet them to see
if you want them for the in-person interview.
Next,
you're going to come up with another list of interview
questions for the in-person interview.
Then you're going to come up with a list of test questions that you're
going to ask them to actually test their skills,
and next you're going to come up with, what is your selection rationale?
Your team should get together and discuss how will
you select the best candidate?
Okay, are you ready?
Alright, then let's post it online with the requirements we've put together.
We might use Indeed and things like that,
and we might even use some head-hunter companies to find the best candidates.
Now it's out there posted and we're anxious and ready to
receive any inquiries for the job position.
Here's an example and an approach to documenting your requirements.
First, get your team together and list your soft and hard skills.
Soft skills would be things like team work,
communication, people orientation, writing skills,
etc.
Hard skills maybe things like.
NET, SQL, C#, Bootstrap, jQuery, things like that.
You may have other requirements such as driving,
travel, relocation, so you'll want to itemize those as well.
Then for each item, give it a weight of importance (5,
10, 15, things like that).
All weights should total to 100 and what these weights are,
are weights of importance because when you actually provide,
or so when you actually select a candidate,
you will likely select them on the most points received.
It keeps it a little more objective and a little more fair.
Alright, once you've done this for each new hire,
you simply need to pull out your Word or Excel template and
quickly update it and away you'll go.
So once you lay out a whole list of soft skills and a whole list of
hard skills the first time and provide the weights,
when the time comes for the next new hire,
you've already done all the work involved and you can quickly update the
template and be ready for the next new-hire process.
Okay, let's move on to the phone interview questions.
So here's an approach to your phone interview questions.
Okay, prior to actually calling someone on the phone and interviewing them,
you've received several resumes.
You've gone through those and you've picked a few
that look like great candidates.
So for the phone interview,
you want to ask questions that allow you to pre-qualify them.
Again,
you don't want them to come into the office if they
don't meet some basic requirements.
So you need to determine then, what are the got-to-have requirements?
That's going to be a subset of your full requirements.
So we've already listed the full requirement set.
Now we're going to mark certain questions on there that you
think are appropriate for the phone interview,
okay?
So you'll want to ask questions that specifically tie
to the got-to-have requirements.
As an example,
I might be looking for the requirement that they're enthusiastic
and passionate; maybe the weighting is 15%.
I might look for a requirement of 5+_years of C# and I might say,
hey that's worth 10%.
And maybe I need a 4-year degree in a
computer-related topic; maybe that's another 5%.
So your short list, if you will,
your got-to-have requirements are going to be what you want to focus on,
on the phone and again, no detailed.
NET questions or technical questions.
You're just trying to pre-qualify them to see if they meet enough of
the soft skills and enough of the hard skills so they can come into
the office for a face-to-face interview.
Okay, now let's move on to the in-person interview.
If they are now right in front of you, in your office,
you have found that they are going to be worth your time.
And again, I do not recommend face to face without a phone interview.
Now the exceptions would be people you already know or you
have worked with or there's a phenomenal referral from
someone else in your company.
Then, go ahead and do that, certainly.
Okay, in-person interview questions.
For each requirement, you may have two or three questions and again,
you may not ask all the questions to each candidate.
Depending on their answers, depending on time,
and depending on the quality of their answers.
So have a full superset list of questions of which
maybe a subset will be actually asked.
And document your rating, okay?
Document what you think how well they did.
Is it right?
Is it wrong?
Partially right, partially wrong?
But try not to be too clinical.
It doesn't have to be exactly perfect.
We're looking for order of magnitude like yes,
they are pretty good in this area, etc.
I prefer one-on-one first.
In other words, you as the leader are interviewing them one-on-one and again,
it's a vetting process.
If you don't think they're worthy, the interview may be over and off they go.
If you think they are worthy,
then it's time to pass them then maybe to the team or other team members.
I wouldn't waste the time of yourself and the full team in the
interview only to find out after 10 minutes the person did
maybe great on the phone interview, but not so great in the face to face.
Then it just wastes more time.
I'm always a believer in conserving time.
Next, team member versus full team.
For example,
they've passed your face-to-face with you as the leader; now
you're going to pass them on to the team.
Should it be the entire team, the full team,
or maybe a particular member, or one member at a time?
That will be up to you to decide.
Again, I like to conserve time and I don't want to waste everyone else's time.
But sometimes an interviewee may feel uncomfortable or unsure because
they're staring across the table of five other people.
So, be careful about that as well. Okay, now let's look at the selection criteria.