Based on the candidates that passed your phone interview,
you can now schedule them to come into your office.
The goal of the in-person interview, of course,
is do they meet your threshold of requirements that we put
together in step 1 to join the team?
If so, they would be in the final selection list.
So have a prepared list of questions and based on the
requirements we wrote in step 1, you can prepare your list of written questions.
Here is where your verbal and interpersonal skills will come in handy.
Your job is to ask questions and to get them talking.
Involve your team in the interview process and in the decision process.
Remember,
your team members will work with the new hire probably more than you will.
Now you need to decide who on your team will also interview.
Is it one or two?
Maybe the full team, and if so, what is the form of discussion?
Everyone at once or one on one?
You make the call,
but whoever does the interviewing must always start
with the same list of questions,
though not all will be answered and they must always take
notes during and after the interview and you want to
review the results with the team.
So gather the team up, review all of the notes from each interview,
and have each person who conducted an interview
report out and share their experience.
Of course, always keep all documentation and notes.
Now, let's talk more about what you should ask.
Remember,
you're relying on your communication and leadership skills to pull
out and see what level of those skills they have.
Basically we just want to get them talking.
Remember,
we had three key areas we wanted to address earlier in the requirements?
Business, technical, communication and leadership.
And for me and my company, I focus on communication and leadership,
of course,
and my technical team will focus on the business and
technical aspects in their interviews.
So what do I like to do?
Well, get them talking.
So the most common and leading question is, can you tell me about yourself?
Now you really don't care too much about the specific answer to this question,
but more about the confidence, enthusiasm and passion that they display.
Also,
you might look at the speed of the response because the
speed of the response is the response.
Are they pausing, stalling or fumbling with the answer?
They may be showing a lack of self-awareness and self-esteem.
Now we're not trying to trip them up or confuse them,
or just want to let them run out and see what happens.
Come up with a list of open-ended questions to get them
talking like the one I suggested above.
Again, the point of the first interview,
if you will, in my case, in my interview,
is I'm looking for leadership and communication.
For the technical and business questions,
you would likely ask more specific and detailed questions and that is just
fine because that is exactly what you may be looking for.
Now let's see a more detailed sample question.
Here is another broad question, but just a little more focused.
Please rank these items in order of importance to
the success of an organization, and here are the items: technology,
customer service, communication, people,
and process and of course,
why they would rank them in the order they may rank them in.
What I like about a question like this is you will see where they gravitate
and what they might find themselves more comfortable.
If they say technology might be number one,
I feel they may be not the best, say for maybe a leadership role,
but may be perfect for a technical role,
and while they are answering, you are listening,
watching, learning and maybe thinking about some follow-on questions.
So you too can construct questions like this to get them talking,
and now that we have our in-person interviews complete or most of them,
we move to the next step, the follow-up interviews.
Next is the follow-on interview and it's here really more for completeness.
The goal is to further filter the list of in-person
interviews down to even a smaller list.
Say you have it narrowed down to two people and they are both just great.
Maybe a followup interview for both would be beneficial to really be sure.
Reflect, review,
and discuss the results of the in-person interviews with
your team and then do a down- select.
That term really just means reduce the list down,
I would say to two or three at the very most.
So if you've interviewed maybe four or five,
down-select down to two or three and then maybe those two or
three come in for the follow-on interviews.
Invite and schedule the next round and then this time,
a little more of a deep dive.
Now in this step, you want a very deep dive in your discussions.
Can you find a couple of topics to really do that deep dive on?
Maybe come up with a work scenario they might find
themselves in and how they might get out of it.
Also, as always, keep all documentation and notes.
Okay, let's now say you are complete,
you have all your feedback and you're ready to finally select the candidate to hire.