A final word.
Thank you very much for taking my course.
I, like you,
confronted my fears of migrating from technical roles
to leadership and management roles.
My metamorphosis was even a struggle at times and actually took a few years.
As I look back, I am glad and very rewarded by my career choices,
so I want to give you encouragement and confidence as well.
So if you have the opportunity for a leadership role,
go forward knowing you have my course as a guide to navigate the
challenges of leadership and I'm here to help as well.
Send me an email at any time if you have questions. Now let's check out my other Pluralsight courses that might be helpful to you.