First off,
anyone that answered yes to any of the previous slide's
question is a great candidate for this course.
This course targets software engineers who have reached a point in their
career when the business is expecting them to begin leading,
managing, and influencing others toward a common goal.
Software engineers have great technical skills,
but maybe lacking sufficient and essential leadership and
communication skills that are required to meet the performance
expectations of their management, company,
and possibly of themselves.
So this course is for technical and business
professionals considering a leadership role.
Technical and business professionals already in the leadership role,
but need a little more help.
Also,
anyone interested in developing and improving their
leadership and communication skills.
In my experiences in observing hundreds of people in my career,
I am suggesting to you the following. Never stop learning and improving your leadership and communication skills.