Welcome to the first module in this module we'll learn about how to use data science to solve a practical
problem and we will also introduce our first machine learning algorithm namely linear regression regression
is the workhorse of data science business analytics and research.
You'll find people using regression whenever someone is looking to model a phenomenon or make a prediction
or discover the hidden relationships among things.
Also I want to show you how to solve problems using Data Science.
So what kind of problem are you going to look at.
Well imagine that you're a film producer you provide money to make movies and when the movies make money
you make money.
And when the movies lose money you lose money.
But today you discover a problem.
You found out that you just put a whole bunch of money into a movie called Zombies rise again.
Part 5.
And if that doesn't sound like a terrible title for a film then I don't know what does worse yet you've
staked your reputation on this film.
You've mortgaged your house you've sold your car.
You've sold your grandmother's silverware to fund this film.
So is your money gone.
Will you go bankrupt.
Well to answer these questions you would have to be able to predict the future.
And this is where data science will come to the rescue.
Let's have a think about how a data scientist would approach this problem well first a data scientist
would carefully formulate the question that they're looking to answer why.
Well a clear and well formulated question will determine the research and it will also affect the kind
of data that you will go out and gather in fact.
Step 2 is gathering the data that will help us answer the question but real world data is also messy.
So we have to clean the data.
We have to look out for missing data or incomplete data.
We have to look out for errors and even bound formatting.
In fact we have to explore the data that we've gathered.
And often this means visualizing the data so that we can better understand what it is that we're working
with a graph or a chart is much more helpful than a table of numbers.
And after we've done all that.
The next step is actually training our algorithm using our computer to identify patterns in the data.
In our case that algorithm will be our linear regression.
And finally we have to evaluate the results.
How did our algorithm do.
Did it answer our question how accurate was our algorithm.
In answering our question the process that I've outlined here is the process data scientists used to
solve problems.
This is their workflow for understanding and making sense of the world.
So let's tackle that first step.
Let's formulate our question.
So here's our first shot at this.
How much money will our movie make now.
This is actually not a very good question.
The problem is is that this question is too vague.
For starters what do we actually mean with the word money.
Can we be more specific.
How about this.
How about how much revenue will our movie make now.
This is already a much better question because revenue is something that means something very specific
in the business world.
It's something that accountants actually measure and track and that means that we can actually find
data on movie revenue.
But what does movie revenue actually depend on.
Let's have a think about this.
Maybe it depends on the actors do movie starring Scarlett Johansson do particularly well or maybe depends
on the script or maybe what actually matters is the film's overall budget.
Because after all you have to pay good actors and you have to pay for special effects and marketing
costs a lot of money too.
So maybe the overall budget would be the best thing to look at.
So if that's the case then we have a hypothesis the movie budget could indeed be the thing to investigate.
After all there are many famous examples of big budget films that did exceptionally well at the box
office.
Movies like Avatar Titanic and The Avengers cost an absolute fortune but they were enormously successful.
But can the success of these movies tell us something about the success of our movie.
If we knew how much movies like Avatar The Avengers spent and how much they made Can we predict how
much we'll make.
Based on how much we're spending so let's go back to our original question and let's make it a little
bit more specific.
Can we use MOVIE BUDGETS TO PREDICT movie revenue now.
That's already a much better question.
Why.
Well it's testable and by testable I mean that we can actually check if there is a relationship between
movie budgets and movie revenue.
This is something that we can measure using data and linear regression.
And as data scientists we can actually look at this question and identify exactly what it is that we're
trying to predict namely the movie revenue a data scientist would call this the dependent variable and
in machine learning this would be called the target.
Also we can identify what it is that we're using to make the prediction namely the movie budgets a data
scientist would call the budgets the independent variable and in machine learning this would be called
a feature.
So now that we've formulated our question we can move on to Step Two.
We can go out there and gather some data and we'll do just that in the next lesson.
I'll see you there.