First let's add a markdown cell and some late tech notation so it changes to markdown put two pound
symbols there.
Right.
Correlation.
The latest notation we're gonna add it's gonna look like this good all the signs and then I'm going
to have the Greek symbol for row and then we're going have an underscore open curly brace.
X y.
Closing curly brace and then equals core c o r parentheses X comma Y closing parentheses.
And then to add all the signs.
Let's see what this looks like.
I think this makes a nice section heading just for completion.
Let's add two more pound symbols to Dollar Signs minus one point zero and then let's have the following
tag slash l e q and then we'll have slash row space underscore and then curly braces.
X Y and then another Q tag.
So slash at least Q plus one point zero and then two dollar signs at the end for the closing tag.
Now we've got the minimum and maximum values of the correlation in our heading as well and in the latest
notation the Greek symbol row is given like this with the slash and then the keyword we create the subscript
x y with the underscore and then the curly braces.
And finally we've used the slash and then Ellie Q for the less than or equal to symbol.
So now that we've added our section heading let's calculate the correlation between the average number
of rooms and the house price.
Now before we just punch in the python code what would you expect to see.
Do you think this correlation should be positive or negative.
Do you think that the correlation between the number of rooms and the property price is strong or weak.
So looking at the latex notation in our section heading here pick out a number in your head between
minus 1 and 1 Ready.
Did you make your guess.
Okay.
So to get the answer you simply call the core method on the series object so data square brackets single
quotes price dot c o r are open parentheses data square brackets single quotes R M will retrieve the
price column from our data frame.
So this is our series object and then call the core method on that series object and then as an argument
between the parentheses for this method we supply a single piece of information namely the series that
we want to calculate the correlation against.
In this case the average room size hitting shift enter.
You see that the correlation is indeed positive and around zero point seven and that makes sense right.
The larger the property is the more rooms that house the more expensive it should be.
Now as a challenge I want to do the same thing for the property prices and the pupil teacher ratio.
I want you to calculate the correlation between this feature and the property price point before you
type in the python code.
I want you to make another guess at the correlation.
So pick a number between minus 1 and 1 and then write your python code.
Do you think that the house prices will be positively or negatively correlated with this feature.
How.
Figuring out the reason for this is probably harder than typing in the python code.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and just give it a shot.
All right ready.
Here's the solution.
I can simply copy what I've written in the cell above pasted in and then change R.M. to the name of
the feature that I want to calculate my correlation against.
And this is P T ratio in all caps.
And when I hit shift enter I see that the correlation here is negative zero point five.
But why is that.
What does this number actually mean.
So the first one was a positive correlation.
It was fairly strong.
Zero point seven.
And this is a fairly strong negative correlation minus zero point five.
Now let's have a little think about why this might be.
If you had one teacher and two students what would the value of P T ratio be equal to the P T ratio
would be equal to two because there's two pupils and one teacher now two students and one teacher.
It's kind of like having private tuition.
So if we take this thinking further what if you had 15 students per teacher then the value inside peachy
ratio would be equal to 15 and with 15 students instead of two.
Each student is getting less attention from the teacher.
Sort of that class size grows.
What if you have 30 students then each student is getting even less attention from the teacher.
You can imagine the students in the back of the class giggling passing notes playing clash Royale on
their cell phones and throwing paper airplanes right.
In other words there's T ratio feature measures the quality of the education the quality of the schools
the schools with many kids and few teachers are under-resourced and they tend to have a lower quality
of education and this quality of education is reflected in the house price.
If the PDP ratio goes up which is a bad thing because we have so many pupils per class then the property
prices tend to code down and this is why we see a negative correlation.
Okay.
So we've picked out two correlations one by one.
I can't start target against our house price.
What if we wanted to calculate all the correlations at the same time because doing this one by one is
gonna be pretty painful right.
Well panders has got us covered in this next cell here.
I want to take my whole data frame data and call the correlation method on it.
So data aren't core parentheses and shift into will produce this.
This is an entire table that doesn't just show the correlations with the house prices.
Those are in the last column here.
It also shows the correlations amongst all the different features.
For example how the average number of rooms is correlated with the amount of crime in this table.
You can still find these two values.
So price versus room size and price vs. peaky ratio.
If I go down here the first value zero point seven is here and that second value minus zero point five
is right here.
But the other interesting thing about this table is this diagonal here you see these cells of ones along
the diagonal all the correlations are equal to one.
And that's because the correlation of a variable with itself will always be equal to one.
So crime correlated with crime is equal to one.
The correlation of number of rooms versus number of rooms is equal to one.
The correlation of age against itself is equal to one.
And so on.
So you can pretty much ignore this diagonal.
It's not telling us anything interesting.
In fact you pretty much can also ignore half of this entire table.
You see this table is symmetric.
This value here.
Crime versus zoning is the same as zoning versus crime and industry versus zoning is the same as zoning
versus industry.
In other words the two halves of this table split along the diagonal are the same.
Let's come back up here to this correlation method and hit shift tab on our keyboard to bring up the
quick documentation if hitting the little plus sign expands.
This whole thing and we can see something kind of interesting.
Now it turns out that we didn't supply any arguments to this correlation method.
There's no value here.
We didn't put any inputs between these two parentheses.
And what this means is that going with the correlation methods defaults and it turns out that there
are multiple ways you can calculate a correlation and we're using that default way of doing this calculation.
Our specific type of correlation is the Pearson correlation.
There's two other ones down here which we could have picked but Pearson is the default correlation that
we're going to be looking at.
So we look at this as a comment here in this cell.
I'm going to say Pearson correlation coefficients.
That way there's no ambiguity here.
Now since we brought up this table here this kind of brings me to our next point.
We spoke about kind of two things that we look for with these correlation calculations.
We look for the strength and we look for the direction of the correlations but there's actually also
a third thing that we kind of care about because in this table we didn't just have the correlations
between our features and our target house prices.
We also had the correlations or the features with each other.
So let me ask your question.
If two features were perfectly correlated would that be a good thing or would that be a bad thing for
our regression model.
And the answer is It depends.
But it could be a bad thing and something that we probably want to discover early on.
Let me explain the problem that high correlations between features could pose for our regression model
with an example suppose your medical researcher and you're analyzing the bone densities of people.
Your goal is trying to figure out what makes people have strong healthy bones and you have all this
data on people and you're running your regression and the kind of data that you're feeding into your
regression model includes a person's age a person's body fat and a person's weight.
These are your explanatory variables.
Now here's the catch.
It turns out no one looks like this.
The people who actually do look like this get put up on a stage and cast in movies like Conan the Barbarian.
And the thing about these people is that they have a very high weight but very very low body fat.
But in this world they are very very few tall heavy but lean bodybuilders for most of the population
body fat and weight are actually really highly correlated.
Most people who weigh a lot tend to have high body fat at most people who are very very skinny tend
to weigh very very little.
So given this pattern in the data what does this imply for the medical research that you're doing.
Because body fat and weight move together you're going to have difficulty telling apart their effects.
In other words body fat and weight are highly correlated and it becomes very difficult to see the individual
contributions to bone density of either of these two explanatory variables.
One of these features is redundant and this problem that you've just encountered in your hypothetical
medical research actually has a name.
It's called multi colon the charity now healthy calling the charity of the word that only a statistician
could love but put simply multi calling the charity is when two or more predictors in a regression are
highly related to one another.
So for this example it was body fat and weight which are very highly related.
Each of these do not provide unique and independent information to the regression.
Now the result of your regression having this problem of multi colon parity means that the estimates
start becoming unreliable and your findings stop making sense.
Put simply the models starts getting confused.
But the thing to remember is that high correlations don't automatically mean that you have this problem
of multi colon parity.
I wish it was that easy however what it does imply is that we should be looking at these correlations
between our features we should be investigating if our features are highly correlated and if we find
a high correlation between our features we should investigate why that is the high correlations can
be an early warning sign that there is some sort of problem high correlations between your features
are kind of like a toothache that make you go to the dentist the tent is well then investigate further
to see what the actual problem is.
So having introduced this topic we're going to keep this in mind for our regression analysis stage.
This is when we're going to be revisiting this question of multi calling charity.