This lesson will introduce you to one of the cornerstones of programming namely functions functions
go by many names and other programming languages functions have been called subroutines methods procedures.
But don't let the jargon get to you.
The central idea is always the same in Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet.
Juliet famously said A rose by any other name would smell just as sweet.
At the time she was talking about Romeo.
But had she been a programmer I'm sure she would have said the same thing about functions hand on that
note.
I hope you're ready to start your love affair with functions.
Her goal in this lesson is to explain exactly what's going on with a line of Python code like this show.
Followed by the parentheses.
We're gonna be focusing on the part after the dot.
That way we can break down the programming concepts of functions into bite sized lessons and build up
to the big picture.
As such.
This lesson really sets up the next couple of lessons and arguments return values and on objects so
you can think of these videos like a combo like bread and butter or burgers and fries or a Java cross
or Coca-Cola and Mentos.
You get the point.
So what's so great about functions.
Well imagine I'm your little housekeeping robot because I don't know you didn't want to buy a Roomba.
Something and if I was a human you could tell me Hey go and buy me some milk.
That instruction would make sense to her to a human.
A human would understand what to do in order to complete this task.
However when we're giving instructions to a robot it doesn't quite work like that robot doesn't know
what getting milk involves especially if you've bought the base model with no machine learning capabilities
so when you're dealing with a robot you have to specify every single step of this task like taking the
money opening the door closing the door walking to the store etc etc etc. You have to specify every
single instruction.
Now come the next day and you need to get more milk.
Well you have to specify all these instructions again and that would be incredibly annoying and you'd
probably bend your housekeeping robot in short order.
Here's where functions come to the rescue with a function you can bundle all these individual instructions
into a single instruction and we can also give this function a descriptive name like get under school
milk that every time we want to use get milk.
The housekeeping robot knows exactly what to do.
It will execute all the instructions contained inside this function.
So there's something to note here what we just described is actually a two step process.
First you have to tell the robot what get milk means and second you have to tell the robot to execute
the set milk instruction.
In other words step 1 is defining or declaring the function and step 2 is using or calling the function
the syntax looks like this when defining the function you'll always see this keyword DCF.
Def followed by the name of the function followed by parentheses followed by a colon after the colon
on the lines below.
You have the instructions inside the function.
This group of statements is going to be indented and the indentation tells us what statements are inside
of the function.
Now there's actual words for the anatomy of a function.
While you and I have got a head and a body a function has got a header and a body and the header is
this line right hits the line with the D F keyword at the top and the body are all the statements all
the instructions that are inside the function.
Basically all the lines that are indented that's the body.
Now let's take another look at this line of code where it says peeled he dots show parentheses the parentheses
at the end are telling us that show is a very different beast from math thought Pi or Hitchhiker's Guide
dot the answer.
And that's because show is a function because it had these parentheses at the end.
Now there's no parentheses after a math thought pi and there's no parentheses after Hitchhiker's Guide
on the answer.
These two are not functions.
So now that we know a little bit about what a function is supposed to look like let's create our own
first function scrolling to the bottom of our Python intro notebook.
We can write def get underscore milk and then parentheses followed by a colon and when we hit Enter
we'll get taken to the next line which is indented and here we can print out some instructions like
open door and then we can hit enter again.
Could take him to the next line which again is indented and follow up with some more instructions that
are going to go inside the function like print walk to the store and then print by milk on the ground
floor.
Hen we'll finish it up with printing.
Return
with milk galore.
So in our function body we have for individual print statements.
Notice that when you hit enter on your keyboard Jupiter notebook already indents these lines for you
and we have an indentation of one two three four spaces in python.
This indentation or whitespace actually matters quite a bit in station in Python.
It's like a full stop at the end of an English sentence just like the full stop at the end of the sentence.
The whitespace helps Python determine where one instruction ends and another one begins.
Now just like Jupiter notebook has shown us you also want to have four spaces between the beginning
of a line and the first print statement.
Usually the text editor that you're working in or Jupiter notebook in this case will help you indent
this correctly for you.
That's a shift enter on the cell and see what happens.
Nothing right.
Nothing at all.
And that's because we've only defined the function we actually haven't executed it yet.
Remember how we were talking about the two step process.
Let's call that get milk.
Function now.
With me right get on the school milk and hit shift enter.
Now I'm noticing that I made a typo so let's fix this.
Gonna hit shift enter again and execute this function again.
Okay that was really bothering me.
Pillow the cell where we're calling the function where we wrote get milk.
We see the four statements from the function being printed out.
The other thing I quite like about to put a notebook is that the syntax highlighting here actually helps
us differentiate visually and see at first glance on which part we're defining the function had on which
part we're calling the function the part where we're defining the function the function name is highlighted
in blue and the part where we're calling the function.
It's regular black Python code.
Now let's take it up a step in complexity in the next lesson.