Now that we've extracted the body text of an email from a single email we need to do this for all our
emails and for that we need to create a function that kind of function that we're going to create.
And this lesson is a special type of function in Python called a generator function.
In other words we will create a function that reads all the files in a folder.
Now the functions that we've encountered so far run ones and they return a value.
If you recall a standard python function just has that return keyword and then it spits out a value
following whatever comes after that keyword.
And that's it.
And what this means is that a function needs to return all the results at once.
It needs to return all the results at the same time.
Now if we wrote a function that read all the emails and extracted the body text from all the 5000 e-mails
all at once then we would have to return 5000 email bodies all at the same time as well.
Now if this sounds like a lot of work then you're absolutely right.
And we don't have to write a python code to do it this way.
There is an alternative and this is where generator functions come into play in our Python notebook.
Let's add a markdown cell that reads generator functions and in the cell below we're going to go over
this advanced functional pattern that you're going to encounter every time you want to spit out a series
of values.
We're gonna be combining two very powerful programming tools.
The first one is loops.
And the second one is this generator function.
So before we pass 5000 e-mails let's go through a practice generator function starts out the same way
as every other function with a definition the keyword then I'll give it a name generate on the school
squares and then I'll give it maybe a capital and as a single parameter and then inside his function
I'll write a loop for my underscore a number in range.
This is gonna be up to and yield my underscore a number to the power of two times times two.
This here is my generator function.
It will take in a single value and and it will run the loop and times.
Now one difference that you'll notice is that we don't have a return keyword.
Instead we've got this other keyword here.
Yield.
Let's call this generator function to see how it behaves then we'll talk a little bit more about the
syntax.
Having pressed shift enter on the cell you might think that all we have to do is call the function by
using its name like so generates squares three say and press shift enter.
But in this case the output looks a bit unexpected instead of squaring say the number three.
What we get is a generator object.
So how do we call this function in a more useful way.
One thing we can do is wrap this whole thing in a loop and then you'll also see how does generator function
actually works.
So if I say for i in generate squares semicolon print I and then the comma and then say at the end put
all ARROW IN BETWEEN THE RESULTS AND LET'S HEAD shift into now.
So this is interesting right.
We get 0 1 4 and then each number is separated by little arrow here.
What's going on our loop will run three times because n is equal to three.
But what we're doing here is we're feeding in the values into our generator function one at a time the
first value that we feed in is the value 0 and 0 squared is equal to zero.
Then we feed in the value 1 1 squared is equal to while 1 then we feed and the value to 2 squared is
equal to 4.
And the amazing thing here is that this function is using the yield keyword remembers where it left
off.
So let's change our argument here to the number five and see how this goes.
Now our sequence looks like this 0 1 4 9 16 in contrast to the return keyword for normal function where
the function basically exits with a value.
And we're done for good with the yield keyword.
It's sort of exiting the function but it remembers the state where we had exited from.
So in this case we're iterating through our loop and it remembers the previous value that it was at.
And we're starting from the point where we had yield it from.
But why is this interesting.
Why does this matter at first glance it looks like we could achieve the very very same thing with a
normal function that uses the return keyword instead of having these loops and iterating through a generator
function.
Why would we do this.
Well here's the thing with a generator function we don't have to do all the upfront work.
So in our case we've got 5000 e-mails that we have to pass with a large dataset like that or an incredibly
long list.
It takes an incredible amount of computation to even produce a single value let alone thousands of them
at the same time.
So what we're going to do now is we're gonna apply this generator function to loop over and iterate
over all the files in our directory that holds onto the spam emails and then we're basically going to
pass one email at a time.
That's how we're going to use this generator function.
Let me add in the markdown cell here that reads email body extraction and what we'll do here is will
define a generator function that walks over all the file names in a particular folder.
This is a function from the operating system.
Here's how we're going to use it.
So we'll wrap the whole thing in a function.
Yeah.
Def email under scoped body under school generator.
And this is going to take a single parameter namely the relative path to one of our folders.
The spam folder or the folder with the legitimate emails.
Now what we'll do is we'll write a loop.
We're going to see for root comma directory names DSR names comma file names in walk parentheses path
this Walk function is where our operating system comes in the Walk function generates the file names
in a directory by walking the tree from the top to the bottom and it yields.
That's right doesn't return it yields a tuple so three things consisting of the directory path which
is this first one here that directory names which is the second one here and the file names which is
this third one here the directory path is obviously the path to our spam folder in this case that directory
names are the sub directories which we're actually not going to use and the file names is the bit that
we're actually interested in this is gonna be a list of names of all the files in our directory.
In other words if we point this function to easy honest go ham on a score one then we're gonna get all
these file names right here we're gonna get all the file names in this easy honest go ham directory
This is what we're after now the Walk function is not inbuilt it belongs to the OS library so let's
imported at the very top of our notebook scrolling up you can see from os import walk and while we're
up here we're also going to import something else that we're gonna be using in this function namely
the join method.
So from OS thought path import join.
Now let me hit shift enter and scroll back down let me add a semicolon and let's write the inner part
of this loop the inner part of this loop is going to make use of all the file names that we're retrieving
using the Walk function.
So what we want to do with a single file is actually very very similar to this bit of code that we've
written earlier but since this function is kind of return all the files to us we're gonna have to tackle
each file one by one.
But let me copy this code nonetheless and then down here we can add another loop namely we'll see full
file on the screen name in file names semicolon and then Let's paste in this code to select this bit
here and just hid tab on my keyboard to indented and make sure hits in the body off my inner loop and
then I'm going to have to make another change we're not gonna be targeting our example file we need
to be targeting a particular file in this list of file names how do we get that well we'll see the file
path of a particular file.
It's gonna be equal to joining the route which we're getting here from our outer loop to a particular
file name that we're iterating over in our inner loop so we'll say combined the path for the root directory
with a file name that we're iterating over in our loop and then in our open function we can replace
example on a school file with file path.
Everything here will remain the same.
The only thing that's gonna change is that we're not gonna be printing out the email body.
We want this function to spit out two pieces of information.
One is the file name and the other one is the email body and this is where we're gonna use that yield
keyword once again.
So we'll say yield file on a screen name comma email and a school body.
Now I know this bit of code looks very very involved but we've broken it down quite a bit in the previous
lessons already.
So for example we know that this bit of code extracts an email body from a particular file and we know
that using the yield keyword this function here will give us a result every time it loops over a particular
file in our directory.
So spit out this file name that I'll spit out this file name and this email body then I'll spit out
this file name and this email body and so on the only thing that's really new is this Walk function
from the OS library which spits out a tuple which we're using in our loop and we're nesting a inner
loop inside this one here to go over all the files one by one.
Now that's half of the work done.
If we look back up here we've essentially done this bit we now need to write the second piece of code
that actually calls our generator function.
We need to write a loop that repeatedly calls our generator function.
Let's put the second piece of code inside a function as well.
So I'm gonna go down here and I'm going to call this function data frame from directory.
So Def under school from under school directory and it's going to take two inputs it's gonna take a
path and a classification and by classification I just mean whether this email folder is going to contain
spam emails or legitimate emails to create our data frame we will start out with two empty lists.
So I'll say Rose is equal to half empty square brackets and row underscore names is also equal to a
pair of empty square brackets our generator function is going to be called Inside A Loop.
So we'll say for file on the school name comma email unescorted body which is what our generator function
is returning in email under school body on a school generator and then our generator function here needs
one input namely a path and by the way if you haven't pressed shift enter on this it's a good idea to
do so now and once you've done that all we need to do is supply a path to our generator function as
an argument and I'm just going to feed through the path that is being passed into this data frame from
directory function to our generator function right here inside the loop.
We're gonna append our email bodies to our rows list so see rows.
Don't append parentheses curly braces single quotes message colon email and a school body comma single
quotes category.
Colon classification.
So what I've done here is I've created a Python dictionary using the values that are generator function
spits out each time this loop runs it's gonna give us a file name and an email body and we're storing
this in a list where we're appending the email body one by one as it goes over the files.
Next we'll do something very similar for the row names so row underscore names dot append parentheses
file on the school name.
How this data frame from directory function here is gonna be a regular function.
It's not going to yield anything.
It's going to return a data frame so PD for pandas dot data frame parentheses rows comma index is equal
to row on a school names and that's it.
Except that we need to import pandas as PD at the top of our notebook of course.
So let's do that now import pandas as PD shift into scroll down and head shift into on this as well.
Now we've written quite a bit of code and we haven't tested it at all.
So we're not even sure if all of this will work or if we've made an error.
Let's try and call this data frame from the directory function and see if it works.
But before we do that let's add all our paths to the top of her notebook.
Under this constant setting the paths that I'm interested in are the paths to easy ham underscore one
the path to easy ahem I just got to spend one and spam two.
So let's create four constants with these paths the kind of path that we're gonna be working with.
It's gonna be a relative path that pays classified notebook is located under M0 projects so our path
will have to go into spam data.
0 1 processing Spam Assassin corpus.
And then I'll have these folder names afterwards.
So here we go.
Spam on a score one on a scroll path is going to be equal to this first bit here which I'm just gonna
copy and paste.
Then we said it was spam underscore assassin underscore corpus.
And then we said it was gonna be spam underscore one.
This is the relative path from our base classifier notebook to our spam on a scroll one folder.
Now remember everything is case sensitive and you've got to use forward slashes between the folder names
to avoid getting any errors.
Let's tackle the other four relative paths now.
So I'm just going to copy this paste it three more times and rename our constants here as well.
So spam to path this one I'll call easy.
Non spam one path and this one I'll call easy on a school non spam to path the folder that these ones
are going to point to.
It's gonna be easy on the school ham to easy underscore how one spam two and spam one of course.
And that's it.
If we hit shift enter on this and just make sure we haven't made any typos we're good to go let's call
RDF from directory function and create a data frame of spam emails.
So I'm going to call this data frame spam underscore emails and when I said it equal to def from directory
note I don't have to type all this out I can just hit tab on my keyboard parentheses spam one path comma
and then the category for spam is going gonna be the number one now before I continue going.
Let's look at the head of this data frame to check out the first few rows.
So spam under school emails dot head parentheses and shift into.
Well here we can see the file names of the first five rows.
We've got a category.
Category is going to be one for spam and zero for non spam.
And then we've got the messages.
In other words the bodies of all the emails as a column in our data frame as well.
Let's take a look at the shape of the state of frame to see if we've got all our emails spam underscore
emails dot shape shift enter gives us five hundred and one and two to four the number of columns the
category and our email bodies and five hundred one for the number of rows.
In other words the number of messages in this folder.