Now that we've covered the function basics we can take it up a notch in complexity in this lesson.
We're gonna talk about functions with inputs namely parameters and arguments.
So I realized that if you're new to programming you're going to be hearing a lot of new words in these
lessons.
And one thing I'll say is that when you're learning anything new.
The hard thing isn't necessarily the concepts.
It's often the language and it doesn't really matter if it's programming or medicine or cooking.
Every field has its own jargon and its own words.
A big part of learning Python programming is learning some of this vocabulary.
I'm going to be doing my best to introduce this vocabulary slowly over the course of the lessons and
how I realized that learning vocabulary words doesn't sound very fun.
But the upside is that you're not gonna be learning words that people invented just to sound smart.
Come to think of it the Olympic champions of inventing meaningless words and catchphrases are probably
the business consultants of this world.
I've heard people say like the most ridiculous stuff with a completely straight face.
I think my all time favorites are words like helicoptering which apparently means looking at things
from above and it's another one peeling the onion which apparently means doing more analysis.
So let's get back to Python programming otherwise I won't be able to keep my lunch down.
Looking at the code we've written previously we can see that some functions take inputs.
So for example does use function here had an input called 538 and I read CSB function had an input that
was a filing all of these inputs to functions go in between the parentheses after the function name.
In contrast our milk function had no inputs and this is the same with the show function which also had
no inputs.
In contrast the read CSB function had a piece of text between the parentheses and this piece of text
was the input to the function these inputs are called arguments or parameters.
Let's create our own function that takes an input.
That way we can put all of this into practice and see how the code actually works.
I'm going to quickly copy paste this code from the get milk function into my cell below and I'm gonna
modify this code.
First I'm going to give this function a different name.
I'm gonna call this function Phil underscore the underscore fridge also inside these parentheses.
I'm going to specify an amount this amount is gonna be our input to our function finally.
I'm when a modifier third print statement down here.
So what says by I'm going to use the single quotes and the plus sign and then I'm going to put a mount
here.
Like so.
So it reads buy in single quotes plus amount plus single quotes contents on the ground floor this way
I'm making use of the input within the body of our function the plus sign in this print statement concatenate
all strings and by concatenate I mean merge or combine.
Let's call this function to see it in action.
So when I hit shift enter and then I'm going to write fill the fridge which is the name of the function
followed by the parentheses.
And then within the parentheses I'm going to put single quotes and write five and at shift enter.
Now the piece of text that we entered between the parentheses shows up in our print statement.
Let's think about what just happened here.
First you'll notice that the plus sign in Python actually means different things in different contexts.
When the plus sign is used with numbers it adds them together.
But when the plus sign is used with text it combines the strings.
Let's call this function again but this time the substitute a different amount.
I want to write.
Fill the fridge parentheses 1000 and head shift into let's look at this code and think very carefully
about what's going on.
Our fill the fridge function takes one input that input has a name and is called amount.
But the really cool part is how a mound is just a place holder.
The value of a mound is determined by whatever we specify when we call our fill the fridge function
the first time we specified the value five and amount held on to that piece of text.
So the word five was printed in the print statement when we executed the function.
But the second time we substituted the word 1000 so that the amount took on this value instead.
And we saw 1000 printed out on the third line.
In other words a mount behaves just like a variable it gets its value when we call the function.
And every time we refer to a mound in the body of the function we are able to use the value that's stored
inside now there's two other things that you might notice about the code we just wrote.
First let's try to call this function with empty parentheses.
So when I write fill the fridge separate it button the scores and then have empty parentheses and hit
shift enter in this case we get an error and the details of this error message read missing one required
argument amount.
In other words because we've defined our function with an input we must provide it we specified one
parameter in the function header so we must give a value.
We can't just leave it out.
The other thing you'll notice at this point is that print is nothing other than a function as well.
Print takes a piece of text as an input and prints it out below the cell so if print is a function that
means we're calling a function inside our function where nesting our function calls functions inside
functions is like I don't know dreams within dreams in the movie Inception.
In other words one piece of code can trigger other bits of code.
And this idea is actually really really powerful when you think about it.
So here's a quick recap.
When working with functions with inputs we specify what the input is upfront when defining the function
the input is specified between the parentheses following the function name in this example the input
is called money and money is just a place holder in programming jargon when referring to an input as
a place holder or as a variable.
We tend to call it a parameter as in Get milk has one parameter called money.
Now remember how I said we're going to have some vocabulary training.
Well when we call the function we must provide a value to this parameter.
In this case we must provide a number that value is gonna be twenty point five when I call this function
the value that's passed to a function when it's being called.
It's called an argument.
How oftentimes you'll see the words parameter an argument used interchangeably.
People aren't always super pedantic in the real world but if you want to express yourself precisely
or get technical it's good to know these definitions a parameter is when we're referring to the inputs
to a function and we're talking about it as the place holder or as the variable and we use the word
argument when we're talking about the actual value that we're giving the function when we're calling
it thorough.
That's probably enough vocabulary training for now and we've also covered quite a few different kinds
of functions so far.
For example we understand the syntax behind show and we also understand the syntax behind use or read
C.S. v show had no arguments but read see as V has a file name as an argument.
Now we're gonna look at functions with multiple arguments.
We've actually encountered multiple arguments when we called the scatter function for our plot and we
also had multiple arguments when we called the Fit function for our regression fit had two arguments.
Capital X and lowercase Y X was our movie budgets and lowercase Y was our movie revenue.
We can see that these two arguments are separated by a comma but let's create our own function and have
it take more than one argument so that we can see this in practice back in the python Internode book.
I'm going to copy our previous function that we defined here the fill the fridge function and I'm going
to paste that into the cell where we had the era.
I'm not going to modify this function first by changing the name.
So when I call this function milk underscore mission and then I'm also going to change the function
header.
I'm going to change the number of parameters that are between these two parentheses.
So after amount I'm going to add another parameter.
I'm going to add a destination.
We're going to use this parameter in our second print statement.
Which instead of reading walk to the store we're going to have it read.
Walk to the plus destination.
So we're gonna concatenate the string walk to the with whatever is supplied as a destination.
I can't wait to try out our new function.
So I'm going to shift enter and then in the cell below I'm going to call this function.
I'm going to say milk on a school mission
and for a mount I want to write 20 and for destination I'm going to write in single quotes
department store.
Here we can see that our first argument 20 is gonna be for the amount and our second argument department
store is gonna be for destination when a head shift enter.
I can see these values substituted into our print statement accordingly.
Now here's the question What do you think will happen if instead of writing milk mission 20 comma department
store we write milk mission department store comma 20
you guessed that I walk to the 20 and I buy department store cartons of milk what this tells us is that
our arguments to our function are passed by their position.
In other words the order in which we give the inputs to our function matters and it matters quite a
bit.
The arguments are passed from left to right.
So as before we must supply exactly two arguments when recalling milk mission but we also must be careful
to supply these arguments in the right order.
Now looking at the syntax for calling a function it still strikes me kind of strange every time I think
about it.
Imagine how that would play out in real life.
I imagine your girlfriend or boyfriend telling you to go to the supermarket and saying go buy eggs potatoes
milk cartons doughnuts and apples by 2 10 1 12 and 5.
This is confusing right.
And yet many programming languages work exactly like this but confusion is bad and nobody wants to come
back from the supermarket and have an argument with their partner because they've messed up the order
of their arguments.
Lucky for us Python can actually help us have a successful relationship.
It provides an alternative for passing arguments by position.
We can also match our arguments by providing a name that believe it or not we actually did this previously
in our notebook.
Check out how we called Scatter for instance we had X comma Y comma color equals blue comma alpha equals
zero point three.
The point that I want to draw your attention to is the part where it says color equals blue and alpha
equals zero point three.
Here we are matching our arguments by name.
Let's go back to our milk mission function remember how when we got the order on we printed nonsense
Well we can add the name of our parameters to the function call.
So that python will match these values by keyword.
So if we say destination is equal to department store and amount is equal to 20 and press shift enter.
We can see that the output below the cell updates to the way that we wanted to namely walk to the department
store buy 20 cartons on the ground floor.
So here we are setting the destination equal to department store and we're setting amount equal to 20
looking at the code where we called Scatter again.
We can actually see that in this case we're kind of mixing and matching supplying arguments by position
and by name the equivalent when we're calling milk mission would look something like this
we'd have milk underscore mission parentheses 20 comma destination equals store and had shift enter.
In this case the argument 20 is set by position and the destination is set by name.
Now personally I actually quite like named arguments.
They make the python code much more readable.
It's like having labels for the data.
Suppose I went back where we called scatter and I deleted and had deleted the names for these arguments.
In this case we just have x y blue zero point three.
Anybody looking at this code is gonna wonder what on earth this zero point three and that somebody might
as well be yourself in like two weeks time when you forgot what you did.
I guess the message I'm trying to convey here is that having a bunch of naked values separated by commas
doesn't make the code very readable to us humans providing these keywords and calling a function just
makes everything so much more readable.
So here's a question for you What do you think will happen if we call our function like this milk on
this commission parentheses store karma amount equals 20 hitting shift enter.
We see that we get an error and the reason is is that we're trying to assign a value to a mound twice
the first time we're assigning the store value to amount because python is evaluating our arguments
by their position and the second time we're setting amount equal to 20.
By using the keyword Okay cool.
So we're coming to the end of this lesson on parameters and arguments and we've covered a lot of material
here.
This material will sink in more with practice I promise.
And if you've heard any recent buzzwords that make you want to stick needles in your eyes please share
them in this lessons.
Q and A section I'd love to hear them.
See you in the next lesson.