Now a really nice thing to do at this point is to potentially save this information as a file because
we've done all this work reading all the individual files extracting the email bodies cleaning up our
data and creating this nice structure here that we're going to work with going forward.
It's probably a good idea to save this data frame in some sort of format as its own file.
That way we can simply load this one file and skip all the work that we've done beforehand so when I
insert a markdown cell here and I'm going to write save to file using pendants add a few more rows in
here we're gonna write the code that saves our data frame to the disk.
Now we could be saving this file in a number of different formats for example like a C as V file or
a text file or what have you.
And most of these libraries like pandas or NUM Pi or what have you.
They'll have the functionality to create a file locally on your desk.
The method that I want to show you in this lesson is called to Jason data don't to underscore Jason
will be the method that we're going to use if I hit shift tab.
Get a quick description.
And here you can see that the key information that we need to supply is a path or a buffer.
Now this is just a string with a relative path and a file name.
We've actually worked with something very very similar already with our practice email.
So let's create another constant up here and call it data underscore.
Jason on the school file and set that equal to single quotes and then when a copy this bit here because
I'm very very lazy and I don't want to make any typos and I'm going to paste it in here and then just
tack on my file name as well to call this email hyphen text hyphen data dot Jason Jason here is the
file extension let me hit shift enter on this now I can come down here and simply call on this constant
how before I hit shift enter on the cell I've pulled up my processing folder here on the left so you
can see what's happening when I actually execute this code.
You should see this new Jason File being created and here we go.
There it is.
Now if you've done some web development or you've worked with API then you're probably familiar with
the Jason file format but if you're not and you're seeing this for the first time.
Let me quickly show you what the Jason File Format looks like.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to open this file in my text editor.
Now one thing to be aware of is that this file is actually huge.
This is a file that has seventeen point seven megabytes in it.
So it's a quite a large file with a lot of text as you can imagine from passing about five thousand
eight hundred emails when you open this file.
Then you see something that looks like this.
You see a curly brace then the word category then zero semicolon one comma one semicolon 1 2 and so
on right.
This formatting here looks very very very unfriendly.
Right.
But I can show you this in a lot more of a readable fashion.
If I select my entire Jason and paste it into a Web site like Jason meet dot com we can beautify our
Jason and make it easier to read after clicking beautify and letting this Web site run for a little
while we can see that the formatting here is a lot more friendly now scrolling down to that Jason editor
we start to recognize our column names from the data frame as three different keys in this Jason.
We've got the category key we've got the message key and we've got the file name key.
The category was simply 1 or 0 4 spam or non spam and these numbers here highlighted in blue those are
my document I.D. So document number 60 was a spam email.
Similarly if I expand the messages I can have my document I.D. here 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 and so on all the
way to five thousand seven hundred and ninety five.
And I have the text of all the spam emails here.
In other words even though the file formatting does look kind of scary on the Jason especially for a
massive file like this it still preserves the overall structure of our data frame.
And Jason in fact is one of the most common ways that messages are passed around the web.
So every time you hit up a server and request some weather data or what have you the information that
you're likely to get back is going to be in this Jason format.
All right.
So that pretty much wraps up the data cleaning that we're going to do.
We've also managed not to just read a bunch of files from our disk.
We've also managed to save all the work that we've done to a Jason File.
The next step in our workflow is exploring and visualizing the data in our dataset looking forward to
seeing you in the next lesson.
Take her.