In the coming lessons we're gonna be introducing some more realism and building out our intuition for
the machine learning problems that are to come.
We're now going to have a look on how you'd run a gradient descent algorithm given some data points
and using a real cost function this cost function is called the mean squared error or M S E.
Previously we've been using example cost functions to learn more about how our gradient descent algorithm
behaves.
And this was fine at the time but now we turn our attention to a cost function that is actually being
used in practice for many machine learning problems.
Now to recap a little bit about linear regression.
We said that the goal of linear regression was to minimize the distances between the points and the
line and a good line was one that minimizes the residual sum of squares.
When we were talking about the distances we meant the distances between the data points.
So the actual values the wise and our fitted values or our hypothesis to calculate a residual sum of
squares.
We took the difference between the actual value and our fitted value and then we added them all together.
But because some values would have been below the line having them all up just like this would create
a problem.
So what we have to do instead is we have to square all the values and then add them up.
Thus our goal was to choose a line or choose the parameters theta zero and theta one that would minimize
the sum of the squared differences and the name for this equation was the residual sum of squares or
RSS.
The way to interpret this number this residual sum of squares was as follows.
It's how much of the dependent variables variation our model did not explain.
So it's the sum of the squared differences between the actual y values and the predicted y values and
the smaller this residual sum of squares the better our model fits our data and the greater the residual
sum of squares the poorer our model fits our data.
Thinking about it this way what would be a perfect fit.
What kind of model would have a perfect prediction.
Well it would be one where the residual sum of squares is zero.
Right.
Value of zero for the residual sum of squares would imply a perfect fit.
So I know that at this point you're probably thinking with the residual sum of squares make a good cost
function.
And the answer is yes it would but with one small modification and that modification is dividing the
whole thing by the number of data points then the residual sum of squares gets a new name.
And this equation is called the mean squared error or M S E and that's the cost function.
We're gonna be using in our last example back in our Jupiter notebook.
Let's add some section headings so when I change myself to mark down here and I'm gonna put in one pound
symbol and then I'm going to write.
Example 5.
Working with data and real cost function.
And below that I'm going to add a subheading that reads
mean squared error Colon a cost function for regression problems.
This is also a really good opportunity to try your hand at writing some more late text notation in Jupiter.
Let's add the formula for the residual sum of squares first and to make this fairly large.
So going to give it three pound symbols to Dollar Signs RSS is equal to and now we need that summation
symbol and it's gonna be with the sum tag.
That's how we're gonna get that summation symbol.
Let me add another two dollar signs as the closing tag shift.
Enter and show you and show you what I mean.
So backslash sum gives us the summation symbol.
Now we need to add some things to the top and the bottom of the summation symbol I can add things to
the bottom with the underscore and they're inside some curly braces.
I'm going to write I equals 1 and then I'm going to use the carry symbol and other pair of curly braces
and put an end to put something on top.
Let me shift enter and show you what this looks like.
Now I'm going to add the rest of the equation in some big parentheses so when I had backslash and then
write big for the big tag open parentheses and then space another backslash big closing parenthesis
and then everything inside the parentheses will be raised to the power of two.
So I want to see Carrie and then two.
Let's take a look at what this looks like now.
All right.
So now I'm just gonna add the final bit and that's gonna be why to the power of curly braces parentheses.
I it's gonna be the eighth value of Y minus H underscore backslash and theta for the Greek symbol.
Space X Carrie curly braces parentheses.
Eye for the eye the value of X..
I'm going to put another space here at the end to make it a bit more readable and that shift enter and
take a look at this equation.
Okay.
So I think that looks pretty solid and in the process we've discovered a few more latex tricks.
One is that this underscore adds things to the bottom like this.
I equals 1 for the summation symbol or the Greek letter theta for our hypothesis for H.
And we also see the big parentheses in action with the big tag.
Now having the later equation for the means quit error is actually gonna be very easy.
So I'm just gonna copy this and paste it and I'm going to modify it.
So instead of RSS it's going to read MSE and then just in front I'm going to add a fraction so I'm going
to add backslash F R A C A pair of curly braces and then one and then another pair of curly braces and
then add and when I hit shift enter I can now see my mean squared error equation like so.
Now one thing I'll point out is that you might see an alternative way of writing this equation.
Sometimes this equation is written with a y hat with a will carry symbol above the Y instead of this
notation with the hypothesis function instead of this H theta x ie.
So let's add the alternative notation as well so that we've got it on here.
So I'm going to select this point here which reads each underscore backslash theta X. I am going to
delete it and instead I'm going to show you guys another late tech tag which is backslash hat followed
by a pair of curly braces and a Y inside when you hit shift into now.
You should see this tether thing I'll do is I'll remove the carry the curly braces and the I from the
preceding y value.
So when it delete that and it shift into and let's see what this looks like.
So these are the two notations that you gonna come across.
Most often the predicted values either represented as the hypothesis function.
So using this H notation or it's represented with these y hat notation This is also very very common.
And y hat is also gonna be the way I'm gonna be referring to our predicted values in our Python code
that we're gonna write how with the notation out of the way and just looking at these equations you
probably might be wondering why is the means squared era more useful as a cost function than the residual
sum of squares.
I mean they look pretty similar.
Right.
But let's think about it.
What would happen when our dataset gets large.
We're gonna have a Y and a Y had value for each and every data point.
Right.
So as we're adding more and more data points to our dataset that sum starts to get pretty big because
we're adding up all the squared differences right hand.
We've already seen what happens when computers are confronted with very very large numbers before.
That's right.
When working with very very large numbers we might encounter our old friend the overflow era and this
is where the mean square error comes to the rescue.
Because what happens when we're dividing by the number of samples by dividing that sum by e the number
of data points we're kind of taking an average write an average a mean.
So hence the name means squared error and dividing by that number of samples.
You can start to handle very large datasets right datasets with tens of thousands of data points and
the cost function isn't going to encounter an overflow error because you're keeping that means quit
error manageable be small.
I hope that explains why the mean square error is a very very popular cost function because it allows
people to handle data sets of all sorts of sizes and your gradient descent algorithm won't cause an
overflow as your scaling up.