So the next question is how well does the model fit to data now has a challenge.
Do you remember how to print out a regressions r squared value from the previous lessons.
I want you to print out two different r squared values.
I want you to print out the r squared value for the training data set and the r squared value for the
testing dataset.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give us a shot and here's the solution to obtain
the r squared.
We access it through the regression objects score method.
So my first print statement is gonna read
training data all squared colon comma rigger dot score parentheses x on the school train comma Y on
a school train.
So this will be the r squared of the training data set and the r squared off the testing data set will
be test data r squared colon comma regular dot score parentheses x underscore test comma Y underscore
test.
So let's take a look at what these turn out to be.
For our training data we get an R squared of zero point seven five and for our test data set we get
an r squared of zero point six seven.
Now these values are actually both quite high.
I mean when you think about it the real world is a very very complicated place.
But we've been able to explain approximately 75 percent of the variance in our house prices with just
13 features 13 things and we can explain a lot of what's going on in the real world how a question that
you might ask looking at these two values is why is the r squared lower for the test dataset.
And the answer is is that what we've done so far is calculate the status only on our training data.
The algorithm hasn't seen the test data before.
As such the performance of our model on the data that a model hasn't seen is always gonna be worse.
It makes sense for the r squared to be lower on the test data than on the training data.
However running the model on data that's not in the sample actually gives us some idea of its predictive
power.
We get a little bit of a feeling for how our model would fare in the real world.
And it's very encouraging to see that the r squared even on the test data is still quite high.
So our model actually performs relatively well.
Okay so we SPECT out our model and we've run our first regression.
We did a quick sense check and looked at the performance.
Now we're getting to the evaluation stage now before we move on to the next lesson.
Let's add another markdown cell above this one here and add the section heading multi variable regression.
That way we can keep track of what we're doing.
The other thing I'm going to do is take these two lines of code.
Cut them and paste them down here.
That way when I had shift enter we'll be able to see our data frame of coefficients.
Otherwise the output is hidden by the print statements.
There we go.
Now we're ready to move on.
I'll see you in the next lessons.