Welcome back.
In the next couple of lessons I've got a really exciting topic for you.
We're gonna be talking about an LP natural language processing natural language processing is a huge
field.
It used to be a subfield of artificial intelligence actually but it moved more and more into the domain
of machine learning and an LP is big business to all sorts of things fall into the domain of natural
language processing.
For example it covers things like search sentiment analysis of tweets or reviews Google AdWords automatic
translation spellcheck auto correct Siri Alexa you name it as you can guess an LP is what most of Google's
earnings actually depend on.
Now how are we going to use an LP for our naive based classifier Well we're gonna use it to prepare
a piece of text for our learning algorithm.
We have to convert our email bodies into a form that the algorithm can understand and this means pre
processing our text.
Now what kind of things do I mean by pre processing.
Here's the high level overview.
First off we're gonna start converting all our text to lower case.
Second we're gonna token ize our text meaning we're gonna split up the individual words in a sentence.
Third we're gonna be removing the stop words by stop words I mean very common English words like the
word the which is the to convey grammar rather than meaning next we're also going to strip out the H
to male tags that are in the emails.
A lot of the emails are not written in plain text but contain a lot of H2 mail formatting which we're
not going to feed into our algorithm.
Next we're gonna do some words stemming and that means converting the individual words to their STEM
word.
So for example if you have the words going goes and go then all of these words actually share the same
words then it's only really the grammar that changes their spelling by stemming the words we're able
to treat them all as the same word.
And lastly we're also going to remove the punctuation and that is because as you can tell our naive
based classifier will ignore the grammar.
Now without further ado let's get started.
All right.
So I'm going to add a few markdown cells once again in Jupiter so that we can find this section really
easily when we're scrolling through it.
So I'll call the first heading natural language processing with two s's not three and then I'll add
a subheading that reads text pre processing.
Now the first step is normalizing the casing of the letters.
Very often the case of the words should not matter if I search for what is the airspeed velocity of
an unlit and swallow then if I were to type what is the airspeed velocity of an unlabeled swallow.
Now now even though that is horrible to read the answer to this vitally important question should not
depend on the upper or lower casing of my letters.
And you can also verified home that when you type in a search query Google completely ignores the upper
casing of your letters the casing of the letters doesn't affect our search results.
And similarly for our spam classifier we will treat the words loan or Viagra the same way regardless
whether they're spelled with uppercase letters or lower case letters so coming back to our Python code
suppose we have a message.
We have some sort of string that reads all work and no play makes Jack a dull boy full stop.
How can we convert all of these letters to lowercase.
How can we ignore the casing of the words in this string Hall Python strings have a handy little function
called lower so MSE dot lower parentheses will actually convert all the letters in the string to lower
case so you can see that Jack becomes lowercase and the word for all also becomes lowercase so converting
to lower case is one kind of text pre processing that you can do now for a lot of other pre processing
that we're going to do we're going to use a python package called The Natural Language toolkit or an
L T.K. the Web site for this module looks like this it's on an al T.K. dot org and this is actually
a package that almost every professional in the MLP field will use at some point for their natural language
processing needs.
The NL T.K. package can do a huge number of things and we're gonna start using it with some of the fundamentals
namely pre processing our text so that our machine learning algorithm can use it.
Now since we're gonna be using the multi K resources I'm going to add a very quick section heading here
to download the multi K resources and those include something called a token Nisar and a list of stop
words amongst other things but before I do that I'm going to import the package itself along with a
couple of the tools someone to come up here to my notebook imports and then I'd say input an L T K and
then from an LTE K Dot stem we're going to import the port of.
From multi K Dot corpus
we're going to import stop words
and from an LTE K Dot token eyes we're going to import word underscore token nice.
I think this will do for now when it import the package as a whole.
And then we're going to import three additional pieces of functionality the port toss them a stop words
and a word token either so when it shift into on the cell and and scroll down here to our section where
I'm going to show you how to download the healthy K resources and this is what we're going to do in
the next lesson two token eyes outwards.
I'll see you there.