In a previous lesson we've already written this line of code from s killer and linear model import linear
regression.
In other words we've already imported our linear regression functionality into this python intro notebook
for consistency.
Let's follow the same pattern that we employed when we were estimating our movie revenue.
We're going to create a variable called rigour and this variable is going to store our linear regression
object
to run our regression.
All we have to do is call the good ole fit method.
So we're gonna see record dot fit.
Open the parentheses and then for our explanatory or independent variable we're going to use the amount
of drugs in the tissue.
So we're gonna type LSD and then put a comma after it.
And now we can add our dependent variable or the values that we're going to try to predict.
In this case this is the school and that's it.
Now if you remember previously our explanatory variable was called Capital X and our dependent variable
was called lowercase y.
Now remember our cycle loans fit method essentially computes the parameters of this equation.
We've got our theta zero which is our intercept and we've got our theta one which is our coefficient
in front of our explanatory variable.
Let's see what happens now when we try to run our regression.
We in fact get an error.
Looking down we see that we get a value error found input variables with inconsistent numbers of samples.
Now this is odd right.
Why would there be an inconsistent number of samples.
We've got seven rows in each of our two columns.
We've got seven roads and LSD and we've got seven rows in the math school.
So why would there be an inconsistent number of samples.
Now even though this error message seems a little bit like a red herring.
The reason that we're getting this problem actually has to do with the fact that we are working with
series and not data frames we're getting this error because this notation here data square brackets
and then the column name actually extracts an object of type series instead of an object of type data
frame.
Now if you recall the way to get a data frame from another data frame is to double up on the square
brackets.
So if we add an additional pair of square brackets this notation now will extract an object of type
data frame and store it in LSD and in school.
So if I press shift enter now we are now no longer working with series we are working with data frames
going back down to where we're fitting our regression I can press shift enter again to rerun this line
of code and we can see that our regression runs without a problem.
Now you don't have to take my word for it.
Regarding the change in types you can double check this yourself so you can always add a cell below
and check the types if I say type LSD then I see it is a data frame and if I take away the square brackets
press shift enter and rerun this again I can see that it is a series in this case and this is what we've
talked about when working with data frames in the previous lesson.
So now that we've successfully fitted our regression let's take a look at the values of this theta one
and this theta zero parameter.
If you remember the way we did this in the past it was looking at the attribute of our regression object
the attribute in question was called co F with an underscore.
So let's add that here regular dot co f underscore and let's it shift and to see what happens.
Our Jupiter notebook will print out array then parentheses.
Then one set of square brackets two set of square brackets and then the value of our theta one parameter
so we can see that our coefficient is stored inside an array.
It's an array of one element.
Let's pick that element out.
So I'm going to say square brackets zero to access the first element in the array.
Let's see what happens when I press shift and turn now.
Huh.
In this case one of the square brackets has disappeared but we're still left with an array.
We're not yet able to access the number inside directly.
We're still getting a collection containing just one element.
So you might ask did this just work.
We access the first element of our array and we still got an array.
It seems like a bug right.
Well the answer is is that we have to go one level deeper to get the raw value.
You've probably noticed that there was one square bracket less right.
So if I don't have this at the end I have two square brackets but if I do access an element inside my
array I have one square bracket.
And the reason we get this is that we have to go to level steep.
We actually have an array of arrays.
Mind blown right our coefficient is buried inside an array that's inside another array.
So how do we access and arrange set an array.
Well we can access the first element which is the array and then we can access the first element of
that array again to get the raw value.
And this is how you would access a particular value of a nested array.
Let me add this to a print statement.
Similarly print and just say theta one semicolon maybe space comma and then close up brackets here.
So may I add this to a print statement like this.
Now let's take a look at our intercept our intercept was the intercept on the school attribute from
our regression object so I can see record dot intercept on the school press shift enter and we see that
our intercept is also inside a collection that's also inside of an array.
But there's only one set of square brackets here so we can access the raw value inside just having that
square brackets 0 following the name of the attribute.
If I had shift enter we see the raw value printed out and again I can wrap this inside a print statement
intercept semicolon single quote comma space rigger intercept and close the parentheses at the end.
There we go.
So here's our intercept.
Now what about the goodness of fit or R squared.
To find out how much of the variation in our data is explained by the amount of drugs in the volunteers
tissue.
We call the score method on our regression.
So we type rigour don't school and then we have to provide two values.
One is our explanatory variable and the other one is our dependent variable which was school so regardless
school parentheses LSD comma school.
Print this out we see that r r squared is approximately point eight eight let's wrap this inside a print
statement as well r squared semicolon single quote comma we go.
So in this cell we fitted our regression so we've run our machine learning model and we're printing
out a couple of stats about our regression a couple of the a couple of the statistics that describe
what went on with the calculation one of them is the coefficient another one is the intercept of our
line and another one is the squid or the goodness of fit.
So we've got some basic information about our regression and we see that the amount of drugs in the
contestants tissue explains close to eighty eight percent of the math test performance and we also see
that for every increase in LSD parts per million our volunteers math performance was approximately 9
percent worse than the control this is what the theta one is telling us how.
Now even though this is all very well and good it be really nice to represent this graphically because
we like pictures pictures are very very important for making sense of data so let's create another plot
I'm going to do this in the cell below.
Now one thing that you've already seen a little bit in the python code is that when creating nice looking
graphs it's a two part process in the first part.
We do all the styling and in the second part we plot the data and show it off.
So what I'm going to do isn't wedded to the second part first.
I want to plot the data and then when I had my styling code later on.
So plotting the data as it is I can write BLT dot scatter and then provide the inputs to our scatter
plot and that's going to be the LSD parts per million come up and then the school.
These are the math scores.
So let's see what this plot looks like.
By adding by adding PDT dots show beneath.
Here we go.
This is what our plot looks like before we've done any styling on it.
Now I think this chart looks.
I think this looks super ugly actually though we're going to have to do something about this for starters
let's add some arguments by keyword to this plot.
So in your scatter method you're going to put a comma at the end after school and then write.
Color is equal to and then single quotes.
Blue let's shift and to see what it looks like now we've got our data points in blue.
So this is a slight improvement to the black and white version.
Now we don't have many dots on here.
We don't have many many data points.
So let's increase the size of these individual dots on our chart.
And I want to leave this to you as a challenge.
So I've got the documentation of the scatter method up in front of you right now.
And what I would like you to do is I'd like you to look at this documentation and see if you can figure
out how to increase the size of these data points.
And also maybe add some transparency in other words instead of having it a solid blue color make those
blue dots slightly transparent.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video.
The hint I'll give you is that it's going to be in the keyword arguments of the scatter function hand.
Here's the solution.
So we wanted to increase the size of our dots.
So the way to do this is to look at these keyword arguments.
So for example s is the size in points of our dots and the transparency is this alpha value here.
The alpha value will be between zero which is transparent and one which is opaque coming back to our
Python code.
We can add these key word arguments to our scatter method.
So after Blue I'm going to add a comma and then I'm going to see as equals and let's experiment here
a little bit.
So what happens if I say s equals 500 in a hit shift enter.
I get enormous blue dots does actually doesn't look half bad but I think I'm going to go with something
like maybe 100 is the right value here so that's the size of our data points covered.
Let's change a transparency now.
This was in the alpha parameter so messy.
Alpha is equal to I don't know.
Zero point seven head's gonna be a value between 0 and 1 remember.
So hitting shift enter I get a nice little bit of transparency here on my data points which I have a
little bit larger so we can actually tell what's going on.
OK so we'll leave it at that.
And now I'm going to add some labels to our chart and make it look a little nicer since we've done this
before.
I'm going to leave this to you as a challenge so you can return and remember the python code that you
wrote.
Can you set the title of the plot as a whole as arithmetic versus LSD 25 and then add some labels on
the side one for the x axis that reads tissue LSD parts per million and one for the y axis that reads
performance school
and here's the solution.
So we take our plotting object put a dot after it and write title parentheses and then provide the string
a rhythmic tick vs. LSD 25 and then we do the same for the labels on the x axis and y axis PDT dot X
label parentheses tissue LSD the parts per million and peel T dot why label
performance type performance school.
There we go.
Let's shift and take a look at what this looks like and we see that may be the thing to do is to increase
the font size a little bit on these three labels.
I think in our previous chart 17 for the title and 14 for the labels worked really well some as a font
size equals 17 for the title and then when I add another keyword argument to our X labels and Y labels
font size equals 14 and font size equals 14 again.
So let's take a look.
That's starting to look pretty good.
Now to round things off a little bit.
We can try again setting a limit on the range.
So why.
It's gonna be between 25 and 85 25 and eighty five and exclaim it's gonna be between maybe one and six
point five yeah.
Doesn't need to go all the way to seven.
I reckon and for the style maybe P.L. Dot's style.
Use then we can choose our good old friend.
Five thirty eight shift and to apply the changes.
I don't think that I think that worked.
Try again.
Okay so here we go.
This is how it would look like with our styling as it is currently.
We've got our range set.
We've got our colors set and we've got the font size set as well.
At the very top of the cell I'm going to add again this little percentage sign and write that plot lib
in line.
And what this does is it tells Jupiter notebook to export this graph as it is when we say file download
adds notebook.
So there's really only one thing left to do which is plotting our regression line on here.
Because at the moment we've got our data points we've got our chart nicely formatted and looking good.
All we have to do now is plot our predictions from our machine learning model on here so our machine
learning model will have a prediction for every level of LSD tissue concentration in the data set to
get hold of these predictions.
We use a method called predict so we would write rigour.
Don't predict.
And as a parameter here has an argument here.
We would supply the LSD tissue concentration.
So this predicts a math school based on the amount of drugs in the tissue.
Now we'll want to store that information somewhere.
So I'm going to create a variable called predicted under school school and set it equal to the output
from this method right here.
Now remember you've got a press shift enter to actually run the cell.
Otherwise the cells below won't know about this code that we've just written.
So when shift enter now
so looking down at our chart we see the actual scores indicated by the blue dots.
And now we just have to plot the predicted scores alongside these actual ones had all these predicted
scores are gonna be connected by a line.
This is the line that we want to superimpose on our graph so we can write PDT dot plot and then provide
the line that we want to draw.
It's gonna be the Alice the tissue concentration on the x axis and then on the y axis it's gonna be
are what are predicted scores right.
Predicted on the school school.
Now let's hit shift enter.
And here we go.
We've got our predicted values connected by a line superimposed upon our scatter plot.
Of course we can start this line any way we want to.
So I'm going to say color equals red and line width equals three.
Now we've got a chart with you in more contrast between the blue data points and our red fitted regression
line.
So I think that concludes all the analysis that we're gonna do for our Python intro.
And what have we learned from all this.
Well drugs are bad for you.
Boys and girls especially if you're studying math tests.
But the other thing that you'll notice is that if you look at the original paper and you look at the
equation that the researchers have estimated we can actually see what their estimate was for the intercept
and the coefficient that we've estimated it as well.
So they've got eighty nine point seven for the intercept and negative nine point four for four.
The coefficient in their equation in contrast our coefficient is negative nine point zero in our intercept
is eighty nine point one not eighty nine point seven.
So we can see that we're not able to reproduce the researchers output Exactly.
Now I suspect that's because the researchers and we are not working off exactly the same numbers you
see they actually don't provide the information on parts per million.
And the math scores in the PDL that we're looking at.
I actually had to hunt around the web to get these numbers and they might be slightly different from
what's in the original paper.
But that said I think that our results are so close that we can say that we've successfully reproduced
the research that's in the paper there.
Oh and by the way this is in no way relevant to the study at all.
But many of the calculations that we just did the original authors ran on something called an IBM 360
computer.
The reason you've probably never heard of the IBM 360 is because you don't have one of these monstrosities
sitting in your living room.
How.
I find this so funny that the researchers actually mentioned this particular computer model in their
actual paper and I can't figure out if it's maybe some 1968 humble brag about how high tech they are
or if IBM actually paid them for this shout out in any case plugging the computer model that you've
done your research on in your scientific paper there's probably gone a little bit out of fashion these
days.
But yeah I I did find this interesting.
And how is your reaction of me telling you about this just now was wait wait a minute.
IBM made computers then.
I highly highly recommend watching this documentary called Silicon cowboys silicon cowboys is a really
really fascinating film about a little startup called Compaq that battled it out with big blue in days
gone by.
So yeah watch it and I'll see you in the next lessons.
Take care.