After having defined the problem and formulated our questions.
The second step is gathering the data that will help us find the answers.
Now previously I've provided data sets for you and you've imported this data from a CSP into Jupiter
notebook.
But what if you're on your own.
Where would you get your data from or how.
Typically you'd Google away and search for one of the many datasets available online.
Haftar all what if you wanted to build this valuation tool using house price data for your own city
rather than for Boston.
In that case Google is going to be your best friend in every respect.
But there's a third alternative for when you're just getting started and you want to practice your data
science and machine learning skills and that's to use some of the popular practice data sets that come
directly from a Python module.
In other words some Python modules actually come with sample datasets that we can use.
One of my favorite Python modules out there is psychic.
They've got excellent practice data sets and you could see a whole list of psychic learns toy data sets
right on this Web site scrolling down we can see that they not only provide the Boston house price data
set that we're gonna use in this section but they've also got the famous IRS data set which is used
for flowers classification.
They've got a dataset on diabetes on digits on wine and on breast cancer.
So this makes the search for data sets that you can use to practice machine learning and data science
much much easier.
And that's because the really really neat thing about using one of these data sets is that these tend
to be much cleaner and user friendly than some random CSB that you download from a Web site.
These datasets are meant for testing and for practice.
So you'll encounter far fewer missing values fewer weird data formats less non relevant information
and fewer other problems.
In other words somebody has already done a first pass on the data set so that you can crack on with
a head start.
Now since we're gonna be examining and predicting house prices in Boston let's pull up the official
documentation for this dataset and have a look at what it has to say.
The information provided on the website is fairly basic.
We can see the total number of samples five hundred and six.
We can see the dimensionality which is 13.
You can think of this as the number of columns in the data set and also down here.
We can see some sample code for how to use this built in data set from cyclone.
We're gonna be making use of all of this information.
All of these things in the coming lessons so let's crack on and get started.
The first thing we have to do is create a new notebook.
It's gonna be a Python 3 notebook.
When I click up here it says untitled and give this notebook a name.
Call it 0 4 multivariate regression click rename and then let's add some section headings for the first
section heading.
I'm going to change my cell to mark down put a pound symbol there and then write notebook imports below
this section heading we're gonna have all our input statements.
So what's the first input statement that we're gonna put in the first import statement.
We're gonna be putting in here is going to be loading our Boston house price data set into our Jupiter
notebook from the psychic learned documentation.
We know what this input statement should look like.
It should read from s on dot data sets.
Import load underscore Boston.
So let's write that in here and say from ASCII learn dot data sets.
Now I'm going to add another markdown cell to single out the section of the notebook where we're going
to gather our data.
So I'm gonna put a pound symbol here and then write gather data.
We're gonna try out a little bit more of the code that we saw in the documentation to get our data set
into our notebook.
I'm going to insert some cells as well so that when been working more in the middle of the screen and
here we can call the load underscore Boston function because this is the function that will actually
return our data set.
So when I create a variable call it Boston on the school data set and set the value of this variable
equal to the return value from load on the school Boston.
And then two parentheses at the end.
So this function here will return to us our data set and we'll store it in a variable called Boston
on a score dataset.
Let me hit shift enter and let's check out the type of this variable someone to write to type.
Open parentheses Boston underscore.
Data set and hit shift in tone.
And then we can see what kind of object we're actually dealing with.
And as per the documentation we can see that we're working with an object of type bunch.
Now usually we typically want to work with a data frame so let's make a mental note right now to convert
our data to a data frame for later.
But now let's take a look at what our data actually looks like in its raw state.
And to do that all we have to do is write Boston underscored data set into an empty cell and hit shift
into what we get to see now is a whole bunch of output.
How.
This is a really really difficult to read and it's not formatted in a way that we want to sift through
it but the good news is that our data is there.
We've successfully imported our data set and we've got it in our Jupiter notebook and this will bring
us to our next step exploring our data set cleaning our data set and visualizing it.
I'll see you in the next lesson.