All right.
So in this lesson I'm going to talk a little bit more about the data that we're working with.
And I'm also going to show you how you can get hold of it in terms of where we are in the project.
Well we've got our objective sorted and we've clarified what it is that we're going to do.
In other words we've nailed down the question that we're looking to answer that is is an e-mail spam
or is an email legitimate how we're gonna go on to the next step which is gathering the data to answer
this question.
Remember the premise is that a company has provided the data for you.
And I'm going to play the role of the company here.
So in this lesson's resources there is a zip file that you can download with everything that you need
for this module.
Now I highly encourage you to pause the video and do that right now just download the lesson resources.
But this isn't what this video is about right.
What I really want to show you is where I got the data from in the first place and that way you'll know
how to source the data and how you can pull up detailed information about the data yourself.
You never know this kind of stuff might really come in handy with future projects of your own.
Right.
OK.
So let's dive right in.
So where does the data actually come from.
Well all the e-mail data that we're gonna be working with actually comes from an open source anti spam
platform called Spam Assassin.
Now I know that in terms of design this Web site doesn't look like much but I think this is a really
really great project.
And the other thing is that Spam Assassin actually have a huge data set of spam emails and legitimate
e-mails that they're making available to the public to do things like train a spam classifier.
The easiest way that you can find this data set is to google the words Spam Assassin public corpus.
And if you do that the top results should look something like this.
If I click on this link I could take you to this page here.
Mind you the euro up here might change right.
That's completely up to the people who are behind Spam Assassin.
So hence googling Spam Assassin public Corpus is a surefire way to find the right Web site.
Again the design here can be a little bit off putting it looks a little bit dodge but what you've essentially
got here are a list of archives you've got a list of collections of spam e-mails that you can download
the file naming here gives a little bit of a clue to the recency of the archive itself.
Right.
So sometimes you'll see like a duplicate because the archive was actually updated for example this file
here.
It's probably just an updated version of this one here.
I'm just going by the file name here.
I don't think the last modified column is actually that useful in this case.
Now a moment ago you saw me use the word corpus in my google search query and you see that word again
here.
Corpus.
Right.
This is actually quite an important piece of jargon to know because it'll come up again and again when
you're working with text datasets a corpus is defined as a large and structured set of texts.
You'll hear the word corpus also used when people refer to see all the written works of a particular
author like Shakespeare.
Right now a related term that you'll come across as well when gathering text data is the word document.
Now this actually means something quite specific in this context a document refers to a particular email
in our corpus to the Corpus refers to a set of all documents.
A document refers to a particular item in the corpus.
So you'll see both of these two pieces of jargon come up again and again in this module.
And here's a bonus question for you.
Can you guess the plural of the word Corpus.
I'm not gonna leave you hanging there.
It's a a core poorer one corpus three core poorer not corpses or core Pi or what have you.
I found this out the hard way by the way with people giving me quite funny looks at a conference and
I don't want the same thing to happen to you.
So there you go.
Core poorer height you know back on the spam assassin website let me point you towards the detailed
description of the data set that we're working with.
It's right here under this unassuming read me HMO.
This is where you can see the revision history of the dataset and a brief explanation of what's actually
in the archive files.
Now speaking of archives you might be wondering how to actually download and open these files to look
at an individual email.
It's actually not that straightforward because you don't tend to see these dot TAVR dot visit to file
types very very often and it's not an extension you come across every day a hint.
So let me show you how you can work with these files on a Mac.
First and after that I'll show you the workflow on a Windows machine too.
Obviously the first thing you have to do is download one of these files.
So I'm gonna click on this spam archive here.
The most recent one from 2005 and I'm going to save it to my downloads folder.
If I pull up my downloads folder I can see it sitting right here.
It's got the icon of a zip archive and it's two point one megabytes on Mac.
All you have to do is pretty much double click on it it expands it meaning it on archives or unzips
it and it'll create a new folder for you like so.
So let me open this folder.
You can really see here it contains a thousand three hundred and ninety seven items.
There's quite a few things in here and they all look like this.
That's a pretty intimidating.
And looks like complete junk when you see it for like the first time.
So let me show you what these files actually are and how you would look at them to open one of these
files.
You need to use a text editor on Windows notepad comes pre installed on Mac.
It's text edit but the thing is if you're right click on this and you go to open with my operating system
isn't even suggesting a text that it's here to open it with.
So I manually have to choose it.
One of my favorite text editors these days is actually called atom so you can download and install this
thing if you like.
Let me show you what it looks like when I open this file with this text editor this is pretty much what
you'll see.
You'll see the top of the e-mail here followed by the body text of the email.
Like so.
So we've successfully opened one of these emails any text editor after an archiving the thing that we
downloaded from the spam assassin Web site.
This is the workflow on Mac.
In any case everybody who's on Windows.
I apologize for making you wait this long.
I'm going to get to that right now.
All right.
So this is a Windows 8 machine but Windows 10 isn't so different and all the same principles apply.
We first have to extract the zip file and then we can open a file in a text editor like notepad or yes
ATM.
So I'm going to download this t r dot be set to file and save it to my downloads folder which I've got
open for you right here and then I can open it with an unmarked server of my choice.
So I've got a couple.
There's quite a few options here.
I'm gonna use a program called seven zip and you can follow the two step process here with me.
So this is the seven zip program with the archive file inside and I'm going to say extract and I'll
extract it to my downloads folder and you should see the T A R file pop up here.
So this is actually another archive so I wouldn't have to repeat this step one more time so I'm going
to open this again with seven zip and then I'm going to extract my spam email folder from inside this
one and put it into say my downloads folder.
So this is the process that I have to follow on my windows machine to get to my spam emails extracting
him twice how let me show you how you can pull up one of these emails in notepad if I double click on
this thing I'm going to have to choose what program I want to use to open this file the file extension
of this particular file isn't helping windows figure out which program is appropriate to open this file
with by default.
So again we have to choose it manually if I go to more options I can scroll down here and I will find
the notepad program listed here.
So this is notepad.
Uh good ole good ole notepad.
And it does open the file perfectly.
It's not formatting it uh in a very friendly way but it is opening it.
So this is how you can look at a particular email with a default program not having to install anything
on your machine.
Right.
So you shouldn't have a problem opening any of these files and looking at the emails individually if
you want to know how I think you'll tire of notepad pretty quickly.
So you know if you have a decent text editor like ATM or say notepad plus plus or what have you then
it formats it for you a lot more user friendly.
And this is what I would encourage you to to use rather than the uh the default program that's installed.