In this lesson we're going to do the setup on our local machines on our very own computers.
I want to talk you through how to get your laptop or your desktop to run tensor FLOW AND CARIS previously
we've been using the Google collab notebooks to play around with the pre trained models and for most
of this module you can actually still use the Google collab notebook.
In fact if your computer is a bit older and you want to make use of the jeep use that are available
through Google collab then I recommend using Google collab in your browser.
However the reason I really want to run things locally this time around is because Jupiter notebook
is a little bit snappier than Google collab.
And in addition we're gonna be learning to use a tool called tense board.
You see neural networks are actually really complicated and tense a board is going to be our flashlight
that will help us monitor and compare different versions of our model.
So tensor board is what we're going to use to spot problems to fine tune our parameters to check how
our training is going and to try out different datasets.
Now the distribution that we've got installed that came with a lot of different packages was called
Anaconda and Anaconda comes with a lot of stuff.
But at the moment it still doesn't come bundled with tensor flow and carries these are the two packages
that will need to download and install.
How are we gonna do that.
Well we're going to do it the same way that we can download install pretty much any package we're going
to use the command prompt if you're on Windows or the terminal if you're on Mac post the command prompt
and the terminal pretty much look the same.
They're both going to expect you to put in some sort of command some sort of instruction.
And the way this works is we're going to supply three things we're going to supply the key words Conda
install then we're going to supply one argument with hyphen C followed by the channel name and then
followed by the package name.
So to install tensor flow this whole thing is going to read Conda install hyphen C Conda hyphen forge
and then tensor flow.
So here's the plan I'm going to show you how to install tensor flow first and then you can follow the
same process and install Caris on your own afterwards.
The reason I recommend going through the command line is because if you go and open the anaconda navigator
go to environments and then search for tensor flow then you might find that installing the package doesn't
quite work as expected because it's looking towards like a particular channel or what have you and configuring
the anaconda Navigator is a little bit more tiresome going straight to the command prompt and just installing
the package directly with the right instruction.
So once I open terminal on my mac or if you've got a Windows computer you just opened and a kind of
prompt instead there you'll just simply type condo space install space hyphen see space condo hyphen
forge space tensor flow then you'll hit enter and then you'll wait and you'll notice that you might
actually wait for quite a while.
So in my case it definitely took several minutes for it to solve my environment for me once that was
finished and all done.
You're going to be prompted to proceed or not.
Yes or no.
So type Y and hit enter and then what you'll see is all the dependencies of tensor flow being downloaded
among those dependencies.
You're actually going to spot a tensor board which we're in to use later on in this module again this
installation can actually take quite a bit of time.
Tens of low is no small package but it's worth the wait I promise.
But uh yeah just let your computer run and get a coffee in the meantime when it's all done.
You should see three messages that read something like preparing transaction done verifying transaction
done executing transaction done and your cursor will blink on the next line in your command prompt so
congratulations on successfully installing tensor flow.
Now you've got one more thing you've got to do and that's installing Charisse constellation for the
carrier's package will work pretty much exactly the same way you're gonna fire up the command prompt
put in kinda install high fancy condo forge Caris and then follow the prompts until it's all done.
And after all that when you're ready you can fire up a brand new Jupiter notebook and we'll get on that
in the next lesson.
I'll see you there.