In this lesson we're going to wrap up our introduction to Python programming with something a little
bit more fluffy.
A hot topic on the Internet is always coding style.
But what do I mean by coding style coding style is whether use capital or lowercase letters where they
use tabs or spaces where you put your curly brackets and so on.
It's how you arrange your code and what sort of syntax you use how the thing about programming style
is that it's the classic bike shedding problem right.
Everybody has an opinion on what color the bike should be.
And so everyone gets in a heated and lengthy argument about it in the same way.
People also have very strong feelings on how code should be formatted.
Now the irony is that the standards vary hugely between programming languages.
So mainstream Python programming style is a little different from the mainstream Java programming style
which again is different from C++ or swift.
So the question is how do we find out what good Python programming style is or should be.
And what are the guidelines that we should follow or what are the guidelines that people tend to follow.
Well lucky for us there are so-called style guides out there on the Internet.
And the most popular style guide I think these days for python is the official one from the Python Software
Foundation.
And it looks like this.
It's called pep 8 the style guide for python code.
And if you ask me this this makes excellent bedtime reading Yeah hits pretty long.
It's very comprehensive and it's also not something that needs to be followed religiously.
It's a suggestion for writing readable Python code write readable for humans.
The computers don't really care.
The thing I'll say is that this isn't the only style guide out there.
In fact many companies have their own style guides to that you know might be slightly different from
the ones of the Python Foundation for example.
So here is the style guide from the engineers at Google.
The Python style guide to be specific.
Now I was actually looking through this and trying to spot a difference with the foundation's style
guide and the thing I noticed is that these style guides are actually very very similar and there are
if you like some differences in Python software Foundation says line length should be 80 characters.
Google says it should be seventy nine.
Most of the suggestions are actually really really similar.
So one of the differences I actually found seems to me more philosophical than anything else right.
So at the end Google says they're parting words.
Be consistent.
Right.
This is this is the formatting they use all caps.
And contrast the PEP 8 style guide from the Python Foundation says a foolish consistency is the hobgoblin
of little minds.
So what they're saying here is that you can be a bit more flexible in your coding style if you need
to be.
Now as I said before in the end none of these style guides are hard and fast rules.
They're more about aesthetics and readability of the code.
So you yourself you can make a choice right.
You can choose one of these style guides and just stick to it.
That's really all there is to it.
That said let's have a look that we've written so far in the lessons and see how it stacks up against
the style guide from the Python Software Foundation.
I'm not going to ask you to read through all of pep 8 and play Spot the difference but truth be told
with actually violated some of the style recommendations of pep 8.
So what I want to do in this video is kind of give an introduction to familiarize ourselves with what
is considered good practice.
And afterwards we can return to our Python code and make changes if necessary.
One thing that we've already alluded to in the previous lessons is the indentation.
So the layout of our code and we recommended that we use four spaces for each indentation level.
If we look back at our Jupiter notebook we can see that this formatting has already been taken care
of for us right.
So we can see that this print statement open door is one two three four spaces indented.
So in many ways the editor that we're using Jupiter notebook or other text that it has modern text editors
not notepad actually shoulder some of this code formatting burden for us.
Another thing that I want to point out is naming conventions.
So I'm gonna dwell on this a little bit because it's very very handy for reading and interpreting the
code that other people have written.
So naming conventions are handy for being able to read Python code and know a little bit more about
what it is that you're looking at just from how it's typed so let's start with variables.
Typically you'll see variables written as single letters especially if you're doing math or physics
or machine learning right.
So lowercase Y Capital X these are variable names that you'll see very very often and how short variable
names like this are good when there's like an accepted convention in place.
So for example with psychic learn you'll often see the variable name for the training data as capital
X and you'll see that target values as lower case Y.
And this is a convention that they adopt in and try to be consistent with across like their whole code
base.
But there is also a big big advantage from not using single letters for variable names because if you
have a descriptive variable name right as opposed to a single letter you can help make your code a lot
more readable for a nice long descriptive variable name.
You'll want to write it in all lowercase and you want to separate if there's multiple words you want
to separate the words with an underscore so lightning underscore McQueen was an example of this kind
of formatting and if you really really want to use a single letter variable names then please please
please do not use lowercase L or uppercase I or uppercase o as your variable name.
It's really really hard to tell these apart with smaller fonts right.
If you're looking at a screen so yeah.
Single letter variable names maybe just exclude these ones for readability and how a module and package
names they actually tend to follow the same naming conventions as variables really.
Right.
They're written in lowercase and the longer names have the words separated again with an underscore
and again for functions and methods we typically use lower case words separated by underscores as well
if the function in question has parameters then the parameters tend to follow the same naming conventions
as with variables.
So with this in mind we can actually quickly spot the coding style in our Python intro notebook where
we've run afoul of these guidelines.
For example at the very top of our Python intro notebook we had some variables called my age restaurant
bill and service charge and these are written in camel case.
So camel case means starting with a lowercase letter and then capitalizing each word.
And this is quite a popular style in programming languages like Java but you see it much much less in
Python cool.
So that pretty much covers our introduction to Python programming.
We'll be diving deeper into Python programming techniques and the subsequent lessons because programming
is actually strongly linked to both data science and machine learning.
And the reason is that programming goes well beyond how to call functions from psychic learn knowing
programming develops your mindset as an engineer.
And to succeed in this course and with machine learning more generally having an engineering mindset
is key as part of this course.
And in the workplace you're going to be putting a lot of different skills together from different fields.
And those include mathematics statistics design and of course programming.
And the reason is that outside of academia you're gonna be in a position where you're going to be trying
to solve a real life business problem and figuring out how to solve this problem will test your engineering
mindset.
You know a common misconception these days is that to solve problems you need to use the most sophisticated
model possible or I don't know artificial intelligence.
Everybody is talking about A.I. right.
Artificial intelligence.
However in reality A.I. is not the only thing that matters.
And A.I. doesn't solve all problems.
Now depending on your specific problem that you're faced with A.I. might not even add all that much
value especially considering the high cost and the high amount of data required to build an A.I. system.
So you know with your engineering mindset as an engineer you're going to be thinking about how to solve
your problem in an efficient way.
So maybe a simple model will do for your purposes and this is why this course will teach you a variety
of tools and that way you can use the right tool for the job.
After all if all you've got is a hammer then everything starts to look like a nail.
And coming back to programming and programming in Python specifically python is actually a really really
nice language to start learning to program in contrast to other languages like C or C++ because Python
actually takes care a lot of the error prone grunt work that goes on behind the scenes for you.
And I don't think this is a bad thing because unlike with C or C++ with python you don't have to do
chores like laying out the memory structure managing the memory allocation or implementing axis routines
that don't get me wrong.
I think there is a time and place for all those things and becoming familiar with like how computer
hardware actually works will definitely definitely help down the line but I don't think it's useful
to get confronted with this right away especially if you've got so many other things to worry about.
Which brings me to our next topic where are we going next.
The next couple of lessons and sections will introduce you to the core of machine learning namely lost
functions and a technique called gradient descent.
This is where the actual learning takes place and we're going to take a look at how this works under
the hood for regression techniques.
Hall So we're going to be looking more closely at regressions that use more than one explanatory variable.
In other words we're gonna spice up our regression model.
For example if you were trying to predict a house price then you probably have to look at a number of
different factors like the number of bedrooms the location the total area of the flat or the House the
proximity to amenities like a park or a good school.
There's a number of factors that contribute to price of the House and the technique that will tease
out the individual contribution of each of these factors.
It's called multi variable regression and on that bombshell it's time for me to get some more coffee
and then I'll see you in the next lesson.
Take care.