All right so now it's time to visualize our means squared error cost function.
How I don't know about you but I can't look at these equations and picture what they actually look like
in my head.
I'm the kind of person who really needs a graph or a chart who has something visual to really understand
what's going on.
So let me insert a subheading here with markdown to pound symbols and I'll just write 3D plant for the
mean squared error cost function and let's have a subheading here that reads make data for theta is
the first step in creating our plot is to create a whole range of theta values that we can use to calculate
the mean squared error for.
So remember high said that the cost function depends on the parameter values and not the data itself
not the X5 or the Y five arrays but it depends on the Theta.
That's what the cost function is trying to map.
The first thing they want to do is I'm going to set the number of data points for our chart.
I'm going to call this number status.
It's gonna be a variable.
And to start off with I want to set equal to five.
And then I'm going to create our data points.
So I'll create a variable called T.H. on the underscore 0.
I want to set that equal to the return value from num PIs Lynn space functions.
That's gonna be N.P. dot fly in space parentheses.
And then we're gonna supply three inputs.
Start value.
We're gonna see minus one stop value to save equal to three and a number of integrals so the number
of points that we're gonna create I'm going gonna set that equal to an underscore status.
So that way when we look at t h underscore 0 we see that it has 5 values it's an array of 1 2 3 4 5
items.
Then when a copy this line of code here pasted in and have the same thing for theta 1 theta one is also
going to go from minus 1 to 3 and it's going to have 5 values.
So what we've done here is we've created a one dimensional array but we're gonna have a 3D plot.
So we're going to need a two dimensional array.
We're not plotting a line we're plotting a surface and for these we need an array of two dimensions
the way we're gonna create a two dimensional array is by using PIs mesh grid function.
So we've done this before.
And just to differentiate between the one dimensional and two dimensional variables I'll create another
set.
So when I say plot T Zero comma plot underscore t 1 is equal to end p mesh grid so mesh grid is the
function that will give us a two dimensional array and who are using this common notation plot T Zero
plot to one as a way of unpacking a sequence because mesh it will return to us a tuple mesh grid in
turn needs two inputs so it's gonna be theta zero and theta one from these inputs it's going to create
art 2d arrays.
So if we look at t h underscore zero dot shape we'll see it's a flat array one dimensional with five
elements and if we compare that to plot on a score T Zero dot shape then we see that it is a five by
five arrays it's two dimensional It has twenty five elements total so effectively the that shape and
I press shift enter I can see it here it looks like this five by five twenty five elements total.
Now it's time to calculate the mean squared error for all the theta zero and all the theta one values
in our range.
So let me ask you this do you think that the cost that we calculate will have one dimension or will
it have two dimensions and the answer is it's also gonna be two dimensional the surface plot needs to
know the mean square error value for all the combinations of theta zeros and theta ones we're gonna
be plotting a surface not a line after all.
So here's what we're gonna do we're gonna start out with a two dimensional array of just zeros and then
we're gonna calculate the mean squared era for each value in our array separately.
This will give us a chance to learn about another Python programming technique which is very very common
and that's using nested loops.
Let's add this as a subheading actually some changes to markdown three pound signs and then I must say
calc MSE using nested for loops going to add a few more cells down here.
Keep working in the middle of the screen.
And the first thing I want to do now is I'm going to create a two dimensional array just of zeroes so
num pi actually has a function called zeros which is perfect for this.
All we need to do is supply the dimensions of the array that we want as an output.
So the variable that's going to hold on to all our means squared error calculations is going gonna be
called plot underscore cost.
And that's gonna be equal to the return value from this zeros.
Function that I mentioned.
So end p dot zeros parentheses.
And then inside the parentheses we supply the dimensions.
So if I supply two by three.
So to come out three and then say plot on the scope cost.
I can see what a 2 by 3 array of zeros will look like.
There'll be three columns and two rows two rows three columns.
If it's five by five.
On the other hand it'll be five rows and five columns.
Now I'm not going to have a hard couldn't five in here.
Instead I'm going to use the number on the school status variable and and feed it as an argument two
are zeros function.
So what I want to do is I'm going to supply a tuple which you can see by the two parentheses and it's
gonna be square it's gonna be symmetrical so it's going to have the same number of rows and the same
number of columns.
So it'll be an on a school Fatah's comma and I'll underscore status.
This is gonna be the input to our zeros function.
So if I ever have to change my variable up here and update this cell then my plot on the score cost
will update as well.
Now it's time to talk about nested loops.
Let me add that as a commentator seen nested loop practice.
Let me show you what I mean.
So to create a nested loop we're going to use to for loops.
So the first for loop it's gonna look like this is gonna read for i in range and then say the number
three between the parentheses then colon and then inside this for loop there'll be another for loops.
So I'm going to write for j in range parentheses 3 colon and inside the second for loop.
I'm going to put a print statement.
So let me print the string hello and hit shift enter and what we see is that hello is printed a total
of nine times so three three and three three times three is nine.
So this is how many times we print Hello.
Let's go a step further than just printing Hello nine times.
Let me show you another way of doing the string interpolation with python.
This is a different way that we can work with the strings from what we've seen before.
This particular method is called an F string.
It's an F string because there's an F right in front of the string.
So it's gonna be f and then you have the single or double quotes and then within the string itself I'm
going to say the value of I is and then I'm going to use a set of curly braces and inside these curly
braces I can access a variable in my Python code.
So for example I can access this variable.
I hear the iterator in my outer loop somewhere.
See I.
In between the curly braces and then going to continue and Jay is.
And then another set of curly braces.
And then inside these curly braces I'm going to actually put the value J.
So I'm accessing this variable the second iterator the one for the inner for loop head.
Now I'm going to hit shift and to see what we get.
So what we see here is that the values that are printed out from inside these curly braces change every
time the loop is executed by having this special notation the F in front and then the curly braces were
able to tell Python that something inside this string should not be considered a string.
Instead we're able to reference values that are stored in variables elsewhere.
Now the other thing that's really cool about this particular pattern is that we can see what happened
exactly when our loop executed nine times.
So before we had Hello print it nine times.
But this time we can see what's actually going on and how these I J values are changing when the loop
first starts out.
I's equal to zero.
And J is equal to zero.
And then what happens is that the inner loop executes three times J becomes equal to 1 and then to 2.
And after that it's done executing.
And then the outer loop increments by 1.
So I goes from zero to 1 and then it's Jay's turn again J goes from zero to two executes three times
and the whole thing repeats one final time.
So one of the things you can probably already tell is how this might be applied to many many different
kinds of problems.
In particular it goes very very well with iterating through a 2D array or a 2D matrix if you want to
hit up every single value then you can go row by row and column by column.
And this is exactly what we're going to do.
The important thing with this sort of stuff has with all Python code is to make sure the indentation
is correct and that way Python knows that this loop is indeed nested inside this first one.