In this lesson we're going to discuss how to remove the h m l tags from our emails.
What I mean by h Tim L. tanks well H.M. is what makes an e-mail look pretty.
If I look at the newsletter from Product Hunt here I've got wonderful formatting.
I've got images embedded I've got animations embedded and it just looks incredibly well put together.
The same email message in plain text will look like what I've got here on the left on the right.
I have the rich formatting on the left.
I have the plain text.
So the purpose of HMO in emails and Web sites is to add both structure and some formatting.
Let me quickly show you how to add some basic formatting using HMO and this will also show us how each
team l tags basically work.
See we have a regular plain text that reads Do not reply then this text will be displayed in the email
in a standard default way however if we wanted to make this text stand out you might consider using
ECMO to make this text bold and you can do this by surrounding this piece of text with a tag namely
the B tag B for bold the way the HMO works is that there is a beginning and an ending tag and that way
we can mark where the bold text begins and where the bold text should end.
One of the best places to see each Tim Allen action of course is on the web.
If you go to a website called example dot com and then right click on the page and go to view source
you will get something like this.
This is what the HMO code that's behind the Web site actually looks like this is what the developer
for the website will have actually written.
And thanks to our browser this code here is rendered like so looking at the HD email behind the Web
site allows us to see a couple of things.
For example we can see here that there's a title called example domain example domain sits in between
two tags an opening tag and a closing tag.
And what this little bit of code does is it makes example domain show up here on our tab bar for example.
Another neat little trick that you can try out with this particular website or any Web site is inspecting
particular elements about right click and then select Inspect Element I will see something like this
when I move this over slightly move this over slightly.
And now what I can do is I can hover over a particular element from the HDMI code and my browser will
highlight which bits of the website the piece of code is referring to.
So for example right now I'm hovering over a heading which is marked with the h1 tag each for heading.
If I move my mouse down a little bit then I get to a paragraph I can explode this here and select the
text inside.
But the paragraph as a whole is this bit here.
And again they each html tag for this bit here has a P 4 paragraph at the beginning and at the end.
So this is our heading this is our paragraph and both the heading and the paragraph are contained inside
the body and the body refers to the whole thing here.
So that's a very short introduction to each team l tags.
Let's see how each HTML is used inside our corpus of emails.
One of the emails that I've looked at and a bit more detail is the one document idea number two.
This is the email with the file name beginning 0 0 2 1 4.
Let me show you what the body of this email looks like in Jupiter notebook.
This email is at position number two in our message column so we can access this email with theta dot
and square brackets 2 and then the string message in all caps.
And what we get is something like this.
Now personally this isn't the most helpful formatting here that we're getting.
So let me show you how this email would look like in my atom text editor where the formatting is a bit
more user friendly at the top.
We've got the email header scrolling down.
We get to the email body and at the bottom him with the syntax highlighting.
You can easily spot the HDMI all tax if I scroll down a bit further I can show you.
There is a paragraph in this email and you've got the do not reply part that's going to show up in bold
due to the fact that it is surrounded by these bolding HDMI attacks.
Now these are the HDMI tags that we're going to remove from our message bodies.
We're going to clean our data in such a way that these H2 tags are no longer present.
And the reason we're doing this is because we're interested in only the actual words for now as well
as the text with our bag of words approach in our naive bayes classifier.
So in a way we're gonna be treating these HDMI tags just as we were treating punctuation namely we're
going to remove them back in Jupiter.
Let me add a markdown cell here and that markdown cell is going to read removing H terminal tags from
emails using this at property of the data frame.
We've had a very efficient way of looking up and accessing a single value in the pan this data frame.
This is where we specified the index name and the column name when it comes to stripping out the HDMI
tags from this particular email.
All the heavy lifting will be done for us by a python module called beautiful soup at the top with our
notebook imports we're going to write from peaceful import beautiful soup then we'll hit shift until
here scroll back down and just inside this cell here where we've access a cell in our data frame we'll
create a variable called soup instead of equal to beautiful soup parentheses then we'll take the code
that we've just written and just contact pasted inside here put a comma after it and then supply a string
called H T M L dot puzzler what I've just done is applied to arguments the first one is the text that
I would like to pass and the second one is the parser that I would like to use how the beautiful thing
about Python is that it comes with an HDMI El Paso that is ready to go.
That is why we can just tell beautiful soup to use the built in parser in Python with this string here
now what we can do is print out the formatted version of this email so let's write a print statement
and then supply the following argument.
We're gonna say soup dot pretty define
parentheses and hit shift into what we see now is a pretty defined version of the original text.
So this is closer to what we saw in the atom text editor that I used earlier for make it a bit larger.
Like so you can see it a bit better.
There we go.
The only thing Jupiter doesn't do here is do the syntax highlighting on our tags but other than that
with the indentation you can actually tell which parts are H.M. and it's a lot more readable.
All right.
So we've seen how beautiful soup can defy a piece of text that contains HMO but it can also remove all
our tags.
And this is actually the primary purpose of what we're gonna be using it for so just below the cell.
Let's remove all the HD hymnal and we can do that by calling the Get text method on our soup object.
So soup don't get on a school text will remove our HD hymnal now our output will no longer have any
HD hymnal in it and you can verify this by looking at the output him.
So for example the bolding tags that used to surround do not reply have disappeared.
Alright so that's pretty much it.
All the heavy lifting has been done for us by Python module him.
The next lesson we're finally gonna start tackling more of these emails and what we're gonna do is we're
gonna put all of our work all of the cleaning all the pre processing into some Python functions.
I'll see you there.