In this lesson we're going to talk about simplifying our model.
And that's because all else equal simpler models are preferable to complex ones.
Remember the Zen of Python simple is better than a complex and complex is better than complicated and
this doesn't just apply to programming.
The same thing can be said about our regression model.
By the way you can always bring up this little gem of programming philosophy when you type import this
in Jupiter notebook simple models really are preferable to complex ones.
All else equal.
So the question is how can we simplify our model.
One of the easiest ways is to remove some of the explanatory variables but can we just drop some features.
Is that a wise thing to do.
And if so which features should we drop.
What about the features that we're not highly correlated with property prices in the correlation matrix.
We saw that distance from employment centers only had a zero point two five correlation with our target.
DHS had a low correlation with price but also it had a high correlation with our industry factor of
minus zero point seven one.
At the time we were wondering how much value that distance from employment centers feature really added.
But now we know scrolling down.
We've got the p values which test for the significance of our different factors and we can see that
distance is actually very statistically significant.
So we should probably keep DHS around now on the other hand looking back up at our industry factor.
This has a p value of around zero point 4 4 meaning it is not statistically significant.
The threshold for p values if you recall was zero point zero five.
So now the question is should we try removing the industry factor from the model.
And the thing is it is really really tempting to remove insignificant predictors.
But even dropping statistically insignificant features is not something people do lightly because even
a feature with a low p value can add value to the model as a whole by providing some kind of information
that the other features do not provide.
Actually deciding on what to keep and what to throw away from a machine learning model is a bit of an
art and it gets into this whole topic of feature selection which is a very very big topic indeed and
one that we will continue to tackle throughout this course.
The goal of this lesson is to introduce you to this topic a feature selection in the context of a regression
model and we will be looking at a metric that you can use to help you make your decisions.
And that metric is called Bayesian information criterion or B I see the patient information criterion
is a way you can measure complexity.
It's basically a number that allows you to compare two different models.
So what you end up doing is you run a regression with model number one and then you run a regression
with Model Number two now model number one might have a big value of 1 4 8 and model number 2 might
have a big value of 1 5 for the actual number doesn't by itself mean very much.
What matters is which one is lower because all else equal a lower big number is better so this measure
can help you pick between two or more models.
So what models will we compare Well for starters let's compare the model that includes the industry
feature and the model that excludes the industry feature.
Let's commemorate this with another markup sell in Jupiter notebook so I I change my sell here to markdown
and then put a section heading here.
Model simplification and the Bayesian information criterion to calculate the patient information criterion.
We're once again going to use our stats model modules regression capabilities instead of psychic learn
so let's copy the sell here and paste that below.
I'm going to delete these comments and I'm going to add a new comment up here.
That reads our original model with log prices and all features and the data frame that I've got here.
I'm going to store inside a variable so going to see original on a score QF is equal to PD dot data
frame and so on and now what I want to do is I want to add some additional print statements and in these
print statements will output both the patient information criterion value and the r squared for the
regression.
Now previously we've used psychics learn score method to print out the r squared but things work a little
differently with the stats model module and I think this is a good time to practice making sense of
the official documentation.
So as a challenge can you look up the stats model docs for the regression results and figure out how
to print out both the patient information criterion value for this regression as well as the r squared.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give this a shot.
You ready.
Here's the solution.
Being able to read and interpret the official documentation for all a lot of these Python modules is
one of the key skills and becoming a better programmer.
If I click on my results object and press shift tab on my keyboard to bring up the quick documentation
I don't actually get anything useful.
I just see that to get further information I need to look at the regression results documentation.
The same thing is true if I click here and I find out that I'm just dealing with a data frame or when
I click here.
So in all these cases the quick documentation isn't actually helping me all that much I'm just not having
any luck on getting the relevant information.
So what I'm going to have to do is I don't have to google the documentation myself.
The best keywords to enter into that white text box are stats model regression results and that should
pretty much take you to one of the stats model pages.
Now out of these three that I've got here the one I'm looking for is the page for the documentation
on the regression results object.
So it's the third one down here.
This is the regression results object from the linear model.
This is the documentation page that you want to be looking for.
The other reason why the regression results page that I've clicked on is the relevant one is because
this particular object the regression results wrapper inherits most of the methods and attributes from
regression results meaning the capabilities of a regression results wrapper object which we've got and
a regression results object are pretty much the same.
They have a lot in common a lot of the methods and attributes are inherited from this particular object.
Yeah they're closely linked.
So this is why I'm looking on this page now.
This is an incredibly long page if you look at it it's very Hey comprehensive but the interesting thing
is that we can find both the parameter attribute and p values attribute on this page.
So if I search for parameters on this page I can find parameters listed as one of the attributes and
I can also find p values listed as one of the attributes and you probably already spotted it at the
top of the page is the p i c attribute that Bayes information criteria to be I C is the name of the
attribute for the Bayes information criteria and the way we access this attribute is simply by writing
results.
Don't be.
I see when I if I had shift into I can see what the value of this actually is it's negative one hundred
and thirty nine point eight five so about negative one hundred and forty and what about the R squared.
Going back to the documentation and scrolling down squared unsurprisingly has the attribute name r squared
all lowercase and in one word so results dot r squared will bring up the R squared for this regression
which is zero point 7 9 3.
Let's have both of these lines of code in a print statement.
So what have print B I see is in the single quotes comma results done by C closing parenthesis and then
I'll have print
r squared is comma results start ask what closing parentheses.
There we go.
Okay so now we have both the r squared and R pick printed out the comforting thing to see is that the
stats model and socket learn is exactly the same R squared.
So we're doing things right now in this case the patient information criterion is actually a negative
number and that's absolutely fine.
What matters is how does number stacks up to our next model.
So I'm going to copy this paste it and then I want to modify my comment.
And when I write here reduced Model Number One excluding in this and then what I'll say is that X on
a score including on a score constant is equal to X on a score including constant don't drop parentheses
square brackets single quotes in this all caps comma axis equals 1.
So in this line of code I'm redefining the data frame of features by overwriting what's stored inside
this variable.
I'm dropping the in this column from the data frame and storing that as the new feature data frame.
So on this line when it comes to training our model we are excluding the index feature next I'm going
to change the name of this variable to Cliff underscore minus on a school in this.
So that way we're not overwriting the coefficient data frame from the cell above.
And I'm going to delete this comment here.
Now let me hit shift enter and refresh this cell.
So this result is already quite interesting.
What we can see is that our patient information criterion has gotten more negative.
We've now got the value minus one 4 five point two.
So this is an even lower number than before.
So we have an improvement in terms of reducing complexity but at the same time it's also really nice
to see that the r squared at zero point seven nine.
Pretty much stays where it is.
So even though we have removed one feature from our dataset it hasn't really impacted our fit in a material
way.
This is actually very encouraging.
Let's go back up to our p values and experiment with removing something else.
Let's experiment with removing age coming back down I'm going to copy the cell paste that changed my
comment here to reduce Model Number Two excluding endorse and age and then in this line I'm going to
have to add the single quotes and age between the square brackets.
I'm also going to rename our data frame of coefficients to maybe reduced co F and now when it shift
into and what we actually see is a further improvement based on the Bayesian information criterion.
So we get an even lower pick number at minus one for nine and a half but we see no material change in
the r squared.
So this makes me think that removing both innocent age is actually a beneficial thing.
We can probably safely drop these two features simplifying our model without incurring too much of a
cost in terms of lost information and a worse fit.
How even though I just gave you two examples where removing a feature improved the patient information
criterion and left the r square pretty much unchanged.
This isn't always the case if I change age to one of the other features say maybe zone Z in and press
shift into what we see is not really all that clear cut.
In this case we have a higher big number and a lower ask word than before.
So this is probably not the direction we want to go.
Same thing if I change this to our tax feature.
Again we're making our model worse.
And same thing if I change this to the else that feature removing else that actually makes our model
much much worse.
You can see how much the Bayesian information criterion jumped and how much lower our r squared is.
In this case so else that is actually a very important to keep in the model changes back to age and
press shift and so that we're back to where we started.
Okay.
So where are we now.
We've made two small tweaks to our model.
We've removed two of the features which were not statistically significant and we've looked at the Bayesian
information criterion and the r squared to provide additional justification for leaving them out and
simplifying our model and by doing so we've managed to improve our pick number from around minus 140
to minus 150.
So we get about a 9 10 point improvement in the big number but we don't incur a material penalty on
the r squared.
We're still on zero point seven nine.
Cool.
So that about wraps up our introduction to thinking about feature selection and one thing that we can
do now is we can link this lesson to our previous one.
We can link this to the discussion on multi calling parity and looking for stability in the theta estimates
for our features because we've made quite a few tweaks to our model and we said that one of the symptoms
of multi calling parity are unstable coefficients.
Having run three different versions of our regression and having stored our coefficients in some variables
we can now look at them side by side and double check if there are any strange developments.
Now I'd be surprised if we saw any.
Because we have no indication of MultiClient parity so far.
But take a look at this.
If I create a variable called frames and make that equal to a list of our data frames.
So we had the original coefficient we had the QF underscore minus underscore in this data frame.
And then finally we had you reduced on a score coiffed data frame of coefficients to put them all side
by side.
I would use Panda's con cap method so PD dot com cat and then in the parentheses to provide my list
of data frames and an axis I want this to be concatenated along the columns.
So side by side as opposed to top to bottom right so axis is gonna be equal to 1 instead of 0.
Let's see what we get.
Fantastic.
Now what you can also see here in this table here is how Python treats missing values in a data frame.
You see these nans n n Nan stands for not a number meaning there is a missing value here.
So this column here is a reduced model without the age and without the industry feature.
So we've got nans in place of these rows.
Looking at this table is actually very very encouraging because what I'm seeing is that despite tweaking
the model all the coefficients.
Yeah for all three.
So like Charles River crime they all are remarkably consistent so the numbers change somewhat but they
don't switch signs.
They don't change drastically.
So these are all very very stable coefficient estimates and the same actually holds true.
If you were to remove tax which we suspected was a potential problem source.
So even removing tax and rerunning this you'd see that the data estimates are nice and stable between
the three models and that brings us to the end of this lesson in the next one.
We're gonna take our evaluation of our regression even further.
We're going to look at how far off our models predictions were from their true values.
We're gonna be looking and analyzing how our regression residuals how.
As an aside while putting this lesson together for you I found myself googling the word big hand trying
to read up on the information criterion a hand for a split second I was quite confused.
Well hi all I got on the front page was information about pens hand the website of the Bournemouth International
Centre.
The other time that happened to me was when I read up on nested tables then I was confronted with this.
So yeah if you have any stories like this to share please put them in the comments section for this
video.
Laughter here at CNN next lesson.