All right so how do we get to making a prediction or a forecast we have to provide.
Two things.
The estimated property price and the range that goes with the price.
Because this is what the pros do and will also provide an estimate of what the home was worth plus a
degree of uncertainty around that number.
The estimated price is easy enough right.
Because once we have the theta parameters for the model all we have to do is plug them in and then together
with the values for the individual features we get an estimate we get our y hat.
But what about the range.
What does that come from.
The range will actually depend on the shape of the distribution that you're working with.
If we know the distribution we can estimate the range very accurately.
And here's the thing.
Our go to distribution is usually the normal distribution because the very very nice thing about the
normal distribution is that we know its shape.
We know that for a normal distribution 68 percent of the observations are between these two points.
Sixty eight percent of all the values in this distribution are within this purple range right here.
And for normal distribution we also know that around 95 percent of the values are between these two
points here.
Ninety five percent of the observations fall within this pink range that I've highlighted right here.
The individual points that I've drawn on this histogram right here actually have a name.
They quantify the amount of variation around the mean.
The mean is right here in the middle of the distribution and the distance from the mean to that bright
purple point is called one standard deviation for a normal distribution.
You'll usually see the Greek letter sigma used to denote the standard deviation.
Now what about the other points that I had drawn on here earlier.
Well the left purple point is at minus one standard deviation minus one standard deviation from the
mean and for normal distribution as we said before around 68 percent of all the observations lie between
minus and plus one standard deviation.
OK.
What about the pink points.
Well the right pink point is that two standard deviations and the left pink point is at minus two standard
deviations.
And as we've said before approximately ninety five percent of observations lie between plus two and
minus two standard deviation is for a normal distribution.
Now let me ask you this.
If this green point here right in the middle is our estimate for the property price from our model are
y hat What is the distribution that we're gonna be looking at here.
Any guess once the distribution that tells us something about the variance in our price estimates how
we're going to be coming full circle here.
It's actually the distribution of the residuals from our regression.
This is the reason why we care so much about whether the distribution is a normal distribution or not.
Now the next question you might ask at this point is well.
OK.
So if the distribution is the distribution of the residuals then what do the purple and pink dots represent.
How do we get our range.
Do you remember our mean square error.
And then the mean square is not the purple dot but we can make one small modification to the mean square
error and get something very very handy for calculating the range and making predictions.
And that small modification is by taking the square root of this thing by taking the square root of
the mean square error.
We get another metric and this one is called yes surprise surprise.
The root mean square error or our MSE and it's this metric the RNC that has a really really nice interpretation
because the root mean square error represents one standard deviation of the differences between our
actual and our predicted values.
The root mean square error is one standard deviation in the distribution of our residuals.
So let's look at the chart again to create our range around our estimated price our so-called prediction
interval.
The first thing we choose is how wide we want that interval to be say we want to cover around 95 percent
of the observations.
Then we would use two standard deviations either side.
And this means taking our prediction and adding two times the brute mean square error to it for the
upper bound and subtracting two times the root mean square error for our lower bound on our prediction.
And that's how we get the range in our Jupiter notebook.
This means simply taking the square root of R means quite error that we've already calculated coming
to the cell where we've got our data frame with our mean square error.
What I'm going to do is add another column so I'll put a comma here go to the next line single quotes
and put R and S E here and then a colon.
Now I can take this entire list here.
Copy it.
And then here what I want to do is I want to use num pi and call the square root function from num Pi.
And as an argument I'm going to pass in the list that I just copied and what this will do is I'll take
the square root of all the items in the list.
Let me refresh the cell.
Here we go.
Now that we've done that I want to give you a challenge.
Suppose we have an estimate from our model.
Yeah for a house price of thirty thousand dollars.
Can you calculate the upper and lower bound for a 95 percent prediction interval using the reduced log
model.
In other words can you calculate the upper and the lower bound for the range around this estimate.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video before I show you the solution
all right.
Let's take it from the top.
Someone out of print statement and to spell it out.
Someone say one standard deviation in log prices because we've got two units is and that will be the
square root of our log means quote error.
So end p dot square root reduced underscore log MSE agreed What's that equal to it's equal to this much.
Now what about two standard deviations.
I can calculate that simply by taking the first print statement copying it and then multiplying this
whole thing by two.
Here we go.
This is two standard deviations the upper bound for the prediction interval will be equal to our White
Hat plus two times the route means squared error.
Now I've been pretty sneaky and I've given you the y hat in dollar values.
So you actually have to use a log transformation and put out log 30 since our model is given in thousands
and then you have to add two times and p dot square root reduced underscore log underscore MSE So this
is our y hat plus two times the root means squared error let me print that out so I'm going to say print
the upper bound for a ninety five percent prediction interval is comma upper and a score bound that's
equal to three point seven eight approximately how if we wanted to see this and dollar values then we
can say well the upper bound in land prices for a 95 percent prediction interval is this much and I
can copy this pasted in and I can say the upper bound in normal prices is and p dot e to the power of
upper bound.
So let's see what that is.
I can make that more explicit by multiplying this whole thing times 1000.
Putting a little dollar sign here and there I've got my upper bound the lower bound is very very similar.
Can you copy these three lines paste them in and change this to lower bound is equal to N.P. dot log
thirty minus two times the root mean square area then I can change my print statements to read the lower
bound and log prices for 95 percent prediction interval is lower underscore bound and the lower bound
in normal prices is end p r e times times lower I just go bound times 1000.
Let's see what this reads.
The lower bound in this case is twenty thousand and six hundred and thirty five dollars.
Now the trick with this challenge is to do the addition of the root mean square error and the transformation
in the right order because otherwise you'll get a very very different result.
The incorrect way of calculating the upper bound would have been to take two times the root mean square
error and simply say well okay we've got a estimate of thirty thousand and then we're going to add to
it the transformed value and Piedmont e times times and then the root mean square error.
Times 1000.
So this was the little trick in how I phrase this challenge in summary we often look towards the root
mean square error when we're interested in the predictive power of our models and to some extent we
can use the root means squared error.
To also compare the models and the reason is is that the root mean square is a very good measure of
how accurately the model predicts the target because we can determine a range the width of this range
is a very important criterion.
If the main purpose of the model is prediction and this is a big contrast to something like r squared
because r squared says absolutely nothing about the predictive power of the model or the prediction
error.
Okay.
So we're slowly coming towards the end of the section in the next lesson.
We're gonna finish it up by building a valuation tool for our boss and our real estate office and that's
going to involve probably updating the prices to reflect today's dollar values a little bit.
I think the past an upper price of fifty thousand dollars is not really that accurate anymore.
And we're also going to be looking at how we can create a python function with optional arguments.
So arguments where there's already default values set similar to what we've seen with seaborne and my
plot lib and we're going to cover the syntax the python syntax how we can create functions like this
ourselves have see in the next lessons care.