Are you ready.
Here's the solution.
Going to the top of the file I'll add another constant and call this constant skull file and it's going
to point to the skull icon dot PMG
this one right here shift enter on the cell scroll back down and now it's time to put all of this text
that's in the Shakespeare hyphen Hamlet dot text file from the analytic resources into a single string
so call a variable Hamlet under school corpus and set that equal to a healthy K Dot corpus dot Gutenberg
dot words parentheses single quotes Shakespeare hyphen Hamlet Dot T X T the same file name as right
here the word list is going to be equal to square brackets single quotes dot join and I'll join the
word up from my loop for word in Hamlet corpus will give us our list of words and then I'll see Hamlet
as string as equal to single quotes with a space dot join word list that's our play as a string.
Now all I need to do is maybe go skull underscore icon is equal to image dot open.
So here we're using pillow feet in the relative path to the file and now it's time to create that mask.
So I'll say image on the school mask is equal to a new pillow image object with mode equal to our GDP
the size equal to the skull icon dot size and color equal to white 2 5 5 comma 2 5 5 comma 2 5 5 inside
a tuple the RG B array for this skull image will simply be a num pi array created from the image mask
now we can create our word cloud word on a school cloud it's gonna be equal to word cloud parentheses
mask equal to the RG B array from Hamlet I'm going to choose my background color as white and then I'm
going to pick a color map the color map that I'm going to go for for my skull image is gonna be called
bone I figure that's gonna be a nice combination and for the maximum words max underscored Wood's argument.
I'm going to pick in I'll start out with 50 and then I'm going to up it just so you can see how a higher
number will actually look a lot better then I'll use word cloud to generate to generate my image but
of course I have to feed in which string I want to use.
So Hamlet a string.
That's it for the word cloud.
Now it's all gonna be mad.
Plot lib peal T dot figure sets the size of our figure.
I'm gonna go again with 16 and 8.
Think that's a good science for me and for the video I'll use the I am show method feed in the word
cloud along with an interpolation of by linear by linear.
So I think that's spelled right.
Good.
I'll remove the axes so axis parentheses
and then I'll show my chart.
The moment of truth of course is hitting shift enter on this.
Let's see what it looks like
all right.
So I've got a value era canvas size is too small.
Any idea what went wrong.
The reason is I've got an entirely white canvas.
The RG B array is fully white.
There is no place for the word cloud to draw anything and that's because I haven't called.
Image mask dot paste with the skull icon.
So I need to write image on a scroll mask.
Dot paste parentheses skull icon comma box equals skull icon and if I refresh myself now then this error
should disappear.
So here's my image and nobody in the world will be able to tell that this is indeed a skull image.
The culprit this time is the maximum number of words this number here is too small.
It doesn't actually help us see any of the detail in the image.
So I'm gonna change it from 50 to 600 and refresh myself.
For this many words your computer might actually run for a little while because it's doing a lot of
work to generate this image but I think the wait was worth it.
We've got a beautiful word cloud here with a fantastic color scheme and a lot of the details in the
word cloud being made visible by the high number of words in the word cloud.
Now that we're done with you to practice word clouds and using the analytic resources it's time to create
a word cloud.
Far ham and our spam messages those we will create from our dataset and I'll see you in the next lesson.
Take care.