Over the next couple of lessons we're going to talk about Python programming in depth.
The aim of this section is to make sense and explain the code that we wrote in the previous lessons
when we we're estimating the movie revenue.
As such the next lessons are not going to teach you more machine learning concepts.
Instead the lessons will focus on the Python programming fundamentals.
We're going to take a deep dive into the python code that we wrote for visualizing our data and for
running our aggression in the Jupiter notebook.
What Python programming fundamentals will we look at.
We're going to discuss programming concepts such as variables data types functions methods and objects.
These are the fundamental stepping stones on which all the other future lessons are going to be built
for these lessons.
I will assume no prior programming knowledge.
So if you've already got some programming experience feel free to skip ahead through the upcoming videos
or just watch the videos at double speed.
How I also tried really really hard to find you guys some interesting data sets for us to look at hand.
I came across a pretty weird medical study that was done in the United States in 1968.
So for her programming exercises we will use the data from this study which examines how math test scores
were affected by the use of psychedelic drugs.
Now without further ado let's jump straight into how to get set up.
Let's fire up a new Jupiter notebook.
This time we're going to use the locally installed version instead of the try.
Don Jupiter dot org Web site.
Now there's different ways you can do this.
First let me show you how to do it with the anaconda Navigator.
So simply open the anaconda navigator and then click on launch Jupiter notebook at this point.
The Jupiter notebook will open in your browser but you'll notice if you look at your address bar instead
of it reading tried out Jupiter dot org.
It will read local host the other way to open a Jupiter notebook without going through the anaconda
navigator is simply by going through the terminal or the command prompt.
First let me show you how to do this on a mac on a Mac.
You'd open the terminal
and then you would type Jupiter notebook and hit enter and you'll get exactly the same result as going
through the anaconda navigator.
Since loading the anaconda navigator can be a bit slow at times.
I actually prefer this as a way of getting to the Jupiter notebook very very quickly.
Now if you're running a Windows machine you don't have a terminal.
Instead you'll have something called the command prompt.
In fact when you installed Anaconda it would have actually given you something called the anaconda prompt
as a convenient shortcut you'll find this Anaconda prompt in your start menu.
So if I go to show all my apps it's right here Anaconda prompt
and this is what it looks like since I use this Anaconda prompt quite a bit.
I've actually pinned it to my taskbar for easy access and this is what I'll recommend for you guys as
well in the anaconda prompt.
You simply give the same command as on Mac.
You're right Jupiter notebook
when you hit enter you do put a notebook should fire up in your default browser.
Now what we're gonna do is we're going to create a folder where we're gonna save all our work and we're
gonna call this folder AML projects the way to create this folder is to go to new and then go to New
Folder.
You should then see an untitled folder appear.
But instead of leaving it as untitled folder you're going to put a tick box next to it and then you
get ahead rename.
And here you're gonna give it the name M.L. projects and confirm so click on your MLK projects folder
to open it.
And then once inside you're going to create a new Python notebook.
Click on you then Python 3
and then let's rename this notebook to zero to Python intro hit rename and then let's navigate back
to the MLK projects folder.
You've probably done some work in the previous lesson when we were working on tried on Jupiter dot org
and you've probably downloaded your notebook at the time what you can do now is upload that notebook
to your M.L. projects folder.
That way you can keep all your coursework together.
So just click upload.
Select your python notebook and select the cost underscore revenue underscore clean data set as well
that see as the file that I provided previously and then click open.
You should see the two line items appear in your AML projects folder where you can confirm by hitting
the blue upload button how you've got your previous work accessible here together with the data set
that we used great.
Now we're all set to dive into Python programming.