In this lesson we're going to learn about data visualization and Data Exploration.
So why visualize our data well graphs and charts are incredibly powerful and very useful in being able
to understand what it is that we're actually dealing with because there's actually only so much that
you can learn from looking at a table of numbers.
Very often you want to put it up on a chart so that way you can spot problems you can spot outliers
you can spot trends and you can spot patterns.
Pictures are incredibly informative so let's create this chart in something called Jupiter notebook.
Head on over to a website called Jupiter dot org.
If you scroll down here then there's a button where it says try it in your browser and this will take
you to Jupiter dot org slash try.
I want to put a link to this very site in the course resources so you'll find it there as well.
Once you're here click on Try Jupiter with Python.
And after a little loading time then you should be dropped off on a screen like this.
Now if you didn't end up on the page that I showed you just now and instead you got this message then
you can do one of two things Either you can skip ahead and see how we can install Jupiter or you can
wait a few minutes and just refresh.
And that should drop you off somewhere like this.
So why do I like Jupiter and why are we using it.
Well this is an incredible tool.
It's very powerful.
It's very easy to use and it provides instant feedback.
When we're writing our Python code Jupiter works on something called cells.
And you can execute the code in these cells individually.
Let me show you what I mean.
So with this little plus sign here you can insert your cells and if you type something in one of these
cells say five plus five and hit shift enter on your keyboard then this cell will execute and you'll
see the output below the cell.
Alternatively if you don't wanna use the keyboard shortcut there's also this run button up here.
So let me just change this to five plus six and press run then you'll see this cell being executed and
the output being updated.
The other reason I really like Jupiter notebook is because it's fantastic at allowing you to present
information because the cells are actually all not created equal.
Some of these cells only present you with information like these ones and these are so-called markdown
cells and other cells are actually cells that expect Python code like these ones and you can see this
in the difference in the formatting.
Now let me show you how to start a notebook of our own.
If I click up here what says Jupiter just on the logo I could take into something that looks a little
bit like a Windows Explorer or Mac finder.
I've got folders and files on him.
And here I can click on new and say new notebook and I can specify that I want a new Python 3 notebook
and this will open a new tab in my browser with a fresh notebook that we can use for this project.
So let's get this notebook a name instead of it being called Untitled let's call it linear regression
and then we'll hit rename.
And if you change Tamps back to the first tab here you can see this notebook appear in green right here.
So how do we get our data from our spreadsheet into our Jupiter notebook.
Well there's a small button here called upload and if you click on it then you can upload a CSB file
to Jupiter.
Now you can either download your data from the Google Sheet in a C is V or a comma separated value format.
But what I'd recommend is to download the cost underscore revenue underscore clean dot CSP file that
we've provided in the course resources.
This way we can ensure that we're all working from the same clean data.
And there's no accidental typos.
So just select this file and hit open and then confirm your upload.
You should then see the CSP file appear right here.
So now we've uploaded it successfully heading back into our Jupiter notebook.
We now have to get the data from the CSP file into our notebook.
In other words we need a way of accessing the data in the notebook itself.
The problem is is that our notebook is currently blank.
It doesn't know how to do anything yet.
So we have to give our notebooks some sort of functionality and we can do this by accessing code that
other people have already written and taking advantage of that other people's Python code is bundled
up in something called a module.
And in order to use a module in our notebook we have to import this module the first module that I'd
like to introduce to you is called pandas.
So if you write import pandas in his very first cell and hit shift enter on our keyboard or press this
little run button then we've accomplished just that.
Now our notebook has all the functionality that the pandas module has pandas is one of the key modules
for Data Science and we'll be using it a lot on this course.
It's incredibly useful from manipulating and analyzing data and the pandas module can already help us
because it knows how to read CSB files.
So let's use it to get the data into our Jupiter notebook.
If we write pandas don't read underscore CEV and then we open a path parentheses.
Then we can supply the file name of our CSC file between these two single quotes our file name.
If you recall was cost on a school revenue underscore clean don't CSP and you can see that right here.
So I'm just going to copy this and then pasted in between these two single quotes.
The key thing to understand here is that we're accessing the ability to read CSP files from the panels
module using this dot notation but now that we've read our CSP file we need to store the data from this
file somewhere.
So we need some sort of object that holds onto our data like a container and we can create this simply
by writing data equals on the left hand side and then having pandas don't read CSB on the right hand
side.
What this will do is it will create an object called data which then gets a value that data that's contained
inside the CSP file.
And if we run the cell we can actually look at it.
So let's click Run and then write data and then just hit run again and here what we should see is all
the data points and all the information that was previously stored inside our CSB file.
The great thing about this is now we have an object in our notebook that we can use to analyze and explore
our data.
Let me show you what I mean.
So instead of printing out all these 5000 rows below the cell what we can do is we can put a dot after
our data object and tell it to describe itself.
So with data dot describe and two parentheses at the end and hitting shift enter we get the following
output we get some summary statistics on the data that's in the two columns production budgets and our
worldwide gross we get to see how many entries where in our data frame we get to see how many entries
were in these columns.
In this case we have five thousand and thirty four entries.
The reason that these numbers look a little bit funny is because they're in scientific notation.
So for example five point zero three four E three equates to five thousand and thirty four and three
point two nine e seven equates to thirty two million so three point two nine e seven or thirty two point
nine million is actually the average production budget of all the films in our dataset and this is what
we see here labeled as the mean but not only do we get the number of entries and the average of the
values but we can also see a number of other statistics like the minimum value the smallest value to
the smallest production budget was and one hundred dollars and we also see the smallest amount of worldwide
gross revenue which was two thousand six hundred dollars.
So now we've got all our data in one place.
We have it all stored inside an object called data but let's separate it out let's separate out what
we're using to make our prediction our production budget from what we're going to predict namely our
gross revenue.
And the reason we're doing this is because we're preparing our data for the next steps.
We want to be able to create some charts and we want to be able to create our linear regression.
So it's going to be very very nice to stay organized and have our features separated from our target.
So I come down here to a new cell and I'm going to create two more objects.
One is going to be called Capital X. And the other one is going to be called lowercase y.
Now our X is going to hold on to our production budgets and our Y is going to hold on to our revenue.
So we're using that equals sign again just as we did up here.
So now we have to think about what should these two things be equal to what kind of object should our
X and our y be at this point.
I'd like to introduce you to one of the main workhorses of data science.
The pandas data frame you can think of a data frame as a very powerful spreadsheet like a spreadsheet
on steroids.
So the question is how do we get hold of a panda's data frame.
Well we can come back up here where we're importing pandas and we can import the data frame from pandas.
So from pandas import data frame.
Now if you hit tab on your keyboard then Jupiter notebook should actually autocomplete some of the code
for you.
That way you won't make a typo here with say a lowercase f or something autocomplete is incredibly useful
for avoiding these small mistakes.
Now we can come back to our X in our y here what we're gonna do it's going to create a new data frame
and this data frame is going to contain our production budgets so X is going to equal data frame open
parentheses data common columns is equal to square brackets and in the single quotes we're going to
provide the column name the column name for X's is gonna be production budget USD so you can just copy
this from the spreadsheet or you can type it out as long as you make sure that the spelling matches
exactly and then your line of code should look like this.
So what are we doing here.
We're creating a new data frame from our raw data which we've got him and we're selecting a single column
from this data namely the production budgets and that's how we're splitting up our data frame here for
our X's.
Now at this point I'd like to throw our challenge to you.
I'd like you to pause the video and split up the data for our wives.
Can you create a data frame just like this but instead of grabbing that first column can you grab the
other column.
The worldwide gross and then this information as our Why.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give this a go all right.
Here's the solution.
You can actually copy the line above and paste it below and then just replace the column name with the
column name for the worldwide gross revenue.
So in this case you need to take this column name here and added between the single quotes inside the
square brackets.
Having done this we've separated our data.
We've created two new data frames one called Capital X which holds onto our features and one called
lowercase Y which holds onto our target.
So let's execute the code in the cell and see what happens.
So if we click Run him then what you see is that we actually get an error.
We get something that says name data frame is not defined.
And the reason we're getting this error is because our notebook actually doesn't know what a data frame
is.
But why is that.
If we go up here we can very very clearly see that we're importing the data frame from pandas.
The reason we're getting this error is because we've modifying the cell but we actually have not run
this cell yet.
In other words we have to select this cell run the cell and it's at this point that our notebook knows
about the data frame.
So if you come down here to where we're creating our X and our y and run the cell again this arrow will
disappear the code will now execute successfully.
So now that we've successfully separated out our data let's visualize it and for that we need some functionality
from another module that module is called Matt plant lip.
Matt Gottlieb has a whole bunch of graphing and plotting functionality and this is the module that will
help us create our chance.
So let's import Matt plotted into our notebook going to the very top where we've got all our import
statements nicely organized.
Let's add another one.
Let's say import Matt plot lit.
Now the specific plotting functionality that we actually need is only a small part of that plot loop
and this plotting functionality is called Pi plot.
So if we input map plot lib dot pi plot and hit shift enter on our keyboard to execute the cell then
we can start creating our chance coming down to the bottom of our notebook in a new cell.
We can now create our first chart let's create a scatter plot so let's get a hold of matte plot lib
dot pie plot dot scatter open parentheses x comma Why.
What this line of code will do is it will create our scatter plot for us to show our chart in our notebook
we actually have to tell Matt plotted to show our plot and we can do this with Matt plot lib dot pie
plot don't show and then parentheses at the end lets it shift enter and see what this looks like after
our cell executes we should see something like this.
Now I want to do a couple of things.
First off I want to simplify our code.
And second I want to Pretty Fly hour chart so that it becomes a lot more informative.
The problem with the code is that it's a little bit long.
If you go online and you take a look at some of the documentation you rarely see code written like this.
What people do is they shorten this bit of the code.
So what we can do is we can go to our import statements at the very top and we can create something
called an alias for our PI plot and we can do this by simply writing as BLT and this as keyword gives
our PI plot this short name.
So we're importing matte plot lives pi plot as BLT and this means we can come down here and instead
of writing all of this and then scatter we just write PDT dot scatter and here we just write PDT don't
show and just to prove that this works.
I'm going to have to execute this select first because I've made some changes here and then I can come
down here and execute this cell and what we should see is the same result as before.
So what can we do to make this chart a lot more informative.
Well we can add a title to it or we can add labels to the axes to make it a lot more clear what's going
on.
To do that we can adopt a very very similar approach to what we did up here.
We had a we had some sort of object.
Then we put a dot after it and then we told it to do something up here where we're using our data object
but with our chant We're going to use BLT.
So to add a title to our chant we simply write PDT the title and then in the parentheses we provide
the title.
So I'm going to call this charge film cost versus global revenue and when I hit shift enter to refresh
the charts then the title will appear just above.
And similarly we can add labels to the so with Piel T dot ex label we can add production budget in dollars
to the x axis and with Peele teed up y label we can add worldwide gross to the y axis.
Brilliant.
Now what else can we do.
Well first let's make our chart larger.
So if I come up here and I write peel dot figure I can change the size of our chart and I can do that
by setting the figures finger size with Fig size as equal to and then parentheses and I can supply a
within a height here.
So I'm gonna go with ten by six.
And if I had shift enter then my chart will update and become much larger than before.
And at this point what's becoming very clear is that our y axis and our x axis are actually going below
zero.
So there's some space here to plot anything that is a negative number.
But if we look up here we can actually see that for both our production budgets and our revenue.
We don't go anywhere near zero.
So what we can do for our chart is we can set a range for what should be displayed on the x axis and
the y axis to customize our chart.
In this way we would write PDT dot y Lim.
And then in the parentheses we set a minimum at a maximum value.
So for a Y I think we can go between 0 and 3 billion just so that we capture this data point up here
in the top right corner.
So I'll add peeled T dot y limb and then in the parentheses zero comma three and then billion billion
has nine zeros I believe.
So one two three six seven eight nine.
Lets it shift enter on the cell and refresh that chart.
And let's take a look at our changes.
Now that empty space below has disappeared.
So let's do the same thing for the x axis.
And actually when I leave that over to you as a challenge see if you can figure out how to add some
code to the cell to set the limit on the x axis to have a minimum value of zero but a maximum value
of four hundred and fifty million.
That way when you refresh you should get rid of this whitespace here and we should see our chart much
more clearly.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video before I show you the solution ready.
Here we go.
It's very similar to what we did with our y axis.
In this case we have to modify one thing in our code instead of Willam.
We're gonna go for X limb and instead of three billion we're gonna go for 450 million which is 450 followed
by six zeros.
If I hit shift central myself then I should see my chart update like so.
But we can actually improve the styling a little bit further.
One thing we can do for example is we can add transparency to our dots here so we can go to our scatter
plot and similar to what we did here with setting the figure size for the figure.
So the overall size of the chart we can actually set the transparency for the dots in the scatter plot
and we can do that by putting a comma after the Y and setting something called the alpha value.
So by setting Alpha equal to zero point three and hitting shift enter then we'll see that our dots have
become a lot more transparent and this will give us a good appreciation for the number of data points
that we have in certain areas of the chart.
So down here we have loads and loads of movies and loads of data points and as we go to the top right
there's fewer and fewer films.
So where are we at now at this point.
We've done some excellent work visualizing our data and this has helped us spot some of the clear outliers
in the film world.
For example this film right here has had an enormous production cost and also made a lot of money.
This movie is called Avatar by the way.
If you're wondering and looking at this chart you can see just how out of the ordinary this film was
relative to other movies.
But there are also some films that have made very very little money but cost a fortune.
And these films are down here.
That said what's very clear from this chart is that most films are actually smaller productions less
than say 1 million.
And we can see that from this very dense cloud of data points and the lower left hand corner.
Looking at this chart we can also start to understand more about the relationship or the potential relationship
between movie budgets and movie revenue because there indeed seems to be some sort of upward trend that's
visible in the chart and higher budget films do indeed appear to have higher revenue.
But how much higher exactly but how much higher exactly and how strong is the relationship.
To answer these questions we will need to turn to our linear regression our linear regression can help
us quantify this relationship.
But before we do that in the next lesson let's save our work.
We've written quite a lot of code and it would be a shame to lose it.
And I can tell you one thing trying Jupiter online is prone to get you disconnected if you leave it
alone for too long.
So go to file and then go to download as Jupiter notebook.
And this is the DOT IP why and b extension that way if you do get disconnected your work is saved and
you can come back here to upload your Jupiter book if need to continue where you left off.
I'll see you in the next lesson.