Welcome back.
Having just completed some very beautiful visualizations let's get back to pre processing our data for
our base classifier.
Now there's lots of individual words among the five thousand eight hundred odd emails that constitute
our dataset.
We won't actually use every single word that came up in these email bodies.
We're just going to use to two thousand five hundred most frequent words and when add a markdown cell
here to commemorate this and it's going to read generate vocabulary and dictionary the two thousand
five hundred most frequent words in our dataset are going to form our vocabulary and we will generate
this vocabulary from our stemmed list of words to get our STEM list of words we're once again going
to call our clean message no h t a malfunction that we've created earlier.
Now I know that for the word cloud we commented out this line.
So if you have this commented out commented packin because we actually do understand the words this
time around and if you made this change make sure that you do two things.
If you comment this line back in make sure you comment this one back out and also press shift enter
on this cell.
Otherwise you're going to get some very unexpected results later on.
All right.
So let's use our apply method and call this function right here.
Create a variable called stemmed underscore nested on the score list set that equal to data dot message
dot apply and then I'll feed in the name of our function clean on a core message underscore no underscore
HMO.
Because this is a nested list I'm going to flatten this list and store it under flat stemmed list and
set that equal to the result of some Python list comprehension.
Item 4 sub list in stemmed nested list for item in sub list.
So far nothing new.
Let's run the cell and move on the next step.
We'll be getting a unique set of words.
This is gonna make up our vocabulary.
The easiest way to do this I think is to generate a penned a series and then use the values Kant's method.
Once again you can ignore this warning here.
This is aimed at people who are trying to use beautiful soup to open a URL now to create that series
of unique words.
I'll create a variable really quickly that that's called unique words and set that equal to PD dot series
parentheses provide the flat stemmed list that we created a minute ago and then I'm going to call a
method by the name of value and a score counts.
Let me show you what we've just done here.
The number of unique words I can print out using the shape of my variable so I'll see number of unique
words is going to be in a print statement that a comma and I'll say unique words dot shape square brackets
zero.
This will print out the number of unique words in this series and to look at the first five rows the
first five entries in the series.
I'll see unique words dot head.
See what we get and what we see here is that after cleaning and stemming we are left with twenty seven
thousand three hundred and twenty words in our dataset twenty seven thousand unique words across all
our email bodies.
Now this is an absolutely huge number and we're actually only going to train our classifier with a subset
of this number namely to two thousand five hundred most frequent words you might be wondering why HP
is up here.
Well HDP pretty much precedes every single year l.
So this goes to show how many hyperlinks people have included in their emails and how to get the two
thousand five hundred most frequent words I wanna throw this over to you as a challenge.
And the reason is this is another good opportunity to practice sub setting and working with these series.
Can you create a subset of this unique world series and store it in a variable called frequent underscore
words which will only contain the most frequent two thousand five hundred words out of the total.
And then afterwards print out the top 10 words.
These of course are going to overlap with the top five words that you see above.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give this a go.
Here's the solution.
Frequent underscore words is equal to unique words and then we use that square bracket notation zero
to two thousand five hundred.
That's how we create a subset and to print out the top 10.
We'll say print most common words and then I'm even going to use a skip character and a new line comma
frequent words.
And once again when I create a subset this time from the beginning so I'm even gonna leave out the zero
to 10.
These are the top 10 words and here they are.
With this notation when you're creating a subset you're setting a starting point and an ending point.
And with this notation of creating a subset you're going from the beginning to an end point.
So I hope this was a useful review.
One thing that we can do to improve our code though is removing some of these magic numbers that we
see here.
So what I like is instead of having two thousand five hundred float around in my code here I'd like
to define a constant.
At the very top called vocab under school size and set that equal to the size of the vocabulary that
I'm gonna use in my code later on that way if I ever want to make a change all I have to do is change
this number here and it will filter through as long as I replace this number here with my constant vocab
under school size.
Now you've got to remember if you've changed a cell up top get a press shift enter.
Otherwise you're gonna get an error.
Now with frequent words we're working with a series right.
So type parentheses frequent words we can see that we have a panda's series and not only that if we
look at frequent words we see that this bit here the actual words form our index and the number of occurrences
are actually the values in this series.
Let's practice how we would go between a series and a data frame and how to work with these indices.
We're also going to take this opportunity to assign a word I.D. to each word similar to how we assigned
a dark I.D. in an earlier lesson body markdowns sell here real quick that's gonna read create vocabulary
data frame with a word on a school I.D. Now our word I.D. is just gonna be integers that gonna be ranging
from zero to two thousand four hundred and ninety nine meaning we're gonna work again with this range
object and we can create a range very easily with range parentheses zero comma and then going up to
our vocab size right.
This is how we create our range and how we can do is store all these numbers in a list.
So I'll wrap this call to the range into a list and I'm actually gonna store this in a variable called
word I.D..
So where do these is equal to list parentheses range parentheses zero comma vocab size and then closing
the parentheses.
Now let's create our data frame with PD dot data frame open parentheses and then what I want to do is
I want to provide a dictionary so I'll have those two curly braces our dictionary is gonna consist of
a key and a value.
So the key will be whatever I want that column heading to read vocab underscore a word.
Sounds good to me.
Now the values I want those to be the actual words scrolling up a little bit.
The words are here in our series.
So this means that if I use frequent words like so I'm actually accessing the frequencies the numbers
what I need to do to get the words is work with our index right.
So index dot values will be the way I can store all these different strengths in a column for our data
frame.
So far so good.
Let's see what we've got.
Let me hit shift enter on the cell at the moment our data frame looks like this fair enough.
Let's add our word I.D. explicitly to the state of frame so we can do that with setting the data frames
Index.
Right.
So index is equal to word I.D. and then we can also give that index a name.
But first let me give our data frame a name as well so say vocab is equal to PD dot data frame and on
the line below.
I'll say vocab dot index dot name is equal to single quotes word on a score I d let's look at the first
five rows in our data frame with vocab dot head and then shift into.
There we go.
Fantastic.
We've generated our vocabulary that we're going to train our classifier with and previously we've had
a pending state of frame and we've used this to Jason functionality to save a file in the Jason format
to our disk.
Now to Jason it's very well and good but of course printers can save many different file types.
A common one that you're gonna be working with a lot is a CSP file a comma separated value.
This is a file format that can easily be opened and nicely formatted with Microsoft Excel or google
sheets.
Now you probably already surmised that you're going to need a file path for this to CSC function that
we're gonna call.
So let's go back up to constants and create a concept that will hold on to our file path and our file
name for this CSP file that we're gonna create a copy.
This constant right here pasted below.
And then make a few changes to it of course.
So I'll call this one in all caps would on a school I.D. on a score file and we're still gonna save
it in our processing folder but we're going to call it would hyphen by hyphen I.D. and then add the
don't C S the extension to it.
So that's our file path and I'd shift into to make sure this is saved and then down here gonna add a
quick section heading it's gonna read save the vocabulary as a CSA file as you can guess will access
R to CSB method from our vocab object so vocab dot to underscore CSP parentheses and then we're gonna
pass in r word I.D. file path and name.
Now if I hit shift tab on this I can see some of these other parameters that I can specify and that
includes a header and an index.
Now what does this mean coming down here.
I can see that our header can be a list of strings and our index label can also be a string by default.
No index label is provided.
So let's provide these two additional inputs to our two CSB method call so that a comma here and the
first thing I'll do is provide the index label.
Now I can provide it as a string with single quotes and c word on the score I.D. but what I could also
do is instead of typing this out and risk making a typo.
If I want to make sure it matches what I've got in my data frame I can access this directly with vocab
dot index dot name and for our header it's actually the very same thing.
I could either write single quotes vocab on the school word which is our header right here but alternatively
I can also grab our column.
So with vocab dot vocab underscore a word.
Don't name this will accomplish the very very same thing.
Now I'm not gonna hit shifting around this right now.
What I want to do instead is bring up my folder here on the right hand side and then hit shift enter
so you can see the file appearing.
Here you go.
There it is.
Now you can open this in a text editor say like atom and the CSB file will be formatted something like
this.
It's not a particularly impressive.
But if you have a spreadsheet program like Microsoft Excel or google sheets or in my case this uh numbers
program that comes with Mac then you'll see the values formatted nicely in these columns.
So as you can see the CRC format is very very handy.
Now we're covering quite a lot of stuff in these lessons and with programming.
The best way of learning it is by doing it.
So the next two lessons will consist of some very quick exercises to review some of the concepts that
we've talked about.
I'm off to grab some more coffee and then I'll see you there.