Okay ready.
Hope you had a go at doing all this.
Here's the solution let's very quickly just recap where we are in terms of the data that we're working
with X on a school test thought ahead we'll show us the first five rows of our feature matrix the first
five rows of our target values y underscore test look like this so you've got document four thousand
six hundred seventy five as the very first row in both X and a school test don't shape we'll chose the
size of our data frame that we're working with this is gonna be much smaller than X underscore train
and as such the function call that we're gonna make to a make underscores sparse underscore matrix function
will take a lot less time to run let's check it out.
Percent percent time will benchmark this for us and I want to call a variable sparse on this court test
underscored D F to hold on to result from our function call so sparse on school test as IDF equals make
and score sparse on the score matrix parentheses x on a school test comma would index would an X is
the same for both our training data and our test data and then comma third argument y on a school test
let's run this and see what we get.
Scroll down a bit add a few rows in the meantime there you go.
Now we play the waiting game.
I could try and yodel for you to help pass the time but think of us would enjoy that very much.
Oh man come on come on.
These are the times when you start feeling a bit of the pain of working on a 4 year old laptop but my
patients has paid off two minutes 45 seconds to complete this calculation.
Let's take a look at how many rows we've got here.
Sparse on this contest on what the f dots shape reveals to us that we've got about one hundred and ninety
thousand individual rows.
We create another variable called test on a school grouped and set that equal to sparse on the score
test on the score DLF dot group by parentheses square brackets and I've got to have those column names
right.
The first one was on a school I.D..
The second one was word on the school I.D. everything's case sensitive of course and spelling really
matters which makes this extra difficult for me.
Third one is label.
All of these are in a list and at the end will sum it up and I'm going to chain reset on a school index
straight onto this finally when I look at the first five rows test on the school groups dot head give
me the following.
As you can see it summed up the occurrence of word number 19 in email number eight quite nicely tests
on the score grouped don't shape will also show me the has five euros only one hundred and ten thousand
as opposed to one hundred and ninety thousand to save this as a text file will use number again and
p dot save t x t parentheses and now we supply that constant we created test data file test Moscow grouped
format F T equals single quotes percent D.
I move my browser over a little bit keep that finder window in view hit shift enter and there it is
there's my test hyphen data dot text file if I open it in item then I can see that the first five rows
that we print out in Jupiter here and are showing as an output mirror what we see in the text file exactly
the document that is the first column where that is the second one label is this third occurrence is
the fourth column.