In this lesson we will convert our model our tensor flow model to tensor flow.
Yes.
And in the process we're going to learn how to set up a separate Python environment and also switch
between development environments.
Now we're gonna do that well regular tensor flow models can't run in the browser.
For that our models need to be in the tensor flow J.S. format and this means that we have to convert
our saved model and its PDB files and its variable files into a different format.
The tensor flow J.S. format.
So how we're gonna do that.
Well as always our first stop is going to be the official documentation.
So if I check out tensor flows website here under a model conversion I can see quite a lengthy and descriptive
article.
And as you can see here there are different instructions depending on your starting point.
So there's a slightly different way to go about it.
If you have a saved model versus if you have a Caris model.
This is if you have a tensor flow hub model and because we're working with the saved model we're going
to be making use of this tensor flow J.S. converter and this tensor flow JS converter lives on this
getup repo right here and there's some instructions below but I'm think there is slightly complicated.
So when I walk you through them the thing is and I'm going to say this upfront it can be a little bit
tricky to get this to work.
It certainly was for me and the reason is is that there are a lot of moving parts that all have to play
nice with each other the kind of moving parts I'm talking about are tensor flow tensor flow yes Charisse
and python.
All of these have specific versions that the converter cares about and all of these different parts.
Update periodically but not at the same time.
So I actually had a little bit of trouble getting this to work at first because I ran into some incompatibilities
between the different versions of python and the converter and the converter and versions of Karras
and some other things.
So this was actually a little bit difficult to troubleshoot.
So as a little bit of a backup I'm going to add my output files under the lesson resources so if you
run into any problems and you're having difficulty troubleshooting it you have those available and can
continue on with the module so the question at this point is what's the solution.
How do we get all these components and all the versioning to play nice with each other and to work.
How do we lock down all the versions in a controlled way.
And the answer to this problem is we need a separate environment.
We need a special environment just for the tensor flow GSK converter.
In other words the 10th floor JS converter will use its own version of Python.
It's gonna use a very particular version of Caris and it's gonna use particular versions of all the
other dependencies including its own version of tensor flow Jesus and all these versions may not be
the latest versions but they're the ones that are gonna work.
So how do we set up the separate environment.
The good news is is that Anaconda makes this really really easy for us.
It makes it really easy to set up separate Python environments in parallel and allowing you to switch
in between them.
If you look at the documentation right here we get a little bit of a description of how to go about
it.
Here we can see how we can go about creating an environment.
And here we see how to activate and deactivate an environment all of these instructions pertain to the
terminal or the windows command prompt.
They're all we have to do is type in something like this kinda create which is the command.
Then we provide the environment name that we want to create and then we provide a python version.
So in our case we're gonna write kinda create hyphen and converter underscore environment and then Python
equals three point six.
Now you can actually do this in the anaconda Navigator as well if you prefer using agree as opposed
to the terminal or the command prompt if you fire up the anaconda navigator and you click on environments
right here.
Then what you can see is you can simply click on this button here.
What's this create then you can provide a name converter underscore environment and then you can select
the python version right here and we're gonna be using three point six.
Now at this point you can either click Create or if you want to follow along with me you can do it in
the terminal on Windows.
You'd be using the anaconda prompt which looks like this.
Here you simply type kinda create hyphen n and then you provide the name of the environment you want
to create converter underscore and space python is equal to three point six so I've got my line wrapping
around him but it's all a single line that looks something like this.
Make sure you don't have any typos and you're indeed using python version three point six.
That's quite important.
So hitting enter here.
You can actually see that it's working in the background.
And as it's doing this it's asking us whether or not we want to proceed.
So type Y and hit enter and then you can keep an eye on the anaconda navigator even if you've got it
open and you should actually see it working and creating that second environment.
Brilliant.
So now that you've set up this environment.
How do you activate it.
How do you get into it and how do you get out of it.
The terminal actually shows us the instructions right here.
So I can even copy this pasted in or just type it and kinda activate and then the name of the environment.
And if you hit enter then you should see a change in your prompt instead of reading base in the beginning.
You should see it read converter underscore environment at this point.
Anything you type here will be a command.
That's specific to this particular environment that you set up and took it out of it.
You simply type Conda deactivate just like it says in the instruction above.
And when you do that the command prompt changes back to base now that we've got our environment setup
we're ready to take the next step.
Now there's one little thing that all the windows users have to do first though and that thing is changing
the maximum character limit for our path.
And that's a special extra step for everybody using Windows because by default you've got a 260 character
limit on the path to a particular file.
So that's that piece of text at the very top in your folder that reads C colon slash users slash your
username slash whatever sub folders you've got.
And then the file name at the end.
So by default Windows for historical reasons has had a limit on how many characters there can be in
total here.
And because this 260 character limit will give us a little bit of a problem when we're installing tensor
flow.
Yes we have to lift this limit beforehand and for that we have to go into the Windows Registry Editor.
And the way you would do this on Windows is you simply search for the Registry Editor by typing Reg
edit into the search ball.
And when you click on it you give permission to make changes and then you should see your Windows Registry
pop up at this point.
You have to navigate to a particular place in the registry.
So go to each key local machine then go to system then go to current controls set expand the folder
that reads control and then scroll down a bit until you see filesystem
and inside file system you should see an entry that reads long paths enabled.
So at the very top of the Registry Editor you should see what I have right here.
Each key local machine system current controls set control and then file system double click on long
paths enabled.
And if you've still got the limit in place on two hundred sixty characters then you should see a zero
there.
And what you need to do at this point is you need to change that zero to a one then click OK and then
simply restart your computer.
That way.
The changes will take effect all right.
So now that we've set up our converter environment and we've lifted the 260 character limit.
If you're on Windows the next step is installing tensor flow.
J.S. and the we we're gonna do this is first we're going to activate the converter environment that
we've just set up and so we should see our prompt change and we should see the converter environment
reflected in the beginning of the prompt and then we're going to install tensor flow Jesus and the way
this is gonna work is we're going to issue a command called pip install followed by the package name
and then the version of tensor flow Jesus that we're looking to install.
So Pip stands for Pip install packages.
And yes the abbreviation has the word Pip again.
So there there's some more python in jokes for you but the command that we're going to type into the
terminal or into the kind prompt if you're in windows is Pip install tensor flow G as W equals.
And then we're gonna go for a very particular version which I know works and that's version 1.0.
Two point three.
So here's how it's going to look pip install tensor flow G.S. W equals one point two point three.
So there's some line wrapping happening here but this is all one line one command.
If it enter it's gonna take a little while for tens of low just to be installed.
So there's gonna be some downloads happening and the way you know that it's finished is that you should
see your prompt appear again.
So if you see this blinking cursor in front of your name then you know it's done now.
The next step is actually running the tensor flow J.S. converter because now you've got tense flow.
Yes right.
So how do we do that.
The detailed instructions of course are on the Github page for the tensor flow gas converter and scrolling
down we see that for a saved model.
This is an example.
Now how does this actually translate for us.
Now even though these instructions are not bad it's even simpler for us actually.
So the only thing that we have to type into the anaconda prompt or into the terminal is tense offload
J.S. underscore converter which is the command and then we have to supply a couple of inputs.
The first one is what the format is that we're going to be converting from.
And that's a 10 serve flow saved model T F underscore saved on a screen model.
The next thing that we have to provide is the output format that we're looking for.
And this is a tensor flow J.S. graph model.
Again the spelling has very important and you're going to have to spell everything exactly as you see
here for this to work.
Now you have to supply two more things.
The first is where to find the saved model files.
So these are the PDB files that we generated from Jupiter.
And the next thing is where the output files should be stored.
So this is the folder where the Converter will put the output files and that's it.
Actually it's gonna be a little bit of typing but it's actually just these four things.
All right.
So how's this actually gonna work in practice.
Well let me show you in the terminal it's gonna be tensor flow J.S. underscore converter.
So that's the command.
And then it's gonna be two hyphens with input underscore format equal to T F underscore saved underscore
model then our second input that we're gonna provide is the output on a score format and that's gonna
be equal to TFG s underscore graph on the score model.
Now before you continue on just double check the spelling here.
Make sure you've got no typos in this incantation.
Otherwise we're going to have a problem.
So everything's lowercase.
You've got the underscores where they need to be.
You've got double hyphens where they need to be.
And if you've got some line wrapping Don't worry about it.
So once you're happy with that you can provide the third input.
And that's where those saved model files are saved.
Now all you need to do is drag and drop the directory in to your command prompt and so you can just
drag and drop it in and you'll get the full path of where to find that file and your variable files
and so on.
So that's the third input and the fourth input is where you want the converter to spit out its results.
And so in this case I recommend creating a new folder in your projects folder and you can call this
folder anything you like but I'm gonna go for TFG yes.
And I want to take that folder and I'm going to drag and drop it into the command prompt again to get
the full path to this folder.
And once you're happy with that you can actually run the converter and let's see what happens.
The converter actually doesn't take very much time to run and once it's done and you should see no error
messages at this point you should see this TFG s folder that you've just created populated with two
files the first file is gonna read something like group one short one of one.
And the second file is gonna be your model.
Don't Jason.
Now again if you had any problems any errors.
I'm actually gonna add these two files under the lesson resources so that you can download them in case
you get stuck and you don't have to spend a just troubleshooting the tensor flow just convert them but
I hope this worked for you.
And if you're wondering what this is then you've got on one hand the actual graph and you can see this
beautifully.
If you open it in something like the Firefox browser which formats this Jason File very very nicely
and then this other file here you've got the actual weights of your neural network.
So here's your model.
And these are gonna be your weights.
Now these are gonna be much harder to inspect because this is a binary you're not actually gonna be
able to open this in a program and make sense of it.
So there you go.
Congratulations on successfully converting a tense flow model to a tense flow J.
S model in the next lesson.
We're gonna be starting to look at the Web site that we're gonna build we're going to look at these.
The project I'm going to start learning about h Tim L and CSX.
I'll see you there.