Ha right.
So if you haven't fired up to put a notebook in a while then open your Anaconda command line.
If you're in Windows or go to terminal if you're on Mac and then type in the command Jupiter notebook
and hit enter your browser should fire up and drop you off on local host with your folders here.
You want to navigate to the email projects folder that you've set up earlier and there you want to create
a new Python 3 notebook
hand.
We're gonna click up here what says Untitled.
I'm gonna rename it to 0 3.
Great.
Oh man I can't type gradient the scent.
We're gonna hit rename and now we're ready to go for our first cell in our new notebook.
We're not gonna be typing any python code.
Instead we're going to be making our notebook a little bit more pretty a little bit more readable by
inserting a heading.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to cell and then change the cell type from code to markdown
so select markdown here and you'll notice that the AI in here has disappeared because this cell will
now no longer be evaluated as code.
So we said we're gonna make a title.
Our first title is gonna be notebook imports and packages.
Yeah and when he'd shift into sin how we can see here this is just plain text and in the cell below
we're gonna be adding our import statements.
So the first thing that we're gonna import is our old friend Matt plot lip pie plot where we're doing
some plotting in this notebook.
So when I write import Matt plot lib dot pi plot as party when I stick with the same naming convention
here.
And we're also going to import another library another package called num Pi.
And this is commonly referred to as an P.
So a lot of people use end p and we'll use that as well.
So when it import num pi adds N P and we're also going to add the good ole Jupiter notebook statement
percentage sign.
Matt.
Plot lib in line.
So when doing some plotting so we're gonna add this Matt plot lib in line statements so that we can
export our plots very very nicely and head shift enter now and before we go on I want to revert back
to this markdown up here.
I'd really like to have a section heading and let me show you how we can get that because notebook inputs
and packages is very very small.
If we put a hashtag in front of this and head space then immediately the font becomes a lot bigger bolder
and blue and this is because this hashtag is telling Jupiter that now notebook inputs and packages should
be considered as a heading that's not actually gonna look like this when I hit shift enter it's going
to look like this it's gonna be big and bold.
So this is a very nice way to create section headings in your notebook.
Now if you wanted this a little smaller and one level down in the size and boldness then you can put
two hashtags and you can see how the markdown adjusts really nicely and will look like this in contrast.
Right.
And you can even try three.
So there's different levels of boldness and size that you can you can play with for your section headings
to keep your notebook organized.
So I go with one and this way we can find our imports very quickly.
Now we're gonna dive straight into our first example.
Now the thing I want to do though is I'm going to take this cell here and I'm going to modify it to
be a markdown cell as well.
So this is my chance to share a little bit about what Jupiter notebook can do someone say example one
example one and the example one is going to be about a very very very simple cost function and the cost
function is going to look like this.
It's going to be f of x is equal to X squared plus X plus 1.
Let's see what this markdown would actually look like.
Would look something like this but um the cool thing about markdown is that you can actually make the
mathematical notation look a lot better.
So you can add a dollar sign in the front and you can add a dollar sign in the back.
And if I press shift enter now then you can see that indeed we have this formatting here in the markdown
cell looking like an actual equation.
So this is gonna be Example 1.
Going to look like this.
I can make this bigger as well so I can give it a section heading if you will.
And now it's going to look like this so this is gonna be a simple cost function.
All right.
Here we go.
How.
If this is the first time that you're seeing this then you might be confused about what are these dollar
symbols right.
Well this is a markup notation from a system called late tech and late tech uses tags like these dollar
signs to mark a particular section as a mathematical notation if I hire if I double up on the dollar
signs then I'm giving it a different kind of tag.
And you can see that you'll have a different formatting as well.
So in this case it's centered so single dollar sign is in line.
And the other tag the double dollar sign is for display.
So we're gonna be using a late tech a little more in this module hand.
You might actually see this in in many many other places as well it's it's super popular for writing
mathematical equations or scientific papers especially in an academia.
The best analogy that I can think of of how low tech works is that it works really similar to X AML
or HD.
So if you were to go to a Web site like say example dot com and you right click on it and you go to
view page source then you'll see the HMO documents.
So while the website will look like this example.
Domain is actually surrounded by two HD tags title and title.
So a beginning tag and an end tag and late tech sort of works a bit like this as well.
You've got a markup meaning these tags that kind of give structure to your document.
So it's through these tags that the Jupiter notebook knows how to format a particular section of text
in the in the markup cells that we've added the the markup and our section heading.
We can now actually you know write the python code for this function and it would look like this D def
space f parentheses x semicolon New Line return x double multiplication sign for the power.
So times times to plus X plus one.
And that's our function.
Right.
This is our function in Python code.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to generate the data.
Now just add a little comment and here make data and the way we're going to do this is by using num
pi.
So our data is going to sit in a variable I'm going to call it X underscore one call underscore one
because this is our first example so X and on the score one is gonna be equal to something and it's
gonna get its value from a num pi function num PI was NDP and the function we're gonna call is Lynn
space.
Yeah.
And Pete Lynn space parentheses start it's going to equal minus three comma stop it's gonna equal three
and then and u m num is gonna equal say one hundred mid shift into and explain who what I did just there.
So the uh Lin space function is something that comes from the NUM pi library I'm going to pull up the
documentation for you guys and I've got a couple of arguments that I gave it I gave it a start value
a stop value and a value for this third one called num now Lin space creates a sequence yeah a sequence
of numbers that creates our data for us and it creates a sequence of numbers between the start value
and the stop value and the number of samples is set by that third parameter so that third value at the
end you add value back in our Python notebook we can actually take a look at what this would look like
so if I put X underscore one here and it shift into then we can see what it is that we've actually got
back we've got back an array that starts at negative three and goes to three and has a hundred individual
data points.
One hundred individual values that are spaced out equally between minus three and three.
If this you know was I don't know the number 10 instead of 100 then I'd get an array with much fewer
values right.
Just one two three four five six seven eight nine 10.
Right.
So you can see this little space function here is very very handy for generating data.
And one of the things I quite like doing is actually adding the names for the arguments.
When I make a call to my function because I just find it's so much more readable than having it like
minus three three and 10.
Right.
That's that's that's much much harder to read especially when you're coming back to it and you might
not remember it so well.
So X on a score one is an array with approximately 100 values.
We can even give it more room and give it like say five hundred.
Right.
Go ahead shift into.
And that's us having made our data now that we've got our data.
Let's plot it right.
Let's graph it using our function so we can add the plot by using our map plot lib PDT so we can actually
do this in one line.
Right.
We can say Pulte dot plot and then parentheses x underscore one comma and then what.
F of effects no f of x underscore one we're going to feed the actual data that we have in x1 into our
function here and we have plot f of x as the sort of this is our y right.
And X and it's co 1 this is r x.
So now it's called peel T dot show parentheses at the end.
See what happens.
And here it is.
This is what our function actually looks like a parabola I actually sent to this a little bit as well
so I'm going to set the axes by writing P.L. T dot X Lim parentheses and I must give it a range of minus
three.
Uh two I don't know three.
Right.
This is what we generated our data from right from minus three two three and the y axis.
We can set with P.L. T dot y Lim parentheses zero comma I don't know C from zero to eight.
See what we get.
This is starting to look a little bit better.
I'm going out to labels as well with PDT dot X label parentheses and then the string X a font size of
16 headed for the y axis.
We're gonna just write F of X so t dot y label parentheses and then I'm going to give it the string
F of X comma font size my typing font size is also equal to 16.
There we go.
All right so that's the plot of our function.
That's pretty good right.
So we've got a cost function.
An example of one X squared plus X plus one.
And the way we've kind of broken this down is we've created a function of python function right.
Also called it f of x less confusing.
We've created some data and the reason we had to do this was so that we could generate a nice graph
right.
So Exodus go 1 one used num PIs Lynn space and then we've just used map plot lib again to graph our
data here in the next lesson.
We're gonna set the stage for minimizing our cost of f effects is our cost.
Then the lowest cost will be at the bottom of this graph.
Right.
So it'll be somewhere around here.
All we have to do now is find out what's the lowest cost and for what value of X is our cost.
The lowest.