Now that we've discussed a final step on how our need based classifier makes decisions we should talk
about where the probabilities that feed into this decision making actually come from.
And this means backing up a bit and talking about statistics how this is the part that no one gets excited
about.
I've yet to hear somebody say yes statistics.
My favorite topic but the thing is statistics is everything in machine learning and this project will
give us a chance to get some exposure.
All right.
So we're interested in calculating the probability that an email is spam.
However it's not like we can simply work out the probability the same way we would work out the probability
of safe flipping heads on a coin flip or rolling a six with a die with coins and dice working out the
probabilities is fairly straightforward.
But let's review some of these concepts nonetheless because they're gonna come in handy later.
How with coins we know that there's two sides and a flip has a 50/50 chance of showing heads with this
dice here.
We know that there are six sides and we've got a one in six or roughly 17 percent chance of rolling
a six or any particular number.
Now let me ask you a question outside of the realm of flipping coins and rolling dice.
How would you work out your probability of getting hit by lightning.
Yeah I know you could probably ask Google and get the answer but if you had to calculate it yourself
how would you do it well.
The simplest way to do this is by dividing two numbers the total number of times people get hit by lightning
and the total number of lightning strikes.
Now I trawled through the key PDA for you and I've dug out these figures about 240000 people are injured
by lightning every year.
Now at 24000 actually sounds like quite a lot of people but there are an order of magnitude more lightning
strikes every year around 350 million lightning bolts actually strike the ground.
So then just given these two numbers what's the chance of your AI being hurt by lightning.
Well it'll be 240000 divided by 350 million or zero point zero seven percent.
The point I'm trying to get across here is how to use basic probability.
We took some observations like the number of times a lightning struck a person and the total number
of times we observed lightning in a year.
To calculate this figure.
Now suppose we had to work out the chance of an email being spam.
Any email that is right any email in the whole world we can apply the same technique as in the lightning
example the chance of an email being spam should also depend on two things namely one how many spam
emails were sent and 2 how many emails were sent and total with these two quantities in hand.
We can work it out so trawled the internet and here's what I pulled up in 2017.
There were an estimated one hundred and forty eight billion spam emails sent.
That's right billion and the total number of emails being sent was approximately two hundred and sixty
nine billion.
So that means if a new email comes into your inbox the probability of that email being spam or having
pin spam in 2017 was 55 percent.
And this is simply based on the observation of the frequencies namely the total number of spam emails
divided by the total number of all email traffic.
So you can think of calculating the basic probability as step one.
We figured out the overall probability of spam but we can't build a classifier with this alone.
So what's step two.