So far we've talked about basic probability independence joint probability and conditional probability.
We're now ready to start talking about Bayes theorem.
Bayes theorem is where the naive bayes classifier gets its name.
You see a long long time ago in a 17th hundreds in Kent England there lived a clergyman by the name
of Reverend Thomas Bayes Thomas Bayes got very very interested in probability.
Later on in his life and he came up with a neat little trick let's go back to our weather example with
the conditional probability formula.
The hardest part was this joint probability term namely what is the probability of it raining and being
cloudy.
Now it turns out one can phrase the conditional probability formula in another way.
Instead of having this joint probability in the we can have another conditional probability namely given
that it is raining.
What is the probability of it being cloudy now this is different from given that it is cloudy.
What is the probability of rain.
These two are not the same.
Have you seen rain on a sunny day.
Yes but not very often right.
The probability of clouds when it is raining is probably around 95 percent.
On the other hand the probability of it raining.
Given that it is cloudy is probably more around 40 percent.
So these two numbers are as different as the conditions.
But the point I'm trying to make here is that changing the top part of this fraction in this formula
is all Bayes theorem is.
Reverend Bayes basically figured out how to reverse a conditional probability in the formula to make
this whole thing easier to calculate the conditional probability.
Looks like this.
Here's the generic formula for Bayes Theorem in terms of and b and you'll find this theorem very early
on in any statistics textbook but let's go back to our spammer example.
Given that the email has the word via granted what is the probability of this email being spam using
Bayes theorem.
We cannot calculate the same probability like this using this formula.
The calculation becomes very very easy and that's why I'm harping on about this so much.
Let's tackle one term at a time starting with the probability of spam.
We've actually already discussed this.
We figured out how common spam emails were.
This was 55 percent in 2017.
If you remember so let's plug that number in here.
Zero point five five.
Now what about the probability of the word VIAGRA coming up in an email.
To calculate this number we have to figure out how common the word Viagra is.
In emails as a whole.
How often do people use the word VIAGRA in an email.
Both spam and in normal e-mails say we've looked at an enormous dataset of emails containing 700000
words across thousands of e-mails and we count how many times Phi aggregates mentioned if the word VIAGRA
gets mentioned 75 times then the probability of Agora coming up in an email is seventy five divided
by 700000.
In this case we're just applying basic probability just like with our calculation of the probability
of getting hit by lightning would take the total number of times of aggregates mentioned and we divided
by the total number of words that we looked at in our dataset.
Next let's tackle the probability of Agora being in an email.
Given that the email is spam what does this mean.
This is a conditional probability given that the email is spam.
What is the probability that the email contains the word VIAGRA.
How would we calculate this.
Again we look at the frequency of the word VIAGRA.
But this time just within the spam emails this allows us to figure out what is the probability that
an email contains the word VIAGRA.
Given that it is spam and looking at our dataset of emails we count the number of times the word via
gra occurs and we look at the total number of words in our dataset that are in spam emails say three
hundred and seventy thousand.
If we find that the word VIAGRA appears sixty five times the conditional probability is simply sixty
five divided by three hundred and seventy thousand hand.
That's it.
We've got all our numbers.
We can work out the probability that an email is spam given that it contains the word VIAGRA.
And based on our data here the probability is around 90 percent.
What this example shows is that the frequencies of a word really are key by looking at the frequencies
of a word in a spam messages vs. all messages.
Our algorithm learns which words are spammy.
The reason we think words like online pharmacy doubled your cash etc. are spammy is because these words
often appear in spam emails.
But the story doesn't stop there.
If we look at an email message then we're going to have more than one word in the email body right.
Well that depends on your friends actually.
But my point is that we can calculate the conditional probability for every single word in the emails
in the entire dataset.
Not only will we have worked out the conditional probability of an email being spam if it contains the
word Viagra but we will have worked out the probabilities of all the other words as well like expert
free cash and so on.
So now when an email comes in what if it has both the words free and the word fag ran it.
What's the probability of an email being spam in that case let me rephrase that.
Given that the email has the word free and the word via granted what is the probability that the email
is spam at this point we've come full circle all the way back to joint probability.
Remember how with the coin flipping example we simply multiplied the probability of heads.
Times the probability of heads to figure out the chances of getting two heads in a row.
The reason we could do that was because the two events were independent.
And this brings us to the naive part of the naive bayes classifier.
The reason our algorithm is naive is because it assumes independence between the words in the email.
In other words if our email has both the words Viagra and the word free it we can multiply the two probabilities
together and we can do this for every single word in the email.
The more and more spammy the words are the higher the final number.
Now let's continue with this line of thinking.
If an email has lots and lots of spammy words in it it's probably spam.
And if an email has very very few spammy words in it it's probably a normal email.
So this brings us back to the final decision where we compare to probabilities.
Say we have an email with the words hello friend.
Want Free by aggro.
Well using Bayes rule we can calculate the conditional probabilities for all these words and figure
out what the probability is that that email is spam.
Then using that independence assumption we multiply all these probabilities together to get a final
number namely the probability that the email is spam and then we can compare this number to the probability
that this email is a normal email.
So for that first term we would have given that this email contains the word hello.
What is the probability that the email is a normal email next.
Given that this word contains the word want what is the probability that we have a normal email.
And so on.
We then multiply all these probabilities together and then we can do our comparison.
This is the classification step that we talked about in the very very beginning.
We will classify this email simply based on which final number is higher.
What I've just described to you is called the bag of words approach for classifying documents each word
is looked in isolation and the frequency of each word becomes a feature in our machine learning model
and the fact that we've looked at each word in isolation is why this model is called naive.
We're treating each word separately.
We're ignoring grammar.
We're ignoring sarcasm.
We treat the city name New York as two separate words.
New York we're treating the phrase not bad as two words not and bad.
The context is lost with the bag of words approach the dependencies between the words are ignored.
We are assuming that the words are independent like well words in a bag at this point you're probably
skeptical.
Will this really work.
This whole approach seems super strange and the assumptions also seem really crude.
Well I don't want to spoil it for you.
You will find out just how well this works.
If not coming lessons and now that we've covered the theory behind the need Bayes model our path for
the python code is clear.
The first step will involve extracting all the text from the email bodies and this means moving on to
the next parts of our project workflow.
Namely cleaning and exploring the data.
For example we will need to figure out just how common each word is.
In an email we will need to do this for every single word not a spammy words like Viagra but every word.
How often do people use the word Japan in emails.
How often do people use the word weekend Apple Android computer lawyer a friend in emails.
We will need to count how often these words appear in all the emails in our dataset and we have over
5000 different emails in this dataset that we're working with and we will store all this text inside
a panda's data frame in order to manipulate it and we're gonna do all that in the upcoming programming
lessons.
I'll see you there.
You know I vividly remember learning about probability in school and a home my textbook exercises were
constantly about urns always balls and urns red balls from an urn picking out a sequence of balls from
an urn picking out a particular ball out of an urn.
Then the memories.