All right.
So welcome back.
In this lesson we're going to start taking a look at another quirk of the gradient descent algorithm.
We're going to be taking a look at an example where our gradient descent algorithm actually diverges
and spirals more and more out of control.
And also we're gonna be working through some more hardcore Python programming concepts so when I click
in my last cell and then I'm going to go change the cell from code to markdown here when added hashtag
and see.
Example 3
divergence overflow and Python tuples the function that we're gonna be looking at in this example it's
gonna be this one it's gonna be h of x is equal to x to the power of five minus two X to the power of
four plus two forgot my closing tags in the end.
There we go.
Maybe add another cell below actually to three so that we're not at the bottom of the screen.
And then I want to generate some data has always that's gonna be my first thing.
So when I make data and since this is example 3 am when I use X underscore 3 as my variable.
And when you use MP Lynn space starting at minus 2.5 going to 2.5 and with the new M argument set to
1000.
Okay.
So now it's time to write that equation above in Python code.
It's gonna be D F H of X colon return x times times five minus two times x times times four plus two.
And then our derivative of this function is gonna be D F D of H of X colon return.
And then you've probably already worked this out by applying the power rule.
It's gonna be five times x to the power of four minus eight x to the power of three.
Okay.
So let's plot this function.
I'm gonna scroll up and I'm gonna take this cell here.
It's a copy cell and then I'm going to paste it above.
Now I'm going to have to make some changes to this code over here.
The gradient descent.
We're gonna be calling D of H.
And I'm going to say my initial guess should be equal to zero point two.
I wanna leave a lot of the other stuff as it is but I won't change my x axis and y axis on my graph.
So this graph is gonna go from minus one point two to two point five and the y axis is gonna go from
minus one to four.
So that's our cost function gonna change the Y label to read h of x.
I'm going to plot x underscore three on H of X underscore three and on the scatter plots.
I'm also going to be plotting H of X not G of X similarly for my derivative might change the label.
And on the access we're gonna go from minus one to two and then from minus four to five.
And then on the plotting going to change this 2 x 3
D.H. of x 3.
And then I'm gonna hit shift into well so we can see here on our graph we start at positive zero point
two and then our gradient descent slowly slowly slowly makes its way down into this local minimum.
Right here.
Let's modify the cell here to print out what the values actually are.
So going to see print local men cause at and it's gonna be local underscore min and then I want to print
the cost at the minimum is and then I'm going to say h of local men right.
So local men remember is the last value calculated by a gradient descent.
We're going to work out what the y value is on our chart here at this particular point.
And finally let's print out the number of steps that our algorithm has taken including the initial guess.
So that's gonna be the length alien of our variable called list underscore X how we run this.
Now I can see the output here at the bottom.
Below our charts the local minimum occurs at around one point six the cost of this minimum is about
minus zero point six two and the number of steps is one hundred and seventeen.
So our gradient descent algorithm has run over 100 times to get to this point okay.
So we're converging to this minimum here.
And so far nothing new.
We've seen all of this before but let's see what happens if instead of at zero point two we start at
negative zero point two.
Let's see what happens if we start a little bit on the other side of this chart.
So when I scroll back up and here where my initial guess is zero point two I want to change this to
minus zero point two.
And I want to rerun the cell and see what happens scrolling down we see an era.
In fact we see an overflow area where it says the result is too large.
What does that mean.
I'm going to change the initial guess back to zero point two shift enter reload the graph so we can
think about this if our initial guess was negative zero point two.
Then we would be on the left hand side of this hump and this means that the algorithm would be starting
to move down and down and down and down this line here now would continue going all the way down to
like negative infinity.
Now I know what you're thinking.
Negative infinity.
That makes H of X a very a very unrealistic cost function but it does illustrate several things.
First we can see how our gradient descent algorithm behaves when the algorithm diverges.
And second it shows us how our python program behaves when this happens.
So conceptually we've explained the problem but I do think that seeing this overflow error gives us
an opportunity for understanding something a little deeper about our Python code.
So let's run our code in slow motion if you will and examine what's actually happening and to do that.
I'm going to modify our gradient descent function so my scroll back up what we've defined our gradient
descent and in our function header I'm going to tack on another parameter this parameter is gonna be
called Max underscore it's her for Max iterations and give it a default value of say 300 and instead
of this hardcoded 500 value here in our range I'm going to substitute our argument I'm going to substitute
in Max it's her from Max iterations so this way we can specify the maximum number of times our loop
will run when we are calling our function.
So I'm going to press shift enter to update the python code now.
So when to update the cell and then down here where we're generating this graph with our third example
I'm going to change her function call as follows.
For our initial guests I am going to use minus zero point two but then I'm going to give a max iteration
value of 10 and see where this leaves us so many head shift enter.
Take a look at the graphs OK.
So in 10 iterations we're still pretty much on this hump if instead the max iterations of our loop are
set to 40 then we can see we start moving a little further down
and if I change it to say 60 I can see we're moving down even more.
Let me update this to 70 and rerun this function when we examine the chart.
Now what do we notice.
Well yes it's moving down to the left but very interesting here is that the step size gets bigger and
bigger with each step as this slope starts getting steeper and steeper and steeper.
Our steps start getting larger and larger and larger.
So what's the last x value that the algorithm calculates.
We're printing out the last x value with this print statement so we can see below our graphs are the
printouts from our three print statements.
We can see that the last x value that's printed out is negative 2 million.
That's the first print statement here.
And this is definitely not a local minimum in this case but when we feed our negative 2 million back
into our function then we can see that the cost.
Yeah.
What's on the y axis at this point.
Equal to minus three point eight times ten to the power of 31.
So in our print statement here python is giving us this number in scientific notation but it's actually
an enormous number.
It's around 3 8 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0.
It actually continues going right.
I'd have to copy this paste it three times.
This is how large this number is.
That's being printed here in scientific notation hits three point eight with a lot of zeros after it.
Yeah I mean you're going to be looking at this number and you're like well it's a computer right.
So what we sent a man to the moon over like 40 years ago surely my computer can handle calculating large
numbers right.
What's the big deal.
And you're not wrong.
We can and we should be able to do math with very large numbers.
But the thing is your computer and Python doesn't do this straight out of the box if you want to work
with numbers of this sort of magnitude.
If you're are I don't know calculating the number of atoms in the universe or what have you.
Then you have to employ a couple of tricks.
The thing is you can actually see what the maximum is that you can reach on your particular machine
at home right now in Python.
Straight out of the box and that's without importing any libraries or any modules and using python as
it is that you've got installed right now.
So if you're curious and you wanted to pull up this sort of system specific information you can actually
do so with a module called sis.
So import system.
This is the module where the system's specific information resides and there you can pull up a number
of different things to see the kind of things that I'm talking about.
You can write something like help and then put sis in there and then you'll get some documentation on
the system module so you can read this.
This is by the way very very similar to what you can pull up by pressing shift and then tab and then
hitting that little plus sign.
You'll see that this also pulls up the same documentation.
But let me show you two things that might be quite useful.
I'm going to come out the the help here.
Don't need this.
So for example one thing that you might be interested in looking up is what version of Anaconda you're
using or what version of Python.
And you can pull this up by writing sis dot version.
So version is an attribute of this system module.
So right now you can see that I'm using Python 3 and I've got a 46 bit system and you can also see that
I'm running this on a Mac.
Let me comment this out again and let's look at something else.
Let's pull up what the largest floating point numbers that I can calculate in my python program now.
Now you might ask why why I'm interested in floating point numbers why do I say floating point numbers.
Well if you have that type of the thing that we're looking up right the type of thing that we're calculating
each of.
Take a look.
In this case it's H of low Coleman.
So this is the thing that gave us the problem.
So this is a float and this is what we're looking up to largest float that we can use is this dot float
underscore info dot Max and here's our answer.
Right.
And this number that you see printed out here is specific to my machine.
If you're using a different type of machine with a different architecture say 32 bit then you may see
something else printed below the cell right now but this is my maximum floating point number that I
can use on on my architecture.
Yeah it's one point seven nine times ten to the power of 308.
Yeah.
This is huge but it's still well shy of the 10 to the power of 31 that we had just a moment ago.
Right.
It's many many orders of magnitude larger.
So you might ask why are we running into this problem.
Well looking at our chart we can see that our step size increases dramatically with each step.
And if I go up here and I change this from Max iterations the number of times I run my loop from 70
to say 71 and I look at my cost then I get minus two point one times ten to the power of one hundred
and twenty one.
So this is the crux of the problem I'm going to blow through my limit at the very next iteration on
iteration 73.
This is when I get the overflow error.
Now in your machine at home if the number that you're seeing printed here the number that span out by
thought float on underscore score in fact Max is smaller than this then you might actually get that
overflow error much sooner than I do right.
You might not get it at iteration 73.
You might actually be getting that error far earlier that overflow error.
Now one thing that you might like to know about Python lingo is that errors like this are also referred
to as exceptions but no matter if you call it an exception or an error we still crash and burn.
So so yeah I hope you enjoyed that little detail into the the low level of representation of numbers
inside your python computer program but I think that while we're on the topic of Python programming
we should revisit a piece of code that we've written in a previous lesson namely the code up here the
code for our gradient descent algorithm because I have to confess something I've been a little cheeky
in having our Python gradient descent function return multiple values without actually explaining how
this works.
And this is a good point to cover the python code.
Before we go back to actually analyzing our algorithm so let's add a new section heading at the bottom
I'm going to click this little plus sign here to insert some cells below.
And this cell here I'm going to convert from code to markdown and the section heading I'm going to give
this is Python tuples
so what's a tuple a tuple is a data structure that's very very similar to a list a tuple is just a sequence
of values that are separated by a comma.
And this is what we've used in our gradient descent function.
Let me show you how you can create a tuple quickly.
Plus again here and let's do this let's.
Let's insert a quick comment here.
Creating a tuple my first tuple is gonna be called Breakfast and it's going to contain three values
bacon eggs and avocado.
This by the way is a fantastic way to start your day.
It also illustrates the general format for tuples.
You have a sequence of values that are separated by a comma when a crit another tuple here call it unlucky
on the score.
Numbers home give it 13 four for China 9 for Japan 26 for India and 17 for Italy.
So it's the same pattern as above.
And this way of creating tuples actually has a name.
This is called tuple packing because we're packing multiple values into a single tuple.
So now that we've got our tuples how do we access them.
Well I'm going to add some print statements here like I love comma breakfast.
Square brackets zero.
Now that shift into my lack of spelling ability has foiled me once again I want to take out the superfluous
e here and then hit shift into again and then we can see that the syntax here with the square brackets
for working with tuples is actually very very similar to working with a list.
So you've got a tuple that has a name.
In this case breakfast and you're accessing the values inside the tuple through the index.
So zero is the first item in the tuple and to show you a second example.
I'm going to print out the string.
My hotel has no space and then I'm gonna have two plus signs another string at the end T.H. floor.
Now in between here I could put unlucky underscore numbers and then square brackets and say provide
the index one
and if I try to run this right now I'll get an error because the string concatenation with the pluses
does not convert the integers here to strings so I have to actually wrap this in a function called SDR
and only now can I press shift enter and run this if I try to do this without wrapping it then we'll
get an error like this must be string not INT.
And that's because my tuple here contains ints and those are not converted to strings by the plus operator.
So when I wrap this in a string function and press enter.
So we've covered how to how to access a value in a tuple brilliant and how we can try something else.
Because I'm sure you're looking at this and you're saying well how are tuples different from lists.
How how are tuples used.
Why why do we have something that's so similar and yet different.
Well in contrast to lists tuples are often used when the data they contain is heterogeneous.
Now what I mean by that tuples often contain a mix of data and contrast to lists.
So lists often contain the same kind of data like all strings all integers but tuple like C not on the
score my underscore address equals one comma and then the string infinite loop and then karma and then
another string Cupertino.
And then karma 9 5 0 1 4 for a postcode.
Then we've just created a tuple with a mix of data a mix of different data types if you will and this
is something that you don't usually see in practice with lists.
Lists are usually homogeneous meaning people don't tend to mix and match the different types of data.
Now another difference with lists is that tuples are immutable.
What does that mean.
It means that we can't change the tuple after we've made it.
So for example if I had C breakfast and I wanted to change bacon which is at index 0 and set that equal
to a C sausage and just you know innocently swap out the value then python will actually yell at us.
It's gonna give us a type error it's gonna say the tuple object does not support item assignment and
this basically means that once we've created a tuple like this we cannot change the values here and
we also can't append a new value say we can't stick this at say index 3 right.
We get the same error in other words the immutability of tuples means that once you've created a tuple
you can't mess around with it.
You can't change it up.
This is quite different from a list right.
Because if you remember in our gradient descent function we were running our loop and we were appending
items to our lists every time the loop ran our list grew in length because we're appending new items
and this is something we couldn't do with tuples now one more thing I want to show you on the topic
of tuples is a little gotcha.
Say we want to create a tuple with a single value.
So just one value inside our tuple.
No it's strange but for the sake of argument how would think about how you would credit tuple with just
one value.
What would the python syntax look like to store a single value inside this tuple
here's the solution.
So if I put a single value in here say 42 then I would have to put a trailing comma after it.
Now I've got a tuple with a single value so if I print it out print to pull with single value
then I can see it looks like this.
It's got a single value and a comma.
And if I substitute the print for type and check then I can see that indeed tuple with single value
is indeed a tuple.
Now the the very first time I saw this I found this syntax like super weird and confusing trailing comma.
Right.
Well my goodness.
So here it is now.
You two have shared this experience and the the weird syntax.
You're welcome.
Now it's time to come full circle.
We've packed a bunch of values into a tuple but we can also do the very opposite.
So we can unpack these values as well.
So if I take my tuple breakfast and I want to grab the values that are stored inside this tuple and
put them into some separate variables I can do that by writing say main comma side comma greens is equal
to breakfast.
And this is called sequence unpacking.
Yeah.
So if I print out main course is and then comma main then I get main course is bacon.
So here's the reason I mentioned this and why say we've come full circle.
If I scroll back up to where we had our gradient descent function we can see here in our return statement
what we're doing is we're returning three separate values but in fact we're packing all these values
into a single tuple.
Yeah.
And when we're calling our gradient descent function say here then we are unpacking this sequence and
storing the results in three separate variables local men.
This underscore X the reverse underscore list.
So we've actually been using tuples but we've never had to access any of the values from the tuple by
index.
But we can do that.
Let me show you how it would work.
So if I created a variable called data underscore tuple and set that equal to gradient underscore descent
and for my derivative on a scroll function I supply D.H. and for my initial guess I supply zero point
two then I can print out the local men at data underscore tuple square brackets zero because that's
the very very first thing that is stored inside our tuple I can print out the cost at the last x value
which would be equal to.
Well in this case it would be H of data underscore tuple square brackets zero and then I could also
print out the number of steps which in this case would be the length of so it would be data underscore
tuple square brackets 1 then you're on this and then you can see that it works exactly the same way
as before but instead of unpacking the sequence we're using the tuple now explicitly.
Okay so we've paused a little bit on analysing our algorithm and we've talked a little more about Python
and Python programming so now it's time to change tracks and go back to our gradient descent algorithm
now a reasonable question to ask is why that I show you this H of X example function I mean this function
by my own admission seems a little bit contrived and hurriedly confessed that a non convex cost function
is not very realistic but truth be told is that we can get this divergence and the very very same overflow
error in another way too and we can see this divergence and see the same error even if we are working
with a very nice clean cost function where we know for a fact that we should be able to reach a minimum
and this is what we're gonna be examining in the next lesson in the next lesson we're gonna be looking
at the elephant in the room the gradient descent learning rate how I'll see you there.
Take care.