Hi, this is Grant Little from Pluralsight,
and welcome back to this Practical Enterprise JMS Playbook.
If you've been following this playbook all the way through,
then you'll have noticed that all the examples so far use the basic JMS APIs,
which is all fine and good,
but it also means that typically there is a fair amount of boilerplate code.
Most enterprises use some form of framework to help
reduce this amount of boilerplate.
In this module, I'm going to look at using JMS within the Spring Framework.
JMS has long been part of this framework,
so it has mature support and generally makes working with JMS pretty simple,
taking care of much of the boilerplate code and basic concerns for you.
There are two general approaches to configuring an
application using the Spring Framework,
one via XML and another using annotations within your code,
which is now heavily used within the Spring Boot Framework.
This is not a course on teaching the Spring Framework,
so I'm assuming you'll have at least some familiarity with it, and using one or both of the configuration mechanisms.