Hi, this is Grant Little from Pluralsight,
and welcome back to Practical Enterprise JMS Playbook.
This module contains standalone plays on how to
perform some basic JMS functionality.
I'm assuming you already have some knowledge on JMS,
therefore these plays can be used as reminders how to do
some of the basic tasks using JMS.
I won't be going into great detail on any of them,
but just providing some guidance.
So first off, connection factories.
Once we have a message broker up and running,
the first thing we need to do is look at how to create a
ConnectionFactory that will connect to it.
Unfortunately, this is not part of the specification,
the resultant ConnectionFactory object is,
but how to create that factory object is not part of the JMS specification.
We're using Apache's ActiveMQ in our examples,
so let's see how you can achieve that with ActiveMQ.
Generally it's pretty simple actually.
You just need to know the host and the port that the
ActiveMQ broker is listening on.
This is not the admin port,
but the TCP port used for communication with the broker.
The default port for ActiveMQ is 61616.
We therefore need to create a ConnectionFactory that takes in a URI.
Just as a quick pointer, if you are using ActiveMQ in a HA environment,
then the URL you need to use is slightly different.
In that case, you would use the failover protocol,
passing in a list of URLs to your available brokers.
We only have one broker though,
so we'll go back to the original single broker configuration we had.
Now there are actually a few connection factories that we can create.
We've already seen the generic ConnectionFactory,
but the JMS API also supports a
QueueConnectionFactory and a TopicConnectionFactory.
If you specifically know the type of destination you will be using, e.
g.
a queue or a topic, then you can create instances of these interfaces directly.
Again, how is dependent on your JMS implementation,
but on the case of ActiveMQ and a number of other JMS implementations,
the ActiveMQ ConnectionFactory class implements all
three of the ConnectionFactories,
therefore we can create a new createQueueConnectionFactory method that
returns a QueueConnectionFactory implementation.
Inside that method, we can create a new instance of ActiveMQConnectionFactory,
and return that.
Similarly, for a TopicConnectionFactory,
we can create a new CreateTopicConnectionFactory method,
which returns a TopicConnectionFactory instance.
The implementation of that method also returns a new instance
of an ActiveMQConnectionFactory object.
If you are going to be using JMS within a transactional environment,
and by that I mean a distributed transaction environment,
then you will need to consider using the XA versions of these interfaces.
Now typically you will be more than likely using these in a
Java Enterprise Edition application server,
but let's demonstrate how you can create direct
instances of these required interfaces.
First off, we want to create an XA ConnectionFactory.
I'm actually just going to copy the existing
CreateConnectionFactory method and make a few changes.
First, I'll rename the new method to createXAConnectionFactory.
I'll change the return type to a XAConnectionFactory,
and finally, I need to change the implementing class.
I need to change from an ActiveMQConnectionFactory to
an ActiveMQXAConnectionFactory.
It takes the same parameters.
We can now replicate this pattern for the
XAQConnectionFactory and the XATopicConnectionFactory.
Now obviously this isn't the cleanest code,
there is a lot of duplication,
but I've done that deliberately to be a bit more verbose, so it's clear what's happening.