In order to use JMS in a Spring Boot application,
you need to add a few dependencies into your project.
I'm using Apache Maven, but if you're using Gradle,
then there will be a similar approach.
First off, our project's parent is the spring-boot-starter-parent.
I've also added a dependency for the latest spring-jms jar.
Now there is a spring-boot-starter-activemq for working with ActiveMQ,
which can be used for basic scenarios; however,
I'm not going to use it,
and instead I'm going to just include the activemq-client jar file.
Why?
Well, as much as the spring-boot-activemq-starter does get you up and running,
I find that some of the defaults make it difficult to
work across an enterprise solution,
but it's great for doing smaller applications and proof of concepts.
Another reason is to try and give you a bit more in-depth
knowledge about how the wiring works,
rather than rely on sort of out of the box magic.
In your application code,
you need to tell Spring that you want to enable JMS by adding
the EnableJms annotation onto a class that is annotated with
the configuration annotation.
So in my configuration,
I'm declaring a new Bean for my ActiveMQConnectionFactory.
It takes in an ActiveMQProperties object, which contains the broker URL.
There should be nothing really new in here,
as it's been covered earlier in the course.
Now if you are using some other message broker,
then you'll have to replace this implementation with
a functionally-similar method.
I'm marking the Bean as Primary,
so this will be the default connection factory
returned for injection into Spring Beans.
I'm also creating a second ConnectionFactory called CachingConnectionFactory.
It takes our ActiveMqConnectionFactory as a parameter,
and it effectively acts as a wrapper.
It will take care of caching connections, sessions, etc.
for us.
In its configuration, I've enabled caching of consumers and producers, as well as telling it to reconnect when an exception occurs.