So to ensure my project compiles and runs,
I've added a couple of dependencies in my project's pom.
xml file.
These are the latest spring-jms and activemq-client jars.
Inside my applicationContext.
xml file, I've declared a new Bean called ActiveMqConnectionFactory,
which creates the ConnectionFactory for us.
The properties are all similar to those we have seen in previous modules.
I'm also creating a second ConnectionFactory called cachingConnectionFactory.
It takes our activeMqConnectionFactory as a reference
and effectively acts as a wrapper.
It will take care of caching connections, sessions, etc.
for us.
In its configuration, I've enabled caching to consumers and producers,
as well as telling it to reconnect when an exception occurs.
If you happen to be using Spring within a JEE environment,
then your ConnectionFactory should be registered in the JNDI.
In this case,
you should a jndi-lookup to get a reference to your ConnectionFactory for use within Spring and not declare your own.