The next thing we need to create is a session.
Now a session is generally the transactional scope
of one or more JMS operations.
So during the construction of one,
we need to think about whether or not the session is to be transacted,
and also something called the acknowledgement mode.
You'll see those parameters in use,
but I'm going to cover them in more detail in a
later section within this module.
So if you're looking for specific information on those,
then please jump to that section.
Note that this operation can throw a JMS exception.
You can probably tell if you've been following along
that there is a common pattern,
in that we can also create a QueueSession object in a similar way,
as well as a TopicSession object.
I'll write those methods out here for completeness.
Also, we need to create the XA versions of these three methods.
Creating an XA session is similar,
it can be created from a XAConnection object by
calling the createXASession method.
This time you don't need any parameters to the method,
following the similar pattern that our createXAQueue session and
createXATopicSession methods that work in a similar way,
you just need to use the XAQueueConnection and XATopicConnection objects respectively.