We'll be using the Spring JMS template as the main
mechanism for sending messages.
It's actually capable of receiving messages as well,
which we will touch on, but generally I use messageListeners for this,
which we will see in use in a later section.
The JMS template can create basic JMS messages for you,
but it is also possible to send business-level objects.
For example, if you have an object in your system representing a customer order,
then it's possible to send this using a JmsTemplate.
It will use a define message converter to convert the
message into a suitable JMS message,
after which it will be sent to the destination.
This functionality requires the use of a message converter implementation.
There are various ones available, for example,
XML, standard Java serialization, and JSON,
or you can declare your own.
In our examples, we will be using JSON as the message format.
I would not recommend using the standard
serialization implementations in production.
To have a serialization does not really have a concept of object versioning.
This makes it difficult to upgrade your application without having to delete
messages from queues and/or topics during the release process.
Jackson is the JSON serialization library I will be using,
and it can generally fairly easily serialize objects into a JSON format.
This is then stored within the body of the JMS message.
In order for Jackson to de-serialize a message from raw
JSON back into a business object, which is required at the consumer end,
Jackson needs to know the type of object,
therefore as part of the serialization process,
it also sets a JMS property on the message,
which contains the fully-qualified class name of the object.
When using the JMS template,
it assumes by default that you are sending message to a queue,
unless you explicitly declare the JMS destination object when you're using it.
In our upcoming examples, we don't want to have to do this.
So we'll actually be declaring two implementations of the JMS template,
one for queuing destinations and another for topic destinations.
In the documentation for the JMS template,
it also suggests using cached or pooled connections,
therefore we will be using the cachingConnectionFactory we created in the previous section.