I'm going to create a method called consumeFromDestination,
which takes a JMS session object as a parameter,
and also the queue name we want to consume messages from.
I'm actually going to show you two ways of consuming messages,
one which uses polling, and another one which uses the JMS message listener.
For both, I need to create a reference to the queue we need to consume from.
We then need to create a message consumer object by calling
createConsumer on the session object.
To use the polling method, we can then call consumer.
recieve, which will wait or block indefinitely for a message to be received.
I'm going to change this slightly, as I typically try and avoid this approach,
but it may be useful in your scenario.
I'm going to create a Boolean called someCondition,
which would represent some condition in your application that
defines how long we should consume messages for,
i.
e.
it's related to some form of lifecycle in your application.
While the condition is true, we continuously loop and request messages,
timing out every 500 ms.
If no message is received within that time period,
then we will simply try again.
But if a message is received,
then you can do something with that message and process it in
whatever way your application requires.
This will work perfectly fine, but generally I prefer a different approach,
which is to use a message listener.
Now it does depend on your application.
Sometimes you want your application to simply request messages at certain times,
in which case the polling approach is best,
but generally I try and keep systems loosely coupled with messaging,
and therefore I have my consumers generally listening all the time.
Therefore, the message listener is a good solution for this.
I'll change the parameters of this method to take an
implementation on the JMS MessageListener interface,
then I'll get rid of the loop,
and let the JMS implementation effectively take care of that work for me.
All I need to do is simply call setMessageListener on
the message consumer I've created, and pass in the messageListener parameter.
Actually, I'm going to return the message consumer from this method,
and you'll see why in a moment.
Let's see how this method could be invoked.
Back in my main method, I'm going to call the consumeFromDestination method,
passing in the session, the queue name,
and a lambda expression for the messageListener.
Now if you're not using Java 8,
then you can pass in an anonymous class here or do something similar.
Inside the lambda, I'm simply getting a reference to the message,
and stating that you can do whatever you need do with the message,
which will depend on your application.
One other thing we need to do though is to free up any
resources which our application uses.
Now you can do this in whatever way is best for your application,
but to kind of represent that here,
I'm going to add a shutdown hook to the runtime.
Inside that, I'll close the consumer we returned,
the session object, and the connection.
Actually, there's one more thing you need to do to make this work.
You need to start the connection, and you do this by calling connection.
start.
And therefore, when shutting down your application, you should also call the stop method on the connection.