Sometimes to be able to diagnose issues or watch performance,
you need the ability to browse the contents of a queue.
The JMS API provides a mechanism to do this.
This approach can be especially useful if you want them ability
to count the number of messages on a queue,
although generally your JMS provider should provide
some mechanism to do this; however,
the queue browser is the only mechanism I know in the JMS API to be
able to count the number of messages on a queue.
The queue browser actually gives you access to the JMS message object itself.
Therefore, you can preview its contents.
This can be good in the case of a dead letter queue,
or you might want to get an impression of the types of
messages on that queue without processing them.
So here is an example of how you browse a queue.
I've got a single method here, which takes in two parameters,
my JMS session object and the JMS queue I want to browse.
I then use the session object to create a new queue browser object.
This is another example of where I think the JMS API could do with an update,
we call getEnumeration on that queue browser object,
which returns a list of objects.
Now really those objects are all JMS messages,
but as it's using an old Java API,
there are no generic types on the enumeration returned.
Therefore when you iterate around your enumeration,
you need to cast the object returned to a message,
and then further checking the type to see if it's an
instance of a JMS text message, which all of our examples used in this course,
and if so, output the contents to the console.
As I'm iterating around the objects, I'm also counting them,
which provides the queue size.
It's important to note the order of the messages within the
enumeration is the same as the order on the queue itself.
So let's just run this to see.
From the console output,
you can see are the contents of the messages and the
number of messages on that queue.
Now I'm actually going to run this again.
Notice I get the same output namely for two messages.
So my queue browser didn't consume the messages, they're still on the queue waiting to be processed.