Before we go and jump into JMS examples and code,
let's pause for a second and possibly take a step back.
This course has practical in title,
so we need to consider is JMS a practical solution for
the problem you're trying to solve.
Now don't get me wrong, I'm not trying to scare you off JMS,
but there are plenty options out there,
and we should just make sure that JMS is the correct choice.
So what are the pros and cons of JMS?
Okay, it's good to end on a positive, so let's start with the negatives.
JMS is a Java specification, therefore it only runs on the JVM.
You can interact with it with other languages such as Kotlin and Scala,
but it does depend on the language you are using,
and how interoperable it is with Java.
For example, there isn't a pure.
NET equivalent of JMS.
Now that does not mean that messages put on a queue can't be read from.
NET or vice versa,
but it does mean that it's more vendor specific and that specific
capabilities of the underlying message broker.
If you are really in mix language or technology stack environment,
then maybe consider using something like Advanced Message Queuing Protocol,
or AMQP for short.
As the name suggests, however, it is more of a protocol than an API.
Some of the JMS APIs can be a little clunky to use; however, with JMS 2.
0, which is still backwards compatible, this is somewhat improved.
Also,
there are various frameworks and patterns you can put in
place to mitigate a lot of these concerns.
There are some example plays within this course that cover these off.
One of the pro sides, JMS is really mature.
It has been in use now for many, many years,
and therefore has great support right there,
both in terms of the number of JMS providers and implementations available,
as well as the amount of documentation that is out there in the wild.
Considering how long JMS has been around,
the APIs haven't changed that much, so chasing your tail isn't a big concern.
Sometimes this is a concern with newer APIs and frameworks.
It's generally fairly simple to move from one JMS provider to another.
If you stick to the specifications,
then you'll find there isn't much work in changing provider.
This means you can avoid vendor lock-in,
which is a concern for some corporations.
Although every JMS implementation is different,
most JMS implementations are now really stable,
extremely performant, and have good solutions for high availability,
but the feature sets do change,
so that is something you will have to check out for yourself.
You can usually find a JMS vendor to match your budget.
If you are looking for an all-singing and dancing solution,
then you can find one within the commercial players.
If you are looking for something a little cheaper and
with less administrative features,
then there are plenty of open-source offerings around with
the possibility of a commercial support.
Even some of the open-source offerings have good
administration features these days.
So based on all that,
let's assume you're here because you are on the JMS journey and want to see some examples, so let's get cracking.