Now in most enterprise installations,
you will more than likely have some sort of requirement or
service-level agreement around uptime.
Generally, you have at least two of everything for redundancy purposes.
Using JMS is no exception.
You should use a JMS provider that provides a good HA architecture,
is clustered in some way, and has reliable and fast failover.
This is done differently by every JMS provider,
and you really need to look at the documentation,
and best consider what is best for your environment,
therefore, I can't really go into detail on it here.
What I will look at is ways you can use the JMS APIs to
allow for high availability and throughput.
Let's look at an example.
So in this example piece of code, I'm not doing anything particularly fancy.
I've got a class that registers a messageListener on a queue.
The messageListener is this class called DelayingMessageListener,
and if we look at that, it's pretty simple.
It takes two parameters,
an ID that we can use to identify the instance of the delaying message listener,
which we'll see in use in a little bit,
and also a time in milliseconds for which the thread goes to sleep.
The reason for this is to mimic some processing that takes a little bit of time.
Now I've set the delay I'm using to 200 ms,
so it will take at least 200 ms to process every message.
If I have 100 messages, then it will take at least 20 seconds to process those.
Just to show that,
I'm first using this small application to put 100 messages on the queue.
Then I'll start up my example app, and it will start processing those messages.
Now in some large-scale systems I've worked in,
there could be millions of messages being processed every day,
so if we can only do 120 seconds, then we're pretty much in trouble.
So how could we improve on that?
Well, the obvious answer is to start more consumers.
I can do that by running multiple instances of my application, so let's do that.
So let's start say another three instances.
So now with 4 processes running,
I'm going to put another 100 messages on the queue.
So a couple of important things,
one you can see it makes it easy to scale your application by
simply starting more instances of your application,
but secondly, and just as important, if any one of those four application fails,
then the other three will continue, and have the data to sent to them,
and also take up the additional load.
So it provides additional throughput,
but it also provides a highly-available solution.
As long as you consider where those applications are running,
for example,
you need to consider having them on different physical machines
or virtual machines in different data centers,
etc.
So,
we have seen that the load is being load balanced
roughly equally between all the consumers,
so this is great and required for a highly-available system,
but possibly it may also be a slight waste of resources,
for example, starting up a number of these services across multiple JVMs,
especially on the same virtual machine or physical machine
requires all the base memory for the JVM metaspace,
etc.
So it might be just as good in some applications to
create multiple consumers per JVM.
To demonstrate that, I've got another example piece of code.
In this case, I've got a for loop, and I'm creating a new session and consumer,
and storing those in a couple of lists.
This is mainly so I can clean up the resources later on
as you can see in the shutdown method.
In this case, each consumer is another instance of the delaying message listener,
and this time I'm passing in the index of the for loop as the name,
which helps to determine which consumer is
processing data in the console output.
So let's run this application up.
The example application automatically puts 100
messages on the queue when it starts.
From the output,
we can see that the load is shared among the consumers fairly equally.
Now as I've said,
you would need to run a number of these components on different
virtual machines in different data centers to allow for failover
and high-availability use case.
I'm going to show you a third example, which I would generally recommend,
which is showing the use of the default messageListener
container from the Spring Framework.
Now even if you don't use the full Spring Framework,
you can still use this class standalone.
It's available in the Spring-JMS library, and I would highly recommend it.
Why?
Well it already takes care of many of the concerns we've talked about.
It takes care of the connection session consumer caching for you,
and caters from multiple consumers, and can scale up and down based on demand.
It also takes care of automatically reconnecting to the JMS
broker if the connection should fail.
To demonstrate that, I'll start this example up.
And again we can see it consumes the messages as we would expect.
And it's actually doing that across five concurrent consumers.
But now if I jump to the console, and stop the ActiveMQ broker,
then I can see my application has detected the connection failure,
and is attempting to reconnect.
If I restart the broker again, then after a short time,
we no longer see any errors, and we can see a connection is established again.
And just to prove the point,
if I go back to the MessageSender application I have,
and send through 100 messages to the broker, then we can see from the consumer output that it is receiving those messages.