Well that's it for this module and this Practical
Enterprise JMS Playbook as a whole.
If you followed it all the way through,
then I hope you got enough knowledge to at least start
preparing your JMS solution for the enterprise.
But to quickly recap, let's briefly go over what we covered.
We first started to consider the big question,
should use JMS at all, and some of the alternatives.
We then looked at some basic JMS plays,
which you can use to refresh yourself if you need to.
Next some more advanced JMS features, which can be useful within the enterprise.
Then we looked at using JMS within the Spring Framework,
some of the benefits it offers, and quickly getting going with JMS,
and removing a lot of the boilerplate code that's required.
Then onto JMS within a Java Enterprise Edition environment,
specifically using JNDI to look up your resources,
and the use of the JMS 2.
0 API.
And finally in this module,
we've gone over some techniques for monitoring and
administrating your JMS solution.
Well, that's all from me. If you have any questions or queries, then please let me know.