Receiving a message in a JEE environment is also a fairly
trivial affair when using message-driven Beans.
Here is a typical example of an EJB 3.
1 message-driven Bean.
Firstly, my Bean is annotated with a MessageDriven annotation,
which takes a number of configuration properties.
There are a number of predefined ones in the specification
like destinationType and messageSelector,
but one that is missing is how to define the
destination the Bean should consume from.
This led to implementation-specific versions that weren't consistent,
and luckily they fixed this in the EJB 3.
2 specification, which is part of JEE 7,
so there is now a standard property used called destinationLookup,
which will look up the provided JNDI name for the destination
from which the Bean should consume messages.
So for the most part, once you've declared the class level annotations,
the class is a fairly standard JMS messageListener implementation
that could well run outside of a JEE container.
We have seen a number of examples of these
messageListeners already in this course,
so I won't cover them again.
The only comment I will make, however,
is that these are considered Beans within the JEE container,
therefore, there is a pool of them,
and that pool size can be controlled via your JEE administration console.
What this ultimately means is that the number of available
consumers from the queue is based on this pool size.
This is how you control the throughput of the messages through your JEE application.