Most good JMS brokers will have some form of message
redelivery and a dead letter queue.
It's not specifically part of the API, but in an enterprise system,
it's important to consider.
It generally applies to messages being sent to
consumers from the message broker.
Sending messages to the broker generally has to be taken
care of within your application logic.
If you can't send the messages to the broker,
then you have to decide what to do.
For consumers though,
the message broker has effectively taken responsibility for the message,
and therefore it needs to deliver it.
That messageListener simply throws an unchecked
exception indicating that it has failed.
In this case, you can tell the message broker to attempt redelivery,
and after so many attempts fail, and put the message back on another queue,
commonly called a dead letter queue, or DLQ.
We can then monitor that DLQ,
and take action based on the messages that are on it,
which in my experience,
quite often means some form of human interaction to resolve the issue,
but not always.
As I say, it's not part of the API,
so let's see how we do it in Apache's ActiveMQ.
Well,
it's actually controlled at the ConnectionFactory level by
something called a redelivery policy.
In this piece of code, as part of creating the ConnectionFactory,
you can see I'm saying a maximum of 4 redeliveries.
So the message broker will attempt to deliver the message 5 times in total.
ActiveMQ then relies for a backing-off algorithm,
which means the time between subsequent redeliveries will be longer,
allowing some time for the system to possibly recover.
So let's see this running.
From the output,
you can see there is a total of 5 attempts to consume the message,
then it stops.
If I jump onto the ActiveMQ Admin console,
then I can see from the queue section are two queues.
Note that even though the message was not successfully
consumed from the test destination queue,
there are no pending messages.
Instead, the message has been added to the DLQ,
which has one pending message,
which we can then consume using some other process.
Now it's important to mention that you do need some way
of reading messages from this queue, and the message can come in many formats,
as the message potentially comes from any queue within the message broker. So the DLQ consumer needs to be fairly generic.