So that's it for this module.
Let's quickly go over what we covered.
I started off by demonstrating how to configure the
WildFly application server for use with JMS.
We then looked at how to define queues and topics inside WildFly.
Next,
we looked at creating a generic and reusable-messageSender session
Bean that hides some of our JMS boilerplate code.
We then looked at how we can use a generic messageSender EJB
to send messages using both the JMS 1.
1 and 2.
0 specifications.
We then looked at how we can receive messages
asynchronously using message-driven Beans.
And finally,
we looked at how you can implement your own message converter to work
with business objects within your JE application.
In the next module,
we will be looking at administering and monitoring your JMS application within production, so I hope you'll join me for that.