[Autogenerated] it's them or time.
Let us run some demo to demonstrate AWS cognito User poll and identity pool.
Let's start with the user pools.
We have the following scenario.
We have a basic user pull configuration with no local user.
Configured Authentication is done by means of external identity provider
Google and is them or we will also show how to use AWS.
Cognito hosted the user interface to facilitate stagnant procedures.
Also, take note that given the complexity off Italy escalator configuration,
we will review and already configure the environment.
Let's move to AWS Cognito dashboard and let's go for user poll section.
I have some configuration already in place.
Let's select for these them or the one called the test.
Now integrated.
There are towns off possible configuration.
So let me go for the more interesting ones and let me skip the ones which are
configured with default values as dictated by this scenario,
we have no users configured the here.
This section will be automatically populated after that user
has been authenticated against the Google.
Let's move to up integration and less taken out of the domain,
which represents our public face in entry point for AWS cognito user poorly.
Instance when we moved to AP client settings,
we see that we have enabled Google and user pools as our identity providers.
Also note that we have a place that a generic cold back you are ill,
which is where we will be redirected after authentication process.
Now it's time to move to Google console.
We go to open authentication constant screen.
As you can see, we have configuration in place,
which says that Amazon cognito domain is authorized.
Then we moved to credentials and select the already created the client.
A few things to note Here you were.
I was already being configured with our AWS cook me to domain,
also taken out of client I D and a claim to secret,
which we will need at a later stage.
Let's go back to AWS, cook me to dashboard and let's select identity providers.
As you can see,
Google is already selected and configured with
proper Client I D and Client Secret.
Now the fun part.
Let's move under application clients,
settings and letting start hosted user interface.
A second in page pops up we select continued with Google option.
We are really reacted to my personal Google account feeling with past suit
and done were redirected back toe Our test called back.
You were all which is example dot com.
And now Well, now Google has redirected here and also provided the code.
Now,
since we're not developed a full framework which
automatically takes this code and do some action,
I will show you how to use discord in a more manual way.
Let's move to Boston men.
I have already crafted an FBI coal.
Not that the your l is our AWS cochinita domain.
Be sure that the client and the match with one configured and passed
the code we received back from Google and done.
A token is returned to us.
This token can be used at a later stage with AWS Cognitive entity pools and exchange it with AWS temporary credentials.