[Autogenerated] we have reached the end of this model and discourse,
it's time to quickly wrap up the main topics discussed So far,
we have discussed and implemented AWS guidelines to
secure access to AWS account, including the lock down of root User,
The creation off I am users to perform all operations on the account.
The use of multi factor authentication.
We have provided long tour on AWS.
I am policy topic we have described and the implemented identity
based the policy results based policies and session policies
across several real world scenarios.
We have explained how to set up in AWS cognito custom instance to
allow authorization and authentication for external Web
application landing over Target AWS account.
Also,
we have described how to integrate cognito with external identity providers.
Finally,
we have explained how to ensure proper governors on AWS
account by leveraging on cloud trail.
Also,
it is worth to remember that we have encountered several
demos are getting a wide least of scenarios.
We are now ready after course compression to ensure
identity and access management for single AWS account as
well as for cross account scenarios.
Finally,
let me provide a list of useful references first
place to go is Amazon documentation.
Of course, I can't.
We invite you to go through user and developer documentation and
guidelines to have a look to a P I references also note that there
is plenty of tutorials and examples.
Then you have plural site.
At the time of edging off this course,
we have nearly 200 courses on AWS topics for all
level and for all target audience.
I hope that you have enjoyed this course and then you find the material useful.
Thank you for taking the time to watch and learn with me. I wish you all the best in your future adventures with AWS.