[Autogenerated] in this section we will go on with a couple of addiction.
Aleshin Aires related to session Policy topic In this scenario
which we will denote as the inter account scenario,
Robert is a user residing in AWS account of global Mantex partner,
your task is an 80 administrator off Global Mantex is to provide
Robert temporary access with full of me in power.
As you can see, I'm locked as Bob in AWS account.
We have used the so far which we will call our main AWS account.
We moved to the role tabs and let's start to create a role.
First thing you have to decide is the type of trusted entity For these scenario.
We use the second tub named another AWS account.
We are asked to enter the AWS account i d.
And here I would provided the ideal off my secondary AWS account.
Also,
I will request that user covert in this role must have MF a
device enabled just to increase security,
you know,
Then we moved to permissions and provided as requested
by the task full admin privileges.
Let's keep for the moment the tag page and let's provide a meaningful name.
I think, Robert Dash External feats here role is created.
Let me just point out if you click on role and enter the trust tub,
you see that the trust relationship has been created between
current account and another AWS account.
Bay means off the roll object.
Now the fun part.
Let me log into my secondary alias account as Robert let me over in
the drop down menu and click the switch roll button.
You are asked to provide the I d off the AWS account where
we're landing and the rule name and done.
We have been magically redirected to the main AWS account and we are
lorded here as Robert let me check as three resources.
All s three boxes creates so far are here Does proving that we have
successfully implemented across account authorization by means of roles and
the session policy finally to leave the assume it roll.
All we have to do is to hit to the bottom,
name the back to Robert, and we are redirected to the secondary AWS account.
And is she an area which we will denote as the service rolled
scenario Global Mantex developer has some instances which needs
to connect it to s three buckets.
Your task as an 80 administrator off Global Mantex
is to provide easy to instance,
proper temporary privileges to access s three results is
let's look in as Bob on our main AWS account.
And let's move too easy to dashboard.
I have already my test Easy to instance, in place.
Let's attach a roll on it.
Let's create a new role.
Let me specify the trust entity type, which in this case,
is AWS easy to service.
Now we move to the permission tub and we selected the pre
configure the S three full access policy.
Let me skip the tag page and let me provide a meaningful name here.
Something like easy to dash role will feet back to easy to
dashboard window was selected the role we have just created
and in a matter of seconds, the role is associated with our easy to instance.
Now we move to see a lie I have broken figured that the easy to machine
with Aws Pitre Necessity K called the boat or three and I have created a
very simple script which least all the buckets residing in the current
AWS account when we run this creep that we can see that all buckets are
chronically listed.
Okay, One moment.
Who has provide the easy to with credentials to access to the S three buckets?
If we retrieve security, metadata off the easy to instance,
we can see that a complete set of credential as being pushed to
the instance when we have attached the role.
With this set of credential,
we have been able to run the script and to retrieve the least of markets.
Just a final note.
Let me switch to the dashboard in the role description
and go to revoke session bucket.
Let me here to the revoke session button and confirm now it was which again,
Back to seal interface and run again.
The same bite on script will receive a never does proving that the
set of credential granted by the role is temporary and can be revoked at any time by an administrator