Already end of the section we're just getting started into the fun stuff.
But don't worry in the next section we will talk about some very powerful insights you can read for
models and for this section.
This is what we learned.
Number one we talked about the accuracy paradox and that helped us understand why we cannot just use
the accuracy rate which comes from the confusion matrix as the driving factor for defining whether our
models are good or not.
Next we talked about the cumulative accuracy profile and when we got so used to it that now we just
call it the cap or the cap curve.
And basically what it is is a measure for how William is performing.
There is a mathematical way to assess the cap curve which is calculate the area under the ideal scenario
calculate the area under your model scenario and then divide one by the other and get the actual accuracy
ratio.
However we also talked about a rule of thumb which is very visual which is very quick.
Just look at the 50 percent line see where William all sitting there.
And then you have some certain thresholds which I told you about the ones that I personally use.
And then what we talked about is how to build a cap curve in Excel.
Plus you got the template so hopefully you now know how to build one but also hopefully that template
will save you lots of time and you can just use it again and again again.
Took me a while to come up with that template.
Usually for me it was always very messy when I was building these cap curves but now I know how to structure
it in a great way so that it's very efficient and I don't get cluttered with all these extra columns
and I don't need.
Number four is how to assess your model using the cap curve.
So that's we talked about that already.
That's the 50 percent line.
And just visually see how it is how the curves are structured how close it is to that ideal curve that
you know you can never achieve but you're always you always want to get as close to it as possible.
We'll talked about overfitting models and how you can avoid it.
So we're using a train data and test data so separating a test group from your daughter said early on
.
So that further down the track when you're ready you can actually apply the model to your test data
and then see how well you went on in that scenario.
So then compare the accuracy ratio in your train scenario and your test scenario and make sure that
there was no overfitting in your trained data.
We also practiced how to verify models by test.
So we didn't just talk about the theory we actually did it in practice and this time we had our test
data prepared for us or separated for us in a separate file.
Further down the course we will talk about the correct way of separating your test data from your training
data yourselves.
But this time we already had it and we did actually practice and visually compare the two.
And I really think that's that's a good exercise because you'll be doing quite a lot of that if you
want to build robust models.
And number seven there was a preview as to what's coming next.
So we talked a bit about how models can deteriorate over time and how you compare model we can compare
models side by side even if there are different models using the cap curve.
So that's coming further down the track in this course.
Hope you're enjoying the material so far and I look forward to seeing you in the next section of the
course.