And finally interpreting coefficients in front of us here we've got the four models that we built in
our backward elimination method.
And as we agreed Mahler 3 is the best one is the best fitted model.
And if we were to deliver a model on our project it would be this one.
So let's go ahead and start interpreting coefficients by looking at this model.
Here we've got two variables.
R&D spend and marketing spend so it's basically how much companies are spending on their research and
development and on their marketing and also about the constant.
And we're predicting profit.
So these coefficients here these B 1 and B 2 what they're telling us is that.
So how to how to interpret them.
First of all you look at the sign if the sign is positive that means your variable is correlated with
your independent variable is Kolstad with your dependent variable.
Meaning that if you change the value of your independent variable then the value then you can see that
the dependent variable will be changing in the same direction.
So basically if you'll be increasing spend on R&D then your profit will be increasing If increasing
spend on marketing then your profit is also increasing which makes sense right.
So if you're spending more in research and development making your party better than probably your profit
should increase eventually as well.
Same thing with marketing.
The more you spend marketing the more you sell and therefore the profit should also go up and that's
the sign if the sign is negative if the sign were negative We'll look at an example a bit later than
it's the opposite effect.
So basically increase your depende variable and your depende variable decreases.
And now let's look at the magnitude.
So here you can see right away that magnitude is higher foreign the spend and the magnitude is law for
marking spent.
Magnitude is always tricky we're regressions.
Be careful of magnitude sign is kind of you know pretty obvious.
It's either it's one way or the other magnitude can really trip you up and I can give you an example
here so you might think that OK right away.
Magnitude is greater so this this coefficient for R&D spend is bigger than the market spend coefficient
So definitely R&D spend has a bigger impact.
Well what if I tell you that I could easily fall changing anything in the regression I could easily
make this coefficient bigger by a lot by a thousand times bigger than R&D spend.
Well it's easy to do.
All I have to do is say marketing spend instead of looking at it in dollars.
Hobert I look at it in a fraction of a cent so every market is all good and sense.
So marketing spend instead of consing an adult is counted in cents right away because of variable has
gone down 100 times all catfish and will proportionally increase so it'll go up 100 times and if I change
my data and replace everywhere marketing spend with cents and everything else I will leave the same
then rerun this model I guarantee you that the coefficient here will actually become 2.9 9 0 7 9.
So it'll just increase 100 times.
Everything else will stay the same.
And that way right away you'll see oh wow.
The market is Bank of Shin's greatest so than market has been has a bigger impact on your dependent
variable profit and that's a mistake that a lot of beginners make you should not fall into this trap
Magot.
It is a tricky thing and the way to think about it is always say magnitude in terms of units of the
independent variable.
So the correct way to analyze this is even if not knowing what they're measured and maybe this was measured
in thousands of dollars and this was measured in dollars.
I don't know for instance although I do I do know of course I've seen the data but if say I don't know
.
You can still make a conclusion you just have to say this is R&D spend has a greater impact on profit
per unit of R&D spend then marketing then marketing spend has per unit of marketing spend and that's
all.
So basically even if they're measured in different things by saying per unit of the underlying variable
you are protecting yourself from that error that you know they are they are measured in different things
.
And moreover Imagine if they're measured $100 are the ones measured in kilometers or something like
that you can compare dollars and kilometers.
Right.
But you can always say per unit.
And this leads us to the actual interpretation of these variables all these coefficients What does it
mean.
So this means 0.7 nine means that for every unit if you keep all other variables constant so you only
have on the verbal So if you keep everything else constant but you are able to adjust R&D spend for
in this model or for it for a hypothetical company for every dollar for every unit of R&D spend that
you increase your profit will increase according to his model your profit will increase by 79 cents
.
That's exactly what this coefficient is saying.
And so for every unit that you decrease in your R&D spend your profit will decrease by seventy point
seventy nine over unit of profit.
And because R&D spend is mission dollars and profit is also $2 that means so for every unit increase
in for every dollar increase in R&D spend your profit will increase in by 79 cents.
So let let me just repeat that again that you are looking at units increase in R&D spend.
They translate through this coefficient into units increase in profit.
So if your profit was measured in apples then a 1 dollar increase and 1 unit increase is always going
to be true one unit increase in R&D spend will drive point seventy nine units increase in profit and
all of course of the profit units.
So let's turn turn that into dollars and apples a one dollar increase in R&D spend will drive a point
79 or 80 percent of an apple increase in profits.
So here you're talking about units of R&D spend and profit you're talking about units of profit and
this coefficient.
It links them together.
So as long as you say per unit you're fine once you already know what these variables are measured and
then you can start comparing them if they're on the same scale and in this case they are on the same
scale because they measured everything is measured in dollars here and you can say that a dollar increase
in R&D spend drives 79 cents dull 79 cents increase in profit and mark a dollar increase in marketing
spend drives only 3 cents increase in profits so basically if you're the venture capitalist which companies
are going to invest in well from this model you're going to decide that you should invest into companies
that are spending more on R&D.
There may be lots of reasons behind this and this is not just around the fact this could be true in
reality because profit is revenue minus expenses maybe marketing does drive a lot of revenue to a company
but at the same time maybe for these specific companies that were looking at their expense the cost
of marketing so the prices that they pay for mortgages so high that the increase in profit the net increase
in profit is actually marginal.
So the marketing is eating up a lot of the revenue is creating whereas R&D is you know is creating a
lot of revenue and a lot of it is actually staying in profit something like that but were not worried
about that right now thats more financials.
What we're doing is we're delivering a model.
All right so that's how you interpret professions with the same sign and on the same scale.
What's going if they're on different scales just say per unit and now let's move on to one of our previous
models is look at this one to a here for example and we'll say we'll kind of ignore for now that they
are insignificant.
So we'll say okay we're not looking at that right now we just want to practice with the coefficients
let's say for instance that they're all significant what would have said to us.
Well R&D spend here you can see we already know that these are old dollars.
This one is a dummy variable so we'll get to that in a second.
So R&D spend.
What happens here.
You know that's a per dollar increase in R&D spend your profit will increase by 80 cents.
Great.
Then marketing spend per dollar that you increase in marketing your profit will increase by 2.6 cents
.
Great then with administration what happens here.
Well you can see that it's negative.
And assuming once again that this is a significant variable independent variable in this model then
what this is saying is that for every dollar increase in administration expense that you incur your
profit is decreasing by 2 cents.
So the more you spend on this administration the lower your profit will be.
And that's an important thing to understand once again this is not a significant variable.
It's not the case in this example so it doesn't really matter what it's saying here.
Could say a million it's significant So we're throwing it out of the model anyway but if it were significant
then that's the thing to think about.
So if you're running a company and you know that the more you spend on the station the lower your profit
then maybe you should stop spending on administration or maybe you should reshuffle your funds or something
.
So it's very insightful actually to know these things.
And in terms of New York what does this saying.
Well this this comes back to the point which we're talking about that our models are not actually biased
towards one categorical category or the other.
As you can see we don't have center California here so what this is saying is that by default if the
New York is zero then the equation is deemed as if it's for California and then if you're in New York
if your company is in New York what happens is this is a one and that means that this profit goes down
by 1332 units if you keep everything else constant.
And you compare a situation in California and New York then.
So basically two companies everything is the same except for one is in California in New York than the
one in New York will have profit which is less by 1332 units point is there are nine of profit because
profit is million dollars that means the profit will go will be lower by 1332 dollars just because the
cost that's in companies.
But once again this isn't a statistically significant variable.
So it doesn't matter what it says here it doesn't matter what the sign is.
It's not portable model because that's our final model so this is just an example.
But once again it would be insightful So if there was a statistically significant Birbal then maybe
the venture capitalist is interested in that and that can drive their decision in which region they
want to invest whether it's California or New York.
So that's how you interpret coefficients with linear regression It's very simple.
Just remember about that per unit trick or tip I guess because if you forget about that you can you
know make the wrong conclusions.
Otherwise it's all pretty simple.
The last thing that I wanted to mention here is that you can see that every time we run a model the
coefficients change.
So what that is telling us is that coefficients actually only talk about the additional effect of every
single variable given that the other variables are already in place so for instance in this example
you could fission of marketing which is 0.39.
It means that given that R&D spend is already in your model and it's fixed then marketing spend adds
additional you know contributes this additional effect of zero point zero to 9 9 or so 9.
Meaning that if you were to ring around a different model and take out R&D spend then the coefficient
would be completely different.
And that's what we see here that when we take our marketing the coefficient for R&D spend is Tichenor
So that's another thing you should remember about that coefficients merely portray the additional effect
that every single variable brings into the model.
Hope you enjoyed this.
Tauriel and I look for see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing