Last time we talked about the correlation matrix and also the intuition behind multicollinearity.
And today we're going to finish off this whole section of a conclusion.
But before we do that I would like us to save the model because we will be using it in the next section
of the course.
So I'm going to close this.
You don't need the correlation matrix here in our final version of the model.
The one just makes shows the one that includes LOEG balance and doesn't have any wealth accumulation
or log of wealth accumulation.
So basically if you use the same variables as me then it should look like this.
What you need to do is go to File Save As I'm going to save it as an RTFM Word document click OK and
then just select a folder I'm going to save mine in my standard folder for this section save.
Oh yeah definitely a name.
So what I'm going to call it let's call it in my case model model 20 code named model 20.
OK save.
And now if I go to my folder you'll see in your document here.
So this is my model.
Scott this thing is to be fixed up.
So basically save the final results and that will allow us to when we need to recreate the model because
we'll know which variables went into this model.
And so we're just going to save that.
OK.
So that's ready.
And at this stage we can say thank you Grettel it really helped us out.
What I would like to do now is move on to our recap for the section.
So just close Grettel
ops.
There we go so there is our recap section recap what did we learn in this section and this section learned
.
Number one what a demographic segmentation is we talked about we talked about grouping of customers
by similarities of their behavior and using prior knowledge to predict any future trends and basically
predict future behavior.
So you can anticipate it so you can pre-empted maybe do something about it if required so examples are
like for example looped in here is chern modeling to understand when your customers are going to leave
and who is more likely to leave who's less likely to leave.
There's lots of different applications of demographics segmentation.
Number two is we practice building a real segmentation model which was great fun we had real variables
.
So it was variables that you would find in a bank such as balances credit card.
Yes.
What's the €10 of the customers ages and so on.
So something that is very very like the real world.
It's a law like that you would actually build it in the real world and we went step by step through
everything and understood how to exclude variables how to see that our model is still robust.
And we went the whole journey from start to finish which was which was a great experience in my view
.
We also learned how to transform independent variables.
So that's an important part.
If you think that's been a variable is misrepresenting the effect just due to the nature of the effect
because it should be represented by this variable is a role for my brain should be squared or there
should be a square root a logarithm or something.
I mean looked an example of taking a logarithm of balance plus one we learned how to create derived
variables so new independent variables and you would need to do this in cases when you have certain
business knowledge around how variables are combined to achieve the desired outcome.
Very very powerful technique as well.
The we understood the intuition behind multicollinearity and why it is basically bad for your models
if they're correlated independent variables that you're putting into the models.
We also looked at how to check for multicollinearity using variants inflation factors and also how to
read the correlation metrics and basically check for multiple neurology effect that fixed that way as
well.
So those are two techniques that'll allow you to get rid of or pre-empting any multicollinearity in
your models and act upon it in a timely manner.
So two things that I wanted to mention.
First of all of course this is not your hundred percent coverage of everything that you will ever do
when building a model.
However what we looked at today represents approximately 80 percent of any kind of techniques that you
will be using to Korean model it's usually this standardized approach a lot of is trial and error experimenting
with derived and transformed variables understanding which variables to include exclusions on of course
their little other things that you will learn along the way you will pick them up as you create more
of these.
But what I gave you here this blueprint this is an 80 percent base of what you will need in modeling
and the second point is tools.
Let's face it Grettel is not going to be the ultimate tool that you're going to be using.
However any tool that you'll be using will have its own way of showing you the Vivus or the correlation
matrix or running a binary logistic regression.
So those things you get accustomed to quite easily and once you know them the fundamentals are the same
.
And what was important about the section is for you to grasp the fundamentals to understand how exactly
these things are done and why they are done in this way.
And so once you've learnt that you can move on and wherever you apply this knowledge you're going to
be successful.
Thank you for staying with me through this section.
It was fun exciting.
The next one we're going to assess our models.
We'll show you how to read the cumulative accuracy profile.
We'll talk about the accuracy paradox and I will give you a template an actual Excel template for you
to take home and play around with.
That will help you assess your models.
I look forward to seeing in the next section of the course.
And until then I'd be analyzing