As you recall we have to row files that we're working with in this section and so far we have only created
a proc and a working file for one of them.
So let's go and create a second proc and a second working file and we'll do this for our row for our
table which is called transactional data.
So let's open up the table and there it is.
So those are all rows as you can see we've got row number order id date custom ID region wrap item units
and unit price.
So we've got a good mix here.
We've got dates we've got tech so this will as we agreed this will stay as a text and so will order
ID and region and we'll talk about that in a second.
This will definitely says text units is an integer it can be a.
It can have a decimal point points.
So it's definitely going to be a whole number and unit price is going to be a float type so great mix
of types of variables here.
What are we going to do next is we're going to show you a way that she can look at these two files or
two scripts at the same time.
By the way we we're not going to recode all of this as you understand where we have this prepared and
we don't want to rewrite all of this script from scratch so we're going to actually use this file as
our basis to create the new Proc..
So you'll see that in a second.
Right now what I would like to do is just take this script that shows you the table and drag it to the
side and then select a position where you want for it to be.
If you can put it to the right you can put it under your file to the left to the top.
I'm going to put it to the right of my existing file and now I can see it to fall side by side.
And if I close this window here which I never actually use then you will see that I have enough space
to work with both for the same time.
I don't think you can do is you can unpinned this object Explorer and then it will be like popping up
when you need it and when you don't need it you will have all this room to work with your files.
So actually am going to keep my objeck Explorer.
I think this is enough room for me.
Maybe make it a bit smaller like that.
So let's go ahead and do this first thing that I want to do is I want to make sure that I'm not going
to modify my existing product so I'm going to change this word to create.
And I'm just going to change the name here right away as it's been highlighted in red because I can
create this Procrit exists and that's fine.
I don't want to create this proc I want to create a proc just like it.
But for this other file so I'm gonna take the name of the file here between role and the date.
Al capias and I'll put it in here.
After the word work.
And as soon as I execute that I'm safe.
That means that I'm no longer working in the old proc.
I'm working in the new proc which you can see here so transactional data.
I'm working on that one right now.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to set this proc up for accepting this data because we don't
even have the table prepared yet the work table.
So today's date is the 11:30 time flies and let's take this again copy and we will pasted everywhere
.
We need to.
So here here you can use a Find and Replace functionality.
I'm just not doing that so that you can see exactly what I'm doing.
So here obviously get rid of all of the columns except for the first one because it's going to be the
same.
Then here replace again the truncate replace get rid of all the columns get of all the columns.
And here you need to put in your RAW file so take the whole name of the whole file and just place it
here.
And here I usually just put an X back to remind me that I need to put in the correct number of rows
when I'm done.
And at the bottom it's going to be again the final file.
So sorry this is the raw file.
So get rid of that.
And also I like to actually put it here.
The final file in fact will put at the top because it's a bit more important from.
And what is it going to be.
The final file is going to be the one I'm creating here.
There you.
So just so that at the end we can compare.
So that's how our proc looks currently.
Now we want to populate it.
We have the correct rows.
So we'll start off with the create table part.
Obviously we want to take these same columns and create create them in our table once again as we discussed
you might want to rename them you might not want all of the columns although I do advice for the working
table took all the columns but there might be cases when you have like a thousand columns and you were
all fine.
You only need 10 for analysis and in that case you don't really need to bother with everything so same
trick shift tab and then tab.
Oops forgot about this guy.
OK.
Next we're going to give these columns their designated types right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to bring up this file over here so that I can zoom in comfortably
and you can see everything.
So that's this file
and I'm working on this table.
So here Order ID it looks like an integer.
And this one is probably one of the trickiest ones or one of the most tempting ones.
It looks like an integer.
It's sequenced you know.
In this particular case is going from one to 43 it looks like a great opportunity and it's also me a
meets the date.
There are cases like maybe in this particular case you could use it as an integer because you if you
if you have knowledge that it is sequenced and sequenced by date and there are no discrepancies So it's
always the case that if the or the great order ID means it was that order was created later.
So maybe in this case you might use it as an integer because that will allow you to order this column
ascending descending and you know compare orders between each other.
However I'm not going to do that because I have the philosophy that if something is not meant to be
an integer I'm not going to make it an integer it's like not a whole number it's it looks like a whole
number but in reality for me it's text.
For me it would have been the same if these were letters if these were ABC all the way up to Zed and
then you know a B B and so on.
It doesn't make a difference that it's simply an idea.
So I can identify this order and may be connected to other tables.
That's all it's there for.
So for me it's not actually doesn't carry a numerical weight that numbers you know numbers and databases
have what they're used for here.
It's simply a text for me so I'm going to I'm going to keep it as a bar chart.
You can perhaps maybe select something else if if you're more comfortable with that.
Whoops excuse me.
So var char and I'll just give it a 100 meaning it doesn't go.
Not that it goes up to 100 music.
You can have 100 characters.
That's a lot.
That's good order date.
So this is just going to be a date.
If you have a date and time than any date time.
But we only have date customer id is going to be a VAR charm
and here it's evidently going up to seven in previous Tauriel or previously when we were talking about
the other table you saw that we didn't know how long they were and we put a 100 so I'll put 100 here
as well.
But we'll talk about customer ID in a seperate video so region once again looks like a number but you
can take an average of region you can add them up compare them you know it doesn't mean anything here
.
It's a purely categorical variable so we're going to keep it of our char and looks like it is only it
only goes up to 3 so we'll only give it one symbol rep.
It's a VAR char it's a name so a 100 item it's also name but items can be long so you get a thousand
units units as an integer.
As we discussed you can have a fraction of a unit.
So that's how a first integer and unit price is going to be a float because that's a dollar a dollar
amount.
All right.
So that's creating a table.
Next we're going to truncate the table yes that's good.
Now we're going to insert into a table.
This is the tedious Bidwill you just take and copy this part you put it.
Oops you put it here and you just get to get rid of these
types.
Could have we could have done that actually before.
Yeah you can do that before you specify the tabs.
You can just copy it in here maybe a bit faster.
Now you need to select from here so I'm going to copy these columns so these columns from here.
OK.
All right.
So that's us pretty much done.
Let's save the proc.
Just execute the whole proc.
So what's what is it telling us that I didn't change just to alter.
Let's changed that to alter because this proc is already existing in the database.
There we go.
And now we're going to execute everything between Begin and then we go execute down 43 rows affected
again.
So this just so happens that the tables both have 43 rows.
All right.
Now I've changed part of the pro-corporate a combination executed again.
And let's refresh.
That's good.
And here's your file.
Let's see file.
All right.
There it is.
So here you can see that everything is good.
And since this file actually has lots of different types of data I thought it'd be quite handy to share
another trick like here you can see that they're there types property but if you right click the file
and you click design you don't often do this but here you can actually see the data type so you can
see that we've specified the data the target types who specified are reflected here.
So Ron number is always going to be an intern that's our identity column.
And here are the actual columns that we specify so all your ideas are char 100 then date customer IDs
of var char region rep item units these are in a float.
So just if you want to ever check the data types of a table just click that design option and there
we go we've created our second proc and our second a working table