Let's have a look at some of the errors that could happen in essence has we've already experienced these
three truncation.
That is when your record in a cell is too long.
The number of characters is greater than the number of characters that you're allocating for that column
in your database in your table and therefore that specific cell gets truncated you get an error.
We know how to deal with that.
Next the bad input file format.
An example of bad input file format is when remember when we did not specify the quotation marks and
went on to upload the data.
There would have been a right but in our case we had commas within the columns and therefore they were
unqualified.
And that meant that everything got skewed either left or right and so on.
So that's an example of bad input file format you need to make sure that you specify the text qualifiers
.
Another example is when you have two columns with the same name you cannot import data when there are
two columns of the same name.
You will get an error at the stage of the flat file source.
Manager.
So make sure your daughter doesn't have two calls with the same name and code page mismatch.
She saw me get that error.
That's because I have two languages installed on my computer and you also now know how to deal with
that error when it comes up.
Just make sure that after the upload you don't have any weird symbols in your final table you need to
make sure that the data is uploaded correctly in the correct code page so that way you will get the
right you'll be able to see the right text in the final table.
And here another three errors that you could potentially get out of memory or database logfile too big
.
When skill stops inserting data and connection fails so those are normal errors that are associated
with technology and capacity of your S-sh Siskiyou else servers and so on.
So potentially you could get those errors and you would have to deal with them on the case.
Case by case basis.
And now here's a list of errors that you won't get.
If you use this blueprint some metadata changes data type mismatch primary key unique index violations
permission issues configuration file missing and deadlocks.
If you use the blueprint that I have provided you you will not get these errors in as it has.
Why.
Well simply because the way we're doing things we're uploading daughter as a text format so we're not
converting data into different formats insofar as we're going to be doing that in as well and we'll
talk more about that in the summary of this section.
And we're not using any complex transformations.
The only transformations that we're using are conditional splits and simply the way this whole blueprint
is structured is to minimize the amount of work that is done in Sosias we're transferring all of the
hard core calculations and conversions and D'Attoma manipulations into his kill because you have more
control over it.
In my view you have more control over it in Eskew all that is and a great advantage of this blueprint
that we studied in this section of the course.
You can only experience six out of the 12 Sosias errors listed here and maybe perhaps these these are
not all of the errors that can happen in our society but these are the more common or most popular errors
that happen in this piece of software.
My advice to you is stick to the blueprint you will save yourself lots of time.