We're rapidly approaching the end of this section and we've pretty much done everything we needed to
do to work with our daughter from here so it might be a surprise but pretty much our tables are ready
to do analysis on.
So for instance let's have a look at this one.
Orac office supplies a customer list.
We've already prepared the table.
We've put the columns in there correct formats.
Everything is ready so we've done everything we could to get from our row file to a workable file.
Same thing with transactional data here you can see the dates customer IDs everything is in the correct
formats and so on and we've got all prox saved in case we need to check the process and redo some of
this work.
So pretty much what you can do from here is you can connect different types of analytics tools like
Tablo are Piscean whatever tool you're using to analyze data to these tables in as few.
So there you have like a lot of benefits that first of all they're clean they're prepared.
You've done all the groundwork.
Q Well you've got all this traceability of what you've done.
Also NSU all unnecessary but also on top of all that you have a storage facility.
These tables are now stored in as well and you don't have to work with CSC or Excel or other types of
files you just hook up your analytics tools to your server and you access your tables from there.
And that's that's how it works so pretty much you've done this 70 percent of that work that remember
was always saying you've done that 70 percent of the time you're going to be doing more work of data
preparing.
Well we've done it that this is the end pretty much.
We are ready to work with our data.
The remaining 30 percent are the fun bit.
They're the exciting happy visualizations and modeling and and stuff like that but just to finish off
of this section I wanted to show you a few more other things that you can do and ask you all just to
perhaps make your life easier or maybe give you some ideas of how you can structure your daughter for
analysis so just to clarify this is we're done with for the preparation that this is like an extra bonus
that you can do to maybe make your work easier further on.
Why.
Well on top of all of the things we mentioned are beautiful bottom scale.
It is also a very good facility to manipulate your data so if in case your tables are not exactly as
you want them for you or our modeling or for your Tablo visualisations you don't have to you can you
can connect to these tables as they are now to the working tables to these two.
And and then combine them in our or in Tablo all of those analytical tools they have the capacity to
do that.
However you can prepare your tables a little bit more in this Deuel and that way make that last part
of your work where you visualize and so on.
Even even more seamless because you don't have to do any you know won't have to connect different doorframes
to each other different tables and merges and joins and so on.
You can do a lot of that other remaining groundwork and Asgill And right now I'll show you one of those
tricks.
So all right let's get into it.
We have two tables here let's put them side by side.
Which one is this.
This is the customer list and this is the transactional data.
So here you can see customer ID and you know where they live zip code gender age and here you can see
the transactions that those customers conducted.
Once again these are tiny tables are only 43 rows and and they match one to one.
So there's nothing difficult about them this is just for practice sake.
Here you have the order date order number date customer I.D. region who sold to the customer what they
sold.
Number of units unit price.
So right away you can see that these two tables have one common field it's customer I.D. and you can
connect the two on that field.
And let's say for instance what we want to visualize later on in Tablo or analyze in our is how different
how many sales we have per zip code for for instance a which zip codes are selling the best.
Or let's let's say something like that so we want some data from this table and we want some data from
this step or it could be which genders are buying more.
Let's do that and probably So we want to understand are males buying more are females buying more and
just.
Just so you understand and we're not doing this analysis in as well.
We're just preparing the data so that later we can do this analysis in another tool.
And by that I mean that we need to make sure that gender and units and unit prices are all in one table
altogether.
Right now they're in two separate tables.
So let's see how we can do that in Eskew al.
So I'm going to close that close that we need to create a new prok obviously all we need to create a
new query to join this sort of inquiry so we're going to use at the top we're going to use Diest training
as we're used to go and we'll just write a simple query so select a star from which table we want to
can I grow on take customer lists right and we'll call a table a and will left join it too.
We've talked we talked about joined in the previous section so I'm assuming that you are quite comfortable
with what we're doing right now.
So everything from these to tables.
Join them on a door to have customer ID here equals b b Daut also have Customer ID should come up and
let's run that let's see what happens cyclic top 5.
And as you see here we've got the first stable customer table.
There it is.
And now it's joined to the second table and they have been joined on this field.
Customer ID customer ID so you can see it always matches up.
And this by the way this wouldn't have been possible if we hadn't restored the leading zeros so it's
great that we restored the leading zeros in our data preparation phase.
As you can see we can seamlessly connect the two data sets right here.
And obviously we don't need all the columns we might for our analysis we and definitely we don't duplicate
it like customer did twice.
For analysis we might only need gender.
So we could keep the customer ID as so we know which record came from where.
So would keep customer ID would keep gender and we would keep units in unit price and in fact we don't
need units in price for our analysis.
We know that we need units we need the sales we need the revenue so we need Munis times unit price so
let's go ahead and type that in.
So we want customer ID all we want customer ID from table a then we want and probably better to expand
it like this.
Customer ID from table a then we want gender from table than we want from table B.
We want units.
And so we will call this call because we're multiplying and altering and call them.
It won't have a name so we'll call it revenue.
Let's have a look at that.
So I'm going to execute they go we have customized the gender revenue and now you can simply connect
you know like well you could simply connect tabel or some other tool to this table.
And do you have isolations make no make awesome conclusions and analysis but to perform analysis.
But right now this is just a select statement so this table doesn't exist anywhere.
It's basically we just did an ad hoc query and as soon as we close this query we know we're not going
to have it anymore and we won't have the table or anything.
So right now what I'm going to show you is two things.
First of all we want to put this query into a table.
Right.
So it has to be somewhere here so that later on we can connect to it and to.
We want to save this query as well why we want to say this query because you don't have to say this
query if you know if you just want the table and then connect to it you can sure but I highly recommend
to save all queries when you create a table that you're going to be working with and doing analysis
on so it's not just some some something you did quickly just to check something out you're actually
going to be working it you want to save the query just like before working for us so that then you can
repeat it you can audited you understand what you've done.
You can modify it if you need to.
So that's what we're going to be talking about now and it's going to be long is going to be very very
simple because we already know most of this stuff.
We need a Proc. as you guessed.
That's the way we save stuff in Esky all right.
So let's go and find out or find a proxy or we're going to modify and we will take this Tobit and including
this as.
And then we'll remember to put in.
And there's our.
It's on a template.
This time it won't be at work.
We're building a r table D R B and we're going to call our table.
We're going to keep the name of the project because we normally would have a separate database for every
project but Or or a schema.
But in this case we'll just keep this prefix.
And here we will call this and we'll say gender as well.
So Author everything.
I'll just leave that empty phone for today.
Sheer rule will say it's a work to a d'Harville file so what it does the table is it's derived tables
when you combining two tables when it's not just like a working table is one to one we're here you doing
something so.
And that's why also it's good to add some description so split by gender something that's so totally
up to what you'd like to happen here.
That's our Jarvi Proc..
That's how we start it then we'll have to have an end here.
So right now we need to create it instead of altering it.
That's pretty much it.
So if we run this now it's executed successfully and here you'll see a D'Arby proc PLDT Arvie.
Now the last thing that we have to do is put this result into a table and instead of creating that whole
thing from start where we create the table we delete it created truncated and then select into the to
insert into the table like we did with the workforce.
You can do that but that's tedious and you'd only do that for important files for important tables like
work tables or if you have a major table that you're putting a lot of stuff into for an ad hoc query
like this.
There's a fast way and I'll show you now.
So all you have to do is once you've selected the columns here you just say in two and then you give
your table name so where it you know what the name is going to be it's going to be this name.
And if you do that if you run this now four or three rows affected once again we're going to copy that
.
And if you refresh here you will see that there is a select there's a diary file so we just basically
very quickly selected all the columns in there.
And if you also go to design you will see that they have the right types they have the exact same times
as the columns that we selected from.
So here's a flawed because we multiplied an integer by float and that gives us a float.
And these are char 100 on a larger one.
So like that on the fly very quickly you can create a D'Arby table.
And I recommend this approach if you don't want to waste time.
If you want to save time.
The only thing is how they execute your proc to save it.
Of course you can execute you've got to change it to alter so you Praag But if you rerun this code you'll
see you get an error because there's a dairy file.
So I recommend putting a comment here at the top a multi-line comment where you will drop the table
so drop table this table this one.
No not this one this one.
So if you ever need to rerun this bit you just have to select this line execute and then the table gets
dropped and you can execute this part.
And by the way this is a this is a safe option because if you ever highlight everything in here it will
be highlighted as a comment and if you run it it's not dropping the table because the table this line
is in the comments.
It's not being executed at all so that kind of prevents you from accidentally dropping table so if you
ever want to drop the table you have to specifically select this line by itself.
Drop the table so you assume it's assumed that you know what you're doing and then you select in two
.
And if we're fresh we've got our DARBEE table here ready for us to work.
And then finally say the Proc..
So that is how you can use GRV prox and files to save yourself some time in other analytical tools such
as Tablo and are you're really leveraging the purpose skills design for its design for storage and manipulation
of data.
So if you need to combine some tables why not do it in a secure all