Hello this is the solution to the tutorial about the chi squared test.
And remember we had some homework we had to look at these variables over here so for geography we had
observed values and we need to run a square test.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And the show going to get rid of these.
Going to add a new column here.
This is our template for Cascade test.
So let's give these names France Germany and Spain.
Ok and now I'm just going to copy the values from our test.
So here actually I want to get rid of those as well.
I'm going to copy the values from our PowerPoint and I'm just going to copy the formats
and now I just want to make sure that these are OK.
See that's not OK because it's not taking everything so I need all plus plus plus plus.
This is all right so I need to get these again all plus plus plus plus plus plus.
And what do we have here plus plus.
So in short it was faster to just recreate the table from scratch.
Just make sure that you adding up everything you're adding a buried thing.
10000 makes sense.
All right.
So this what do we have here.
Get rid of the totals again.
Copy these over and let's maybe we'll move this up a little bit so we have more space.
So now let's copy our results.
This will need to redo.
Let's check this.
This is called taking the correct column taking that dividing by that and multiply by that.
That's good.
Divide that divide by that multiply by that that's that that that's good.
That looks good.
So we just have to basically copy if you've locked your cells using the dollar signs then copying them
should work fine for you.
So I'm just going to add another row.
All plus plus plus plus plus plus plus plus plus plus.
And so she can see something is wrong here and something is actually wrong here.
What it's doing now plus plus some those so that's something I should have picked up which we actually
want those.
And here as well we want to some these.
All right so this one second some of those this is taking some of those has good looks good now.
So now let's run S.H. I test actual ranges.
This one so it doesn't matter.
We have more rows now.
It can as long as it's the same number.
Same type of table in actual and expected run.
So those are P-value very very low P-value which is good which means there's a significance level not
random.
So now let's go ahead and do the same thing but using this tool.
All right.
We all just have let's see if we can copy it like that.
No we can't.
OK.
We're going to have to copy them one by one.
There you go.
And just one more left.
All right so let's calculate.
So here you got your totals.
Just making sure it's same.
You've got the totals here.
Make sure it's the same.
Now let's focus on this.
If you look here P-value is tiny.
Very very small.
What does that mean.
That means the effect is not random.
There is some correlation.
So basically the outcome is not independent of the country variable.
So that's how you run a chi squared test for three categories you can run a case score just for as many
categories as you like.
And it's very it's the same approach every single time.
Hope you are successful with this homework.
And hopefully it will help you solidify your knowledge about the chi square test.
And I look forward to seeing you back in the course.
Until then happy analyzing