Before we dive into the section I wanted to give you a quick heads up that there's a caveat around everything
that we're doing with linear regressions linear regressions have assumptions and the assumptions I list
below linearity homeless kids a city multivariate normality independence of errors and lack of multicollinearity
and before building a linear regression model you need to check that these assumptions are true.
And then you can only proceed and be sure that you're building a good linear regression model.
Well in this section we won't be focusing on that we won't be checking these assumptions at all.
And the reason for that is that we have a different goal in mind.
Linear Regression is not our end game linear regression is just a stepping stone for us to get used
to regressions and get comfortable with them and then proceed on to the main part of our modeling section
which is Geo demographic segmentation.
We want to build demographic segmentation model and for that we will actually need a logistical regression
and logistic regression have different assumptions around them and therefore we won't be focusing on
the assumptions of linear regressions.
In this section of the course but if you ever do need to build a linear regression then make sure that
you don't just blindly follow the steps that I present to you in this section of the course but you
do need to go back to the assumptions of the linear regression and research them and make sure that
they are correct when you're building your linear regression.
However having said that I want to point out that from my personal experience logistic regression is
hands down.
By far the most frequently used type of regression in data science.
So what you will learn in this part of the Course will definitely give you the maximum benefit for your
data science career.