The tutorial we visualized our distribution of customers by age bands and we talked about Binz.
We created a new categorial variable for age when it's been.
And we created this amazing chart.
Now let's go ahead and save this worksheet as age distribution
and also let's just save our work book in general because we haven't done that in a while.
And now what we're going to do is create a new chart and let's have a look here.
Now we know dimensions.
You'll notice that we have a new dimension which is age been oh wow what a surprise.
Where did that come from.
Well you know we created that in the previous tutorial.
So what do we want to do now is hello we take advantage of this and go ahead and create a kind of like
an A B test that we were doing previously or a classification test.
But now with this new variable so we already have our tests here so let's take one of them and say this
one and we'll duplicate the sheet we'll move the sheet to the end and we will call this H.
Just call it age because that will tell us that it's on distribution because it doesn't have the word
distribution.
And now we'll just take Age been and will drag it to replace active member and let's make some space
.
What I'd like to do here is get rid of the text label because it's taking up too much space.
Maybe let's string this now because there's less labels.
So there you go.
As you can see we've got a beautiful distribution or actually test this is not distribution.
These are percentages.
It's a beautiful test has been already created for us.
And how quick was that.
I just just want to focus on that for a second.
How quick did we create this test.
It's amazing what what can we see from here.
Well we still have all average line as you remember from the previous section.
That's how many people leave the company or from the sample how many people left over the period of
time.
So if take out age and remove it.
You'll see that right away that's our Eddie 80:20 split of people who stayed and left some going to
price controls had to return age.
So that's how average that's how people live.
So here he comes here in a way that people in the lower age bands are less likely to leave.
And people in the higher age bands are also much less likely to leave people that do leave quite a lot
or that age bands that are most at risk are these age bands are here between 45 and 60.
So 40 and 65 they're about average even though four is a bit higher.
But between 45 and 65 years old people are at a very high risk of being so those are the customers that
are for some reason leaving this bank and that is something that you need to like something that can
be put in to report and investigate that further understand why these customers are leaving white customers
between 35 and 40 are less affected or in between because customers between 25 and 40 or less affected
and so on why these customers are not affected.
So that would have been already great insights but at the same time remember that thing we talked about
that you have to make sure that you're avoiding anomalies like or kind of anomalies that are not there
or they're Ju-Ju insignificance of your test or the they are there because there's a lack of records
.
So here you can see right away there's a couple of those that might be suspicious.
For instance 100 percent here 100 percent 100 percent it doesn't because these are the tails of your
distributions or not the distribution or age distribution.
The one that we looked at previously because they are the tails of the distribution they might be not
too many records here.
And so how do you check that everything is going smoothly.
Well we'll find that out in the next tutorial.
I will show you how to combine the two charts how to combine your age distribution chart and your test
chart so that you can very quickly visually assess what is a significant result and what is a non-significant
result.
And I look for the next tutorial and until then I'd be analyzing