This whole section we'll be dealing with regressions quite a bit.
So in today's tutorial we're going to talk about the different types of regressions we will be covering
off.
This is how we keep media.
It defines a regression in statistics regression analysis is a statistical process for estimating the
relationships among variables.
The focus is on the relationship between a dependent variable and one or more independent variables
.
So let's look into this a bit more.
They're going to look at two types of regressions in this part of the Course linear regression and the
logistic regression.
They both have two subtypes.
The simple linear regression and the multiple in your regression and the simple logistic regression
and the multiple Just vigorish And in terms of logistic regression.
The distinction between simple and multiple.
It's of course of course there but people rarely use a simple logistic regression.
So whenever you hear a logistic regression it implies multiple.
And moreover we can talk about logistic regression when write right when the time comes because we're
not ready for that yet.
So in this turtle is going to talk about a simple linear regression and will also cover off multiple
integration in the in the next few tutorials as well a little bit.
So simple in your regression and multiple introgression What are they.
Well a simple integration is basically this formula where y equals zero plus B one times x.
And you might recognize this formula from back in high school is just a formal over a trend line or
a slope sloped line on a x y axis.
And let's go through these variables and coefficients one by one.
So this is the dependent variable the dependent variable something you're trying to explain for instance
how does a person's salary change with the years of experience that he has.
So in that case why would be the dependent variable or how what grade does a student get depending on
how much time he's put into studying.
In that case why would be the dependent variable so something that you're trying to understand how it
depends on something else X is your independent variable.
In this case and the simple integration only have one independent variable.
So we don't even have to call it X Y or we could just call it X and this is the variable that is.
You're assuming that it is causing the depan variable to change or as we will learn further.
Sometimes the independent variable might not be a direct causal factor but it's still there might be
an implied association between the two.
And in that case you're trying to figure out this association then B one is a coefficient for the independent
variable.
And it kind of says how the effect or how a change in X-1 a unit change in x1 and we'll be talking about
this a lot.
Unit changes a unit change in X-1 how that affects a unit change in Y.
So it's kind of think of it as the translator or the multiplier or something like that that that connects
to the connector between y and X-1 so you can just say you can always say X-1 is directly proportional
there is.
Well you can't just say.
Why the change in x is always equal to change and why they might be at this coefficient of proportion
to which proportion that change is inflated or deflated.
And B zero is the constants as a constant term and we'll talk about the constant just in a few seconds
or a few in a minute after we cut off the multiple integration.
So multiple introgression same thing but many variables.
So bizzarro one constant and then many combinations or many pairs of B and X and it can go up to quite
a lot depends on how many regressors you have here on the you've got a dependent variable y.
So something you're explaining but this time the difference is that you think there might be a few causations
.
So in the case of salary for instance it could be how much years of experience you've done how many
other courses you've done and how much you know how much time you spend at work or things like that
or how valuable how much money you make for the company in terms of a student and his grades.
If you're depende verbal is what grade does the student get than in the independent variables could
be how much the student has studied for the exam maybe how much he has slept before the exam how many
lectures he has attended throughout the course and things like that.
The concept is still there.
And also you've got Tech officials.
So now let's look at the simple linear regression because it's the easiest one to discuss.
It's very pretty straightforward you can visualize it quite well.
So here we got the y and x axis.
Let's look at that specific example where we have experience and salary.
So experience is going to be our horizontal axis.
Salary is all vertical axis and we want to understand how people's salary depends on their experience
.
Well what we do in regression is we don't just come up with a theory we look at the evidence we'll look
at the live hard fact.
So here are some observations we've had.
So in the CERN company this is how salaries are distributed among people who have different levels of
experience and what a regression does.
So that's a form of a regression.
In our case it'll change to salary equals be 0 plus be 1 times experience.
And what that essentially means is just putting a line through your chart that best fits this data and
we'll talk about best fitting in the next toile when we're talking about ordinary squares.
But for now this is the chart.
This is the line that best fits as Darren even looks like it right.
So I don't it's quite hard to draw a line that fits is not a better and assumption here is it's impossible
this is the best line that approximates is not what does that mean.
Well we'll talk about that in the next tutorial once again.
For now let's focus on the coefficients and the coffin and the constant.
So what does the constant mean here.
Well the cause that actually means the the point where the line crosses the vertical axis and let's
say it's $30000.
What does that mean.
Well it means that when B when experience is zero.
So when as you say on the horizontal axis when experience is at 0 in the formula on the right you can
see that the second part 1 times experience becomes zero so salary equals zero.
That means that salary will equal to $30000 when a person has no experience so soon somebody is fresh
from University and joins this company.
Most likely they will have a salary about $30000.
You know there will be some confidence intervals there but we won't go into that right now.
Just we can say that according to this model that person will be probably getting paid $3000.
Now what is be one big one is the slope of the line.
And so the steeper the line the more you get more money you get per extra year of experience.
Let's look at this.
In this particular example let's say somebody went from maybe four to five years experience right.
So then to understand how his salary increase you have to project this onto the line and then project
that onto the salary access and you can see that here for one of your experience the person will get
an extra ten thousand dollars on top of his salary.
So if the coefficient P1 is less than the slope will be less and that means the salary increase will
be less per every year of experience.
If the slope is greater then that means the experience will yield more increase in salary and that's
pretty much it.
That's how a simple in your regression works.
So the core goal here is that we're not just drawing a line theoretically that we can we came up with
some how we're actually using observations that we have to find the best fitting line and what is best
fitting line is we'll talk about that in the next tutorial