Joe's demographics segmentation What is it and what is it used for.
Let's imagine a scenario.
You're a data scientist working at a bank and this bank has lots and lots of customers and at some point
you decide to take a random sample.
All these customers and take a snapshot in that point in time meaning that you gather all the information
you can on these customers.
And we're talking about things like age gender how many products they have with your bank whether or
not they have a credit card.
How long they've been with your bank and things like that.
So as much information as you can and you attach it to their records.
In this case for simplicity we're going to track two things.
The first thing is gender as you can see here.
And the second thing is their favorite color now tracking the favorite color of a customer a bank might
not add a lot of value.
However this is just a representation for something for any other variable.
It's just for simplicity sake in this specific example.
And then what you do is you track these customers for the next six months and six months on the track
.
You look back and assess which of these customers left your bank and which of these customers stayed
So my question to you here is do you think that this information would be helpful to you that you now
know that out of a sample which is quite a large sample let's say 10000 customers out of that sample
every single female whose favorite color is red.
Left your bank and everything.
And two thirds of the males whose favorite colors purple left bank and one third of the females whose
favorite color is green left her back.
So do you think that she could somehow apply this information in the foreseeable future to prevent other
customers from leaving the bank or as they call it churning from your bank.
And that is exactly what Joe demographic segmentation is what you would do going forward is you would
take another sample of your customers or even perhaps all of your customers.
And the first thing you would do is you would find out their gender which you know and their favorite
color.
Once you found out their favorite color based on your prior experience you can group them or segment
them.
And this is how you would segment them.
The first group on the right here is the group at highest risk of churning.
So these are females with the color red.
Based on what you know within six months they're probably all going to be gone.
Then the next group is the males whose hair color purple.
Also based on your experiment probably 60 percent of them will be gone within six months.
And then it's the females with their favorite color green.
30 percent of whom might be out of your bank in six months.
Then you've got a group over here who are kind of in between.
So their favorite colors match those that leave but then their genders don't.
So they might be addressed and might not you would give them a probability of living so a certain chance
a likelihood that they will leave and then you've got the orange and the blue who are definitely your
loyal customers and who are not going anywhere.
And so this knowledge and information will allow you to further preempt any kind of churn that might
occur and perhaps talk to these customers or give them a special offers or just something that will
prevent them from leaving.
So be really proactive in your approach and this is what's called Geo demographic segmentation because
you are taking into account factors like where these people live in what country or what region or what
postcode.
Then you take into account the demographics data.
So how affluent they are or what their income is how much they bank with you how many children they
have whether they're married or not whether their spouses have accounts with you as well.
So you don't know the future but based on certain similarities of these customers that you're investigating
right now to the customers that actually left.
You can put the new customers or the existing customers into groups and assess the likelihood of leaving
.
And this is what we're going to be doing in this section all in this section in the next section and
the section after that.
We're going to be creating a robust Joe demographic segmentation model using logistic regression because
this is one this is a zero in one situation right.
Yes No Did the person leave or did the person stay.
And so finally we're going to put everything together.
We're going to use logistic regression to create this incredible job demographic segmentation model
that will allow us to draw conclusions and predictions on who is most likely to leave our bank and who
is most likely to stay and then will be able to draw insights and give recommendations.
So that's how Joe demographic segmentation works.
And in the next tutorial we're going to start building this model