Welcome back to your ultimate data science course this is curial are a Manco as always and to day is
go time.
We are building our first Geo demographic segmentation model.
Hope you're excited about this because I'm super pumped.
And let's get straight into it.
So I'm going to open up Grettel and now I'm going to open our to set some minds on my desktop as usual
Mullings S. Joe demographic segmentation.
It's a CACP file so not the test data we're looking for that chern a modeling Dotsie as we open that
up.
Nope.
OK.
So here we've got a list of categorical variables.
We've got the surname which won't be using so we don't care about that.
Then we've got the geography which has three categories and we've got genda which has two carriers so
we need to take care of those right away and that's what we're going to do now.
We're going to create dummy variables for geography and gender.
So let's go add dummys gender and dummys geography.
OK.
Hope you're following along.
So we're going to recode these now added attributes.
France I'm going to go to France next.
Spain and Germany.
So we just basically changing the names so that it's easier for us to navigate.
Now they have proper names and gender same thing added attributes female and male.
OK good.
So that took us about a minute.
Now we want to run our model as you can see there's so many variables.
It's going to be very exciting.
All right.
Model limited logit binary.
OK so now let's take our exited variable.
That's the variable that we're trying to model.
We're trying to predict if a person is going to exit or not.
So that's how dependent variable I will set as default because we're going to be running a lot of these
models.
Now as you remember we the bank had a snapshot of 10000 people at a certain point in time and then it
watched which one of them.
Which ones of them exited and which ones stayed.
So that's why exit as our dependent variable.
Now let's look at the other variables that we want in our regressors.
So row number doesn't affect whether a person exits or not.
Customer ID same thing surname same thing.
So those are obvious obviously not going to be a normal credit score that could be a regressive credit
score could affect or could be associated so the effect is probably not the right word when you're talking
about logistic regression because there is no actual causation.
What we're talking about here is a sociate Association.
Is his credit score associated with people exiting and that's important to understand that his other
credit score makes them leave.
It's the people that leave.
Do they have a certain type of credit score or can we describe them by looking at their credit score
and say for instance people of high credit scores are more likely to leave than people with low credit
score so that's sort effect that's association.
But sometimes you'll hear me say effect.
Just think of association when you're talking about logistic regression.
In any case so credit score geography and gender.
We won't be using these two because we've created dummy variables which are at the bottom and we'll
get to them in a second.
Age age could affect or age could be associated with people leaving or staying with the bank.
Good tenure.
So how long has the person been of the bank because they are a loyal customer or is this somebody who
just joined the bank recently.
That probably could also determine whether a person is going to leave or not balance.
So how much money does a person now the bank how affluent is he or she number of products how many products
does this person have if a bank a very good one it's its stickiness.
It's what share of the wallet does the bank have does the bank have a does the person have a mortgage
loan with the bank.
Does a person have a credit card does a person have an a savings account.
How many of these products or more products as you can imagine the more pros you have the harder it
is for you to leave the bank.
So we'll put that in.
Has a credit card or not.
That's a that's kind of a subset of number of products so this is a one a yes no variable but it's already
been coded for us by the kindly by the I.T. department into a one in a zero so we don't have to create
dummy variables because it is already in essence a dummy variable and does a person have a credit card
of the bank or not does that.
Is that associated with them leaving.
Can that help us classify the people.
So put that in as well.
He's an active member so active member is an interesting one.
Different companies define that differently.
And it's also good metric to have for any company because it kind of tracks how frequently your customers
engage with you and what they do on the Web site what they do with all of your services and so on.
So in this case it could be that has the person logged into online banking in the past month or it could
be has the person made a transaction in the past three months.
So it's a time frame and a certain action that you're looking for in that time frame and that way you
classify every person as an active or inactive member and in this case we won't go into detail what
exactly this means.
We were actually just given this variable and that's the beauty of logistic regression you can throw
it in.
You can see if it actually affects your logistic regression then you can when you're reporting then
you can dive deeper into what exactly it means and maybe you should adjust the definition so put it
in estimated salary based on the person's balance and age perhaps maybe industry they work in the bank
is able to estimate the salary of the person and provide us this information.
So let's put that in has the person is it or not that's a dependent variable.
So we're not going to touch that.
Now in terms of gender we have to select a baseline.
So the variable that we don't include in here will be the baseline.
And I suggest we select male as a baseline and see and see just insert the female dummy variable into
the regressors.
That way whenever female is 0 it's implied that it's male persons male if the verbal female is one.
That means that the person is female and four countries will select France as a baseline and will put
the other two into the regressors.
So you are welcome and free to choose your baseline here with dummy variables.
However if you want to see exactly the same values and the same coefficients as you will see in this
video then I suggest that you select the same baseline sose put female Spain and Germany into regressors
and leave out male and France.
Once again whatever you choose won't affect the ultimate final result so you're scoring and how you
know the model works and so on.
This is just dummy variables but for the sake of training you could you could copy what I'm doing.
So I'm going to put a show p values here because we don't want slopes of Minu on p values and I'll click
OK.
Whoa that was nerve racking wasn't it.
Our very first Joujou a graphic first iteration of our very first demographic segmentation model.
So here we've got all of variables are independent variables are p values.
We've got some stats on the morals some confusion matrix.
So this is all exciting.
We've got a lot of variables here and we won't go through the coefficients right now because we still
have to build them all right now they don't mean much because some of these variables will be eliminated
through our backward elimination process and we will commence the backward elimination in the next tutorial
.
I will show you exactly step by step how to do everything and how to track your changes there's going
to be lots of steps.
This is the real deal.
We're building this thing.
I look forward to seeing you next time