Ordinary least squares in the previous tutorial talked about the linear regression being a trend line
that best fits your data.
Today we'll find out how to find the best fitting like or in fact how simple the new regression finds
that line for you.
So here's our simple in your aggression the same chart salary versus experience.
We've got these red dots which represent the actual observations that we have in our data and we've
got the trend line which represents the best fitting line or the simple linear regression model.
So now let's draw some vertical lines from the actual observations to the model.
And let's look at one of the specific examples to understand what we're talking about here.
So here you can see that the Red Cross is where that person is sitting at in terms of salary so let's
say this person with five 10 years of experience is earning $100000.
Well the model line.
So the blackline at the bottom it actually tells us where that person should be sitting according to
the model in terms of salary.
And according to our model should be a bit lower it should be somewhere where that Green Cross is which
is about maybe let's say $8000.
So now the Red Cross is called Why are you so why if the subscript.
And that is the actual duration the Green Cross is called Why I hat and that is the modeled observational
.
The modeled value So basically with those that level of experience where would he be.
Where does the model predict that earning.
And so the green line therefore is the difference between what he's actually earning and what he should
be earning.
So on what should be what he's modeled to be earning.
So therefore the green line will be the same regardless of what dependent variable you have whether
it's salary whether it's grade school whatever.
So it's the difference between the observed and the modeled for that level of independent variable.
Now to get this best fit in line what is done is you take the sum you take each one of those green lines
are those distances you square them and then you take some of those squares.
Once you have the sum of the squares for you got to find the minimum.
So basically what a simple linear regression does is it draws lots and lots and lots of these lines
.
These trend lines all this is like a simplistic way of imagining the linear regression draws all these
all possible trendlines 3.0 and counts the sum of those squares every single time.
And its recall records are somewhere in a temporary you know for file or something like that.
And then it finds the minimum one so it looks for the minimum sum of squares and finds a line which
has the smallest sum of squares possible.
And that line will be the best fitting line and that is called the ordinary least squares method.
So that's how the simple linear regression works out for you on the next tutorial.