Or write course pathways exciting tutorial ahead as you will see this course consists of four major
parts results for data mining modeling daughter prep and communication and presentation.
And you can combine these molecules into your own learning program.
The thing is that this course has over 200 lectures and over 20 hours of content and of course it's
very beneficial to go through everything.
However you might want to go through it in different order or something might be an urgent requirement
for you right now and you want to address that.
So let's have a look at some of the template pathways that you can create using these building blocks
.
We're going to put the pathways on the right over here.
And the first and most obvious pathway is the independent one where you can take any of these modules
by itself and the course is structured in such a way that these modules are completely independent so
you don't have to worry about missing out on some lectures that might be required in the model that
you're taking.
You can simply start the module and you will safely get to the end without having to worry about a thing
.
So if you have a pressing need to get into one of these topics right away Feel free to do that.
You will be able to get to the knowledge you need very quickly.
Number two the full monty.
You just basically go through those full course as it's laid out and you'll go from visualization for
data mining to modeling to data prep to communication presentation.
Now the Course is structured in exactly this way because this is the most fun and engaging way to discover
these topics.
Option 3 is the sequential option where you take these modules in the sequence that they would come
in a data science project so you basically start of data prep then you move onto his position for data
mining then to modeling then to communication presentation.
Now I had the idea of putting data prep at the very start of the course but I realized that this is
the most tedious task and it does take the longest in any given day Innocence Project.
So it would be a major turnoff to put it at the start of the course because it's not the most fun part
of data science.
So therefore we first go through viz. and then through modeling and then we go to Dapra when we already
know what why we're sacrificing so much time what the end result of our data prep will be.
However having said that if you feel that you would like to sort of data prep please feel free and go
ahead and do that.
Just be warned that data prep will take quite a long time.
It's the biggest module of this course.
Number for the Explorer here you start viz. for data mining and then you proceed directly to communication
and presentation.
The prerequisite here is that you have to be sure that Eudora is clean and it's ready to be analyzed
and also through this pathway you won't be creating any models or forecasts.
So basically you'll be skipping the part where you create a long term solution for the problem that
you've identified.
Nevertheless these insights will be very agile and you'll be able to communicate them properly to the
key decision makers and take it from there.
Partho m. 5 is called the modeler.
So this pathway is for people who are tasked in their daily jobs to create models and deploy them.
So once you already have knowledge of what goes into the model for instance you might be working a bank
and you're in know how your credit scoring model works.
So all you need to do is prepare the data load into a database and then build the model for that credit
scoring system so you don't need to do any investigations.
You don't need to communicate it later on.
You just need to build it and deploy it and then maintain it assess it and see how it goes in a year
or so and deploy the next one and so on.
And that's that is quite a frequent type of role.
And this might be very useful to some people.
Number six the senior.
So here I mean senior data scientist and basically these are the lucky people that have somebody else
doing their data prep for them.
And of course you have to trust these people and rely on them.
But if you're sure that your daughter prep has been done and your daughter is clean then you can totally
skip the data prep part and just do the fun bits which is the visualization for data mining modeling
and communication and presentation.
And finally number seven reporting services.
So I've done quite a lot of work of reporting services or business intelligence units of organizations
and I've seen what the work they do and it really fits in well with what we discuss in these two parts
.
So if you in your role are the data custodian in the organization or you work closely with the data
custodian you find yourself creating reports and preparing the data to be stored in warehouses and working
with sequel and Microsoft Visual Studio and essays and things like that.
Then you might be interested in this pathway because here we totally talk exactly about that how to
store the data how to clean and how to prepare it and also then you can move on straight to the communication
.
So basically this pathway doesn't imply any kind of analysis or data mining or modeling is just getting
the data putting it into the right place and then presenting it to the right people.
So those are the pathways for this course.
Once again this is not an exhaustive list.
You can come up with your own totally unique pathway that will suit your needs but otherwise I hope
you enjoy the course.
And I look forward to seeing you within these modules.
And until next time happy analyzing