And the person you're always talking about odds and how they're linked to probability.
And today we're finally going to get to the bottom of this challenge with the coefficient of logistic
regression.
I got to warn you right now it's going to be a math heavy to Tauriel.
So you have been warned let's proceed with care.
Last I waited on the operability when to lose all odds because probability divided by one mile per billion
.
Basically this is the form that links your odds ratio to your pribumi So when you hear people say the
odds of this team winning are ten to one.
Now you know how to convert that to probability.
Basically use this formula.
Well this one actually converts pre-built into into his odds ratio.
But we also looked at the other equation that works in the opposite direction.
So we'll be using this equation.
And let's quickly transform it into this one.
So from now on when we say odds we mean when to lose odds All right.
Now do you remember this from way back when we were talking about logistic regression how probability
is linked to an independent variable x in this case.
Well do you remember the equation that actually describes this curve.
There it is.
I'll remind you there that's a question.
It's a logarithm of a p divided by one minus be equals bizzarro Plus the 1 x.
So this is in the case of a simple logistic regression and this put the two equations side by side.
So this is the one we the green ones the one we've talked about we talked about a long time ago when
we were just introducing a logistic regression and the one on the right is the new equation that we
now know for the odds ratio.
Geez.
Notice any similarities here like on the left on the right there.
The ratio is actually the same one.
So what we can do is take the Pido out but one must be and plug it into the first equation as ords.
And that in that way will get this equation.
So this is ligand logarithm of awes equals to be 0 plus 1 x.
It actually has a special name log on.
So that part on the left is called log odds.
And then just for reference we're worried we won't be talking about log orders at all.
We will be focusing on odds because that's what we want to get to the bottom of.
Now this equation is exactly the same for a multiple logistic regression or just the logistic regression
in general so that's what our geo demographic segmentation would look like in terms of odds.
Now what we can do with this equation is do a mathematical operation it's called taking exponent of
it.
So we'll take the exponent of both sides of the equation which will give us this.
So each of the power of LUGG natural logarithm of AWS equals each the power of that whole right part
.
Now the left part of the equation is very simple.
Each of the power of the natural logarithm of anything equals that anything which is in the brackets
.
So basically Odd's the right side can be broken down by replacing addition in the power of the exponent
with multiplications of the exponent itself.
And this brings us to this equation.
So this a very nice and fluffy equation to work with.
What are we going to explore is one individual in different variables.
So let's just take any random What are we here let it be be one x 1 and let's look at it separately
.
Now what will happen.
And this is what we're actually interested in this is what we want to find out what will happen if instead
of if we hold everything else constant but we increase X one by one unit of that variable what will
happen to the odds what will happen to this whole equation.
Well as you can see here on the right if we take each of the power of be 1 times X one plus one that
is actually equal to each of the power of B1 X1 times each of the power of the one.
Now here you can notice that each of the power of BE1 X1 is that part of the equation as it was before
we increased X one by one unit.
So the new part is this part over here.
Each of the power of big one.
That is what happens the orders they get multiplied by a factor of each will be one.
And this is the part where you shot Erica.
We got it.
This is what we were after.
Now let's put this in writing so that we definitely remember what we just found out.
You know how I don't like putting too much text on my slides but this time is an exception.
More important conclusion and we'll get to write it out increasing an independent variable x i.
So any any independent variable x by one unit will increase the odds by a multiplicative factor of each
of the power of PIII.
So that's exactly what we talked about here that if you increase X one by one unit then your odds will
actually get multiplied by E to the power of the coefficients of x1 which is be one very very important
conclusion.
Very very insightful.
And don't forget we're not talking about probability.
We're talking about odds here.
So the odds that we discussed in the previous tutorial.
So now let's look at an example.
This is our model from previously the world we built for our judgment graphics segmentation.
And here we've got a variable called age.
Let's look at what happens when we increase age by 1.
So our Asper our conclusion the odds will increase by each of the power of the age b age is the coefficient
of age here.
So that means each other of 0.07 2 6 5 0 and that equals to 1 0 7 5 or so.
This means that whenever you increase age by one year.
So if you take two people and hold everything else constant all of the other variables credit score
number of products is active meme members the gender the country the tenure and the longer their balance
you can hold those other variables constant.
But one of those people is older by one year than the other then the older person their odds of leaving
the bank increase by 1 point 0 7 5.
So they get multiplied by this factor of point 0 7 5.
So what does that give us that gives us two things.
First of all we now know as as actually we did previously that if you increase age the odds will increase
meaning that the probability will increase because remember that if you increase probability increases
if or decrease probability with Chris but the second the more important thing is that now we have a
quantifiable metric to tell by how much exactly the odds will increase.
How many times what's the multiplicative factor.
And that is very powerful because it will allow us to compare the different independent variables and
their contribution to this model and we'll do that we'll start doing that in the next tutorial.
And I think 14 next time.
Until then happy analyzing