All right.
So our data is imported and now we're going to run our very first linear regression model.
Hope you're excited about this.
Let's get straight into it.
So in Grettel we need to click this menu up at the top model and then we'll just select the ordinary
least squares which is our simple linear regression.
So here we're going to take a salary and we're going to put it into the dependent variable because that's
the variable that we want to predict.
And years of experience we want to put it into the regressors.
So that's going to be the independent variable and we want to see what is the relationship between salary
and experience.
And also here you see that there is a variable here by default which Grinnel puts and therefore is constant
.
It's always going to be there by default and we're going to leave it in there as well.
Okay so we're going to click OK now and voila.
This is the magic screen.
So if you have not seen this before then you should start getting used to it because depending on how
you structure data says carrier you will either see this a lot and all the time or you might see it
occasionally infrequently but you will still eventually have to deal with this report.
And this is actually the result of running your model and this report will be exactly the same wherever
you run your regression whether it's an SAS SPSS are python anywhere.
Their report will look like this.
So let's learn how to read this report and let's learn how to extract the valuable data that we need
.
So at the top you've got the observations that were used the type of regression.
So ordinarily squares in this case then you've got the dependent variable name.
It was salary next.
There's two parts to this part.
And then this part this part is a breakdown of information of statistics per independent variable.
Right now we only have two independent variables so the constant which is actually a variable is just
just a constant and then we've got this independent variable.
Years of experience and then here you've got information which relates to the model overall.
So let's start with the first block.
What are we seeing here.
Well here you see the coefficients.
Those are the coefficients that we discussed in our formula and constant being twenty five thousand
seven hundred ninety two point two dollars means that the line of the linear regression crosses the
vertical axis at twenty five thousand seven hundred ninety two point two which means that if you have
zero years of experience so if this variable is 0 then according to this model your salary should be
twenty five thousand seven hundred ninety two dollars and 20 cents.
And then the coefficient for years of experience is nine thousand four hundred forty nine point ninety
six dollars.
What does that mean.
Well that means that for every one year increase in experience the salary goes up by 9000 $449 and 96
cents in the modeled world.
So not it doesn't necessarily happen like that in real life but from what we've modeled and we'll see
that in a second when we look at the graph.
This is the way things work in the model world with somebody who has three years of experience starts
with this salary and then for every year of experience the salary increases by so much.
And if it's a fraction of year your experience or if it's half a year then it'll be an increase of half
of that.
And that's all in line with the linear regression formula.
Then you've got the standard error here you've got the t ratio and you've got the p values for each
of your constant or variables in this section or in this part of the course will be folks of course
these are all important and it depends on what you're doing with your data science project you might
you might need to work with these.
But in this particular part of of course we're going to be talking about the P-value is mostly why well
that's because the p values allow us to understand the statistical significance of individual variables
and we will be focusing this on this quite a lot in the further sections of this part of the Course
because it will allow us to filter out variables that are not actually predicting anything.
So I'll give you an example here.
Right now the P-value is very very small so it's a one fourteen looks quite a lot.
But then you've got multiply this this over here is a scientific term for 10 to the power of minus 20
.
So that's you've got to multiply one point fourteen times ten to the power minus 20 which makes it a
very very small value tiny value.
And well that is a good thing the smaller the P-value the better.
That means that this variable actually predicts something.
So if you had a P-value which is great which is quite high for instance even higher than 0.05.
So in percentage terms higher than 5 percent that is already considered of a high P-value.
And what what it's saying is that when you change the independent variable it won't actually be associated
with any change in the dependent variable.
So you can only you got to pick and we'll talk about this further in this part of the course and the
modeling part of the course.
But you've got to pick a threshold for your P-value.
So for instance if you stick to 5 percent which is probably the most used p value or the conventional
P-value threshold then if your P-value is above 0.05.
So if here is above 0.05 and there's no multiplying by 10 to a very negative number then that means
that your p values about 5 percent and that means that the relationship between these two variable salary
and the years of experience isn't statistically significant.
And so basically your model in layman's terms it's not actually working so this variable is not predicting
anything.
So that's how you read this part of the report.
Let's move on to the second part.
So here you've got some stats about the model overall.
And the ones that will be focusing on in this course that are most important to us are the R-squared
way here and the adjusted R-squared.
And we've already spoken about these two parameters back in the previous section were talking about
refreshing our stats knowledge.
So we will see how we're going to be using them further in the course especially when we're building
our customer segmentation model further on