Right how did you go off that challenge.
Here's what I got Here's my result.
And as you can see the valleys very small so there is a statistically significant difference.
And today we're going to finish up with the chi squared and after today's tutorial we'll definitely
get back to the fun stuff.
There is Alsatians.
However we do need to discuss one more thing in terms of statistical significance and that is what to
do when you have more than two categories in your variable.
And let's get straight into it.
I've got we've got a variable here which is country right.
So how about we create a we start a statistical test for country.
So I'm going to copy this tab over here just as we did previously.
I'll rename it to country actuals.
And now I'm going to take a country where is the geography replace gender and let's make some room and
get rid of the label.
And there we go.
So we've got the actuals here.
So I'm going to show you two ways.
First I'm going to show you the proper way and then I'm going to show you my tricky quick way that I
like to use sometimes.
So to start off with the proper way you need to run a square test for a larger table you can't just
run it for two categories that you need to run and for all three categories.
And for that there's a different website which is B.
S S A R A stats dot net slash new CSIR HMO.
And what we can do here is input the values into here we don't even need the actual totals for each
category we just need the numbers in the blue and orange squares by the way there is a quick way to
look at this data as a table.
So if you just go to show me and you click table and then you transpose it and then you make some more
space then you pretty much have the table ready so that where you can make a mistake when you're copying
your values.
So let's zoom in on that.
And then we go for 4 8 10 1 6 9 5 8 1 4 and 2 0 6 4 4 1 3.
So calculate and this chi square test has been run for three categories now.
And as you can see there's the P-value it's very small.
And once again that means that there is a statistical significance meaning that when you go to the overall
population rather than look at sample when you go to the overall population you will also see an effect
similar to this you'll see that people who reside in Germany are more likely to leave the bank than
people who reside in Spain or France.
So that's how you should do it properly.
But as you can imagine as you get more categories it gets harder to put that table.
And moreover this specific tool only has a limitation of five by five right.
And you don't want to sit there and just input data all the time especially when you can see we can
already see that there is a difference.
You can see it here.
So why should you waste your valuable time and in put this dotted just to validate something you already
know.
You do need to validate.
But is there a quick away.
So I offer you my approach that I kind of like a lot and let's have a look at it in a visual manner
that'll make a lot of sense.
So here's our countries.
So France Germany and Spain.
Right.
What are we trying to do is compare these rates of living or these chances of people leaving the bank
for different geographies and what to say.
Is this a statistically significant results or will this result be the same for the overall population
.
Right now we're comparing all of them so we're saying is in general the country you reside in an important
variable.
So my suggestion here is why do we need compare all of them.
Why do we need to compare all three.
How do we just separate one of them like we forget about this part.
Forget about the popular or the people from the sample size that live in Spain and just compare France
Germany.
Right.
What if we find a significant difference there is between the two these two categories then that will
mean that overall there is a significant impact.
So basically we're saying that if Germany and Germany are leaving more have a higher chance of living
and people in France than by adding people from Spain it won't change it's still going to have a higher
chance of living than people in France.
Maybe something there will be a different relationship to people from Spain.
But we don't really care about that right now what we're saying is that there is a statistically significant
difference for this specific variable and we can extrapolate it onto the whole population.
And in a way what you the way you can confirm that this logic is true is.
Think of it as this is your test right.
You had people from France people from Germany and people from Spain participate in your test.
Now imagine you had decide designed your test differently imagine you had designed a test in a way that
you only looked at people from France and people from Germany.
You didn't look at people from France from Spain at all and you looked at exactly the same people.
So do you think the result would have changed.
Well obviously not because these people are not related in any way.
And that's that's how your test is constructed that there is no interdependencies so the decisions of
these people to leave or stay if the bank does not affected by the decisions of these people.
And so therefore you can totally separate your categories so you can if you have many categories within
one variable like here country you can take any subset of those categories and compare them between
each other using a chi squared test.
And that is totally totally fine.
So let's go back to our worksheet.
So here you can see that between Spain and France is probably not a significant difference right.
So why would you ever run a quick test between this and this right to prove something instead let's
run a quick test between France and Germany and prove that there is a similarly significant difference
between them.
And that will be sufficient for us to say that geography as a variable is an important variable.
It does play an important role in the decision of people to stay or leave the bank.
And that's my handy trick.
So that's our country of.
We've already done the test for country actually right.
So obviously if we run this test now for France and Germany we will also get a statistically significant
result and I'll leave that up to you if you'd like to check that.
That's totally fine.
The other thing I wanted to show you here is that if we all go to age you'll see that there's a lot
more categories here and would be a very painful exercise to run a quick test for all of them.
However you can use this as practice and pick out the categories where you think there is a statistically
significant difference.
I'll give you a hint.
Maybe a 50 and 55 or 25 and 35 something got any to that where you can see there's it looks like there's
a difference and just run a quick test for those two.
And that way you will have sufficient evidence to say that age is an important variable.
And so that's how we validate the insights that we derive from this visual improvisation of our statistical
tests.
As you can see it's not that hard.
And in combination those two methods complement each other you can quickly get insights using Tablo
.
And then where you do suspect a statistically significant difference you can quickly validate it using
a squared test and that's all for today's tutorial in the next one.
We'll get back to creating some more cool visuals and I'll look for see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing