My brainstorming method this is going to be like an insight into how I come up with the text for my
presentation.
So it might not work for everybody but this is how I call for presentations.
First of all I have a Dallasites project and I know like I came what I started where I finished right
so that's going to be my journey for the audience I want to show them.
I went from here to here.
And by audience once again we mean be a massive audience and be a small as can be when your manager
is talking to a manager.
So you went from here to here in order to convey this.
As we discussed previously you don't use minimal text don't put text on your slides your slides should
be assisting you not using your slides and put pictures.
So go through your journey mentally how did you get from here to here.
And remember like I think of the images that are the best portray that journey.
So you had different checkpoints that you went through.
What results did you have and find out the images that are best conveying those messages put them into
a presentation.
And after that the last thing to do is some of the text.
So how does a person call the text when you're putting in the images when you think about all of this
project.
You're very tense you've got all of this information in your head and you're trying to come over it
takes longer to work out.
It's going to be too technical or too detailed or too boring.
What you have to do is you have to relax.
That's why when I prepare my text I wait until the evening so when I'm really tired so after that I
know eight hours 10 hours of work I'm just sitting there and I just want to go home want to say but
then I forced to actually write out this text when I'm tired.
My brain switched off and I'm just riding like I would be talking to a normal human being.
It takes you down to that you know like just non-technical level so you can communicate to people better
or you wouldn't be.
You have to be in a state where you're not you're not endorsing the scene where you're just a normal
person so try to communicate your insides their When you're tired maybe you might want to have a glass
of wine in the evening or you know maybe just came back from the movies on the weekend or something
.
Like when your brain is not functioning in that super hyper alert state that it normally is when you're
at work.
And once you've got that you write down the text in the evening.
So really when you wake up in the morning then you look through it and then you you know take out some
where when you have too much text you take some of that out or you add some details some technical things
that you forgot to think of that night before.
Personated that's how I do it.
I that's the first draft.
And from there I take it forward and I rehearsed rehearsed like I recreate it.
I show it to a small audience practice audience and maybe your peers and so on just to make sure that
you know everything is going well.
So that's my tip to you in creating your presentation or your text or presentation.
Make sure you're not.
My advice is don't be too tense when you're creating.
Like be in a more normal kind of human being state when you can communicate properly.