So I was wondering if you had noticed a minor little detail that changes when we modify a proc So when
I right click the prok here and say modify there's one little thing that has changed compared to when
you actually created the proc for the first time.
And that thing or that little detail is that this word used to be create when it first created the prologue
.
This was create.
Now it's alter.
So I'll show you if I create a new proc here then the word is creates procedure so create has been replaced
by faulter.
So why's that.
Well that's because you cannot create the proc again.
You can only modify it.
There's already an object with this name in our database with the name of a b l d w r k office supplies
customer list so you can only alter so if I try putting create here and executing.
I'll get an error saying that the object already exists and on the other hand if I delete the object
so if I drop a delete here and then execute this script then everything goes fine and I refresh refresh
the objects is there if I try to execute again I get an error because you can create something that
already exists.
You can only alter it so just so that you know if you want to after you've created it to modify it you
type in the word alter here.
Or if you right click and slide modify that is already set up for you.
So the word alter is already present there.
And what we're doing here is we can change the code that is stored in the procedure we execute the script
and it'll be saved in our stored procedure so let's have a look at that.
If I want to select a star from another table for instance we are soaking from custom lists.
Let's look at transactional data.
And now I execute this proc.
So I've executed the proc and now I close it.
And now I open it up again you can see that this new table has been saved and if I want to run the body
of the proc and I highlight what I want to run I click execute.
I select two tables or I can select one table I can select the other table if I want to.
So you've have that freedom to do what you want inside.
But the code has been saved for us.
And so important a very important point here is that a lot of people when they start out with this blueprint
they confuse the two things or they don't separate them.
These are two completely separate things that you're doing.
One is running the code two is saving the proc by running the whole script.
So let me illustrate an example I want to change a proc again and let's say I want to select only the
city column from the customer list table.
Right so I've changed my code.
I'm happy it.
I've modified it and now I'm going to run it.
And I get the results and then I'm happy so I go and put this into my report.
I can I can tell the executives or whoever that now I know which cities the customers live in and so
on.
But then you know after a long day you have lots of tabs open up here and you know it's time to go home
.
So what do you do.
Just close the SQL Server.
OK maybe you don't maybe just want to close this tab so you close this tab.
Or would you want to save it.
Yeah I want to save it but then it offers you just saved this script as a text file or a scale file
on your hard drive.
You're not used to doing that you don't want to do that so you think oh actually I don't want to save
it.
That's right it's in approx it's stored over here so I'll just close it off and I won't so what happens
now if I open up my Proc. it hasn't been saved.
So the code inside doesn't mean say you change the code you put in a slick CD from this column from
this table you deleted that table and you ran it so you got the result you want but you forgot to or
the person forgot to save the proc itself.
So there are two separate things.
One thing is running the code here.
So let's select let's look city again one is running the code here so if I highlight and run that runs
the code for me and gives me a result that I want maybe creates a table maybe gives me a view of a table
or something like that.
But the other item that you need to remember about is running the whole proc.
So now if I just click execute without highlighting and you think I'll see a message commands completed
successfully and my proc has been updated.
So now if I close this window before saving and I open my proc mortified you can see that it has been
saved.
So make sure to separate those two things.
Another thing that I personally somehow got into the habit of doing is when I want to run the code I
saw a select this code and I run execute and when I want to save the proc I highlight this bit and I
run execute but I'm not going to do that.
Now all Actually I will but I won't close this when what happens is it will alter the proc So basically
I think the way I I got used to doing this is because here you have a command saying select and so you
can see where this blue highlights started from you can see it's starts at the command.
And I know that the command is to select.
It's not going to change a proc and then just so that I don't forget I highlight this and I see that
.
OK so the command here is alter proc So I remember that this is going to actually change my approach
So if I run this it will save the prog but there's one little issue.
So let's run that command.
So it's a complete successfully.
I'm not going to close this when I'm just going to modify the proc again.
Here you can see that what happened is only this part got saved.
The part above the Commons didn't get saved and I don't really like that I don't like that they get
lost.
So what I'm going to suggest for you is before you get your you know to use to this template let's change
it up a little bit.
So let's do it.
How will I personally prefer doing it.
And this is my recommendation to take this common section and drag it under the alter proc section.
So now you have all this preparation which always is going to be there.
That's not a problem.
But now you're going to keep your comments under the alter proc header so it's inside your proc.
And so now if you ever want to run your contents of your proc so your body then you highlight this bit
and you execute you get your result if you want to save your proc you can run the whole script just
by not highlighting anything like as a kid.
But if you want to be like me and you want to be very specific so that in your you're visually you remember
that you did save the proc then you highlight this and you click execute.
And now if I if I can close this even not a problem if I open it up it's still there so the comments
are saved and that's important.
Important.
Have these columns because my how important for mission.
And so that is the two differences or the difference between saving your proc and running the body of
the proc completely separate things you from Excel you're very or from other programs are very used
to.
Everybody's used to clicking the save button and saving the file in working with prox it's not done
like that.
You have to save the proc by highlighting this bit or running the whole script.
And then if you want to run the proxy run what's inside the body.
And so just to finish off everybody if one day you make this mistake you don't save a problem after
working on it for a long time.
It happens it's not it's it's not something that you can be immune to it's everybody goes through one
or two of those cases.
I remember my idea a couple of times I create a huge like or modified a huge model with thousands of
lines of code and you know after a very long day you just just completely forgot to save the proc.
And I just had the result the next day I just had the result of the model but I didn't have the model
itself and it's pretty hectic when you get into those situations you have to reprogram everything from
scratch and make sure the results match up so try not to get into those situations get into the habit
of saving your prox before you close Asgill match server management studio.