The art of saying no this is going to be a fun one.
This is one of my very topic.
So no is your favorite work from now on you know how this movie.
Yes.
And as a scientist eventually you will become the No man.
And that is why is that.
Well that is because a lot of people will come to you as you get better as people in the organization
talk about you more as you deliver more value and change people's day to day role and make them more
efficient and easier.
People will come to people walk to you.
They will want your help.
They will all still beg for you to help them on their projects and you'll just have too much requests
too many requests you won't have the time to fulfill them.
And you got to know how to say no.
Now there's two parts to this.
First one is when Hardage is a project that you want to work on.
And second one is how do you actually say no.
So we get started with the first one.
How do you choose the projects that you are working on.
Some of them might be interesting some of them might be less interesting.
But the ultimate decision criteria for you should be the business value that you drive.
So you have to assess a project based on what will the outcome mean for the business how much value
add and will this project deliver.
And compare that across all the options that you have heard in front of you and select the one that
you had the most business.
So don't think about things like Who is your best friend or which of these projects is the most interesting
one to work on.
Ultimately you are doing a service for your business and you want to deliver the most value.
Now how do you measure value.
It's completely up to you.
So it might be in dollar terms in my customer experience.
It might be in efficiency.
Maybe I don't know how you measure value in your particular organization or in your particular situation
but once you've established that find the project will deliver the most value and plus that will be
a great aid for you when you're explaining to other people why you're not taking on their.
Which leads us nice segue to part 2.
How do you say no.
Well first of all you've got to explain to people you've got to set their expectations right away you
don't say yes never say yes right away.
Once you have an idea for a project you say I will think about it I'll get back to you within 48 hours
or something like that.
And then you assess them and you explain to people that I will select the project and I'll be working
on.
If you have this autonomy or you have to talk to your manager first.
You will have a say in any case even if you have to talk to your manager and assess what project he'll
take on with them together.
You still have a say in what you'll be working on.
And you've got to explain to people that you will be working on the project that drives the most knowledge
of business.
And of course people understand that they won't understand if you choose the project that's the most
interesting for you or they won't understand the future of the project that is your best friend's idea
or you know your buddies idea.
You got to if you choose the one that drives the most value.
You're able to explain to people that that project drives the most value to the business then they will
understand you'll be on your side.
So that's like one tip on how to say no you've got to explain why you're selecting a different project
and why you'll be working on that and not on their project.
And the other thing like the other idea I like can convey here and something that I do is don't position
yourself from the very start don't position yourself as a data chief like like somebody or the analyst
that just crunches numbers and you know doesn't drive value for business.
Just somebody that basically just sits and crunches numbers don't position yourself that way like that
you will get lots of requests and people will have expectations that you'll perform the position yourself
as a consultant as an advisor as a data science adviser to people so when they come to you even though
that you cannot work on their product and you explain to them that unfortunately I can take up your
project because there are other things that are more important for the business at this stage.
However I believe that what you're doing is very valuable.
And here are some tips on how you can use data perhaps assist yourself more.
You know like self-help give them some ideas for self-help in terms of the I've done this lots of times
and this is much better than telling people no and giving an empty hand.
Give them like do something do a bit of research spend half an hour research what they're asking for
maybe or find some online hacks that have already been created that will help them maybe you'll find
a tool that you can guide them.
Tell them about and will guide them in the right direction.
Maybe this work has really been done in the business and they don't have to reinvent the wheel and you
can also direct them that way.
So give them some level of advice so that from there they will perceive you rather than as a person
who says yes or no they'll perceive you as a person who might say yes if they like it or if he can take
up the project we'll give some valuable feedback valuable insights valuable you know dot advice and
plus will benefit you as well in the long run because you will get exposure to different parts of your
business even if the products you will know how it works you'll know intrinsically what does exist and
how you can combine it together to actually deliver value when the time comes.
So that's my advice to you on how to say no and how to pick your product