S..
Recap.
So what did we learn in this rather intense section and this section learnt.
Our number one ranking dimension so we saw how our model has provided a new dimension which we can use
to look at our customers that dimension is their ranking in the model their probability to leave the
bank or us an action.
And that allows us to drive additional insights or see customers create deciles Corel's and so on to
better service our customers.
Number two how to draw insights from the cumulative accuracy profile and specifically we looked at two
types of insights.
Number one if you have a budget constraint What do you do how do you find out the people you contact
and how do you talk to the manager of the department that's contacting these people.
How can you say exactly what's the return on investment will be for that budget.
And two is efficiency so sometimes you don't actually need to contact everybody to get a good and efficient
outcome.
So basically you can save a lot of money or maybe focus on other things and deliver a better customer
experience because you're not bothering people with too much e-mails or contacts.
And by the way just to clarify we are talking in terms of customers and a customer and American Grafix
condition.
But as I mentioned a couple times throughout this part of the course all of these principles are also
applicable in other industries where there is a factory that addition to the brushes or it's a fraud
investigation engagement anything.
So just basically replace your independent depende verbals with the correct observations that you are
interested in.
All correct effects that you're looking for and you'll get to basically the same result their numbers
after all right.
So it doesn't matter what form they take it matters how we deal with them and what insights we're able
to produce.
So just keep that in mind that it doesn't have to be a cosmic joke.
Joe demographic segmentation model and number three odds ratio.
So this was one of the advanced topics this is where they started.
We talked about the odds ratio and how it links to probability.
Then we talked about how you can actually interpret the coefficients of logistic regression.
It's not as direct and straightforward as in a multiple their regression that's why these topics were
it was because we had to go into a bit of math.
But we did find out how a 1 unit increase and in an independent variable over logistic regression actually
translates into a change of the odds ratio for the probability of the event occurring.
And Number 5 we looked at the practical application.
So I give you an example of how I would go about presenting my findings in a logistic regression to
a manager or to an executive of the company and how to really visually portray your findings using a
heat map.
So that's all for this section.
Hope you enjoyed it.
Hope you had fun and learned some valuable knowledge here.
And I look forward to see you in the next section of the Course.
Until then happy analyzing