Welcome back to the ultimate data science course and I am super excited about today.
I've got an incredible tutorial prepared for you I'm going to cover off a very important topic and that
is how to build models step by step.
I couldn't hold myself.
I had to add that extra line step by step to the name of the tutorial because that is exactly what we're
going to be looking at.
I'm going to give you a framework for several different methods and it's all going to be step by step
.
So let's jump straight into it.
Do you remember the good old days when we had one dependent variable and one independent variable.
Everything was easy and we just had a simple linear regression that we had to build.
And everything worked great.
But now in our Datto we have all these columns.
Those easy days are gone now all of these columns are potential predictors for our dependent variable
and there's just so many of them and we need to decide which ones we want to keep and which ones we
want to throw out and you'll ask why do we need to throw out columns or do we need to get rid of data
why can we just use everything in our model.
Well I can think of two reasons of the top of my head.
Number one is garbage in garbage out.
If you throw in a lot of stuff in your model then your model will not be a good model it won't be reliable
it won't be doing what it's supposed to be doing.
It's going to be a.
So to speak garbage model and number two at the end of the day you're going to have to explain these
variables and understand the not just the math behind them but actually what it means that certain variables
predict the behavior of your dependent variable and you will have to explain that to your executives
to your boss to people you're presenting to.
So if you have a thousand variables is not going to be practical to try and explain that so you want
to keep only the very important ones the ones that actually predict something.
So how do we construct a model.
This is the process of building the model selecting the right variables.
Well there are five methods that we're going to discuss of building models.
Number one is all in the Mattew is backward elimination.
Number three is forward selection.
And before is bi directional an elimination.
And number five is score comparison.
We're going to talk about each one of them just now before we do I wanted to say that sometimes you'll
hear stepwise regression so stepwise regression actually refers to number two three and four because
those are really the true step by step methods.
But sometimes you will hear people say stepwise or stepwise regression in reference to just not before
so there will replays be bidirectional elimination of stepwise regression and that's fine that's that's
normal that's just because that's the more as you'll see from what we discussed by directional admonition
is kind of the more general approach.
And when people say stepwise regression they kind of by default infer imply imply that is bidirectional
illumination and you have to infer it from there.
OK so let's move on to our methods.
Method number one all in.
It's not a technical term I just call it all in basically what it means is just throw in all your variables
.
Something we just discussed the Russian too.
When would you do that.
One is if you have prior knowledge if you know that these exact variables are the ones are your true
predictors you don't have to build anything you already know that this is the case.
You might know it from domain knowledge or you might know it because you've done this model before somebody
just gave you these variables and said please build a model.
Well then you don't really have a choice.
You just build the model that the one is you have to perhaps like.
I can't really think of good examples here but maybe there is some framework in your company that says
that you have to use these variables right.
So it's kind of similar to prior knowledge but it's not a it's not a it's not your decision it's you
might want to do it differently but there is a framework you know like maybe a bank.
And to predict credit like or the likelihood of somebody defaulting on something they have to use these
variables.
Once again I'm not sure in which industries that would be the case but perhaps that could be the case
.
And number three you would use this method if you're preparing for a backward elimination type of construction
of regression which is our next type.
So let's move onto backward elimination.
Okay so here comes a step by step stuff you might you might want to get your pens out and write these
things down because we're going to have here truly step by step method now.
All right.
Backward elimination first thing.
Step one you have to select a significance level to stay in the model.
So by default we're going to go with 5 percent so 0.05.
And we're going to use it in the next step so it's at the beginning you decide on this significance
level.
Step 2 you fit the full model of all possible predicter So you kind of do that all in approach which
we just talked about and you put all of your variables into your model and now we're going to start
getting rid of them.
Step three you considered the predicter with the highest P-value.
So remember those P-value that we talked about in for instance in Grettel or in any software or you
can see them.
So after you fitted the model you'll see the one with the highest P value.
So if p is greater than your significance level then you go to Step 4 and Step 4 is you have to remove
that predict to remove basically the variable that has the highest P value.
And from Step 4 you fit the model before this variable so there's a star here because I just wanted
to remind myself to tell you that if you just remove the variable obviously you can just say that.
OK now now I've got the new model you have to actually refit them all you have to re recreate them all
rebuild it with the fewer number of variables so if you had maybe I don't know a hundred variables and
you removed them one of them may have 99 now.
Well you have to rebuild it so the coefficients are going to be different.
The constant is going to be different.
And you you need to perform that step because once you remove a variable it affects all the other variables
in your whole regression.
And so after Step 5 you go back to Step 3.
Once again you look for the variable with the highest P-value in your new model.
You take it out you remove it.
So basically step 4 you remove it.
You fit the model again with one less variable and so on and you keep doing that until you come to a
point where the even the variable of the highest P value that p value is still less than your significance
level.
So if that condition P is greater than s.l is not correct then you don't just have 4 anymore.
You go to fin and this case ffin is the finish.
And your model is ready.
So as soon as all of the variables that you have left in your model are there p values are less than
the significance level.
Your models prepared.
So that's how the backward elimination method works.
Let's move on to the next one.
Next method is the forward selection.
This is it sounds like the opposite and the picture in the top right corner does illustrate the opposite
.
But it's a much more complex than just simply reversing the procedure.
You will see that it's a much larger procedure.
We start with step 1.
Select the significance level to enter the model.
And in this case once again we're going to select 5 percent.
Then we go to Step 2.
We fit all possible simple regression models.
So we take the dependent variable and we create a regression model with every single independent variable
that we have.
And then we select out of all those models we select the one which has the lowest p value for the independent
variable.
So you can already see that that is in itself a lot of work.
Then what we do is we move to step three.
We keep this variable that we've just chosen and we fit all other possible models with one extra predicter
added to the one we usually have.
So what does that mean.
That means we've selected a simple linear regression with one variable.
Now we need to construct all possible linear regressions with two variables where one of those two variables
is the one of various like.
So basically we add on all possible all of the other variables one by one so we choose OK let's add
on this variable and then let's add on the next one like.
But separately so we construct all possible 2 variable linear regressions and just keeping definitely
keeping the variable that we're very selected.
So what do we do after that.
Out of all of these possible two variable regressions we consider the one where the new variable that
we added had the lowest p value.
So if that p value is less than our significance level meaning that you know that variables a good one
it's a significant variable then we moved back to Step 3.
What does that mean.
Means that now we have a regression with two variables and now we will add a third variable We'll try
all possible variables that we have left as our third variable and then out of all of those models with
three variables we will go to Step 4 and we'll select again the one of the lowest p value for that third
variable.
We added.
And I'll keep doing that.
So basically we'll be keep growing the regression model but not just randomly we'll be actually selecting
out of the all all of the possible combinations every single time and growing at one variable at a time
.
And then we will only stop when the variable that we've added It has a p value that is greater than
our significance level.
So when this condition is less than SL is not true then we don't go to Step Three we finished the regression
y well because that variable that we just added is no longer is not significant anymore.
And we also know that we selected the one with the lowest P-value So there is no other variable that
we can add that its p value will be greater or will be less than s.l any any regression which is from
then onwards it will the Arab the new variable will always be insignificant.
And so here we finish the regression and the trick here is that you keep not the current model but the
previous one and that makes sense because you've just added a variable which is insignificant So what's
the point of that variable just move a step back.
So that's how forward selection works.
I know it's a bit confusing but just try to wrap your head around and maybe read through these instructions
one more time.
It does make a lot of sense when you and it's like kind of picture what is it exactly is going on.
And next we're moving on onto the bi directional limit elimination.
So this one as you can assume or perhaps guess it combines the two step one.
Select a significant level to stay or to enter and a significant level to stay.
So we're going to select in both cases 5 percent but it's up to you what you select set to perform the
next step of the forward selection meaning that's the one that we just discussed.
So where new variables when they enter in order to enter they have to be less than the significance
level to enter.
So basically add on a new variable based on the forward selection method.
Step 3 perform all of the steps of the backward elimination process.
So now if you have two variables start getting rid of them and see if you can get rid of any of them
and then move back to Step 2 so then grow it by another variable.
And every time you go by verbal say let's say you were at five variables and went to six since you went
to six you have to form all the steps of backward elimination so you don't just eliminate one variable
if you can eliminate one to three however many you can.
And then from there you go back to Step 2.
And so this is a very iterative process.
You keep doing that until at some point you cannot add new variables no variables can enter or no old
variables can exit as soon as you get there.
Then you proceed to the finish because your model is ready to call.
You can add anything you can take anything out that means you've you've created the model.
So this is one of the more tedious methods.
Of course you would have to get a computer to do this for you because otherwise you'd go insane putting
variables in and taking them out.
But that's how bidirectional elimination works.
And once again some people call it stepwise regression.
And finally all possible models.
So this is the most probably Saro approach but also the most resource consuming approach because you
select a criterion of goodness of fit for instance that caky criterion can be the R-squared lots of
different criterions then you construct all possible regression model.
So if you had and variables and all they'll be a two to the power of and minus one total combinations
of these variables and that that's exactly how many models there can possibly be and then step three
you select the one of these models with the best criterion that you're looking at.
There you go your model is ready.
So sounds easy but let's have a look an example even if you have 10 columns and a daughter you'll have
1023 models.
That's insane.
That's an insane amount of morals and we're not talking about columns that you've already filtered out
so call them that.
You know that's like in our example you might have five or six columns.
Now we're talking about when you get a data set that you you just is pretty much a rule and it has like
maybe 100 columns like I've worked with data sets were around that maybe 50 to 100 maybe more columns
and instead of going through them there's what this method is suggesting is that we're going through
them and picking out the ones that you think should be in the model.
You just throw everything in.
Well that's not a good approach because basically it's is growing exponentially the number of models
is growing exponentially.
And it's it's very resource consuming to get a result from this approach.
And finally so where how we come to we've come to our conclusion.
We have five methods of building model models all in backwords elimination for selection by directional
ammunition and the score comparison.
So the one we are going to be looking at in these tutorials in order to get our head around how to build
models step by step and get some practice is the backward elimination process because it is the fastest
one or all of them and you will still get to see exactly how the step by step method works.
And plus we'll throw in a few extra tricks along the way to make sure our models are very robust Can't wait
to get started.
Lots of theory.
Let's get to the practice.
Forcing in next time