In this tutorial we will continue dealing with our corrupt cxxviii File.
We're not we're not going to do any modifications to this slide because obviously we don't have this
data we don't know how to return it.
The only thing we can do is exclude it completely from our analysis and not uploaded and but we definitely
have to still keep it for our own records.
So I'll show you how to do that.
We're going to open up our folder again.
And then here in uploader daughter actually in uploader Darwood we need to do is we'll do that later
we'll delete this file.
Well we'll do that just now actually we first met you go to analysis and we need to create here a folder
which will call daughter anomalies or let's call a daughter errors same thing.
So here we want to create a folder we need to create a folder or we'll call it manually excluded results
and into this folder we want to copy just disrobe but not from our prepared file from the original file
.
So here we've got this copy of the original.
So what we're going to do is we're going to take everything out from here.
To take everything out all the way to the end.
Just make sure you don't delete anything in this row.
There we go.
And now we're going to take this row and we'll save it as manually extruder results.
And here we will say Fakenham original something like this so it's up to you how you name this because
these are anomalies and you never know what you come when you come across so row 81.
So there it is it's a very small one kilobyte.
That's that's our specific Rovere we want to look at it.
And now from our prepared data file We're going to go to row 81 this we can close this.
We're going to go to row 81 and we're going to this one.
That's it.
That's the one with the arrows and we're going to get rid of it.
So now we've got 80 82.
But we know that we've excluded this role from our analysis Roe 96.
Once again this 96 this row 96 we have fixed it up and there shouldn't be any problems with that rule
.
OK so that's that's that's the last thing that we need to have a look at.
Here is why is this column here.
Well this column is here is here because exactly of things like that when browes got shifted to the
right.
In Excel Excel didn't cut them off.
It created a new column for them.
And in a way we should thank Excel for that because otherwise we would have lost this data.
So we're not going to remove this column at all or anything.
We're going to upload our data and then we will look for more anomalies because these are the first
100 rows right.
That can be much more of these anomalies or doora discrepancy.
And by the way give you a hint there are there because I put them there because this is training and
we're going to have to find ways to deal with them along the way.
So this is how data upload works.
And to finish off today's tutorial we're going to cancel this because this upload failed we're going
to have to redo it.
Now we're going to go to our notepad.
Plus plus.
And we need to remember to save this file where we modified row number 96 so we made it work and we
deleted row number 81 So let's go ahead and save that.
This is the prepared daughter fake names.
Yes we were saving not good.
Close that.
And now we're going to go to our folder.
This is our excluded result.
Now we're going to go back to analysis fake names so here in the prepared data for that we don't need
this anymore we're just using that to compare and then to extract extract that Roe 81 which we excluded
from our analysis.
So we're just going to delete this and this fake name file We're going to copy it and we're going to
go to upload a daughter.
Still today's date.
So we want to get rid of this file because that's the one with the errors.
Now we're going to paste our file that we've corrected in here and we're not keeping the old one if
there is.
Because in your uploaded dotted folder in here you never want anything that wasn't actually uploaded
so you want only the things that got uploaded.
So there you go so that's the file in there.
Now if we create a new connection manager if you go to browse and you find this new file there it is
you put your delimiter in.
So now everything should be fine.
Scroll to the right and scroll down.
There's nothing in column 46 good so that's around 96.
Let's have a look at it for you scroll.
Here you can see.
Thank you great experience that's great.
It's working.
And then row 81.
It's not even here.
We've excluded from analysis.
So that's how you deal with errors like this.
One more thing to finish off.
You probably want to keep track of a rose that you've corrected manually so if you go back to this folder
here which is an analysis of errors manually exclude results so here you might want to create another
file and just say
adjusted row.
What is it 96.
And then here just say manually manually corrected the feedback field.
So just so you remember just in case.
So actually an excluded road so you might want to like create another folder here manually corrected
rows.
So get rid of that and put it in here.
So just you keep track of these things as well.
So that's it that's how daughter preparation works.
Once again this is just the first hundred.
Are we going to have to find a way to deal with the rest and I'll show you how to do that later in the
section.