Welcome back.
How did you go of the exercise with number of products.
It wasn't difficult was it.
Here is the result that I got.
And here you can see right away a couple things.
First of all there are a few anomalies.
So you would expect that as the number of products increases the customer is more likely to stay off
the bank.
So in in banking term I think is called stickiness or the share of the wallets of the customer so as
you know the bank has a greater share of the wallet.
It is harder for the customer to leave and that is what we're observing in the first two.
So people who have two products with the bank are less likely to exit than people have one product.
In fact as you can see we can see the labels here because the font is too big so why don't we just take
out the text label for now for our analysis and that way we'll see all of the labels.
So here you can see that only 8 percent of customers with two products left and 28 percent of customers
with one product left.
So there a massive drop.
It is much harder for these customers to leave.
But then we see an anomaly here so we see how the as yet more products are three and four products it
is customers are leaving at a rapid rate at a very very high rate 83 percent and 100 percent for products
which does not apply for intuition whatsoever.
So those are massive anomalies or very distinct anomalies and we need to understand what we can do about
them.
So the first thing that comes to mind and the first thing that you should always remember when you have
anomalies that great there might be something wrong with the data are not wrong with that it might be
it just might be a insignificant result.
That's that's what I'm looking for here.
It might be an insignificant result and therefore it might not be worth reporting what if there are
only five people that have for products or if if because this is a large sample it's 10000 people together
.
What if there's like only 100 people that had a 100 had for product and they all just happened to live
So it's kind of like a random effect rather than something that you can rely on.
And that is why we have to be cautious that these tests that we're doing they're not statistically fully
fledged test full fledged statistical tests.
They're more ad hoc visual tests.
So in these cases we would need to check the actual number of people.
So now I'm going to show you how to do that.
And in order to check the number of people that left.
We'll talk more about this kind of approach or a more thorough approach on this in the next section
of the course.
But for now I'll just show you a quick way to do it so I'm going to take the number of records over
here and I'm going to drag a number of records into label just as a text so rather than doing a table
calculation I'm just dragging in as it is.
And so here you can see now we will just take out the table calculation for now because once again we
can see what's in there.
So here what you'll see is that these these two categories they have quite a lot of people in in these
categories but these categories they have fewer people in the category so there is only two hundred
and sixty six people in with three products is only 60 people with four products.
So that can possibly explain why we're seeing a tsunami it just happens that we.
The samples were randomly selected among them all the people that had for products they were very high
list of leaving and they actually did leave over the observed period of time.
So sometimes when things like this happen you have to investigate further and you have to conduct proper
statistical tests to make sure that these results are valid.
So in this case you can say that going from one product to products it's harder for people to live for
three or four products you would need to investigate this further.
So that's what I wanted to show you with this chart.
We will return it back to its previous state now.
And maybe you want to add a comment for yourself here so that in the future remember that there is some
investigation to do.
So you go and state and then you just select area for instance and here you want to say something like
low observations in a last two categories.
So just a label for Celso we're not going to go into the details of these investigations.
Our goal is to understand how to work with Tablo.
But nevertheless you want to have some information for the future.
So there you go.
I just added a label so whenever I go back to this chart I'll be able to see that there is a low number
observations in these categories and I need to do something about it.
So that's all for this chart.
What I wanted to show you today is how to validate your approach.
And in fact validate your daughter.
So let's go ahead and create another test.
I'm going to duplicate this one over here.
So duplicate sheet and this one will call validation and we can get rid of this comment.
So the idea here is to find a variable that you know for sure does not affect your end result.
So something that is definitely not a important variable in the choice of customers to stay if the bank
or exit the bank and a good variable here would be a number.
So like a digit one digit number.
So if say the customer My favorite is if the customers if you have four mobile phones and the data and
you can just take say the last digit of the mobile phone or in this case we have customer I.D. So let's
take the last digit of the customer I.D. as you can imagine it has nothing to do with whether or not
the customer of the bank it's not a predictor.
It doesn't matter what last digit in fact doesn't matter what customer I.D. you have at all in terms
of your decision for staying or leaving leaving the bank.
And so once we run the test for the laws the age of the customer I.D. We can then check that yes everything
is fine.
It has to be all of them all of the hostages have to have the same possibility of leaving.
So let's go ahead and check that we're going to Right-Click customer I.D. and we're going to create
a calculated field.
Haven't done one of these in a while have we.
So we're going to say run.
We're going to say last digit of customer I.D. And here we're just going to say right as in the last
character one and from here you can see that table calculations are correct.
That's because customer ID is still deemed as a number we need to change it to a string so we'll just
say SDR and we'll close the brackets.
So that looks good.
And now we have a new variable here last digit of customer I.D. as you can see is a calculated variable
and we can take this and replace number of products as we go ahead and do that.
And so right away you can see a beautiful very uniform picture here that approximately on average every
customer ID that you have or the last digit of the customer I.D. It has the same people that digit have
the same probability of living as average about 20 percent so plus or minus some fluctuations exist
always in your daughter.
But in this case it's plus or minus a little tiny bit which is insignificant.
So on average it's 20 percent.
So that's how you check your data another way you could do it.
You could look at the last or first letter of the customer surname but that is a bit more tricky because
lenders are generally less uniformly distributed they're not as randomly so you'll find that letters
like q are rarer letters like TR more frequent and that can affect your results so try to find something
that is uniformly distributed across your population or your sample.
And at the same time it does not affect the end outcome at all whatsoever and that will allow you to
validate two things.
First of all our approach.
Now we can see that our approach is valid because if it wasn't or if we did see some some skewness here
then maybe we would question our approach.
And also we can see that the data is there are no errors or issues with the data because let's say if
we saw that one or a couple of these is too high then that would mean that perhaps maybe there are some
problems with the data why is why is there this observation this anomaly that shouldn't be there.
And that's the end of this tutorial.
You can come up with other similar ways to validate your data and I encourage you to use them just to
make sure that along the way while you're doing your analysis everything is running smoothly.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing