In this tutorial I will show you how to install Microsoft business intelligence tools and this course
you'll be using a free package distributed by Microsoft.
Note that if you have Microsoft Visual Studio then skip to the last part of this tutorial and perform
the check to see if your Visual Studio has business intelligence tools integrated.
If so you're all set to go.
All right let's get on with installation.
To start off we will need a browser in Google type in s s d t be-I which stands for a sequel server
data tools business intelligence.
You need the Microsoft link here you can see that the latest version of the be-I tools is for Visual
Studio 2013.
I recommend going with that.
If you cannot find it and there is a later version available that should also work expand the system
requirements and make sure you have the right operating system and meet the hardware requirements.
Note that this distribution supports both 32 and 64 bit machines.
This will be important for us in an installation step further in this tutorial in the requisites.
You will see that these tools require Microsoft Visual Studio shell to run.
If we now expand the additional information section then you will see that this installation packet
actually contains Microsoft Visual Studio shell.
This is great and means that we won't have to install anything else to get the Beatles working.
Download the file.
This is a big file and may take some time to download.
Once the file has been downloaded you need to extract its contents.
This can take up to 10 minutes
after the extraction completes.
You will be presented with the following menu.
You will notice that it looks a lot like Asgill server installation menu.
But don't be worried you're not installing it asking all server all over again.
Select the top option newest kill server a standalone installation.
Microsoft will run some checks and finally you'll be presented with the installation type selection
menu.
Now this is the important step.
Logically you would press add features to an existing instance of a SQL Server 2014.
That seems like the right way to go because you have already installed as Ezekiel's Server Express.
However if you go down this path you will most likely get an error.
Further down in the installation the reason is that if you have a 64 bit machine then you installed
as he'll server for 64 bit machines whereas as we noted the business intelligence package we are installing
is designed differently.
It works with both 32 and 64 bit machines.
This difference in architecture will prevent you from combining the two.
The correct option here is perform a new installation read through the license agreement and accept
if you agree.
Under feature selection make sure that Asgill server data tools business intelligence and skill.
Client connectivity SDK are selected.
I cannot proceed with this solution because I already have the package on my computer.
We've done the bulk of the work default settings in the remaining steps of find so just click through
and start the installation after the installation has completed go to Start All Programs and find Microsoft
asking all server 20:14.
There you will find a purple icon named Ezekiel server data tools for Visual Studio 2013.
Right click the icon and create a shortcut on your desktop.
Here it is.
You can launch the program.
Great.
The program is launched and now we will test if the be-I tools are installed correctly.
Go to file new project and under business intelligence find integration services.
Notice the description on the right.
It says this project may be used for building high performance door integration and workforce solutions
including extraction transformation loading ITIL operations for data warehousing.
This is exactly what we need.
The tool is ready to go and we will learn how to use Sosias in one of the next sections in this course
.