Hi everyone.
My name is Wojciech Lesniak, and welcome to this course, Spring
Framework: Using Spring Security OAuth2 Login. OAuth2 and OpenID
Connect make it easy for your users to register and access your
application without providing their passwords.
That's powerful.
It can significantly improve user experience and make your
application more secure. In this course, we are going to implement
user authentication using OAuth2 OpenID Connect with Spring
Security OAuth2 login and Spring Boot.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include adding
social login to your existing application,
completely outsourcing authentication in your application to an
authorization server, persistent login and logout with OpenID
Connect, dealing with public clients.
By the end of this course,
you have the skills and knowledge of OAuth2 support in Spring
Security needed to secure modern day multi and single‑page
applications with OAuth2 and OpenID Connect.
Before beginning this course, you should be familiar with the Spring Framework.
I hope you will join me on this journey to learn OAuth2 login support
in Spring Security with the Spring Framework: Using Spring Security OAuth2 logging course, at Pluralsight.