Hi.
It's Wojciech Lesniak, and welcome to my course,
Spring Framework: Using Spring Security OAuth2 Login.
During this course, when I refer to OAuth,
I actually mean OAuth2 and not the first version of OAuth as the first
version is no longer relevant and is not widely used.
OAuth2 is an open standard used to allow entities like users to grant limited
access to their resources without sharing their credentials.
Now, let's unpack this.
Traditionally, as developers,
securing an application meant the application
prompting the user for their credentials,
like their username and password.
This, however,
no longer scales well. Just think of it from a user's perspective.
Let's introduce Victoria here. Now, she would need to maintain
separate credentials for each application she uses, at her work, in
her personal life, like social media,
etc., and best practices state that she should not reuse the same credentials.
But the more credentials that a user has to maintain,
the greater the probability that she will reuse the same ones.
Now we've all done that.
Now from a systems perspective, there's greater chances of failed login attempts,
password resets, and, hence, more support overhead,
not to mention her credentials and personal data being maintained in multiple
places, providing a larger attack surface for a hacker and making them as
secure as the weakest link. Now, OAuth can provide single sign‑in where
Victoria can authenticate with an identity provider,
which is known as an authorization in OAuth, and then be granted
access to all the applications she's authorized for. Same deal for the
Google apps she uses in her personal life.
Once authenticated with Google's authentication server,
she has access to all the Google apps like Gmail, Docs, etc.,
without having to maintain separate credentials for each application.
Now,
let's say Victoria also wants to access our demo application, CryptoPortfolio,
which will allow her to maintain the positions and the
value of her cryptocurrency holdings.
Now she could register and sign in with the application; however,
Victoria is not too keen on adding another set of
credentials she has to maintain.
Hence,
we could also offer her social login where she could be signed
into Google or Facebook and get access to her portfolio without
CryptoPortfolio having to handle, store, and maintain her data and credentials.
That way, if CryptoPortfolio gets hacked,
her data and credentials won't be on a list sold on the dark web.
Additionally, the crypto app might want to access her data in Google or Facebook,
such as her mailing list from her Gmail account so that it could email
her friends and invite them to join the application, or to get the
registration data, the application needs to automatically register her
without prompting her with an annoying registration form. Now in the
past, to achieve something similar,
apps would ask the user to provide their email provider credentials and
would then sign in on their behalf to retrieve the list.
Now this is a bad idea.
Firstly,
authentication now more and more is no longer just the username and password.
It's now at least also two‑factor authentication.
It also exposes the user's Facebook credentials to another application,
which,
if it needs to store them, at best that application could encrypt the password,
which is against best practices,
which requires the password to be stored as a hash. And this results in
more places the hacker can steal Victoria's credentials,
and it also broke the principle of least privilege.
CryptoPortfolio should only have access to the resources that
are necessary for its legitimate purpose.
Having access to the user's credentials will allow the
application to do anything on the user's account.
Now, fortunately, OAuth also provides a solution to this challenge,
and it allows you to place a bounded context around your
authentication authorization code credentials user data,
which will be isolated from the application code.
This is more secure as developers will release more changes
and features to an application's code,
then security changes; hence, any injection vulnerabilities introduced to the
application would not expose sensitive user credential data.
And also,
if you want to change the authentication strategy, like
adding two‑factor authentication, then you only have to do it in one place.
Next,
let's look at why you would want to use Spring Security to add OAuth to your application and how OAuth is supported within the framework.