OAuth is a very flexible framework.
Since its inception in 2012,
there have been many new RFCs published that add and remove functionality,
as well as recommendations and best practices on how to implement OAuth.
In fact, OAuth 2 is not even designed for authentication.
It's actually designed for delegated authorization.
Now,
you might find this strange as authentication seems to
be one of its most popular use cases,
but the OAuth 2 spec simply mentions authentication should happen,
but doesn't mention how.
That's up to you,
and you would have to create your own implementation on
top of OAuth to support authentication, like Facebook's Facebook Connect,
or you could use the OpenID Connect extension,
which adds authentication to OAuth 2.
This complexity is best summarized by the following maze diagram from Okta,
which as a developer, you would have to traverse.
The OAuth 2 group is actually trying to currently
address this with the OAuth 2.1 draft,
which is simply a consolidation of all these published changes and best
practices of OAuth 2 to simplify things for developers,
but as mentioned, it's still a draft.
Fortunately,
Spring Security can take care of a lot of this
complexity for you right out of the box.
So why reinvent the wheel?
When you use Spring Security,
you are joining a large community of security nerds with a
vested interest in keeping the framework up to date with
the latest security threats, trends, and best practices.
In the past, however, OAuth 2 support in Spring was a bit messy.
It was scattered between a number of projects.
If you look at the OAuth 2 feature matrix for Spring,
it was supported in Spring Boot OAuth 2, Spring Cloud Security,
Spring Security OAuth 2, and Spring Security 5.
You might have even heard of Spring Social in the past.
Now, this made things very confusing as to which one to use,
and it depended on your requirements, hence the Spring team have
decided to unify JWT, JOSE, OAuth 2, and OpenID Connect support under
Spring Security proper as of Spring Security 5,
which actually makes a lot of sense. Effectively,
it's a rewrite. Now, currently, there still isn't full feature parity,
but if you go through the matrix, you can see the gaps.
But the plan is to unify all the projects under one.
So if your feature is supported by Spring Security 5 and above,
then use it. The other projects under maintenance mode until
the features are migrated to Spring Security.
Okay, great.
Now, that's all the theory out of the way, so let's get started on implementing OAuth 2 in our demo application.