In the first interaction of the OAuth 2 Auth Code grant,
three parties are involved, the resource owner, clients,
and the authorization server.
Now they are all using the browser as an intermediary
to communicate between each other.
Now to see this in action, in your browser, select Inspect, Network
tab. Now this will show you all the browser traffic.
If you access the portfolio web page, use localhost in the filter are
to remove some of the noise. As you can see, Spring Security redirected
the browser to Facebook. This is the first part of the Auth Code grant,
when the client redirects the resource owner to the authorization
server for authentication. And this is the URL to Facebook's
authorization server.
Typically, you would need to preconfigure Spring Security with this URL,
but because we are using Spring Boot, we get the configuration for free. In
the CommonOAuth2Provider enum, you can see there's Google, Facebook,
GitHub, and Okta, all currently supported out of the box. And here is that
URL. Now if we were using some other provider that's not in this enum, then
we would have had to provide this detail to Spring. Now there are a number
of key parameters like the response_type=code, which indicates that we
actually want to use the Authorization Code grant; the client_id,
which is what we added to our configuration.
It's our application's unique identifier with Facebook.
The scope. Now in OAuth, scopes define the scope of the access the
client is requesting to the user's protected resources.
Now in this case, the app is asking for the user's public profile and
the email address. Now on the Facebook website,
you can see the types of scope supported by Facebook and
the fields each of these would return.
Next is the states and redirect URL. We will come
back to this at the later stage.
Our browser is now redirected to Facebook's login screen.
We are now no longer interacting with cryptoportfolio. As outlined in the OAuth
2 spec, Facebook's OAuth server needs to first authenticate us to confirm our
identity and ensure we are in fact the resource owner and can authorize
cryptoportfolio access to the protected resources.
Now if you're already signed into Facebook, obviously have a cookie,
you will not see the login screen. In this case, we'll sign into Facebook, and
now it will ask us to authorize cryptoportfolio with the following fields,
which line up with the requested scopes we previously asked for. Facebook even
allows you to edit this and perhaps reduce what we provide to the client,
which is kind of a cool feature.
Now if we agree, you can see Facebook now sends a
redirect back to cryptoportfolio.
The redirect is to the URL that was provided in the initial
authorization request from cryptoportfolio.
Now one important thing to know is that most authorization
servers, including Facebook, will only redirect to URLs that
are preregistered with them.
So, if we go back to the Facebook developer page,
Facebook Login setup, here in the redirect URL validator, now currently
we don't have an entry as Facebook simply, by default, approves localhost
domains as they are most commonly used for local development. But in a
production instance, the app would have to preregister the redirect URI.
This is effectively a whitelist of all the redirect URLs Facebook will
accept and protects against any malicious party changing this value,
which could result in the user being redirected to some malicious page.
Another parameter worth mentioning is the state parameter. In
the original redirect, Spring Security generated a random value
and included it in the request.
Facebook simply included it back in the response.
Now this is to protect against cross‑site request forgery attacks, where some
malicious party tries to send someone forged redirects to the server with
another user's authorization code, for example.
And since the malicious party won't have the original state parameter,
Spring Security will just reject it.
Next is the authorization code, not to be mistaken for the access token,
as there is still one more step to perform for our application to get
the access token, which is to exchange this auth code for the access
token at the authorization server.
You might be wondering, why the extra step? Wouldn't the
authorization server simply sent back the access token instead of
this authorization code? Well, up this point,
the communication has been between multiple parties,
user, client, and authorization, over the front channel using the
browser, effectively using the browser's address bar.
Now this works really well when you need to involve multiple
parties in a transaction, and some of them might not have an IP
address, but it's not very secure.
Can you really trust the browser as it stores URLs in its
history, and a malicious plugin could intercept or even alter
it? Hence, to get the access token,
the OAuth 2 spec requires the clients to go directly to
the authorization server, providing the auth code along
with its client ID and secret.
So even if the auth code was to be intercepted,
it's useless without the client ID and secret, which is only
known to the client and the authorization server.
This is why you won't see this exchange in the browser. But in the background,
Spring Security is making direct calls, ideally in production over TLS, to
Facebook's token URI, which Spring Boot has conveniently configured for us in
the CommonOAuth2Provider enum. Our demo app can then use this access token to
retrieve the user's personal data.
Now, to see this in action,
let's put a breakpoint in the
OAuth2AuthorizationCodeAuthenticationProvider and restart and reaccess
the application.
We can now extract the access token returned back from Facebook, and we can
use that to request the user's details from Facebook.
So using the userinfo URI from the enum, we can make a simple get request
to this URI, providing the access token in the header.
As you can see, we get the user's info back. As this is a bearer token,
anybody who has access to this token has access to the protected resource.
Providers like Facebook built their own authentication implementation on
top of OAuth 2. The problem with this is each provider of OAuth sign‑in
did things their own way, making life hard for developers.
Hence, OpenID Connect, which is a standard for authentication
built on top of OAuth 2 to consolidate all these best practices
and rules into a common spec so it's consistent across all OpenID
Connect certified providers, making life easier for developers.
And Spring Security also supports OpenID Connect, so
it's even easier to use OpenID Connect. Let's check this out next.