Persistent login and session management can be a
whole course in itself; however,
the key is to understand the different sessions between
user's browser, client application,
authorization server, and social login providers,
which will make your life easier when debugging issues or deciding how and
where to implement persistent login in your application.
Tokens also have their own expiry,
so you could have an active session with an expired token.
Refresh tokens can be used to get new access tokens without
bothering the resource owner; however, they need to be kept secure.
You shouldn't share them with other services as it's like sharing a password,
and it's not recommended to use refresh tokens in public clients.
Once a user is authenticated,
the next stage is to restrict them to what they are entitled to in
accordance with the principle of least privilege. So next, let's look at authorization with OAuth 2.