The main takeaways of this module are, OAuth2 and OpenID
Connect can be difficult to implement.
Fortunately for you, Spring Security simplifies things a lot. Ideally,
for authenticating your users,
you should prefer OpenID Connect to an OAuth2 implementation.
Now, the default implementations in demo application
are far from production ready, but neither is our web app, and fortunately,
Spring Security is very configurable,
so you can tailor the framework to your application's
architecture and unique security requirement.
In the next module,
you will learn how to complement your current in‑house
authentication with OAuth2 Login,
effectively giving users the option to either register with
your application or use their Facebook and Google accounts
to sign into your application. Let's check this out, next.