Hi, everyone.
My name is Zenon Saavedra, and welcome to my course,
AWS Infrastructure with Python: Getting Started.
I've worked with Cloud for several years,
and I have automated everything from PCI compliant networks
to multiple environment CI/CD pipelines.
Infrastructure is code is becoming a more and more popular process
for provisioning and managing your cloud resources.
With the AWS Cloud Development Kit,
you can write infrastructure code in your favorite programming languages.
Instead of infrastructure as code your infrastructure, now, is code.
In this course, we'll cover using the CDK in four contexts,
serverless environments, containerized environments,
network environments, and virtualized environments.
By the end of this course,
you'll know the basics of writing a working CDK application
and how to deploy it using the CDK CLI.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with the common AWS architectures,
CloudFormation, and Python object‑oriented programming and dependency management.
If you're not comfortable with any of these topics,
I suggest looking up these courses here on Pluralsight to get you started.
From here,
you should feel comfortable diving into the following CDK
courses available here on Pluralsight.
I hope you'll join me in this course to learn more about bleeding edge cloud automation, here at Pluralsight,