Welcome again to the course entitled AWS
Infrastructure with Python: Getting Started.
My name is Zenon, and I'll be your instructor for the course,
and we're going to start with the introduction to the AWS Cloud Development Kit.
Now what is this Cloud Development Kit that everyone keeps
talking about? First off, in this module,
we're going to understand the use case for CDK.
Why do we even need to learn this new framework to
provision your infrastructure?
Secondly, we're going to understand the components of a CDK app.
How do we begin building a CDK app?
Lastly,
we're going to discuss, specifically, how the CDK is
used with Python. Now, first off,
let's take a look at the cloud automation journey.
Some of you may have started your journey in the cloud through manual processes.
You go to the console, you point and you click,
and you provision your infrastructure from the console.
However,
you may have realized very quickly that that becomes
very hassle and very inefficient.
Afterwards, some of you may have attempted to script out your infrastructure.
Some of you have used the AWS CLI to automatically attach
an EBS volume or detach an EBS volume.
Some of you have used the CLI to automatically assign security groups,
for example.
However,
you notice, also, that the syntax for this can get quite
long and quite difficult to manage.
Lastly,
some of you may even use some sort of resource provisioning
engine. So some of you have used CloudFormation. Some of you have used Terraform to provision your AWS infrastructure.