Now in this demo,
we are first going to create a bastion host using the
BastionHostLinux construct that is available on the CDK.
Secondly,
we'll create an autoscaling group and attach a role to this autoscaling group.
This will allow us to connect to the autoscaling group via Systems Manager.
Lastly,
we're going to implement automatic checking for termination
protection by implementing a JSII interface.
What this will do is it will check all of our stacks if
they have termination protection enabled.
You can see here I now have a user_data folder which contains a
shell script called user_data.sh, and what this shell script does
is it installs an Apache web server,
downloads some assets from GitHub, and then transfers them to
my HTTP web server folder. It then starts the HTTP web server
and serves it up to your customers.
Let's start as we usually do and create the instance_stack that will
hold all of our constructs for that environment.
Now from here, we're going to be importing the EC2 library from CDK.
We'll also be importing the Elastic Load Balancer library from
CDK, the autoscaling library from the CDK,
as well as the IAM library from the CDK.
And, of course, we're going to add these dependencies to the CDK setup file.
We won't need to add the EC2 dependency anymore, because the
EC2 dependency is already here from our previous stack.
Going back to the instance_stack,
we are going to include some arguments that may help with customizing the stack.
First off, we're going to include a vpc.
Next, we're going to include an asg_min parameter with a default value of 2,
then an asg_max argument with a default value of 5, an EC2
instance type that defaults to t3.micro, and lastly,
we're going to specify the user_data, which our web app instances will be using.
Now that we've set up our constructor arguments,
let's create some actual constructs.
The first construct we're going to create is the bastion construct,
and the CDK has an excellent construct for this called BastionHostLinux.
We actually don't need to specify anything else except for the vpc,
the subnet which our bastion host will be provisioned in, which is
represented by this SubnetSelection, the instance name for this
bastion host, and the type for this instance.
AWS will take care of everything else,
including the role attached to this instance for a session
manager and the OS used by this instance.
Take note, though,
that the SubnetSelection here uses something different from the SubnetSelection
we talked about in the Network Environment module This SubnetSelection uses a
subnet_type field which specifies that this bastion host will be provisioned in
the first private subnet within this vpc.
So it will look through this vpc, look for a private subnet class,
and provision this bastion host in that subnet.
The next construct we're going to provision is an ssm_policy.
This is the policy that our autoscaling instances will be using so
that we can connect to them via Session Manager.
So in this policy we're going to specify that were going to allow these
particular actions on all resources, and we're going to specify the actions
that are needed for ssm. These are actually the minimum actions needed for ssm.
Next we're going to specify the alb resource.
Now in this alb resource, as usual we just need to give this alb
resource a name, and then we need to specify the vpc that this
resource will be provisioned in, whether or not this alb is internet
facing, in this case we will make it internet facing, and the name
for this load_balancer.
So the name for this load_balancer here is actually going to be added to the
load_balancer_name tag, and it's different from the resource name we specified
first. We also need to specify that we're allowing all IPv4 addresses to connect
to this ApplicationLoadBalancer on port 80.
This is because this ApplicationLoadBalancer is going to be
what our customers will be accessing, so it needs to be publicly accessible.
We also need to add a listener for this load_balancer so that
we open up port 80 on this load_balancer.
Next, we have to create our AutoScalingGroup.
Now the CDK has a construct for an AutoScalingGroup, and
similar to the bastion host construct, we just need to
specify the vpc, the SubnetSelection,
which, again, we're going to say is just the private
subnet in this particular vpc.
So, again,
the CDK will detect all private subnets in this vpc and add
that to the autoscaling configuration.
We're also going to specify the instance_type,
which, again, will use the EC2 type parameter that
we specified in the constructor.
Now we will also need to specify a machine_image that this AutoScalingGroup is
going to use. Now how do we specify an AMI image for the CDK?
Now we can actually create a separate variable above this asg called
linux_ami, and we're going to create an AmazonLinux object which takes in as
input the generation of this AmazonLinux instance, in this case we're going
to use AMAZON_LINUX_2; the edition for this AmazonLinux instance, we should
be fine with the STANDARD edition; the virtualization technology for this
instance, in this case we're going to use HVM; and finally, the storage for
this instance, in this case AmazonLinux GENERAL_PURPOSE storage should be
fine.
Notice that there's no need to actually indicate a specific ID. If
you've actually used CloudFormation before, you know that the ID is
one of the most difficult things to actually specify in an automation
tool, so in this case the CDK actually takes care of identifying that
ID for you automatically.
So now we can just pass this linux_ami variable to the constructor of the
AutoScalingGroup. Next, we just need to specify the user_data, and we're going
to read this again from the input from the constructor.
And lastly, we need to specify the capacities for this AutoScalingGroup.
First, we set the desired_capacity to be equal to the minimum_capacity.
This is considered normal best practice when working with AutoScalingGroups.
We then set the min_capacity to be asg_min and the max_capacity to be asg_max.
After creating the AutoScalingGroup,
we can use the policy we created earlier to add a role to this AutoScalingGroup.
So with this add_to_role_policy function,
we can actually add this ssm_policy to the role attached to the
instances in this AutoScalingGroup. We will also need to allow
connections from the load_balancer to this EC2 instance in this group.
So notice we can actually pass the alb object itself without even
referring to the ID or the name of the load_balancer, just the
variable of the AutoScalingGroup.
This is another thing that is considered a pain point with normal
provisioning options, so the CDK makes this much simpler for you.
Lastly,
for the listener for the load_balancer, we need to add a
target group to this listener, and we can pass port 80 of the
asg as our target for this listener.
So the target's argument for add_targets actually takes in as input
an array, but if we pass in the AutoScalingGroup,
it will just apply to the entire AutoScalingGroup. We'll also add a CfnOutput,
and this should be familiar for those of you who have used CloudFormation
before. This CfnOutput is just a value that the output section of
CloudFormation will actually display, in this case we're outputting the alb dns
name so that we can access it more easily.
Let me just go over the code one more time to make sure there are no typos.
So I really suggest doing this at least once, because the CDK does come
with a lot of complex naming conventions, and checking your code after
writing it is always good practice. So now we have created the instance_stack class that our app can provision.