Now in this demo,
you will see how we can use local assets to build a Docker container.
So we'll build the Docker container on the client
machine before uploading it to ECR.
Secondly, we're actually upload the container to ECR using the CDK app.
So we're not going to do it manually.
We're not even going to use the AWS CLI.
We're actually going to use the CDK to upload the container image.
Thirdly, we're going to provision the app using the CDK CLI.
So we're going to deploy the resulting application.
Finally,
we're going to view the resources on CloudFormation and take note of
the different characteristics of these resources,
as well as the resources tracked by CDK.
Now as you can see here, I have a globomantics‑container‑app folder.
Now, if we open this app folder, you'll see I have a webapp here,
as well as a Docker file.
Let's take a look at the Docker file.
The Docker file originates from the Ubuntu container image.
We're then declaring some environment variables to
ensure that the update goes well.
We're then updating our repositories and installing the Apache 2 web server.
We'll then copy the content of the web app directory
into the /var/www/html folder, expose port 80,
and run our Apache web server.
Now, if you look at the contents of webapp,
you can see here that we have all of the assets necessary to run our website.
We have all of the CSS files, images files,
and HTML files needed for Globomantics landing page.
We can actually visit Globomantics landing page.
You can see here all of the content that Globomantics has, and all of the information about the company.