We will also need to edit the app file.
Now let's just import the lambda_stack,
which is the new class and the new file we just created.
We're also declaring the LambdaStack class here,
as well as naming this CloudFormation stack as LambdaStack.
Finally, we can also specify a new set of environment variables.
Currently it is set to the US West region.
Now what I personally do is I change this environment variable
to actually get information from CDK itself.
So I can actually specify an environment here,
and I am going to specify my AWS account to be the default account,
which is specified in my operating system.
You can access this through CDK by using the
CDK_DEFAULT_ACCOUNT environment variable.
Even if you didn't manually define this, CDK will take care of defining this.
For the region, we can do something similar,
and we're going to retrieve the CDK_DEFAULT_REGION as the region for this app.
And of course,
we have to import the Python OS library to gain
access to these environment variables.
Now let's actually attempt to run cdk ls.
You notice that we did everything correctly; however, we still have an error.
The error is we cannot import the AWS API gateway library.
This is because this library actually does not yet
exist in our virtual environment.
We will need to make some edits to our setup tools
to gain access to this library.
Now, to do this,
all you have to do is go to setup.py and then specify the
new libraries you're going to import.
In this case, I am importing cdk.aws_lambda and cdk.aws_apigateway.
Now we're also specifying that we're using version 1.58,
again to ensure that we don't run into any breaking changes.
Whoops.
So don't forget to also include the comma,
so syntax errors can be very common,
and then we can install all of these dependencies again.
Now it will look for all of the dependencies in Setup tools.
So it will find all of the dependencies that you enumerated here in Setup tools.
So you can see it's now installed the lambda and API gateway dependencies.
Now, if we run cdk ls, you can see we can now view the LambdaStack.
We can even synth the LambdaStack,
which will get us a CloudFormation template for this LambdaStack.
I can actually again upload this lambda's template to the CloudFormation
service and CloudFormation will provision this LambdaStack.
Also, take note that there are additional metadata attributes in this stack. This is for AWS to actually use for tracking purposes.