So now that we created the stack for our instances, on our app file,
we'll just import the instant stack, and we'll read the user_data from
the file we have in our local machine.
Afterwards, we can create our instant stack class.
We'll just name it InstanceStack,
and we're going to specify that the NETWORK.vpc construct
is going to be the VPC for this stack, and the user_data
will come from our local file.
Now,
to show you the full benefits of the CDK, let me actually provision this
for you on a larger screen, and you can see again if I run cdk ls, we have
all four stacks available for you to provision.
And if we deploy the InstanceStack,
you can see, like what we saw in the networking module, it
actually deploys the NetworkStack first.
So after deploying all of these subnets and the VPC, it then
asks if we want to deploy the InstantStack.
I just need to say yes.
And then after deploying this InstanceStack, we can again go to
CloudFormation and view the InstanceStack from there.
If we go to Outputs, we can again go visit this DNS, and we
see that the load balancer redirects to our web servers hosted on our application instances.