Now that we viewed the CloudFormation template,
normally we actually deploy using the cdk deploy command,
and we just specify the stack that we want to deploy.
We don't actually need to generate a CloudFormation template and upload it.
If we run cdk deploy,
you can actually see all of the resources that this
CDK stack is going to deploy.
So you can see we have the lambda function,
the permissions for that lambda function, and so on.
All of them are viewable from the console.
Afterwards,
just confirm that you want to deploy these changes, and CDK
will take care of creating this LambdaStack.
If we go view the CloudFormation console,
you'll actually see the LambdaStack in the CloudFormation console.
Now you can see the create is in progress,
it will take some time to create,
but it's a fully working CloudFormation environment.
So all of the things that are true for
CloudFormation are also true for this stack.
If I delete this stack,
all of the resources associated with this stack are also deleted.
Now let's just wait for this stack to finish creating.
And you can see that the stack has now finished creating.
We can actually visit the endpoint seen in the Outputs file.
So if we visit that endpoint and we pass in the proper GET
parameter we can actually view the result of the app.
So you can see here that we specified Hello, Marc!
You have a hit.
We can change the name to whatever name we want as well.
So this is a very simple lambda function fronted by an API gateway.
Now to delete this stack,
we can delete it from the CloudFormation console. We can also use the
cdk destroy command to destroy the LambdaStack.
It will ask for confirmation, and then you just need to say yes.
It will destroy all of the resources associated with this LambdaStack.
If we go back to CloudFormation,
you'll actually see that the stack is in the process of deleting.
So the CDK handles everything from provisioning to destroying your CloudFormation stack.