Now, in this module,
we first demonstrated how to automate the provisioning
of subnets using the VPC construct.
Take note that the VPC construct only supports FSLM,
or fixed‑length subnet masking.
Secondly,
we use the default child attribute to access the
low‑level CloudFormation resource construct,
or CfnResource construct, to look at more specific and lower‑level
attributes that are not available to the higher‑level construct.
Third, we used Python loops to simplify the adding of network ACL rules.
So instead of writing and manually specifying each rule one by one,
we actually used Python code to simplify adding these rules.
And lastly,
we added custom arguments to construct constructors so that we can
actually add some input logic to our resources.
So you saw we specified what subnet we wanted, how many NAT gateways
we're going to use, and even the database port that our DB is actually going to possibly use in the future.