You may have heard the term page object model before.
This is a common term in the automation community,
which is basically referring to the idea of mapping your test framework, or the
model of your test framework, to the model of your pages.
So in an application,
you may have a series of different pages in the web application,
and those pages are going to be modeled in our framework the same way.
We're going to create some mapping between them.
So the idea here is that, for example, let's look at our login page.
If you have a login page,
we're going to create a class inside of our test framework called Login Page,
and it's going to have some of the same functionality that your login page has.
It's going to be responsible for being able to get
elements that exist on that login page.
For example, a username field and a password field and a login button,
it's going to manipulate that.
It's going to work at the highest level possible.
That's what makes a good automation framework.
Instead of having a method on this login page that our tests are going to use
that says get username field or enter text in username field,
we're going to have a login method on the login page,
and we're going to pass in a username and password.
It's automatically going to know how to insert the username and password
into the correct field and push that login button.
So this is going to aid in our automation. When designing your framework
for your test, you want to test in the same way that a user might use that
web page. By doing it that way, you make it very simple to write your
tests and to understand your tests.
So you see here also that pages in a page object model don't have to
necessarily map to exact pages in an application.
In this instance, I have a shopping cart example here,
and maybe you have a shopping cart on every single page.
Maybe it's in your header. But it's a section of your web
application, so it's going to map to its own logical object in your
framework, and that shopping cart is going to have methods that
your tests can call and use that are going to work in the shopping cart just like a user would.