To set up Selenium Server,
you just want to open up your browser and navigate to selenium.dev.
And there is the menu item up at the top for downloads.
If we select that, we'll go to the Downloads page,
and you'll see at the top here Selenium Server and in parentheses grid.
Don't be caught off by their naming convention or their numbering metrics.
This is a dot release in the sense that .4 is actually less than .141.
One of the previous releases of this course had us using .34,
which is a much older version than 3.141.
And so we're going to grab the latest release here.
And when you download this,
you're going to get a warning in here saying that there's things of
this type of download that could harm your computer,
and that's because it's a JAR.
It's an executable Java archive.
We do want to keep it, so let's click that Keep button and let it download.
And we'll switch over to where that downloaded it on the file system,
and you can see I have mine downloaded here under my dev/tools directory.
And you're going to want to remember that path and probably put it in an
easy path for you to navigate to from the terminal because we are going to
now go out to the terminal to execute this JAR.
Inside of my command prompt at my terminal,
I'm going to navigate to that directory where I just downloaded the JAR to.
So for me, I'm going to cd to dev/tools.
And then,
we're going to execute that JAR, so I want to type in java
‑jar selenium‑server‑standalone‑3.141.59.jar.
Your version maybe different.
Obviously, do the version that you downloaded, but
this is the current version for me.
I'm going to hit Enter, and we'll see this start up our server. You'll
notice a couple of things, that it is started up and running on port
444, and it's initialized our WebDriver Server. So we are up and running, and our server is ready to go.