Now that we have our server set up and ready to go,
let's change our test so that it will run against that server instance.
We want to start off by‑‑‑ I'm going to make this full
screen so you can see it a little easier.
We want to comment out that WebDriver because we're
not running it locally anymore.
We're going to create a new WebDriver.
But before we do that, I also need to set up some Chrome options.
And to do that, I'm going to say ChromeOptions chromeOptions = new ChromeOptions.
We are going to just accept the defaults.
This is the place where you could specify a specific version that
you wanted to see or some other attributes,
but we're good with just the defaults.
Now we will say WebDriver driver = new RemoteWebDriver.
And here is where it gets a little bit different.
So we'll say new URL.
And inside of here, we need to pass in our URL to our server,
and that is http://localhost:4444/wd/hub.
This is the default address and configuration by Selenium
for when you start up Selenium Server.
So these are their parameters. Don't be thinking that you missed where we
specify this. We didn't. This is what they have set up by default.
We will show you how to override this,
but this is the default URL. Now the other thing we need to do is
pass in our chromeOptions and close that line.
Now before we continue on here, you'll see that there's a red
underline underneath the URL, and that's because there's the
chance for it to throw an exception.
I'm just going to do the hot fix of add the exception to the method
signature. Save that, and now we have everything configured here to
actually run our test. I'm going to exit full screen mode.
Right‑click on our main and say Run.
And this will now go out and contact our server and run it, and I'm going
to show you two different things. So our test is running just fine. First,
we want to verify that our test did actually run, which looking at our
browser window that pulled up, it did. And you may notice a slight change
in behavior in that your browser window is no longer popping up to the
front of your screen when you're running it, and that's because we are
running that through the Selenium Server and not just our local instance.
So it may stay behind windows for you now.
Now let's also go over and look at the terminal.
The terminal shows a lot of information here that will be valuable for you
maybe troubleshooting some things. And it's going through and just showing
you what the capabilities are of this test. You can see that we passed in
those chromeOptions. We took the defaults,
but you can specify some unique characteristics for your test.
And you can see the communication that took place here.
So it's really good to look at all three.
Look at your IDE output, look at your test to see that it ran in your browser,
but also look at the terminal window to see if anything popped out
of there that looks uncharacteristically odd.
Everything here looks good.
It is a bunch of noise,
but there's nothing like an exception or a stack trace that was thrown on this page to show you that something abnormal happened.