Now that we have everything running for Chrome,
let's show you how to do the same thing for Firefox.
I'm going to comment out that current ChromeDriver we have
and add a new WebDriver for Firefox.
We're going to run into almost the exact same set of problems.
So if I add that FirefoxDriver and try and execute it,
it's going to tell us that it's not installed and we need to
go through and install it the same way.
And it's the exact same process whether you're on a
Windows box or Linux box or a Mac, just like we did before for the ChromeDriver.
I'm going to switch over to our terminal and install that Firefox
driver using Homebrew. And to do that, I'm just going to say brew
install geckodriver. It'll go through and download the resources that
it needs to. It'll take it a second that first time you go to do it.
And now this is installed,
we can switch back over to our IDE and run it. Back
over in our IDE if we run that,
it'll go through and fire up the FirefoxDriver, and you should
get a browser in Firefox that's loaded up and pulled up the
Pluralsight website. And sure enough, that's what I've got here.
One interesting thing to note about Firefox is that if you look up at
the address bar where it says www.pluralsight.com,
you can see the robot icon that is telling you that this browser was
launched and is operating under the control of a bot, which is kind of
an interesting feature, and I like how it kind of cues you in on that.
But our test is now set up to run that way. Let's switch back over to
the editor and switch it back to Chrome just to keep it consistent with
the rest of course.
But you can see how easily you can switch from browser to
browser with this. Switching it back,
I'm just going to get rid of those comments.
Delete that line, and I'll clean up my imports while I'm at it and save
that. We're back to running everything with Chrome.
You can go ahead and test it on your end,
but I know it's working on mine already. So we're good to move on and see about how we can find elements on a page.