Let's start off by creating a another HTML page.
We're going to do that by going to src, main,
webapp, right‑clicking and saying New, HTML File.
And we'll call this CheckboxTest.html.
And inside of here, let's change the title to CheckboxTest.
And for the body,
we're going to add a form with those checkboxes inside of there,
and I've gone ahead and done this with a three‑checkbox form for mayo,
lettuce, and turkey, just simple selections for building a sandwich.
I actually did this for an application for an online ordering for a client.
So let's save this,
and now we can go ahead and create our test using
WebDriver like we did with the radio buttons.
And to do that,
we're just going to right‑click on our package, com.pluralsight, and say New,
Java Class. And we'll call this WebDriverCheckboxes and click Enter.
We're going to do the same thing.
We're going to give it a public static void main.
In fact,
I'm going to open up my other example and copy that and paste it
inside of here. And I'm going to add the closing curly brace as well
so that that's balanced. Then I'm going to change our URL here to
CheckboxTest, and it is going to need the exact URL. So if you're not
sure of what yours is,
you can do that trick where we went ahead and rebuilt it in Finder and grabbed
that out of the address bar. But we have it sitting alongside a radio button
test so I know I can just change that to CheckboxTest and save that. Then we can
go down below that code and grab the WebElement. So we'll say WebElement
checkbox, and that is going to be equal to driver.findElement, and we can do
this By.id. And since its unique,
we can grab just that one element, and inside of here, we'll say
lettuceCheckbox. Close that off and say checkbox.click, and it will
toggle that one as being selected for us.
So let's go ahead and run this and exit full screen so we can make sure there's
no errors as it's starting up our server. We'll say Run checkbox main, and it'll
open up our browser for us. And we can see that our file was served up, and our
lettuceCheckbox was, in fact, checked.
I want to show you one little more trick with the checkboxes, and that is
click. Let me switch back over to our IDE. Notice there is no toggle. We just
have to say click, and we have to know the state of that. And in doing so, if
we add another checkbox.click down here,
save it and run it, it's going to actually uncheck it.
So you need to understand the state of what your application is
in. And we can see that looking at our web page,
it is, in fact, unchecked.
So it went through and checked it and unchecked it. There isn't a toggle or some boolean. It just clicks it.