Similar to our previous examples, let's go ahead and create another HTML page.
So I'm going to right‑click on src, main, webapp and say a New, HTML File.
I'm going to call this SelectItemTest.html.
And inside of here, I'm going to give it a title of SelectItemTest.
And for the body,
I'm going to add in there a form with the select element and
three options underneath there of Yes, No,
and Maybe.
I'm going to go ahead and save this,
and then I'm going to create another WebDriver test just like we
did with checkboxes and radio buttons by going up to src, main,
java and, on the com.pluralsight package,
right‑clicking and saying New, Java Class. We'll call this
WebDriverSelectItem and hit Enter on here. And we can go ahead and copy
out of one of our other examples that public static void main
WebDriver. We'll change that address of that file.
We'll go over to our WebDriverSelect and make sure that we add in there
the closing brace so we don't have unbalanced curly braces. And we need
to get the correct URL in here for this,
which is going to be SelectItemTest and save that.
Remember, if you forgot how to do that, you can right‑click on your file,
Reveal in Finder, and open that up with your browser, and it will
give you that correct address for that file.
Now from here, we're going to do something a little
differently than what we've done in the past.
Not far off,
but there's a support or helper class that makes this a
little bit easier for these select items.
So I'm going to make this full screen for a minute just to give
you a little bit more real estate. And inside of here, I want
to say WebElement selectElement.
And we're going to just do a simple driver.findElement, and we're going to do
it By.id. And the id that we want to use is just select1, and that was in the
HTML that we had just pasted over there. Now underneath here, there is a
helper class under the support package.
So I want to say Select, and you can see it right here is that first
option that's just the straight word Select, and it's under the
org.openqa.selenium.support.ui package.
So it's one of their support jars that contains these
classes for making things a little bit easier.
So I'm going to say Select select = to new Select. And you do something
a little interesting here. You pass in the selectElement. And if you're
at all familiar with design patterns, this is a wrapper pattern.
So we're taking and wrapping that select element with a Select object to
interact with that interface differently and make it a little bit more easy
than having to do some of the nuanced fine details of navigating through that
element. From here, we can now say select.selectByVisibleText, and we'll say
Maybe. So we want to choose that option for maybe. Now let's go ahead and run
this and see what it did inside of our page for us. So I can just right‑click
on this and say run WebDriverSelectItem, and it'll pull up my browser. And we
can see that it pops up with the option of Maybe selected. Looking at our
drop‑down list, that was the last one in our list.
It could have started with Yes,
No. It selected Maybe, which is exactly the
functionality that we are looking for.
So those helper classes make that a lot easier, and we don't
have to navigate through that element and do different
find‑bys or selectors to get it. We can just use that wrapper class.