Since recording our test in the Selenium IDE, we have now
generated some steps, or rather some commands.
Before we look at those commands,
let's talk briefly about what that syntax is though.
These commands are called Selenese, and Selenese is just a
language that is independent to the Selenium tools.
And what I mean by that is it's not C# or Java or Python,
it's not anything,
it's just general syntax, and there are some various implementations of that.
The recorder uses an HTML table to lay out the commands,
and we'll look at that here in a second.
The basic idea of Selenese is really simple, though.
You have a command and then optionally have a target and
a value associated with that target.
So some commands will just be the commands themselves and some of them
will take a target and optionally a value as well.
Let's look at a couple of these commands that were generated by the recording that we just did.