Hi everyone. My name is Bryan Hansen, and welcome to my course,
Automated Web Testing with Selenium and WebDriver Using Java.
I'm a director of development at Software Technology Group,
as well as a Pluralsight author.
Automated testing is now almost mandatory to guarantee
the stability of an application.
Manual click and testing doesn't guarantee regression testing
won't break previous functionality by itself.
In this course, we're going to test web pages using Selenium,
WebDriver,
and then writing a test framework to build a complete
testing solution for web applications.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include the Selenium framework,
how to use the Selenium IDE to record and play back tests,
building tests using WebDriver and Java,
and building our own testing framework to separate our app and
tests from the tooling that executes them.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to test web applications using the Selenium tools and when
to use record and playback with custom WebDriver tests.
Before beginning the course, you should be familiar with Java and Maven.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn automated
testing with the Automated Web Testing Using Selenium and WebDriver Using Java course, at Pluralsight.