You're now beginning to see how we can use the Selenium
IDE to go ahead and create pieces of our test to
incorporate back into our framework.
We could go ahead and start up a test using the IDE here,
like we've done all along.
And the Selenium IDE can help us gather things that we
want to add into our test framework.
So, for example,
I could scroll down through pluralsight.com and click on Authors,
and I can see it's starting to build stuff out for us.
I've already got the click for linkText=Authors.
I can do various things like start to work with the search field
and enter in Bryan Hansen and search on it,
and it's building out this case for me on the right.
I can stop that, give it a name, I can even wait till later to give it the name,
and export out that code as we learned before and,
in turn,
open that up and now see what I would like to add inside of
our WebDriver framework that we're creating.
So I've got all of these pieces here,
and I don't need to copy and paste this exactly in my WebDriver.
We would now start going through and add this to our Browser object
and our Pages objects so that we can navigate through and use these
driver.findElements or manage and that type of stuff inside of our
code base that we're creating, That's how we can use those two in conjunction with one another.