We've already shown an assert text because we had that up above,
but we haven't done a verify,
and we haven't shown what happens when an assertion fails.
Let's begin by adding a verify to this test first and
show what happens in a failure on that.
To do so,
I'm going to click below our commands and hit the
record button to start recording,
and you can see we automatically get a icon flashing in our
browser telling us that it's recording.
And we can come over here inside of here and say Selenium IDE,
Verify, and let's just verify the title.
Now we have a verified title for beta, and I can stop this test.
And instead of running the entire test each time,
I'm just going to click on the command above it and say play from here.
That's just one quick way to go through and see how that's going to run.
You have to go through the entire test harness each time.
Let's change that though to see what it does when we have something incorrect.
So let's add bbbeta and run it from there again.
So I'm going to go a command above there and say play from here.
And you can see that we have a failure, and it's highlighted that line in red.
Well that's great,
but we don't know if the test will continue going if we hit a
verification error or what happens from there.
So let's actually go up to our assert text and say play to this point.
It's going to go through and run our test down to that command,
and we have our assertion here.
We're going to assert text, and we have the target.
We have the value.
Let's change that and just make another spelling error inside of here. And so
we'll say PPPublic and run this test. And as we get on here,
you'll see it's hit that and it's failed.
Let's change that text back so that it will continue to run
and go through and run to this point again.
So we'll say play to this point. That will stop on our
assert text. And from here, we can stop the execution and
say that we want to record from here.
So it'll go through and do the same thing.
It'll pause at that assertion again and will ask us if we want to
start recording. We'll say yeah, let's go ahead and start
recording. And we can verify the text here.
So we'll say Selenium IDE, Verify, Text. And it will come
in here and say that for that verification, we have this
option of looking for this text.
We can change this to Thursday. Add a couple of Ts. And
let's run this whole thing over again.
We'll see this verify fail, but the test will continue to
run and just report at the end of it that it's failed. So
we need to stop recording.
Run that test again.
The assertion will succeed. The verify will fail, but it will continue to run.
The assertion stopped us, and the verify allowed us to continue and just reported the error at the end of the test.