In the first release of this course,
we had an image navigation that didn't show up right away,
and we had to use what was called an implicit wait.
Google Images has since changed their navigation,
as well as the WebDriver API,
but we could still use a wait to verify an image is,
in fact, there before proceeding.
An implicit wait sets a global setting for our driver so that every
single time that we select an element on that page,
it's going to wait for that to time out if it can't find that element.
Under the covers,
it's actually pulling the DOM every 500 ms to see if that element exists yet.
Now that's useful, but it has a little bit of overhead,
and it can slow things down when you're writing complex tests.
We're going to look at an explicit wait as an alternative to an
implicit because it can be more performant.
The implicit wait will delay on every element of the page
where we have more fine‑grained control over the explicit
wait, Whichever way you go is fine.
I just prefer to use explicit wait because I want to specifically call out when
something is dynamic and should be available right away. And when something
isn't dynamic, when it should be available slower,
I want it to fail fast.
I don't want to wait for 10 seconds or however long for a timeout. Let's look at how we can do this inside of our code and use an explicit wait.