I want to point out one more thing about the base URL inside of our application.
And you can see in the News test here that we have
selected https://www.selenium.dev,
and our first command is an open command on slash.
And in our Downloads test, and I didn't do this on purpose,
it actually caught it as I was filming this. The next open
command is for https://www.selenium.dev.
So even though I have a base URL, I have a hardcoded URL in there.
And I actually want to change that because that can break.
And the reason that that can break is I don't want this to be hardcoded to
that web page. I'm going to save that so that everything is based off of this,
and I'm going to go back to our workspace that we have for Selenium and choose
the SeleniumNews.side and replace that so that I don't have multiple copies of
that same thing out there.
Now, what does that do for us or why does that matter?
As we run our tests, we oftentimes want to run them
against different environments. Right now,
we're just going against this www.selenium.dev.
But what if we had something, and we don't in this example, but what if
we had like prod for production or we had dev or test?
I want all of those tests to run against that URL, and that's a
common thing with a test harness or a test suite.
And so I don't want things hardcoded or absolute path
hardcoded inside of our commands.
So a good little error that we just produced and we caught, and we want to use those relative paths inside of our application.