As I previously mentioned,
Selenium and WebDriver are actually meant to be used to complement one another,
not against one another.
In this test that we just ran in the Selenium IDE,
I can actually export all of these commands and open them up inside of my IDE,
and you'll notice it looks a lot like Java code.
So let's do that.
If we go up next to our Test name and choose a specific test and click Export,
and it will ask you how you want to export that.
C#, C# xUnit, Java JUnit, JavaScript Mocha,
Python, Ruby,
all that stuff you can choose specific things, if
you're going to run it on Selenium Grid.
We'll just say Java JUnit for now, and it's going to
actually export that for us as a JUnit test.
We can select Export, and it will ask us to navigate to a directory.
So I'm going to say dev\workspace\selenium, the folder that I've already
got set up. And I'll just leave this named TestTest.
You can see it went ahead and downloaded that file. And I'm going to open
that up inside of my Notepad. And here's that file inside of Notepad. You can
see it's set up as a JUnit test. It has all of the imports for org.junit and
all the various things to fire that up.
It also has imported all of the Selenium drivers that it needs.
In fact, it's got some extras that we don't need in there just yet.
As we get down into the actual Java code itself,
we have a public class named TestTest, which was our project name and our
individual test name, and you can see from here it fires up WebDriver and
takes a map of arguments and a JavaScript executer and fires up the Chrome
drivers since we ran this in Chrome, and you can use Firefox or one of the
other browsers that you choose, I'm doing this in Chrome for this course.
And, as part of our test,
the driver navigates to selenium.dev, as you can see in that driver.get,
and then it manages the window size, and that's just because I'm running
mine in full screen, and from there it finds an element on the page and
clicks it, and then once that comes back it asserts that we have actually
gone through and navigated to that Downloads page. This is all code that
you can now save, you could export it to your suite of tests that you're running,
store it in GitHub or Bitbucket, or whatever source control
that you're using, you could build a whole suite of tests
just by doing exactly what we did.
In fact,
you could navigate your entire site map for your site just to make sure that
none of those links are broken in this exact fashion and you'd have a
complete walkthrough, or a spider as it's called,
of your entire site map of your company's website.
And this is all done through that record, playback, and
then exporting to a WebDriver test.
So we used Selenium IDE to generate that Selenese and then export this Java test that is ran using WebDriver.