[Autogenerated] Hello.
Welcome to this model about spring GOP introductions.
You'll see how we'll make our flights implement new interfaces
at runtime with the help of this technique.
So I will let off to the explanations and demonstration.
What are going to discuss in this model?
What is the introduction and what is it for?
What can you help us to do?
How we can advise objects programmatically with the help of the the
40 Introduction Advisor delegating Introduction,
interceptor and proxy factory classes.
How we can advise objects decoratively with the help
of the declare parents annotation.
So what is an introduction and what is it for?
Our introduction is a spring GOP technique to declare mixing types a
mixing is a special type of multiple inheritance.
You may use it when you would liketo add optional features for a class spring.
GOP allows the introduction toe on advice,
object of new interfaces and very corresponding implementation.
How do you use introductions?
We may face the situation when we need to work with some
object flight in our left hand example.
But we needed to implement an additional interface flyer in our right hand.
Example.
However, we cannot touch the code of the flight class.
It is not available for change or it is possible that we would
like only some particular object to implement the flyer
interface as well and not the entire class.
It is the appropriate situation to use a spring GOP introduction.
Our demonstration will start with a flight class that will need
to implement on additional flower interface.
Will show how we can advise objects programmatically with the help of the
default Introduction Advisor delegating introduction,
interceptor and proxy factory classes and how we can advise
objects decoratively with the help of the declare,
parents and rotation.
Well, then compare the programmatic and the clarity of approaches.
We start with this flight class having to fills the string I d and the String
Company for the fields we provide the Gators and the sitters.
We also have the flyer interface having three methods take off fly and land.
The flower interface is implemented by the flyer In plus,
we also provide implementations for the three methods.
Take off, fly and land our flare test.
This class only accesses the context and gets a flight in stuffs.
So we're expecting toe successfully run it the flight been
is defined inside the GOP dot xml file, and it has two properties.
The idea with Value A 1234 and the company with Value ABC flights.
This is the initial spring application that will start with and would like to
demonstrate the spring a Opie introductions capabilities.
The flower in class needs to extend delegating,
introduction,
interceptor and implement the interface that you would like to be introduced.
Flyer.
In our case,
we will need to add this flare Advisor class that extends the
Fort Introduction Advisor These the Fort Introduction Advisor is
that the fourth implementation for advisors that performs one or
more a Opie introductions.
It's constructor will receive as argument a flier in,
for instance,
we're moving out to the test to verify the mixing that has been created.
We create the Flare Advisor instance.
Then we create a new proxy factory object.
This is a factory for a Opie proxies.
Toby used programmatically proxy factory allows us to obtain and
configure aopa proxy instances in our coat.
We can figure the proxy factory instance toe have our flight being as target,
and to advise using the flare adviser we have just created we need
set optimize with through as an argument in order to use the CG
leave strategy which is needed here, the proxy class will be a surplus of flight.
We are extracting the proxy flight object from the proxy factory and
we're asserting that it is an instance of flight.
We would also like toe display the idea of the
flight and the company of the flight.
Now let's run the test.
That test is green and you're getting the idea a
1234 and the company ABC flights.
So we have verified that it is indeed our flight.
We move further and we check if the proxy flight object is a flyer itself.
Then we check that it can act as a flier and we're executing the methods.
Take off fly and land.
Let's run the test.
So we have checked that our proxy flight object is
able to take off to fly and to land.
Is it proxy flight?
An instance of flair, Imp?
No, of course not.
The proceed flight object belongs to a class that extends flight.
Remember, Jabba does not allow multiple inheritance,
So as long as we extend flight, we cannot extend any other class,
but we implement the flower interface and we delegate
toe a contained flyer in object.
But which is the effective class of the proxy flight object?
Let's check it.
We are running again.
The test, the effective class of proxy flight is prom,
not parole side, not spring europea dot flights management,
not domaine dot flight Dollar Dollar a hand,
sir by spring CJ lib Dollar dollar CB FB 67 to 4 The name
showed that it is a class dynamically generated at runtime by
spring framework Using CG Leap.
The usage of the door door sign is allowed in the Java class names.
The New America offset CB FB 67 24 makes this class name unique tow.
Avoid conflicts with existing classes.
Let's stop for a minute from the co demonstration and have a look at the
structure of classes that is built behind the curtain by spring.
GOP.
What have we done so far,
we have created a flower interface and its
implementation Flare imp and a flight class.
What the the Spring GOP framework do It has created a proxy flight
class that directly extends our flight class,
and it also implements the flyer interface.
A proxy flight has a flower, in instance, so it can delegate behavior to it.
This way we may conclude that the proxy flight class acts as a flight and as a
flier and in particular by delegating tow the flower imp.
It may also act as a flower empty,
so we may say that we obtained a mixing a special type of multiple inheritance.
The proxy flight class constructed by the spring GOP
framework is at the same time.
Ah, Flight and the Flyer.
We proved it acts like a flight.
We were able to obtain its I D.
And it's company and it asked like a flyer.
We proved that it takes off.
It flies and it Lance, how does it do it?
It does it as a flower imp. The implementation we introduced.