[Autogenerated] Hello.
Welcome to this model about the implementation of crosscutting concerns.
For normal execution,
you're see howto build a real life application using
the normal execution annotations.
So the last move farther.
What are going to do for our demonstration will introduce
the flights management application.
A program working with flights,
passengers and tickets will implement a new feature working with aspect
for the normal execution floor will work with Logan capabilities that
track operations for flights and passengers.
Well, great aspect that manage logging operations and will use normal execution.
Annotations aspect Point got before After After returning around and order,
we moved to the code and show a starting spring application
that manages Flight's passengers and tickets.
The flight class is described by the I D,
which is a string by the company, which is also a string,
and buy the list of passengers.
We provide the others and sitters for these fields and the
print method that passes through all the passengers in the
list of passengers and prince them.
A passenger is described by his or her name,
which is a string and by the country, which is also a drink.
We provide getters and centers for these fields and the print method that
will print the name of the passenger and the country where he or she is
from the ticket class contains the number,
which is a string and the passenger that the ticket belongs to.
We provide getters and centers for the fields,
the emitting country method that returns the country of the passenger,
that the ticket belongs toa and the overridden to string mattered.
That is, just returns, ticket number and the number itself.
Let's have a look into the AARP dot xml file that describes
the beans that belonged to the application.
We have a passenger, Jim from the United States.
We have a passenger jack from the United Kingdom and have a passenger,
Jill from Australia.
All these three passengers have been introduced to the list
of passengers of the flight with I D.
A 1234 belonging to the company ABC flights,
and there is one ticket belonging to the passenger Jim having the number
1234567890 We remind that these beings arrive under the management of the
spring container once the application is started.
Let's have a look at the flights management
application containing the main method.
First,
we load the context from the flights management slash AARP
dot xml file that we have just seen.
Then we are getting the being with the i d flight from inside the context.
We are printing the flight.
We are printing its i D.
And we are sitting another i.
D.
We are printing the company that the flight belong stool
and we passed through the list of passengers from the
flight and we're printing them.
Finally,
we are getting from the context that being with the I D ticket
and we are sitting another number for it,
the last operation is closing the context.
Let's see now how the application works.
So we are getting various information about the passengers of the flight A
1234 Our next goal will be to add crosscutting functionality. Tow the metals that we have just seen here in action