[Autogenerated] Hello, I am cattle into dosa.
Welcome to this aspect oriented programming with Spring a Opie course.
It targets Java.
Developers who are already proficient in writing Java core code already
know the basics of the spring framework and are interested in learning how
to develop applications that may easily separate the rial business logic
from the cross cutting functionality.
So let's get started and first answer these questions.
What this aspect oriented programming This course will show you howto
build applications using spring aspect oriented programming and applying
it in working with a simple job application,
implementing the business logic for the management of flights and passengers.
The focus will be on clearly explaining the concept of
aspect oriented programming toe.
Apply them In practice,
this introductory motor will first review the key concepts of aspect
oriented programming will discuss about common AARP use cases.
We'll discuss the concepts of aspects during points,
advices, point cuts, target objects,
introductions and we'll explain how a Opie proxy and
weaving are working will illustrate the concepts and the
need for aspect oriented programming.
Starting from an example,
we create a simple matter trying to get the information
about the passenger from a database, and the method contains one single line,
the one retrieving the passenger by I D.
But it is necessary that we add crosscutting functionality logging.
So we introduced two more lines to log the bugging information
before and after retrieving the passenger by i D.
And it is necessary to handle the possible exception.
If the passenger that we look for cannot be retrieved,
then we have to catch SQL exception to wrap it within around
time exception and to throw its further.
And we have to check the user's rights and to throw exception if the user is
not allowed to execute an operation and we have to add cashing so that we
optimize the access to the database and we do not try to query again for a
passenger that has already been retreat.
So we may know, ask ourselves, How did we evolve?
Where did we start from and where did you arrive?
We started with a simple idea in mind.
Our business logic intended to get the passenger from the database by i d.
And we arrived to a large amount of service coat.
Our current method arrived to 17 lines of code.
The service code practically buried the original business logic,
and it continues to grow.
So this is where aspect oriented programming comes in action.
We take the or diagonal or crosscutting functionality and move
it to the separate classes called aspects.
So when may use aspect oriented programming,
which are it's common use cases, it may be used for separating logging.
For exception, handling for user writes checks,
for cashing for transactions or for tweaking legacy
applications that need their code improved.
Our starting example has already pointed out.
A few of these situations will show how to implement them with spring GOP.
During this course in principle, how doesn't aspect work?
You will do something before the method, for example, to longer message.
Then you will execute the original mattered,
and then you will do something after the method. For example, to log another message