[Autogenerated] we'll move for her to our next demonstration.
We implement a new feature working with aspect for the normal execution floor.
More exactly, we're going to track the operations through logging,
and we're going to use the before annotation the after
annotation and the after returning an imitation in order to
introduce the spin your profession AL it ease.
The first thing to do is to add two new dependencies to the poem XML file.
First, we'll add the spring GOP dependency.
Then we'll add the spring aspects dependency.
The first new requirement to be implemented is two lager message.
Every time the get idea method of the flight class is called,
the idea of the flight is its most sensitive information,
and we should keep track.
Every time this one is accessed,
we will create a separate package called com dot parasite dot springer.
P dot flights management don't aspect where to introduce the logging aspect,
and we'll create this logging aspect.
One class will mark this class with the aspect annotation,
and we'll introduce this private longer field.
We introduced this looking advice, Get I D method that will log a message.
Well, Adam,
before annotated method to log the fact that the method
calm parasite spring GOP flights management domain flight
don't get i d will be called you.
See here the joint point that this before method is executed
right before the execution of the method.
With this signature, we also need to configure the application to use a o.
P.
This AARP aspect J Dash Auto Proxy directive will enable
spring to use the AARP facilities,
and we need to introduce this looking aspect one being belonging to the class.
Calm the parasite dot spring europea dot flights management thought aspects,
not logging.
Expect one in order the logging aspect toe Get in action where you mind
that by introducing these beans into this configuration,
they will arrive under the control of the spring container?
Let's run the current application.
Let's have a look at the results and we see this newly
introduced crosscutting functionality.
The looking message appears right before calling the
get I D method from the flight class.
The next requirement asks to log a message after
successfully executing any print method,
either the one from the flight or the one from the passenger class.
In order to do this will create the logging advice print method well annotated
with after returning as it has to be executed on Lee after successfully
executing another method and which is the method that this looking advice
print needs to be executed after its success?
Any method that ants with Sprint because you are looking for
both the print metal from the flight class and the print
method from the passenger class.
As the information is printed and may become visible for different people,
we are looking this message as warning.
Let's run the current application.
Let's have a look at the result and we get this cross cutting
functionality that the print method has been called.
And there is a new requirement asking to log messages for
any ticket method that is called tickets are the most
sensitive objects in the applications.
Tons of them are created every day,
and we should keep track of everything that happens to them in order to keep
track of the execution of the metals from the ticket class.
We're introducing this logging advice method when we re executive,
but introduce this point cut referring to anti matter within
the class Corn dog parole site dot spring GOP dot flights
management dot domain Don't take it,
and we are annotating this logging advice mattered with the after an imitation,
providing as argument the all ticket methods point cut.
These means that the method will be executed after any method that
matches the point cut defined by the all ticket methods.
Let's execute the application.
Having a look at the results,
we see the cross cutting functionality recording that different metals from the ticket class have been executed.