Hello, my name is Jose.
I am very happy to welcome you to this course,
Java Fundamentals: The Java Reflection API and Method Handles,
and to this module, Introducing Java Reflection.
First of all, what is this course about?
Well, it is all about the Reflection API and method handles.
You may have already heard about the Reflection API since it has been
introduced in Java 1 back in the old days of 1995/1996 and has been used in
many applications and frameworks as we are going to see it.
Method handles is a more recent addition to the JDK.
It has been introduced in Java 7 to fix several problems raised by the
Reflection API that we'll be covering in this course.
The Reflection API is about reading and modifying the content of an
object at runtime without any prior knowledge of the structure or even
the class of that object at compile time.
In fact,
the Reflection API is about discovering the content of an object
and the structure of its class at runtime,
which is very powerful functionality.
Why is this API so important?
Well, the reason is simple.
It's that most of the Java frameworks are using it.
Odds are that the Java application you are working on currently is using the
Reflection API through the Java frameworks it is built upon.
Let us just name a few.
Hibernate and EclipseLink, the two main object relational mapping tools,
are built on the Reflection API.
JAX-B and JSON-B to map your Java objects to XML or to JSON
are also built on the Reflection API.
Spring, and CDI, Guice,
the three main frameworks of dependency injection are heavily using Reflection.
JAX-RS for REST services, JAX-WS for web services are also built on top of that.
JUnit, TestNG, Mockito, ACID J,
all the main testing Java frameworks are also built on the Reflection API.
And believe me, this is just a short list. There are many, many more Java frameworks built on this API.