Let us first introduce the MethodHandle API.
First, the entry point of the MethodHandle API is the Lookup object.
We saw that the main issue of the Java Reflection API is that the security
checks are done again and again on each method call.
So this Lookup object is going to encapsulate all the security information.
We'll check it once.
And since those information are not going to change,
it will be used all the time when accessing a class,
a field, or a method.
From this Lookup object,
you can create MethodHandle instances to access the class itself,
the methods within that class, and the fields within that class.
So this single method handle will give you access to all the
content of the class that was distributed among several
objects in the Java Reflection API, namely,
method, constructor, and field objects.
You can also create VarHandle instances to gain access to fields.
Now we just saw that the MethodHandle object also gives you access to field,
but the VarHandle does it differently.
You can use this object to access fields in a concurrent way. We will be covering this point at the end of this module.