Let us configure our project to be able to use this database server.
For that, we first need to open the properties of the project.
Click here and hit the Alt+Enter shortcut,
select the Java Build Path here, go to the Libraries tab,
select the Classpath, click Add JARs there,
and then navigate to the lib folder and select the h2 .jar file.
Click OK, and this is going to add this JAR file as a dependency to this project.
This tab may look different if the version of Java you're using is pre Java 9,
that is, Java 8 and earlier, but basically,
the steps are the same.
What you need to do is to add this JAR as a dependency to your project.
Let us click Apply and Close.
And now we are going to create the DB package and the DBLauncher class
in that package and add a main method in that class.
And in this main method, all we need to do is just call Server,
which is the Server class from the H2 package,
.main.
We do not need to pass any argument.
It is going to throw exceptions, so let us throw them and add a message,
DB Launched.
This class should compile.
If, for some reason, you cannot find the Server class,
it's probably because you did not put this h2 .jar
file as a dependency to your project.
Let us run this class.
There is a shortcut for that,
and this is going to launch automatically the H2 console,
which is a web application.
If we switch back to Eclipse,
we can see that the database server has been properly launched.
Now what I would like to do is that this H2 server should store its data,
table, objects,
and the like in this directory here that I've created
in the project called db-files.
To do that, we need to check the path of this file.
So you can open the properties of this folder by hitting Alt+Enter.
It will open this panel, and from there,
you can just copy/paste this, close this,
go back to your navigator window, paste this directory in the JDBC URL box,
and then add the name of the file.
Let me call it db-Pluralsight.
Let me check the connection.
The connection is okay, so now we can connect to this database.
If I go back to Eclipse and refresh this folder by hitting F5,
I can see that the db-Pluralsight file has been created here.
Let me go back to the console, and from there,
I can, for instance, create a table, create table Person with an id,
which is of type int and is a primary key,
and age of type int, and a name of type varchar of 40 chars,
for instance.
Let me execute this code and make this window a little wider.
Click here on this button, and this has created a table,
which I can open here, with the three columns,
ID, AGE, and NAME.
So with those very simple steps, we can create a DB server, an H2 DB server, and from the console, interact with it using SQL requests.