Now that we have annotations on our fields,
now that we know which field we should be reading or writing in what context,
how can we use the Reflection API to read and write
a given value to a given field?
The problem is the following.
We have a person bean,
and we want to read the content of this person bean without
knowing that is an instance of the Person class.
We want to do that only using the Reflection API.
And then when we have read the content of that bean,
we want to be able to write this content to any kind
of storage whether it is a file, an XML file,
JSON file, or even a database.
Then the question is how to read fields using this Reflection API,
and after that, how to write some value back to a person bean.
So suppose we have a Person class, which is here,
and we have already created several instances of this Person class,
P1 up to P5.
Remember that for all those instances, P1 to P5,
there is only 1 instance of the Person class itself.
So from that Person class,
you saw how to get a particular field as a Field object.
Suppose that the field that we got corresponds to the
name field of this Person class.
If we want to give a value to that field,
we are probably going to write the following code,
nameField.setValue, and pass the value we want to set as a parameter.
But remember that for all the instances of person we have,
we have only one instance of the Person class and also one instance
of the field that corresponds to the nameField.
So if we call this code like that,
the question is which is the instance of the Person class
that is going to receive the value Sarah.
In fact, the API is missing information,
which is the person instance we want to set that value on.
And the real pattern is the following: nameField.setValue.
The first parameter is the instance we want to set the field on,
and the second parameter, the value we want to put in that field.
This may look a little confusing at first,
passing an instance of the Person class as the first
parameter to the setValue method call,
but this mandatory since we have only one nameField object available.
And by the way, the same will go for the getValue method,
which will take the instance on which we want to read the
field as we are going to see it in a minute.
So here is the code.
We have an instance of Person.
First step,
we can get the class of this instance by calling getClass on it; second step,
we get the field corresponding to the nameField from
the Person class; and last step, we call field.setValue,
passing the instance as a parameter because it is on that
instance that we want to set the field,
and then passing the value we want to set for that field.
So this is the right pattern to set the value of a field using the Reflection API.