Now is the time for the live coding part of this module.
Let us see some code in action.
We are just going to create that BeanManager object that is going to
spot the write method to invoke to create the database connection
and to inject it in the EntityManager.
And then we will be able to run our EntityManager again,
but this time with a separate code for the writing and the
reading of the objects to the database and for the
connection to the database itself.
As we said in a previous module, we would like to fix the previous example,
the previous project,
by using composition instead of inheritance to make particular
EntityManagers for particular database connections.
So to do that,
I just copy/pasted the previous project from the previous
module so that you have a clean project for the previous
module and a new project in that module.
We still have this DBLauncher class here that we
can run to run the H2 DB server.
And if you check the console,
the only thing you need to do is to make sure that you are
still pointing with the copy of the files the one that are in
db-files folder of this new project.
Test the Connection, Connect, and if you check the content of the table,
you can see that we still have the four instances of PERSON in our base. Let me disconnect and go back to the code.