The first thing we need to create, of course,
is this EntityManager as an interface.
Let us do that really quick,
and we are going to put this interface in a package called ORM,
like object relational mapper.
Let me move this here.
Okay.
We need this factory method of in the EntityManager.
Of course, it should work with any type T,
so let me just change this instead of having something
that is going to work only for Person.
We are going to implement that in a minute.
And from that, I need a persist method, so let me create this void persist.
That is going to take an instance of T.
So this is the first version of our EntityManager.
This of method has to return an implementation of our EntityManager.
So let me implement that.
For the moment,
I am going to call the implementation of this EntityManager interface,
EntityManagerImpl.
Now this is not a very nice name for an implementation,
but we will change that in a minute.
Let me create this class.
We are going to create it in the ORM package.
It depends on the type T, and of course,
it needs to implement the persist method.
So what should we do in this persist method?
This persist method is getting your Person instance,
this is the example we are going to take,
and it should write the fields of that Person instance
in a Person table from our database.
We just created the Person table,
so this is not the responsibility of this persist method to
create the table that we hold the instances of T.
There are two things we need to do.
The first one is to generate the SQL request to
write this object to the database,
and the second one to execute this request on the database to insert the
instance of T we are passed as a parameter in the database.
So let us do that.
For this,
we are going to need an instance of the Metamodel
we created in a previous module, and we are going to create it like this,
Metamodel.of and pass t.getClass as a parameter.
There is just a slight change in the Metamodel class
compared to the previous module.
I got rid of the declaration of the type at the Class level just because,
in fact, we do not need it,
and things are going to be most simple if we get rid of it.
So let us go back there.
First step, we need to build a SQL string,
and this is probably a responsibility of the Metamodel.
We are going to call this method buildInsertRequest,
and with this request, we are going to create a PreparedStatement from JDBC.
A PreparedStatement is just an object that can carry a SQL
query from our application to the database,
and we are going to create that object using a fluent pattern.
So let us suppose that we first need to prepare this
statement with the SQL query and then set the parameters
from the object t that we have.
And once we have this PreparedStatement,
all we need to do is call the executeUpdate that will
execute the query on the database engine and hopefully insert this object t in the database.