Second pattern, how to create a method handle on a method.
This pattern is a little more complex than getting a reference on a class,
which was very simple.
So let us see it.
How to get a handle on the method.
Well, it is, in fact, a two-step process.
The first step is to get a method type object that will
just model the type of this method.
It carries information on the type returned by this method and
the types of the parameters this method takes.
And then with this method type,
we can call the Write method on the lookup object,
passing this type as a parameter to get a reference on the method we needed.
And we are going to see what methods are available
on this lookup object to do that.
We also have a bridge from the method class from the
classical Java Reflection API to the MethodHandle API when
what we have is a method object.
So suppose we have our lookup object.
The first object we need to create is this method type object.
We have a factory method for that on the MethodType
class that may take several arguments.
The first argument is the type returned by that method.
On this simple example,
which is a plain getter that returns a string and does not take any parameters,
the MethodType just takes the string.class as a parameter.
Now if we consider the setter,
the setter returns void and takes a string as a parameter.
So the first argument passed to this method type
method call is the void.class object,
meaning that the setName method returns void,
and the string.class object,
meaning that this method takes only one parameter of type string.
You just need to be careful because in the JDK,
there are, in fact, two ways of writing void.class.
The first one is this one, and there is a second one with a capital V,
and you do not want to use the one with the capital V.
If you do so, the rest of the code will not work.
You can also create a MethodType for constructors.
The convention is that a constructor returns void.
So if we have a constructor of person that takes a
string and an int as a parameter,
the corresponding MethodType as void.class as the first argument,
string.class and int.class for the two other arguments.
For the empty constructor type,
the method type is built just on the void.class parameter.
Those are the four main patterns to create method types for methods and for constructors.