Now that we have the proper method type for the method we are looking for,
the second step consists in finding the Write method of this lookup object.
We have three available methods to find the
reference on the method or constructor.
The first one is the findVirtual method for any kind of method,
the second one is the findConstructor method for constructors,
and the third one is the findStatic method for static methods.
So let us see the pattern of code to get a method handle on this
getName getter method from the Person class.
We have our lookup object, we have the right MethodType.
All we need to do is to call the findVirtual method on our lookup object;
pass the Person class as a parameter since what we are looking for is a
method from that Person class; pass the name,
of course, getName here; and then pass the methodType as a third parameter.
We can do the same kind of thing for the setName method.
The findVirtual called is exactly the same.
The only thing that changes, of course,
is the name of the method and the methodType object.
Let us see the pattern for the constructor.
We have our lookup object, the constructorType that we just saw,
and then what we need to do is to call the
findConstructor method on this lookup object,
passing the class on which we want to get the constructor,
and the constructorType.
Of course, here,
we do not pass a name since we know that a name of a constructor
has to be the same as the name of the class.
The pattern for the empty constructor is, of course, the same.
The only difference being the methodType object that is used.
So here are the four main patterns to get a reference on a method
or a constructor using the MethodHandle API, and all those objects that we get are instances of MethodHandle.