We saw how to use the MethodHandle API to get a reference on a class.
We saw how to create method handles on constructors and methods.
So now we are going to see how to create method
handles on the fields of a class.
The lookup class has also these two methods,
and I put a warning sign here for a reason.
The first method is called findGetter,
and the second method is called findSetter.
Now you may think that findGetter will give you a reference on the getter
method on a field and findSetter on a setter method on a field,
and it is not the case.
The getter method returns a method handle directly on a
field to get read access to that field,
and the setter method to get write access to that field,
but they have nothing to do with getters and setters from
the bean specification from the JDK.
How can you create this read method handle and write method handle?
Well, it all starts with this lookup object.
You can call the findGetter method, passing the name of the class,
the name of the field, and the type of that field.
And this nameReader method handle will give you read access on a field.
The pattern to get write access uses the findSetter method,
takes the Person as a parameter, the name of the field,
and the type of the field.
And what you can see is that getting read access and getting
write access is done with two different objects,
but that have the same type, which is the MethodHandle type.
So we need to be extra careful here because if you are using this
nameReader object to write a value to the corresponding field,
you will get an exception, and the same for the nameWriter object.
If you try to read the value of that field using that object,
you also get an exception.
The problem is that those two objects are the same type so the type does not carry the information and what this object can do exactly.