So now we need to add the getPrimaryKey method to this class,
so let us do that, create method, and the same for the getColumns method.
Let us create this method.
If we want this code to compile, we need to create this type, so Ctrl+1.
This is going to be a class, so create a class,
putting it in the util package is fine, so let us do that.
It should compile here.
And let us do the same for this ColumnField class in the same package.
This Metamodel is a Metamodel of Person, so let me just add this here.
Now we have a code that compiles.
What we need is a code that working, of course.
To find a primary key in a class, we need to add a special piece of code,
which is an annotation.
So let me just type this annotation.
This annotation does not compile because we have not created it yet.
But once again,
we can ask Eclipse to help us in that by typing Ctrl+1 and
select Create annotation PrimaryKey.
We are going to put it in the reflection.annotation package.
Let us click Finish.
And you can see that an annotation is a very simple piece of code.
It is basically an interface with this special declaration,
this at symbol in front of the interface keyword.
Let us go back to the Person class, and let us to do the same.
This is a Column, and this is also a Column.
Let us create those annotations in the annotation package, and now our Person class is compiling properly.