Now there is one thing we need to fix with those annotations due
to the way annotations are working in Java.
An annotation is first handled by the compiler,
and the compiler needs to decide at what time of the lifecycle of
a class an annotation will be made available.
And there are three stages when an annotation can be available.
The first stage is the compile stage itself,
so only the compiler will be able to see that annotation if we choose to
do so; the second stage is the class loading stage,
so the annotation will only be seen by the class loader; and
the third stage is the runtime itself.
If we need to analyze an annotation to take an
annotation into account at runtime, we need to tell the compiler to do so.
And to do that, we need to add an annotation on this declaration,
which is the Retention annotation.
The Retention annotation takes an attribute of type RetentionPolicy.
And this RetentionPolicy is an enumeration, which may take three values.
The first one is SOURCE,
meaning that this annotation will be only available at
compile time; the second one is CLASS,
meaning that this annotation is available only when the class is
loaded and not after that; and the third one,
the one that we need, is the RUNTIME value,
meaning that the annotation will be made available at runtime.
So let us select this value, and let us do the same on the Column annotation here.