Before we run this code, let us go back to the H2 console.
We can just click on this table.
It will generate the proper SQL query to check the content of this table,
execute this query, and check that.
Indeed, the table is empty.
Now we cannot have two instances of a server using this same data file,
so you need to disconnect the console from this file,
go back to the code here.
We are going to print out the different people that have been returned,
linda, james, susan, and john, james, susan,
and john, and I'm just going to add something here.
Put this in a variable.
This is the id.
And while we set the value of the PrimaryKey in the statement,
we are also going to set it in the object itself.
So from the metamodel PrimaryKey, get the field.
Let me create that method from here, return this.field.
This is the PrimaryKey field.
Let me make it accessible because most of the time,
it's going to be private, and call field.set on object t,
which is the person we are currently writing in the database,
to the value id, which is the PrimaryKey we just generated.
So if we go back to the main method,
here we are just writing the object before we write them to the
database then add the message Writing to DB,
write them to the database, and once this has been done,
we should see that the PrimaryKey have been seen in
the instances of the objects.
So let us run this code.
And indeed,
you can see that the values have been set showing that the
objects have been properly written to the database,
which we can check again by connecting here and executing this request.
So this is a very basic way of creating an EntityManager able
to write instances of people in a database.
It is very basic, very naive,
but you can see that from that you can create much more complex systems, system like Hibernate and the like.