Let us now write the find method on our EntityManager.
I've just created a simple code able to read back the object we
created in the database in our application.
So for that, we need the find method.
Let me create this method.
It's going to return an object of type t.
It is a class T.
Let me call it like this, and this is going to be the PrimaryKey.
Since we should be able to deal with any kind of PrimaryKey,
we are going to say that the PrimaryKey itself is an object.
So, of course,
the implementation of the EntityManager we created does not
compile anymore because it is missing this method,
which has been created here.
This method is constructed in the same way as the persist method.
So first of all, we need the metamodel, of course,
because this is where we put the information on the class,
so let us get the metamodel from the class.
We need the SQL string.
Just like in the previous example,
we are going to create this method buildSelectRequest,
and just as previously,
we are going to prepare the statement by calling this
PreparedStatement with the SQL request we have and the PrimaryKey,
which is this PrimaryKey here.
Executing this statement, let us execute this query,
will return this time a ResultSet.
And by analyzing this ResultSet,
we are going to be able to create an instance of this class,
and we are going to create another method,
buildInstanceFrom this class and the ResultSet.
This is the pattern we want to create in our find method.
So first of all, we need to create this method,
buildSelectRequest,
and I am going to put it just near the buildInsertRequest
because it really looks like this one.
We want to type in select id, name, age from Person.
And you can see that we already have some of the elements we need.
Basically,
we need this piece of code because those columnElement is precisely the id,
name, age string of character.
And we want to return select + columnElement + from this.clss .getSimpleName.
And here, we need to specify the value of the PrimaryKey,
and for that, we have getPrimaryKey .getName,
which is the name of the column, plus, and add the question mark.
Here, we are missing, of course, where id =?. So this is the select request,
which is fairly simple. Same kind of the thing as the insert request we already saw.