Let us create this method.
It's a private method.
Private T buildInstanceFrom takes a Class and the ResultSet.
We are going to need that class.
As usual, the Metamodel.of, pass the class as a parameter.
And the goal of this method is two-fold.
First, create an instance of that class,
and second,
populate all the fields of that class with the content of the resultSet.
So the first step is to create an instance of that class,
so clss, you can call newInsance here,
and put the result in a variable of type t.
But you see that this newInstance method has been deprecated.
Let us check the code, and you see that it has been deprecated since Java 9.
We are currently running Java 11, so we see this method as a deprecated method.
Let me close this.
The right method to call, and even if you are running Java 8,
it's better to use this second pattern, is to get the constructor of the class,
the empty constructor, so we do not need to pass any parameter to this method,
and on that constructor, to call the newInstance method.
And this is going to create the same instance as the
newInstance from the class method.
This is going to throw many exceptions, the Instantiation,
IllegalAccess, IllegalArgument, InvocationTarget,
NoSuchMethod, Security, and that's it.
Now that we created this instance,
we need to populate the fields with the right value. And the first field we want to populate is, of course, the primaryKeyField.