Now I told you that EntityManagerImpl was not a great name,
and indeed it's not a great name.
What we can see here is that we have a portion of the code,
which is really completely general,
which does not depend on anything more than the JDBC and the type t,
which is, in fact, a parameter of the class.
And we have a little portion of the code,
which is this one, the prepareStatementWith,
which creates a specific connection to this H2 database.
So let me put this in a method called buildConnection.
OK.
This buildConnection is there.
We are going to make this method public because,
in fact, this buildConnection is something that is specific to the H2 database.
So the right way to handle this is, in fact,
to create an H2 EntityManager stating that the H2
EntityManager extends the EntityManagerImpl and move this
method from here to this H2 EntityManager there.
And by doing that, this EntityManagerImpl in fact,
becomes an abstract class because this method can be made abstract.
It still throws a SQLException,
but then we do not need this implementation anymore,
and now this class may be made abstract.
So we do not need to call it EntityManagerImpl anymore,
we can call it just AbstractEntityManager,
and here,
fix the code by telling that we are going to return this H2 EntityManager.
So we created a dependency between the EntityManager and the database itself.
If you need to connect this EntityManager to a MySQL database,
for instance,
all you have to do is create a MySQL EntityManager
providing the right JDBC connection, which is just,
in fact, one line of code specific to MySQL,
and the system will continue to work against MySQL
instead of using the H2 database.
This is a very powerful mechanism,
but it is not that great because we are using
inheritance instead of composition.
In the next module of this course,
we are going to see dependency injection and replace this
system with a dependency injection mechanism,
which is much better because this time,
we will not have any inheritance anymore and a much better separation of concerns.