Hey everybody,
welcome to just this quick introduction
video on Appendix B- Statistics Overview.
So in this Appendix B, it's just gonna be
a series of IPython notebooks that go over
various topics and statistics and
these topics can help you a lot when
you're thinking about data analysis.
Or even some machine learning topics.
So just to give you a quick overview of
what these appendix notebooks
are gonna look like.
They'll usually have
an overview of the main topic.
Then they'll start off with either
an example problem or a manual creation
of the distribution if it's talking about
a specific statistical distribution.
Then you'll see the notebook.
We'll use SciPy to either create or
analyze the specific statistics topic,
and then you'll have links
to additional resources for
learning more about the topic.
So all the online notebooks
can be viewed at this link.
It's the same nbviewer link
you've been using before.
Except instead of the Udemy course,
it's in statistics notes.
So it's just
nbviewer.ipython.org/github/jimportilla,
and then /Statistics-Notes/, and
then you go to the tree and master.
So if you click this
link you'll go ahead and
see a page that looks something like this.
And then some of these
are still being created,
so just have a little patience if
a particular topic isn't ready yet.
Or for something like the continuous
uniform distribution,
you just click on that link.
And then you'll see the IPython
notebook here, so like I was saying,
there's a little introduction to
the topic, an example problem.
We solve it using Python, and
then we see how to create distribution
automatically using SciPy.
For the rest of these lectures, I'm not
gonna be typing as I go along and talking.
I'm just gonna open up the IPython
notebook and view it with you guys.
And just go over it, cuz there's quite a
bit of LateX use to write these equations,
and it just takes too long to type it out.
So go ahead and check out these notebooks.
You can even just check
them out by yourself.
You don't really need to
follow along with the videos.
Everything's really heavily commented, and
it has explanations within
the notebooks themselves.
And it's just an additional resource for
you guys to learn about statistics, or
give you a refresh,
in case you don't remember.
All right, so thanks a lot.
And just remember you can view
these online notebooks at this link
mpviewer.ipython.org/github/jmportilla/St-
atistics-Notes/tree/master.
And the text file attached to this
lecture will have that link in it.
All right.
Thanks, guys!