Hey guys.
Welcome to lecture 24.
This is gonna be on Index Hierarchy.
So in this lecture we're going to learn
about Hierarchies and index formation,
so you're gonna be able to have
almost like an index of an index, and
I'll show you what I mean about
that later in this lecture.
So let's go ahead and
start off by just importing the usual.
Import numpy as np, from pandas import
Series, DataFrame.
Import pandas as pd, and
then since we're gonna be using random
numbers later as we've done in the past,
we're gonna import from numpy.random,
gonna import randn, okay, cool.
So, pandas allows you to have
multiple index levels, and
I'm gonna show you with
a quick example on a series.
So let's go ahead and
make a series called ser,
we'll call it Series,
let's construct it using np
Or we can construct it using randm Six,
just make six random numbers.
We'll create an index.
And you'll notice that my
index is gonna be two lists.
So I'm gonna past two lists in my index.
First list I'm just gonna say 1,
1, 1, 2, 2, 2.
And then my second list,
I'll have it be letters,
so we'll say a, b, c, oops.
And then we'll repeat it again, a, b, c.
So usually we're only passing one index,
but now since we're gonna learn about
index hierarchy,
we'll be doing multiple indexes.
Let's go ahead and
see what that looked like.
Cool.
So what pandas did,
is it created a multiple index level so
it matches up the two lists you gave it.
And assign one index
level to the other one.
So for instance since your first three
values of your first index list were 1s,
then it assigns that one index to the
first three values of your second list.
So those first three abcs,
were all assigned on the one index and
then you have a sub index of abc and
then similarly the three two's were
assigned to the second set of abc.
So we can also check multiple levels.
So if I for instance call
the index method on my series,
it'll give me the number of levels and
their labels, as well.
And let's say I wanted to
check a specific subset.
So, if I wanted to check, for
instance, the first A, B, and C set.
So, the 1 in index 1.
I can call it, and
I'll get those first three values.
And if I called the second index,
I will get the second ones.
0.93, 0.157 and then 0.411.
Let's say I wanted to call an index
from an internal index level.
So let's say I wanted to know everything
on the series that was
associated with an a.
So I wanna know both this value 1 a -0.34,
and
I also wanted to know the second a, 0.934.
The way I can do that is by selecting
everything using a colon in
the higher index level, and
then specifying that I want all
a's in that lower index level.
And there you go,
that gives you that outer index level, and
the two values that were associated
with the inner index of a.
So we can also create data frames.
From a series of multiple levels and we
can do that using a method called unstack.
So we can name our dataframe, dframe and
then call the unstack
method on that data frame.
And then let's go ahead and
take a look At what happened there.
So since you have multiple index levels,
now you can create a dframe using unstack.
And it'll create the lower
index levels as columns and
your higher ones will be
now the index of the rows.
And we can also apply
multiple level indexing
to dataframes since the very beginning.
So if you wanted to construct
the DataFrame with multiple index levels,
we can do it like this.
I'll show you an example.
So you have your DataFrame.
You have np.arrange.
So we're gonna choose 16 points and
then let's reshape this into a matrix.
We'll just have it be
a four by four matrix.
And then were going to create
an index and again were going
to pass two lists in the index.
The first list I'm going to have
it be two pairs of letters and
the second list I'll have
it be a set of numbers.
Then we can also do subsets of columns.
So how can I do that?
Well, we can specify that the columns
is also gonna be a set of lists.
So let's have the first column be cities,
we'll call NY NY.
Let's say LA and SF, and
then the next one we'll do
cold, hot, hot, cold.
All right, awesome.
And then we'll have a dframe2 to show it.
So let's just see what happened, and
then let's go over what we just did.
So we created a data frame.
We arranged our 16 point array.
We reshaped it as a matrix, so if you look
on the inside we have zero through 15, so
that makes sense, and it's a four by four.
And then we passed two indexed lists,
a, a, b, b, 1, 2, 1, 2.
So each of these gets matched up.
Now these first 1, 2s are associated
with a on the outer index, and
the second set of 1, 2s are associated
with b on the outer index.
So that's what we've got going on.
On those index of rows and then if we
wanted to make an index hierarchy for
the columns we can do the same thing.
We create an NY and YL, LA, SF,
that's gonna be your outer index.
And then your sub index there we decided
would be cold, cold, hot, cold and
that's what we got here.
And they're associated with
the first value on your first list
that's associated with the first value on
your second list that you pass, and so on.
Second value, ny, associated
with the second value here, hot.
So you get that going
on in your data frame.
So if you wanna keep better
track of your index levels,
you can name your index levels.
Let's see how to do that.
So let's go ahead and
name our index levels.
And we can do that by
passing index.names method.
And since we have multiple index levels
on the rows, we can just pass the list.
So, we'll say index Index 1 for
that first row index.
Index 2 for that second row index.
And then we can also name the columns.
And we can do it by just
passing the method columns and
And then passing a names on top of that.
And let's call our column names.
So it looks like, so the first index
with the columns are cities so
I'll call it Cities.
And the second index is temperature,
well more or less hot and cold.
So we'll call it temp.
And after doing that, let's just
see what the data frame looks like.
Cool, so
now we have the names of those indexes.
So your first index, the AB, and
your second index the one-two, one-two.
And then your column names: cities and
temperatures, cold-hot, hot-cold.
Cool, let's say you wanted to interchange
the level orders for some reason.
You can do that, so if I wanted
temperatures to be the outside index and
cities to be the inner sub-index.
How could I do that?
So you grab your data frame, and
you pass a method on it called swaplevel.
And then you give it the two
index levels you wanna swap.
So, we wanna swap cities.
And temp.
And we're gonna set the axis equal to
one because we wanna swap the columns.
If we don't put an axis it'll try
to swap the axis zero by default,
and that would be the rows.
So since we're swapping
columns we're gonna input one.
Now let;s see what happens.
Nice, so
now you can see we've swapped the levels.
So now the temperature is on
the upper level cold hot cold and
you have your cities that
are associated with those temperatures.
You can also sort levels.
So if you wanted to sort a level,
you just pass the the method's sortlevel.
And let's go ahead and
pass that and see what happens.
So now
if we look at the row indexes,
they've been sorted.
So one one two two.
And what this,
the argument I passed here on sort level
is for
which sub-level of the index to sort.
So let's say I passed a zero instead.
Well now it's gonna sort if
by the outer index As and Bs.
So those are already sorted.
If I wanted to sort it by the one index.
So remember, INDEX_1,
that's your zero index here.
INDEX_2, that's your one index.
Since it starts at zero.
And now we've sorted it by the second
index, a one, one, two, two.
We can then perform operations
on particular levels.
So this is where it gets interesting.
We take our dframe, and
let's say we wanted to compute a sum.
But if we only wanted to compute a sum
on a certain level, for example, we can
pass the level argument and I only wanna
compute sums on the temperature level.
And I wanna compute the sums on the
columns, so I'll pass access equal to one.
Let's see what happens.
So now I've kind of ignored the cities,
since I specifically say that the level
to be temperature, and
I've added based on the temperature level.
So let's look and see what happened there.
If we look at our previous data frame.
Index 1 is a.
Index 2 is 1.
What are all the cold values equal for
this index?
Well, it was zero plus three, and
now you have three as your cold.
And then the hots were one plus two,
so now you have three by your hots.
And you can take that and expand it
to the rest of the rows and columns.
And that's what you get.
Cool.
So we'll be messing around more with
index hierarchy in the future.
It's gonna be a really useful tool.
That's the end of this section,
next up we'll look at section five,
it's gonna be working
with data the first part.
You can go back on previous lectures,
get a little more familiar with data
frames and series if you want to and we're
going to be reviewing using those tools,
a lot through the rest of this course.
So, I'll see you at the next section.
Okay.
See you there.