Okay, hello everyone, and
welcome to part five of the stock
market data analysis project.
So in the last video,
we went over quickly,
just a basic way of analyzing risk
by comparing your standard deviation
of daily returns versus your expected
return or your average daily return.
And we created a little scatter
plot to show that visually.
And now we're gonna take
a look at value at risk.
So right now I'm just using NV viewer,
to take a look at the iPython notebook
that I already made for you guys.
So we're gonna look at a couple of
definitions and different methods, and
then analyze the risk of
our technology stocks.
So value at risk, we can basically treat
this parameter as the amount of money
we would expect to lose, or we're putting
at risk, for a given confidence interval.
There are several methods we can use for
estimating a value at risk.
And we're gonna go ahead and
see two of them in action.
So we're gonna use the bootstrap
method to calculate value at risk.
And for this method,
we calculate the empirical quantiles
from a histogram of daily returns.
So for more information on quantiles,
you can go ahead and
check out the Wikipedia link I left for
you here.
It'll take you here and you can learn
about quantiles, and percentiles.
Cool.
So and there's a couple of these examples
for you to go ahead and check out.
Basically it's going to help us
find our confidence interval.
So let's go ahead and repeat the daily
returns histogram for Apple stock.
So I'm gonna go ahead and
jump back to our live coding.
And you can go ahead and
follow along here.
So sns.distplot.
And we actually already did
this in an earlier video.
Remember we just plotted out,
the daily returns.
Remember to drop any null values
that could possibly be there.
I set the bins=100, that's a whole
year's worth of information.
And I set the color to purple.
So we've already done this,
we're just repeating it.
And I have a large amount
of empty space in the cell.
We're gonna get rid of it.
Okay, so we've seen this before.
There's our histogram
with the daily returns.
And now we can use Quantrill,
which is actually built into Panda's
to get the risk value of the stock.
So I can just say, rets.
Remember that was the returns
data frame we made.
I'll show you a preview of it.
So remember this is the daily returns for
your stocks, every day.
So if I say.
APL, or the Apple stock, and
call quantile 0.05, and run this.
That means,
well you get this number showing up.
So what this actually means is that
the 0.05 empirical quantile of
daily returns is at negative 0.019.
And so this means with 95% confidence.
So 95% of the times for
simulations you would do this your
worst daily loss would not exceed 1.9% or
100 times this.
So if you have a $1 million
investment your one day
5% variance at worst would be 19,000.
So to show you what I mean by that,
let's hop over here.
Actually, I have this written out.
So, you have your 0.05 empirical quantile
that we just got for the Apple stock.
And what this means is that
within 95% confidence,
you're only gonna lose 1.9% of
your money on any given day.
So that's your value at risk.
So your value at risk is
1.9% of your investment.
So everyday at worst you'll
lose 1.9% 95% of the times.
Okay.
So hopefully that made sense.
If you need a little more review go
ahead and check out Investopedia,
the bootstrap method for risk analysis,
and you can go ahead and
check out that Wikipedia link for
quantiles.
But all we're saying here is that 95%
of the time, your worst daily loss
will not exceed 1.9% for Apple stock.
Okay.
So now I'm scrolling down the NB
viewer portfolio iPython notebook.
We're gonna look at value at risk
using the Monte Carlo method.
So let me go ahead and
walk you through this.
What the Monte Carlo method
is gonna allow us to do is
we're gonna run many trials
with random marked conditions.
Then we'll calculate portfolio losses for
each trial.
So, after a lot of these trials or
simulations we're gonna use
an aggregation of all these simulations
to establish how risky the stock is.
So a brief explanation of what we're gonna
do, and there's actually a link down here
at the bottom for
more information on Monte Carlo methods.
We can click it, and
it'll take you to this page right here.
So I'll explain it and
then if you want some even more in depth
information you can check out the link.
But basically what we're gonna do is,
whoops, use
Geometric Brownian Motion or GBM and this
is technically known as a Markov Process.
And this means that the stock price Is
gonna follow what's known as a random wok.
And a little bit of jargony terms,
but it's consistent with,
at the very least, the weak form of
the Efficient Market Hypothesis.
Which is also known as EMH, and
it says that the past price information
is already incorporated and
the next price movement is conditionally
independent of the past price movements.
So what this means is that the past
information of the price of a stock
is independent of where the stock's
gonna be in the future.
So, this basically means you can't
perfectly predict the future
price of a stock solely based on
the previous price of the stock.
So looking back, the equation for
the geometric brownian motion is
given by this equation right here.
Delta s over s equals mu times delta t,
plus sigma times epsilon
times square root of delta t.
So s stands for your current stock price,
mu is the expected return,
which we calculated earlier.
Remember, if we scroll up here, we had
our daily returns for the Apple stock.
So the expected return,
that's just your mean.
Expect a return.
Sigma is the standard
deviation of those returns
which we can get from that histogram.
T is the time and
epsilon is a random variable.
And we'll tackle that
subject a little later on.
So, if you multiply both sides by
that stock price of the equation,
you get a formula here and that will
solve for the change in the stock price.
So you can see that the change in
the stock price is equal to the current
stock price, s,
multiplied by these two terms.
The first term, which is mu times delta t,
the average daily return
multiplied by the change in time.
That's known as drift.
And then the second
term is known as shock,
which is sigma times epsilon
times the square root of delta t.
So for each time period,
the stock's gonna drift either up or down.
And you have that information based
on previous daily return values.
And then it's gonna experience a shock,
and
this is where the Monte Carlo
method comes into play.
The shock is going to be random.
And it's gonna either push
the stock price up or down.
So, you're gonna do this series of steps,
drift, and then shock up or down, drift,
shock up or down, thousands of times.
And then you're gonna do a simulation
of where you might expect the stock
price to be.
So I'm gonna hop over to
the Investopedia page just to show you
some nice figures they have here.
So here's, again,
the equation explained for
you using the geometric Brownian motion.
And to show you this,
they have a nice figure here.
Like I said before,
we're gonna drift our stock price
with mu times delta t based
on the daily return values.
And then it's going to experience a shock,
either up or down.
And then again, it's gonna drift and
it's gonna experience another shock up or
down and that's gonna be your
random walk or random trial.
And then here, they generated a series
of random trials over ten days, and
you can see here's where
the stocks ended up, all over.
So, now if you do a histogram,
you can get some sort of risk
analysis based on your end trials.
And here they did a histogram at the end.
So, we're gonna do all
this in Python right now.
So let's go ahead and hop over.
Okay, so
what we're gonna do to demonstrate this
Monte Carlo method we'll start with just
a few simulations, and then we'll define
the variables we'll be using in the Google
data frame, using the Google data frame.
So let's go ahead and
set up our time horizon.
So I'm gonna set an object
days = 365 days, so a year.
I'll set my dt = 1/days, I'll set my Mu,
or my average, Mu = rets.mean() [Goog,
of the Google column.
GOOG, so that's the average of this
column right here, of that Google column.
So mu is gonna be associated for
our drift and let's go ahead
and then grab our sigma,
basically the volatility of the stock.
And that's gonna be equal to the standard
deviation of the daily returns
that we can get using Pandas as well.
Whoops.
Sorry about that.
Okay, so, now we have our days,
our DT, our mu, and
our sigma, and let's go ahead and
make a function.
That takes in the starting price and
number of days.
And uses the sigma and mu we already
calculated from our daily returns.
Okay, so
I'm gonna create a function def and
I wanna call this function
stock_monte_carlo.
And it's gonna take in a start price,
the number of days you want to run it,
your average return and
then your standard deviation
on your daily return.
Okay.
So to start off here, let's go ahead and
define a price array.
So on create price is
equal to mp.zeros and
we're going to have it be an array of
zeros with the same length as dates.
And then that first term is
going to be the starting price.
And then I'm gonna have the shock
be equal to again another array.
And if remember you can always go back
to the NumPy tutorials in the beginning
lectures if you're a little hazy
on this or just want a refresher.
And, don't worry, I'll break down
the whole function at the end.
So we have our shock and drift arrays now
so we're gonna run the price array for
a number of days.
So I'm gonna say for x in x range.
Remember if you're using
python three you don't need to write
x range you can just write range.
And I'll say one days.
So from one to days in that range.
We're gonna calculate the shock first,
so my shock of x at that point in time.
I'm going to grab it from
a normal distribution,
with its censor around mu times dt.
And its scale is going
to be equal to sigma
times np dot the square root dt,
which we got from our equation.
If you are a little confused about
the np.random.normal, you can go ahead and
check out in appendix B,
D, Normal Distribution.
Statistics videos, and
that will clear up any confusion there.
But again I'm going to break down
this whole function a little bit.
Our drift term is just
equal to mu times dt, and
then finally our price at that
particular moment in time at x
is going to be equal to price x minus 1 so
the previous price plus
that delta s value.
So we can say price [x
minus 1] times the drift,
the current drift value plus
the current shock value.
And, close parenthesis here.
And then,
we'll just return that price array.
So, let me go ahead and
break down what we just did here.
Okay, so
we have our stock Monte Carlo function.
It takes in a start price, the number of
days you wanna run it for, your mu, or
your average daily returns, and
your standard deviation on those returns.
We created three arrays, price,
shock and drift that were
arrays full of zeros of with the length
for the number of days you wanna run it.
And then we set the first term of
that price to the starting price,
so we have somewhere to start.
And then for every day we go
along we calculate a shock term.
Which is just grabbed from a random
distribution with yours scale
being equal to sigma times
np do square root of dt.
Which is this term right here.
That's sigma times epsilon
times square root of delta t.
So instead of just inputting an epsilon,
I'm kind of setting epsilon equal to
a normal distribution defined by sigma
times the square root of delta t.
There's various ways to choose your random
epsilon value, but in this case I'm just
using a random normal distribution based
off the information for that stock.
Then our drift term,
if we hop back over here.
Remember our drift term
was just mu times delta t.
And there's our mu times delta t, and
so then your current price It's gonna
be equal to your previous price plus your
previous price times that drift plus that
shock value and then at the end of the
function, just return your price array.
Great.
Just go ahead and click shift enter,
so we create that function and
now we're gonna put that function to work.
So let's go ahead and
look at the starting price, so GOOG.head.
Remember, we created this
at the very beginning.
So now,
I see that my opening price was $540.74.
So I'll say, start_price
= 540.74.
And now, I'm gonna run this
Monte Carlo simulation 100 times.
I'll say, four run in xrange (100),
so 100 times.
Remember, if you're using Python three,
you don't need to type in xrange,
just type in range and
I'm gonna plot it out.
I'm gonna plot out the array
given back from my
stock_monte_carlo function and
then we pass in the arguments,
(start_price, days mu and sigma).
Remember, if we scroll back up, we
already defined those here in this cell.
365 days, our dt, that mu and
that sigma for that Google stock.
And so we're going to run our stock Monte
Carlo function with those variables and
then we're gonna plot it out and
we're gonna do that 100 times.
And then before we see it, I'm just
gonna put some labels on that plot.
So xlabel,
x will be days.
The ylabel, plt.ylabel
will be the price and
then plt.title is going to be
the Monte Carlo Analysis for Google.
So let's go ahead and
run that and there you have it.
So we just simulated a years
worth of random trials using
Monte Carlo method for
that Google style and
you can see now we have,
it's kind of crazy distribution here,
but let's go ahead and
try to make some sense of it.
So what we're gonna do is create
a histogram of these end results.
Now I'm gonna do a much larger run, so
I'm gonna set runs = 10,000.
Now if you're thinking, hey, now I can
compete with the big guys on Wall Street,
they do this for hundreds of
thousands to millions of runs and
they do much more complicated
analysis than this simple simulation.
But who knows, you might get lucky.
Anyways, so then I'll create
a new array called simulations.
And I'll have it be zeros
of the number of runs,
so at 10,000 length of array and
then I'm gonna say, for
run in xrange(runs)
simulations of that particular run.
So at that point = stock_monte_carlo,
again with our start price
The number of days, the mu and the sigma.
And it's gonna be the previous days,
so days-1.
So just a quick note,
depending on how strong your computer
is this might take a while to run.
If it's taking way too long,
you can go ahead and
lower the amount of runs you have here.
Let's go ahead and run it.
So we'll see how long it takes.
If it takes too long, I'll shut it down.
But hopefully, it can handle it.
I'm just gonna break down
real quick what we did here.
So I'm saying for 10,000 runs,
every run that point
in that simulation is gonna
be defined as the end price,
which I why I say, days-1,
so that's gonna take.
If we look here at our plot, it's gonna
take this very last price point and
set it as the term in that array.
So we're basically, gathering an array
of all these ending price points for
10,000 runs.
Great.
So now that we have an array simulations,
we can go ahead and plot a histogram and
we can again, use quantile to
define our risk for this stock.
So what I'm going to do is say,
q = np.percentile.
(Simulations,1).
So what this does is it uses NumPy to
define q as the 1% empirical quantile.
And what this basically means is
that when we're doing our analysis,
that 99% of the values should
fit within our output.
And now we're gonna plot a histogram,
plt.hist(simulations.bins, I'm
gonna set it = 200 bins.
Remember, we did 10,000 runs.
So we're gonna have to
have a lot of bins and
then I'm gonna use plt.figtext to fill
in some additional information
onto the plot, figtext.
So I'm gonna go ahead and
input the starting price, (0.6, 0.8).
And instead of actually
typing all this out,
what I'm going to do is
go nbviewer here and
just grab it from this notebook.
Now I definitely suggest,
you type it all out, but
what really all this is just the text
that's gonna go on top of the figure.
So I'm gonna put my starting price,
string, define the starting price.
I'm gonna put my mean final price
as the mean of all those final
prices of the simulation.
And then I'm gonna put my 99% confidence
interval as the (start_price- q) and
then I'll display the 1% quantile and
I'll plot a line at that 1% quantile and
then I've put a title for that plot.
So let me go ahead and
run it and there you go.
break this down real quick.
So this is a histogram
of all the final prices.
So our starting price was $540.74 and
our average final price was $540.79.
So what this means is this is actually
kind of a pretty stable stock.
And if we scroll backup, you remember when
we did our scatter plot Looks like Google
and it's probably more clear in this
NV viewer, so I'll scroll up here.
If you look at the average
daily return for Google,
it's actually really close to zero.
So, it's not changing that much.
Looks like it is pretty stable,
which explains why in our
analysis the mean final price is so
close to that starting price.
Now what about risk?
99% of the time and
I drew a red line here, so
I plotted a line at that
1% quantile result and
that line is at $524.40.
So what does that actually mean?
So if we look at that that,
means that the value at risk for
each Google stock is gonna be $16.34,
so $524.40 is our starting
price minus that 99% variance.
So this means that's our value at risk.
So 99% of the time that you run
this Monte Carlo simulation,
the amount of money you
would lose at most,
99% of the time is $16.34, so
that's your value at risk.
Which isn't so
bad considering that your initial
investment was $540, so
it's not a huge risk.
It depends on your financial
situations and other factors of course.
But $16.34, 99% of the time over a year,
it's not a whole lot of money to risk for
an initial investment of $540.
So that's the most amount of money
you could expect to lose 99% of
the time is $16.34.
And that's it for
the stock market data analysis project.
I'm going to hop over to the MB Viewer.
Here's a couple more questions
I want you guys to answer and
feel free to post on the discussion board,
if you have any questions, but
I want you to do a couple of
additional questions and exercises.
So go ahead and estimate the values
at risk using both methods we
just learned for a stock not related
to technology and go ahead and
build a practice portfolio and
see how well you do for real stocks.
There's a bunch of different websites,
where you can make a little practice
portfolios and
not actually invest any money.
And see if you can start to build
algorithms or different analysis
techniques to see how you can predict or
trade well the stock market and then
another thing I want you to do is look
into further correlations of two stocks.
So remember, if I scroll up here,
we looked at the correlations between two
stocks or a bunch of stocks actually,
but go ahead and repeat this for
two stocks not really into technology.
So do you think, for instance is there
a relationship between let's say,
Tesla stocks that make electric cars and
gasoline stocks, such as like ExxonMobil?
If one goes up does one go down?
It might be interesting to see if
there's a correlation there or
just use your imagination, see what
other stocks you're interested in.
So great job.
This is a pretty epic projects and
I'm really proud of you guys for
going all the way through it.
And if you have any questions,
feel free to post a discussion.
Thanks, guys.