Hi everybody,
welcome to the third data project.
This will be the election analysis.
So in this data project we're going to be
looking at data from two data sets and
they're both concerned with the 2012
election between Mitt Romney and
Barack Obama.
The first data set's basically an
aggregation of a bunch of political polls
and, we'll be answering questions such as,
who is being polled and
what was their party affiliation?
What were the poll results, and who
were they in favor of, Romney or Obama?
And did that change over time?
And did any events change
that voters sentiment?
And then scrolling down here, so
we'll look at those questions.
Answer them.
Use cborne to try and
visually answer some of those questions.
And after that, you can see here
we analyze how voter sentiment
changed over time between Obama,
Romney, and the undecided voters.
So we'll look at all that then we will
see if any events played a part and
that poll data.
Afterwards, we're going to
look at a donation data set.
So this data set's going to have
data on people that contributed to
the campaigns of different candidates,
not just Barack Obama and Mitt Romney but
everyone, all the other Republicans
that ran such as Michele Bachmann or
Herman Cain, et cetera.
So, we'll look at how much was donated,
the average donations,
how the donations differ
between parties or candidates.
What were the demographics of the donors?
Is there any pattern in
the donation amounts?
And we'll be looking at that
visualizing some of the data there.
And we'll also be looking at best
practices for displaying data.
It'll go into further
detail in that later.
And then finally we'll also be
looking at donations by occupation.
So the CEOs, as you can scroll
down here and see, CEOs seem to be
a little more heavily conservative since
they donated more towards Republicans.
And retirees Maybe might surprise
you seems to lean a little more like
a Democrat and we'll go over all
that in the following videos.
Great, I'll see you there.