Hey guys.
Welcome to lecture 26.
In this lecture we'll be learning how
to use JSON with Python and Pandas.
JSON is the JavaScript object notation
that's used a lot around the web.
So I've imported the usual numpy as np,
Pandas Series data frame as well.
Let me show you an example of
what a JSON object looks like.
I'm gonna copy and
paste this from the iPython notebooks.
That you have links to.
You can go ahead and open up that link,
and then just copy and
paste it into your own iPython Notebook.
So, it almost looks like
a dictionary in Python.
It's very, very close to that format.
In this particular JSON object, we have
a zoo animal category, if you will.
We have it called lion.
We have the food it eats.
It eats meat vegetables and honey.
We'll have a descriptor for its fur.
It's golden.
It doesn't have any clothes
because it's an animal.
And, then we have its diet.
And that will consist of, for
example, if there's a zoo animal,
gazelle, its food that it eats
is grass and its fur is brown.
So we can have several layers of
zoo animals in the JSON object.
So we can only have two zoo animals here,
the lion and the gazelle and
the gazelle can only be
part of the lions diet.
Okay, so we're gonna import
the JSON module to work with it.
And in order to load the JSON
data we're gonna say data =
json.loads and
then the object name we gave it.
Go ahead and see what that looks like.
We'll type out data.
Cool.
So now we've loaded the JSON
object as term data.
We can also convert this back
to JSON if we wanted to.
We can just say json.dumps and
then you pass whatever you want
to dump onto as a JSON object.
And now we have our JSON object here.
Looks almost like a dictionary.
So what else can we do?
If you wanted to open up
a JSON data after loading
with a data frame, you can do that.
So we can name our data frame dframe,
and then load,
let's say we wanted to see our data,
and we're just interested in the diet.
Let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
And so now we have the diet
section of the lion, and
then we have information on that.
So, it was the zoo animal Gazelle.
It's fur was brown, and
the food it eats is grass.
We won't be working a whole lot
with JSON objects with Python.
So I'll leave this to you guys if
you want to learn more about it.
There's a lot of different
arguments you could pass, and
custom selections, so you can
specify a specific number of rows or
columns to read off from the JSON object.
But, really, we won't be using
them that often in this course.
This is just almost an in case
if you wanna use JSON objects.
And, if you're already familiar
with JSON objects, then you'll
be familiar with their formats and this is
just to teach you how to import and load.
But this isn't really
a huge part of this course.
So it's just for
the more you know basically.
Okay, so
in the next section we'll go over,
quickly, xml and
html file formats of Python.
And that will be lecture 27,
so I'll see you there.