Hey guys welcome to lecture 44.
This lecture's going to
be on data aggregation.
I'm super excited for this lecture
because after the previous 43 lectures,
we're finally gonna be able to
look at some real data sets and
do a lot of analysis on them.
So, lets go ahead and get started.
You're going to import NumPy as np,
pandas as pd, and
from pandas import Series and DataFrame.
We do that for
most of the IPython notebooks we start, so
we're definitely gonna do it now.
So that aggregation consists of
operations that result in a scalar.
For instance, the mean,
the sum, the count, those operations
that we've done in the past.
So let's go ahead and
get some data to play with.
So here's the URL we're gonna use.
We're going to look up the archives
of UC Irvine machine learning class.
So this is the link.
When you click this link, or
you can copy it from the IPython notebook
viewer, you'll come to this page.
And it's the machine learning database
wine quality and we're gonna go ahead and
mess around with the red, so
the winequality-red.csv file.
All right cool.
Once you download it, go ahead and save
it where you're saving your notebooks.
And if we open up that file real quick,
I'll open up in notepad,
notice that it's separated by semicolons,
not commas.
So, we're gonna use read_csv,
like we learned in the past
to set up a data frame, but
we're gonna have to set the delimiter
as a semicolon, not just a comma.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We've got dframe_wine,
that's what we'll call our data frame.
And then we're gonna use pandas,
so pd.read_csv,
and then go ahead and
input the name of the file, so
this one is winequality.csv.
Actually, it's winequality_red,
the way I called it.
You can just call it whatever you want.
And then remember the delimiter or
the separator, was a semicolon.
Okay, so now we have our data frame.
Let's go ahead and get a preview.
Let's just see the first five rows.
And we can do that again,
like we've done in the past,
by calling just the head
of the data frame.
All right, so what do we got here?
We got our index, zero,
one, two, three, four, etc.
Pandas has done that automatically for us.
We have different acidity values, residual
sugar levels, the chlorides, the dioxides,
the density of that wine, the pH level of
that wine, and then the interesting ones
we're gonna play with for this lecture
is the alcohol content of that wine.
So for instance,
this wine was 9.4% alcohol.
And then the quality rating for that wine.
So they rated it on quality.
Okay, cool.
So how about we find out the average
alcohol content for the wine.
How can we do that?
Well, just like we've done in previous
lessons, we're gonna say dframe_wine.
We'll choose the alcohol column, and
since we wanted the average alcohol
content, we're just gonna get the mean.
So this is a data aggregation so
it's gonna produce a scalar.
So the average alcohol content for
all these wines was 10.4%.
All right great, so what else can we do?
We can, if we want, just take a quick peek
at what the entire data frame looks like.
So the entire data frame is
a whole lot of wine, it's 159.
Oh, sorry.
1,599 rows.
So we've got tons of
information here to play with.
We know that the average alcohol content
of the wine is 10.4%, what else can we do?
So that's an example of data aggregation.
Can we make our own data aggregation?
So there's built in methods such as mean,
but can we make our own?
And yes we can.
So what we can do is we
can create a function.
We'll use def to create that function, and
we're gonna create a function
called max_to_min.
So max_to_min, we'll have it
accept just arr as its input.
And then we're going to return
the max value of that array.
And then,
subtract the minimum value of that array.
So we're gonna basically serve
this as a peak to peak function.
So it's going to find the max and
subtract the minimum.
So now we have our function max_to_min.
So using that, let's go ahead and
keep that in the back of our minds.
We've learned a lot about group by.
So let's go ahead and
implement that on our data set.
So let's make a data frame called wino,
or a group by object called wino, sorry.
We'll take our data frame,
the frame wine, and we will group by,
and we're gonna group it by quality.
So this was the quality
rating of that wine.
So we've done that, and let's go ahead and
see the statistics on that.
So we'll use describe like
we've done in the past.
All right.
So now, we've grouped all
the wines by their quality rating.
So the quality goes from
three all the way to eight.
And we have stats on all the wines.
So we have their alcohol content, their
densities, their acidities, sugar, etc.
And we have their counts,
the mean values, the standard deviations.
All right, awesome.
So we're gonna be messing
around with that later.
We can now apply our
own aggregate function.
So this function takes the max
value of the column and
subtracts the minimum value of the column.
So, let's go ahead and take that group
by object we just made, wino, and
the way we pass a general
aggregation method is .agg, and
then you're gonna pass your function
max_to_min that we just made.
Let's go ahead and run that.
Okay, so now what this has done
is it's gone through wino,
that group we just made,
that was sorted by quality, and
it took the max of each column value and
subtracted the minimum.
Okay, so that's what we got as the result.
And we can also pass string
methods through aggregate.
So to show you what I mean by that,
we call the method wino.agg.
And we can actually pass mean as
a string instead of .mean method.
We could actually just
do a more generic mean.
It's gonna give you the same result, but
it's just good to know you
can do it that way as well.
So, there you have, for instance, the
average alcohol percentage for each one.
All right, awesome.
So, let's go back to the original
data frame, dframe_wine.
Just see the head of it,
the first five rows, okay.
Nice.
Now, let's add a quality
to alcohol content ratio.
So what I'm interested in,
I wanna see if that quality rating
has a link to the alcohol
percentage of the wine.
So I'm gonna do that by adding
a new column to this data frame.
I'm gonna say dframe_wine,
and then I'm gonna name this column,
I'll say qual/alc ratio.
This is the quality to
alcohol content ratio,
and it will be equal
to the quality column.
So this column right here,
quality, divided by dframe_wine.
The alcohol content column,
this column right here.
All right.
So let's run that.
So now we've created that new column,
let's go ahead and check out the head now.
Okay.
And
there's our column now,
the quality over alcohol ratio.
Great.
So we have a whole column.
We got that going.
So, just to go over some other
stuff we've learned in the past,
let's go over pivot tables.
So we could've used pivot
tables instead of group by.
So how would we do that?
We would say dframe_wine dot,
and instead of calling group by,
we could have also have called pivot
table like we've done in the past.
And this case,
we could have specified that the index
be equal to the quality column.
Whoops, let me spell that right.
Quality column.
Excellent.
And now, let's take a look at that and
you get, pretty much the exact same thing,
we got when we used the previous
methods of group by.
Great.
So, we're not quite yet
at the data visualization section,
but I'll give you a little preview
taste of what that might look like.
In order to show you the plots, I'm going
to need to call matplotlib and inline.
That will allow us to see
the plots inline in the notebook.
And then, what are we going to plot?
How about we make a scatter plot.
So we'll say dframe_wine, and I'm gonna
call a plot method on that data frame.
So we've seen this once before,
but we'll see it in much more
detail in future lectures.
So the kind of plot I wanna make,
let's just make a scatter plot just for
the heck of it.
And on my x, I will make quality values.
And I'm gonna plot those versus the y,
I'll say the alcohol.
Okay, let's go ahead and do that.
All right.
So now I've made a scatter plot
of alcohol versus quality, and
it's plotted all the points.
So all the wines based on their quality,
rating, and
their alcohol percentage content,
so that's pretty interesting.
So we can see that the data is probably
better fit for a box plot of some sort.
So we can get a more concise view and
maybe add some standard deviation
lines and get averages.
So we're going to learn about
box plots in the future.
I'll leave it as a challenge to you
if you wanna figure out how to do
box plots right now.
But don't worry about it, we have
a whole section on data visualization,
this is just a little taste of it.
The most important thing to learn from
this lecture was data aggregation,
so let's scroll back and
make sure we got that.
So remember data aggregation
is basically just functions or
methods you call that allow you to have
a scalar result afterwards such as mean,
count, sum, etc.
You can just call these by saying .mean,
.sum, .count.
And you can also, the important part is,
make your own aggregations.
So we did that.
We made a function called max_to_min.
And you can pass aggregation functions
on your data frame by using .agg.
And then you can also pass string
aggregation methods by just saying .agg,
and then the string name
of that aggregation.
All right.
So we got a little taste of what it is to
work with field data sets, and I'll see
you at the next lecture, lecture 45.
Awesome.
See you there.