Hey guys, welcome to lecture 31.
This will be on Concatenate.
So we're going to be able
to join data frames and
matrices together,
almost like a sandwich if you will.
So we're gonna import the usual
numpy is np, panda's is pd,
and from panda's we'll import series and
data frame.
So, first let's learn about Concatenate
and numpy, so I'll create a matrix,
I'll just call it ARR1, and
I'll construct it using NP dot arrange.
I'll get nine points, and then I'll
reshape it into a three by three matrix.
And i'll type it so I can see it.
Okay, perfect.
So you have our three by
three of nine points.
So we can concatenate along axis one.
So to do that,
we just pass np dot concatenate,
and then the list of matrices or
arrays you want to concatenate.
So for instance, I can just get two copies
of that matrix and specify access one.
Let's see what happens.
So now they've been sandwiched together.
So I have a three by six, and you can
kind of see how they were attached.
So zero, one, two, three,
four, six, seven, eight, and
then a repeat of the same matrix.
If you wanna do it on a different axis,
you totally can.
You just got to specify.
So for instance,
let's say we wanted top to bottom.
We could again, just get two copies.
Of those arrays, and
then specify axis equals zero,
and now you'll see we have
done it from top to bottom.
Cool.
So that's how to concatenate in numpy.
So how about we try in pandas now?
So we'll start off by making some series.
So SER one, we'll just call it,
we'll make a series with
a point zero one two,
and we'll set its index to be T, U, V.
And we'll make another index,
we'll say series, and
this one we'll just give it two points,
two values, and
then its index will only
be two values as well.
We'll just choose some other letters.
Let's say X and Y.
And then we'll just see
how they ran correctly.
Okay, cool,
let's see them buff real quick.
So there's our first series.
And there's our second one,
so zero, one, two, T, U, V.
And the second one is 3, 4, X, Y, awesome.
So how do we concatenate in pandas?
We can do that by saying pd dot concat,
so that's the method you can call,
and then similar to numpy,
you just give the two series you want
to concatenate ,and it will
concatenate them together.
So now we have zero, one,
two, three, and four, and
the letter index for both of them.
You can also specify which access.
So, we can say concat, pd dot concat,
again we'll pass in those two series.
And, we can specify,
for instance, axis one.
And if I do this,
it will produce a data frame.
So create index zero and
one for the column names, and
then it will create a data frame
because you have some null information.
So your second series didn't have T,
U, V information and
your first series didn't have X,
Y information.
So it fills those with a null value, but
now you have a full data frame from
concatenate of those two series.
Awesome.
So let's say we wanted to add markers or
keys to the concat result.
So we could do this by
using a index hierarchy,
which we've learned about in the past.
So I can call concat on the two series,
SER one, SER two.
And I can set keys for them, so
I can call one let's say cat one, and
I can call the other one cat two.
Let me make sure those are strings,
all right let's see what
happens if I do that.
So now it was able to concatenate
both of the series, but
it's labeled them through
a hierarchical index, so
I can remember which series was which.
So, cat one is my first series, and
now cat two is the higher
index of my second series.
And then lastly,
everything that we've done works really
similarly in data frames, not just series.
So let's go ahead and
make two data frames.
We'll make D frame one.
Call it Data Frame, and
we'll call np dot random,
thought ran end since we didn't import it.
Specifically, we'll make a four
by three ran the matrix,
and then we'll set the columns equal to,
let's just say X, Y, Z.
And then we'll make a D frame two,
and we'll start it from Data Frame.
Again we'll say rand N, and
this case let's make a three
by three random matrix and
set the columns equal to Y, Q, and X.
So now that we've created those
data frames, let's go ahead and
take a quick look at each one, so
we know what we're dealing with.
That's what our data frame one looks like.
That's what our data frame two looks like.
So, they both have X and Y columns.
One of them has a z, the other done
doesn't, the second one has a Q.
The first one does not.
So let's see what happens when
we run them through concat.
So say,
pd dot concat to concatenate them, and
we'll run them through a list,
D frame one, D frame two.
See what the result is.
So as you'd expect,
it binds them together, and
you're gonna get null values for where
each data frame didn't have any values
under the columns of the other data frame.
So data frame 1 didnt have any Q values.
Q values so leave them all as none.
Data frame two didn't have any Z values,
so that puts a null there.
If we don't care about the index
information we can get rid of it, so
if we look at the concat result on
the index specifically, you'll see zero,
one, two three, and then again,
the index zero, one, two.
So it kept the index information when you
used concatenate on the two data frames.
If you didn't care about that index
information, and just wanted it
to keep going, for instance, zero,
one, two three, four, five, six.
You can make that happen.
You can just have it ignore the index.
So in order to do that,
we can call concat again on D frame one,
D frame two, and I can pass the argument,
ignore underscore index.
Set it to true, and it should ignore that
index and give us a continuous index now.
And that's what we've got.
So now we have zero, one,
two, three, four, five, six.
So that's about it as far
as using concatenate.
If you want to get a little more specific,
there's always more information and
documentation, so there's a link
in the I Python Notebook, and
I'll also write it down here.
I'll copy and paste it from the I Python
Notebooks that we have in the viewer, and
I'll leave it there for you.
So, to go, just a quick overview
using concatenate and numpy.
It's np dot concatenate, and
then in pandas, it's pd dot concat.
And it works on both series and
data frames.
And data frames panda will
take care of index values and
null values for you automatically.
And you can ignore the index to get
a continuous index, if you wish to do so.
All right, so you can check on
documentation if you want even more
detailed information, but until then we'll
go ahead and head off to lecture 32,
and we'll learn about combining data
frames with overlapping indexes.
Okay, I'll see you there.