Hey, guys.
Welcome to Lecture 16.
This lecture is gonna be on index objects,
which we've been learning about
in series and dataframes.
So let's start off, as always
just importing the regular stuff.
You can go ahead and just copy and
paste this if you want to.
I'm gonna import Series and DataFrame and
then import Import pandas as pd.
So let's just go over quickly
about series and index objects.
So we'll create a series,
we'll call it my_ser.
And we'll create this series by,
let's just make it a 1,
2, 3, 4 array or I should say,
list in this case.
We'll pass a list and
then we'll define the index as A,
B, C and D and then we can just take
a quick look at what that appears.
So now your index is A, B, C, D,
since you specifically set
that through that list and
your series is 1, 2, 3, 4.
Let's say, I wanted to get the index.
I can set that as an object,
I can say my_index.
And you might remember this
from previous lectures,
you can just get the index
by saying .index.
Let's go ahead and show what we set.
So now, we have our index unit.
Just don't worry about this u.
It won't actually be part of the index
it's just indicating it is the index.
So we have A, B, C, D, that's object type.
We can grab index values
just by calling them.
So lets say, you wanted to grab
that number two index value.
Think about what you
would expect to pop up.
So it's C, if you were thinking
B was going to pop-up,
remember that the index starts at zero.
So it would be zero, one, two.
So out of that list,
the third object appears as we called two.
Zero, one, two, so
that should be letter C.
Let's say that we wanted everything
passed two, then you might remember,
just from knowing Python that you can
use a colon to indicate everything.
So this should get us everything
past the second index marker and
it does, it gives us C and then D.
So those are basically the main
ways to mess around with index.
Got indexed to call it off the series and
then you can input
specific values you want,
just by calling them through
the arrays index value.
What happens if you try to change
an index value is a good thing to test?
So check my index,
my very first one, zero.
We should get an A out and we do.
If we wanted to change this, let's say,
we try to do 0 and let's say,
we try to change it to Z.
What would happen?
Well, you get an error, which is good.
So indexes don't support mutable
operations and what that means is that
indexes are immutable, so
you can't change them like this.
You'd have to pass an entirely new index,
which is good,
cuz that makes the DataFrames or
series really stable.
You can't just be change the index
values willy nilly in a sense.
If you want it to re-index,
we can do that.
So that will be lecture 17 on re-indexing.
Take a look and just make sure you
understood everything in this lecture,
we'll be doing tons of indexing and
re-indexing in the course.
This is just a brief intro on it,
so you'll see this again and again.
I'll see you at lecture 17
to learn about re-indexing.