Okay, everybody.
In this video,
I'm just going to be doing a quick
overview on the binomial distribution.
So the binomial distribution,
it's a specific type of a discrete
probability distribution.
So let's go ahead and
see an example question first and
then I'll go over
the binomial distribution.
So in this example let's say we have two
players and they're playing basketball.
So there's player A and player B.
And player A takes an average
of 11 shots per game and
has an average success rate of 72%.
And then player B takes an average
of 15 shots per game, but
has an average success rate of 48%.
So we're gonna have two questions here.
What's the probability that player
A makes six shots in an average game, and
what's the probability that player B
makes six shots in an average game?
Now pay attention closely to
what the question's asking.
It's asking exactly six shots, so not at
least six shots, but exactly six shots.
That's gonna be important later on.
Okay, so
how do you classify a binomial experiment?
So you're gonna need to
meet some conditions.
So in order to classify this
as a binomial experiment,
it needs to consist of a sequence
of trials, of n trials that is.
And there can only be two
exclusive outcomes for
each trial, a success and a failure.
So an example of this is a coin flip.
You can have heads be a success, and
tails be failure, or vice versa.
Or in our case we have
the basketball shot.
Either you make it, success,
or you miss, failure.
So it just needs to have
two exclusive outcomes.
Another condition we need to meet is
that the probability of success is P.
Then the probability of failure
needs to be defined as q or 1- p.
So you only have two probabilities,
that of success and failure.
And if you sum them up, it equals one.
The entire probability space.
And lastly, we need all the trials
to be independent of each other.
So, for example,
on coin flips your first coin flip
can't affect your 100th coin flip.
All right, so what's the formula for
the binomial distribution?
Well, the formula for the PMF, or
the probability mass function.
The reason it's a mass function is
cause it's a discrete distribution.
Well that turns out to be
the probability the X = k, so
that you get k number of successes is
equal to the combination of (n,k),
times the probability of a success to
the power of k times (1- p) or q, which is
just the probability of failure,
to the power of n- k.
So n is the number of trials.
K is the number of successes.
P is the probability of success.
And (1- p) is the probability of failure.
If you're confused by
this notation of C(n,k),
that's just known as
a combination probability.
And you can go ahead and
check out the combinations notebook if you
want to get an overview of that, right.
So if we break this down,
this means that we need to get
exactly k successes in n trials.
So we want k successes, so that's where
we get the P to the power of k term.
And we want n- k failures.
So that's where we get the 1- p
to the power of n- k failures.
And finally, the combination or
k successes in n trials.
These are the different ways of
putting k successes in n trials, or
choosing k out of n.
So we multiply all these together, and
that gets you the probability of exactly
that many successes and
failures in those n trials.
So I said before, C(n,k) just
refers to the number of possible
combinations of n things,
taken k at a time.
It's also equal to n!
over k!
times (n- k)!
That's its definition.
So that's what you can input
mathematically to get that number.
Great, so let's go ahead and
try out the example problem.
We set up player A.
Player A had a probability
of success of 0.72, and
it took 11 shots per game on average.
And we want him to make six shots, so
I can import scipy.misc or M-I-C-S,
excuse me, M-I-S-C, as sc.
And then using that,
I can call combination.
So this is just for me to avoid having to
write this factorial every single time.
So you can do it by just setting
up your n number of trials.
So in this case for
player A, I have it as n_a.
And k successes, and now we put it
together to get that probability.
So combination A, p_a to
the power of k, probability of
a failure to the power of n- k here,
sub A because it's just for player A.
So what I'm highlighting right
here is just the Python written
out version of this right here,
that probability mass function.
And then to get the answer in
a percentage form, I'm just gonna say
100 times the answer, because it will
just give it to us in a decimal at first.
And then I just repeated all the steps for
player B.
So again,
you can just open up the notebook and
take your time to look through over this.
I'm going a little quickly just because
this is mainly just an appendix overview.
Yeah.
So then I'm going to print the answers.
And so we find out that the probability of
player A making six shots in an average
game is 11.1%.
And the probability of player B making
six shots in an average game is 17%.
So we know that even though player
B is technically a worse shooter,
because he or she takes more shots,
they'll have a higher chance of
making six shots in an average game.
But remember, this was the odds of
making exactly six shots in a game.
What about a higher amount of shots?
Will player A's higher probability
take a stronger effect then?
So let's look at what's the probability
of making nine shots a game for
either player.
So we just did the exact same thing here.
Let me fix this typo.
Remains the same, all right.
And if we look at these odds now, the
probability of player A making nine shots
in an average game is 22.4%,
and the same for B is 13.4%.
So now we see that players A [SOUND] gives
better odds of making exactly nine shots.
So we need to keep in mind that
we are asking the probability of
making exactly those amount of shots.
So that's a different question than what's
the probability of player A making at
least nine shots.
So now that we looked at an example and
at the probability distribution,
let's go ahead and
investigate the mean and standard
deviation of the binomial distribution.
So the mean of the binomial distribution
is just equal to n times p.
So this intuitively makes sense because
the average number of successes should be
the total trials multiplied by your
average success rate, so n x p.
And then you can see also that standard
deviation is just equal to the square root
of n x q x p.
So now we can ask, what's the average
number of shots each player will make
in a game, plus or
minus a standard distribution?
So again, I just plug into
the formulas here to get the mean and
the standard deviation.
And player A will make and average
of 8 plus or minus 1 shots per game.
Player B will make an average of 7 plus or
minus 2 shots per game.
So if you notice here I used a cutoff for
that floating point.
So initially using this python script you
would get, for example, 8.2 shots a game.
But that doesn't really make sense,
because you can't have
half a basketball shot, so
I cut it off when I was printing it.
But you can go ahead and
input more decimal values if you
wanna get more precise about it.
Okay, so let's go ahead and
see how to use scipy to automatically
create the binomial distribution.
So we can say from scipy.stats
import binom, B-I-N-O-M.
And if we wanna get particular stats such
as the mean or variance, or the skew or
kurtosis, you can just say,
in this example,
I'm just grabbing the mean and variance.
And you just go binom.stats
method on it and
input your n and your p values.
So here I got 7.92 and 1.48.
So if you look at that, that actually
matches up for manual methods.
So up here, I had 8 plus or minus 1.
Remember I was cutting it off.
So if I don't round using scipy.stats,
I get 7.92 and 1.48,
which was rounded down to one.
Great.
So now instead of having
to do all this manual work,
you can just call scipy.stats binom.
And you can get the mean variance and
other statistical
properties automatically.
You can also get
the probability mass function.
So lets go ahead and try another example.
Imagine you're flipping a fair coin.
You're probability of
getting heads is p = 0.5.
So we'll have that be
success in this example.
So what's you're probability mass
function, or your PMF, look like for
10 coin flips?
So I'm gonna import numpy as np.
Set up the new example so
I'll say, n equals ten coin flips.
Probability of success is 0.5.
Then I'm gonna set up n successes.
Remember indexing starts at zero.
So I'm gonna say x is range(n + 1).
And then in order to create
the probability mass function,
it's really easy now that we use scipy,
I just say binom.pmf to call
a probability mass function method on it.
And then it takes the inputs x, n and p.
We'll have that equal to Y.
So we'll show what Y is equal to.
So we have this array here.
And let's go ahead and
visualize it by plotting it.
So to do that, I'm just gonna
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt.
So for this kind of a simple plot
Seaborn is kind of overkill, so
I'm just gonna use matplotlib.
Then I'm gonna say plt.plot, the x,
the Y, and set just 0 dot points here.
Sorry that's not actually a 0,
just an o dot points, excuse me, for
little blue dots.
And then I just set the title by plt.title
and then the x label and Y label.
And that's what the probability
mass function looks like for
that particular problem.
So go ahead and go back, take your time
to look over this entire notebook.
This is just a quick overview
of the binomial distribution.
The main conclusion here that you want
to take away are really the probability
mass function and the conditions on
what makes a binomial experiment.
So remember,
any consists of a sequence of n trials,
there can only be two exclusive outcomes,
either success or failure.
And those two probabilities,
p and q, need to equal one, and
all the trials need to be
independent of each other.
And that's the good test to know if
something is a binomial distribution.
Great.
So if we scroll down here,
there's plenty more resources for
you to learn more about
the binomial distribution.
Wikipedia's great, StatTrek right here,
and then mathworld.wolfram.com.
So go ahead and click any of these
links if you're interested in
further learning about
the binomial distribution.
All right,