Hello everybody, and welcome to Lecture 9.
In this lecture we'll be
going over indexing arrays.
So we're gonna import numpy as np.
Alt+Enter to get a new cell and run it.
Let's go ahead and create a sample array.
So, in this case I'll just call it arr and
I'm gonna set it equal to np.arrange, and
let's go from 0 to 11, so in this case.
And then let's go ahead and show it.
Think about what you expect to see
here before you click Alt+Enter.
And let's go ahead and see it.
Okay, so hopefully you figured
out that the index starts at 0,
so in this case calling it all
the way to 11 means I would get 10,
here we go, 11 points.
Excuse me.
0 through 10.
And if I wanna get a value at an index,
I can say call the value at 8, index 8,
and that should be equal to 8.
Which makes sense cuz if I go 0, 1, 2,
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, I'll end up at 8.
Great.
So what if I wanna get the values
in a particular range?
I can also do that by inputting
a range from 1 all the way to 5,
and remember,
this should go to 1 before 5, so
it should output 1, 2, 3, and 4.
Let's go ahead and see if that's true.
And it did, so it outputted 1,
2, 3, and 4 in your array.
Perfect.
And let's go ahead and
get the values in a range again.
So how about 0 through 5?
And that gets us 0, 1, 2, 3, 4.
Okay.
So that's how you can
get values in a range.
You can also set a value
with an index range.
So I can say from the range 0,
whoops, excuse me.
0 to 5,
I can set all those values equal to 100.
So before you click Enter,
think about what's gonna happen.
I'm telling Python to say, hey,
all the values from 0 to 5,
go ahead and set them equal to 100.
But remember, you start at 0, so
it should be 0, 1, 2, 3, and 4.
Those five numbers should be equal to 100.
And then it will go 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
So we should expect five instances of the
number 100, and then 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Let's go ahead and
see what our array looks like now.
And we've got just that.
So here we have the five 100s.
So 0, 1, 2, 3, and 4.
We're turning to 100.
And then we have 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
All right, perfect.
Now let's go ahead and
just reset this array.
So I'm gonna say np.arrange(0,11) again.
Let's see what it looks like, so
I have my 0 through 10, the 11 points.
And now we can do slices of an array.
So I can set an object to be
equal to slice_of_arr and
set that equal to the range from 0 to 6.
So in this case I would expect
slice_of_arr to, or array,
depending how you wanna say it,
to be equal to 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
5.
So those are six values there.
And then let's just type it out, so
we can see what that looks like.
Okay, and there we have it.
Here are the six values,
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and
now we created a slice of
the array in the same fashion.
We can go ahead and change the slice.
So I can say slice_of_arr or array.
I could say, using a colon,
say all the elements in that
array are now equal to 99.
And let's go ahead and check if that
is what happens and that's the case.
So using that colon, you can select
all of the elements in your array.
So now note that the changes also
occur in our original array.
So what do I mean by that?
I'm going to show you the original array.
Now you might be thinking,
whoa, that's weird.
I was only changing values in
slice_of_arr, not in my array itself.
Well, in numpy, this data isn't copied,
it's just a view of the original array.
So this avoids memory problems.
That way you don't have several
copies of your array floating around.
You only have one copy of your array.
And if you grab slices of it,
and change stuff,
change the elements,
it's going to affect your original array.
So that's something to really keep in mind
when you're messing around with arrays.
If you don't want that to happen and you
want to get a copy, you gotta be explicit.
So if I say arr_copy = arr,
that will still affect
your original array.
It's not gonna actually make a copy.
What I have to do is explicitly say copy.
So .copy(), no extra arguments.
And then I can look at this array and
now I have a copy of it.
All right, great.
So let's learn about
indexing in a 2D array.
So let me make an object called arr_2d.
And use np.arrary.
And then as we've done in the past,
I'm gonna put in several lists.
So I can say something like, let's see.
Let's go ahead and
go in powers of or counts of five.
So like 5, 10, 15.
That'll be one list.
Then 20, 25, 30.
That's another list.
And then my next one I can say 35, 40, 45.
All right.
And then let's go ahead and
show that by typing it out.
All right, excellent.
So now I have a three by three 2d array.
Awesome.
So how can I index this?
I'll type out my arr_2d,
and if I want to see a row,
I can type in the index of that row.
So think about for a second before you
click Alt+Enter, what this should be,
and remember in Python and
numpy, your index starts at 0.
So what do we expect to see here?
We see the row of 20, 25, and 30.
So that makes sense because
your index starts at 0, and
what I mean by that is if I called 0,
I would see the first row here.
5, 10, 15.
So here's your 0 index row,
here's your 1 index row, and
then here's your 2 index row.
All right, great.
What if you want
an individual element value?
Well, you can do that as well.
You can just say the row you want and
then also ask for the column you want.
Okay, so think about it for a second.
What value should this get me?
I'm asking for index 1 row.
And index 0 column And
hopefully you got that it was gonna be 20,
so that makes sense.
Here's my index 1 row, and
then that was my index 0 column.
Great.
Okay, so we can also do 2d array slicing.
So how does that work?
Let's go ahead and
see that 2d array again.
So there's my 2d array.
Let's say I wanted a 2,
2 shape array from the top right corner.
So I wanted the 10, 15 and the 25,
30 as its own 2 by 2 array.
So I can just do that by taking a slice.
And so what I'm gonna ask for
is everything up to 2 and
then 1 and beyond as far as the columns.
So let's see if that works.
And it does, excellent.
So if you look at, for instance,
the columns here, I asked for
the one column index and
everything beyond that.
So that would be these two last columns.
And so that's what allowed it to
take the 10, 25 and the 15, 30.
And then to cut off the 40 and
the 45, I ask for
everything until the second indexed row.
Okay, great.
Now what else can we do?
So we've been able to take
some 2d array slices.
We can check out the bottom row if
we wanted to by saying 2 there.
That would have been the bottom row.
Perfect.
And we can go on to something
called fancy indexing.
So fancy indexing,
I'll show you what it means.
So we can say something like, let's
just make this array another 2d array.
I'll won't put the underscore
to differentiate it, and
I'm gonna make a zeroes array.
And if you remember from some
previous lectures, we can say zeros.
Then let's go ahead and input the size,
so I'll make it a 10 by 10.
Let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
Okay, here's my 10 by 10
2d array of all zeros.
And looks like they're all floats.
That's why there's a decimal there.
And now I can get the length of the array.
I can say, object arr_length,
_length, = arr2d.shape of that first.
And if I look at that I should get,
whoops.
Equal to 10.
So it has a length of 10.
So that's how I could get the length.
So now we can set up the array.
So I'm gonna say for i in range.
Length of the array, so for i in range
10 basically is what I'm saying.
That array element value of i = i.
Okay, so
now that we've done that operation,
I'm gonna check out the multi-dimensional
array but go ahead and
think about what we just did here,
as far as this function.
So, we said for every i in the range,
arr_length and that arr_length was 10.
Go ahead and
set that element there equal to 1.
So what should that do?
That should give you straight ones.
All right, so that makes sense so far.
What if I said equal to i?
Now let's go ahead and
see what happened to our array.
Go ahead and think about what this
should look like before you check it.
Hopefully you thought about it right and
you got 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 all the way to 9.
And then everything across is yet
the same.
So we only changed those
across the rows themselves.
So every row, every value in that row,
equals that count number.
Okay, so fancy indexing allows for
us to do the following.
So we can say something like arr2d.
And just index it by the values in
that row so we can say 2, 4, 6, 8.
Great, and so that will give us
the second, the fourth, the sixth, and
the eighth rows for indexing.
And we can do this in any order,
which is why we get the term fancy.
So it doesn't have to be in order,
we can just do random rows here,
so I can say 6, 4, 2, and
7, and that will return the 6,
4, 2, and 7 index rows.
And that's fancy indexing.
So main takeaways here are, again,
we reviewed how to create arrays,
and the main takeaway is how to index.
So remember, this is really important
if you wanna explicitly make a copy,
you've gotta state that .copy.
Otherwise, changes you make and slices of
the array will affect your original array.
And then for indexing you can ask for
the row or you can get the row and
the column and you can use
colons to get certain slices or
chunks out of your
multi-dimensional arrays.
And that's it for indexing arrays and
we've finished off with fancy indexing.
Okay, next up we'll have Lecture 10.
I'll see you there.