Hey everyone, and welcome to the third
video in the Supervised Learning
linear regression series.
So in the previous video, we just
completed a single variable regression, or
a univariate regression, using
the least squares method with Python.
And remember we created this plot up here.
So now let's see if we can find
the error in our fitted line.
So if we check out the documentation
here on this link, checking out this
documentation, we see that the resulting
array has the total squared error.
So for each element, it checks
the difference between the line and
the true value.
Remember that was our original d value.
So it basically looks around and sees how
long that green line or that d value was.
So it takes that, squares it and
returns the sum of all these.
So that was the sum d squared
value we discussed earlier.
So all those distances
between your data point and
your fit line squared and then summed.
It might a little easier though to
understand the root mean squared error,
which is really similar to
the standard deviation.
So in this case,
to find the root mean square error,
we divide by the number of elements and
then take the square root.
There's also an issue of biased and
unbiased regression, but
we'll delve into these
topics a little later.
For now let's go ahead and
see how we can get the root mean squared
error of the line we just fitted.
And you can go ahead and
check out the normal distribution
lectures in the statistics appendix
if you need a little bit more review
as far as the standard deviation.
But we're basically kind of getting a type
of standard deviation using this method.
So, let's go ahead and
jump back to the live coding.
So what we're gonna do now is
in order to get the error,
I'm gonna get the resulting array, so I'm
gonna say make an object called results.
I then call again the n
p dot linear algebra
dot least squares method on those x and
y we made earlier.
And my total error is stored at index one.
If you look up the documentation,
it'll let you know that.
And a lot of machine learning,
as far as getting to know your tools,
is looking up the documentation.
So, it's gonna be a lot of reading
throughout these machine learning lectures
that you're gonna have to do
through the documentation.
So we're gonna set the total
error as the result index one.
And then in order to get the root mean
squared error, root mean squared error,
or rmse, I can take
the square roots of that total error or
error_total object I just made.
And divide by the length of x.
So this is, if you're familiar with
what a standard deviation looks like,
you can kinda see how this
equation looks pretty familiar.
Now, let's just go ahead and
print our results.
I'll print the root mean square error was,
and
in this case, I'll cut off
the floating point at two points.
R, s, m, e.
And oops.
Root mean squared error.
Okay, it look our root mean
squared error was 6.60,
as far as up to two
places past the decimal.
So since the root mean square error or
rmse,
corresponds approximately
to the standard deviation,
we can now say the price of
a house won't vary more than two
times the rmse value 95% of the time.
And so what I mean by that if we hop
over back to the iPython notebook.
This is really similar to
the normal distribution.
So go ahead and check out this link.
It will just take you here to the 68, 95,
99.7 rule, it has to do with the normal
distribution and the standard deviations.
So what we could basically make out
this root mean square error to be,
is that 95% of the time,
your value's gonna be at least within
two times that root mean squared error.
So you can reasonably expect a house price
to be within $13,200 of our fit line.
Now remember,
this is in the unit of thousands.
Okay, so go ahead and review your
normal distribution appendix lecture.
If this didn't quite make sense to you,
but hopefully it did.
Remember we're just basically
getting this error that we discussed
up here earlier, the distance between all
these lines, squaring them, summing them.
And then dividing it by the number
of data points we had, and
then square rooting that whole thing.
And that basically corresponds
to a standard deviation here.
And since we're within two standard
deviations of it or 6.6 times 2,
95% of the time, you're only
gonna be off by two times that rmse,
that root mean square error value.
All right.
So that's how you get your error.
Now let's move on to the cool part
using scikit learn to implement
a multivariate regression.
So, we're gonna keep moving along.
And we'll keep moving along
with using scikit learn
to a multivariable regression.
So, it's gonna be a similar approach to
the above example that we just did, but
scikit learn will be able to
take into account more than just
the single data variable
effect on the target.
So we'll start by importing
the linear regression library.
Let's go ahead and
check out this link here.
So again, I really encourage you to
really fully read and understand
the documentation as we go along through
these machine learning lectures.
You'll really get the most out if
you completely read through all this
documentation, but we're importing
from sklearn.linear_model library,
the linear regression.
So this does,
as you can see here, an ordinary,
least-squares, linear regression.
All right.
So hopping back here.
The sklearn.linear_model.LinearRegression
class is what's known as an estimator.
So what an estimator does, is estimators
predict a value based on observed data.
So in sklearn, all estimators
implement the fit and predict methods.
So the fit method is used to learn
the parameters of the model.
And the later method, the predict method
is used to predict the value of a response
variable for an explanatory variable
used in the learning parameter,
such as the crime rate or
the number of houses.
And your prediction would
be the price of that house.
So now it's easy to experiment with
different models using scikit learn,
because all the estimators implement
the fit and predict methods.
So go ahead and
read through the documentation
to get a clear idea of what that really
means as far as making estimator class.
And implementing the fit and
predict methods.
But hopefully for a linear regression,
it's pretty intuitive
as far as giving data.
All this different housing data and
then trying to predict a house price from
that data based on what you already know.
Okay.
So, let's go ahead and
jump back to the live coding and
we're gonna import sklearn,
or scikit learn, and
from sklearn.linear_model
import LinearRegression.
Okay, so now we're going to create
a linear regression object.
Afterwards, we'll go ahead and
do some more stuff on it so,
gonna make a linear regression object.
Call it lreg, and then I could
do that just by setting it equal
to LinearRegression close parentheses.
Great, so if we take a quick look
over at the documentation here,
the linear regression has a bunch
of different methods on it.
Fit, get parameters, predict, score,
subparameters, decision function.
So you can go ahead and read throughout
the documentation on this, and
there's actually, what's really,
really nice about the scikit learn,
is there's tons and tons of examples.
So you can actually see here,
there's already a linear regression
example done it out for you.
So in case you want even more, besides
what this lecture offers, you can come
here, and they're gonna do a very
similar thing using a diabetes data set.
So you can always come back to
the documentation and check out examples.
There's examples for most everything
in the scikit learn library.
It's a really, really nice documentation.
So I encourage you to check that out
after you're done with these lectures
just to get another set
of examples to look at.
But if we just take a look
at pressing tab, oops.
You can look at the different methods.
So.
We have all these different methods.
We have fit, fit_intercept,
normalize, predict, score.
And what we want to do, is we're gonna
be really using just a few of them.
So hopping back over, the functions
we're gonna be using are the fit, which
fits a linear model, the predict, which
is used to predict the y using the linear
model with the estimated coefficients.
And then the score, which returns
the coefficient of the termination,
otherwise known as an r squared value.
And really all that gives is just
the measure how well the observed
outcomes are replicated by the model.
If you wanna learn more about
the coefficient determination,
again Wikipedia is your friend here.
Click the link I provided and
it'll basically give you more context
of what the r squared value means.
But a perfect r squared
value would just be 1, and
in that case its a perfectly linear fit.
And you can judge how
well your data fits to
your line based on that coefficient of
determination, your r squared values.
All right.
So, lets go ahead and start the multi
variable regression analysis
by separating our Boston data frame back
into data columns and the target columns.
So, the way I'm going to
do that is like this.
I'm gonna say my data columns as X_multi.
And I'm gonna set that as
my data frame boston_df.
And drop the price.
Remember, in order to drop a column,
you gotta pass a one index and then my y
target is gonna be equal
to boston_df.Price.
And now we have our X_multi
equal to everything
in the data frame minus the price and the
Y_target is now just equal to the price.
And notice we didn't use in play so
we haven't effected our original
Boston data frame permanently.
So finally we're ready to pass the X and
Y using the linear regression object.
The way to do that is just lreg,
that linear regression option we made.
And now we just pass those
into the fit method.
And now I've created a linear
regression fit and we can go ahead and
check the intercept and
the number of coefficients.
So, the way to do that is
by calling those methods.
So I can say, print, and I'll type
it out and then break it down here.
So the estimated intercept coefficient is.
And I'll leave it to two
places after the decimal.
And then I call the intercept
method underscore off it,
and then I'll also print.
The number of coefficients we used.
Which should have been 13 if
you remember from the dataset.
And I'm just gonna call the length of that
linear regression coefficient method.
And remember, just check the documentation
to get a true understanding of what these
intercepts and
coefficient methods return to you.
So come over here and
learn about the actual
linear regression class in scikit learn.
So, whoops,
put the b in the wrong spot here, number,
so the number of coefficients was 13,
as we expected.
It's the length of that coefficient
method, and the number, the estimated
intercept coefficient is 36.49, so
what we've done is we've basically, and
I'm hopping over back to
the iPython notebook here.
We've basically made an equation for
a line.
But instead of just one coefficient, m,
and an intercept b,
we now have 13 coefficients.
So to get an idea of what this looks like,
you can check out the documentation
link here for linear regression.
And if you notice here they have
a following set of methods for regression.
And they have an equation here as well
as a coefficient in the intercept.
But what you've done is, hopping
over back to that iPython notebook,
is you've made an equation of a line,
but instead of y equals m x plus b, or
in this case it's written as y
equals w not plus w 1 times x 1,
you've gone all the way
up to 13 coefficients,
because you're using 13 different
types of data variables.
Okay, so what we're going to do next
is set up a data frame showing all the
features and their estimated coefficients
obtained from that fit that we just did,
that linear regression.
So basically scikit learn is doing
everything we did manually in Python
using numpie in one simple
step with this fit method.
So let's go ahead and
set up that data frame.
I'm just gonna type it out and
then break it down for you.
I'll make a data frame called
coefficient or coeff_df.
Okay, so I set a data frame from Features.
Now I'm going to set a new column lining
up the coefficients from the linear
regression.
I'll call it a coefficient
estimate column.
And I'll have it equal
to a series of pandas.
And I don't need to call pd
here since I imported series
of the coefficient method.
And I'll show that data frame.
So let me break down what I did here.
I create a coefficient data frame
based on the columns of my
original Boston data frame.
Renamed that columns just features so
made this columns a features.
All those different
features from our data set.
And then made a new column
called coefficient estimate and
I just passed all those coefficients here.
So when were in this last print statement,
we just printed out the length for
those coefficients.
So what your fit did.
You use scikit learn.
You fit a multiple regression, multiple
variable regression, using this X_multi.
And scikit learn was able to return
basically these coefficients that are used
to build up this equation of a line.
Okay, great.
So just like we initially plotted out,
it seems if we look at these coefficients,
the highest one, 3.8,
actually corresponds with the room,
the average number of rooms.
So it seems like its
the highest correlated feature
between a particular data feature and
the house price was the number of rooms.
So in the next video what we're gonna
do is move on to predicting prices and
using training and validation datasets.
So just a quick overview
of what we did here.
We were able to now use the scikit learn
library to perform a linear regression.
There was a lot of documentation
reading to be done.
But it was definitely worth it, and
we were able to get a result and
set them into a panda's data frame.
Okay, so I'll see you at the next video,
where we'll be performing step seven and
step eight, where we'll use training and
validation sets, predict our prices, and
then, finally,
we'll see some residual plots.
All right, thanks guys,
and I'll see you there.