Hey, guys.
Welcome to lecture 17.
This will be on reindexing.
So, last lecture, we went a little
bit over indexes, how they work,
how you can call certain index values.
We're gonna learn how you can reindex and
change the index if you wanted to.
So we're gonna import
the usual NumPy as np.
From pandas we're gonna import Series and
DataFrame.
We're gonna import pandas as pd.
And last thing we're gonna do which
is a little different from usual,
is from numpy.randn,
we're gonna import the randn,
which will grab numbers
with a normal distribution.
So, we'll just use this later in this
lecture just to grab some random numbers.
Let's go Alt+Enter,
import all the libraries we'll be using.
Let's go ahead and create a new series,
we'll call it ser1 and
we'll build the series,
the usual method so
we'll call the self to be,
just a list 1, 2, 3, 4, and
then we'll set the index as A, B, C, D.
And then we'll show what that looks like,
cool.
So, now we have a series A, B, C,
D index and the values are 1, 2, 3, 4.
So let's say you wanted
to reindex to rearrange the data to
a new index, how would this work?
To show you, let's go ahead and
start building a new series.
We'll call it a ser2, and this new
series is gonna be built off series one,
and now we're gonna call reindex on ser1,
our first series.
And we'll pass a new reindexing list.
So, we'll call it A, B, C, D, and we'll
go all the way to F on this new index and
see what happens.
Let's go ahead and show it, awesome.
So pandas since it's very good at
dealing with missing value points,
when you reindexed it,
E and F didn't exist in your first series,
this ser1, so
it automatically just gave it null
values for E and F which is really nice.
So, you don't have to worry about doing
a perfect reindex or not having values for
your reindex, pandas will automatically
give you null values there.
We can also fill in values for new, and
since we write, so for example,
if we reindex our second
series that we just made.
We'll go A, B, C, D, E, F, and
now we'll bring you all the way to G.
If we wanted to fill certain values,
we can pass the argument fill_value and
set that equal to something,
in this case I'll set it equal to zero.
So, that should do,
is instead of passing a null,
it will pass a zero as
the new index values, cool.
And that worked, so our original series
two was 1, 2, 3, 4, null, null with E, F.
I reindexed it and
I added G to the index and
I also passed the argument
fill_value equal zero.
So since G was the new index, it will
be filled as a zero which we saw here.
E and F stay null since those
existed in the previous index.
All right, cool.
You can use particular methods for
filling values.
So, to demonstrate that,
let's go ahead and create a third series.
We'll call it ser3.
And in this case, let's go ahead and pass
just a list of countries as the series.
USA, Mexico, and
Canada, all right, and
we'll have the index just
be some list of numbers,
let's go 0, 5, 10.
All right, let's go ahead and show that.
Cool, so we have our third series.
The values are just USA, Mexico,
Canada and the index is 0, 5, 10.
Let's say we wanted to reindex this
all the way from 0 to 14,
how would we do that?
And, what would we want to fill?
So, we can all reindex,
and for the reindex self
we'll just pass range 15 and
to give you a better idea of the range
will do, I'll actually pass it separately.
So, I'll make a new object called ranger,
and call this range 15.
Now, let's take a look at ranger is.
So range just makes a list of
15 points as we've seen before.
And NumPy, and it goes from 0 to 14
since the index starts at 0 for a raise.
So back to reindexing this
third series we made.
I'll call ranger, which would be the same
as just typing range(15) in there.
That's the argument and
I can pass the argument method.
So what kind of method do we
wanna fill for interpolating
values between the new index,
indexes that we're gonna put into it.
So one argument we can pass is F fill.
So this stands for forward fill.
So what's gonna happen is,
right now our index on series three is 0,
5, and 10, but we're gonna be
filling it with a bunch of values.
So, 0 will have USA.
1, 2, 3, 4 would be null if we
didn't have a method argument here.
So what's gonna happen instead
when we say forward fill,
it's gonna grab the previous value,
USA, and forward fill it for
the next indexes until it hits
something that already had a value.
So that will be 5 next go.
And then for 6, 7, 8,
9, it's gonna forward fill those with
the previous value, which was Mexico.
And then once it hits 10,
that already has a value, Canada, and
it'll forward fill
the rest of them Canada.
So let's see if that works.
And that's what we get.
So it forward filled USA into
the next four indexes, index values.
It forward filled Mexico into
the next four index values, and
it forward filled Canada.
There's different methods you can pass.
You can check out the documentation for
the different methods.
You can do a backwards fill,
which would be basically opposite,
Mexico would then fill everything back,
and Canada would fill everything back.
And then these guys would be null,
since there's nothing ahead of them.
So, let's say you wanted to reindex rows,
or not just rows but
columns, or even both of them.
How would you do that?
So, in order to see that effect,
we'll make a whole data frame.
So we'll call this object D frame.
We'll call DataFrame.
And how should we build this DataFrame?
Let's say,
what do we want the self to be?
We'll call 25 random numbers and
then what we're gonna do is pass or
call reshape on this.
So randn(25) will just get
you a list from 0 to 24,
and then if we call reshape,
we can actually,
instead of just having it be a straight
vector, we can indicate it to be a matrix.
So this can be a 5 by 5 matrix.
So those will be the values of the data
frame, should be random numbers, 5 by 5.
Let's go ahead and give it an index, so
the index for all the rows, again,
we'll just use letter index here.
Let's skip C,
just to show you in effect later
on and we'll go to F so we have five,
one for each row of this 5 by 5 matrix.
And then if we want to set the columns,
we just pass the columns arguments.
And, we'll just label them col1, col2, and
I'm running out of space here so
I'm actually gonna start this on a new
line, remember to have the comma there.
Col2, col3, col4, and there's
gonna be five columns since this is a 5
by 5 matrix, so we'll stop with col5.
So that will be our DataFrame.
It's gonna be, we asked for
25 random numbers,
we reshaped them into a 5 by 5 array.
So that's the values of that data frame.
Then we set the index of the rows just
to be A, B, D, E, F, we skipped C.
And the columns will just be called col1,
2, 3, 4, 5,
you can call the columns
whatever you want.
And then we'll type dframe, just so
we can see what it looks like, cool.
So like I said, A, B, D, E,
F is your index for your rows.
And we have our column names, and
you can see the random numbers
that are filled in the data frame.
So since we forgot C,
let's reindex onto the data frame.
So we'll call a new data frame dframe2 and
we'll have that equal to the old data
frame with a reindex called on it.
And, in this new index, we won't forget C.
And then,
we'll go all the way to F.
So what's gonna happen when we do this?
Let's find out.
We'll call dframe2.
Think about what you think is gonna happen
and how pandas deals with the reindex
values, then if your intuition is right
then you should have guessed that it would
add null values in for that entire C row
just as if we scroll up it did before
for the values in the series
when it was reindexed.
Cool, we can also
explicitly reindex columns.
So, let's go ahead and
just make a list called new columns.
Call it col1, col2, and
let's go all the way
out to col6 this time,
since we only went to 5, previously.
So we make a list, new columns, and
now we're gonna grab
the dframe2 that we just made,
this one here above with that new zero,
and we're gonna call reindex on it.
And the reindex for
a reindexing of the columns,
you have to call columns specifically.
And then you can say equals, and we could
either manually type in this list or
just call it using its name, new columns.
So think about what you expect
the data frame to look like now.
Hopefully, you guessed right.
Column 6, you added it in and
panda's automatically put in null
values for that entire column, cool.
You can reindex really
quickly just using .ix.
We'll see more of this in the future.
We've seen a little bit of it in
the original indexing lecture, but
we'll see much more in the future.
Just to give you a little taste of it,
let's see the original DataFrame, dframe.
And we can call ix to reindex,
the first argument takes is your rows,
so we'll just call it A, B, C,
D, oops E, F, and
then the second argument
it'll take is the columns,
so we'll just pass new columns.
So, this is our original dframe.
Remember, it's missing the C and
it doesn't have that column 6, and
now using ix,
we're gonna really quickly reindex it.
Just in one single, quick step.
So, Alt+Enter to see that, and boom.
Now, you have the same
dframe that was dframe2.
So, instead of having to
reindex everything separately,
the faster way to do it is using ix.
And we'll see more of this in the future.
All right, excellent, so
I'll see you in lecture 18, and
we'll learn more about data frames and
how they work.
All right, see you there.