Hey everyone, this is part two.
So in the last part of the first project,
we looked at a general overview of
the data and we're still trying to look
into further details of the first
question, Who are the passengers?
So let's go ahead and continue on
with the KDE plots we're gonna make.
So what we wanna do is use
a facet grid with Seaborn,
in addition to the pandas
data frame we made.
So how can we do that?
Well, we can set an object called fig
as the figure, and then call sns for
Seaborn, and
then Facetgrid is what we're gonna use.
And facetgrid allows you to do
multiple plots on one figure.
So the first argument I'm gonna
pass through is our data frame,
and then in this case I'll have the hue
be sex or the gender of the passengers.
And I'm going to set one more argument,
aspect = 4, and
that will just set the aspect ratio.
And then what I'm gonna do after that is
I'm gonna use map to plot all the possible
KDE plots for
the age columns by hue choice.
So what I mean by that is if I say,
fig.map method, I'm going to map
a bunch of KDE plots, and
those plots will use the age column.
And the KDE plots will have shade=True.
So these are gonna be the multiple
KDE plots based on age.
And then what I'm gonna do is
before I click Shift+Enter so
we can see the plots, is I'm gonna set
the x max limit by the oldest passenger.
So I'll say the oldest,
make an object called oldest.
And I'll have that be
equal to the max age.
And since we know no one can be negative
years old, I will set the limit,
the x limit, so
I can do that by putting the set method.
So fig.set(xlim = and we'll have it be,
just so we can input, the 0 to oldest.
Oops.
And then we'll have to manually add
a legend just by calling add_legend.
All right, so what did I do here?
Let's take a quick look at
it before we click Enter.
We created an object called fig or
figure and
that was done by using Seaborn.facetgrid.
And we've said the titanic_df for
our data frame we're using,
set the hue equal to sex, so male, female.
And then we changed the aspect ratio so
it'll look nice,
a little more stretched out so
it fits our window well.
And then we mapped the KDE
plots from the age column.
Then we set all this
equal to the max age and
we set the x limits from 0 to the oldest,
and we manually added a legend.
Let's go ahead and see if that all worked.
And there we have it.
So now we have a KDE plot on
the ages on male versus female.
We could've done the same thing using that
person column we made to include children.
So to do that, I'm just gonna Edit > Copy,
Edit > Paste all that old information.
But in this case what I'm gonna change
is the hue argument in the beginning.
In this case, the last case, the hue
was done by female versus male, but
if I wanted to include children
separately, I'll pass the hue as person.
Remember that column we
made in the last video.
And now I can see the age distribution for
the children, and it cuts off, and
then we have the distribution for
the rest of the males and females.
Now, remember, since this is the KDE plot,
it's subject to the bandwidths,
which is why you still have the KDE
plot going past that 16 mark,
but in reality, that's just the bandwidth.
Okay, what else can we do?
We can do this exact same thing for
classes, so
see how the age ranged by class.
So again I can just Edit > Copy,
Edit > Paste that figure.
And then set my class hue, or excuse me,
my hue to my class column, p class.
Shift+Enter and take a look.
And so now we can see how
the ages ranged by class.
So, interestingly, that first class
had a really normal distribution.
But the second and
third class definitely skewed much more
towards the 20 through 30 range, and
as we saw earlier in the last lecture, the
average age was about 30 on the Titanic.
So we've gotten a pretty good picture of
who the passengers were based on sex, age,
and class, so
we're gonna move onto our second question.
What deck were the passengers on and
how does that relate to their class?
Whoops.
So in order to do that,
let's just go ahead and
take a quick look at our dataset again.
So I'm gonna do that by saying titanic_df,
and
call just the heads to do the preview,
first five rows, okay.
So if we notice,
we have this cabin column.
So we can see that cabin column
is information on the deck, but
it also has several null values.
So we're gonna have to drop them.
So the way to do that is we'll
make a new object called deck,
and I'm gonna have that
be equal to titanic_df,
and gonna have that be
equal to my cabin row.
And then,
as we've learned in previous lectures,
I'm just gonna drop all the null
values using the dropna method.
Okay, and now let's take a quick preview
of Of the decks.
Okay, so now you can see it's gotten
rid of all those null values.
Now we're just seeing a preview, just the
first five that didn't have null values.
And you can see the information
here is the cabin deck,
so it's A, B, C, D, E and
then there's the cabin number.
So what we wanna do is we only need the
first letter of the deck to classify its
level, A, B, C, D, E, F, G.
So let's grab that letter for
the deck using a simple for loop.
So I'll send empty list called Levels.
And then what I'll do is loop
to grab that first letter.
So I'll say for level in deck.
I'll append the first letter here.
So, let's take a quick look
at what this loop is doing.
I created an empty list called levels.
And I said, for every level in deck, and
remember deck was just the cabin column
with all the null values dropped.
Go ahead and grab that first letters or
first item in that string, if you will.
So C, C, E, G, or C here and
then append it to that levels list.
And then once I have that, I can reset
the data frame and use a factor plot.
So I can say, let's make another
data frame called cabin_df
= DataFrame(levels),
cabin_df.columns = ['Cabin'].
And then we can use a factor plot.
And I'll pass the cabin column.
Set my data argument as that new
data frame we just made, cabin_df.
And another little thing I'm
gonna do is set the pallete.
And in this case,
I'll set the palette as winter_d.
So a little note about
this palette business.
If you look up matplotlib plus colormaps,
you can get a range of
palettes that you can be used.
So, to show you what I mean,
I will actually just go to that link.
So, if you go to
a matplotlib.org/user/colormaps,
there's a bunch of different
colormaps you can use.
So this is a great little tool for
data visualization.
You can choose the color maps and
this case, I chose winter.
And you can make these color maps darker
by adding _d to that color map name.
So in this case, I chose that winter
color map and added underscore d.
So before I click Enter to see this factor
plot, let's just go over, see what we did.
So, I created this deck and
then that was the cabin column
with all the null values dropped.
Did a quick preview of it to make sure it
worked, then created an empty list called
levels, and then for every level in
that deck, I appended that first letter.
Then I created a data frame from that
list, set the columns equal to cabin.
There's only one column in that data
frame, and then I'm gonna plot it out.
So this should give us a factored plot or
a bar plot of all the cabins and
how many people were in them,
so the different counts.
Let's go ahead and see if it worked.
And there you have it.
So, if you notice something
weird happened here.
At the very end, we have this T Cabin.
So that value doesn't make sense, so
we're gonna have to drop it out, and we
can read the find cabin DF as everything
but where the rows were equal to T.
So to do that.
I can just say, cabin_df = cabin_df[ and
then I can say where it's not equal to T.
And then I will replot it by Edit > Copy,
Edit > Paste.
Same thing.
This case, I'll just go ahead and
choose a different palette so
we can distinguish the two.
So before I click on through,
I'll just go over what I did.
I redefined that same cabin
data frame as the cabin data
frame where everything does not equal T.
So to get rid of those random T
values there, and there you have it.
Now you have the count or a histogram,
if you will, of A, B, C, D,
E, F, and G of the cabins.
Cool, and like I said before,
you can go ahead and choose color maps,
whichever ones you like or think look
good, for your data visualizations.
All right, let's go ahead and
take another look at our original data.
So I can do this by
saying titanic_df.head.
Okay, so if you note here the embarked
column has values of C, Q and S.
There's no Q right now, but if you went
further along, you'd see Q values.
Reading about the project on Cagle,
over here, you'll
notice that the port of embarkment or
embarkation in
this case what they call it,
these letters stand for towns or cities.
So, C is for Cherbourg, Q is for
Queenstown, and S is for Southampton.
So if we go back, we can make a quick
factor plot to check out the results
of where people came from.
So if you remember, our third question
was, where did the passengers come from?
So in order to do that,
we can just make a quick factor plot.
So I'm gonna say sns.factorplot.
In this case,
I'm gonna pass the embarked column.
Set my data equal to
titanic_df.original data frame.
And let's go ahead and
classify the hue by class.
So what this means is we're gonna
see all the cities that embarked and
see who from which class
came on on which cities.
So the certain cities have a lot of
third-class people, certain cities have
a lot of first-class or second-class
people embarking on those cities.
And I'm just gonna state the order here
using the x_order argument to be C,
Q, and S.
So, let's run that.
Unexpected end of line while parsing.
I forgot to add a parentheses at the end,
whoops.
Let's just check what
we need to debug here.
And it's cuz I don't
have an equal sign there.
Put that list.
Okay.
So I made a factor plot, passed
the embarked column, set my data equal to
titanic_df, my data frame,
selected the class as the hue,
and then defined the order that
my cities would show up in.
So here's some interesting finds.
It looks like in Queenstown,
almost all the passengers that
boarded there were third-class.
And what you might be thinking
of as a data scientist is,
what are the economics of the town
of Queenstown in that period that
all the people that boarded there
were pretty much all third class?
And what are the economics
of Cherbourg where
a lot of first class people board there?
Okay, so
that's the interesting find there.
In the next video, we're gonna look at
the fourth question on who's alone and
who was with family?
So, we'll have to make a new column, and
check out more stuff
there in that lecture.
Just a quick recap of what we did in this
second part was we really looked into
how to use the KDE plots,
how to use the facet grid,
making this cabin and
the deck information available to us.
So analyzing what cabins people were in,
or what decks people were in, excuse me,
and then checking out where
the passengers actually came from.
So next up, we'll look at who was
alone and who was with family.
Okay.