Hey guys, welcome to Lecture 51.
This lecture will be on box and
violin plots.
So, I've already imported on my first
cell all the imports we've been using for
the data visualization section.
And in case you're a little
fuzzy on box plots or
violin plots, you can go ahead and
check out this link.
It's just a link to the Wikipedia page for
box plots.
So they're pretty straight forward.
It's just another way of representing
a probability density function using
quartiles so you can see here, this figure
kinda shows how the probability density
function relates to the box plot so
just take a look at that.
Okay, so let's find out how
to make these box plots.
All right, so
let's just start off with two data sets.
So, I'm gonna make data one
equal randn just a 100 points,
and I'm gonna do the same thing for
a second data set randn a 100,
and now let's go ahead and
create a box plot.
So the way we can do that
using Seaborn is sns.boxplot.
And let's go ahead and pass both data
sets and we can do that using a list.
So, I'm gonna pass data1 and data2.
Let's see the result.
All right, and
there you have your box plot.
So if you notice here,
on top of this blue box plot,
you still have an extra outlier point, and
if you wanna include those into
the range of the whiskers, you can.
And you can do that by calling box plot.
Again, both data sets, data1 and
data2 and this will be passed as a list,
so put them in brackets.
And then you can have
the whiskers include any outliers
by setting it equal to np.inf, infinity.
So np infinity, and there you go.
So, you can see now the whiskers
on the blue box plot
have jumped out to that outlier.
And, so now your whiskers include
all your outliers as well.
You can also set it
horizontally if you wished.
So box plot, let's just do one data set.
We'll just do data1, and
if we want to set it horizontally,
we can just pass the argument vert for
vertical, equal to false.
And now you have a horizontal box plot,
great.
So, while box plots are really useful and
great, especially for
things like financial data and
stocks, we can also use violin or
some people call them viola plots and
that combines the simple format
of a box plot with the information
of a kernel density estimation plot.
So, let's see how we can make those,
first I'm going to
show you an example where the box
plot won't give you the full picture.
So in order to do that, I'm going to
first make a normal distribution,
gonna rename data1,
and I'm gonna use stats.norm
to make this distribution
and so what we're gonna do is
call it from input 0, 5 and
then I'll use .rvs to get 100
points from the distribution.
And then, I'm gonna also make
two gamma distributions and
then I'm gonna concatenate them together.
So, I'm making some really specific data
sets to show you the example of when a box
plot won't give you the whole picture.
So don't worry too much if you don't get
how I make this second data set, it's
not actually a big deal as far as learning
how to create a box and violin plot.
So, I'm gonna use NumPy concatenate, we
actually learned how to use that before.
And I can call the stats gamma,
to get a gamma distribution.
And I'll just run it five,
five and I'm gonna get 50 points.
And I wanna subtract one from that.
And then, since I'm gonna use concatenate,
I'm gonna make another gamma
distribution using stats.
And again I will run it with five and
in this case, I will also call 50 points.
But what I'm gonna do here on
the second gamma distribution,
I'm just gonna multiply
it by a negative one.
All right, and then I'm going to
box plot both data1 and data2.
So I can do that by saying sns.boxplot and
then pass the list of both those guys,
data1 and data2.
And let's set our whiskers to include any
outliers so have them go to infinity.
And I spelled gamma wrong here,
there we go.
Okay, so if you just quickly
look at these two box plots.
You could say that both
distributions are pretty similar,
just one's a little wider then the other.
But if you wanna get the full picture,
you might need to look at
the kernel density estimation plot.
So, that's where
the violin plot's come in.
They're gonna basically,
combine a KDE plot with the box plot.
So in order to do that,
I am going to call violin plot, so
sns.violinplot, and
then let's go ahead and
call data1 and data2.
And, now you can see the distributions
look actually, quite different.
So this is pretty revealing.
Here, it's clearly a normal distribution,
and then you can see
here the set of the two gammas,
one positive and then one negative.
So, the box plot definitely doesn't
show you that whole picture there.
So violin plots can be pretty
revealing for your data.
And just like we used for the KDE plots,
we can also change the bandwidth
of the kernel used for
the density fit in the violin plot.
And, you can do that just by passing your
data and then specifying the bandwidth.
So if I specify some
ridiculously small bandwidth, so
it's super sensitive to the frequency,
that can affect your violin plot.
So, you can decide what bandwidths
you wanna do if you want to
input specific bandwidths
into your violin plots.
Just like we did for
kernel density estimation plots.
Also, kinda similar to our rug plot,
you can include the individual points.
So what I mean by that, to show you an
example, let's have our violin plot data1.
So here's our violin plot data1 and
let's say, I want to include, just like
a rug plot, all the individual points.
Well, I can do that either with points or
sticks.
So I can pass the argument enter
equal to stick, and
now I should get a line,
and all these lines are individual
data points along this distribution.
So, it's almost, it's basically bringing
the idea of the rug plot to a violin plot.
All right, and that's pretty much
it as for as box and violin plots.
Just remember you can call them using
either violin plot and box plot.
And, it's always good to keep in the back
of your mind about the kernel density
estimation plot just to make sure you're
getting the whole picture of your data.
Okay, and that's about it.
In the next lecture, I will be going
over multiple regression plots.
I'll see you then.