All right guys, let's go ahead and
start lecture 52.
And this will be on regression plots or
multiple regression plots.
Okay, so I've already filled out
my cell with the normal inputs and
imports for
the data visualization section.
And we're gonna have to learn
how to use visual with lmplot.
So, Seaborn comes with
some example data sets.
And we can use those in conjunction
with a panda's data frame.
So let's go ahead and
upload one of those data sets.
I'm gonna make a data frame
called tips and from Seaborn,
sns.load_dataset, and
then the name of this data set is tips.
Wait for it to load.
All right.
Once it's loaded, let's just go ahead and
check out the first five rows.
Calling tips.
Okay, so what's in this data set?
We got a total bill,
the tip left on that bill,
the sex, whether the person was
a female or male, were they a smoker?
The day.
They pay their bill, the time of their
meal, and the size of their party.
All right.
Great.
So now that we have that information,
let's go ahead and plot it.
So let's plot the tips
versus the total bill.
So we can do that using sns.
And we're going to use lmplot
to to a regression plot here.
So let's put in total_bill and
we'll plot then tip and then the data
frame it's gonna come from is tips.
So let's go ahead and plot that.
All right, awesome.
So first off, we can see a scatter plot of
all the points on tip versus total bill.
And then we see the linear
regression line.
And, that's just an estimated
linear fit model for all the data.
So, this is the linear regression fit for
all this data that's been
scattered on this plot.
All right.
So, just like before, we can use
dictionaries to edit in the visual
parts of that plot so
to show you an example of this.
Let's go ahead and say sns.lmplot.
Again, we're gonna do the total bill.
And then the tip left.
And we're gonna grab it
from the tips data frame.
And now,
if you remember from previous lectures,
we can say the name of the plot type,
_kws.
And now I can set a dictionary for
some additional arguments,
for each individual plot.
So, let's say I want my scatter plot
to use a particular marker type.
I can say marker as argument, and
have that key have the value of O and
you can look at the documentation.
You can also put in stars and
other different markers for scatter plots.
And then I'm gonna set
the color of the scatter plot.
Have the key color be Indiana red.
All right.
And then for the line, for
that linear regression plot.
Let's see.
I'm gonna set some of those,
I'm gonna set the line width
and I'll set that equal to one,
and then I'll set the color
key equal to blue, well not equal,
sorry I keep saying that, but
actually it's your dictionary so
it's a key and
then your values associated with it.
You're not actually typing in equals.
All right.
So let's go ahead and
see how that plot works out.
And there you go so now on this multiple
regression plot you've been able to
individually pass arguments
on the scatter plot and
the linear plot separately.
Okay.
So this is just a first order treadline,
we can also do multiple higher orders.
If we want to do some quadratic
fits to this data set.
So, for instance,
the way I can do that is by passing order.
So, I'm actually going to
do it on the previous cell,
since we'll keep all of
the information the same.
I can indicate what order
Polynomial fit I want.
So if I wanted a fourth order,
I just passed the argument order four,
so let's see how that changes our fit.
And so
now we have a different fit on the data.
So you can use that in case
you don't want a linear fit,
you can just specify
what order fit you want.
Okay.
So we can also just not
fit a regression at all,
we can just have it be
a pure scatter plot.
So we can say sns.lmplot,
again the total bill,
The tip, and then the data frame we're
gonna get it from is Tips, and then if we
wanna just get rid of the regression fit,
I can pass fit_reg=False.
And if we do that,
let's go ahead and see the plot.
And so now we basically just have
a scatter plot of all the data.
So lmplot also works on discrete variables
such as the percentage of the tip.
So let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
So to get the percentage of the tip,
let's just go ahead and remind ourselves
what the data frame looks like again.
All right.
So we got the total bill at the tip.
And then the other columns.
So let's go ahead and make a new column.
So we'll say tips.
And I wanna say tip_pect.
So it's a tip percentage.
And I'm gonna see that
equal to 100 times tips
the tip column divided
by the tips total bill.
So now I am just making
a new column onto this
tips data frame called the tip percentage.
So what percentage of
the tip was the total bill.
I'm sorry what percent of
the total bill was the tip.
And so I am going to say a hundred times.
Tip divided by the total
bill to get that number.
So, let's go and do that.
And now let's take a quick
look at that column.
Here we go.
So, for instance in row zero
the total bill is almost $17.00.
You add a $1 tip and
that's about 6% of the bill.
Great.
So let's go ahead and plot that then.
Since we're gonna check how it works with
discrete variables we can do sns lmplot.
And now I'm gonna plot the size.
So I'm gonna plot tip
percentage versus the size.
So I'll have my x be size.
And then my y be tip percentage.
Tip p e c t.
And then again the data frame we're
grabbing this information from
is called Tips.
So let's go ahead and see that.
And so there you go.
So now you have discreet variables.
And they then plot it using lmplot.
So here's the size of the party.
And then the tip percentage
they left behind.
If we want to make this a little easier
to read we can add a Jitter to it.
If you're unfamiliar Jitter, you can go
ahead and check out the Wikipedia link for
Jitter.
So, I'll leave it there for you guys.
If you're already familiar with Jitter, or
after you've read that link and come back.
And, the way to add Jitter
is to again we'll run size,
tip Tips and then we can set the x jitter
for jitter related to the x axis, will
just equal to .1, just get a light jitter.
So it should spread out our
data a little bit more.
There you go.
Just makes it a little easier to read.
So not as many points
overlap with each other.
All right great.
So we can also estimate
tendency of each bin.
So each bin is the size of the party
in this case, so if I want to do that,
I could say sns lmplot, again size for
the x axis, tip underscore p ect for the y
axis data frame I'm gonna use is tips and
now I'm gonna say x
estimator equal to np or numpie.
.mean.
All right, and so now this shows
the estimate for the tendency of each bin.
Depending on what tip percentage.
For the size of the party to leave behind.
So it looks like there's
a little more variance for
party sizes of one than of two through
four, which is a bit interesting.
Another thing we can do with
lmplot is we can use the hue facet
to automatically define
subsets along the column, so
I'll show you of an example
of what I mean by that.
I'm gonna say sns.lmplot and in this
case I'll have the total
bill be the X axis.
The tip percentage can be the Y axis.
Again, I'm grabbing it
from the tips data frame.
And now, I'm gonna pass the hue argument.
H, u, e.
And I'm gonna set the hue
equal to the sex column.
So, whether they were male or female.
And then I'm gonna add a markers.
Argumental, as well.
And I'm gonna pass a list for markers.
So in this case,
I'm gonna use x markers, for the female.
And o markers for the male.
And using the hue argument...
We're going to automatically
create hues for the sex column.
So, let's go ahead and
see what happens when I do that.
Okay.
So, now I basically have two regression
plots right on top of each other.
The green is the male, and
the blue x's are the female.
So, I got both scatter plots and
then both linear regression plots.
So this could be a really interesting
case study in who tips more,
females or males and what's
the tendency for the tipping amount.
All right.
So what if we wanted to know does the day
makes a difference in how much the tip is.
So we can do that as well.
I can ask for the regression plot.
Let's go ahead and
set X to the total bill.
Set y equal to the tip percentage.
Take it from the tips data frame.
And in this case I'll use hue again.
H, u, e, and
now I'm gonna set it to the day and
I'm not gonna pass the markers argument.
I'll have them all be the default.
Same scatter and marker.
Right.
So let's go ahead and pass hue for day,
and now we can see whether
the tip percentage changed
on the total bill versus
the subsets of the column for day.
So how much did people pay
percentage tips on Friday?
What was the relationship between
Saturday and Sunday versus just Thursday?
So you can get a lot of
interesting information off
these multiple linear regression plots.
All right.
And then finally, it should be noted.
that seaborn also supports what you can
call local regression model fitting.
So this is definitely a more specific
statistical analysis technique.
We won't be using it in
any of the projects but
in case you're familiar with statistics
you should now that seaborn can do this.
Sometimes it's called loess or l, o,
e, s, s, so you can look that up too.
So let's go ahead and
see what local regression can do for us.
So we can say total_bill tip
percentage as the Y axis.
Tips as a data frame we
are going to graph from.
And so we'll set lowest.
The local regression, =true.
And now, I'm gonna edit my line.
And if I wanna edit my line I
can do that by saying line_kws,
as we done in the past.
And like we done in the past as well,
set a dictionary, so I'll set the color.
Key.
Set that to have a value of black, so
it shows up against the scatter plot.
Okay, and
that's what your lowest line looks like.
Again, this is a pretty
specific statistical thing,
so don't worry too much if you don't
quite understand what just happened.
It's really more of a specific task
that you may want to do in the future.
Okay.
Now, let's zoom out a bit.
lmplot is actually using
a lower level Function
called regplot depending
on how you want to say it.
R, e, g plots is just for
regression plots.
So let's go look at that
lower level function.
So sns.regplot, for regression plot.
And then I can insert total bill,
the tip percentage, and tips.
And so r, e, g plot is the lower level
function that lmplot was built on top of.
So this is the moral bust,
if you will, plotting function.
So here we have tip percentage
versus the total bill.
And regression plots,
they can be added to existing access
of a subplots without modifying
anything else in the figure.
So, if you had a figure of two subplots,
you could use this r, e, g plot.
The regression plot along with
other plots so like a violin plot.
So to show you what I'm talking
about let's go ahead and
create a figure of two sub plots.
So I'll say Fig and
then two axises we'll say axis1 and axis2.
So I'll set these equal to plt.
Sub plots,
that's how we can create sub plots, oops.
That should be a dot, okay.
Call the subplots method on a plot,
and then say
what you want the plots to look like, so
the number of rows, the number of columns.
So I'm gonna say one row,
two columns, so one by two plots.
And then I'll say sharey=True so
they align better.
And then I will call
the regression plot function
with the total bill on the x,
the tip, _pect.
On the y, we're gonna grab
that information from tips and
I will set axis equal to axis1 for
the sub plot.
And then I can also make a violin plot for
one of the sub plots.
And I will have the violin plot be.
Let's have it be the tips.
The tip percentage column.
And we'll have it be
the size of the party.
Tips, size.
All right, and then let's choose
the color scheme for this.
Let's say color equals and
for color schemes if we want it
to be reds we can pass this,
reds_r since there's going to
be multiple violins, and in this
case we'll set the axis equal to axis two
cuz it's gonna be the second plot over.
Right.
So let's go ahead and
see what these subplots look like.
Oops.
And
looks like I,
there should be no underscore there.
My apologies.
There we go.
All right so using REG plot you're
able to use it in a subplot figure.
So here's a figure of 2 subplots.
One regression plot and one violin plot.
All right.
And that's it.
Next up, we're gonna learn about
heat maps and clustered matrices.
I'll see you there.