Hey everyone, I apologize that the last
lecture ended kind of abruptly.
There was,
I think an editing issue with the video.
What I was gonna say is
we've done quite a bit, and
we've seen a lot of data analysis
through the Titanic intro project, and
what I want to do now is hand
over the control to you.
So, there's two questions I want you
to answer with your new skill sets and
the experience you've seen
through this data project.
And what you're gonna
answer is two questions.
Did the deck have an effect on
the passengers' survival rate, and
does this answer match
up with your intuition.
So, does being on A deck make a difference
in your survival rate versus being on E or
F deck, so on a higher deck or
a lower deck.
And how does being a male
affect that same outcome?
So if you were a male on the lower deck or
a male on the higher deck,
did it really make a difference or not?
And does this answer match
up with your intuition?
So that's an interesting
thing to look into.
And then the second question
I want you to look at is,
did having a family member increased
the odds of surviving the crash.
So did having a family enable
you to get onto a life
boat because you have
people supporting you.
Or is it better that you are alone and
didn't have to worry about your family?
So that's a real interesting
question to answer.
So go ahead and
answer those two questions.
Add a discussion on this lecture if you're
having trouble or just even have more
questions that are interesting to answer
and want advice on how to answer those.
But overall,
we've done a lot of stuff with this
data set, which is pretty awesome.
I highly suggest you go check out the
iPython notebook that's attached to this
project, that's in the first lecture for
this project's video.
Go ahead and check it out.
There's a lot more comments,
a lot more information.
Things are explained in a little slower
than I did through these few videos and
you can go at your own pace.
Okay, I hope you enjoy
the Titanic intro project, and
I look forward to the next one.