Hey guys, welcome to Lecture 53.
This lecture is on heatmaps.
And clustered matrices.
All right, so this is the last lecture
in the data visualization section.
So, let's go ahead, as I mentioned before,
C-Born comes with some great data
sets that we can play and learn with.
So in this case, we're gonna grab
a data set called flights_dframe.
Remember to input all
your imports into a cell.
The usual ones for
the data visualization section.
And then we'll set flight_dframe
equal to sns.load_dataset.
And the data set string name is flights.
Okay, so let that load.
Great!
Once it's done loading let's go ahead and
preview it.
So we can say flight_dframe.
And we can check out the first five rows.
All right.
So what do we have here?
We have the year, the month, and the
number of passengers that took a flight.
Either on this airline or on a specific
plane, doesn't really matter for our case.
Let's go ahead and pivot this dataframe so
it's easier to manage.
So, as we've learned some
couple lectures ago on pivots,
we have flight_dframe and
we're gonna set this equal to the pivot.
And we're gonna pivot it by month,
year and
then the values we want are passengers.
So, just a reminder about pivot and
pivot tables.
We set the rows we want.
So we set the rows to be months.
We want the columns to be years, and
we want those values to be filled out with
the number of passengers
that took a flight.
Let's go ahead and
show this data frame now, flight_dframe.
There we go, so
now it's in a much better format for us.
Great, and this one almost looks
basically perfect to make a heatmap,
or a cluster matrix
visualization from this.
So let's go ahead and
show you what we're talking about here.
If we want to make a heatmap of this data,
we just call sns.heatmap,
and we're gonna pass that
data frame through it now.
All right.
And now we have a data visualization for
a heatmap for the passengers.
Now let's say you wanted to actually
know the number of passengers and
annotate each cell with
the number of passengers.
Not just have it be by color.
You can do that.
So let's go heatmap, again,
we'll pass that data frame.
And then we'll say
annotation equal to true.
So in this case A-N-N-O-T equal to true.
And let's set fmt equal to d just for
some formatting.
And there you have it.
So now you have annotated each cell
with the number as well as the color.
So C-Born's gonna automatically try
to pick the best color scheme for
your dataset.
And that basically just depends whether
it's a converging or diverging color map.
So this case, it's chosen a converging
one, so it's gone from a light to a dark.
But if you wanted to choose a center,
if you will, for your color map,
you can do that, so you can specify if
you want a center for your color scheme.
To show you what I'm talking about,
let's go ahead and
do sns.heatmap,
we'll call the flight_dframe on it.
We'll set center equal to flight_dframe.,
and
then we'll get the location,
so we'll say loc.
And we'll have it be January.
1955, okay.
All right, so what is this going to do?
Well, let's go ahead and take a look.
Alt+Enter, so
now we have a diverging color scheme.
We've created our own center.
So white now is going
to be at January 1955.
Values above that,
are going to have a more red color scheme.
Values below that are going to
have a cooler blue color to them.
So instead of like the first one where
it converges all the way up from 600,
now it's diverging from
the January 1955 value.
So that's how you can
choose your color schemes.
We can also add heatmaps on access of
subplots to make more informative figures.
So just like we did with
regression plots and
the violin plots in the last lecture, we
can do something similar for these plots.
So let's go ahead and try making
a figure with multiple sub plots.
So, I'm going to say f for the figure
name and let's make two sets of axes,
so I'll say axis1, axis2, I'm
going to set that equal to plt.subplots
like we did in the last lecture.
So well say 2 1, so in this case,
there's two rows and one column.
Now, I'm going to say, gonna call my
yearly_flights object
equal to flight_dframe.
Take the sum.
So what I'm doing is I'm taking
the sum of all those columns and
the columns are the years.
So you can imagine if I take
the sums all along 1949,
I will have the total number
of flights for that year.
So that's the yearly
flights object I'm making.
Okay, so, since yearly_flights,
if you were to look at it right now,
it's in a little bit of a weird format.
We'll have to grab the values
we want with the series and
then put them into a data frame.
So I'm going to set years
equal to pd.Series and
I'm gonna grab it from yearly_flights.
And then I'm gonna get the index values.
And then I'm gonna set years
to be equal to a dataframe.
So, I'm gonna make a dataframe
out of that, Out of that series.
So, I created a series, and
then ran that seriesthrough a dataframe.
We're gonna do the same thing for flights.
And this is just to take care of
some formatting issues in the yearly
flights data.
Do a similar thing here.
Except in this case,
I just want the actual values,
not the index values, and we'll create
a data frame using that series.
Pd.DataFrame, flights.
All right.
And now we're gonna make the data
frame complete and name the columns.
So I'm going to say year_deframe
equal to pd.concat so
I'm going to use concatenate and
I'm going to put together years and
flights.
And I'm gonna do this
along axis equal to 1.
And then I'm gonna name my columns,
so year_dframe.columns equal to,
now the columns, let's give them a name.
So they should be year and flights.
Great.
That way they go with each of the series,
or
I guess they're data frames now
that were concatenated together.
All right.
So, let's visualize that data.
I'm gonna make a bar plot.
And you can make a bar plot
in C-Born by passing barplot.
And I'm gonna say bar plot of the year.
So let's see barplot.
Whoops.
Barplot Year.
I'll set y equal to Flights.
So the total number of flights that year.
My data is gonna come
from the year_dframe,
so that data frame we just made.
And also ax equal to axis1,
cuz it's on a sub plot.
And then I'm gonna create
a heatmap below it.
So I'm gonna say
sns.heatmap flight_dframe.
And then we're gonna say, let's go
ahead and get a color palette for that.
The way we can do that for
a heatmap is by passing the cmap argument,
and in this case, I'm gonna choose Blues.
And you can look at the documentation for
other color schemes.
We'll also say axis is equal to axis2 so
it goes below.
And then something I wanna do is,
if we scroll back up, we can see
that this color bar is set vertical.
I wanna set it horizontal.
So, the way I do that,
is I pass, as we've done before,
I can say cbar_kws.
And just pass a dictionary.
So in this case,
the key is going to be orientation.
And I'm gonna give its
value as horizontal.
All right, so
that way the color bar is horizontal.
So we've done a lot right now.
Let's go ahead a see how we
were able to visualize it.
Yearly value is not defined.
I probably have a spelling
error somewhere,
let's go back up and try to catch it.
Yearly_values, this is in
line eight of flights.
So yearly_values.
I should have written yearly_flights.
Not sure why.
I see.
I wrote that twice.
That should have been flights.
Okay, now let's try it.
Okay, there we go.
All right.
So, now I have my bar plot on top and
I have my heatmap on the bottom and my
color bar has been oriented horizontally,
so it's on the bottom as well.
And you can see now that
the years match up and
you can get a really nice
data visualization here.
So that's great.
Finally, we're gonna learn
about using a cluster map.
So, let's go ahead and create one.
So a cluster map's gonna
reformat the heatmap,
so similar rows are next to each other.
So, I'm gonna say sns.clustermap,
of that data frame, so flight_dframe.
Okay.
And here we have our cluster map.
So if you notice,
the months are no longer in order.
January, February, November down here,
December's over here.
But in this case,
similar rows are next to each other.
And you can see,
they're grouping and linking.
They're clustering, if you will,
on top and on the left.
And here, you have your color bar scale.
Okay, so let's go ahead and
just uncluster the columns,
so we can do that by
saying sns.clustermap.
Let's pass flight_dframe again.
And in this case,
I'm only gonna cluster by the rows.
So I'm gonna call
col_cluster equal to false.
See what that looks like.
Okay.
So now I've only done it by the rows
instead of by the actual month.
We don't care about the years themselves.
We'll keep those
independent of each other.
So it's only being clustered by the month.
All right.
So since the number of
flights increase every year.
As we saw above if we scroll up a bit,
you can see the number of flights
is increasing every year.
So we should set a standard scale.
So let's go ahead and standardize.
So, I can do that by
saying sns.clustermap.
Say flight_dframe and
I'm gonna set a standard_scale.
And set that equal to one.
So now, what that means is I'm gonna
standardize by the columns, or
by the year.
So let's go ahead and do that.
All right.
So now what do we see here?
You can really tell now that the summer
months are the heavier usage months.
Just everything's been
standardized by the year.
Now, if you look at your scale,
it goes from 0 to 1.
So here, we've eliminated the problem of
flights increasing every single year.
We could also scale it by rows.
So we could say sns.clustermap
flight_dframe, so pass the data set and
then set the standard_scale equal to 0 and
this would then scale the rows.
All right.
Great.
And then finally, we can also
normalize the rows by their Z score.
This is gonna get a bit into some heavier
statistics, so what a Z score does is
just subtracts the mean and then divides
by the standard deviation of each column.
So then the rows have a mean of 0,
and a variance of 1.
So, this is going to be the very last
thing we go over, is going to be cluster
map, flight_dframe.
And if you wanna normalize
by their Z score,
you just input the argument
z_score equals to 1.
Again, what the Z score does,
it just subtracts the mean and
divides by the standard
deviation of each column.
So that the rows have a mean of 0,
and there's a variance of 1.
And so this is what the result looks like.
So you can really tell that it's
the summer months are where you
have higher number of flights.
Okay, so that's it for
heatmaps and clustered matrices.
You should give yourself
a huge pat on the back,
you've made it all the way
through Lecture 53.
Great job.
Next up is a whole new section and
we're just gonna be doing projects that
you can add to your portfolio and
we're gonna be using real data sets.
We're gonna take all
the tools we've learned and
hammer out some great
data analysis projects.
I'm really excited for
you in the next section.
Let's do this.
Congrats again on finishing
all the way up to Lecture 53.
Let's go ahead and
get started with the projects.
I'll see you there.