Hello, everyone, and welcome to this quick
introduction to the second data project.
This data project will be going over
stock market analysis techniques.
Okay, so as always,
you can just go ahead and
go to nbviewer, and go ahead and
type in jmportilla.
That's my GitHub account name.
And then go to udemy notes, and
you'll come to the page where you can
always see the IPython notebooks.
And then you can click on right here
data projects stock market analysis,
let me go ahead and zoom in a little bit.
Here we go.
And then you'll see a completed
IPython notebook for
you to go ahead and check out.
So, there's a lot of stuff here,
we're going to do a quick run down of it.
And then in the rest of the videos we'll
actually go programming step by step.
So you can either watch the videos or
go ahead and
just read along with the IPython
notebook on your own.
So, in this data project we're
gonna be looking at a portfolio
of technology stocks, we're gonna be able
to use pandas to get stock information,
visualize different aspects of it, and
then we'll even look at different ways of
analyzing the risk of the stock,
based on previous performance history.
And we'll be using Monte Carlo
techniques to predict stock prices.
So it should be a really great,
interesting project.
We'll be answering a couple of
key questions along the way.
You can check those out later.
And so we'll be using Pandas to get some
stock information as you can see here.
Then we'll be analyzing the closing
prices, the volume being traded of
certain stocks, in this case this is Apple
technology stock or the Apple company.
We will also be looking
at moving averages.
Next, we will look at
daily return analysis.
This is a really interesting
thing we will check out later.
Basically, your daily
returns on your stock, so
whether you'll lose or
gain on average everyday.
And then after that we'll look at a little
bit of correlation between different
technology stocks.
And then we'll learn
about Correlation again.
And then we'll see how to use pair
plot with cborn to get some
really nice correlation plots.
You can see them here, and
we'll go over all of this
in the following videos, and
here's another correlation plot.
And then we're gonna do some
risk analysis on some stocks.
So we'll plot up difference
here we're comparing risk and
expected returns of Google, Microsoft,
Amazon and Apple, different technology
stocks, and then we'll use two different
methods to analyze a specific stock.
Great, and
then we'll do the Monte Carlo techniques
to simulate some future stock prices.
You can see them here.
This is for Google.
And then we'll get a risk
analysis on that stock.
Okay, great.
So go ahead and you have the option
of either just checking out this
IPython notebook on your own or following
along with the next sequence of videos for
the Data Project.
Okay, thanks a lot.
I'll see you there.