Hey guys, welcome to Lecture 21.
In this lecture we're going to be
learning ranking and sorting, so
how to use rank and sort.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
First off,
we're gonna import the usual stuff.
Import NumPy as np.
From pandas, we'll import Series and
Dataframe and
then finally we'll import pandas as pd.
Alt enter, take it to a new cell.
All right, cool.
So as usual,
how about we make a series to play with?
So I'll make it a series, and
I'll call Python's range function.
I'll get three points, and then I'll pass
an index argument and we'll say it's C,
A, B index, and
let's just see what that looks like now.
And the reason it's not an A, B,
C order, is so it can actually use sort.
So, if I wanted to sort this
index how would I do it?
It's really easy,
you just take your series name and
then you call sort index on it.
Now close parentheses so you don't have
to pass any additional arguments there.
Let's go ahead and see what happened.
Awesome.
So, now my index is sorted.
A, B, C.
And it's sorted its values associated
with that index along with it.
Let's say you wanted to order a series
by its values, not by its index.
Well you can do that, too.
So if I wanted the order zero, one,
two, basically what we had before,
I can take my series and what I can call
on it is order with closed parentheses.
And order will order it
by the values themselves.
Zero, one, two.
When sort index,
we'll sort it by the index values A, B, C.
So that's sorting, and
let's get an idea of how ranking works.
So in order to do that, I'm gonna import,
as we've done before in the past,
from the NumPy random library,
I'll import randn.
Let's go ahead and do that and
let's then make a new series,
and the series is gonna
be ten random numbers.
So, I'll pass in the ten argument,
and we'll see what that looks like.
Awesome, so
now we have 10 random numbers, and
let's say I wanted to sort them and
see how they rank.
So let's just sort them scr2.sort.
And now let's check it out.
All right.
So now we've sorted all the values in
this series from lowest to highest.
That means that every value
in this series had a rank.
If you notice the index
values are all jumbled up,
because they were in order at first,
but the values weren't.
So when you sorted it,
it sorted it by value, and now your
index values are a little jumbled up.
What if you wanted to know the actual
ranking of each value in the series?
Well, I can show you by
calling rank on our series,
and you notice rank then
shows in perfect order.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
So this rank value is what
is actually being sorted.
Previously, all these
numbers had a rank value and
then what sort does is it takes the rank
value and just puts it in ascending order.
And that's how ranking and sorting works.
So on the left column,
we see the original index value and
on the right we see its rank value.
Let's go ahead and just to get a clearer
picture on that we'll do it one more time.
We'll make a third series.
I'll call another random ten.
See what that looks like.
Okay, so I have ten random numbers.
Let's go ahead and check out their
rank right now before I sort them.
Oops, sorry, series three.
All right, so you see the ranking,
while the index is in perfect order,
the rankings are all over the place.
So what will happen when I sort
and then check the rank, you'll see
that the rankings are now in order,
but the index that was associated
to each value is all mixed up.
And then let's check out what
the series actually looks like now.
Series three.
And like we saw before,
everything is now sorted by its rank.
So that's the relationship
between rank and sort.
Each of these values has a ranking and
sort just ranks them.
Sort just ranks them
by that ranking value.
All right, cool.
So next up on L ecture 22,
we'll learn about using descriptive
statistics on data frames.
I'll see you there.