Hey guys, welcome to lecture 37.
And this will be just a quick lecture on
how to use replace with your data frames.
So, Copy and Paste or
just type out the normal imports
which is import numpy as np.
Import pandas as pd.
And then, from pandas,
import series and data frame.
All right, awesome.
So, let's go ahead and make a series.
We'll call it ser1 and
the series we just build using a list.
So, I'm just gonna go one, two,
three, four and then again,
one, two, three, four.
And then, let's go ahead and
show that series.
There we go.
So we have an index and it's one, two,
three, four, one, two, three, four.
So, using replace,
we can select which value we wanna
replace with the new value, and
the new value to replace it with.
So for instance, the way this works
is you call the replace method,
which is just .replace.
And then you select the value
you want to replace, and
then the new value you want in its place.
So for instance, I can say that I want
every one value in that series
to be replaced by a null value.
Let's go ahead and
see if that worked, awesome.
So now, every value that was one
has been replaced with a null.
You can also input lists into the replace
method to show you how those work.
Let's say,
I want to replace the ones and fours,
and I want to replace them with 100 and
400 respectively.
So the lists need to match up so
that every value of
your first list that will be replaced
by the value in your second list.
So every 1 will be replaced by 100,
and every 4 will be replaced by 400.
So let's go ahead and pass that.
Cool, so that worked, and that's how
you can do multiple replaces at once.
And then the last thing,
you can also input a dictionary.
So for instance, I have my SER1.replace
and I can pass a dictionary so that
in a similar manner every four
gets replaced by a null value.
So you can just input a key and
a value to be replaced.
So let's go ahead and
see how that works, and so
now every 4 value was
replaced by a null value.
So that's it for replace, just a quick
overview, you can just call .replace
onto your series, and then you call
the value you want to replace, and
then the value you wanna replace it with.
You can also pass lists to
do multiple values at once.
You can also pass dictionaries
in a similar manner.
You replace the key with its value.
So that's it for replace, up next we
are gonna learn about renaming and
access index.
I'll see you there.