In the upcoming lectures, we will see projection and excerpt provided by spring guitarist.
But before we jump to it, let me give you an introduction about this too.
And let's understand why we need to go for projects and excerpt.
So this is a right we have already seen by which we are getting desperate and it is basically collecting
hope student.
Now look at the decent response.
Here we are getting forfeits right in the just response.
And this is pixel response.
That means every consumer will get this for filling in the form of design.
Now let's say you have a couple of consumers and one consumer is coming to you and ask you, Hey, I
just want I.D. and email I.D. of this student.
I don't need first name and last name in the JSON response, so don't provide me this to fill.
Now, let's say you have another consumer which is asking you that, Hey, I just need ID and first
name of the student.
I don't need last name in email of this.
OK, so don't provide me these two pills in the JSON response.
So how you will handle this kind of situation while working with spelling data is.
So there comes projects and so it projects, then we can provide that.
We just want to expose this particular to release, OK, under that particular projects, and now we
can help on other projects.
And under that, we can provide another fields.
So, for example, ID and email I.D. So this project son of a consumer needs to pass while calling this
API how using the query parameter so that we see in the upcoming lectures.
OK, don't worry, we will see that with the practical example.
So with projects, then we can have a view that which fields we want to expose under that particular
project.
And that project then our consumer can use while calling the EPA.
Now, let's come to exert when we want to have the default protection for our recipes, then we can
go for except now for which it is the IPAs in which we are having the collection of data collection
up student or collection of department or collection up subject so that we can have the default projects
done using the exiled Soviet expert.
What will happen?
Each and every consumer doesn't need to pass the projection while calling the EPA OK.
They don't need to pass the very parameter for the projects, and they will get the default view using
the exact.
So this is an introduction to projects on an excerpt, and we'll get started from the next lecture.
Thank you very much.