Bill, now we have seen recipes using spring that arrest and in the response we are getting this kind
of hyper media links.
So this is hitting us concept, right?
And we are having hell as the implementation of hit you is.
Now here we are using postmen to call over wristbands.
So here comes Hal Explorer.
So what happens, OK?
Hal Explorer provides a nice UI within our application.
With that, we can heat our wristbands so that we don't need any third party.
Just like postman or any other is plain to call our wristbands.
So Health Explorer provides a nice UI to call over wristbands, and we don't need to code anything OK.
We don't need to write code to get this.
You know, HAL Explorer provides that.
And on top of it, we can consider HAL Explorer as documentation about our wristbands.
If you are working with swagger or open API, then you can compare it with HAL Explorer.
So it had exploded within of replicates, and we can have you, I, to call our recipes.
And also we can consider it does raise debate documentation now how to use the explorer so that we see
in the next lecture.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.