Bill, now we have seen recipes which are automatically provided by spring guitarist, but that is not
always the Huskies, right?
He might have some requirements that is automatically bloated.
IPAs are not sufficient.
So for example, we want to have one debate in which we want to pass.
Melody of this is very parameter.
And in return, we want to help students.
It is.
Or let's say we want to have one year debate in which we want to get all those students whose first
name is John.
Well, let's say we have another scenario in that we want to get all those students whose first name
is John.
And last name is Smith.
OK, so what we do in the sequel, Grady V. and Grady date between the two columns, plus niman last
name.
So this kind of requirements we might help and whatever.
Automatically generated recipes by putting guitarist are not sufficient, so we need to have the custom
IPAs.
So this is what we are going to do in the upcoming lectures.
Let me clarify, OK.
We are not going to hold the risk controller to develop this custom space.
We will use the DPA.
So if you are already working with the GPA, then you might be aware find my methods, which are provided
by GPA.
So say, for example, if you want to get the record right by email I.D. So what we do in the sequel
where email equal to this one.
But we are using the GPA.
OK, so we are not writing the sequel grades in our Springwood application so we can use the find my
method to find my full name.
So here, find my email.
So, for example, finding my first name.
OK.
So whatever field you have that you need to put up to the point about and those matters are provided
by GPA.
We just need to write the methods in the repository.
Let's say we want to go and gritty.
So what we do in the Jeep, you find my first name and last name.
So that will apply the ambiguity between the first name and last name columns.
So this kind of methods we need to write in the repository.
So Spring Guitarist will use these methods and will expose them as recipes.
OK, so our duty is to just write the methods in the repository.
That's it.
The rest of the things will be provided by Spring Day guitarist.
And that's why we don't need rest controller for developing the custom APIs.
So this is what we are going to do, and we will get started from the next lecture.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.