Bill, now we have seen recipes using spring guitarist, but here we don't have any validation in place.
So for example, this first name column in this table is having not null consent.
Now, let's say consumer is buzzing null value for this bill, OK, in the Jason Pot, the first name,
which is our basically the crispy lord.
So in that case, what will happen?
Obviously, the record will not get inserted into the table, so consumers will get some Sekula-Gibbs
on something like consent violated, right?
But that is not the proper way to handle it.
We should have proper validation and we should be returning proper error message to alert consumers
that, Hey, you are doing this thing wrong, you need to pass the value for a first name or whatever
other validations you want to put.
So this is what we are going to do in the upcoming lectures that how to how the validations while working
with spending data arrest.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.