In the upcoming lectures, we will see how to do business in and sorting while working with spring guitarist.
So for this, we need to open up records in our student and subject table.
So that's what I did in the background.
OK, let me show you quickly what we have in our musical tables.
So this is the department table.
We have total two records in this table.
Total, we have 24 records.
OK?
I do.
Starting from the two.
So total 24 records.
Now let's go to subject level.
And here we have total.
Twenty eight records.
OK.
It starting from three.
So total twenty eight records.
So this is what we have in our MRGO database.
Don't worry, along with this lecture, you will get disqualified.
OK.
So with that, you can import all these things in your local machine.
Using the bicycle workbench now of a spring wood application is already running.
So let's jump to browser and hit this.
You are to at what our application.
And this is the response we are getting right.
So we have a passport department student n subject.
Now let's focus on this one.
OK, for example, with this, we are getting all the students right.
And look at this query parameters, page number, size and sort.
So using this query parameters, they can do unison and sorting while working with spring guitarist.
And this is what we are going to do in the upcoming lectures.
OK.
So let's copy this API.
You all jump to Postman and call this IPA.
We got the response come down at the bottom.
See this one object obituary page object so size equal to 20.
So by default, bid size is 20.
OK, 20 is the default size provided by spring guitarist.
Total records we have is 24.
OK.
And Total Page is equal to do so in the first bit.
How many records will get 20 on the second page for right?
Because total, we help.
24 records.
Indestructible.
See, here we are getting till 21.
OK?
It's equal to 21.
That means total twenty records.
We are getting OK.
From this green table.
Let's come down see this one.
So total 20 records we are getting.
So this is our being number one.
OK.
Same thing for subject as well.
Let's copy this one.
Call this EPA.
OK, we got 20 seconds total elements.
28.
So on the second page will get eight records because totally out two pages.
So along with the data, your consumer is also getting this information OK?
Bid size bid.
No total bid isn't total elements.
So looking at this, OK, your consumer will get idea that what he or she needs to get on the next page
will depend on the total number of elements, the total number of pages, the current number of the
page OK and bid size.
So with this information, your consumer will get idea that what he or she needs to do for the isn't
to get all the records or support, for example, all the records in the next page or upcoming pages.
See all these things are provided by spring guitarist.
OK, we are not doing anything.
This page object OK in the decent format is being provided by spring guitarist.
Now how do we do the pagination that we do in the next lecture?
So that's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.