Hello and welcome back in this lecture, you will download and set up, dedicate a page, Marian and
Spring to suit in our local muslin.
So first, let's go with Gideon.
That is our development kit, and this is the official website of Warrigal.
And from here, you can download Adjudicate.
In this course I'm going to use Dedicated, which is coming at free cost by Oracle because this is our
personal and development use.
All you can say educational use.
If you want to use her words and then dedicated, you can go with open JDK that is coming under the
open source license.
So it's up to you in this course, I'm going to use dedicate so download to dedicate according to your
operating system, Linux, Windows or Mac.
It's up to you, so download and install in your local machine.
Now the next thing is buildable.
So in this course, we are going to use the Apache Marvin.
If you are familiar with Gradle, you can go for it as well.
So this is the official website of the bottom of it.
And from here, you can download Apache Marvin, whatever latest was and you can see you can go for
it.
So download according to your operating system and install in your local machine.
The next thing is it.
You can go with eclipse in Delhi, the idea, NetBeans, whatever you prefer.
It's up to you.
In this course, I'm going to use a stylus that is spring --.
So this is the official website of ideas.
And here you can download ideas according to your operating system, Linux, Mac or Windows.
It's up to you.
If you are familiar with the intelligencia and you want to go for it, it's up to you in this course,
I am going to use the stairs, so I would recommend download and install ideas in your local machine
from the official website of Sidious.
So download and install these three softwares in your local machine, according to your operating system,
after downloading and installing.
If you are a Windows user, then search for the environment variables and here you see a system environment
variables.
In the advanced tab, you will see environment variables.
So here we need to create two new environment variables.
The first is yellow home, which is basically part two over JDK, and the name is double.
And this is the part to JDK, whatever it is in your local machine, at what location it is being installed
and make sure you are not giving the bin directly in this port deal.
JDK only you need to give.
The second is and to whom the name is M2M, and this is where your apartment is installed and make sure
you are not giving the bin directly in the part.
So after creating this tool, new environment variables, the next thing is we need to set in the existing
part, an environment variable.
So this will be already exist in your machine.
So just edit it and put your two environment variables like this person.
They dollar home percentage lesbian and same for your mom and pop them two homes lesbian.
So this is all you need to do.
Download, dedicate a page, Marvin and stills and install them after that, create the two environment
variables and set those in your path environment variable like this.
So make sure you are doing this before we start the next lecture.
So that's all for now.
We'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.