Till now, we have seen recipes using spring guitarist and spring guitar.
But that was using only one table and that was turntable, right?
But now let's say we have a couple of pebbles in our square database and that is with second licensee
using the port and key concept.
Now, in this case, let's see how to how the rest is.
When you have a couple of tables with relationship.
OK, so how to work with that using the spring guitarist?
So that's what we will see in the upcoming lectures.
But before we jump to that, we need a couple of tables with sexual relationship, right?
So that's what I have done over here.
Inside the university schema, I have created two more tables department and subject.
Let me give you an overview of this table.
OK.
This is the department table.
Very simple.
One with two columns I.D. This is the primary in the park many see as OK.
Now this all three tables are completely empty.
OK?
There are no records inside these three tables.
Now this is the table.
We know what it is, but one more column has been added now.
Department I.D..
So this is the parent basically primary job department table.
This is the subject learning table.
OK, Heidi, this is primarily subject name Mike, Slopping and Randy.
This is Warren G and Primary Job Student Table.
So this is the hierarchy department tables, parent table, rent table and student table is parent table
for subjects learning table.
Let me show you with your diagram that will give you a better idea.
The department is better enforcement level, and here is the Foreign Department, 80 known police,
but Interpol for subjects landing table.
And this is the foreign student I.D..
Now let's talk about the relationship so we can say that many students belong to one department.
OK, so this relationship is basically many to one.
From student to department, it is many to one.
OK.
In the same way, we can say that many subjects or you can see more than one subject right one or more
than one subjects can be learned by a single student.
So this is also many to one mapping from subject to strain.
It is also many to one relationship.
OK.
From student to department also, it is many to one relationship.
So these are the three tables.
Don't worry.
Along with this lecture, you will get disqualified.
OK?
You can download it and import in your local bicycle database using the bicycle workbench.
OK, so no need to worry about it.
Along with this lecture, you will get disqualified.
So these are the three tables, and with this in the upcoming lectures, we will have the rest space,
but not the manual.
OK.
We are going to use the spring guitarist, but the main important part is how we are going to handle
this relationship while working with the spring guitarist.
So that's our focus in the upcoming lectures.
So make sure before the next lecture you are ready with this three day was OK.
So that's all for now, and we'll proceed further.
The next lecture?
Thank you very much.