In this lecture, we will see what is spring data.
So basically, spring data is umbrella project under which there are many such projects.
For example, spring data, GPA, spring data, MongoDB, spring data, Cassandra and many more.
It's not possible to list down all the SAP projects or hear if we are using any relational icicle database.
Then we can use spring data ADP so that we don't need to write the natives equal queries in our spring
board application in the same way.
Say, for example, if we are using the MongoDB database, then we can use spring data, MongoDB, so
that we don't need to the native MongoDB queries in our Springwood application.
And same goes for Cassandra and other databases.
So, for example, Neo4j graph database, so that is bring data Neo4j provided under spring data.
If you want to know more about spring data, you can check out the official page provided by spring.
So for that, let's jump to browser and search for spring data.
This is the official one by spring for hamburgers being not, I'll.
As I said, this is the umbrella project, OK, spring data.
And these are dozens of projects, OK, under the spring data spring that ADP is putting data, MongoDB
spring data, it is spring data, Kassandra Spring Data, Neo4j and many more.
You can read out this one, OK, if you want to know more about spring data in this course.
Our focus will be on two projects.
One is spring data and another one is spring data rest.
So this is an introduction to spring data, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.