In the previous lecture, we have seen how to create a record using dpa.
Now in this lecture, we will see how to update the record using spinning data.
Say, for example, we want to update this record, OK, that's one equal to three so that we will do
using the spring data.
And for this purpose, it will create WDBJ.
So let's jump to his ideas and inside of us one controller, let's say one.
OK, so to say all the time, I'm copying this OK from the create that is basically our post mapping
or steps.
So use the app put mapping.
OK.
This is, I'm going to say, all the time.
This is abridgement.
Here we will get the request mail order in the apartment of Jason, and we're using the same glass.
OK, what entity glass bit, activist body and recent see?
The only difference in the payload will be the I.D..
OK.
This is the dissent that we have used in the previous lecture.
So at that time, we haven't passed the the its value now in this lecture to update us, and it is obviously
we need it right?
So it would appear the only difference in our request payload is that we will pass it up its value as
of it.
OK, now from here, we will call the service later.
Let's run.
OK.
Let's clear this matter, investments, the reason for that.
I will use this one only, OK.
This is now update rent.
That's it.
We need to use the same method provided by GP to update the record.
Yes.
To create the record of yet using this new method to update the record, we are using the same method.
So now you may be thinking that how you will identify that now it needs to create the record and the
other time it needs to update the record.
So that all depends on this entity class.
OK, whatever you are passing this object, if this object is containing the value of it, then it will
update the record.
If this field value is null, then it will create the record.
Basically, it all depends on this bill's value on which you have at ID annotation.
What is your unique identifier on which you have at identity sent, if this value is null, will create
the record when you call doesn't matter.
If this fellow is having some value, then it will update the record.
OK, so here what we will do.
We will pass ID equal to three OK in the apartment of and what he ate.
Like this one?
This is it equal to three.
OK, so Peter is one.
Peter one.
OK.
This is what we want to update the first name of this student.
So this will come to our controller here using the appropriate body that we are passing a service layer
and this object we are passing by calling the Scimitar.
So now this time, OK, this idea of its value is not not so I will update the record.
OK, so now let's run our spring wood application.
So Typekit got started, OK, clear, the logs led some to his ideas.
This to put.
That's it.
OK, call this a.
OK, my bed.
You are right, we forget.
We got the sexist response to that.
OK, let's verify in the database, see the first name got ginger from Peter to Peter one.
So using Jibia to create the record all to update the record, you need to use the same metric that
is provided by Jibia and it all depends, OK, create an update on the field on which you add it annotation.
If this is null, then you will create the record.
If this field has some value, then you will update the record.
So this is how you can update the record using GP.
So that's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.