In this lecture, we will see how the record using GDP, so for example, we want to delete the record
that is equal to three.
So let's see, how do I do this using GDP?
And for this purpose, we will develop the daily debate.
So let's jump to our student controller and here we will develop another API that is daily debate.
So use the and delete mapping.
OK, eps last delete, and we will pass the I.D. as part variable.
Public now on the successful deletion of the record reveals just written the simple message saying that
student has been deleted, so the return type will be string.
Delete student.
Let's get the part variables value using that part variable, in addition.
Long, I.D..
And from here, we will call our service here.
So let me copy this part.
Industrial service.
We will get it.
And now using the repository of stolen repository called the metadata delete my I.D. this one and passed
it its value.
Now let's return the message saying that student has been.
Deleted.
That's it.
So using the GP, if you want to delete the record by it, basically by your primary key, then you
just need to call the matter delete by it.
That's it.
OK.
This one is provided by GP.
Now let's call this matter from over control earlier and the scene will return.
OK, so room service.
Called the matter Bastide, if its value.
That's it.
Let's run spending what application?
So this will get started on Port 880.
Dylan, let's Demko postman, and here this is now delayed and it's equal to three as part variable.
Send this to a TTP delete method and called API.
We got the sexist response saying that student has been deleted.
Let's verify, you know what my school database see now we just have to record the record of it it equal
to three got deleted.
How using that GPA?
So what do you need to do is.
OK, let's go to a western service.
You just need to call the metal delete by ID using your repository.
That's it.
Then that internet security will be carried out by GP.
You don't need to worry about it.
OK?
So called this matter deliberately when you want to delete the record by your primary key, which is
basically your unique identifier.
In other words, your field OK on which you have ad ID and decent in your entity class.
So this is how you can delete the record using spinning data.
So that's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.