While developing recipes, it's not always that we want to expose all the fields in the decent response.
So for example, you are storing some sensitive information in the student table, for example, password
or maybe Secret Service in it answer.
Now this values you don't want to expose in the JSON response.
So let's see how to do this for this as well.
We are going to use the Jackson Library, OK?
Now, say, for example, we don't want to expose students email address.
OK, so on top of this, we'll use the in JSON ignore.
This one.
That's it.
I don't know what's between what obligation.
Dump the Bushmen.
And call this API.
See, now we are not getting email attribute in the decent response, OK?
Get all the students.
See, this is the first.
We are not getting the email address for this one, and this has been.
So, in short, email filled is being ignored while giving that decent response.
And keep in mind, OK, this is not just applicable for your decent response.
This is applicable for your request payload as well.
OK.
So for your request, be alone and just a response email attribute is being ignored.
Why?
Because we have user read these entries and at just an ignored OK.
And this is also coming from the Jackson Library, just like we have seen Jason property in the previous
lecture.
So this is how you can ignore that just an attribute while working with spitting that arrest.
That's all for now.
And we'll proceed further the next lecture.
Thank you very much.