By creating the Sudan, these are the details that we are passing in the rigorous bellowed in the palmtop,
Jason.
Now let's say we want to have validation for first Anfield.
So for example, if consumer provides first name field's value either null or empty, then we want to
throw out proper error message to the consumer.
So this is what we want to achieve in the upcoming lectures here.
The very first thing we need is we need to have the validator.
And for that, we will use the validator interface provided by setting framework.
So let's create.
The validator jumped to his ideas and first thing is we need to have the class that will implement the
validator interface.
So create a new class.
So, for example, validator Olympian.
Mark, this with a configuration.
Let me maximize.
And we need to implement.
Validator interface.
Make sure you select from the steering framework, not from the delegate exhibit, select from the spring
framework.
And we need to right two methods.
Let's come to this matter here, we need to return true instead of false.
OK.
The remove this one.
If you don't return true, then your validation will not work.
OK, so make sure you return through from this matter.
Now let's come to this matter.
Here, the actual validation will take place.
Now this matter has to matter parameters, OK?
One is type of object and another one is errors.
So here we will get the object of over A.D. Class C while creating the student.
These days we are passing right in the parliament of Jason.
So this will be converted to object of our entity class.
That is $200.
Spitting framework will use the Dickson Library right in the background and we will get the object of
student entity class.
So that object will get what here.
Obviously, we need to cast it, OK?
And using this object, we can provide the proper error message to the consumer.
So first thing is, we need to cast this object to a student class, OK, type of student.
So here costed like this.
My bed this is to rent and provide the object imported.
Now, let's head over, well, ED..
So what condition is if?
To get first name is either null.
Or empty, right?
Then we want to throw out error message, but is empty, then using this object, OK, type of errors,
call the meter, reject the value.
Select this one, OK?
With three string parameters.
First is our field that is first name.
Error code, that's fine if we don't provide.
And here is our message to the consumer.
So, for example, name is required.
So now we have created the validator.
Now this validator, we need to register with the spring guitarist so that we will do in the next lecture.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.