Let's get started with Health Explorer for Health Explorer.
We just need to add one dependency, another bombed-out eczema, and that is something that arrest her
explorer.
So at this dependency in the bombed out example?
And that's it.
We don't need to do any other configuration and no code is required.
So now we are good with Health Explorer.
So let's run over Springwood Application Build, then jump to browser.
Now, this is the you are in for everybody guessing, right?
Look on Horst $882 EPA.
So this you are in.
See, now we are getting nice you.
So this is provided by Health Explorer.
See, we don't have any code, OK, you know, what's being good application for this UI?
Here it is, listing down the resources, students, departments and subjects, and there are different
added methods.
OK?
This is the biggest post board, but don't delete.
Now, let's get the students OK, so click on this.
Did the biggest request.
So this is the URL for the EPA.
Here we can pass the bid.
No bid size starting projection, OK?
And this is that it didn't matter.
So this is if you want to, you can put OK.
Click on this go.
Come down.
See, we got a response.
So this is similar to what we used to get with the postman.
OK, now here we are getting that dense runs because our size is 10.
So click on this one.
And this is that it is for that particular student.
Come down.
This is the self navigation links for the consumer.
OK, using the headers and we hope, help for its implementation.
Let's say we want to get the department it is for this particular student.
So click on this at Typekit for the department.
Click on this one.
Go on the top.
See, now we are getting that department.
It is for this particular student that render it equal to 11.
So this is the EPA.
We are calling.
And here you can have the ADP headers while calling the rest API.
Let's go back to the homepage.
It's less AP.
Now, using this added post began, Kerry had decided disappeared, right?
So click on this one.
This is the EPA and see, these are the details we need to parse.
OK, for this to post EPA Department email, first name, last name in subject landing.
Here we can pass our request bill or in the form of Jason and click on Google.
So that will create the student.
So basically that will create the record in the.
So this kind of things you can try out yourself, OK?
You can explore these options.
That'd be good.
Pause board bed, then delete metals.
With her explorer, your consumer will get the idea that what he or she needs to pass while calling
the EPA.
So this is kind of a rest API documentation.
Earlier there was HAL browser, but now it is deprecated and the newer one is HAL Explorer.
So this is your information, OK?
Hal Browser is now deprecated, and the newer version is HAL Explorer.
So that's all about HAL Explorer, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.