In this lecture, we will go for business, and so using this API, we are getting the student information
right.
And by default, our bid says, is trade.
So we are getting that 20 day goals.
So this is our page number one.
Now look at this page information, OK?
The current bid number equal to zero.
Why?
Because this is zero bidder index.
OK, so first bid means zero.
2ND Bid means one.
Likewise, OK, because it is zero business index.
Now let's get the second bids.
And on that page, we should get four records.
OK.
Because total, we have 24 records.
And on the first page, we got 20 records.
So let's see how to do it.
So we need to pass one query parameter bids equal to one.
OK.
This is zero based index, so we will get second page called IPA.
So this is the first round, OK, second, third and fourth come down, see number equal to one.
So this is our second pitch, but it is zero based index.
So current bid number equal to one total elements, 24 total bids to and default bids is equal to 20.
Now, let's get the other page, OK?
So, for example, Tara Page, so page equal to two.
This is what we need to parse in the gritty parameter.
All they say see this area or collection or list, least whatever you say.
OK, this is completely empty and come down.
The information is seem OK.
The current page number equal to two.
That means equal to three.
It is zero business index.
So your consumer will get this all information OK?
And when he will get this empty, he will get the idea that on this page, there are no more records.
And this is applicable for all.
Get abs.
Let's do same with the subject API here.
OK.
Let's first call first page, okay.
That is no equal to zero.
See, we got 20 seconds.
OK, now on the second page, we should get eight records, right?
So page equal to one.
So here we are, eight subject details, OK?
Come down bid number equal to one that means to get zero misery index total wages, we have to.
Now let's get to the.
We should not get any record.
See, this is completely empty.
Come down current paid no.
Equal to three.
My bed.
I think we got affordable.
Bid.
OK?
Let's look toward here.
So this is our total bid, OK?
We don't have any record on the total pitch.
So obviously we will not get any on the fourth page or 20 bids, for example.
OK, let's call it see.
We will not get it, OK.
So this is our verbiage.
See the current bid number equal to two.
We don't have any records on this one, but yes, we do have one, does they can bid that is equal to
one?
But we are getting eight records on that number two.
So this is all you need to do it with you, the business, and while working with spring guitarist,
you just need to use this gritty parameter, Pejic world.
That's it.
And when you are calling this OK, remember that this is zero major index.
So if you want the very first page, the first 20 records, then you need to pass zero like this one.
By default, it is zero and you.
See, if you don't pass any value, then it will give you the first page.
That means first 20 records.
But then afterwards, if you want to sell, then you need to keep in mind that it is zero major index.
So this is second page, not the first one.
OK.
Another 20 records we are getting.
So using bids, gritty parameter, you can do the business, and while working with spinning, they're
dressed, that's all for now, and we'll proceed further and the next lecture.
Thank you very much.