In the previous lecture, we have seen custom APIs using the find by methods provided by submitting
data.
But here just one field is involved.
OK, see here we just have e-mail here.
We just don't post name.
Now, let's say we want to get started and it is by first name, last name.
So that is basically antiquity if we talk in context of security.
OK, so we want to help antiquity between two columns.
So let's jump to my second workbench.
So what?
We can try to get that first name.
Simple example equal to John.
OK.
And.
Last name Nicole to Smith.
Rhonda Aguirre.
So we got the story, and it is now this we want to have as you debate.
And indeed, our consumer can pass these two values, OK, as many parameters.
These are the basically values, OK, or first NIMET last name.
So two very parameters.
So let's say this says goodbye using the spring GDP, OK, and spring guitarist will expose the mattress
goodbye.
So let me copy this what we have seen in the previous lecture.
So find by first name and then we want to know antiquity, OK?
And using which filled first name and last name, OK.
So in the camel case, another will last name and we need another method parameter.
Last name.
That's it.
See, these are the things provided by spring.
OK.
And this matter will be used to by spring guitarist, and it will expose this as GDP a bit to query
parameters.
Now let's I don't know what spring would application.
Let me copy this, Metallica and jump to Horsemen.
Here after the search, OK for students, Les Estes, Les Search and then our attorney.
OK, first name, let's Peter or say, for example, John, you know what?
Example?
Another query parameter, right?
Last name the theme OK, you need to provide from here the exact one.
What you have as method parameter.
OK?
The same you need to possess query parameter for your GDP.
Last, Jimmy Goldsmith called AP.
See, this is just branded as OK, VAT ID equal to 18.
Or let's try another one.
OK.
So, for example, first name Peter and last name Mark, OK, let's try with this one last name, mark
and first name.
Peter.
All they see is equal to two.
So this mythology of what we have right in the repository, this is being exposed less goodbye by spring
guitarist.
So there are several methods, OK, which are automatically provided by spring.
You can explore yourself or say, for example, you want to help or Griddy between first name and last
name column.
OK, so let me copy this.
This also you can try.
OK.
And this is also provided by spring ADP.
Just write the or operator between your two fields.
OK, first name and last name.
Here we antiquity.
Here we go.
Or query between which bills first name and last name so we can say between the first name and last
name column that we have in this table.
Let me stop and again start the spring wood application.
Copy this one.
Provider here.
OK, let's hear first name Peter.
OK.
And lastly, Michael Rosemead, so we should get those two entities, OK?
First name Michael Jupiter.
Last name Michael Smith.
Now we help order parameter.
OK?
See it equal to two Peter Mark and another be we is it equal to 18 John Smith.
So here, OK, for the first student, the first name is Magilla or here and Paul.
Last name OK, it is merging with the second string.
So that's why we are getting to student details.
OK, in that Jason response.
This is the collection or list or area, whatever you say.
Why?
Because our written type is least top student.
This is antiquity, and this is our query.
So these are the couple custom areas that we have developed and others, as I said, you can try yourself
OK, fine by methods which are provided by GP so that you can try out yourself.
So this is how you can have the customer base while working with spring that.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further the next lecture.
Thank you very much.