Hello and welcome back in this lecture, we will download and install Mike Wall in our local machine
in this course.
We are going to use Mike Wall as the database connecting to our spring wood application.
So here is the official website of my sequel just got here and download the music well, according to
your operating system.
So this includes my cycle server and my cycle workbench.
My cycle server is required because we are going to run the database in our local machine and to execute
the queries on that server.
We need you.
That is my cycle workbench to execute the queries.
So download and install, according to her operating system after installing it.
If you are a Windows user, then go inside your program files.
You will see this folder green created Michael go inside the physical server inside the bin.
Here you will see one that is my security to start the my server in our local machine.
We need to run this easy fight file, so just click and it will start.
The music was there were in our local machine.
If this is not working for you, then there is another option as well.
The search for the services and inside the services.
Go for Michael.
You see or here, just right click and start.
So this will start the equals surrounding our local scene.
If you take the properties, it is pointing to only my second deed or the file you see.
That's what we just now thin.
So now my the robot is running in our local machine.
So let's connect to it using my physical workbench.
So open the bicycle workbench.
And you need to make the connection.
Localised, you can you can accent anything almost is localized.
This is the by default port for the local music conservatory.
Three 06.
Rudy the username and password whatever you give during the installation.
Click on the disconnect, then see.
This is successful, so we are good toward here.
Just click audio to connect to local database.
So here are the default schemas provided by my sequel that Spain, as we proceed in the course, will
create another schema for our microservices.
So make sure before the next lecture, you download and install my wall in your local machine.
So that's all for now.
We'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.