In the previous lecture, we created this validator.
Now let's register it with spring guitarist.
So we already have one configuration class, right?
This one that we are implementing repository, it is configured.
So here we need to order it one more method.
So let's go to this interface.
Now, let's come down.
This is the matter.
OK.
This one we need to order, I configured very decent repository event listener.
Read this one, OK.
All right, this matter to add validators manually.
So copy this metadata from here.
And all right.
What he had in our class public, Margaret, with at or right?
Bring this brocades, let me do maximize.
Now, using the object of this listener, OK, we need to call the meter at validator, so here.
Called the matter at a validator.
Now let's go to this matter.
So this matter has two metal parameters, OK?
The first one is event type of setting and another one is type of validator.
In the previous lecture, we have already created the class right, which is implementing validator
interface so that we need to provide order here so that classes right this one right validator Ambien
saw here, whatever it.
So this is the instance of.
Validator IPL and possible here.
Now, let's come to even part, so here we are creating this brand, right?
So before we create the student, we want to impose validation.
So our event will be before create.
So we need to provide like this in the formidable Sting.
Make sure you provide exactly like this, OK, following the camel case, be in the lower case and see
in the upper case.
Now we have created a validator and registered it with spring guitarist.
So in the next lecture, we will test it out.
That's all for now and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.