Below we have seen projection and here we helpless projection using which we are exposing pupils in
an email of the student.
Now let's say there is a consumer with asking for the full name of the student in the decent response.
That means first name space, last name.
So the consumer is asking for the new attribute qualities.
Pull them in the decent response.
So let's see, how do I do this with projection?
So inside our projection, let's say a one meter signature with written Dipper's string say, for example,
get full name.
We don't have any look at his full name inside our student class.
That's fine.
Now to achieve this, we need to consider the values first name and last name, right?
These two values, we need to conclude so that we do using the added value, in addition, that is provided
by spring framework.
So on top of this matter, how to add value in addition, import it now using the spending experts and
language will achieve this, OK?
So with double quotes has and is.
And they don't target.
So this target is basically object to what entity, class, which entity class, the entity class for
which we how these projects and so, you know, for example, the entity classes student.
OK, go inside this class here we held these two bills, right?
First name and last name.
And these two values we want to get and we have the object of this class, right?
So we can access these two pills right inside our projection using the object.
Dot first name like this?
OK, now at the space, OK, using content and in the same way, we need to have that last name.
So copy this and this is now.
Last name?
That's it.
I don't know what's being what application.
Until then, jump to Bossman.
All this EPA to get US warrants and apply the projection using this very parameter.
All these EPA.
See, now we are getting this new attribute in the U.S. response.
Full name Peter Spears mark that means first name Spears last name.
OK.
And this is applicable for all the records.
See, from where it is coming from, this project said OK, first projects and this is the matter will
again matter signature.
And here we are doing the content.
OK, first name Spears last name.
So this is how you can connect the values while working with projects on.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further the next lecture.
Thank you very much.