Look at this response.
We are not getting it its value in the decent response.
So this is the default behavior provided by spring guitarist.
It will not expose the value of your field on which you have added an audition.
Basically, your unique identifier.
OK, so this is the default behavior provided by spring guitarist.
But end it.
And that's what we are going to do in this lecture.
OK.
We just need to do a little bit configuration.
So let's create another class for this.
Say arrest config.
Mark, this with ad configuration.
And we need to implement.
Interfaced.
Repository, it is this one configured at a.
Let me do maximize.
And we need to operate one metallo case or go to interface, come down.
And this metallic country gold repository, wrist configuration, this metal, we need to order it,
OK, so let's copy signature of this metal and in our class.
What here?
Mark Devitt at or override?
Now using this configuration object.
OK.
All the metal to expose IEDs for, and we need to provide the entity glass, so you know what, example,
student or class?
That's it.
OK.
Go to this matter.
It is accepting multiple classes, OK?
Say, for example, we have a department table.
OK.
And there also we help Adekola column.
So obviously we'll be having the department and the Glass department or Java support that we will be
having.
That is Depay's on which end point?
Less departments, right, automatically generated by spring that arrest.
So if you want to expose its ideal value, OK, so you need to provide it or here like this one, OK,
Department Board plus, for example, I'm saying we don't have this entity class.
Say, for example, you have 10 tables in your school database, so you will be having the then entity
classes and for them all, if you want to expose it as well, you provide all 10 entity classes or here,
OK, with comma separated like this one.
But for now, we just know one entity class that is student dot java.
So provide like this one, OK, astronaut class.
That's it.
Let's run our Springwood application.
Jump to postmen and we will call the same EPA, OK?
Getting this plant that is equal to one.
See, now we are getting it for its value in that JSON response, OK?
Let's check for all students now here.
Also, we will get it equal to one in equal to two earlier.
We were not getting this bill's value, OK?
And that was the default behavior provided by spring, that arrest.
But with this configuration, we have changed our default behavior.
OK, now another workaround is also there, OK?
So for that, what you can do?
Go to your entity class.
OK, define one meter.
Say, for example, get student I.D..
OK.
And here done this, not it.
It will tell you basically you're now running again.
So this will get exposed in the DSM response, OK?
As Student ID attribute.
Let me show you OK, all this EPA.
S. Student Aid equal to one.
Equal to two gay.
Get it equal to one where see this one indeed equal to one.
OK, so this also you're going to have the metal and expose it.
So whatever you prefer, you can go with this one, OK?
Let me comment this one for your reference.
In this course, we will go with this configuration when OK?
Provide your entity class.
So this is how you can expose it if its value while working with spring day to rest, so that's all
for now.
And we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.