Bill, now we have developed this custom apps using the Pine Bay method provided by GP here, but let's
say you are right to put our apples.
Same is our methodology.
So here we are, joined by email here we help find by first name or last name.
Same for other methods.
Now, let's say you are not compatible with this part, or let's say it is not as per the standard OK
for the project you are working for or for the company you are working for.
Well, let's say your consumer is not compatible with this EPA, but let's say you are two and you want
to change it so that also we can configure.
And this is what we are going to do in the lecture.
So here we have this part, right?
What about EPA fined by email, which is same is our method name, OK?
This is the default one being used at a base putting that arrest.
Now for this one, OK, so use the energy sun as rest a resource.
OK, and we need to set, but attribute value this one.
So, for example, we want to have it as less decimal, so provide e-mail.
Don't include us less, OK?
Just provide.
But now run Springwood application and jump to postman.
So up to 30, right we have already seen find by email.
Let me see if I am getting.
That's fine.
Let me add, I did OK, this one find by e-mail.
And good parameter email equal to.
John at Gmail dot com.
Call this EPA, we should get photo.
OK, see, we are getting photo four, because now we have a change in the partagé for our EPA.
We need to provide less EPA then our query parameter in its value.
Now call this EPA.
See, big order details, OK?
And this video is in.
But the main part is now we have genes in the part borrowed EPA instead of having this default one,
OK?
Now we have configured it how using this annotation rest resource.
So the same thing you can apply for these methods as well, OK?
You just need to have this kind of annotation and provide the part for your API.
That's it.
Let me go back here.
So here what happens, I'll give whatever methods you have inside your repository.
Those are being exposed by spring guitarist, OK?
As this debate is now, let's say you don't want to expose some particular methods, OK as recipes.
So that also we can do obviously the easiest ways to comment this out, OK?
So splintered that it will not expose this matters, but is Typekit.
This is the best way you can do, but all you can say is that, for example, you can remove this completely.
But let's say you want to have this matter, OK, inside your repository for some reason, for reference
or for any reason.
OK.
But you don't want to expose this as it is debate saw here.
OK, using this generation, that is the resource you need to cite one attribute exported equal to false.
OK.
That's it.
But I'm speaking what application and jump to Boseman?
This is our last e-mail.
Now call it.
See, now we are getting photo port, why?
Because we are now not exposing this, OK?
This as GDP, we have said export equal to false.
By default, it is true.
So this is how you can configure the part for your custom apps while working with spring guitarist.
That's all for now.
And we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.