So now we are all set with our validator.
So let's test it out.
But before we don't know what spending would apply, Gibson, let's go to department repository and
comment this one OK?
Now we want to have our department able to be exposed to this arrest resource.
OK?
So for your reference, I'm having this poor as commented.
OK, now we are all good.
I don't know what Springwood Application will then dump to postman.
Now, by creating the student, let's provide first name value equal to empty like this one.
The CPA?
See, now we are getting 400 bed requests, OK?
Let's check our response, see under the arrows and the glass, which one surrendered our property that
is basically filled, OK?
You know what example that is?
First name and look at this message.
It is saying that first name is required.
So this is the proper error message that now consumer is getting and using this error message, OK,
in the format of this and the consumer will get idea that what things he is doing wrong, what here?
Now let's try to create the department.
So in the same way, I want it to be post API.
OK.
Let's clear, does civil department.
And call this EPA see, he got 500 internet data, OK?
And take this message, cannot cast Department Glass to student glass.
Why we are getting this jump to his ideas.
And this is our validator, OK?
And here we are doing casting right object of this one right target to student class.
So from here it is throwing error.
Now let's go to our configuration.
So here we have registered this validator right and event type is before create.
So this particular validator is applicable for all your ADP post-debate.
So when you create this one, this will be applicable when you create the department.
This will be applicable when you create the subject.
This validation will take place.
So basically, for all your tables, OK, with which you have entity class in repository and those are
exposed, it is.
It is the resource for all those, right?
When you create the record, this particular validator will take place.
So this is applicable for all the post debates, so to avoid this, OK?
What we can do?
We can have one it conditional here.
So, for example, this particular decent and we just want to know when we are creating this one.
Obviously, when we create the department, we will not get the value of poisoning.
And in the same way, if we are creating the subject right, we will not get the value of poisoning.
So if this is instance of student class, OK, then only cost it.
Now, if you want to help another one, it is an OK for your department.
So, for example, department name cannot be null or empty, then.
Copied again with the elusive if like this one instance of department.
This one and put your it isn't what here.
Whatever it is, OK, using this one, you can throw out the error message saying that department in
cannot be null or empty.
So let me comment out this one for your reference.
Now we are all good.
I don't know what Springwood Application.
Dump two policemen.
And call this EPA.
Now we got the success response, OK, 201 created.
So what do you need to remember?
Is that OK, whatever you have inside this matter with this particular event, OK, before create it
will be applicable for all the added to be four steps, basically before you create any record using
this register resources.
So this is how you can impose the will descend before you create the record, that's all for now, and
we'll proceed further.
The next lecture?
Thank you very much.