In this lecture, we will see what is hideous and what is hell.
In other words, you can pronounce it as hit or is whatever you want to pronounce.
So here Haiti transport hyper media is the engine of applications dead and health stands for hypertext
application language.
Now let's understand this to wit example.
See, we have Springwood application by which we are providing the wristbands.
So here is the consumer with hitting over these tips and in return it is getting the response in the
apartment.
Jason.
Now, Heidi, Do is is the principal, or you can say concerning by which you are allowing your consumers
to navigate to other resources.
All you can say to navigate to other apps provided by you.
OK, so that will happen with a decent response.
Let me show you an example.
OK.
This is not just a response or power.
One of the apps, so this is headier is inside which your JSON response will contain hyper media links.
Say this one?
So what will happen?
Your consumer will get this decent response, OK, by calling your API, and it will contain this kind
of hyper media links so your consumer can consume this IPAs, OK?
So that is kind of a self mitigation.
Your consumer is calling one of your weapons in the response it is getting the data along with it.
It will get this kind of hyper media links.
So using this, it can call other APIs provided by you and this call it is hitting us.
Now, let's say you want to provide U.S. support for your wrist base and you want to have this kind
of hyper media links in that JSON response.
So you need an implementation because he does.
It's just the principle.
Or you can say constant, you need an implementation.
So there comes hell.
So basically, is the implementation up here, do yours?
There are a couple of other hurdles implementation as well, like local exemplars, Jason, just an
EPA, et cetera.
But the most popular and widely used are the implementation of video is is hell.
And that's what we will use in this course as well.
See, if we are using the spring guitarist, then we don't need to worry about it, okay, because spring
guitarist will create this kind of hype with media links for our wristbands in the former top Jason
in our response.
OK, we don't need to worry about it.
Spring guitarist will work with the hell and it will put this kind of hype and media links in that Jason
response.
What our research is.
So that's all about headless and hell, that's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.