Inside the glass, we have subjects learning that is they bob list.
Now let's say we want to populate a number of subjects.
The particular student is learning, so that is basically count that we want to populate in the Jeison.
So let's see how to achieve this using projection.
So this is our first projection.
Let's do another method signature with return type as integer because we want to retain the count,
right?
So that is numeric value.
So, for example, get total subjects.
And on top of this, we need to have the added value in and using those putting explicit language right.
We need to do this.
So has called.
And here we will get the object of still going into declassified and inside that we have this list.
OK, so this is the fear.
So this bill, right, is type of list.
So how to get the size of the list in Java by calling the seismometer right, so called the meter size.
That's it.
Springwood application and will then jump to postman.
All these EPA and applied projects and equal to five projects and called EPA.
See, we got the response, but look at this one now, all subjects equal to two come down for this
one total subject, equal to one and so on.
So this is applicable for all the records, OK?
Or let's get this done by it.
So here also we are replaying the first projects and see we are getting total subjects equal due to
how we are getting this using this projection and we know this method signature, OK, inside our first
projection.
So this kind of things you can try out yourself.
This depends on your requirements, what you want to have inside your projects and use the add value
in addition and spitting explicit language.
That's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.