No Springwood application.
We held three and any classes and three repositories using this entity, classes and repositories spring,
that arrest is exposing them as a resource resource.
So this is the default behavior right now, let's say for the particular table.
We don't want to expose it as a resource resource.
So that's what we are going to do in this lecture.
So, for example, we don't want to expose department people as a resource.
So let's see how to do it, OK?
So go to its repository.
You know what?
Example?
This is one, right?
Department repository.
How dangerous it is, rest resorts, this one, OK?
And exported attribute equal to falls.
That's it.
Now let's renovate Springwood Obligation.
Jump to browser.
And it this you are all for our application.
Let me see now we have two resources one force, one table and another one for subjects landing table.
We don't have recipes for our department table.
Basically spinning that arrest is not providing any recipe for our department table.
Why?
Because we how this an addition on top of this repository for the department.
But it is the resource exporter equal to falls.
So this is very helpful because it may be possible that you how many tables in your school database.
And it is not always necessary that you want to expose all of them as rest a resource so that you can
use this annotation at rest resource exporting equal to false.
So this is how you can restrict resources by working with spring guitarist.
That's all for now.
And we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.