In this lecture, we will see how to update the record using the rest API provided by spring guitarist.
So here our Q&amp;A is less students.
OK, so that was the.
We just need to change the ATP methodology, select the pod because we want to update the record.
OK, now let's go to our chat room table.
And here we have three records now say, for example, we want to update us and it is where it's equal
to four.
OK.
This particular record we want to update.
So if we need to possess part variable less for like this one?
Now, let's come to regress payload that we need to pass in the parliament of dissent.
So for example, we want to change this first name from Peter to Peter one.
OK.
Other attributes we don't want to update.
Basically, other column values we don't want to update OK for this particular record.
But still, we need to pass this one.
While calling the debate or debate to update the record called this disappear because the success response?
See first name Peter one.
Let's verify in the database.
See, the first name got changed up from Peter to Peter.
One.
But look at the request below.
We still need to pass other attributes, even if we don't want to update this attribute values.
OK, now let's not pass this one and say, for example, we want to go back to Peter.
OK, Rhonda Peter one.
Call this EPA check the response.
These values got nullified taking the database.
See, for these two columns now, values got update, it is not obviously this has got changed, OK
from Peter one to Peter, but look at this column values, OK?
This two column values got nullified.
Why?
Because we are not passing these two values.
OK?
These two last name and email, you know, what exists or in the form of decent.
So this is the iPad of, OK, that whatever fills you, how you need to pass all the values, even if
you are bleeding, that feels value if you are not updating it.
Still, you need to pass it if you don't provide these attributes so that you don't want to update than
it will consider that you want to update those attributes as null values.
OK, so this is the put that is provided by spring day to rest, and this is how you can update the
record.
So that's all for now, and we'll proceed further in the next lecture.
Thank you very much.