In this section, we're going to write integration tests for the product service.
In order to develop integration tests for the product service,
we're going to leverage MockMvc and DbUnit.
We'll configure the integration test class to create a MockMvc
instance to set up the full Spring application context,
and then we'll configure DbUnit to pre-populate an H2 database
with a known set of data before each test runs.
Then we'll use MockMvc to execute HTTP requests against the product
service and validate that we receive the expected responses.
To do this,
we'll configure our test class to leverage both the
SpringExtension and the DBUnitExtension.
We'll load the full Spring application context
through the SpringBootTest annotation,
we'll set our ActiveProfiles to test so that our
test configuration will be loaded,
and we'll use the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation to tell
Spring to create a MockMvc instance.
We'll add the getConnectionHolder method that DbUnit requires,
and then we'll annotate each test method with the dataset annotation
so that DbUnit will pre-populate our database.
Let's take a look at the source code for the
ProductServiceIntegrationTest and see how it all fits together.
The ProductServiceIntegrationTest class is annotated with the
ExtendWith annotation that includes both the DBUnitExtension
and the SpringExtension classes.
The DBUnitExtension will allow us to pre-populate our
database before each test runs,
and the SpringExtension will manage the Spring application context.
It's annotated with the SpringBootTest annotation to tell Spring to
load all of our classes and wire them together.
The ActiveProfiles annotation tells Spring to use the test profile,
which has our embedded H2 database configuration.
And the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation will create a MockMvc instance
that we can use to make web requests against our service.
From the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation,
we have an autowired MockMvc instance, and from our test configuration,
we have an autowired DataSource instance.
The DBUnitExtension requires that we provide a getConnectionHolder method that
returns a function that returns a data source connection.
With these prerequisites complete, we're ready to write our tests.
The first test method is testGetProductByIdFound.
This method is annotated with the DataSet annotation
that references the products.yml file.
DbUnit will pre-populate the H2 database through the
connection returned by the getConnectionHolder method with
the contents of the products.yml file.
The products.yml file contains two products with IDs 1 and 2, respectively.
In this test, we use MockMvc to perform a GET request to the URI /product/1,
and then we validate that we receive a 200 OK HTTP
response code that the body contains JSON,
that we have the correct ETAG and LOCATION headers,
and then we validate that the id, name, quantity,
and version numbers match the data that's in the products.yml file.
While this test is simple,
it's important to note that MockMvc is invoking the product controller,
which extracts the ID from the URI path and makes the
appropriate call to the product service,
which in turn calls the product repository that queries the database.
This test is validating the end-to-end functionality
of a get/product request handler.
The testGetProductByIdNotFound method uses mockMvc to
perform a GET request for /product/99,
and then validates that it returns a 404 Not Found HTTP response code.
The testCreateProductMethod tests the creation of a new product in the database.
First, we create a new product to post to the product service,
it has a name of Product Name, and a quantity of 10.
We then use mockMvc to post a request to /product with the
contentType set to APPLICATION_JSON,
and the body containing a JSON representation of the new product.
We then verify that we receive a 201 created HTTP response code,
a JSON contentType, and an ETAG with a value of 1.
Because DbUnit initializes our database with the
contents of the products.yml file,
we know that there are 2 products with IDs 1 and 2.
So the next automatically generated ID will be 3.
So we validate that the LOCATION header is set to /product/3
and that the returned product has an ID of 3.
We validate that the product name and quantity match what we passed in,
and then we check that the version is set to 1,
which is should be because we just created the new product.
The testProductPutSuccess method updates an existing product.
It creates a new product with the name Product 2 Updated, and a quantity of 10.
It uses mockMvc to perform a PUT request to /product/2,
passing it a JSON representation of the new product
and an IF_MATCH header value of 2,
which matches the version number of product 2 in the database.
It validates that it receives a 200 OK HTTP response code,
a new ETAG version of 3, the correct LOCATION header,
and the new values that we updated.
The testProductPutVersionMismatch method performs similar steps,
attempting to put a product update to /product/1,
but it specifies the wrong version number in the IF_MATCH header.
It then validates that we receive a 409 Conflict HTTP response code.
The testProductPutNotFound method attempts to update a
product that doesn't exist in the database.
It performs a put to /product/99 and validates that it
receives a 404 NotFound HTTP response code.
The testProductDeleteSuccess method deletes product 1 by
performing a delete request against /product/1 and validates that
it receives a 200 OK HTTP response code.
And finally,
the testProductDeleteNotFound method attempts to delete product 99 and
validates that it receives a 404 NotFound HTTP response code.
All of these tests are very similar to the product
controller test that we wrote,
but the difference is that we're not mocking responses from the service,
but instead the requests are passing through the entire technology stack and interacting with a real database.