MockMvc allows us to execute an HTTP request,
which could be a GET, PUT, POST, PATCH, or DELETE.
It defines RequestBuilders that help us define the request,
set any HTTP headers that we need, and then optionally specify a JSON payload.
It provides methods to validate the HTTP response,
such as the response code, as well as the content type returned.
It defines a set of ResultMatchers that are used in
conjunction with expectations about the response.
For example, we need to tell MockMvc that we expect a status code of 200 OK,
which is accomplished by using the status ResultMatcher and the value is OK.
Next, we're able to examine the HTTP headers,
such as the entity tag, as well as the location,
using the header's ResultMatcher.
You have full access to all of the headers,
but when testing a RESTful service,
the ETag and location are typically the most important.
Finally, we're able to validate the response body.
In our example, the product controller returns a JSON response,
so we're going to leverage the JSON path ResultMatcher to extract fields from
the response payload and compare them to our expected values.
Before we get started reviewing our unit tests,
let's see what a unit test looks like in Spring Boot and how we configure it.
First, we need to add the SpringExtension to our class.
Recall that in JUnit 4 we used runners to integrate
third-party libraries with JUnit.
In JUnit 5 we use extensions, which are added using the ExtendWith annotation.
Extensions receive callback notifications during the JUnit lifecycle,
and the SpringExtension uses these notifications to
manage our application context.
Next we have the SpringBootTest annotation.
Essentially,
this annotation is used with any test class that wants to
integrate with a Spring Boot application.
It searches the class path to find Spring-annotated beans,
including configuration classes.
In short,
it sets up the application context and wires dependencies into your
tests so that you can use the classes that you're testing without
instantiating and configuring them.
Then we have the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation.
As its name suggests,
any test annotated with this annotation enables the automatic
configuration of a new MockMvc instance.
At the bottom, you can see a MockMvc autowired into the test,
which is only possible by specifying the
AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation on the test class itself.
Finally,
we can define mock versions of other Spring-annotated beans for use in this
test class only by specifying the MockBean annotation.
This annotation is defined in Spring Boot's test classes and
creates a mock implementation of the product service,
using Mockito.
The important thing to note here is that this test class will use the mocked
version of the product service instead of the real version.
Spring will autowire the mocked version into the controller that we're testing,
but only for this class.
Now that you understand what MockMvc can do and how to
set up a Spring Boot test class,
let's dive into the source code for the ProductControllerTest
class and see how we can test our controller.
The ProductControllerTest is annotated with the ExtendWith annotation,
specifying the SpringExtension.class.
Again,
this allows the SpringExtension to listen to JUnit 5 lifecycle
notifications and manage your application context.
It's annotated with the SpringBootTest annotation,
which tells Spring to create an application context and load it with all
of the Spring-annotated classes in the class path.
And finally, it's annotated with the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation,
which causes spring to create a MockMvc instance for us and
autowire it into the MockMvc field in our test class.
We've added a ProductService annotated with the MockBean annotation.
Spring will use Mockito to create a mock version of the
ProductService and wire it into the product controller in
the test application's context.
Let's begin by looking at the testGetProductByIdFound method.
This method is annotated with the Test annotation,
which identifies it as a JUnit 5 test case.
The DisplayName annotation is used to report the
name of the test in test reports.
We begin by creating a mockProduct,
and then configuring the mockProduct service to return an
Optional of this mockProduct when the ProductService's findById
method is called with the argument 1.
Then we invoke the mockMvc.perform method, passing it the GET RequestBuilder.
This example statically imports the GET method from the
MockMvcRequestBuilders for readability.
We pass the UrlTemplate /product/id, and then bind the URI ID variable to 1.
The perform method executes a web request against
the Spring MVC servlet container.
In this case, it invokes a GET request against /product/1,
which resolves to the product controller's get product method.
The perform method returns a result actions instance.
The important method that result actions provides is andExpect,
which accepts a ResultMatcher.
A ResultMatcher is an interface with a single method,
match,
that evaluates an expression and throws an assertion
error if the expression fails.
In this code, we see several pre-built ResultMatchers,
all statically imported from the MockMvcResultMatchers class,
such as the status method, which returns a status ResultMatcher,
the content method, which returns a content ResultMatcher,
the header method, which returns a header ResultMatchers,
and the jsonPath method, which returns a JSON path ResultMatchers.
Let's take a quick look at the status isOK method.
The isOK method returns matcher for HttpStatus.OK.
The matcher method executes an assertEquals call against the HTTP
response returned by the product controller.
If we dive a little deeper,
the assertEquals method compares the two values and
calls fail if those values don't match.
And finally, the fail method throws an assertion error.
All of this is to say that if the HTTP status code returned by the
product controller's getProduct method is 200 OK,
then the processing continues, but if it's not 200 OK,
then it throws an assertion error, which fails the test and halts the test case.
This is the pattern that all of the ResultMatchers follow,
so hopefully now they'll be a little bit easier to read.
Getting back to our ProductControllerTest,
we can see the following general expectations: The
expected HTTP status code should be 200 OK,
the expected contentType should be JSON,
the expected ETAG header value should be the string 1,
and the expected LOCATION header should be /product/1.
The jsonPath expectations may take a little bit more explanation.
The jsonPath method accepts an expression and a matcher.
The expression is a string that ultimately gets compiled to a jsonPath.
Pluralsight has an excellent article about JSON
paths that I encourage you to read.
The URL is shown here on the screen.
But for the purposes of this example,
the dollar sign represents the root node of the JSON,
and the dot notation references the path to a value.
So when we write $ .id,
we're specifying that we want to examine the ID
attribute of the root node of the JSON.
The second parameter to jsonPath is a matcher,
which in this case is the is method,
which is statically imported from the Hamcrest matchers class.
This method performs a simple equality comparison,
specifying the expected value.
The jsonPath method compiles the expression and then executes the matcher,
which in this case compares the value of the root
node's ID attribute to the value 1.
Likewise, $ .name compares the JSON name attribute to product name,
the $ .quantity compares the JSON quantity attribute to 10,
and the $ .version compares the JSON version attribute to 1.
That was a lot of detailed explanation for a relatively small amount of code,
but if you understood all of that, the rest will be easy.
Now let's look at the testGetProductByIdNotFound method.
The purpose of this method is to test the
get/product for an ID that does not exist.
We configure the mocked product service to return an optional empty
when its findById method is called with a value of 1,
then we execute a GET request for /product/1 using MockMvc.
Finally, we add an expectation of a NotFound HTTP status code.
Next,
the testCreateProduct method tests posting a new product to the /product URI.
We set up two products,
one that represents the product that will post to /product and one that will be
returned when the product service's save method is called.
We use the Mockito doReturn method to specify that when the product
service's save method is called with any value,
it should return the mock product.
We execute the same mockMvc.perform method,
but this time we pass a post RequestBuilder.
The post RequestBuilder is built in three steps.
First, we specify the urlTemplate, which is /product,
then we specify the contentType as JSON,
and finally, we specify the content, or body,
as a JsonString representation of the product we're posting.
A RequestBuilder follows the builder design pattern,
so we're free to chain these methods together to construct the final request.
The asJsonString method is a helper method that I wrote that
uses the Jackson JSON library's ObjectMapper to convert a
product instance to a JSON string.
The testCreateProduct method then validates the response.
It expects a 201 created HTTP response code,
a return contentType of JSON, an ETAG header value of 1,
and a LOCATION header of /product/1.
It then uses the jsonPath method to validate that the JSON
fields match those in the mock product that the product
service's save method returned.
Next,
we have three different PUT tests that attempt to update an existing product.
The first one, testProductPutSuccess, tests a successful update.
The second one, testProductPutVersionMismatch,
tests a version mismatch,
which means that we're passing an IF_MATCH header value that
doesn't match the product being updated.
And the last one, testProductPutNotFound,
tests an attempt to update a product that does not exist.
The testProductPutSuccess method creates a product to be used as the
body of the PUT and a product to be returned by the Product service
when it's findById 1 method is called.
After successfully finding the Product with ID 1,
we expect the Product controller to call the product
service's update method to update the product.
Again,
we use Mockito to tell the product service to return
true when its update method is called.
We construct a PUT RequestBuilder that points to the
/product/1 urlTemplate with a JSON contentType,
a content body that contains a string representation of our putProduct,
and an IF_MATCH HTTP header with a value of 1.
We expect this request to return a 200 OK HTTP response code,
a JSON content type, and a new ETAG value of 2,
since we just updated the product, and a LOCATION of /product/1.
The values of the payload are then validated as we did in the previous methods.
The second PUT test performs the same steps,
but passes an ETag value that does not match the version number of the product,
so we expect a 409 conflict HTTP response code.
The final PUT test configures the mockProduct service to return an
Optional.empty when its findById method is called,
so we expect a 404 NotFound HTTP response code.
Hopefully from this,
you can see how we test each possible outcome from executing
a PUT request against the PUT controller.
Now let's finish up this test by adding a new delete
request handler to our product controller using a proper test-driven development methodology.