Now let's turn our attention to testing our service.
The role of a service in the Spring application is twofold.
First, it implements your business logic.
While the controller is responsible for handling web
requests and generating web responses,
it should be isolated from the inner workings of the
rest of the Spring application.
The service implements any business logic that you may require.
Second,
the service serves as an abstraction layer between your
controller and back-end dependencies.
If the data is stored in a database and accessed a
repository today and tomorrow it's stored in the cloud and
accessed via a web service call,
the Spring service isolates the controller from needing to know that.
The controller simply asks the service for a product,
and the service is responsible for connecting to the
correct dependency and retrieving it.
The product service provides four key pieces of functionality: First,
it allows us to find a product using its ID or to find all products.
Next, it allows us to save a product,
which creates a new product in the database.
Then it allows us to update an existing product.
And finally, it allows us to delete a product from the database.
Let's look at the source code for the product service and see how it works.
The ProductService is pretty simple because there's not
a whole lot of business logic to it.
First,
the ProductService interface defines five methods: findById returns an
optional product instance for the product with the specified ID.
If the product's not found, then it returns an Optional empty.
FindAll returns a list containing all products in the database.
Update updates the specified product and returns
true if the update was successful.
Save saves a product to the database and returns a
reference to the product that was saved.
Finally, the delete method deletes a product from the database,
returning true if the deletion was successful.
The productServiceImpl class implements the ProductService interface.
It's annotated with Spring's Service annotation,
which identifies it as a Spring service.
When Spring scans the class path,
it'll find the productServiceImpl through this annotation
and add it to its application context.
The ProductServiceImpl defines a constructor that accepts a product
repository and saves that product repository to a number variable.
When Spring is creating a ProductService and sees
that it needs a productRepository, which itself is a Spring-managed bean,
then it will automatically pass the productRepository to
the productServiceImpl's constructor.
The findById, findAll, update,
and delete methods are all pass through methods to
the underlying productRepository.
The save method first sets the version of the new product to 1,
and then passes it to the productRepository.
This service is simple, but if you had any complex business logic,
this is the place where it would go.
As you just saw, the product service is fairly simple.
For all cases, other than the save method,
it's just a pass through to the underlying repository.
As such, our testing strategy is also simple.
We're going to create a mock product repository,
wire it into the product service,
and then test various scenarios by configuring the response from the mock
product repository and validating the response from the service.
Let's dive in and write our unit test for the product service.
The ProductServiceTest class is annotated with both
the JUnit 5 ExtendWith annotation,
to allow the SpringExtension.class to receive JUnit 5 lifecycle
notifications and manage our application context,
and the SpringBootTest annotation,
to tell Spring to scan our class path and construct an application context.
We have Autowired our ProductService instance to test into our Test class,
and we've defined a mock ProductRepository.
The first test method is findByIdSuccess,
which tests a successful product retrieval.
We create a mockProduct object and configure the mockProduct
repository to return that product when its findById method
is called with the argument 1.
We then execute the ProductService's findById method,
and then execute two assertions on the returned object.
First, the returnedProduct should be present,
and second,
the returnedProduct should be the same object as
the mockProduct we created above.
If you've been using JUnit for a while,
you may notice that JUnit 5 has switched the order of
the arguments in its Assert method.
It now expects the condition first and the error message as the last argument.
The second test method is findByIdNotFound,
and it repeats the same steps,
but with a mock repository that returns an Optional.empty and an
assertion that the product is not present.
The third test method is testFindAll.
This method constructs two mockProducts and configures the
mock repository to return a list containing those two objects
when its findAll method is called.
We execute the service's findAll method,
and then validate that we received the two objects back.
Finally, the testSave method creates a mockProduct,
configures the mock repository to return that product
when its save method is called, and then we execute the service's save method,
passing it that same mockProduct.
We then assert that the returnedProduct is not null
and that the version is set to 1,
which is the only business logic that the product service provides for us.
There are plenty of opportunities for you to add more test cases here,
such as support for update, failures and save,
update, and delete, and so forth.
This test class will get you started, and the pattern for all of these test cases is the same.