Hey guys welcome back.
OK.
So it is day.
I want to say nine.
I'm not even tired really the.
I have not yet started posting my 5:55 a day as my goal and in fact actually what I've been doing the
last two days or three days has been just alternating days.
So I only posted one day out of three.
Now I'm just doing that because I want to preserve some of the content that I'm making just because
it's a little bit of a waste in this holding pattern that I'm kind of stuck.
So we can take out the account where we're at Yeah so we had 22 posts.
And again I was just doing this as a holding pattern just because I didn't want to lose followers.
But I also just didn't want it to look like it was in fact over.
I just had a big chunk of time where I wasn't posting anything.
So that's what I've been doing on the posting side.
I am finally to the point though where I'm going to start posting consistently tomorrow.
Now the problem was that I just hadn't gotten to a point where I had a large enough stockpile of videos
and quotes made and also the internal velocity as you would of the contractors I'm using to make these
videos we just weren't up to speed.
I mean we were at a point where we were making five a day but that just doesn't relieve a lot of room
for error.
Case one contractor kind of disappears or starts doing something wrong.
I just wanted to make sure I had a good chunk before I started so.
All right looking at the innovation station Trello you can kind of see what the totals are in each column
and that's really what I was going off of.
This is actually from a system called original card counter for Trello So if you use Chrome just go
to the Chrome store or the Chrome Web App Store and then just search for card counter for Trello and
all that does it just adds this number appear which is actually really helpful because at a glance sometimes
you just don't know.
So I know that needs review that means basically I'm ready to post these.
I have 58 and I'm posting five times a day.
I'M ALMOST AT 12 days of posting so I think that is a decent stockpile.
You can see over here we still have a bit of a bottleneck when it goes from video to editing.
It is perfectly fine.
I mean it kind of makes sense and I've actually been spending more time targeting this one specifically
and then over here and captions.
I mean these just get written very very quickly because the caption is I've been using actually doing
a really good job and they're doing it very quickly and consistently on the contractor front.
If you guys followed the entire section on outsourcing this work or automating this work we talked about
running trials and then how to determine which type of contractor you need.
Now in that section we talk a little bit about this but what happened was I was looking for people to
find media.
So I just wanted people to essentially do this or it says I'm gathering media because it ends up being
the case that it takes about an hour to make a video.
If you have to gather then media yourself.
So I wanted to isolate that activity and then try to get people to find media because then someone can
assemble it really quickly and I could focus on having a cheaper person just find media that just really
do not work.
I only found one person who could do this consistently.
And I went through probably 10 people doing trials and they just were not good enough at it consistently
running into problems so what I am doing was switching to finding video editors and I just kind of ate
the extra cost.
I mean they're not that much more expensive.
Some of these editors are like $10 an hour now.
It's not the ideal way to do it.
But sometimes this just happens.
You just hit a jam.
Whatever system you're making or step by step process you're trying to design sometimes just one of
the steps is wrong and so that was the problem that I was having there.
So so far that's been cleared up.
The other thing I was using was an app called screen full screen full screen f u l dot me.
Now what they do is they take your Trello boards and give you analytics.
Check it out for yourself.
But on this app what I was specifically using it for was because I wanted to make sure I had a lot of
videos ready in the basket so to speak to post.
And then at the same time I wanted to make sure that we were producing enough on a day to day basis.
I was using these analytics to tell what the speed of each card was going through the Trello process.
So here I can see for instance the lead time is six days 19 hours.
That means when I create a new needs captions card this one right here all the way all the way on the
left.
It takes about six days ish seven days to go through the entire process.
So that's perfectly fine.
You can see right here that it sits in that pile a long time usually sits in the pile for four days.
So that's the reaction time before someone actually grabs it.
That's perfectly fine because I'm not using it for say like a web app where we're doing bugs and features
and things that need our e-mails or things that need immediate attention.
Doesn't really matter I just want to make sure that it's not taking too long to get through.
Now this is the cycle time.
Typically it takes about two days.
Once someone starts it to actually get it through.
So what this basically tells me is they wanted to optimize something.
I would start either putting fewer things in the captions or getting the captions to go a little bit
her because you can see that they take up you know four days of the seven and then what I was looking
at over here is just the completed tasks you can see right here.
This is the growth as we've been making more and more posts and this is a rolling seven day average.
So it just looks at the average per day in that seven day period.
Now as I scroll.
So what you see is the essentially the velocity of the average number of ones are putting in the completed
pile are going up.
And that's a good thing.
Also right here in the last seven days we've made 35 thirty five is you know five a day and so that
was kind of the red line that once we completed it I said OK we can start posting.
So that's what I'm happy to see.
So check out screenful.
You guys have an opportunity.
We'll check in here with iconv Square really quickly just so you can see that.
Yeah not much has been happening here right here the follower growth.
So this was growing when I was doing the initial publishing to get my 10.
And then I was doing one a day.
And so I was going up pretty fast and then kind of just plateaued because well I just stopped posting
them because I was just going to wait till I had enough post to just start going full throttle.
So nothing else really has changed.
See in the next lecture how everything's going as we start posting seriously and then we start looking
for shout outs and then we start getting into things like stories and other stuff like that.
But that's the next step and once I start getting that going then it'll be much easier to reach out
to people and really start implementing some growth strategies.
OK.
So you next chapter.