Hey dudes, what's up?
Welcome back.
Welcome to Section 5, technically 6 on Udemy, I don't
know. Last section was a doozy, but guess what?
We made it.
Now you should have the knowledge and tools to make some actual posts and to get the ball moving on your account.
Remember, we just want to get the first 10
posts before we move on to promotions.
So, by the time you finish this section, you should be
at that, give or take a couple content pieces. In this
section, we're talking about posting.
How do you do it?
What do you need to optimize?
Why are hashtags everywhere, including my dreams, and
how do I get people to respond to my post? We'll cover
captions, call to action lines, and how
to not use emojis like a circus clown.
We'll also cover things like
when is the best time to post and
how can I get more comments?
Since we're diving into a new section of the app itself,
the next lecture is going to introduce you to
the part of the app we're now going to be playing in.
If you've already posted before,
then guess what I'm about to say?
Skip the lecture, because I don't want to hear you complain.
Ready? K bye.