Hey guys, welcome back.
All right, so this section, we're going to focus
on stories. Now, stories aren't really that new.
They came out a long time ago when Instagram
completely originally came up with this,
I'm joking, they just stole it from Snapchat,
but it's been a pretty popular feature.
Now, you see this up in the top
of your screen all of the time.
Any time you go to the Explore page, it's at the top,
any time you look at your feed, it's at the top.
A lot of companies are using stories and a lot of
companies are doing it, I'd say, incorrectly. Generally,
the purpose of stories is to engage the audience you
already have, and that's why we're covering it so far
in the course. Earlier on,
if we only had a handful of followers,
then it's not particularly useful.
We had to gather a bunch of them and now
we can actually see the power of stories.
So what we'll do is we'll cover what the best practices
are, some accounts that use them well, we'll cover
a tool for making them,
and then you can follow along as I design a story strategy
for Innovation Station, and then see how that goes.
All right.
That being said, wish me luck.
See you next lecture.