Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, so in this section, we are going to talk about the options available to you if you want to monetize your Instagram account.
Now, not everybody out there is making an Instagram
account that is directly tied to a business, but if you
are, we're going to talk about ways that you can convert
this interest and this traffic into something that
you can make money off of,
and if you don't have a business attached to it, we'll explore a couple ways that you can make money off the account itself.
So we'll cover things like how to
monetize just traffic on your account,
we'll talk about how to capture emails most effectively
and plug them into some email marketing system,
whatever you actually have set up for your business, we'll
also talk about flipping accounts,
and then the last thing we'll talk about
is how to sell directly on the account.
This works especially well if you're in retail.
All right.
With that being said, let's jump right in.
This is kind of a short section, but see you at the end.