All right guys, welcome back.
OK, we're finally in the "let's make some stuff" section,
and that's exactly what we're going to do.
OK.
Hopefully, by this point, you know roughly
what your content strategy is going to be,
so that now it's just a matter of
putting those thoughts into action.
Now, when I say first batch of content,
why phrase it like that?
Well, because when we first start our accounts,
we're going to be at a significant disadvantage.
We have no followers,
we have an untested account, and not really a lot of
media at all to look at. In order to get more followers,
we need to do some marketing and promotion,
but in order to keep them on the page
in the first place, we need content.
It's a little like the chicken and egg problem, so what
I generally propose is that you just first start
by making your first 10 posts. Now, why 10?
Well, because 10 will cover the screen in any phone horizontally, and will at least look like you have a wall of content.
It's really the best that you can do right now.
Also, for whatever reason, accounts with more
than 10 get more followers. If you only have three,
you're losing a lot of people that could be clicking Follow.
There have been studies on this.
I don't know why you would do a study on this, but 10,
for whatever reason, is kind of like the optimal point to hit.
So that's why I say, let's just do 10. Ten, also, for
our purposes, is enough to get the hang of what
we're doing and to clearly see what exactly our
long term content strategy is going to look like.
You might have had an idea that "We're going to
make this" and then you get in there, and on the fifth
one you make, you realize it's not going to work. You'll
get an idea of whether these posts are interesting
or as interesting as you thought they'd be,
and if they were a lot harder to make than you thought.
You'll use that knowledge then to help tweak your
efforts later in the course when we cover automation
and getting someone else to do all of this for you.
OK.
So we should be set to get the show
on the road and start posting.
Make sure that you know going into this
what your content mix is going to be.
We talked about that in a previous lecture.
Now, you don't have to make videos
and stories now if you don't want to.
In fact, it might be a little easier to just start with
photos, and as you grow, experiment with videos,
or you can do it all at once, it doesn't really matter.
We'll cover how to make both in this section.
OK, let's do it.