Hey guys welcome back OK.
This lecture where we're going to do it is we're going to talk about scheduling post in advance and
we're going to do it with an app that you speak called later Graham but now it's just called later.
Now what on screen first came out it was the case that every time you post something you had to be at
your phone and you had to do it with your fingers.
Right.
Then Instagram started adding things like a web version.
Then they started adding in an API that other apps could actually use some of their information.
And then finally they started allowing people to use apps that could publish to Instagram.
Now Facebook and Twitter they give complete control over their platforms to third party applications
but Instagram for whatever reason is still kind of skittish on that topic.
But what we have now are tools that can help you do a lot of different things.
But the main thing we're focused on is being able to schedule in advance being able to schedule these
things in advance just means that you're not chained to your phone and it's incredibly useful also because
you can do it on the web.
The web is way easier to deal with.
In general it's just it helps you with organization quite a bit.
Now there are a lot of tools that do this and you're welcome to try other ones.
Some of the tools we talked about used before claim to offer a post scheduling but I'm sticking with
later ground which is probably the best I've used for this.
The other option is buffer.
And I thought about using them but they're probably equal buffer.
And later sorry as prices go you can use the free version.
They limit you to using one account and only a certain amount of posts per month but you can use them
see if you like them.
And then if you like them then you can actually pay for them it's only like nine dollars a month something
like that.
So check it out.
And when you sign up you they ask you to authenticate your account just to make sure that you are the
owner you are a business account so you should have your Facebook account attached.
So that should be easy once you get through.
It looks like this.
Now you have your calendar near the media library you have conversations analytics certainly post and
then a tool they call link in bio.
Now the calendar is the thing we care about the most.
So the way that this works is I can upload all of my pre-made media including stuff that I have used
before and I can dump it in here.
And then I can set them up here and around here whenever I actually want to post and then I can look
at them in the month view.
You can even drag the blocks around in the preview and it'll automatically reorganized your posting
schedule.
I think that's pretty cool.
You can also do some pretty cool stuff like sharing your calendar down here gives you a preview link.
And if you give it to someone then they can actually see what's coming up on your calendar.
That's pretty useful.
You can also add people if you work with them.
So he would be like a grid.
Want to see the feed.
I can just scroll down through all of my posted ones and upcoming ones and here's what's happening in
the future and here's my record so far of posting I only started posting yesterday but I'll start picking
up the pace as we go through it.
So I wanted to schedule something I could drag and drop it in here if I wanted to.
Or I could use Dropbox or Google Drive which we are to use Dropbox that perfect so I can actually just
attach it.
So I'll go to the station posts here and I can just pick whichever one that I want to add in.
So let's say the Riverbend school is one I could do.
I could go back and interactive TV series.
OK so two selected.
Now if I hit shoes I actually throw this in the pile.
Then what happens is it has to load preview thumbnails so they can actually see what they are but once
they do load Well you can do as you can and labels and you can add notes so I could add notes about
whether or not this piece of video is done.
I can do labels just so I can say video.
So if I wanted to add a label like a video and you know maybe there's something else that I thought
is relevant.
I know it's about education like education and then over here what I can do is and I can sort by labels
that I have.
So if I just wanted to look for video I could click video apply the label and it should just show me
whichever one I just tag that I'll be useful if for instance I was trying to felt my calendar and was
trying to follow a pattern and I didn't want to look at a bunch of photos that I'd made before I really
just wanted a video.
You can also do pretty interesting things like media usage so you can for instance sort by all unused
media or you can just look for ones that have been used.
It is something that we will do once we post something we'll see how well it works and we'll reposed
it if it does work and eventually get to a point where recycling more posts than we're actually creating.
But from our find just going with unused media now they click.
This is actually kind of exciting because I made the label video it already auto tagged it as video.
Now it's not on the calendar.
So have a quick business and actually do anything for me but I can add it and then later on I could
put it in there.
So let's say I wanted to post this.
Echo whatever so I could say create post right here OK now gives me the same exact setup that I had
on Instagram on the phone.
But I can't just do it here.
So when I can do is go over and grab the caption for this one.
It's called Echo.
See like I said this one.
I'll grab the caption and the call to action and then we'll do up a server here.
Then I can do some of the regular cleaning that I would've done anyway so I could copy and paste those
blank spaces that I usually do.
I wanted to so I would just say face that and then I have to go up here and then copy and paste it copy
this out of my notes.
And so I make sure that I don't have any extra spaces.
There you go.
And I can kind of do the same thing I would do.
It was actually in my posts.
Now if I wanted to add a Mowgli's beforehand so I don't have to do it on my phone what you can do is
if you go to the Web site Moji PDA here you can search for all the emojis and then just make sure that
you only sorting by ones that you've seen before or actually are on mobile phone so let's say I wanted
to TV show Black Mirror.
OK so I could put a TV.
So search for TV.
OK some television and I could copy that and throw it in here.
So black air space TV.
Active TV series I could use that one again.
Forward and over it.
They don't like new was added and another line break just for the sake of making it look good.
Copy and paste this again.
So see.
Let's break it up here.
There and that.
Ok cool.
So down here it says create my Lincoln bio page what they're trying to do is set you up with this other
feature that we'll talk about really briefly in a second but it's not always something to worry about.
Now what I can do is I can schedule it.
Now when exactly would I want to post it.
So what you can do is just follow the generic standards that we had before which were the peaks.
Whatever the best times were generically for Instagram users which was like 10 p.m. 2 a.m. and about
8:00 a.m. I think it was.
So those three peak points or you can just kind of go whenever you think it's convenient or based on
the other ones or if you have your own data you can go to icona Square and see when your users are most
active and most engaged and then use it based on that.
So what I'll do is I'll just have a post here and a couple of hours.
So EPM I'll post that.
So then I have notification.
So auto publish for Instagram is not available for video or multi photo posts.
Now if you're from the future and they fix this problem that's amazing.
But for videos what happens is it saves it and then it gives me a push notification on my phone and
then all I have to do is click through to their app and hit a button for whatever reason and I'm only
with people publishing videos from their phone.
I think eventually they'll change that though.
So it's safe.
Now I can see it on the schedule right.
It's scheduled for 8:00 o'clock and I can preview it and there it goes.
And so I can look at the preview and my whole goal was to keep the quotes always in a line.
Honestly I can only do that if I just keep the same pattern of two videos one photo two videos one photo.
OK.
So I'm not really going to worry over that one what I'll end up happening is it'll put the post here
in the next post it'll move it here.
But the next photo will be here so will always be in the same line.
I just can't keep it in one specific one but if I wanted to I could really organize this one with any
of my future posts coming up.
Now the best way of doing this is just to spend like two hours with all of your content.
Plan it out for a week and then you don't have to worry about it.
OK.
So we posted that now let's upload a photo post so we put a photo post to find this to be useful and
we'll schedule that as well.
Now when we schedule photos it can auto post I don't have to do that funky thing where I come in enough
to press a button so that's nice.
However with your hashtags you will have to remember to get on it add your hashtags after it posts which
can be pretty annoying but unfortunately that's kind of just the way it is the way you can get around
that those if you wanted to say go to your post.
It's right here.
Click and it opens up.
You could do something like this where you can take those clear line breaks and just copy and paste
a bunch of those so that it actually hides it at the bottom so we could do that.
Two three four and then we could copy your hash tags.
So that's one way of doing it if you want to.
How that works law.
You're going to have to get used to tweaking it and kind of playing around with it.
So I'm going to copy some of the hash tags I've used before and then tweak some of them.
Ok so like for instance I he doesn't work
activity doesn't really work.
Kickstarter smart doesn't work.
Not really trying to optimize my hashtags right now.
We have a section on that design future of TV so it's really small on the
great TV.
We could try.
It's interesting.
TV interviews publicity to you you travel now.
We say that.
I love TV maybe TV.
So what else could we do.
Virtual reality maybe that's pretty similar to virtual reality.
OK so one more hash tag so I'll do something like.
I don't think you know it's not technically I have to use kind of in the same space.
OK.
So then I can save that and then when it post it it should actually be hidden unless the person manually
scrolls down to find it.
But worst case scenario what I can do is I can go in and copy it into the comments after it posts.
Ok so now we can check out some of the other sections.
So here is the media library so I can just sort of play around with all of the stuff I have here and
I'll fill that out as they go conversations is where I can see all of my likes and my comments and I
can delete the ones I don't like I can respond to the ones I like.
It's just a lot easier to do it in this and I can immediately see for instance like this person I can
see stats on them and as you can see if all the more people than they're being followed by so they're
probably going on a legitimate comment.
And same goes for this one so great then you can do things like post view if you want to just look at
the posts and only work on each post and just deal it that way.
Or you can look at the users see all the comments by one user and this is a great way to keep engagement
with your users to make sure that you are popular users that constantly post.
You always respond to them then they give you some analytics.
Now analytics are kind of the same thing as what you have any Konno Square to be honest.
I mean it's just going to give you summaries and how many comments you made and many followers you haven't
been able Beaubois if you upgrade to a pro it gives you some stats on like if you use their link bio
and just you can rank your posts by how well they did.
And if you want to see a graph you can click here and then you can scroll down and see the graphs specifically
for that.
So it's collecting my data.
It usually needs a certain amount of time.
OK now search and repost this is great for doing shouts if say I had a goal of doing one shout out a
day then I could use this and just search for things that I think might be interesting I might look
for hash tag innovation and just find something.
Let's just say you know theoretically I wanted to post somebody else's quote.
I think it looks fine doesn't really fit with my design but whatever.
So what I could do is just add that to my library and then add it to my library.
I have to say yes I know about the content but the law yes I agree and then.
Yeah.
Hyper again.
So if the calendar then I can create a post out of this post and it gives me all of the stuff they put
in there already.
So what I would do is I would change it right.
And then just make sure that I tagged the original person and that's pretty much how I would do it.
I hit save I'd pick a time and that's it.
So I can schedule it and make sure that I have one a day and that's generally like a pretty good healthy
diet.
Now if I want to get rid of this I just have to trash it right there and throws it away.
There we go.
I mean the last thing is the linked in bio.
And honestly we're not going to really deal with this until we get to the section on how to make money
with Instagram.
This is what this is is for retailers.
People are selling things.
They create an auto generated link that you can put in your captions or your bio and it takes them to
a mobile optimized Web site that shows them the things that are for sale.
And it just converts really well for Instagram and it also has a lot of trackings that you can optimize
that is very useful when we get to it but it's not.
We're talking about today.
All right so that's all we need to know about later for now.
You'll see in the follow along sections I will fill this up and as I tweak it and try to use some of
the more obscure features.
But this is enough to get in and get dirty.
I also encourage you guys to check out buffer if you think that might suit your needs better for the
most part they're really the same kind it depends which brand you like.
They both have to send messages to you to actually post it so just be aware of that.
All right.
That being said the next lecture.