Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, hopefully you are now inundated with ways of
creating interesting photos to post to your feed.
Images are the backbone of the majority
of accounts, so that's why we hit them first.
If you don't think you're going to do video,
although I'd say, please have an open mind,
they're easier than you think.
But if you're insistent, then I'd probably say skip
the next set of lectures, and when you're ready to
incorporate video, then just come back.
OK, let's talk about videos.
Do you remember the basics?
If not, it's pretty simple.
Videos are a maximum of - currently, because Lord only
knows what it'll be when you watch this - 60 seconds long.
They always display like this with this camera icon
in the post corner. When you see them in a feed,
they do actually auto play now.
I might have misspoken before. They didn't auto play
on your profile wall, but they do when you're looking
at them in the feed view.
Kind of makes sense.
You know, if they played on the wall,
you'd probably go crazy, and in the feed view, you're
clearly looking at the video, so it just plays, although
there is a little bit of a lag to let the user
kind of dwell on the thumbnail  a little bit.
Now, videos display at basically the exact same size
images, and they can be uploaded in the same exact
three orientations - square, landscape, or portrait.
There's something like one pixel different
than photos, for whatever reason.
So that's the standard for how they work.
Let's talk about content.
Do you have to have your own camera gear, your own
lighting equipment, a director, and some karmically
challenged peon that has to hold your boom mic?
No, you don't need that stuff.
Instagram is the platform of production value, and
the more you use, the more users will appreciate
though. Plenty of accounts are making
it without any of that stuff.
Now, you can make videos using the exact same stuff you made images with, not the same tools, but the same graphic assets.
It's perfectly fine to make static images and
have text come on and off the screen.
Just take a look at The Onion.
They do this all the time.
You can see it's just headlines followed by images
with quotes, and then they might have like one really
short animation, but the rest of it
is just static images and pop up text.
OK.
So how do you make a video out of
pictures without it looking like crap?
Good question.
You use a thing called motion.
Not emotion - motion, like things moving. Motion is the
differentiator between "Wow, that's a stale image
and I realize it's an image" and "Hey, that looks pretty
cool." Actually in videography we have a term called
Ken Burns, and a lot of people have turned it into a
verb, like "I just Ken Burns that" - maybe that's just me.
I don't know.
Have you ever watched a documentary from
Ken Burns like "Ken Burns - The Civil War" or
"Ken Burns - Vietnam War"?
What else did he do?
He did a bunch of stuff, he's really famous, you hopefully
have noticed that he uses this technique over and over again.
So what he does is he just takes one image and then
he just slowly zooms in on it so that you have the
effect of getting closer to the image and also
have your frame of reference move slightly.
So technically it zooms and pans - panning, of course,
is when you move side to side with the camera.
It's incredible how much of a difference this really makes.
It just feels like you're watching a video even though it's not.
So that is the secret sauce.
Just add motion. For images, just
zoom in slowly or pan from side to side.
Then you can bring in text with a basic animation,
like have it pop on screen or swing in from the side.
If you've watched my other courses, you'll notice
I love that slide effect for text, where it just flies in
from one direction and lands in place - I probably overuse it.
Can you incorporate videos and
images in your Instagram video?
OK, of course you can, and we'll cover how to use other people's footage as well and how to incorporate them in your stuff.
That's a later lecture.
Now, how do you make an effective video?
OK, it's all nice and whatnot to know how to put
them together, but what parts make it work?
Well, first of all, you need the video to
get to the point as quickly as you can.
Whatever it is that's interesting in the video
needs to be front loaded in the first 15 seconds.
Why is that?
Well, attention spans. Look at this video engagement graph that shows attention as you go from zero to 60 seconds.
It's like a roller coaster going straight
down for the first five seconds.
So you need to hook them as soon as you can.
Otherwise, they'll just leave the video. And people
that don't watch the entire video are much less likely
to engage with the post, which is what we want.
Another tip for video.
Don't forget your CTA or your call to action.
You'd use a call to action in a video
just like you would in a picture.
You want people to like your post?
You say it in the video.
You want them to follow you?
Say it in the video. If you want them to
tag a friend, say it in the video. OK.
You have their attention, so don't waste it.
Another thing you really need to incorporate,
guess what? Did you know that 80% of
video views happen without volume?
Yeah.
That's what you get when you make autoplay a thing,
Instagram. People almost always watch it on silent
for at least a couple seconds to see if it's worth
tapping on, and then deciding to hear the audio.
So what does that mean for us?
Well, it means you need to make sure
the video makes sense without audio.
Otherwise no one is going to tap on it.
That means focus on the imagery and not the dialogue, or at
least put text it on the screen that narrates what's happening.
That one is really important for getting
people to watch your video.
Cannot stress that one enough.
The last thing I'll say on making your videos effective is
you need to remember that your video usually displays
first as a static image and then plays.
That means one of the reasons someone either
stops to watch or skips your video is the thumbnail.
OK.
The static starting image that they see. You want to
make sure you pick a thumbnail that makes sense
given the context of your video, one that doesn't have
someone making a contorted face, or ideally show
something visually interesting, or at least
implies action and piques their interest.
When you upload your video to the Instagram
app, they let you choose a thumbnail there.
Unfortunately, they kind of limit you to only using
a frame that's inside the actual video, which is, you
know, perfectly fine sometimes, but there are ways
around this, and we'll probably talk about it later.
Now, the next couple of lectures, we're going to cover
apps that let us create videos optimized for Instagram.
I'll tell you upfront that editing videos inside
of Instagram itself is pretty much garbage,
and we're going to skip it. I don't even suggest capturing
video inside of their camera app or the camera function
inside of their app, because, well, it crashes all the time.
That kind of limits your control.
OK.
That's more than enough to take in all at once.
Videos are awesome, but only if you do them right.
Make sure they're visually interesting.
This is Instagram, remember? People have the same
attention spans as bats or other winged creatures.
Remember to consider how the video will look if it's muted,
and don't forget your thumbnail.
Also, video in the Instagram app is crap, unless it's been
updated since I've filmed this - possible, I don't know.
Alright guys, see you next lecture.