You guys just checking in to show you where we're at and give you an update on how things have been
going.
OK so at this point we're at thirty four thousand followers believe that's rounded up.
So last time we checked in talked a little bit I think about how we were starting this push towards
doing shout for shout and for the most part has worked out.
We're still having issues where we're not large enough to really make it worth it.
But you can see here this is kind of the war room so far with regards to outreach to companies or accounts
that might make sense.
So we have actually done some I'd say were doing something like probably three or four a week and for
the most part they're pretty straightforward.
We just started doing mass messaging to people and saying hey do you want to do a shout for show so
we can look at our messages for the most part.
Let's see.
Yeah.
I mean we have a lot of people who say like yes and then we respond with You know here's some information
and then honestly takes a while for some people to actually get back to us.
You know like here's one Stargazer official OK so we did one with them all.
This entire process takes like as you noticed messaging a 21st smartphone the 22nd.
Today's lawyer responded blah blah blah and then it looks like we posted I think the next day.
Right.
So yeah I mean for the most part it's pretty easy to get these going for the most part you really just
have to be kind of on it when it comes to responding to people.
A lot of times they'll respond late or the responses aren't super useful.
But you know for the most part it's fairly easy.
You know have someone else doing it for me.
They're doing the outreach.
It's for the most part pretty much just automated.
And then I also have it set up the same person is sending the same message back to them.
And the way we have it set up is we just say you know hey you like your recount like your audience I
think our audience would like each other let's do a shout out in the story and then we respond after
they have some form of affirmative by giving them a link to our video and asking them for a video and
then as soon as we get their video we just post it on our story and then it automatically will pop up
in our direct message to them saying like you've been tagged in a story so that's been pretty useful.
You know at the size we're at 34000.
We've done this probably 10 times in the last like two weeks I would say each one on average will get
you a hundred followers just because of the size.
So again it's one of those those issues where it really just depends on the size of your account.
And you'll notice that this snowballs rapidly.
Like say we a million people on our account and someone else had a million that they did a shout for
shout We probably get $2000 just from that.
So that could be pretty easy.
Then all of a sudden you know we're gaining a hundred thousand dollars a month.
We just do this like once or twice a day whereas with this it's like yeah you get anywhere from 50 to
150 followers and it's also hard to then convince the other person to keep doing that with you.
Just because again it's just not really worth it at this size.
Also I mean we get most of our followers from hashtags primarily and the follow bought and then we still
get a lot of rebounds from the zombie accounts that are running.
So yeah it's getting there where it's getting to the point where it's worth it but not yet have we hit
the sweet spot where this is going to be the main growth channel.
I'm going to start using.
So let's just check in and see how community growth has been for the most part.
It's been pretty solid.
I mean it used to be the case that a good day was gaining 100 followers now are getting to the point
where like a good days like 250 and this is largely just due to the changes in the size of the account.
I mean that's really it used to be the case of I posted something that was really popular and get a
lot of interactions.
And then on the hashtags it might maybe maybe 10 percent five percent of time show up in the top post
for the hash tag page.
But now since we have 34000 it's just getting more and more common that even with some of the mediocre
posts We're showing up in the top post for hashtags.
So it's really just that kind of a snowball effect now you can imagine this effect then when you have
a million followers and then all of a sudden you're showing up on like 90 percent of the hash tag pages
that you post for.
So it's really just kind of a game of patience.
But as you can see you know 300 319 400 those a great day three 22 and then really just depends on what
we're posting.
Our content strategy has shifted slightly.
I think I talked about this before where we're starting to rehash a lot of our old stuff and then trying
to feed in a slow diet of best hits and of new content.
But for the part that means that the 70 percent of our content is going to be stuff we posted four months
ago.
So hopefully no one notices and for the most part you can kind of tell by the comments that no one really
does notice.
Another thing that's also seemed to improve quite a bit is our comments used to be a case like a good
post would get an extra five comments.
Now we're getting like 25 10 13 so even some of his mediocre posts are getting a lot of comments like
this one at 13.
This one I don't even know I haven't even looked at the post.
Got 36.
I think it's what I'm finding is a lot of the posts that are kind of controversial like dumb tack gets
a lot of people to respond and say this is dumb.
And that is kind of the catalyst to then get other people to participate in the conversation like this
one.
This is one of the ones that man people just hate it.
And it's because of this what it is is it's a crop sensor that will flop around as it goes across a
cable across our crops like that.
So it kind of swings right.
And so like 90 percent of the people are just like why is it do that.
Why can't it just be on a track system.
And what I've been doing is just trying to engage people as much as possible and really just playing
into whatever going to get them to respond.
They say that's awesome.
I'm like yeah it is awesome and if it's not awesome then I'll try to argue with them just to get him
to keep responding and that's essentially how you get more engagement and you'll notice that a lot of
the people that actually will engage in these arguments do continue to show up in the other posts and
to you know give their opinion on whether or not it's useful or not.
So yeah not much else has happened there.
We're still using a rotating hash tag strategy but we're slowly starting to incorporate larger hashtags
as we get larger.
It's kind of overkill if you're using a hashtag that only has like 9000 posts or so for an account that
gets you know on average.
I don't even know.
I mean you know say these old videos likes for each video sometimes.
I want to say it's like usually three or four hundred three hundred.
Sure.
And that seems to kind of make sense so we can look at our hype auditor report and see how we're doing.
OK.
So we're about 83 out of 100.
Our engagement rate has gone down and that is just really a change in US posting old stuff and new stuff.
So you know the bread and butter is going to be stuff that's untested.
So if we are doing only posts or only if we are doing only best hits then yeah I would expect this to
be quite a bit higher.
So this average is kind of being thinned out by some of the less than fantastic posts you can still
see that this is kind of goofy like it thinks we're in the photography category.
That's just because every post we do is different we have no theme it's just interesting technology.
But for the most part we're still doing a very good job with followers.
We're only getting people who are real followers who are actually going to see our posts.
Engagement rate is good yeah.
I mean it's about a little over double what our average what we would expect for our category.
That of course is can be something that's kind of hard to really benchmark.
But you know sometimes our engagement rate is as high as like 15 20 percent.
Usually I think of an average around like 8 or 9 and that's kind of what we've seen historically.
So if we take a look at our monthly update though we got about Milko rounded up say 9000 followers last
month.
That's I think is pretty good.
I think this will tick up as we started getting larger and everything we do starts snowballing and also
as we maybe start getting a little more optimized with our hashtags so you can see here like for instance
last month our engagement rate was about 10 percent and it dropped down to the average of about almost
6.
But you'll notice things like I was saying comments received that went up almost doubled likes received
pretty much static as our audience is getting larger more and more people are seeing it that's fantastic.
Some of the impressions I think this has more to do with a couple of other videos really started to
go viral typically with a post will get like ten thousand views maybe.
And if the algorithm really likes it it can go up to 80000.
So yeah.
And then media person you noticed you post the exact same schedule so nothing's really changed.
I think that might be something we uptick in the future just because more posts means more hashtags
means more exposure means more engagement.
And so that's generally just a good thing all around.
All right guys that's it for now for the most part this is on autopilot like I'm not really doing much
other than arguing with people in the comments like that's really all I'm doing.
And I still have someone posting these and I still have someone doing the shout for shout outreach.
If I were a very patient man I get here and do nothing and it costs me zero dollars because I'm just
reposting the same content over and over again and it would slowly just snowball.
So I'm putting a very limited effort into expansion by doing shout for shouts which are pretty much
the bee's knees.
They're followers.
Basically you don't pay anything for it.
And as long as you pick other accounts wisely then actually it's a total win win like your account likes
the posts and by their account likes to post.
I don't really see any downside to it.
Obviously there's limitations to how far you can take it.
All right guys with that being said I will check in again don't expect to check in any time soon because
again we're on autopilot so I'll probably check in at the next milestone maybe 40 or 50.
All right see you then.