Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, let's talk about how, if you don't have something
you can automatically use your profile photo,
how can you get a professional profile photo done.
OK.
It's going to depend on obviously
what type of account you are, right?
If you're a themed account or a business account,
then it's a question of "Do you have a logo?"
If you don't have a logo, we'll talk about that in a second.
If you're a personal account,
well, this one's pretty easy, it just needs to be your face.
I mean, it's going to be your face, up here,
like, minimize the shoulders and body.
So what you need is a headshot. Options with that one,
it kind of varies. A lot of times, if you
want to be cheap about it,
you don't want to spend any money, you
can just find a friend who has a DSLR,
that's a pretty good one.
I would strongly suggest that whenever you take a photo
for a headshot, you get as far away from the background
as possible, because then what they can do is they
can just blur out the back using that bokeh kind of
effect, that works fine, right?
Because we talked about having not
too much noise in the background,
that's pretty important, so that
people can focus on your face.
Ideally, if you have lights, then stand up in front of like a white sheet of paper, or a white sheet, that helps, again, quite a bit.
You have to do a little bit of post-production after that
just to brighten up the back, but that's pretty easy.
Now, if you want to spend a little bit of money, what
you can do is you can actually hire someone to take
your photograph, or you can rent
a nice camera and do it that way.
Renting a camera is probably like the middle option.
I've done this before.
The best camera I can think of for doing something
like this is, the one I used was a Sony A7R2,
it used to be a kind of expensive camera, not anymore,
you can rent it for like $40 a day.
It's one of those cameras that's so nice that
it's really hard to take a bad photograph with it.
All you have to do is just kind of hold it down
or get somebody to hold it down for you.
You can even do timed shots with it.
The resolution is insanely high, and it always
comes out like a really sharp picture.
So that's one way of doing it.
If you want to rent something like that, if you guys
are in the US, there's a website called CameraLends,
that's probably the cheapest way you can do it.
Other than that, if you want hire a professional, you can
use, in my experience, Thumbtack is actually pretty good.
The headshots that I have, that you see on Udemy
and everywhere, I used Thumbtack for that.
And then also, you can... Craigslist, a lot of times
they list, people list that they're offering headshots,
if you go to Craigslist and look in the services section.
There's even places that will do mobile headshots, they'll
come to you, they have a van you go in and take the photo.
There's even places where they just have a permanent setup
and you walk in and they take your shot and move on.
Those places are actually pretty cheap, relatively.
You know, I think there's a place like here in San
Francisco, and this is San Francisco, and it's $100.
So you just go in, and you're in and out in like 30 minutes.
That's how you get a decent shot,
especially for a personal account.
That's really all you need.
Now, if you're making a corporate account, like a logo
or a themed one, again, it's going to depend on like,
do you want to spend money?
Cheap, free options, there's not a ton.
I mean, one, you could hack it out yourself.
You can use like Photoshop and just do it yourself.
There's some free logo generators out there,
they're not particularly great. If that's the case, what
I'd strongly suggest is just taking the text from
your name and then just trying to stylize that. If
you're new to graphic design, then it's going to be
really way too hard and a large waste of time to
learn how to actually design a symbol for a logo.
So, again, just use text and try to
position it, just try to go through fonts.
That's usually relatively easy to do, and sometimes
you can come out with a good outcome.
There's some other websites that are worth looking at,
if you can spend a little bit of money for a logo. This is one
website you should probably be familiar with, it's Fiverr.
The whole concept here is that you can get something
done for $5, so you can just look for logo design.
Usually, they're a little bit more than $5, so you can pay
more to have more versions made, you pay more
to, you know, give them instructions on the logo.
Sometimes they're just templates, but usually,
you know, they have some pretty decent ones.
You just have to make a decision about what you want,
you know, if you want something that's modern or do
you want something that's casual and fun. And you
can tell that a lot of these logo makers are pretty good, so like
here, you can literally pay $5 and they'll give you three.
Yeah.
So this is fine if you want to wait or can wait 4-5
days, it usually ends up being pretty cheap.
Here's one that personally I actually
love, and it's called ShapeFactory.
So what they've done is they've made a generator for
creating logos, and it's actually really good, especially
for Instagram, like the way that they compile them based
on whatever text you give them is incredibly good.
I mean, this is something that I will probably use for any
other, like, copy accounts or dummy accounts in the future,
especially later in the course, we'll start talking about
creating zombies, and that's probably what I'll use.
So what you do is just go to logo.shapefactory.co,
and hopefully when you guys go to this it's actually up,
because you never know with some of these newer
tools. So you just type in your account name,
so mine might be like, you know, innovation a day,
and then what you do is you just pick a text,
then you pick your logo mark, and then it gives
you different variations. So I might do
something like clean, like that, sans serif
meaning it doesn't have the little
hooks at the end of each letter.
Then what you can do is you can
pick a category for your logo.
It doesn't really matter, I mean, you can
just search up here for something too.
So mine's innovation, right?
So I might go down here to, like, beaker,
because science is just an easy association with innovation.
So I could probably... Just pick
something that kind of fits your style.
OK.
So there you go, and then it just
pumps this out for you right there.
And it gives you different variations, different shapes that
you can work with, and it even gives you color variations.
So this is actually a really fun one to play with.
It's, at the end of the day, it's only $40,
so honestly I think it's worth it.
All their icons are really good, their text is good, and
I'm surprised sometimes I've come out with logos in
this that I like more than the logos I paid $1,000 for. So
one other option I think worth looking into is 99designs.
Now, this is if you're ok spending a lot of money
and you're actually serious, especially if you needed
a logo anyway and it's a legitimate business.
Well, what happens here is it's a contest website, so
basically you go and you'll give a description, what
you want, and it'll ask you questions, it's like a
questionnaire, you don't have to come up with all the
stuff in your head, it gives you these sliders
you can pick from for aesthetic styles,
and then it tells you to show them
what types of logos you like,
and then over time people just compete on them,
so you'll actually end up seeing anywhere from 20 to
100 different logo variations, and you rate them, and
it kind of goes through this trial process, and then
usually around, you know, 7-10 days later,
you have something you want.
I also like the fact that it's not something
that you absolutely have to commit to.
So if you don't like what you got, you
don't actually have to purchase it.
So yeah.
You can go down here and it gives
you a lot of ideas that you can use.
That's kind of the view of the slider
you use to decide, then you can even go and look at
other people's logos and see how it goes. Typically,
I think for a logo the range is $300.
You can pay up to whatever you
want, really, but $300 is the lowest.
I think the most common you'll see is probably $500,
especially if you need them to do a logo plus something, like
a little bit of branding work, especially for, like, Instagram.
This actually might be what I'll end up doing for the
Instagram accounts, just because I'm not super oriented
towards design, so it would help to have someone
do the logo, but then also help with the way that it's
going to be positioned on each individual photo,
so I think that would help a lot.
I haven't entirely decided what I want to do yet, but you
can see those in the follow along lectures as we go.
You'll see what I picked.
OK.
I think that's pretty much all you need to know.
Again, if you need a headshot for a personal account,
pretty easy, there's usually headshot studios in whatever
city you're in. If not, use any platform,
you can just just hire someone directly
on it to take your photographs.
If you want to do it cheaply, just
get a friend who has a DSLR.
I mean, you can even use your iPhone if it's a newer
one, because the camera is actually decent enough,
especially with the newest ones with the portrait mode.
That's one way of doing it.
And if you're really lazy, you could just take a photo
you have and then run it through Instagram and
use their filters and kind of screw with it that way
to make it a little more like stylized. I don't obviously
suggests that, but if you need to get something
done today, that's one way of doing it.
And then, if you need a corporate account, so a logo
for a corporate account or a themed account, I like
ShapeFactory, I like Fiverr for this,
and I think 99designs works as well.
One other one, I would say, if you just want to hire
one specific designer or one person, Dribbble is
a good one, it's Dribbble with three Bs, and you
can just go and look at all the different stuff they
have, and just find someone you like and
then just message them through the system.
This is how actually I find a lot of designers, because
they just post little snippets of cool stuff.
I see it, I love that style, then I message
them, and that's how we figure it out.
All right, guys. I will see you in the next lecture.