Hey guys welcome back.
OK this lecture talk about shooting your own video and in a short period of time hopefully I'm going
to try to give you a bit of a head start on things like equipment and settings and strategy.
If you're trying to actually plan out video shoots and then use that for your Instagram channel.
Now a lot of people do that businesses do this a lot with their employees.
Take a camera around the office take photos or you know actually make videos and then post that.
There's also things that you can do a lot of people do like go pro shot like videos and then throw those
up again it just kind of pends on what you're doing if you're planning on making your own original content.
Well this is be a lot harder.
I mean you have to do a lot more but I know some of you out there will be interested in doing that.
So if you're promoting yourself like a personal brand or something and you were traveling around the
world will be pretty useful understand how some of this stuff works.
I'm very sorry I can't go into too much depth on this because you know an entirely different course
on how to become a videographer a slash photographer but I'm going to show you what I use and what has
worked for me so far.
So first off you can use your phone cameras.
All right.
So like this is the iPhone 10.
You can use that if you want to.
This is the pixel too.
This also has a pretty good camera that the pixel toos camera is better than iPhone 10.
It's gotten to a point now where the megapixels and the color contrast and the dynamic range on these
phones are good enough that you could completely use these you could use these on Instagram especially
because it's going to reduce your video size to something really small like you're kind it.
It's kind of hard to get across a really fancy or good looking camera anyway.
And most people have these phones so it's a great place to start if you want to actually upgrade and
get into something more like a DSL or my original first camera for shooting courses was called a Canon
70 and that one is pretty cheap now and you can buy the body for like $400.
It's very usable It's easy to grab it's kind of bulky but it has a flipout screen that you can kind
of point in either direction.
A lot of YouTube's use that if you're George Casey nice that you use as a canon 70.
Believe it or not.
Downsides it is only shoots in 10 ADP HD it doesn't shoot for OK depending on when you're watching this
course for K could be the new lay of the land or maybe it's this is way in the future and it's like
12 K or something.
That is one downside because if you shoot for OK not only are you future proofing your videos but you
can reduce them down in size and it'll still look better than if you shot in that reduce size to begin
with.
So that's one option I assented graduated from.
Now I use what are called Panasonic G.H. 4S.
The reason why I use these is because they're kind of a bit of like a videographer's hack.
They're really cheap relatively searching now at the G.H. five is out and good.
You're watching it could be N-Gage eight.
Which means that they're even cheaper now.
But the thing with these is it's the cheapest way you can possibly shoot for AK and for AK video resolution
is a great place to try to get to because more resolution just means that you can screw up more things
and still make it look good at the end of the day.
I like it quite a bit.
It's got a flipout screen it's very easy to use.
It pairs well with other apps.
I actually use a iPad to start and stop and preview all of my videos.
So that was pretty useful.
It is of course a standalone camera which means you have to mount it on something or you have to carry
it around with yourself.
Now you guys watched the lecture about Final Cut Pro we talked a little bit about warp stabilizer and
adored the Premier that can solve a lot of it but a lot really comes down to making sure that you're
not bouncing around every time you're filming.
Usually shooting freehand like this is a terrible idea try to just get at either a tripod which means
that it's completely standard or you can pre design your shot beforehand or what's called a monopod
which is just one little stick you stick this on top you can't balance by itself but it allows you to
stand behind it and move it around and stabilize it somewhat.
There are also these rigs that you can wear like they're literally like boxes that go in your shoulders
and then you can put this in the middle and it keeps it in what's called a gimbal gimbal Basically it's
like a three axis a little contraption so that every time you move it can actually stay straight.
So you don't have this going on no matter what.
If you're shooting life style photos and you're in a city or whatever I can be the truth a useful.
Personally the way that I shoot those if you notice in some of my promos they'll need these moving shots
and cities.
I don't walk around like this because that's just going to look terrible.
And also I can't really control the way the White interacts with this.
I use what's called an Osmo and they're relatively old now but it's like a stick and that stick has
a little ball on it top.
I don't have it with me.
I won't show you otherwise but.
And what it does is it uses film with that.
And as I move my arm it always stays static no matter what.
And that's some other cool stuff like you can double click it and turn it on for a selfie and things
like that so that's really useful.
I'm just walking around or tracking someone following them.
That's incredibly useful.
Also really small things can make a huge difference in your shoots for instance like these.
These costs like $8 and they're called like gorilla pods but yeah you can put these pretty much anywhere
and then attach your phone to it and shoot from any angle that's incredibly useful.
They even have like bigger ones that you use for.
Yes a lot of which can be really helpful in a pinch.
Really it's going to come down to what your budget is like.
One thing I'd like to point out is when you're shooting something and say you want to shoot stuff that's
more produced right like this is static.
I come and I talk to you at virtually the same shot every single time.
There's a lot of small things that you can do to focus on and get the best quality.
One thing people don't realize is that lighting is just incredibly important.
I personally think it's more important than the camera and more important than the lens that you attach
to it.
You have the right lighting then any camera or even your iPhone can pick up a great shot.
So that's one thing also to pay attention to just look around in your room is the lighting coming down
in a really harsh way on your subject the person you're actually shooting or can you see everything
on them are they illuminated.
They're really easy ways to get portable lighting kits I mean they're just a little $30 attachments
that go to the top of your camera that shoot ladies.
These aren't fantastic but they're great in a pinch especially if you're shooting in like dark spaces.
But if you have the luxury of being able to set up or you shoot then just look into lights I mean there's
three different types of lights.
We have fluorescence we have toung stands and we have Ltds fluorescents are what we call daylight so
they shine white and they're generally medium range in cost.
They don't produce a ton of heat.
The other thing is tungsten.
Those are the cheapest but they produce the most heat and those glow warm and they grow in a kind of
an orange.
So they're sitting in your living room right now.
Look at the light bulb that's above you.
If you just look at it you probably just noticed that that's an orange glow and that light glows in
different ways.
Indoors we usually use tungsten for whatever reason it just makes it look more homey because day lights
make it look like you're in a hospital.
It's more like visual clarity.
Either way your camera will actually filter that out so it doesn't matter what color you use it's just
each one kind of has it's pros and cons the last thing is Ltd's and all can be in either type of color.
The problem is just they're really expensive but they're incredibly portable and useful.
So personally I go for Ltd's just because I don't have a lot of places to store this stuff.
And if you're on a shoe and you're going like going to shoot something you could actually conceivably
bring Ltd's and they can run from batteries.
So that's actually a huge plus.
Whereas if you had only daylight's or florescence I mean you'd have to know how you do it.
You have to bring a lot of equipment or have something behind you running with it the entire time.
It's worth pointing out that on Instagram audio is not going to be big no matter what you make you're
probably going the overlaying music on top of it.
So it's not really a big part of it like very rarely do people watch videos where it's so important
that you hear the audio or like what they're saying and it needs to be perfectly clear.
So audio is not really something I generally worry about.
There are things like like I have a road Mike and what that is is a mike that just sits on top of your
camera wherever you go it points directly at whatever you're trying to film.
That's great for if you're just on the go.
You can use it in other spaces as well.
I think it's fine because just like they're saying and scam audio is just lower.
It's not a big priority.
You can do what I use and see it but this is a what's called a shotgun.
Pull it down low and that is basically a stick and you're seeing like movie sets where someone is carrying
a big stick and it's got the microphone at the end of it.
That's a shotgun mike.
Yes cut like a boom mike.
That's good if you're in a static place because the quality of the audio is the best they give you the
best audio easily and they're the best for like her doing Acco and fragmentation and things like that.
Now another thing I'll say is when you first get say like a lawyer or like a camera like this and you
just start playing around with it.
It's a lot of fun.
I mean they're fun to play with.
One thing I will suggest is that don't obsess yourself over things like white balance.
So what balance is there like how you want your photo to look cool or warm but it also depends on the
lighting.
We use those tungsten.
I was talking before.
You have to balance it to tungsten light.
Otherwise it just looks orange.
Same thing with daylight.
You tell your camera all cameras now have auto white balance and that just does it for you.
It's really not worth just worrying about that stuff.
That's something you see on really high productions.
And also it's something that you can fix after the fact in editing and it's pretty easy to do.
So that's something I just I wouldn't really worry about that stuff.
Things that you could concern yourself with are things like Aperture and ISO and shutter speed but you
can learn that stuff in 30 minutes.
I mean you can put links to that kind of stuff in the resources.
We talked a little bit more about that and one of my other courses of how to get your first thousand
but it's really pretty simple.
Personally I think that the best place to go to learn how to shoot videos is wisteria.
OK if you ever use wisdom there an online video platform they don't compete with YouTube necessarily
but they are for people who want to privately embed videos on their Web sites and then get analytics.
They have a platform for that and they're out of like Cambridge Massachusetts.
You go to their Web site they have a great section if you go to learn a dot com and there are videos
and things like shooting your computer screen or how to shoot someone who is working at your company
your quick little things that you can do to set something up on the go and it comes out great.
It also shows you how to do shots that are really really common like the blank background with a gradient
kind of growing out of it and it's just a head shot that I actually use in some of my courses so that's
probably the best resource I can then go for really quick and dirty ways of making fun video that applies
to Instagram too.
There's tons and tons of stuff out there about shooting video but they're not scaled down to what you
would need on Instagram which is just a much lower requirement.
The other thing I'll say is if you're shooting outdoors look into a thing called a scrim.
S C R I M or a reflector.
And if you are shooting outdoors then all you need is a camera some way of getting audio.
It doesn't really matter.
And something like a scrimmage or a reflector.
They're really easy.
They're just small things you can carry with you and some of them are small unfold.
The Basically what it is is when you're outside the sun is a very capricious thing to work with.
You never know what angle it's going to shine down at or if it's going to be harsh it's like the color
temperature of it changes throughout the day.
It can wreck your shots you can have something really really cool and find out that just looks like
crap.
If you use a scrammed what is basically a very thin sheet that you can just hold out in a certain direction
and it diffuses the light.
So whatever is underneath it actually looks like something you'd want to see.
And reflectors kind of same thing if the sun's coming down in one side way too strongly not the other.
Put it on the other side and it bounces back and evens out the lighting.
So those are two things you can look at there.
I mean you can buy them on Amazon for 20 bucks.
I won't go into any of the more expensive or fancy stuff because it's just not worth it if you're just
shooting for a 10 80 by Trinity Square on Instagram.
All right guys hopefully this is somewhat useful.
I mean you could just go down the rabbit hole of this for months and months and months.
But these are the things I found out work pretty well.
The D.H. for are really cheap easy to do.
You can also just get the 70 Ds from Canon.
Really really easy stuff.
Get a lens that's adjustable just because you can twist it and zoom in and zoom out.
Don't use what's called a prime lens.
That means you can't zoom in and out.
They have a clear picture but they're not as flexible.
You don't really want to be sitting there changing lenses all the time past that.
Just make sure that you're paying attention to lighting.
Audio is really not something to worry about.
And then look into things like the Osmo or things like gimbals so that you can carry cameras with you
as you go.
And it helps you to stabilize everything because when it stabilize it looks great.
Oh did that check out.
I think they're probably the best for getting started on this.
Any other questions about how I do anything or how I would do something.
Feel free to post in the slack and we'll talk to you there.
Otherwise see you next Dr..