Hey guys welcome back OK.
This lecture what we're going to do is I'm going to show you how to use an online video editor to make
videos pacifically for Instagram.
Now the software that I need to use is called Final Cut Pro 10 and it's specific to Mac computers only
if you have a PC there is a complimentary software called Adobe Premiere.
It's actually a lot better than Final Cut Pro 10 but it's made for professional videographers or video
editors whereas Final Cut Pro is kind of dumbed down for the rest of us.
I use both of them but Final Cut Pro I can get the same thing done and last time that's why I'm going
to show you guys that software in the resources will attach some guides on how to do roughly the same
thing with Premier Premier is great.
I use it for a lot of different things.
If I'm trying to do something really fancy or really professional it's great.
It can also do the basics but it's like using a 32 piece Swiss Army knife if you only need a spoon.
That's kind of the problem.
If you guys are also familiar with eye movie you're on a Mac.
That also is incredibly easy to use.
Actually a lot of Instagram video makers use the movie that's about as simple as it gets personally.
It's too simple for me.
I like a little more functionality so I kind of go in the middle with Final Cut Pro 10.
But if you are in Windows you also have Windows Media maker which is essentially the equivalent of a
movie.
So we're going to do is spend one lecture getting used to the user interface of Final Cut Pro.
How does it work.
What's the timeline.
How do you make basic transitions and create a project how do you make the framing the right size and
then in the next lecture it will go into the follow along lecture where you can watch me make an actual
video that I'll post on the Instagram account later.
So without further ado let's jump into it.
OK so this is final cut pro It doesn't say 10 at the top.
It usually says an X for whatever reason Final Cut Pro is no real there's no difference between that
and Final Cut Pro 10 so don't really worry about it.
There's two different ways of getting this one.
I think you use pay out right.
The second one is there is usually a subscription service you can pay for.
And the third one is how Like I say it out loud.
Look at me look at me.
I'm the captain now anyway so the way this works is you open it up and you have a workspace kind of
like this.
Over here we have your libraries now.
A library is generally thought of as like a project right like I have a library usually for all of my
course production.
Why.
Because in that library I didn't store all of my clips all of my scenes and things like that.
I generally get to keep it in one.
So what ends up happening is every time I read reference an image or a video that I've used before it's
easy because it's in the same library.
If you want to create a new library you go up here to file and then you go to a new library.
One thing I will suggest doing is if you're going to use this a lot get an external hard drive and attach
that to it and save your library to your external hard drive.
That way as your library gets larger and larger and it will it will balloon like no other.
It doesn't freeze up your computer and take up all your space.
That's usually what I do.
But in this case I'm going to be using a really small library so I should be fine.
OK.
So once you have your library set up then you go over here which is where you're going to list off your
projects.
OK.
The way that they call the hierarchy of file types in here is you have libraries and then individual
projects and then clips now clips are just little chunks of video.
That's it.
They're not polished they're not finished.
They're things you put into projects so a project could have 20 different clips a project.
The easiest way to think of it is a video.
OK.
So if I was doing lectures then one lecture would be a project want to do one video for Instagram.
That's a project you want to create a new project and do the same thing up here.
New project.
Or you could use quick key which command in it was you create a new one.
Once you have that done now let's look at the other parts of the user interface rest of it's pretty
simple.
So this is going to be your actual preview screen.
So this is what's going to show you what's actually happening now down here is the most important part
and it's called the timeline.
You have haven't edited before or used anything that has a timeline.
You never use Flash or like the Photoshop timeline editors or anything like that.
This can be a little confusing at first but it's pretty easy once you get the hang of it the way that
this works is it's a literally a time line.
It starts from the left and goes to the right and you appear this is the time stamp.
So in the video whatever is right here like the objects I'm going to throw in here it's going to happen
around zero point zero and in about 30 seconds it's going to be here in a minute and 15 it's going to
be here.
I'll throw in some clips just to show you what this looks like so it makes a little bit more sense.
OK.
So I threw in some trees that if I were to hit command plus intellectually zoomie and you can also just
use the zoom buttons down here and then what I can do is notice how this is the time stamps two minutes
and 10 seconds.
That's where I am in the timeline if it's space.
This is what I'm actually viewing right now right here.
As we go through.
And then it hits the end and it's over.
So that's essentially the timeline works and that's how you manage when elements come onto the screen.
Does you manage how long the clip is that you're making sorry that the clip the project that you're
making.
And that's pretty much everything happens if I wanted to throw something on top of this like an overlay.
I would just draw drag and drop it onto the timeline and it would show up on top of it.
I'll do that here in a second.
Up here we have the inspector window.
And this is just where you can do a whole lot of different things to the clips that you put in your
timeline.
You can edit virtually anything.
And it gives you different types of controls on it.
All of these are kind of complicated or not really worth worrying about.
But some basic stuff in here like you threw in a video and it was large enough.
Here's your scale button right so I can scale it.
And notice how as I scale it above the size of these outer frames.
Anything out there I cannot see because this is the frame.
OK so if I return this back there you go.
It gives you cropping you can just store you can that image stabilization.
I don't prefer using image stabilization in Final Cut Pro I prefer actually using Adobe Premiere for
that one but it still works decently well.
You'll also notice that the inspector window is divided into video audio and info.
Now depends on what you're clicking on here what element or clip or whatever.
It'll change.
But for this time I'm in the video inspector section for status of trees.
It's going to give me everything that would apply to the actual visual of the clip.
You're not going to find anything about shaping the noise or anything like that or like the metadata
in here.
Now if you wanted audio then we can actually start talking about the audio because this one actually
has audio attached to it.
I don't know if you actually heard that but I can actually work with the volume here.
I want it to.
There's also quicker ways of doing it in the timeline.
And here they also give you some easy like audio enhancements that you can use to quickly get some kind
of effect on your sound.
And then the rest of it kind of gets complicated way too quickly and then info's just metadata just
notes and some stuff that would be pretty helpful if you were working with an editor or you could print
those off.
That's about it.
So if you wanted to just change the audio and this clip really all you have to do is go down here click
it and then hover over this line.
Now it says zero D-B DB just means decimal decimal is just a way of counting how loud something is.
So zero to them means that the volume is the exact same as the volume on the clip when you imported
it right.
So if I just play the clip well know if you can hear that but it has a certain level of audio.
But if I go back here.
So zero is what we just heard and if I wanted to drop it I could go lower and I could go higher.
I can also just killed the audio entirely by just going like this right clicking it going detach audio
right there and then just deleting it.
It's really quite simple.
OK now the rest of the user interface is over here and it's just a combination of a lot of different
things.
It's generator's is transition's it's text effects it's music it's it's images and it's a whole bunch
of random things.
It just honestly you could have entire course on this.
It takes an hour or two to explore all of them.
I honestly suggest you do.
And it's pretty useful.
So let's say right here is the effects browser.
So if we click this it's going to give me all of the video and audio effects that automatically come
with Final Cut Pro.
They have a lot of effects that just come with it.
So that's actually quite useful and that's one of the bigger benefits.
Final Cut provers say like Adobe Premiere version of that come with as many built in presets like this.
So the way that you would apply one of these video or audio effects would be to just find whatever it
is that you want to say we want to go to the basics and these look like filters for the most part.
And this is like a what's called a mask.
So as you put a bubble somewhere be a negatives that reverses the colors.
There's a lot of goofy things.
But they also have a lot of more advanced things so for some reason if I wanted add vibrancy all I have
to do is just click it and drag it over onto my video and then drop it.
If it were an audio effect all I would have to do is do the same thing except I would need my audio
to be showing.
So I remember when I detached the audio and you saw it there and I deleted it.
Same thing you just draw.
You go and drag and drop it onto the audio.
OK.
Now that I drag and drop that on there that will add a additional option appear in the inspector window.
If you get a video.
Now we have vibrancy and effects.
Now if I wanted to turn off the effects.
So right now it's just vibrancy.
But if I had multiple ones you'd see multiple I could just click this and it turns them all off.
I wanted it back and I wanted to play with that effect.
Here is where you screw with the amount and you kind of see in the preview window how it's changing
and you go OK we want it back at the euro.
So it goes down to one of if I just want to turn that one off the nuts like that and found it throw
another one on.
See I could find you probably get a look.
So these are very common so I can make it look like a 50s television.
OK.
So if I wanted to either go and vibrancy back the next section in the effects little panel over here
is this and it's not particularly useful.
This is just helpful for pulling clips.
So essentially this does exist pulls all the photos off of your computer or phone or wherever.
I didn't know then that's one easy way of pulling clips over here as audio.
Now they give you a lot of audio clips that you can use they have a lot of sound effects and jingles
and strange movie sounds.
I personally don't use it.
But occasionally you can find something that's kind of useful.
I don't know if you can hear that but that's an airplane landing.
Burkham super useful OK.
Over here is the transition browser so you can kind of tell it looks like a transition least that's
all that icon kind of represents.
Now transition is essentially how do you go from one clip to another.
Right.
So let's say that we have another clip in here and who is a lab.
OK.
So this is a clip of a lab and this is a clip of trees.
How do we go from here to here.
Because if I don't have a transition it just looks like this.
But there you go.
So it just was literally one frame on the trees and then the next frame on the lab and that's just not
going it's not great.
There's a lot different ways of doing this.
That's just up a cold hard cut.
You see this sometimes in like YouTube videos.
They don't put any transmissions on it at all.
But personally I don't suggest doing it.
Now a lot of your branding in a lot of your style comes from how you set your transitions cross dissolve.
Let's take for example the way you do this you would just take it and then drag and drop it on.
I'll show you how it works.
You can also scrub through.
This is really helpful because a lot of the things they have don't really make sense and only throwing
them on over and over again just to figure out what they are.
So if I took this over here and I just drag it into the two like right at the intersection of where
I want this to happen and drop it it'll either just do it or sometimes it'll tell you you don't have
a media pass to your edges to make that it doesn't really matter.
It just has to do with how long your clip is.
Typically what happens is it starts before the end of your clip and up here it's going to start after
the end of the clip because that what it's doing is effectively making this start before this one is
ended.
You can actually do this manually but this is probably the fastest way of doing it.
Now this here is what actually determines the length of the effect.
So as we watch crossed as all the Basically this faded out this faded in.
And it gives you that look.
Now if I wanted to change this.
Let's say I wanted a really short cross is all I can go over here and hold it in.
See how it's shrinking.
So watch the different screen that and let's say this because it is a lot faster and you can keep doing
that pretty much all the way down here to the point you don't even really notice it anymore.
See OK now if you want to do say move this transition.
So if you wanted to say make this transaction start sooner on this clip or later on this one.
You can grab these two vertical lines over here on either side.
And now I can kind of move it in relationship to the right clip.
I can move this in relationship to the left clips you I just kind of overtakes it.
It's kind of a lazy man's way of doing it.
So there's a lot of transitions in here that I like.
The ones that are really like over the top like that.
OK.
Why the hell you don't do that.
But there's also ones that are pretty subtle or just pretty things were just useful.
So like one of my favorites is slide slide just what it does is it slides in.
So it's right here.
And if I just drag so you have to get rid of this transition first drag slide and slide.
You can either do slide in or slide out.
So what happens I threw that in and now I have modifiers up here.
So this is the controller I can control which direction it slides from.
So we take this and move it.
See how it's changing where it's going to come in from.
Now another way of doing this is just to go over here and change the direction.
So that's a custom direction.
I can change it to up or right and see that looks like see it slides in instead.
Alternatively we could do is slide out.
Now sliding out essentially instead of the second clip coming in the first clip we use and the second
one is just underneath it like this.
OK.
Other than that there's a couple other settings there's like a push which I don't ever use it's just
too much motion.
Notice how it just kind of like rotates the whole thing once.
That's perfectly fine but that's a very useful one really just takes all of time to play around with
these.
There's some interesting like Blur transitions there's a lot of I don't know some pretty classic ones
that you can find and use and you see them on Instagram all the time.