OK so the next section over here is text.
And in the tech section it's primarily where are you going to make 3D text.
So where are you going make titles it's where you get to make things like lower thirds lower thirds.
You're not familiar are these pieces of text and graphics that usually pop up in the bottom lower thirds
of your image.
Well if you've seen these before so let's say I wanted to put this on to here again I throw it on and
it's another elements are just thrown on the top.
And let's say I'm over here.
So that pops up and says whatever you want to say so I can go here and click on this element and then
over here now that I'm I have the inspector window working on the text I can go over here to text and
now I can change it I can change the font.
I can change the alignment and even give me things like line spacing and tracking and kerning and things
like that.
So all that's pretty useful and a lot of these lower Thera's they give you right out of the gate are
pretty useful if you're going to do my older courses.
You probably seen this one of use this one before that there's the title pull tab that added here but
honestly I don't even know why they added it or what use it's for.
If you want to add a just plain old text just any old text not something that has three-D or bumper
or ripples or whatever.
All you have to do at least the search for me is you go down go up to all.
OK so now we're looking at all good at the search.
Now since we're in search we clicked all we're searching all of the tax effects and just type in custom.
So that's really it.
So custom is where you do whatever text you want.
And it just gives you some text.
And now if I you know I can see this look at title and text and change all sorts of things about it.
You want to change the color of your tax you go down to face.
So you cook face it cooks show and then I can change it.
Change the color.
I just click this little box right here and there's multiple ways of picking whatever color you want.
Down here I have some saved ones.
Here's where you put in the hex colors if you want to be exact.
And it's pretty straightforward not you but a glow but an outline can do a whole lot of stuff a drop
shadow stuff.
It works well.
Keep in mind that if you add more and more of this stuff this stuff is really computer intensive so
your computer might start getting really slow.
So keep that in mind.
Over here you can screw it the size.
All right.
We wanted to blow it up.
Let's say we wanted to put it in the font that I always use in my courses we're using open sands for
innovation station by the way.
But we can use proxy and Nova for just this example.
Extra Bold really bold.
OK.
All right moving on to the next part.
These are called generators and generators are.
I don't really explain them.
They don't generate large objects.
OK.
So a lot of times your generators and the like backgrounds.
So if I wanted to have a background you could just a text you need to fill it up with something in the
back.
I could do a background like that or now like pieces of paper or bubbles.
Who knows.
I mean they have a lot of different things here.
What's most useful personally that I found are solid solids.
They have custom.
That means you can send whatever color you want.
Or they things like grayscale pastel white vivid like pastels are pretty nice because it automatically
turns whatever color you use into pastel.
So if I were to take over now we're looking at pastels is that whatever I want I want.
All right.
Never want to be really specific and go over to video change the shape Krop it distort it do all sorts
of different things other than that you can add in things like textures.
So if I wanted to add a texture to something but I didn't want it to overwhelm whatever it is that I'm
supposed to be looking at I'd click the element there and then go over to video up and then Specter
go all the way down to positing that opacity to bring down the opacity.
So that was the original.
And I did keep adding it until I kind of get the texture that I want.
You can only see it and they blow it up.
OK then the last thing is this one which is the themes browser.
That's just another little chunk of stuff that you can use.
I honestly don't really know what the difference is.
A lot of times you'll find like lay out effects here you put them in boxes and shape it kind of like
the layout app.
We have an Instagram.
You've got things like Lynde's flares.
Honestly just spend some time and play around with it.
Got the last two little bits I'm going to show you really quickly are the modifiers here for the preview
when do in the preview window.
This can be pretty helpful if you want to make this larger grab here and push this down.
Or alternatively you can push these to the side sometimes if you want to change.
So you like this say will take the background the pastel right here and we wanted to change that element
right.
We could use different types transform cropping to store so if one were to transform this is free transforming
like Cliggott and then it gives me all of these things.
I can spin it if I want to I can shrink it and I can even go like this.
And notice how it's always symmetrical so this doesn't lose scale when you do this it just automatically
goes when you're done.
Click that and you're done.
And here's where you can go full screen if you want to here's where you can change the view.
This is super helpful if you want it to fit to see exactly how it fits or sometimes you need to zoom
out in order to move things that happens quite a bit or zoom out.
Small it is OK.
Other than that there are a couple of things you missed down here on the timeline.
One thing worth understanding is that this right here is called the scrubber.
OK.
And that is I don't really know explain that scrubbing is a common concept in a lot of different technologies
but where are the scrubber.
Is is what you're seeing right here.
And if you want to go over to here you click on that news.
So it just tells you what's here.
So you always know where you are otherwise you would be completely lost because all of their settings
right here.
So this is called Audio skimming.
So if you have this on it's useful but sometimes it can be kind of annoying.
So what happens is if you click it you can drag your mouse across and it automatically updates as I
don't have to click click click.
And with audio it'll automatically scrub and start playing whatever it is that tiny little bit you were
over.
I don't ever use it because personally I think it's quite annoying but you can kind of seems like you
but it's super useful if you're trying to like find an error and audio and you're describing through
try to find it.
Last thing right here is this is what will automatically make your elements match up.
So if you didn't have an on I can actually move this just randomly in random locations that nothing
is related to each other.
And what happens oftentimes is you'll run into a situation where let's say you don't know you're trying
to match things up or one thing shows and the next thing shows but you actually have a couple of pixels
and in between and you didn't realize that.
So it actually looks like crap where you really want to do is click this so that whenever you have multiple
elements on the screen it automatically clicks right to what's relevant and then it'll move on to the
next thing that's relevant.
Which is one of these Aline's So it's constantly up and I'll stop right there like it zooms to fit that
it is really really helpful.
The only time I ever turn it off is if for some reason I need to be more precise or the snapping is
actually screwing me up which happens quite often.
OK so that's the basic UI of this.
You'll notice that I was using a rectangular canvas.
We wanted to make something for Instagram specifically you would want to go create your original project
go down here and it says video properties go to custom and then if you go here all the way back down
to custom custom and then type in 2010 A.D. Or you can type in the other specific ones that we had for
rectangles or portraits or whatever.
This is usually always the same twenty three point nine eight.
That's just what people are used to seeing in videos or at least like film.
So you click and key and now we have a square video.
All right so let's say you had a video that you wanted to finally save.
Here's one that actually made for one of the lectures and then of course you could just go to it and
then I hit command e and it pops up your master file plug pop up.
And then what you do is you basically just set your settings and just pick what you want.
Generally you want your format to always be video and audio the only wanted your video or your audio
you could isolate it right here other ways of doing it just like selling CDs and as the Apple devices
but generally I just do this.
I don't like to worry about all this other stuff.
So the Yokota I often use H dot 2:06 for and that is just optimized for Web.
Basically that's what YouTube uses it's probably the best ratio of quality to size you can get.
You want something massive but also extremely crisp.
You can use these and explore those.
Then next you just sit next find a location where you want to save it save it and once it exports you
are good.
If you want to see the progress of the export go up to window and then background tasks will show you
right there.
All right then once it's done it automatically pops up on your screen you can watch it to make sure
that it comes out correctly and then move on.
OK so now you know the basics of Final Cut Pro tan you could probably get in school around learn a lot
more and potentially put something together in the next lecture if you want to you can watch me create
a video using this for innovation station and it's going to be more of a looking over my shoulder following
along as I kind of hack it together to figure it out.
All right with that being said I'm sorry.
That was a long one but I'll see you in the next lecture.