All right, guys, we are back to wrap up the last major
thing that we need to do to set up our account
and get ready to impress.
Last thing we need to do is put that call to action in your bio.
Now, remember, Instagram lets you put
one link in your bio, and that is really it.
You can't really put links anywhere else.
I mean, you can put them in your captions and in your
photos, but they're not links, like, you can't click
them and go somewhere, they have to manually type it in.
So the gateway from your Instagram account and
something out there that's real and makes money is pretty
much all funneled through this one blue link.
Not to say that Instagram isn't real, and let's be serious,
there are cats with larger follower bases than politicians,
but I think you get what I'm saying. Anyway,
let's use the last sentence of the bio to draw the
attention of the user to that ever-so-important link.
Now, will people just click it themselves?
No, not at all.
People are not just whirl-winding around
your account, clicking at random.
They only do things for a purpose, as shallow as that purpose
may be. You need to tell them why they should click your link.
So, first of all, what is your link?
Well, you know, why exactly do you want to use Instagram?
That's the broader question.
Chances are, you want to use it as
a channel for growing your business.
If you're just a person, then maybe you just want to
promote your personal brand, and there isn't necessarily
a monetary goal attached to it... yet.
We're going to talk a lot more about making money
through your account in a way later section in the course,
but what I can summarize is that, in most likelihood,
you're going to link them to the home page of your
site, to a lead magnet offering something for free,
or directly to a product you want them to buy.
Usually it falls in those three categories.
One gets you traffic, one gets you email addresses, and
the other one just gets you direct revenue, potentially.
So decide what it is that you want to promote to begin with.
That's going to be the focus of your call to action.
Now, the best practice is to use your last line of your
bio as your "Hey, here's a reason to click this thing."
So treat this like any other piece of advertising.
If you were running an ad for Facebook, for
instance, how would you get them to click a link?
Generally, the best thing to do is to convince them they'll get immediate value from it, or to articulate what it is they get.
OK, it could be 50% off of something, it could be
a free e-book, or a webinar, or whatever it is.
It could just be, you know, "This is how your
life will change by clicking the link", whatever.
Want to lose 10 pounds?
Who doesn't? Click the link.
Want to know how I got Instagram famous? Click here.
Free template for success - click here.
You get the point.
I need to know in one sentence that I'm going to get something tangible or it's going to answer a question I have in my head.
The rules of the game really are simple.
It's one sentence.
It should tell them what they will gain by clicking it and I strongly suggest that you make that thing immediate and tangible.
The call to action "To learn more, click here" is
just weak tea, and it performs like soggy said tea.
The next thing I'd suggest is doing what most people
do and using a down arrow to visually indicate
what you're talking about exactly.
It just points the eyes down.
Now, you can use a down arrow like this, or you could
use this angled arrow, which is actually kind of
more accurate, because on web, the link
will be at a slight angle from the sentence.
So use whatever you want, but the whole idea is you
want to direct their eyes downward, and you see this
on pretty much all accounts that are well made.
Now, use something relevant to what you're doing.
I'll probably link in my account to, like, one of my courses.
And in that case, what I'll say is "Want to learn [...]?"
It'll have something to do with my content and
linking to a course that has something to do with that.
Or it could be "Learn to do..." whatever it is,
and then some kind of a kicker, like a discount.
I can also link to a company and just
kind of set up like an affiliate relationship,
we'll decide this later on in the follow along sections.
Now, you usually see call the actions in the
form of "Want to do something? Here's how."
Or "Join [...] and get [...]."
Or, if you're like, say, promoting a book, it'll be
"I accomplished [...]. Learn about it here/Get it here."
Anyway, I think you get the drift.
Go ahead and put together something that
makes sense, and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Oh, and by the way, if you're stuck, we actually have
more templates and examples attached in the resources,
so hopefully just going through those and answering
the questions should get you to a call to action.
You don't have to be a marketing major to pull this off well,
it's actually quite simple, so don't overthink it.
All right, guys.
With that being said, moving on.