Now what I want to do is just then pick an intro and outro for this text so it slides and it pops in.
Who knows.
One thing I use pretty frequently are templates.
So there's a lot of companies out there that just make Final Cut Pro templates and they make all sorts
of little widgets and widgets and stuff that just makes the process for you a lot easier.
One of the companies I buy stuff from is called Motian VFX.
They have some really nice stuff.
It's not terribly expensive.
You can also find free ones elsewhere.
You also just use on the Final Cut Pro has I mean that's perfectly fine too.
I found one a while ago that I find pretty useful.
It's called in behavior and it's just a set of behaviors intros outros just odd things that you can
make anything do.
And it applies to text files images so you can Bronson's like make something rotate in or rotate on
the Y.
Let's see the intros.
Look in their book and it's there you know do that or whatever.
So now it's just me finding something that works.
I mean you want it to be energetic because it's a video when to keep their attention you just don't
make it a little like tacky by doing something that's way over the top like a blur in.
Yeah that could work.
I usually like a nice slide so often the slides are just so common they just look good just sliding
in from the side very quickly.
It's kind of them in between.
It's like a lot of energy but it's also I mean subtle it's not something that just looks ridiculous
like this one.
Or it's like literally says in takes forever or even notice it.
So let me take a screw around with a couple of these and then come back and we'll talk about which one
I chose.
OK so I'm just a creature of habit so I use a slide and then I picked out of that behavior kit a exit.
So without editing anything with regards to speeds this is what it should look like.
So it slides in and then it should fade out.
Now what do you have to do these for whatever reason with Final Cut Pro 10 is that you just take this.
And then you have to merge it with the object that you want to apply that behavior towards.
So the way you do that is to just pick the two things and then it's usually options.
And you create a new compound clip.
I don't really worry.
Now it's together like this as I go towards the end.
You can see it should fade out.
There you go see it faded out.
I can still modify the speed of the intros and outros.
And you just do it a little bit differently.
So you probably.
Now if I wanted to change the speed of that fade out I just double click it and now I'm zoomed in and
I can change the fade out here.
So it's actually a pretty slow fade out.
So make it like that and then we'll make this slide and much faster.
OK.
And I we'll do that because it slides and I like that effect.
That was a little fast and see part of this is you really get to come down to.
How long do you think I need to read this for.
OK.
So now I have it.
Well that's a facile slight and I think that's pretty useful.
Now I need to do the same thing with the text itself so often times you can use copy these.
The timing for both of these.
So if you have your snaps on right there it'll automatically snap to the same area.
So it shouldn't look like it's in unison every go so that just pops up like that.
You know what effect you can do that.
I like doing is having it slide in from the side but this won't come up from the bottom since it's not
a big distance.
They have to cover before they touch.
Sometimes I can actually look kind of cool.
So that's one way of doing it.
See and then x adding I want to make it probably shorter.
I think that's pretty good.
And now it's just a matter of like reusing that way of coming in coming out.
Then the question is just can you read that.
Is that fast enough.
So Tinian rasslin is that type of lightweight.
It's not a lot of not a lot of breathing room for some of the people that are maybe a little bit slower
at reading.
So what I have to do going here is to reapply it fade out.
Actually now I can modify a length slightly.
I Here here.
So hopefully this is enough time to read it
I think that's decent enough gives a little bit longer time for it switches.
OK.
All right now I need to fix the size of this video to match the square because most video you're going
to get this is a problem you run into you repeatedly is not going to be the right size.
It's like a square.
So you have to do is essentially take it out here and then we'll have to increase the size of the background
background.
OK.
So it hits the corners should be better.
Yeah especially because it's high enough resolution that should work.
It's kind of odd that wobbles like that.
But we can live with it.
OK.
So same thing here.
Right.
Well any differences like I might want to just mix it up a little bit.
I might want it to come from a different direction.
So let's first get the image to the right size.
All so for the next one I have to resize this to fit a square.
This is actually a problem because the thing is long right.
So I could go and find another image or I can do a trick that is somewhat commonly done and see this
but often as soon as you start looking for it.
So you take the image and we want to copy and paste.
So two of them.
OK so what can happen is I'm going to take this copy and I'm going to blow it up to the background.
So I take this one and blow it up as background.
So it looks like it's just repeating itself.
And what I can do is I'm going to blur out the background that looks kind of just like an extension
of itself.
And hopefully that will look decent enough that it's not too confusing and it just look kind of like
the ground is continuing hopefully.
But so what you would do is you get to this bottom one.
Right.
So you can see it here in kind of the corner sticking out.
And we're just going to add a bowler to it.
So if you want a blur on Final Cut Pro you figure two effects.
So you would think you type in blur and make sure that you've selected all video and audio and you do
this but it's actually just called Gaussian.
They could put blur so that 99 percent of humanity could know how to find this.
But again you know software developers so take this and you drag it onto it.
So there it blurs out you kind of see that's blurred.
Probably needs a little bit more though.
So we click this we go up to the inspector window and here is the amount of Parliament Jack that
like it's now kind of looks like we're just highlighting it or something.
OK.
So the next thing we're gonna do is since this is an image like you just don't want us to stare at it
like that would be really boring.
So you probably want to do is just add a little bit of motion.
Now the way you add motion and this is a little more advanced than I think you'll really ever have to
deal with.
What better ways of doing this to me honestly.
You can put it in a software called Kim Tasia really easy to do it there if you have a Mac you can use
the thing called Screen flow really easy to do there.
It's a little clunky and final cut pro but again it's because it gives you more control than other ones.
They have tools for doing it.
Co-blogger Ken Burns so you can do Ken Burns right there.
You say where you want to star.
You say you want it.
And so I could do that I could say it like this.
So start slightly out and then we'll do the thought.
Ken Burns this thing like that to that.
So I don't see how this works.
OK so then if you play it it really zooms and see it just like that.
OK.
So that's usually good.
I mean it's a cheap and easy way of doing this would you to just take this first starting position and
make it the whole frame and then set this to whatever you want.
Now here's a key with this.
Less is more OK when you can burns.
Otherwise it's just going to look like watch.
Will you be moving way too fast.
I don't know I just I personally think this is kind of weird like you're zooming in that quickly.
So we all do is make it somewhere in between.
OK.
I really just don't want to make this easy for you.
So do that and then there is Ken Burns thing back on OK.
Then if I hit play we can see it moves in like that.
I don't know why it starts at such a zoom.
That's what's a little odd to me.
But there it goes.
OK.
So zoomed in for some reason because of the view.
But then this is what it looks like.
So we're like slowly zooming in on it.
Now alternatively you could just do a pan and slowly move from one side to the other.
That's another way of doing it just kind of depends of what type of emphasis you want to make.
There's nothing makes sense because like you see it now we're moving.
And the only thing I would do is I might tweak this just to the Ken Burns thing is again a little more
subtle because I like my can subtle.
So like that I think should work pretty well
OK.
So there.
OK great.
Now what we'll do is we'll throw on our text and we'll make it come in from a different angle.
OK.
So I mean the second one and what I did is I just made it come in from a different direction an accident
a different direction.
So it goes like that.
And so I will just continue on and do the rest of them.
And we'll check back in and to do something different or at the end.
It.
So I've thrown down text pretty much everything so far I think I need to work on now is tightening and
spicing things up.
So right now I just have him coming from the same directions and angles.
It's just kind of a manual process now going through and changing it so that they come at different
angles and come in different sizes and trying to use different entries and out outros.
You'll notice that I was a little bit of stutter on some of them.
You kind of get the gist of it.
So does that keep going.
And here was the final one.
A lot of it also will just come down to timing to seeing whether or not we can add figuring out figure
out a way to display each section or video long enough for you to read it because sometimes it's only
like six words during Sometimes it's two sentences.
So I'm going to do a little bit of the dirty work and I'll be right back.
All right.
So what I did was I went through and just did some tweaks I made the text larger in some cases because
if you can make it larger That's better.
So it's easier to read.
And I moved it around.
OK so then it's there.
Then I did an alternate one put it in the middle and I did another one top and then before I went to
change things lately that when I go in I went to that OK and then I kind of just changed up a little
bit more.
Now it will go through and all mix up the intros and outros and all add transitions from clip to clip.
OK you're back.
OK.
So what I've done I've gone through and added transitions from the background to give it some motion
so I go from this one to this one did a blur and it comes in and then it falls down and moves into that.
I tried to match these motions up.
So if you had a downward motion coming after like this is coming down then it should be preceded by
a downward mode something that's matching it kind of that kind of symmetry helps you like this swings
to the left wall that one is going right.
That kind of gives it a little more of a seamless feel to it because I did that I felt like there was
enough energy and that would be plenty and it almost made me a more annoying.
So I kind of laid off on the ones up here and so I really just kept to the slides where they just slide
in.
So I like that one for instance should probably pop in from the side.
You probably want to do it right and do it right from down down side OK.
But other than that you can see the most part works.
I just kind of had to balance the motions.
You don't get seasick.
That works.
Now I think the only thing I need to do is add our watermark and that's pretty much it.
And then have this fade out and then add music and we should be done.
Now one little key trick is if you want to me a fade out the easiest way to do that is just to click
control and vi and it'll pop up these options for each element you go composite opacity gace change
all the time line so I can change this to just make it less or more opaque or here and just make it
like a fade.
So as it goes it'll start to fade out.
So this is an interesting way of making it exit.
So once the text leaves it lingers for a little bit and then the background leaves.
OK.
So that's one way and kind and accepting and ending it.
Realistically I'm going to have some kind of an outro sequence so that in the end it says the Brandur
like whatever it says call the action.
Most likely will say What do you think.
And then I'll have the logo and ask them to comment and they all make that kind of like a brand doable
thing.
There's a lot of tweaking that goes into this and over time you'll get better and better and so you
know the first batch of 10 will probably be OK and then they'll all start figuring out what works and
what doesn't kind of go from there.
OK.
So what I'm going to do last up is at our logo
and figure out a place to put it.
So I don't want it to stick out too much.
But at the same time it shouldn't just look like a smudge on the screen.
So I went to
the thing.
They're probably like always put it in the corner like that's how does one technique.
Just a question of how it looks if everything else is moving and it's not.
Do you have to make it match transitions.
I'm not entirely sure we'll see it like that.
Moving so I should probably skirt the opacity and make it a little bit smaller but I think that's a
good way of making people understand that like you're kind of standing by it.
I prefer to have the innovation station but that would take a little more tweaking to make sure that
you could read it.
So I'm not really going to do that right now.
I think this is a good alternate plan.
We put it a little smaller that will play with the capacity of going to video the inspector and bring
it down a little bit so it looks more like a watermark right like a watermark.
It's like slight.
It shouldn't be a stamp.
You can bring it down even further and see how that looks.
It's like that I think pretty good.
Don't bring it down slowly.
That's about it.
The only thing I see conflicting with is this one little clip where I can just tweak this slightly
OK.
Now I need to grab music.
You get music.
YouTube has a great fantastic royalty free section.
There's a lot of stuff in Final Cut Pro.
I personally like to use things like audio jungle and sometimes I'll use things like the Vado market
like this.
See right here that's also a pretty useful one.
So let's see.
So we just want something science see.
So let me think we'll come back to it.
OK.
So we'll take it for you on YouTube and just search you to royalty free.
They have a channel that you go and call this library usually.
So audio library no copyright music.
Now I'm just hoping because something happy that matches and we're all about innovation and changing
the world go or something.
You know happy music or even full Philip
that
I think this a work.
So you do as you go down to the link it shows you read it download it
and channel subscription so you can confirm in order to download it.
Now that I've downloaded it I go and open it up look for the three and just drag and drop that in three
or there and drag it and put it somewhere underneath everything there.
OK so now I have music go back.
OK.
Generally you just want to make it quiet enough that you can hear it enough that it's distracting.
On Instagram you can make it a little bit louder than you would think since it's kind of carrying it.
And so no one talking someone's talking you have to be pretty quiet.
So right I think this works.
So last thing to do is just clip off the end and make sure that we snap it go.
And I think that should do it.
Should you get rid of any extra little bits.
OK.
So about 28 seconds in total and you can save it as an a good movie.
Pump that out which should be good to go.
OK.
So all attached this in the resources you can see what I made and keep in mind as we go through this.
I'm going to improve on this when I play it the Fontina play with the colors and deploy with the branding.
I might even work with some templates but I'll show you pretty much everything that we do.
So you're not going to be missing any steps that took about an hour for me to do.
And since I was the first time I done that that kind of makes sense.
But in the future I would imagine you take me closer to 30 minutes especially if I start having the
same patterns that it's just dragging and dropping and end when we get to automation that's when it
really starts to take off and I'll show you what I do.
OK.
So hopefully that was somewhat interesting not entirely too boring.
See you next lecture.