Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
OK, so this is an extra lecture.
You don't necessarily have to do this, but I think early
on it's worth doing, it's something that maybe later
when your account is growing you'll absolutely
need, but right now it's up to you.
Ok, so what we're going to do in this lecture is
we're going to set up our account with analytics.
The reason why we do this is because we want to know
as we start going through the process of posting,
and following people, and interacting, all the things
you do to grow your account, what's working.
We also want to know whether or not
we're growing or shrinking over time,
and as we start to bring together an audience, we also
want to know insights about that audience specifically.
Now, there's a lot of best practices out there for
Instagram's audience as a whole, but those are only
partially relevant to us.
We actually want to know specifically how our
group performs, when are they on Instagram,
when do they like photos the most often, things like that.
So what we're going to do is we're going to explore two
analytics tools that are out there, one is free and one is paid.
There's a lot of other free apps out there, but personally
they don't pass my bar of quality to suggest them.
Most of them seem like lead generation tools that are not
particularly consistent and not particularly accurate or useful.
So what we're going to do is instead we're going to first
work with the analytics embedded in Instagram, that's
the free version, and then the paid version,
we're going to use a tool called Iconosquare.
OK, now, believe it or not, Instagram allows you to have a lot of analytics for your account, but they only do it if you're a business.
OK, so you have to switch to a business account.
This is perfectly fine, because I'm assuming all of us
are business accounts, so it shouldn't
really be that big of a deal.
Now, the only thing you have to do before you set
up your Instagram insights, is what they call it, is
you have to create a Facebook page, because as soon as
you try to switch your account to a business account,
it's really easy to do, it's going to ask you to connect your Facebook page, because they're assuming you're a business.
So the first thing you want to do is go on your Facebook,
and we're going to create a business page. Keep in mind, whenever you make a business page,
it does not notify everyone in your personal Facebook
what you've done, so don't really worry about that.
Also, don't worry about filling out your Facebook page.
You don't need a Facebook page, you don't have to use it.
We just have to create the account when we then go to
our Instagram profile and switch it to a business account.
So the first thing you do is just go
over here and click this down arrow,
and then where it says Create a Page,
right there, just click that.
So now what you want to do is pick any of these.
It really just wants to know what type of business you are, because it's going to change the questions and change some
of the pre-made templates that they give you.
We're just going to pick business organization.
This one is kind of generic.
Or you can pick any other, it doesn't
really matter. Then it asks
for a company name and then
you have to choose a category.
So, company name, Innovation Station,
pretty easy, and then choose a category.
What I'm going to choose as a category is just, I'm going
to pick Internet company that works, pretty generic.
We're running on the internet.
Doesn't really matter what you pick,
they just use it for their own statistics.
Then, next up, they want you to add a profile picture, I'm not going to do that, I'm just going to skip, you could just skip it if you want. Add a cover photo, I'm not going to do that either.
You can just skip it. OK, so that's it.
Now I actually have a page, technically.
So all I've got to do is really just exit out of these annoying
tours, and you don't have to do anything else
on this page, congratulations. So next thing to do
is go over to your Instagram app on your phone,
it doesn't matter if you use iOS or Android.
So just go and select Instagram, your app. Then
we're going to go to the bottom right to where our
profile button is. Ok, now we see our profile. Now you
want to click the three dots on the top right.
So what we're going to do is go down to Switch to Business
Profile, and then we just want to click that, and what this
will allow us to do is now become a business, which
makes it so that we can use Instagram ads, we do
that later on in the course,
but it also allows us to put more contact information, so
we can put a phone number, an email, or use an address,
so it gives us extra options of just playing out on
our profile. What I want to do is just hit Continue,
and it gives us some preview of all the cool things that
they give us, which are pretty cool and pretty useful.
And then, you can see a preview of, if we went
to our account page, if you go up here and
click on the bars icon, that's going to be
where we see the analytics for our profile.
Then you can also see that it gives the users more options to contact us, pretty cool if you're using this for lead generation.
Next, we just need to connect a Facebook page.
OK.
So if you did this right and you're
logged in Facebook on your phone,
you should see your pages, so I just have to click
Innovation Station. Alright, now I can set up
a business profile, and if you hit Done, it will actually
force you to put in at least one of these three.
You can always change it.
Personally, what I suggest doing is making an email address
at the pretty link that you made before in the previous lecture.
So I'm just going to have a contact@innovationst.at
and that way they can
contact me for, later on when we start talking
about collaborating with other accounts.
Just make sure that whatever you put,
you're OK with people contacting you.
So if put your phone number, be aware, people might actually
call you, so if you don't have a real business, then I probably
would avoid that. Ok, so now it says
"Welcome, innovationstation." Cool.
Click through it, and now we are a business account. Great.
Ok, then at the top
you can see those bars and the icon, that's what we're going
to use to see insights about our account, so if we go to
that, it just shows us immediately how many followers
we have, how many we got in the last seven days, it even
gives you stats on posts, and other things like that. So
if we scroll down a little bit, you see the followers part,
and it says you need 100 followers to see this demographic
info, but once you do, it's actually pretty useful.
It tells you about the people who follow
you, and that will help you a lot
later on when we start looking for accounts to mimic or get inspiration from. Then, they give you information about your posts,
that's also really useful, it will tell you which ones in the last seven days were the most successful, the most engaged with.
You get some stories insights, which is pretty useful, stories
are kind of hard to track, and then promotions, that's ads.
The biggest thing that is going to be able to see
how many followers you got over the last day.
So, today, Monday, we put 10 posts, and I want
to see how many followers we got from 10 posts.
Maybe the next day we do three posts,
and I want to see the difference.
And also, I generally want to see if I'm losing people too, if I'm posting the wrong stuff, if I'm posting too often, not enough,
this is what we can get out of Instagram insights,
although it's a little bit limited, and that's what we're
now going to cover the paid version, Iconosquare.
Iconosquare has been around for
a long time, they're really popular,
and they give you a lot that you can do. That's one of the reasons I'm picking them. Instagram tools pop up and pop down
every other day, it seems like. There's hundreds of
them and they're always changing, like, for instance,
Social Rank was a really popular one for seeing your followers.
They quit doing Instagram.
Great. Mass Followers was another
one that got shut down by Instagram.
That's kind of different, but kind of the same space.
Now, I'm choosing Iconosquare because
of two different things.
One, it's the cheapest for you, cheapest out there, it's only
$7 a month, and two, it's been around for a long time, so
we know it's not going anywhere.
I also like the analytics they give you. Now, Iconosquare
has added a lot of new features to their thing, so it can be
a little confusing if you should pick them over another app,
and there are seriously hundreds of these
apps out there that do the same thing,
it's just a Venn diagram from hell on what everybody does.
It's going to be up to you which one you want to use,
just make sure that they have the analytics that we
cover in these lectures, and that's pretty much it.
So if you post in the Slack, and you ask, "Evan, have you used such and such tool?" I've probably heard of it, but I probably
don't use it, because they're all the same.
So just try it out yourself and see what it can let you do.
I think they're really reasonable,
if you look over their pricing page.
They allow you to use $7/month up until
100,000 followers, which is quite generous. Ok,
so I'm going to sign up, I will just go over, back
to the front page, and click Start a free trial.
OK.
So fill out your information here, and at the bottom
you'll have to fill out the industry, again, kind of
like we did with Instagram business.
Doesn't really matter what type you pick,
I'm just going to put self-employed. Again, it's
for their information specifically. On industry,
I'm going to probably put information technology or education, since we do innovation and it applies to education, IT is probably
the most similar thing to being an internet company.
It doesn't really matter, just hit next. Ok, the next thing
we want to do is we want to connect our social profile.
So make sure that you are logged in in your
browser to Instagram in the right account.
So then all I have to do is hit "Add social profile" and when you click it, it asks you to connect a social profile, so we'll just click Instagram. Ok,
and then you just have to authorize it.
Great.
Now we have our account, and we
can just hit "Start using Iconosquare."
Now, what you see here is, it's going to pop up and give
you some information, if you want to watch some
videos of how to use Iconosquare, but
it takes a while for them to update,
so that you can use it. For whatever reason,
even if you don't have any posts on it,
it just takes like 30 minutes, 45 minutes, so just open
it up, get it going, and then come back to it later.
In the meantime, we kind of look over here at the side.
We have analytics,
we have, that's kind of the bread and butter of what
we're going to use it for, then we have a comment tracker.
That's pretty useful actually, because it allows you
to see all of your comments, likes, and interactions
on your post inside of their app, and then
you can respond to them all right here.
So it's kind of nice to be able to do it on a web browser as opposed to just doing it with your fat thumbs on your phone. Then
it has Media, and this might be useful to you, but it's just royalty free stock images that you can use if you want to post,
I don't really care for that stuff.
I personally like to use Latergram and Buffer for picking my
media and scheduling, which was the next one, Scheduler.
I don't really care about that. Then they
have Search, and that's for researching
other people and other accounts, but also finding a
post that you want to repost, which can be useful, but
again, other tools do it better.
And then you just have Tools, Instagram feed, and discover. Instagram feed tab is not something we're going to use, that's
for people who want to pour over their
Instagram posts to their Facebook page,
we don't really care about that.
Once it's set up, it should look like this, it's
going to give you a bunch of tour buttons,
you can go through these if you want, I don't really care.
OK.
So up here we'll see our total followers, we'll see our total followings, how many people we followed, total likes received, total comments received.
It's going to chart it out, which
is incredibly useful, it's going to show us follower growth, so it's going to show us, are we decreasing in growth, increasing
in growth, that's what we care about. It'll give us
gained and lost, that can be pretty useful, because we want to see the ratio of how many we gain a day versus how many we lose.
Sometimes you post stuff and you're
like, hey, I see people following me,
but you're actually losing them
faster than you're gaining them.
Then down here, it just gives us big totals of how many
we've gotten, it covers our engagement it covers how, down
here, our media lifespan is how each post persists over time,
are we just getting likes upfront, and later on nothing,
or is it actually something that's a little more evergreen.
It'll give you some more account stuff about likes history, comments history, average likes, and stuff like that, it's actually
all very, very useful.
Over here, we have a Competitors tab, what we can do is we can add a competitor that we can track to see how they do on similar ones.
Here's Hashtags,
we'll use that later on when we start doing our advanced optimization of hashtags. Comment tracker is there...
Honestly, just play around with it,
we don't have any posts in this part of the
course, so I wouldn't really worry about it.
It's just more that we got it set up, and now, as we start
posting and as we start interacting, we'll come
back to this, and then it will actually become useful. I just
want to make sure you have it up since the beginning, because
you want the data from the very beginning.
OK.
Now, with that being said, check it out.
If you don't want to pay money, just use Instagram business.
It works pretty well, just not as robust.
If you've got $7 a month, try Iconosquare, it's quite useful.