Hey guys welcome back.
All right we've got another one of those manual's sessions where I'm going to walk you through the user
interface of Instagram.
This time to focus on the sections of the app where you can kind of create your own content.
Really it's more for tweaking your own content but for some people who will be taking videos on their
phone or photos on their phone.
They do have some embedded tools for doing a decent job with that.
So that's we're going to talk about so that you're not clueless when it comes to the interface when
you get into posting actual stuff.
No actually I'm talking about the posting page itself.
So I get that later but we'll get everything up until that point.
OK.
Now if you have an Instagram account and you posted before PLEASE FOR THE LOVE OF GOD this lecture.
If you get bored it is your own fault.
This is for people who are absolute beginners.
I've said this several times.
OK so let's just open it up and ZERO go.
So open up Instagram will do it on both Android and the U.S. So it'll open you up and the library is
optional.
Last photo that you took.
For the most part the user interface kind of the same here.
They call it a library in Iowa.
And on Android they call a gallery.
I don't know if there's a difference.
OK so first things first.
At the bottom you have library photo video gallery photo video.
Well this is for as if you wanted to take an actual photo or an actual video.
So if I wanted to get an actual photo ID photo and look there's my camera with me.
I can do that if I wanted to.
And then I only get a video.
Same thing it just automatically sets you up to record audio and video and the interface is slightly
different.
So there's my cat cool.
And what will happen is after you take the video if you press that button you'll see the timer count
and then you can press it to finish it.
And the same goes for photo.
So let's go back to the library here for a second because no matter what you do if you take a photo
or video it's going to put it in your library.
But it's also going to them and it ex-friends That's all I'm saying.
So here up on this user interface you can tap it and then move it around.
You can see the grid which you have to hold it on iOS There goes to see the grid.
And on Android whatever it just pops up automatically.
That just helps you to understand things like the rule of thirds of we talked about before to see whether
or not you have space.
So right here we have three icons one looks like that infinity sign.
Now what that is is an app for Instagram called Boomerang and Boomerang.
And if you've seen this before it's Doo's animated images that look like just a little bit of motion
is happening and then it happens in reverse the way it works is you will take I think it's four or five
photographs of something in rapid succession and then stitches it together and plays it in a loop.
It's kind of a cool way of adding a little bit of spice to your photos.
We'll talk about it more later on.
I don't consider it generally consider it a large part of your content strategy on Instagram.
It's really cool if you can integrate them and it's a great way of spicing some up regardless it's not
something we're talking about now.
It's a separate app you have to download whatever next one is this little rounded off square section
off and in the sections.
This is called layout.
Same thing actually usually pushes you to a separate app called Lay out.
And what that is it allows you to make photo collages.
So what you can do is just pick multiple images and then select the way that they display and you can
do it with faces you can do it with events whatever.
So with collages it's another way of taking static content making you more interesting.
Let's say you're taking photos of an employee event can be cool to take photos of multiple employees
doing something or one doing multiple things or one in multiple.
Like first step second step third step and then stitch them together like that.
Personally I'm not going to use them because I think that collages are bound for comprehension.
It's harder to tell what's going on because you're starting with a very small reduced size of the image.
Once you slice it up several times it makes it that much harder to see so it's not something that I'm
going to use constantly.
It's not something you see a lot of accounts use but if you can it can be done decently well.
I'm not super optimistic about it though.
Another thing here is select multiple.
And what that does is it helps you make a carousel of images or videos.
So when that happens if I selected multiple It would put them into a list like this.
And then when I share them you'll see an image and what you do is you tap on these little circles at
the bottom and that's how it moves you through the images.
It's like kind of like a slide show but you use it for video.
So you might do that if you took a bunch of photos and it was like in a sequence you could do it that
way.
You also see people who will say which one is better and they'll do a video and then another video and
you can click between the two and then you know talk in the comments.
There's a creative ways that people have done it.
Generally more photos is better than less or fewer photos.
But again I personally to focus on one if I have ideas for multiple do that it good for me it's just
more content to make so I don't really focus on it.
What you can do then after you pick something that you own or you take something that you want as you
just hit next and are in the filter and now filtering works same way for both Android and iOS.
What is you know here is it just up there you click buttons and they apply different color dilations
to it and the they're called LUTs and that helps you add an effect to a photo.
Sometimes you take a photo and it doesn't look great.
So you can add on say the Edan filter and it might make it look retro or hipster or washed out or something
that you might be going for now filters.
Personally I don't use the filters in Instagram because there's so well know they're trademarked that
people can recognize them and they're overused.
So that's not what you want.
You want someone to look at this and go oh they made that in the Instagram app because it just looks
lazy filters actually though.
Interesting story enough are how Instagram got famous.
That's actually how they started is they started putting filters on it.
And that was basically the foundation of the app.
I think it started when the founders girlfriend was talk or was complaining about photos being posted
on Facebook saying that she doesn't post on Facebook as often as you'd like because her photos don't
look that great.
And then he said well we have a friend who posts on Facebook and that's the same thing and she said
well actually that's because he puts filters on his images so they always look good enough to post.
They go a.m. So like I said it's not really something that I personally use.
I also think that there's other apps that you can use that have better filters and will cover some of
those.
If you want to go that route your other options are here.
You can do the Lux Lux's kind of an odd way of saying brightness.
You can kind of tweak it a little bit.
It's not it's not necessarily brightness isn't necessarily like saturation or color but you play with
it you can kind of tell.
It just brings out certain colors and exaggerates the color profiles slightly again.
I mean I don't know it's not really something I generally focus on but if you're someone who's oriented
towards photography in general you can probably make better use of these.
Now there are things you can do is hit edit over here and you can do a lot of options.
You can adjust the photo so you can twist it like this if you want to.
It also zooms in.
Keep that in mind.
You do like that like you're zooming in on something that's an interesting effect.
You always reset it by just hitting that.
Over here when you could use add perspective so perspective basically bloats the bottom of the photo
or the top of the photo.
And that allows you to make it look like it's leaning forward or backward.
So if we want to make it leaning forward I don't really know why you would do this occasionally sometimes
you can make cool effects.
Well I have a sneaking suspicion that no one does this.
This would be the left or right distortion.
You know sometimes you can make somewhat cool effects kind it looks like a poster if you do it slightly
at an angle.
Also sometimes you can make up for bad photography.
Then you can move on there's brightness and it's pretty simple and it's the general rule with brightness
as you don't want to go past a certain point because it just becomes washed out.
We have the same problem with cameras.
The ISO is what it's called.
I don't know that stands for don't ask me but that's a make things brighter.
Typically the more you abuse it though the crappier the image comes out it actually starts to damage
the integrity of the image like the pixelation of it.
So I use that you know sometimes of the photos to dark.
But if the phone is too dark then just retake the photo.
My opinion.
OK moving on.
We have contrast.
OK.
Now this is something that you can play with too and the effect of making it look contracted or uncontracted.
So uncontracted it look kind of like that like it's a little bit duller and more contrast will make
it look like it's really kind of sharp.
I apologize.
The iPhone 10 because the camera is not great with low light as you can tell but that's it.
So there's a term called contrast.
You might see that sometimes sometimes people just put contrasts on everything they do.
And that's you know one way of getting a certain effect through.
Not again a huge fan but you see this on a lot of movies now as they make it contrast.
OK structure.
So its structure is honestly it's kind of hard to explain all the resources like a more technical explanation
of it but structure is it basically allows groups of pixels in the background to look more structured.
So if you structure it then it looks normal but you add structure then it essentially adds more definition
to objects in the back.
So if you had like say a triangle background in the back then if you unstructured it to look normal
the structure you would notice how more defined those shapes wore.
So again it's one of these kind of loose.
I don't really see that you notice this how it's blurry in the background but as you add in structure
it pulls out the brick outline.
So again you can tweak it and play with it but it's not generally something that I think is super useful.
Ok then we're move on warmth.
Warmth is slightly different than brightness brightness just brings up the dark values to lighter values
whereas warmth essentially takes like the yellows and the what we consider like the warm part of the
spectrum and then moves them up into like the orange part of the spectrum I could be wrong on this.
So people were actually photographers could correct me.
But that's what you kind of notice is it'll take like these cool bricks in the back and turn them more
orange.
And if I do like that it turns it more blue.
Very similar to white balance.
Do you guys use cameras.
This makes it cool.
And this makes it warm like tungsten or like daylight's anyway.
And why do you want to do that.
Then we have saturation saturation they time at every saturation is in landscape photos of a landscape
photo up the saturation.
My God it looks amazing and makes you think like I could eat that mountain.
And that's how a lot of companies make their landscape photos look so good.
True story though with air B and B makes their photos look so great is they just jack up the saturation.
That's all they do.
That's what makes the colors really come out.
And that's what saturation essentially means is it just brings out the colors looks like crap and doors
are on.
People don't over oversaturate someone's face a landscape or a building or something like that you can't
go wrong.
OK.
And then we have color.
And honestly we're getting a little bit in the weeds with this one.
But essentially what this does is you have a color spectrum.
Any photograph should have pixels in all these different spectrums of colors from red green blue black
white everything.
So essentially what you can say is like shadows will be the darker end of the spectrum it will take
all the darker end of the spectrum pixels on your screen and then give them a hue or attend to it.
So if you want to give it like a purple hue on iOS then you go on and on and you know like a green or
an android.
Cool.
Same thing with highlighting of the higher end of the spectrum colors attend.
And yeah.
Anyway that's something I never work with but whatever fade is yeah I mean it's just a specific fact
to just kind of doles out the detail of the photo.
How that's different than a lot of the other filters can tell you.
Then we have highlights and shadows.
Now this just is for brightness of highlights and shadows.
People who work in video or photography know that usually you can just up the brightness of the darker
end of the spectrum or the wider end.
So essentially that's what they're trying to do or what you do on those two.
Now vignetting the big netting is when you create an effect that it blurs out on the corners of the
image which kind of has the visual effect of what you're focusing in on something.
So if I go like this.
Notice how it kind of darkens the outside ring it kind of focuses in on the what I'm looking at.
That's that effect.
That one I think you can use pretty well to make stuff make the viewer kind of focus in on the main
thing of your photo.
Then we have tilt shift.
This one is kind of like the vignetting but it allows you to.
As opposed to making it like a circle around it.
You can do radio or linear radio is like a vignette but it's you can I think you can change the area
so you can change where the blurring happens.
So this is on the radio.
I can move this around like say I want to focus on this thing over here I could do like that in blurting
out except for that and that is useful.
I don't know why in a linear it's like the same thing but I can twist it and I can.
Whatever.
OK.
Then the last thing is sharpen OK and then sharpen.
You can guess what it does.
It just sharpens your image.
It's sometimes hard to tell what that's doing OK.
That pretty much wraps it up for the walk through the user interface for filters.
A fax boomerangs collages carousels and everything like that if you want to create your own content
in the actual app that's perfectly fine although I suggest there's better apps out there for filters
and for taking videos and taking photos.
But it's up to you.
They have some cool features in here.
If you want to pay for another one then sometimes you can lean on these and that's perfectly fine.
OK.
Scenics lecture.