Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, so this lecture, what we're going to talk about is
how to get a good looking link in your Instagram profile.
I said this a hundred times, so much of your business and
so much of the point of making an Instagram account
runs through that one singular link that
you're allowed to put in your bio.
And since it's so important,
then the question becomes, how do we optimize that?
Well, that's what we're going to talk about in this
lecture, and there's a couple tricks that you can do.
Now, the first thing I'll point out is that just in general
with landing page conversion, having a link that
looks like the name of your profile
is generally a good thing.
So Innovation Station, if I had innovationstation.com,
I could put that as the link and that is perfectly fine.
It's going to be kind of weird though if I put
a link to something totally not related.
This is similar to the concept of conversion scent,
people just assume that the link is going to
be something similar to the name
of the page that they're on.
So if you're building an account based on,
say, like, a business, OK, then that's great.
You just use your own home page, or more specifically,
you can just slash and then send them to a landing
page or a specific page that's more relevant to what
people might be interested in if they're on their page.
Now, if you're not capable of linking directly to
your home page, then you have some options.
OK.
There are what are known as you URL shorteners.
There's Bit.ly, there's Ow.ly, even Twitter
has their automatic URL shortener.
Basically what that does is you take a URL that you
want to send whoever clicks the link to, and you
give it to them, and they convert it into a chunk
of text basically that most people recognize.
Now, there's a drawback to doing this.
And the only reason why you'd ever do this is if, say,
you wanted to, like, say we're Innovation Station, but
I wanted to link them to like a Udemy page or something like that.
I think it might be a little weird if that was the link,
or maybe even the link name is just too long.
So what I might do is I might use, say, like Bit.ly,
put in the link to that and then I'll get a Bit.ly
code, and I can even customize it so it's says Bit.ly / some
kind of text, we could put innovation station, and that, you
know, there's a little bit of a connection between
the name and the link if I do it that way.
Now, that's not perfect though because a lot of people
associate Bit.ly with spam and all URL shorteners
with spam, because, well, if you were sending me
somewhere reputable, why would you have to hide the
URL, why would you have to use this cloaking link system?
So what we're going to do right now is do what's called
a pretty link, and this is actually a pretty cool technology.
I think this is probably the best thing you can do.
And if it is available to you, I think it's a fantastic option.
So what we're going to do is we're
going to do pretty links, and then
I'm going to show you how to do custom short
links, and those are the two best options I know.
So, the first one is called a pretty link, and a
pretty link is a technology, it's an app that you
can install, and it works with most WordPress websites.
And I feel fine promoting a WordPress app, because WordPress
is something like 27% of the internet. There are similar
apps for other platforms, if you use Shopify,
or Magento, or something like that.
And so what it does is it goes to your website, you
install it, and then when someone goes to your home
page, it will look at the traffic where it's coming from,
and then direct them somewhere else, so what
you can do is just put your home page,
no slash, anything, no Bit.ly slash anything,
and you can have that system automatically direct
them to where you want to go, so you could send them
to a landing page that's unrelated,
and at the same time you can preserve using
the cool link that you have. Now, as a backup,
we're going to cover how to make Bit.ly custom links,
and if you guys have ever seen what I do with my
links, it looks like evankimbrell.com, but it's evank.im
slash, so just visually it looks similar.
OK, so let me show you how to do a pretty link. Let's say
that I was doing a personal account that was related
to Evan Kimbrell.
What I could do here, and I actually use WordPress,
thankfully, is I could just go ahead and go to
WordPress.org/plugins/pretty-link, and
it's a zip file that you just download.
Make sure that you have access to your administration panel, because that's where we're actually going to activate this.
After you download it, unzip it, so that it becomes a
big open folder, and you can read the ReadMe file if
you want to, it just talks a little bit more about how this works.
Then go into your administration panel for WordPress,
just go to Plugins here on the side, and go to Add New.
Ok, then you want to do is, honestly, instead of
searching for the plugin, because it's actually not in
WordPress' installed library, for whatever
reason, you go to Upload Plugin.
So you then go and click on the .zip file that you
downloaded, it only wants to open up in .zip, you open
it yourself, or unpack it, and it just becomes a folder
with a mess of files, then it should say Plugin
Installed Successfully, if it doesn't, then you probably
have to troubleshoot it, and you want to hit Activate Plugin
Ok, cool.
So now what we can do is, were in the Plugins field,
we can go down and find our pretty links.
OK.
So it probably wants you to upgrade to Pro.
That gives you some more options.
I'm not going to do it, just because I'm demonstrating how this works, but I'll show you how it works. Over here on the left side,
it should have added the pretty links we set up,
and then what you have is an option to go to the home page,
right there, and then it shows you what links you've created.
And then we just want to go to Add New Link.
So you just copy in the URL.
In this case, mine is...
This is pretty long, it's just, let's say I wanted to link
to my Udemy user page, and then the pretty
link, you just have to set something for this.
So if it's Instagram, for instance, I just put insta.
Or you could just put whatever the
name of it is that you're sending it to.
So if I'm sending to my idea generation thing, I can say
ideas, something like that, and then essentially what
it does is it creates that subpage, and then
directly pushes people to whatever this is.
So, in this case, I could just say insta, and I'm pretty
sure if you have the Pro version, which, I'm not
going to buy it just for this demonstration,
but they'll allow you to drop this section,
so what you can do is just do your home page.
You can also do this manually, but it's really complicated.
You'd have to probably be a developer or have a
developer do this, set up a script that essentially allows
traffic to come to your page, to figure out
where the traffic is coming from,
and depending on where the traffic is coming from, just
send them somewhere else, it's kind of complicated.
So this is probably your best option. So
I could do this, say insta, go to Create.
OK.
And then I have this, and they give us some
basic link tracking information, which is great.
I can see who's clicking on it, where they're
coming from, if they're sharing it, things like that.
So right now I have that link.
Now what you can do is you can look at it.
Let's say we just wanted to go to that link that we've created.
We'll do that, and there you go.
So it took me to the Udemy page
where it shows all my courses.
Cool.
OK, so that's one option.
Like I said, if you upgrade to Pro, it's like $50 a year,
you can do all sorts of other things, you can make it
so it's just your home page, I believe, and it gives
you a whole lot of other different options, so
you can do things like JavaScript redirects,
which, that's essentially how you do it.
You go to the page and then it
immediately pushes you somewhere else.
This is something I think is pretty useful if you're
going to send them to, if you have a home page and
you want that as your branding, but you want to send
them actually somewhere else, this also works if you're a
personal brand and you have your name as your .com.
OK.
So the other option is to use a custom Bit.ly.
Now, if you don't know what I mean, it's kind of like
this. Generally, when you make a link with Bit.ly, it
just makes something that looks
like bit.ly / something crazy.
But if I wanted to create a custom one, see, I have it
set up that I can be a bit.ly I can be an evank.im.
Now, that's just a visual trick so that if you looked
at that and you were reading something about me,
and you saw my Udemy page, it would look very
similar to evankimbrell.com, it's the next best thing.
Also, it does have a bit of an advantage if you
post this other places, because it's shorter,
you don't have, you don't take up as many characters,
which can be something that you want to conserve
a lot of times in Instagram.
So let's say I wanted to go to, I don't
know, we'll just say udemy.com.
I think I already have a Bit.ly link set up
for my username, so I can say Create,
and there you go.
OK, so now it says evank.im, and it
gives this number, and I could post that.
Now, if I wanted to customize it, I could go down
here and just drop it down, and just put like a 2 or
something like that, something that just doesn't
look out of the ordinary, then I could copy that.
So if I went down...
Hit Save. I could then take
that and go directly to Udemy.
OK.
So the way that you set this up is a little convoluted
and it takes a little bit of time, but I will
show you how you do it.
OK.
So first thing you need to do is figure
out what short domain you want.
Now, it's kind of weird, like, where does .im come from?
I'm not actually sure which one that is,
it's I think an island somewhere.
You know, you can use like, .io, which is Indian Ocean.
You can use .er, which is Eritrea.
Basically every country out there has their dot something.
So it's just a matter of whether or not you can connect all of the available what we call top level domains to your website.
So the easiest way to do this actually is just
to go to domainr.com and they do it for you.
So then what you would do is you would type
in the domain that you wanted to shorten.
So let's just say I will do it for my account,
since I'm going to use that anyway.
So let's say I had innovationstation.com.
And even if I didn't, I'd still use this,
because it looks like my account name.
OK, so then what it does is it goes all the way down and
it tries to figure out what you can do and then what's
available, so if it says available, that's pretty much your best bet.
All the way down here, you can even see like innovation.st,
you'd have to make an offer on that one.
Where is .st? So .st would be... let's see.
So .st is Sao Tome and Principe.
The other options would be .at.
I don't actually know what that one is, we can check.
I believe it's Austria.
OK, so .at domain is the internet country code for Austria.
Ok, cool.
So what I could do is I could try to do this one.
Now, keep in mind, when you buy a domain specifically
from another country, there's two things.
One, they're usually more expensive
than a normal domain, like a .com.
It's not going to be $7 or whatever you get it from Go
Daddy, it's usually like $20-$30, sometimes it can be $50.
And it also can take time.
So if you want, for instance, to get inno.va, that's
the Vatican, and I don't think the Vatican is
super tech savvy, so it might take
some time before you get that one.
So let's say I wanted to do this one, which is
the best available option, so I might as well.
Now, you can buy it at iwantmyname,
you can buy it at GoDaddy.
I usually use GoDaddy,
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to select them.
OK.
So then what my option here is, it's about $18 per year.
And I think that's fine.
So I'm just going to go ahead and buy this,
and we'll just hyper lapse through this.
OK, great, so I paid $12.59 for that domain. I thought
it was going to be more, I guess I got a discount.
OK.
Then what I can do is go back to manage my domains.
Now, if you guys use a registrar that's other
than the ones that are listed, that's fine.
What you have to do is a redirect,
so you have to go and change the name servers from where
you buy it to point to the registrar that you prefer to use.
Just another step and not everybody has to do it.
I personally suggest just not doing it, and just buying
it through one of the ones that are listed, because
not every registrar can buy these
obscure, like, other country domains.
OK, so then what you want to do is go down to find your
domain, and then we're going to go to domain settings.
Now, what we have to do is we have to change the
settings in here and point it towards Bit.ly. In GoDaddy
then, after you get to domain settings, you're just going
to come down here and you go to manage DNS.
Now, what's DNS?
It's just, it's not really worth getting into, but it basically
tells the ICANN, which is the organization
that controls all of the URLs, where to send this traffic, and it's... Whatever, it basically gives control of this to Bit.ly.
So now what we want to do is we want to go down to our A records and we'll see that we have one and it just says Parked.
OK, so what we want to do is we want to edit this
and we want to send it to Bit.ly's IP addresses.
Now, if you just Google it on their website, they'll give it to you,
but you can also just take it from us right here,
so I can say points to that address, hit Save,
and then I can point one more, so now what I can do is
hit Add and go to Type A, and then do their second one.
And then for host, you just add
an @, that just makes it so that's the default,
the TTL is how long it takes for this to refresh,
so it has to update its records publicly.
Usually you just want to make this as soon as possible,
basically, so we can put this even lower than half an hour.
There is a limit though.
I think you can't do it underneath, like,
five minutes or something.
We could just do half hour, that's fine.
Then you'd just hit Save, it should unlock, if it
doesn't work, just hit Cancel and start over.
OK, so now I have two A records pointing towards the
domains that Bit.ly gives us, 67.199.248.12 and 13.
Ok, then what you want to do is go to Bit.ly, and
I just created a new Bit.ly because if you're on the
free version, you can only have one branded domain,
and I don't feel like upgrading to Enterprise.
So then we go over here to that hamburger menu,
then go to Settings - Advanced Settings.
Branded short domain, and then it asks you, or tells you how
to set this up, and these are the instructions that it gave us.
We're not using a subdomain, so don't worry about CNAMES.
And then over here you want to enter your branded domain.
So it was innovationst.at,
that's the closest thing we could get. Then what we do
is we hit Verify Domain, and it depends on whether or
not the records online have been updated.
Sometimes it takes an hour, 30 minutes,
sometimes it's instant, and sometimes it takes 24 hours.
So we'll see. So then I hit yes,
and it says verification pending.
And we just have to come back to this when it's updated,
like I said, it could be 30 minutes, an hour, it
could be a day. I will come back to you very shortly.
All right, guys.
And we are back.
As you can tell, I've aged severely since we last
saw each other, even changed shirts, I think.
OK, so it took actually about 24 hours for my branded
short domain to verify. So basically what it has to
do is when you add it to Bit.ly, it then goes and checks
with the server or the registrar that holds the domain
information that you own it, and that the
settings are set up, and then it connects itself.
So I just had a little bit of difficulty doing it, but the
way you check it, this is actually a little bit tricky,
if you go here and just go to settings, like we did before,
and then advanced settings, you'll actually find out there's
no information about your branded short domains.
I don't know why.
What happens is you have to go over
here actually, to your account name.
So if you click that, then it says Your Account, go to
Manage, and then up here in Branded Short Domains,
you'll see it right here, and it'll say Verified.
If it says Not Verified or Failed to Verify,
you need to click it and then resubmit it, like,
restart the process and it'll ask you to retry it.
I just went and checked my registrar
to make sure that I had to settings right.
It might just be because of GoDaddy it takes 24 hours,
other ones might be faster.
Now, if I want to actually use one of these domains,
which I will, and I'll throw it in my account later,
I go to Create Bitlink, and right here,
OK, so it says innovationst.at, and I can go
back to Bit.ly if I want to, but otherwise I don't.
So then I would put my Udemy account.
So I'd say... Ok.
And then it creates an innovationst.at link.
and if I want to, I can customize this, so I could change
this to something that's not just gobbledygook,
so I could just say innovationst.at and I can say something like course, or learn how, or something like that, we can say learnhow. Ok, and then I hit Save,
and we should be good.
And then what I can do is I can paste this into
my Instagram account, and we should be good.
OK, I'll do that and you'll see that change in the account
whenever we're browsing it later on, depending
on which lectures are filmed first.
But otherwise, that's how you do it.
That's how you pick something that looks customized, and
if you run out of space, just customize the search shorter.
Other than that, you guys should be good.
See you next lecture.