Hey guys, welcome back.
Just wanted to give a quick note on how
to protect your account on Instagram.
Now, one thing that's worth pointing out is that Instagram
heft is a thing that actually happens quite a bit.
You'd really be surprised how many times people get
their accounts hijacked, and then one day they try
to log in, and guess what, some Ukrainian
person took your account. Why do they do that?
I mean, it's just because Instagram as a platform
has more natural monetization to it.
I think that's probably the reason why.
I mean, there are accounts out there with millions
and millions of followers, and all they have to do
is post a photo of a product, that's
a great way to make money.
There's also a pretty lively market for selling accounts,
so a lot of times they steal them and then
just immediately sell them.
So the way you protect yourself against that kind of
theft is actually pretty simple and it really only
comes down to two things.
The first thing is that when you sign up for your main
account, make sure that the e-mail address you
use is an e-mail that people don't actually e-mail you at.
So one of the most common ways someone steals your
account, and really anything, is they get access to
your e-mail address, and that's something you respond to,
and then what they do is they send you a fishing
e-mail, so they keep trying to e-mail you over
and over some type of attachment or,
I mean, there's a lot of different strategies for phishing,
and eventually you screw up and that's how they
get your password and then they log in and they take it.
So in my case, I use an e-mail address
that I have but I don't use it.
Like, it's just a Gmail that's always been there.
I don't usually use Gmail, so someone
just can't guess that one.
The other thing I would say worth doing
is using a password manager.
What I use is I use Dashlane.
I don't really like Dashlane, so I wouldn't suggest it,
but there's other ones like Last Pass,
there's 1password.com.
Basically what happens is they create logins for you,
you can just go to their page and then
tell it to generate a password for you.
That's pretty easy.
And then whenever you log in, you can actually
have it automatically fill that information in for you.
On Android, it's even easier, because in Android you can
save your passwords to your keychain or what they
call, what Apple would call a keychain,
and then you can just log in.
The last thing I'll say is, in the event of someone taking your account, there's only one thing you can do to get it back.
So one thing I always suggest once you actually have set
up your main account is to connect your Facebook to it.
Now, you don't have to post to Facebook, and people on Facebook don't need to know that you have an Instagram,
it doesn't matter.
They don't communicate between the two
unless you explicitly tell it to do that.
The reason why is because when you lose your account,
and you're going to talk to Instagram, and they
notoriously don't care, you can just say, "Guess what?
It's attached to my Facebook, here's my identity.
I can show you that this is my Facebook," and
that is the fastest way to get your account back.
All right, guys, that's all I have on that topic.
Otherwise, I'll see you next lecture.