Hey guys welcome back.
All right.
So got to follow a long lecture.
What we're going to talk about in this fall along with my shoulder is I'm going to update you on my
progress with creating my first 10 posts OK so I talked about this before that you want to get at least
10 posts before you then go forward and start doing some of the growth strategies some of the follow
unfollowed things that we do later on.
So that's kind of the goal the line in the sand that we want to go for I think nine is probably fine
because usually displays three in a row.
But either way that's kind of like the rule of thumb.
So what I want you to follow.
OK.
So you want to me in another lecture create the Nano would video.
And I did that in Final Cut Pro and it took me about about 45 minutes to an hour or something like that.
I had to go back and tweak it.
So I spent about 10 more minutes going back and tweaking it.
And for the most part it works.
I put music in.
I think that's perfectly fine.
But what I wanted to do is standardize my posts a little bit more and you'll notice as I go forward
my posts are going to evolve and to get more polished they're going to get more consistent.
I'm kind of experimenting a little bit with it right now and that's one of the big benefits of using
for instance like the dummy account.
OK it's a little bit of an update what I've been doing is I've been using Dropbox to store all of my
photos and videos for posts.
And then I've been cataloguing them with a number right next to them.
OK.
So that's just for later on when we get to bringing in people to help us automate this.
Then we can just use code.
So if it's a video I can say for for video subscription video the five urpmi if I want to go to the
photos.
OK.
So that's pretty useful for just keeping track of stuff it also gives you a good easy way to take a
glimpse and see how much I have done so I can see whether or not the trough is full and I can start
posting or whatever.
All samples are a more complicated process.
Moving on later on in the lectures.
But for now I just got to get my 10.
So this is a pretty good preliminary structure now where I've been getting my content before I talked
about it a little bit.
But spring wise is probably the biggest one.
I sucked it up and has paid for a subscription.
Before that I was using their daily update emails because they do a curation of.
They select some of the technologies they like.
I've also been getting them from Mashable too because they've attacked in science section and they often
just have some quirky weird thing that has just come out.
So I've been flagging some of them there.
Most of using Business Insider.
Because they do the same thing over here in tech and you can also find some of them in life.
And between those three I found more than enough and I've started writing some of them down.
But I took some of the easier ones and then I just started going through the process of putting them
together.
I've been leaning a little bit more on images over video into my videos.
Right so my content strategy I'm sorry was going to be mainly videos and I'm going to try photos but
I was kind of pessimistic about how those are going to perform.
I think they're good as fillers.
So for videos I think that's going to be the gold standard.
And I think that's what I'm going to try to make most of my content out.
So if you see the intelligent jacket.
So this is one made it works pretty well right.
And this is an image and then it should cut to a video.
Yeah right so it's a video.
What I've been running into is just that when I cover something it's a question of whether or not I
want to use stock footage that's not very relevant but it's video which is more engaging or do I use
an image that's directly relevant to the company in the product and it's just not as engaging the way
I've been kind of getting around it it's just using more images but doing more of these like zoom motions.
I showed you to do that before in Final Cut Pro.
There's other really easy ways to do it there's even apps that do it for you.
So that's kind of what I've been doing.
Now you'll notice that the text on here is different from the Nano would one.
So if you pull up the Nano would see the new movie that was that one.
OK so I've been just trying different things out.
So what I did was this is what I first started with.
It was a little generic and I didn't think it fit the colors of my count so I actually just reach out
to a designer who have worked with before in the past.
If you ever see the become a product manager intro scene he did that.
He's helped with a lot of the promos.
And so we put together a set of templates for text that kind of have similar animations like this.
And that's kind of setting the stage for later on when I start to mass produce these.
But this will help me keep consistency with my posts and also just a little bit sharper.
You can see it kind of does this like outline then it pops up and then I kind of used a similar transition.
I can't remember the name of my head but see how it changes like it's like a flare.
It turns the next one.
I just liked it because it put the purple color in there and that's really useful because it matches
again my colors.
So if you want to do templates we're going to talk more about this.
But I just found this person on video Pixi a long time ago on one of my project video Pixi is just a
standard freelancing Web site but they dedicate themselves to videos.
So what I had done before was just asked to create a bumper to bumper is just a little three to five
second segment that shows at the very beginning of video and then at the very end because of like bumpers
on each end and you see them on YouTube all the time.
And so I just started working with that person so it worked out fine.
But if I wanted to find a new person I could just do that again and just post it again.
And I think we worked out a deal for $300 to do that plus an outro to the outro will look like this
when I actually get it working.
Now I say outro because it's going to pop up the very end.
So has that same kind of flash.
And then as a call to action and as a rocket it turns into the logo that rocket drives me nuts.
But we're working on that and eventually we'll get to a point where it doesn't look like it's a South
Park cartoon anyway so I think that will make kind of the branding part of this a lot easier and will
pop up and it will be a lot more useful now for the photos.
All I've done is just been using Draney quote.
So Draney Colo.
And then I just go to this and I type in innovation and I've been making these very quickly on Kanva.
So I want to get to my 10 quickly so I can just get a move on and start testing things out.
And so this is a one easy way of kind of filling in some of the gaps.
Right so I put this one by Steve Jobs and this one by Dean Kamen we made this one and one of the lectures
that Dean common one but these two and I'll probably make a couple more.
What I want to do with my lay out is do one photo two videos and then have the photos in the middle
so the middle section so it kind of actually looks like a visual pattern.
That's what I'm shooting for.
So right now I have two images and then I believe the readthrough seven are completely finished.
So I have seven and I probably need two more videos.
And then one more photo.
Right.
And then I should be able to post my 10.
And I've been just doing these in Final Cut Pro the templates that I'm working with were in what's called
after effects.
And I think later on when we get to automation We'll cover that a little bit like how if you have an
after effects template it's kind of obscure.
I mean there's a lot different ways someone can make a template for you.
So yeah I mean this is pretty much it.
I've been writing all of my content here in Bear.
So for the Nano would we sell that one before so like high moment.
So if you wanted to watch high moment this one.
So looks like this.
It's an app that I guess is for people posting things that they're grateful for and so used a lot of
the assets from the company itself.
But for the captions I had to write them out right.
So I just went and read about it and then I just kind of figured out what I wanted to say and a series
of six captions and then I'm kind of experimenting with different types of captions.
So there's about 100 words I'm trying to give a more like a bigger picture of what it is and not trying
to go too in-depth with this but I don't want to be the person who puts one sentence and the last thing
was a call action and this is going to be a total experiment till the last video in the entire course
because you just have to figure out what works.
So I think do you think an app can change a person's mood.
I think it's sufficiently broad enough that enough people will say yes or no.
OK.
Yes I've been doing that and then with the photos what I think I'm just going to do is put the top five
interesting facts about the person who post who made the quote and I put that into the full caption
to the actual caption.
Try that out.
See how it works.
We will know as soon as we get past our tenants are posting consistently.
But for now that's where I'm at.
I'll tell you guys later on when I get my test done.
And then in the posting section you can watch me put them all in.
OK.
Talk to you later.