Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's chat about the best practices when we make images.
Hopefully, the creation process is pretty straightforward.
We have templates and tools.
We know the composition patterns that most people
use, and, guess what, it really is not that hard.
If you're shooting your own photos, then
OK, that's a little bit harder.
OK, first thing, do you know what the rule of thirds is?
OK.
The rule of thirds applies to images or movies,
basically everything all the time,
and it focuses on where in the photo you should
have your subject, or let's just say the points
of interest, at. If you were to divide a photo into three
columns and three rows, and then look at it, it
would look like a grid system, would look like this. For
whatever reason, human potato brains and eyeballs like to
always see things aligned with the guidelines in
the photo, meaning in a position that intersects with
one of these lines. Images with compositions that are slightly askew like this for whatever reason just look more natural to us.
Now, why is that?
It's not really worth getting into.
It has something to do with your brain and how it
processes information and matches it to your vision.
So if you have something of interest, whether it's an
illustration, or a person, or a funny looking flower,
place the things you're supposed to be
focused on on one of those third lines.
So, let's say you're taking a shot of a person,
put them slightly to the left or the right.
If you're shooting a landscape, put the horizon
slightly above or below the middle of the photo.
I don't know, it's basically black magic, and if you ask
me to go into more depth in the questions, I'll
probably lose it and delete the course.
The next tip is to always add your logo
or at the very least a watermark.
The logo will reinforce your branding,
make your account more memorable,
make it look like you're standing by your content,
which implies that your stuff is probably better than
the average junk in your feed,
and so people can't just steal your work.
Or, let's say, easily steal your work.
You can put it in the bottom corner if you want,
or directly below, or just central aligned
with the bottom of the photo.
These are the most common spots.
Usually, it's best if you use the same spot,
but I realize sometimes that's hard.
That's perfectly fine. If you want to add a watermark,
it's really quite simple.
Alright, guys, got it? Pretty easy to do and will
make you look quite a bit more professional.
Now, the next tip is to always, always,
always use high resolution anything.
Low resolution photos or even medium resolution
photos just do not work on Instagram.
It's the most obnoxious faux pas or mistake accounts
can make, it just turns people off, it looks awful. So if
you have an image and you love it, but it's not very large,
then just give it up.
Drop the bone.
It's not going to work.
Last thing I'll say, and I'm not sure how
necessary this is to say even, but here goes.
People hate stock photos.
I don't know if I've said this already,
but I especially hate them.
They're stuffy.
They're fake.
Unless you're posting them specifically
as a joke, it's not really going to work.
And this is why we have things called unstock
photos and why they are so important.
A stock photo is a perfectly population representative
multicultural group standing in a nameless boardroom
grinning at each other like they just heard a joke that was
kind of funny but they also secretly detest each other
underneath the surface. Unstock photos look more
like someone took a shot of an actual setting
while the subject wasn't paying attention - you know,
stuff that actually looks like photographs.
Got it?
OK, rule of thirds.
Put things of visual interest on one of those intersecting
lines as if you were to divide the photo into thirds.
Put your logo or at least a watermark on it to prevent
people from stealing it and make it look better.
Always use high resolution photos, and please, for
the love of God, please stop using istockphoto.com.