Hey guys, welcome back.
All right, so in this lecture we're going to talk about the
three main types of content that's on Instagram.
Now, if you ever used Instagram, you can probably
guess what we're talking about. First type it's the good
old fashioned images and that's what they started with.
The second we have is video, relatively new, and the
third one is what they call stories - and yes, there
are two other types, but they're kind of minor,
and we'll get to those later.
Specifically, I'm talking about boomerangs,
which I kind of consider a subset of photos,
and then you have live, which is very similar
to Facebook live, except it's on Instagram.
Really no difference there.
So, first of all, everyone knows what
I mean when I say photos or images.
This is how Instagram started and it's the backbone of
their system, and it's what people are most used to.
It wasn't actually until 2013, I think, that Instagram added
another type of media other than photos, which
was videos. Now, images are relatively straightforward and they're easy to create and store. When you're creating content,
photos typically have a better shelf life, as in they stay
relevant, can be reused, and get engagement
longer after you first made them.
We have a lot of tools for making these. In this course
specifically we're going to use tools like Canva,
Photoshop, then we're going to use a tool by Buffer called
Pablo, as well as there's some mobile apps that let you
make images on the go, if that's your thing.
It's also worth noting the vast majority of
accounts are actually just images only,
and that's just because in general they're way easier
to make. Video requires a little more know-how
and it might include some nice equipment if you're going
to be filming your own stuff. When you get tired of images,
we have our second media type, which are videos. Now,
videos on Instagram look just like an image, but they
have the little, kind of like a play button,
but it's a camera icon, up in the top right,
and they only last maximum 60 seconds,
although there are some workarounds,
if you really want to get them longer. Unlike Facebook
video though, when you're on the profile page at
least and you scroll, these don't auto play, which means,
thank God, when you get a view you know it's an
actual view from a human and not a scrolling zombie.
Now, the 60 second rule with video is
a blessing and at same time it's a curse.
When you limit yourself in time, it can be easier for
you to produce enough content to keep your feed
fresh and moving along,
and also, hey, it used to be 15 seconds,
so at least count your blessings there.
But 60 seconds can be frustrating if you're trying to, say, show clips of an interview or something a little more substantial.
Instagram generally though is not
the place for that kind of stuff
anyway, it's designed for quick consumption, it's not nearly
as bad as Twitter but it's not Medium or Quora.
The last type of content you need to concern yourself
with are stories. Now, stories are, I guess, relatively new.
I think Instagram added them in August of 2016, and
they're a really original and innovative way to completely
copy Snapchat without even trying.
No, but seriously, this was a thing that Snapchat first
came out with, the idea was that you could stitch
together photos and videos that you're taking throughout
the day and then present those publicly to your
friends, and you didn't have to send
them to anybody, like on Snapchat,
you could just view them at your own leisure. And Instagram basically saw that, they're like, "Well, that's nice.
We'll just do that."
And now we have stories, which admittedly
were actually a pretty good addition to Instagram.
They're actually more successful on
Instagram than they were on Snapchat.
So how should we think about the
three options that we have here?
Well, the idea is that you should
plan this kind of like a diet.
How much video should you have versus images or stories?
If you look at big advertisers and big accounts, let's
look at National Geographic, or ESPN, or even
BuzzFeed, you'll notice that they
have a similar posting pattern.
Usually it's like a 2:1 ratio, you usually
see two images per one video.
Now, some might be completely different,
depending on what they're going for.
Like, The New Yorker is about 8:1 images to video,
they're a written magazine, whereas Tasty,
you know, that site that makes those really
addicting recipe videos, part of BuzzFeed I think,
well, they're going have a lot more videos.
They have 9:1 videos to images.
Now, what does planning for differentiation matter? Because, well, engagement. I'm going to say that a lot - because engagement.
Engagement is the number of likes, views,
and comments on each post you make.
Engagement has a profound snowball effect.
If you use more engaging media, you'll get more engagement, which tells Instagram's algorithm to bump you
up, and then the cycle continues.
Now, it used to be the case that Instagram would promote posts generally just based on the engagement on the singular post,
but recently they shifted to promoting posts by virtue
of the average engagement of the account as a whole,
plus a little bit of the photo.
So if you want to benefit from this, then you need to keep what you're doing fresh. While it's completely counter-intuitive,
be aware that different media gets treated differently.
Videos actually get watched 40% more just
because, hey, it's a video, let's try it out,
and that's kind of a strong impulse
whenever you're scrolling.
But images get 37% more likes.
Now, why is that? Well, probably because people don't
finish videos, and the call to action in the video to
get them to engage is often lost on the user or
lost in the video, because they quit too early.
So what does that mean for you?
Well, when we get to videos, we're going to focus on
videos that are shorter and thus stimulate the attention
span that you're more likely to see on a photo.
The goldfish attention span.
What about stories though?
How does the use of stories, for instance,
mix with the other two types?
For those of you that are new to this, they show up at
the top of your search, your feed, and your... God,
I swear, it's pretty much everything,
they're trying to put them in
everywhere you go. They only show up
though for people that already follow you,
so they aren't used directly to get
new followers and grow your account.
So if they don't grow your account exactly,
then why do we still use them?
The answer is yes, of course,
I mean, they don't directly grow it, but they do indirectly
grow your account. Stories solicit engagement
from your follower base, which increases the
likelihood that they go and then look at other stuff
on your profile and become regulars on your posts.
That essentially rubs the Instagram algorithm in
the belly, which is where it likes it, and voila, you
suddenly get more attention.
The key here is that the variety is the spice of life.
Try not to be an account that only does one type or the other.
The more you mix it up, the more people will engage with
the account, the more your account gets promoted.
It's just a happy little cycle.
So think to yourself, how much time and
investment are you putting into this?
If you can and are willing to try some stuff out,
then videos will really help your account grow.
Now, they don't have to be professionally shot, and
to be honest, you can just stitch together photos that
you have with animations to make videos, or you can even borrow video from other accounts or elsewhere, like YouTube.
These are all things we're going to show you in
this course. Now, stories aren't worth ignoring,
but they do take a little more know-how to pull off
correctly, so it's generally something I suggest
you keep in the back of your head,
watch some stories from your favorite accounts to see
what exactly they do, and know that we'll kind of
circle back to them later on in the course, when we're
a little bit more advanced, especially when we're
assuming that you actually have some followers.
All right, guys, that's it. We're going to
be moving on to the next lecture.
Comments, questions, post in the Slack.
Peace out.