Hey guys welcome back.
All right.
Well that's what we did is we talked over workflows identifying the step by step process you take to
make your post.
Everyone has one.
And if you've gotten to this part in the course and you haven't yet figured out what you consistently
do over and over again.
Well it's about time that you start to figure that out.
Now we went over the workflows that I have and I kind of showed you the step by steps that I go to.
And you don't have to do it and that level of granularity but I think it helps now that we have a workflow
written out.
It's really easy to just look at it and see whether or not it's overly complicated.
If it doesn't have enough detail if there are parts in here that we're not very good at if there are
parts in here as well that you kind of wrote something generic so maybe you said put music OK.
That's something I see all the time.
Well where do you get your music.
What actual criteria do you use to select your music.
So just check it over and make sure that it actually has the level of detail that you want.
And you think that it doesn't really leave anything out.
But it's not overly complex you don't need to say.
And then you type this key or take this word or click this screen just do it in two actual like actions.
Now what we want to do is we want to break down our tasks into unique task groups.
Now the best way I can kind of explain this is kind of like a production line like let's say we buy
a phone at Best Buy.
There are a lot of people who touch that phone in the supply chain before you buy it.
And every single person in that supply chain has different skills and qualities and also cost points.
So usually you have the designers who design it.
Then you have people who work with procurement and manufacturers to make it.
Then you have packaging and packaging and then you have sales for people who make ads and make it easy
for instance informational packets that go in it and then you have people who work with distributors
to solve your transportation and you have retail and obviously skipped a couple in there.
But our process is really not that different.
Right.
So typically let's say with a photo post I have to figure out well enough to find a quote.
OK.
That's research.
Then I have to find an image to put on it.
And that's again kind of just research.
I mean it's very like an administration task pretty easy.
You don't be good at looking at photos to find that one.
Then all I have to do is write a caption for it when I list out tough facts.
And that's again just research.
It's a really easy one to do.
Then I am the actual task of posting it on to later gram or on to Instagram and then putting in things
like the mowgli's and the hashtags now hashtags might take a little bit more skill someone who's used
to a tool to figure that out.
But for the most part these are all things that can be done by like a virtual assistant.
So in that I see really only two different skill sets that are needed.
One is research finding an image finding a good quote and then finding the facts for the captions and
then administration is essentially then just following a set process putting things together and doesn't
require a lot of critical thinking.
But on the video workflow now it's a little bit different.
Now we actually have to bring in other skill sets and we actually have other task groups that can only
be finished by one person the designer of the phone probably can't do the manufacturing manufacturer
probably can't do the packaging and packaging person probably doesn't know how to sell it on the floor
of Best Buy.
So for this I just need to isolate it down by the skills needed.
So what I would say is one two three and four.
These are all research right.
Like you actually have to think about them a little bit have some kind of sense of what's interesting
and what might fit with your brand that's a little bit outside the scope of an administrator than just
market as a separate group.
So unbury can just click that button down there and then I can market like that.
OK so that's one grou then what I'll do is just put a little space here and I'll divide them off by
just adding a line break line separator right there.
OK.
Then what do we have to do.
Then we have to write five captions with one that sends them if to write 100 full captain plus a call
to action.
And then I have to do a short description of the video for each continent.
So what do I have to be able to do in order to do these four things.
Well the first three I have to be someone who's comfortable or good at writing.
Case or a writer has to do those now running on a short description of a video.
That's not nice.
You don't have to be a good writer to be able to look at a caption and say you should probably show
the companies app if you're talking about a feature in the app.
That's probably something that's a little bit more like Administration but it is something that the
writer could possibly do especially because they're involved in the process.
They wrote the caption and they probably had something in their head when they wrote it so I can mark
this as a separate task group.
OK.
And then I'll separate this off again.
Then we have searching stock videos and YouTube suitable clips that match those descriptions creating
a Dropbox folder and then then you essentially start opening up your apps.
Now the first one.
Nine and 10.
These would be something that's like Administration or research Asgari someone who can find clips based
on a criteria.
Now your criteria are always going to be things like high resolution right.
Or something that works and a square resolution or something that just makes sense and doesn't look
bad and doesn't look raster ised.
Each person has a different content process.
They probably have different criteria but that's in general the rough sketch guidelines.
So I can actually identify this as a separate task group because anyone can actually do this.
So what I'll do is I'll just mark this separately OK then next up we have a set of things you have to
do in a video editing player.
And these are not necessarily hard things to do because you're using templates and you're adjusting
things and you're just trying to clip out pieces of the clips to find the best usable pieces pre-selecting
music and adjusting for timing and things like that.
But for the most part these are all things that an editor would know how to do.
Couldn't go to a random person and say do this because they wouldn't actually know how to do it.
Especially like working with the text templates it's somewhat complicated.
So I would say that this is a separate task group OK.
And then the last set of stuff is really just kind of an administration task.
I mean it's just really basic stuff like adding in tax it's early been written.
You're right it's going to be a writer adding in hashtags.
Now that's depends how you do your hashtags right.
If you've pre made them you have a list of ones to rotate through.
Then you know they don't have to do anything as well but this whole section right here this is all this
administration.
So what I'll do is just mark this separately.
OK so what I have is five separate task groups write one up here.
Is it easy.
Yes it's easy to do but it's probably best for someone who understands the brand and probably has some
basic research skills.
The next one is probably best for someone who's comfortable writing.
It's not generally in the range of something that anyone could do.
Like a hundred characters for a full description that can get pretty old if you're someone who doesn't
like to write.
Then we have some basic stuff here like research.
Now you have to have some sensibilities on how to pick certain clips but really I mean it's just a task
with minimal training you can figure out.
Then we have task that editors can do and another set of tasks that are really kind of in the administration
range.
So the next thing I think you do after you separate these out is just have a good think to yourself
what are you good at and which of these tasks just take too long.
OK.
Because at the end of the day if you're constantly stuck doing let's say 10 posts a day and you're doing
the same task over and over again that you're not confident you're good at or they just take you an
inordinate amount of time you're going to burn out and you're never actually going to reach the goal
of growing your account to what you want it to be.
So for instance the things that I enjoy doing on this are literally just the first one.
I like reading the stories and saying this is interesting and I'm good at connecting it to the brand.
Now writing the captions.
Personally I hate doing it but I can do it quickly and then things like searching for stock videos that's
just a drudgery.
I don't generally enjoy doing that.
There's nothing fun doing now and then putting them together.
I mean that's just a manual assembly process.
There's no real creative touch involved.
So I'm not a huge fan either.
And then there's stuff I'm generally terrible at.
I'm terrible at Administration and organizing things and stuff like that.
So really this is the only one that makes sense for me personally to do.
But what do you guys out there will probably want to do a lot of this and that's perfectly fine.
Now just do that for yourself so that you know going forward.
There's some of these things that are going to focus on getting someone else to work on more so than
other task groups.
The next thing I want to do is just go to a Web site called Trello.
So travel looks like this once you log in.
Basically the way this works is you have what's called a board and in your board you can list off task
and you can list them off in a linear process like a step by step process.
Now they will make more sense when I show you it.
So go over up here in the top right to us and we're going to create a new board add your board titles.
Also it's the Instagram demo.
OK and then you could pick some whatever colors you want.
OK.
And then this is basically what it looks like now the way they set it up is you have cards and you have
lists a list is where you're going to store individual tasks and then you'll move them from list to
list as the State of the task changes.
OK so we went back to our process flow we could say that the first one is picking stories right.
So we could say picking a story and then we could say writing captions
that we can do gather media and then the last thing assemble video and then ask Gadgil slash post.
OK.
So what we have here is that five step process that we just kind of designed over in our little text
app.
So first you pick a story and you write the captains for it then you gather suitable media for the video
then you assemble that they are with the media adding the text from the captions and then you schedule
and post it.
That is the rough process right there.
Now you can break these down quite a bit more.
You can make it way more granular and you could say writing video captions and have a separate one right
here that says writing full caption and then how you can even do has a call to action writing the full
caption and we can go writing a call to action
but it's really up to you how granular you want to get.
My tip is that if it's a task group and one person does it in one sitting in one go then you don't need
to do this because there's no point of them coming in and updating this constantly if it's nothing's
changed and they're not passing after another person.
Now the person who gathers media for video needs to know what the captions are before they can work.
Person assembles the video needs the media for they can do then the person who post needs to finish
post.
So there's no point having these intermediary steps like this.
Generally that's something I don't do.
Get rid of that.
OK.
Now a card represents the actual work that you need to do.
And so if I actually had a story I could say we put it here and we would say that those that vibrate.
Goal.
OK.
There's these headphones that you don't put in your ear yet you put them on your head.
And that's called bone conduction headphones.
So you hear the music but it's not in your ears.
It's totally bizarre.
Something I'd probably cover.
OK.
There you go headphones that vibrate skulls.
So if I were the person who was picking a story because I've isolated myself with that I would be filling
this out.
I would be going onto the Web sites or wherever I've identified in my sources and in my workflow finding
notes and then filling them up here.
Then the question is do you want to write the captions if you want to write the captions.
OK then you can collapse these down together.
Be picking a story writing captions into one list.
Do you want to get into the media.
You could do it again if you wanted to assemble the video.
You could do it again.
You could also just use this as a organizational tool.
Right.
So if I have say 10 different stories.
Six 10 then I can very quickly look at this even if I'm only working alone and see exactly where I am
in the process.
So let's say you know we have some that are still waiting on captions that have captions just waiting
for Media and then we could say like we a bunch and assembling the video like that.
OK.
So I can look at this and go oh wow see the train is working perfectly but we have a bottleneck right
here and nothing is ready to post which could be a problem depending on how many times you posted that
day and what your goal is.
Now the rest of the things in Trello that you can use that are useful for this process are just things
like for instance you can click the card right here and it gives you a lot of different things so you
can put individual notes on it so I can take notes to myself here.
I want to you can also edit the description.
So for instance if I'm picking a story I might put the link here and I'll put a description of the link
here so link link.
I can also if I'm working with other people I can tag them by putting it at and selecting their name.
No one's in this group yet but I wanted to I could I'm to things like putting labels on them.
Right.
So let's say one is a photo and one's video I can make green for photos so you can change this two photos.
And then we can make yellow two videos and then what I can do is just go through and then and tag each
one.
If that information is actually useful to you at a distance it could be especially if for instance you
want to post three videos a day and two photos while you can look over here and see what's close to
the end of the pipeline and it might be the case that there let's say all photos that could be a problem.
OK so that's the basics of what's called a con on board and Trello is free forever.
I don't know if they charge for stupid things like putting stickers.
So it's a very popular tool that you can use yourself if you just want to keep track of your projects
and you want to be able to look at it very quickly and see where in the process you are.
It's a great way to remind yourself oh right I need to put the video together for eight to nine and
four.
It also is incredibly helpful if you start adding people or you add them just going over show menu and
then you get an invite and you just type in their e-mail address.
And then when they're added they themselves can actually move things.
And you can notice down here on the activity feed what's happening if another person moves something.
So I say gather media over here.
I moved seven from gather media to assemble video.
OK so that's the basics of setting up Trello and getting ready to design a more efficient content pipeline
whether or not you do this yourself is totally up to you.
It really depends on whether you think you're good at it whether you're enjoy it and whether or not
any of these tasks take you a long time.
Some of the tasks in here take me a long time assembling the video.
Some people are just better at that than I am actually gathering media as well.
But picking a story I think that's something I enjoy and I think I'm actually good at so some other
person probably would actually struggle with doing that.
So generally I focus on that but again find other preferences I might do other parts in this pipeline.
OK.
Next a lecture of what we'll do is we'll jump into the pipeline that I've been using to create post
and then you can kind of see a more specific way that I've set it up.
All right see you then.