Hey guys welcome back.
It's in this lecture we're going to do is we're going to talk about competitions and competitions are.
Well they're Xacto to sound like but it's where you give away something like a prize in return for your
users doing something like making a post or participating in some way writing a comment an essay.
Who knows.
And then there's obviously some type of judgment to that.
Now the most common ways you see this are bigger brands and this is why something I suggest for a company
accounts business accounts or sometimes personal accounts if you already have a lot of followers.
Oftentimes what it is is I'll ask you to post a photo and it's related to your theme.
Now they're relying on you to post that and to tag the same hash tag and it's just a way of kind of
generating buzz and ideally if they get a lot of posts they can try to get press for that or at a minimum
they can leverage your own network because you've now posted it not only to others on their hashtags
but to your followers as well.
But of course it doesn't have to be a photo.
I've seen it in a lot of different ways.
I've seen people do impromptu videos.
We'll just ask them so I saw one that was giving away money for scholarships so they didn't ask people
to just talk into the camera and say why they needed the money.
And that was something that was pretty easy to use.
And then they just said you know we will judge it or we'll have the community judged the best one.
Now generally speaking the best practices for how to run competitions.
So you make sure that whatever it is you're giving away or how you run it is in line with your brand
style and essentially your brand behavior.
If you're a luxury brand it doesn't really make sense to run a competition for a very low prize amount
where you ask people to do something that has nothing to do with what you actually stand for.
Every brand generally speaking has a motto or has some type of values that you associate with it.
And so the better they tie that into their competition the more likely it's going to be a success.
You know that you have to remember people are going to see this competition and as a side effect they're
going to build affinity for your brand and also as a side effect they potentially could become more
interested in you and follow your account.
So if you do something that's completely out of line with your brand anyone who ends up following it
isn't going to be following it for the right reasons and you're not building a real following.
The second best practice I've kind of identified is that you need to make sure that the ask from your
followers is something that they would have done anyway.
Right.
So if you asked them to share about something they would find annoying.
That's pretty useful because that's actually something they might share on their own.
If you're a shoe brand and you ask people to write a haiku about their shoes it's probably not something
that's going to be very common.
And so people aren't going be raring to go to do that.
On the other hand if you're a basketball brand it's very easy to ask people to post clips of them playing
basketball because typically if you're playing basketball and your own Instagram you probably have some
clips of you playing it.
Anyway back to the example in The Last Lecture meant.
Did that competition or I said please post a photo that's associated with some kind of financial success
in your life.
Well that obviously makes sense because if someone for instance paid off all their college loans.
That's something that they would have shared anyway.
Right.
So by aligning themselves with that they kind of lowered the friction in order to get more people to
participate.
So there's an example there's a magazine called the magazine.
I think in Dallas Texas and they're just a lifestyle and city magazine for Dallas yet what they did
is they asked people to post the hash tag stay cool Dallas and then they asked them to show how they
are staying cool in the summer heat.
Now it's on again.
It works with their brand right.
Because they're trying to promote a lifestyle so they're trying to show how the people in their space
live.
And the second thing was that they made it align with something they would have done anyway.
People want instagram post all the time if they're like it's really hot and they're at a pool.
Another best practice with competitions is that you use your own hashtag.
Now this is pretty common.
And the reason why is because they want other people who are not necessarily going to submit something
to your competition to be able to go and view what's already been submitted.
And since Instagram has the ability to create hashtags on pretty much anything it works out pretty well
so it ends up happening is you pick a hashtag that's not currently being used.
And then you kind of take that over.
Typically speaking you'll make it something that's very specific to your brand or your name.
And that's another way of kind of getting your name out there if someone sees that this hashtag is trending.
OK well it's got your name in it.
There you go.
That's an added benefit.
Generally speaking with hashtags there's only a couple rules if you're going to make your own.
You usually want to make sure that it's something that's short.
It's memorable.
It's vailable and it's something that's language universal short obviously makes sense you know want
some insanely long piece because people are less likely to post it as a hash tag because it just looks
tacky.
Memorable obviously makes sense because you're banking on other people telling friends about it or pointing
it out to other people.
The harder it is to remember the less likely that's going to happen.
Universal obviously makes sense because you don't want to use a region specific slang or use a language
or terms that no one in your audience group is going to understand.
And then obviously available kind of goes without saying you don't want to post something that's memorable
short and universal but it's being used by other people for other things besides ends up happening is
people will go to that hash and they'll get confused as to what's going on.
They'll think it's somebody else who's running it.
And also it's just going to lower the quality of that hash tag searchers because they can see other
people posting who are not in line with what they're supposed to be telling.
So how exactly do you set these up logistically.
Well generally speaking you want to start by having a prize then you have to have an ask and then you
have to spend a decent amount of time putting specifications as to what they have to do in order to
enter the price is.
And then the last thing is that you need to make sure that there is a start and end date and then it's
very clear generally out front you have decide what it is that you to give away that you're going gonna
have to decide are you gonna try for some type of UGC strategy with your ass caps on post something
or are you going to ask for just some type of participation.
Maybe you'll instead ask them to repost your giveaway post or tag friends or like and comment on as
many photos as they can on your account.
The point is you just need to decide what it is that's in line with your brand your goals and has to
be useful to your account in some way.
Keep in mind if you want to do a competition say based on whoever does the most of something like Who
likes the most photos or comments on the most photos people can and will abuse that and so that's just
something I kind of keep in mind.
If you guys saw our Instagram live give away.
I had people tag their friends and whoever tagged the most and got an answer correct was the one who
won.
You notice very quickly people figured out loopholes.
They started tagging other people in the live chat and that obviously doesn't count.
But that was obviously my fault not specifying that if you for instance whoever likes the most photos
or whoever gets the most likes on their own post.
Just keep in mind there is a lot of tools out there.
You pay $2 and get a couple hundred likes.
Similarly if you're going to judge it by saying hey we're just going to decide what the best one is
the community is not going to decide.
Well then you need to make sure that you specify what your criteria are it's not generally enough just
to say we're going to decide what's the best you're going to say we're going to judge you based on creativity
originality and relevance.
I don't know.
Keep that in mind.
The more you specify the less people will have to complain.
But also some you always have to keep in mind is that people will always find something to complain
so it's just a matter of minimizing the gaps in what you say you're going to do and what people expect
is going to happen.
The last comment I'll give about competitions is what do people generally give away on them.
Well generally speaking it can be a lot of different things.
Gift cards are pretty popular.
Giving away your product is extremely popular.
If you have money to spend.
Giving away a flight or a trip is also very very popular.
That's something that generally will get a lot of participation.
Of course you have to remember it always has to tie in to your goals.
You can't just be lazy and say we're going give away $50 in cash because you're going to be attracting
people for the wrong reasons.
Sure you can give away a trip for $2000 but unless your account is a travel account or year you cover
media events and they're going to that specifically or some way you can tie in a location to what you
do.
It's kind of a waste and you run the potential of just kind of swinging and missing.
All right guys that's enough about competitions as you notice is not something that we do on innovation
station.
It's too complicated and in general we're not a large enough account to make it work.
High threshold contests like this are not going to get a lot of participation.
And if you don't have a large account yet then you know your odds of reaching that critical mass where
it's actually interesting how many submissions you have.
Well you know you're just going to fall flat right next October to talk about something that's way more
accessible and something we do actually do an innovation session which are giveaways.
See you then.