Guys will come back.
Let's talk a little bit about stories what your strategy for them can be and what other people use them
for now.
First off let me point out that virtually every account has some Instagram's stories strategy you know
some smaller accounts don't but the whole idea behind stories is that they're easy to make and that
you don't feel guilty because whatever you put up isn't the best thing you've ever had.
That's not really the point of stories.
So for the most part any big account is going to have some story content strategy already.
Now the main point of strategies is essentially when you break it down it's an engagement play meaning
you use in stories to drive people back to your posts to then engage on your posts that helps your posts
get more visibility that helps your account in general get more visibility because you really think
that stories aren't particularly useful for a whole lot.
Besides getting people to go to your page right because they can see stories that even being on your
page.
So you use it largely as like a boomerang to remind them every single day to hey come back to my page
and check out my posts.
No a secondary benefit of it I think is for promotion.
If you are going to be running promos selling stuff or promoting other people's accounts then they're
pretty useful because you can very easily crank something out throw it up and you don't to worry about
deleting it or really that people are going to care too much.
So that's really how I think of these I think of these as a way to get people to keep going back to
your account so that your account followers can essentially snowball and as you post more and more and
more you'll have higher and higher engagement.
And that's how you kind of pick up momentum and start picking up more and more people.
Now there are obviously other benefits like you can put hashtags on them but as you saw before discoverability
for stories is a bit limited.
Right.
So you sometimes see them hash tag pages you see them on place pages but they're not really the main
focus.
It's debt little circle up at the top which only takes up 20 percent of the screen or something like
that so it's not a big draw.
Now some people actually have turned this up on its head and they have a story first strategy in a post
secondary strategy meaning that they design their Instagram account to make the best stories possible
and then posts are often just repeats of their stories or recaps or something pretty minor.
Now you notice this with a lot of like personal accounts say like Tim Ferriss right.
He doesn't post a lot of stuff all the time.
Usually it's just reminders that he has a new podcast but he posts a lot of stories and the reason why
is because stories are so flexible that you can use them for behind the scenes or whatever it is that
you're doing that day.
It's kind of like the mentality that you had with snap chat which is that hey this is something I want
my followers my friends to see but it's not so important that I would put it up permanently.
So should you do Instagram stories.
Well the simple answer is yes.
And the reason why is just because it's a really easy way especially if you already have a post content
strategy down to basically create a new hook for people to keep coming back to your account.
It's really easy to take your post and then convert them into a story.
Also keep in mind that Instagram currently as I'm currently speaking rewards people who post stories
and generally like the accounts that use all of their features so adding stories means to them that
you're even more active than you were before and you're someone that's probably worth promoting.
Now do I particularly care about the analytics on stories around me.
Not so much.
Typically what I do is I go to the analytics and I like to just look at how many people see them and
I like to make sure that that's going up over time.
Iconv Square has a section dedicated to stories and you can see that people you know over time more
and more people watch them.
If people are not watching them then it's a question of whether or not you're posting the right content.
So like I said I use them as a constant content reminder so I post this story every single time I post
a regular post and I tell people in the story to go check out the post now.
Like I said this does take a little bit of content conversion but I'll show you how an innovation station
we figured out a way to really minimize this using a share feature that Instagram has recently rolled
out our guys.
That being said take a look at stories see if it's something you can add onto your play.
I think it's worth doing because it's an extra 10 percent effort.
But it is a very effective way of getting people to come back to your account.
If you're a business account it's a really easy way to add some low quality behind the scenes.
Shoot some of your employees show a clip of some new product or even a comment on your page that you
liked.
There's a lot of things you could do that you wouldn't really roll out for a regular post.
Are an individual it's even better because people like to follow you and see what you're up to.
So use it as that separate space where it's OK to post stuff that's not perfect.
All right guys.
That being said in the next hour let's go over how to post stories.
See you then.