All right guys welcome back.
So in this picture we're going to talk about the number two way of monetizing your Instagram account
and that is selling products.
Now we're talking about selling products.
We essentially have one of two different ways of doing this.
Now the first route is what I call easy mode and that's through affiliate marketing.
If you're not familiar with affiliate marketing it basically means you're going to sell other people's
products on whatever system you have for generating traffic which in this case is an Instagram account
when you sell other people's products through an affiliate relationship you typically will just get
paid a flat amount per sale or per lead or sometimes you get a percentage of everything the person that
you refer to them buys the case of affiliate marketing.
It is pretty easy because you don't have to make the product.
You don't have to do the customer service.
You don't have to do the logistics.
You don't have to fulfillment.
You don't have to do anything besides selling it.
Once they buy it you're pretty much off the hook.
Now a second way is to sell your own stuff.
And if you're going to sell your own stuff you probably already have a product already.
I wouldn't necessarily say go and make a product just for Instagram account because that's actually
the hard part.
I think making the Instagram account is easy.
In this case you do have to come up with your own stuff and hopefully you've already done that but you
don't have to say build your own massive software suite in order to make this work.
There's a lot of simpler things you can sell and I would also look into things like drop shipping where
you effectively it's like an affiliate relationship except you take over a little bit more control of
the stuff you're selling.
Now this is actually where we're going to do is we're going to talk about that first option the easy
mode doing affiliate marketing through your Instagram account.
First you need to decide what you want to sell and would look at what your options are or how to find
things that fit your account.
And also we'll talk a little bit about how the mechanics of affiliate relationships work because the
first thing is you just have to ask yourself the question.
Do you have your own products to sell should be an easy question to answer.
And the answer is No but you still think your account could be a great platform for selling something.
Well then the affiliate strategy is probably the way you ought to go.
Let's say for the sake of example you have an account that highlights really nice shoes.
Right.
And your main audience are things like sneaker heads.
There are a lot of accounts out there.
There's an entire mass of people who are obsessed with shoes and spend a lot of their disposable income
on shoes.
Now in this case you always make your own shoes that would take hundreds of hours of know how and manufacturing
and design and marketing or set or you know you just look for another company has done all of that and
then see if you can set up an affiliate relationship.
Now typically affiliate programs work like this.
There's usually a company that has already decided that Affiliate Marketing is a possibility for getting
the word out there about their products and so they've set up a system or signed up for an exchange
that allows them to have people see the products they're willing to sell.
Sign up for it.
Agree to some terms so that they have some limits on how they can advertise their stuff so they're not
doing it in a terrible terrible way and then it gives them the logistics for how Actually can I send
traffic to this site.
Usually it's through like a link and then how can I track who actually buys from that link.
Now for our purposes we really want to look for affiliate programs that use links there's other ways
of doing affiliate programs like cookies.
And that's just a nightmare because it's not going really going to work on Instagram.
You don't know what mobile browser people are using.
It's just not ideal.
We want to look for someone who's just going to give us a very simple link and that link automatically
tracks the activity that user does once they hit the actual destination page.
Once you have a link it's actually pretty simple.
All you have to do is take that link and put it in your bio.
It's like a generic thing that you always want to be selling.
Or you can coordinate it with your actual post say you do a post of a really popular shoe and then say
link in the bio and then you change your bio to a link to that specific shoe.
Now let's say we are the theoretical shoe company how exactly would we find an affiliate program of
shoes.
Well like all things in the world it always just starts at Google.
So we can just say shoe or research for affiliate programs right there.
OK.
Now here's a bunch right.
There's a bunch of companies that sell a lot of shoes like hotter shoes Clarkes those are really sandals
and boots I think vans.
And let's just say shoes dot com I think this one's actually interesting.
It's also interesting cause you can see there's backslash or as affiliates trains they already have
a page set up dedicated to affiliates so they already have their thing well set up.
So let's just take out shoes.
You know she's kind of like Zappos they have just tens of thousands of different shoes so if you were
someone who likes to highlight a variety of different types of shoes maybe this is something that you
might actually tackle because they can cater to anybody and it's very easy for you to find something
on their site that would fit with whatever you want to highlight at the moment.
So right here it has the basic information about their affiliate program.
So it says by affiliate program is fantastic wader and Rabaul the bubble boy.
Now they say the terms of it so 9 percent commissions I means you link to them that buy something you
get 9 percent of whatever they buy.
A three year cookie window which basically means that if that person goes to choose the outcome and
they buy something the next three days you get credited for that.
But if they buy it on the fourth day then choose dagum likes think that that was not necessarily attributable
to you.
I think three three day cookie window is pretty conservative.
There's ones that give you a much better one even like 14 day 30 day affiliate windows.
Then we have monthly payments and dedicated affiliate support.
OK.
Now the way they do it here is sign off now you say Click here to sign up via link share and this is
a very popular affiliate marketing exchange and they basically give software to these companies that
want to have affiliate relationships and they do all the tracking and all the payouts and everything
like that so it makes their life easier.
So if I wanted to sign up I'd sign of as a publisher.
And you have to give them up.
Obviously a lot of information and you'll have to be pretty careful to read through their requirements
on where you can advertise some of them are very strict.
Some of them don't really care like shoes dot com I would imagine probably not currently care.
Once you fill this out then it's just a waiting period.
You know with Link share it's like two to three business days for you'll get a response.
Some affiliate programs are really picky about who they use and some really don't care.
They just want to make sure that you're not a porn site that's posting their shoes on it.
So you would just fill this out and then submit it and then wait a couple of days.
It's pretty simple once you have that set up then it's a matter of just setting up your bank details
how you want to get paid.
Oftentimes it's through paypal and then getting your share link your Sharron Angle kind of looks like
a bitty link but it will have like linked links share in it.
And typically I like to take those and then put them in a bitty wrapper so that it doesn't look like
I'm giving you a link to an affiliate program link shares common enough that a lot of people recognize
that and action might hurt your conversions.
OK.
Now what would you do if you didn't know what you wanted to sell it might not be the case that your
account is that targeted.
So it's not obviously the case you're going to go after shoes or something really specific.
What if you think you could sell a lot of different things and you just kind of want to see what's available.
Well what you have to do is go and browse through affiliate marketplaces or affiliate exchanges and
there's a whole whole bunch of them link shares one of them but we'll just look at two.
One is called offer vault and the other one is called old digger which a terrible name.
But what happens here is they list off affiliate deals all over the universe.
And so in the case of Degger they just aggregate them and then they pass you off to another affiliate
exchange case of offer.
That's also kind of the same thing.
But a lot of times they give you good leads as to where another network is if you look through their
entire thing and you can't learn anything you want.
And the reason why I like Oger could offer of all is because they're aggregators so they pull in affiliate
deals from all different types of networks and that's kind of important because if you're flexible on
what you can sell then you're probably going to want a lot of variety.
And also you might change frequently.
And so if they aggregate all across then you have a broader view of what's available what's hot and
what's giving really good offers right now.
Número shoes are calling it nine percent of everything you sell on a three day window.
Well there are products out there that will give you 50 percent or 75 percent or even just a flat fee
for even something like a Sign-Up form.
So keep in mind the grass is often greener on the other side.
There's always another deal that's just waiting around the corner.
So in ogre's case let's say we wanted to look at shoes and see what they have.
All right let's see what we got.
So it looks like they're offering a lot of things for apps that sell shoes like Net shoes I believe
that's an app that sells it.
There's also an android one Laza Laura it's a fashion and shopping for Android.
So what these would be are you would sign up for them.
And every time you get someone to sign up for their app you get paid which is a pretty low barrier.
So like let's see net shoes Paisley 66 cents every time someone signs up.
So you know I don't know.
It kind of depends on how interesting you think the actual offer is and how well you think it will converge.
But that is generally speaking better offers out there.
One thing that is kind of nice about oh digger's they'll give you a preview of what the landing page
looks like.
And so in this case when you use that link in your bio you can see the page that will actually land.
Let's say you have an account dedicated to beards or like manliness or hygiene or something like that.
Like here's one better beard club.
OK.
They offer you $40 per action which I believe is if they sign up for a trial because they know that
average trial buyer you know pays a certain amount.
So $40 is pretty good.
We can click here and just check out the landing page.
This way we can see whether or not it's something that actually matches with our count what they're
selling.
So it's not to sales.
Now here's the easy little pack.
What to make sure that anybody we linked to is mobile optimized.
Why I shouldn't have to explain this if you go to that site and it's not very easy to use on your phone.
It doesn't matter what they're offering you're not going to get a lot of conversions so if you're just
using like chrome or anything just grab the bottom and then just see how it looks when you shrink it.
Right.
This is very similar to the screen you might see on like an iPhone 10.
And OK look like it's it automatically resizes the buttons are big it's easy to tell what they're selling.
Cool.
So I've already done that.
And then the rest of it might just be checking out what it is they sell and it looks like they sell
these trial packages for grooming and for beards.
There's a lot of people out there really obsessive beards.
I think this is a little weird they sell beer booze which is testosterone.
I always thought that was regulated.
But who knows.
Anyway so make that decision on your own.
Now one other affiliate exchange I just want to point out and this is a great one if you're willing
to sell physical products to Amazon Amazon largest store online in the world.
So if you can't find something you sell on Amazon then well you're struggling here if you just want
to get affiliate Dasch program on Amazon.
You can work with them and then get something like 10 percent I think is the commission for virtually
anything you can find on Amazon so honestly there's so many things you could sell on here that you shouldn't
have a lot of trouble finding it.
Now keep in mind since Amazon is huge they have a lot of leverage over their affiliates so their deals
are not going to be as sexy as say like a smaller nice site that really desperately wants to win over
some good affiliates.
When you find an exchange that you like you basically just sign up and then follow their instructions
for signing up for a deal and eventually you'll end up with an approval on a link and that's pretty
much a rinse and repeat.
Now in the next year we're going to do a cover.
One of the newer features on Instagram and that is shareable by Instagram.
I'm going to talk about how we can make that apply for products that we sell on our own.
OK.
See you then.