All right guys welcome back.
OK so with this lecture we're going to do is talk about creating names and creating bios.
I generally suggest doing this up front as opposed to creating an account and then coming up with a
name and a bio at the same time.
Just because it's a lot easier if you batch these together it's a lot easier to kind of get in whatever
mode you need to be and pull this off.
And also it's kind of nice because if you know how many zombies you want to create.
Well you can just create X amount of account names an X amount of biros and then is just a matter of
copy and paste when you go and set them up.
OK so first thing we want to do is we want to come up with some names that we know are available.
Now previously the way we did this it was through a Web site called name checker and it's without to
eat the very end you can use that Web site.
It works perfectly fine.
I've found that occasionally sometimes it's wrong and when you're doing this in bulk that can actually
be kind of a pain.
So I prefer actually just go directly to the Web site itself and to do my name checking there.
So just go to ask.com not common and log out so that you can see this original Sign-Up screen right
here.
You have to fill out this information if you get a check for a user name.
All you have to do is just fill in username right here.
And if it's wrong you'll get an x and if it's right you'll get a checkmark.
OK.
Now the strategy of coming up using names is.
I mean it's kind of the same thing that we talked about before we came up with these names in general.
I personally like to pick a bunch of common words that are in my space and my niece and then add some
adjectives and by adding those two things together I can find a lot of available account names.
Now my niece is innovation it's technology it's business.
It's gadgets it's robots it's really anything that's generic enough to represent technology.
Also it's pretty lucky because I can say technology and if that's not available say tech Now obviously
easy really good short accounts are just not going to be available socially in bulk.
So give yourself a little bit of a leeway when you start picking names so let's just say I wanted to
make an account that the base of the name was technology and I wanted to say something like It's futuristic
or it's advanced and it's very new.
So I might say advanced
technology and if I think this is available I might just stop in and see if it's available.
Pretty sure it's not.
OK so I'll just add one more modifier so I could say today and let's see if that was available.
Get in and it is so it has a checkmark that means that's a good one.
So it's difficult but I just do is I just copy and paste this into a note dark and have her note whatever
or even physically write it down if you want to just keep track as you go through these.
So you can create a list now.
You know if I want to create 10 zombie accounts that was my strategy Well I don't do that nine more
times.
Now there's pretty easy tricks.
All I like to do is use the base like technology and then just change some of these modifiers.
So instead of advanced I could a future or futuristic Let's see if those are available.
Future technology today a little bit ironic but OK.
So check mark good one.
Now we got to now I can do the next one.
I could say the future is stick.
Yes this one is also available futuristic technology today.
OK great.
Anybody coming to this account knows exactly what it is.
It's futuristic technology today and since it's a repost account they're not going to be confused as
to what I'm reposing all about and chances are if they follow this account means they're interested
in technology which means that they're probably getting interested in my main account is also technology.
OK there's not really any magic to this.
This is just the way that I like to use it.
Pick some adjectives you can even write them out beforehand like what are adjectives you think could
describe your accounts and then use a base word like technology or gadgets or whatever else say you're
taking account yoga.
OK well yoga could be your base stretching could be your base.
I don't know.
Oh my.
Could be your bait whatever is something that your users or that are and you're going to recognize.
You should know this since this is your.
Right.
The next thing you need to do is just pick a bio.
Now again we're going to refer back to the bio strategies that we talked about way back at the beginning
of the course.
So for instance with intimations station we did the bullet point list with one singular emoji.
And I just kind of thought of what are some things that might make my account attractive or something
you might see on a technology account.
And again I just took this and it is kind of remixed it.
So in my old one or the main account we say curated list of the best in tech innovation world changing
trends to watch weekly tech giveaways open submissions to us.
There's a lot of different lines I could have put in if you remember watching me create this account
is a lot of things I could have said I just kind of left them out.
So this is the time where you can kind of start bringing these back.
So I'll give you an example of what I ended up doing.
I just wrote out a bunch of these.
OK.
So the coolest gadgets and tech on the web follow for robot spaceships and everything tech.
Daily Post of the most exciting new technology get inspired motivated and intrigued as you can see there's
pretty much a trend to this right.
I used kind of the same lines that other accounts use that we covered before.
Things like follow four and then say whatever it is that you're going to be posting.
Then you can use something like a broad based description of the account like this.
We posted this here so every day the newest and wildest technology I think you kind of get the picture.
I even read you some of the things like Diom for submissions because that sounds like it's a real account
that someone who is actually running now one piece of wisdom is that don't make these too obvious don't
reuse sentences.
That's a big no no.
If I for instance read used curated list of the best and tech in innovation not only would that be confusing
to someone who followed the zombie account and then came over to the main account and saw this.
It also will set off red flags don't make it easy for Instagram system to figure out that hey this is
the exact same person running two accounts.
So just try to mix it up if you're really lazy you can even jumble the words.
So as opposed to saying curated you could say exclusive lists.
You can set up instead of the best to say the most interesting set of taxi gadgets that have innovation
say the future.
OK you kind of get the idea.
There's enough combinations in there that you can make a lot of different bio pieces.
Now do you need to make the same exact length as this.
No.
Personally I make them simpler just because it's going to drive me crazy if I have to come up with four
lines for every single account.
But it's Tiley up to you.
OK so what I suggest doing is just spend a little bit of time on the Instagram intro page.
Figure out how he's Ahmadis you want and then do another of these adjectives modifiers until you have
enough accounts.
Of course you can do whatever you want just keep in mind that this is an easier way if you're doing
this and bulk.
Then once you have a list of all the names you want I suggest going in writing some BIOS.
I prefer to keep the same style that I used on all the other ones just because it's simpler and I can
mix and match them.
And it's easy.
So I have to come up with another one I can just look at an old one or one of these ones up here and
that usually can give me some inspiration for what I can say.
Not really science to it.
It's really just kind of an art.
It might take you a couple hours if you are literally making 50 accounts or whatever.
Just you know keep in mind that like we said before zombies take a lot of time up front and this is
what we would include in the upfront time.
All right guys so in the next lecture what we'll do is a follow along lecture where I'll go and create
an actual account for innovation station.
It will be a zombie that reposts for innovation station we'll just set up a blank account and then in
the preceding lectures what we'll do is we'll start installing Jarvi which is the software that's going
to help us run these things and then we'll get into the settings of how you set that up and what your
strategy is going to be.
OK.
See the.