All right, guys, welcome back.
So, this lecture, let's talk about something that's probably
for the people that are more serious about Instagram.
If you're just in this to grow really fast, then somehow
flip that into a business perfectly fine, you'll
meet your needs, but you might
not need this specific lecture.
Anyway, we talked about Instagram
being the king of visual, right?
Everything that is well thought out and visually
interesting generally gets rewarded, and things that
are not just generally don't perform
that well. In a similar suit,
those that commit to long term styling
standards also tend to do very well.
Now, some accounts, if you haven't noticed, have
no visual style pattern to them whatsoever.
One post is a white background with a quote, and
then the next one is like a landscape with no text,
then you have a selfie shot of some like goateed man.
They're just posting what comes to mind and then
pushing it out without any attention paid to whether the
posts will fit the general aesthetic of the account as a whole.
OK, let's look at an account called dude.therapy.
Ok, it's not the worst account that I've seen,
but scroll through the feed just a little bit.
Now, what do you notice?
I'm going to tell you what I notice.
There's no real style associated with this account.
I guess we could say that they do quotes a lot, but
sometimes they're memes or funny real life photos.
Each photo has a different background style.
Some are beige, some are plain white, and others are
brown, in black stripes, and all sorts of weird stuff.
Every single post seems to have a different font as well,
so there's really no pattern to the types of posts,
the fonts used, the backgrounds,
the colors are just really anything.
On the other hand, let's look at another
account, this one is called The Froot Life.
It's a mango drink in India.
And holy crap.
Look at the colors. They're all solid colors,
and are vibrant, and kind of tropical.
I see the same purples and the same greens being used, and
guess what, the font is always the same as the company's.
The more you look at this feed,
the more it kind of looks like art.
Let's look at another one.
This is Everlane, which sells fancy clothes.
OK, let's look at the general pattern as a whole though.
Lots of white and gray mixed with subtle blues and browns, lots of product shots or landscapes and people shots at artistic angles.
Same font throughout. They use a similar text placement
style as well, and they use the same models even.
Ok, so which of these do you think is going
to be more popular and convert more users?
Well, the ones that keep some kind of brand guidelines
and have some eye to how the, you know, the bird's
eye view of your wall or feed is going to look.
Now, talking about brands, and brand building, and brand standards pretty much lulled me to sleep, because,
well, it's really boring.
*This is boring.*
Luckily, it's something that just takes maybe 30 minutes
of work and maybe some tweaking down the road,
but I think it actually can pay off in big dividends.
So if we want to keep the entirety of the account
aesthetic, then what exactly do we do?
Well, we first decide on a posting pattern that
we want to try and then we pick a style guide.
Now, it's not really that complicated to do this and
I personally just scribble it down in Evernote
somewhere. If you think your main posts
are going to be quotes, OK, great.
What else do you think you'll throw in
though? Here's a pattern that might work.
Two posts of quotes and one post of video.
Since the Instagram wall feed is only three columns wide,
that will actually create a striping effect with your videos.
If you look at thestartup.co account, that's an okay
account, but you can see that they made all of their
far left posts the same type.
Doesn't really matter what you do,
it's just that you thought out a pattern.
Not only will it make the page look better,
but it will prime your users for what to expect.
People like consistency.
The next thing is a style guide, and that's really just
a fancy way of saying pick a color palette, then
pick one or two fonts, and then pick a composition, which is basically what goes on each photo and roughly what arrangement.
Now, the last thing you have are filters,
which are really up to you.
I mean, we're going to talk about filters later on.
But if you decide to use them, just make sure you use
them consistently and don't switch all over the place.
If you want to pick a color palette, it's pretty easy.
Now, here are my two favorite tools. One of them is
called coolors.co, and it's a web app that basically
just gives you a five color scheme, and every time
you hit the space bar it gives you a new set.
You can just lock the ones you want, and it'll keep
going until you have a group of ones that you like.
It's actually pretty fun.
The next tool is great if you're lazy and you
don't want to put it together yourself at all.
Just go to lolcolors.com, which just has curated color
palettes that work pretty well for Instagram in
my experience. They're pretty colorful,
with decent contrast to them.
You really don't have to think about it.
Just find a set that you like and then just use it.
Now, fonts are up to you.
I strongly suggest that you stick with only one or two fonts,
ideally one. My courses always use Proxima Nova,
but I'll probably use like a similar-ish font
in my account during this course.
If you're a company or a website, then just use the
font that you have on your website, you probably
already have a dominant font.
Again, consistency really helps when you're trying
to convert people into real life customers.
It's kind of weird if you're looking at something that's,
let's say it's in Tahoma, and then you go to
a website, and it's all in Comic Sans.
OK, guys, that's all for now. Hopefully I've opened
your eyes a little bit to the broader aesthetics of
Instagram and how some accounts
do it well and some not so much.
It's really pretty easy.
You just need to stick to a pattern of content.
You can change that pattern of content, but try to stick
to each pattern at least for a little bit for it to show up,
so it doesn't look like you're constantly switching patterns.
Then all you need is a style guide, and that's just a fancy way
of saying pick a color palette, a font, and a rough
idea of how you're going to put the things on the
page, and you're pretty much good to go.
All right, guys.
Next up, we'll talk about some of my favorite accounts that
I think are worth studying for content strategy inspiration.
Stay tuned.