All right guys we'll come back to this lecture.
We're going to talk about what's the most effective way to monetize your account by selling your own
stuff.
Now no not going to get into how to create your own products that's an entirely different course or
how to pick products to sell or how to make them manufacture them so like that.
That is just WAY outside the purview of the course.
What I will show you though is if you have a product or service or something that you've made that you
have more control over than if you're in sales and affiliate marketing situation a show you probably
what the most effective way of selling that is and that's through a relatively new feature called chartable
with Instagram.
Now what is your team's done is that they've realized that a lot of people sell stuff through their
accounts whether it's books courses shoes fashion clothing whatever.
A lot of companies that are retail or have something to sell are on Instagram and a lot of times they
will feature the post or feature whatever they're trying to sell.
And before they would do as they would say go to my bio and click on it.
Now what they've done is they've opened it up such that if you have your own store specifically to use
a platform like Facebook or Shopify or Oblio like Squarespace and we believe in things like that you
can automatically integrate this into it and then automatically sell whatever it is you're posting directly
to your account.
So to give you an example of this let's look at urban outfitters.
They're an account that does this.
OK.
So right here you see they have eight million people that's a ton.
Now you'll notice is if it has this little bag at the top you can kind of see here.
That means that whatever is in this is a shock ball post.
And the way that this works is very similar as tagging.
You know we tag people are posting it.
We just touch it and then tag where on the image we want the tag to be and then who do we want to be
tagged.
So same thing with items right.
So if they see their dress you can just click on the dot.
OK.
And we see our $69 floral dress.
That click through.
There you go.
Now it can actually.
Show me what they're selling and gives me a link directly to see it on their Web site.
And if I click through I just go directly to their Web site and this is a feature that's changing quite
a bit as I'm filming this.
When they first came out with it it was like you can only sell if you had your products listed on Facebook
and then it was Facebook and Shopify and now it's Facebook Shopify and private integrations with large
companies.
OK.
Because if you have your own Web site it's professionally made it's not made through Wordpress or any
of those other platforms you might have to wait on this.
But for the most part you can use it if you use any of the platforms.
Now one other thing I want to point out is when you start doing Schappell posts it'll change your home
page slightly such that you'll have this Shatha button.
Now remember we signed up as a business account and it gave us the option of giving contact information
in there for a phone number or an email.
And that's what shows up there.
So I think on our account yeah we have e-mail right there.
But on their account let's get back to them.
They have a shop button so I can click shop and it gives me this feed of all the things that are swappable.
OK.
So keep that in mind.
Now the first step if you want to do this is to make sure that your account is a business account and
if you're following this course you've already done that.
Right we did as way back at the beginning because in order to get Analytics from Instagram we had to
sign up for a business account you never meant to do that pretty easy just go to your settings and I
think it clicks it's like switch to a business account or upgrade to a business account.
It doesn't take very long.
Anybody can do it as long as you email address and then you give them a phone number or some form of
contact information for users coming to your account.
Now the easiest way to sell something would be to use that Facebook page or we had to set up when we
created our Instagram account.
So let's go to the Facebook page that we have for innovation station.
We set this up just because we wanted to set it up as a business hadn't yet turned this into anything
useful.
We do have a section on how to turn your Facebook page into something that can funnel traffic towards
your account.
But as I'm filming this now we haven't yet done that.
So go to the page you made and most likely it probably just looks like this.
Now typically what can happen over here is you're going to have a bunch of automatic tabs that are created
for your count and these are generated based on the type of account you signed up for this Internet
company so I got posts and reviews and whatever.
Now I click see more and I have this one called Shop and that's where I want to go.
Now if you don't see that which a lot of you guys want you want to go over here to settings and then
go to edit page and it'll show you whatever your template is mine standard right now.
Cool.
So then down here I have my tabs and if I don't have shopped or not there I just hit ad tab and then
it should allow me to select shop as one of these.
OK.
So that's what you have to do.
Now keep in mind depending on where you guys are in the world this might not actually be available to
you.
Right now I know in the U.S. the U.K. Canada Germany France Spain Australia Japan countries like those
they do have this I don't know if they've rolled this out necessarily.
For India or some of them like Middle Eastern or African countries they're rolling it out slowly so
if you don't see it then unfortunately it's just not there and chartable posts are not going to be available
to you.
There's some work arounds for that and put some resources Taxus lecture if you fall into that category
and you really do want to be Schappell will post so check that out.
OK now once I have that shot and set up I just want to do and Cliggott and what will happen is a little
give me this walkthrough where it says set up your shop and essentially what I want to do is I'm going
to add products to innovation station and then because it's already sync with my instagram because he
did this and we created a business account I then will have the option of selecting those.
Now keep in mind once I set this up I have to go through a review process with Instagram and it takes
two to three days and they have to prove that yes in fact I am a shopper at least I have real products.
I'm not even sure what the criteria are but it's a two to three day waiting period.
So in order to show you to the very end of this because Also I'm not trying to sell specific things
on innovation station that's not our time to try to monetize it.
But keep in mind that's kind of the end of the process.
So get get started.
And then what we do is we just pick our region pick a business type.
This is just how you incorporated it.
So I can say sole proprietorship does do whatever address I can think of.
It's important that you give an actual physical address you can receive mail to show because this is
how we verify that you are in fact real and not some fly by night team that's just going to sell crap
and then run away then and ask you for a registration number.
Now this you can skip but generally it's just one of those things if you have it and the Instagram process
will go a lot faster if you skip it.
Then I decided that yeah I want to get paid in currency.
They charge a processing fee.
Pretty similar you get with a credit card finish.
OK so next up you're going to want to add products and then set up your payments.
Now you have to do both of those before you can even think of doing this on Instagram.
Now I would go to add a product and it's going to have a price the name description and then how many
of these I can sell and then some shipping options.
So one of the things that I was I got a lot of attention for was a hydrofoil and it kind of looks like
this is really goofy but it's like you're surfing in the air.
So let's say maybe I wanted to put this as a product down I wish I could publish this because it's not
my product but I could completely do this.
So I asked the company that it was OK to sell it on my account.
So now we have an image of that image Dhoop OK use that photo.
Then I get a call or it's hydrofoil set the price.
God what was it like eight billion dollars.
It was too good and so sweet.
So we'll put it at a premium.
You know obviously it makes money.
And then the description I'll just borrow from them because I do generally speaking these companies
do a great job of writing their own descriptions and I'll go here.
Copy that in my inventory.
It doesn't really matter.
I'm just buying from them directly.
So let's say we have 10 and we can do standard shipping.
Now I'm in the U.S. So it's probably gonna work a little bit different.
I don't know what the page looks like if I were in Japan for example I would give something like an
estimated days of delivery.
It kind of depends how quickly you can buy it.
Typically what I would do is I just go to this company and see what their shipping options are and what
they quote because I'm just going go over and buy it from them.
If I were actually going to sell this but let's just say theoretically three to 10 days the price for
shipping is probably pretty expensive.
And price per additional item.
Okay maybe it's a little bit less than originally what it was.
OK so 10 days.
Right.
So they want it to be no less than 7 so it's 7 great save that we have a return policy 30 days increase
a customer if you want to and then you can always put it in the product category.
I'm going to get it safe.
Okay.
And how can they contact me.
I'll just put one of my e-mail addresses.
All enable messenger sure they've got it.
OK.
Now this should show up in my shop.
Ok cool.
So I have a super sweet hydrofoils processing which means it is going to go through some algorithm checks
to make sure that a bunch of things that your numbers make sense that perhaps it actually looks.
See if you borrowed the image elsewhere I seriously doubt that one but once I have this set up I want
to set up my payments.
Not going to do that.
I'm not selling anything.
But I'll try to set up my payments once that's done.
Then it's just a matter of making sure that my account is attached to Instagram and the way you do that
just go to settings and then we'll go down to Instagram.
Pretty easy.
And it already has my thing right here.
But if it didn't I would have to add right there and then attach my account to it.
Then what happens is in Instagram when you post something you'll post a photo of whatever the product
is and you'll have an additional option right where it says or tag people it will say tag products.
Now you can only do one or the other to attack people you can't tag products tag products can attack
people.
It works pretty much the same way as tagging people and I believe there's a limit on how many things
you can tag per image but it's a pretty high limit.
So it's not really something to worry about.
Once you do that you just you just click on the item and then it'll give you an option to pull from
a list of products you have and it's whatever going to be listed on my Facebook.
And that is pretty much it.
Now I said this before you have to go through an approval process and that can take probably one to
two days on Facebook and then two to three business days Instagram's and this largely depends on what
you're selling whether or not you have a web presence elsewhere if you have a Web site.
You make yourselves and your website should be pretty easy.
There is a limit geographically but they're expanding that pretty rapidly so by the time you watch this
who knows they're probably selling us pretty much everywhere.
OK so that I think is the ideal way to sell your own stuff.
You do a post that highlights something you're selling you Taggett as a product and allow them to buy
it.
That by far has the highest conversion rate for retail.
And that's why I kind of focus on using that specifically if you have your own products to sell.
Now keep in mind this doesn't just work for retail.
You can use it for software or e-books or whatever.
If you go and look at like founder their account they sell software and online courses all the time
and they use the same shop lable posts so keep that in mind.
With that being said we're going to move on to the third way of making money and that is flipping your
account.
See the.