Hey guys, welcome back.
All right.
Last lecture we talked about writing captions.
Now we're going to round that out
by talking about calls to action.
Yes.
Those things that we exhaustively talked about in the
profile section of the course are back, and like before,
they are muy importante.
So captions are great and all, right?
Real inspiring, change the world stuff,
but human beings, being humans, are rarely going to
respond just by themselves without any prompting.
It's like when you meet a stranger and you know
nothing about each other, it's really hard to start a
conversation if you have nothing to start with.
Now, what if you were talking to that stranger and
someone jumped out of a bush and said, "What's your
favorite movie?" or "Ever been skydiving?"
I don't know.
You can kind of tell I don't go on a lot of dating shows.
The point is that little spark right there starts the
process, breaks the seal, if you will, and makes
the likelihood of further conversation that much more likely.
That's what we're doing with our call to actions.
We want them to engage.
So if you were reading this post, what question
would you feel utterly irresistible to answer?
So, me, for instance, I have a
traumatically bad sense of direction,
so if the post said something like,
"Like this post if you avoid going to Target
because you know you're going to get lost,"
I would reach out from whatever phone coma
I'm in and hard press the *** out of that button.
Usually, when you do this, you want one of a few things,
you want likes, usually gathered by asking if people
agree with the post or statement, and to show it by
liking it, or you might get comments by asking them
a question that you want them to respond to.
Now, if you're really gutsy, you can
go for some advanced calls to action.
You can, if you're really good, get people
to tag others in your post comments as well.
Usually, you see this by asking something along the
lines of "Tag a friend if they blank" and the blank
corresponds to the post.
Now, it could be as simple as a product post that says
"Tag a friend that would like this or need this,"
especially if this something helps a friend out, or it's something endearing, or it's something that you both can laugh about.
You tag them if let's say you posted some app that
helps you remember things and you said "Tag a friend
that you love, but they can't remember your birthday."
Kind of saucy.
Someone else would probably do that. Now, you wouldn't
tag your friend to a photo of Viagra, on the other
hand, unless you're just a mean person.
Another angle would be like posting a motivational
quote and then saying "Tag a friend that lives this every
day," and then you get to tag a friend with
essentially a warm and fuzzy comment.
Think about it.
What would you tag a friend for?
Something positive that can be an indirect compliment,
something that's funny that just lets you reminisce
with a friend, something that's actually useful for a
friend because you're helping them out, or even just like tagging
a friend you think would agree with [blank statement].
People like agreeing with one another.
Now, why is this an advanced call to action?
Well, because it's like the bonus round, it's harder
to pull off, but if you do, it's double points.
Tags mean more views, more views means
more comments and more follows.
And these are friends that probably will like your stuff.
What's even harder than getting someone
to tag their friends in your post?
Getting someone to repost your photo
or repost their own version of the photo.
OK, this does happen, but usually it's only with bigger accounts that have been doing this for a much longer time.
Reposting a photo takes a little bit of
know-how and quite a bit of motivation.
But if you have a really engaged audience, then it is
a great way to get your posts spread out, especially
if you remembered to always tag
your photos with your account logo.
Reposting their own remix is even rarer and usually
only works when you're running something like a
contest, so we'll focus on them
when we talk about that later on.
So that's the buffet of options.
Go for likes, go for comments, go for tags, or go for reposts.
This is really one of the easier parts of posting, and
if you spend enough time on Instagram, you'll start
to test out what works and see
what others are doing that works.
You want likes?
OK, well, here are some common templates. Like if
you agree. Like if you love [blank] - it could be like,
like if you love your mother, or like if you love ice cream.
Want to know more? Like the photo.
iOS or Android? Like for iOS,
comment for Android. Like if you want to [blank] in
five years. Like if you watched this show last night.
I like it personally when it says "Like if you don't do
[blank]" and then the blank is something terrible like,
like if you don't forget to call your mom on your mother's
day, or you can imagine possibly worse things.
The more creative you get, the more successful you'll be with this.
There are some pretty hilarious ones where it's just an image,
and by liking it you'll give that person a weird face.
You can imagine that the post that said "Give
Donald Trump a frown" got a whole lot of likes.
It needs to be relevant to your post and it shouldn't be generic, unless you honestly just can't think of something else.
Some call to action though is going to be better than nothing.
If you're going for comments, well, here are
some common ones you'll see and they work.
Let us know what you think.
OK, it's kind of weak tea, but it's like the default.
Like I said, better than nothing.
Let us know if you agree.
Let us know if you think [blank], and the blank here is
going to be like a statement that was in the caption.
Let us know if you've had a similar experience, or comment
and tell us your favorite [blank]. Anything that
has to do with the user talking about themselves is usually gold.
Now, did you see this show?
What did you like or not like about it?
What's your favorite way a guy does blah blah blah blah blah?
Or hey, get people to write content for you with
"Tell us your funniest [blank] story in the comments."
Now, of course, you don't have to use a CTA for engagement
only, if you prefer a business interest, well then you
can use it to tell people to go to your website,
go to an e-mail address, or go buy something.
If you're trying to make money in your Instagram
itself, then you can say things like "Direct message
me" in your call to action, and say something like
"Business inquiries" and then put your e-mail
or just say "DM me for business inquiries."
It might look a little tacky, but it can get you a lot
of connections that will help you later on when
you need to share your account and get other people
to help you get followers. Now, in the resources,
as always, we've compiled a list of
call the actions that we think are great.
Use it if you're stuck or just need some inspiration.
We've also linked to some profiles that we think really do it well.
Now, I think this part is the easiest and
it just takes a couple of seconds to do.
Reread your caption and your post and just think to yourself,
"If I read this, what would I respond to?"
Don't be afraid to try something out.
If it doesn't work, then just move on.
How do you know if it doesn't work? Well, either
no one does it, or the comments or likes would be
considered under the Instagram average of that 2%
baseline engagement.
Or it could be more.
More accurately, under your average,
because it depends heavily on the industry.
You could have a better average and so
being under the 2% is just not a good gauge.
OK, guys, that's it for now.
Questions, comments, just post in the group discussion.
Make sure to screenshot posts if you're actually referring
to them. Otherwise, see you in the next lecture.