They is welcome back.
OK so in this lecture let's start talking about the number three way of monetizing your Instagram account
and that is flipping your account.
Now it's not 100 percent flipping.
You know when I say flipping you typically think of like someone who bought a house and proved it and
sold it I just like to call it flipping it.
In reality it's more often the case that you built an account with the idea that you're going to sell
it later on.
So that's what we're talking about.
How much money can you make and what's the eye on building an account to a certain follower accounts
or engagement rate and then selling it.
But the first question I think it's worth tackling is how much can you make.
Right.
Because that will determine whether or not this is a viable strategy for you.
And honestly it's kind of hard to say.
And the reason why is because a lot of large accounts sell but they don't post anywhere with an asking
price that you see they're usually done in private one on one negotiations so we don't actually know
a lot about how much you can sell a large account for what we can tell for sure.
Is that typically any account that sells under 100000 is going to sell at a baseline at about $20 per
thousand followers.
Now whether or not that is worth it for you it depends on who you are how much money do you want to
make.
I think it's especially attractive to go this route of monetization if you can grow multiple accounts
at the same time.
Then you can kind of take advantage of the synergies of helping them all grow together and then you
can sell them off one to one on one or you can sell them as a whole ring and potentially charge a premium.
So now let's go back to that figure I said which is that in general you have a baseline of about $20
per thousand followers.
Now that depends on a lot of different things that's why I call it a baseline.
The things that could actually change that rate are things like your engagement rate things about whether
or not the person who's buying fits into the niche that you've chosen.
How many comments do you get on average per post.
Are you creating your own content or are you just reposting content.
Also things like how many posts do you have in total.
Now let's talk about why each one of these is important.
With regard to how many posts you have and whether or not it's original content.
Well that actually helps the person who purchases it because once they buy it they're not going to just
stop posting on it.
Ideally they're going to want to use it for some purpose and in order to keep that momentum going and
to keep it from losing a lot of engagement they still need to post on it.
So if you have a lot of post that means it's relatively easy for them to find all posts and re post
them and keep the content going and then also they don't have to think a lot about how to create content
for this specific audience because that would be kind of hard if you just bought an account you didn't
know anything about the users.
So the other thing was whether or not you repost or create your own.
Typically speaking if you create your own that's better repost accounts are kind of cheap.
I mean it just means that you went around and picked nice things and you curated them which is fine.
But in general you're just not selling as much.
Not as much.
IP is a very unique account there's a lot of reposte accounts and in general they're going to have lower
engagement rates which is not as attractive as a purchase option.
Now your engagement rate just obviously matters because it's an indicator of the quality of what you
post and the quality of the following.
Right now if you're an accountant has a lot of mass followers are fake followers you can have a low
engagement rate.
Also you know if you a low wage rate it may mean that whatever the Massereene your content and your
audience is that you found is not particularly effective.
So higher engagement means more people are going to see whatever I post which means that I'll be able
to milk that account more because more people actually react whenever I do something.
Comments obviously matters too just because that's something that screams algorithm likes.
But I you know we kind of consider this like a secondary one.
Higher comments will push your posts higher up you're more likely to go on the explore page.
But you know obviously a little bit of a drawback in that oftentimes you'll buy an account a lot of
comments and it's kind of hard to respond to all those comments and to keep up some of the best practices
we covered before.
The last thing obviously is what your niche is and that just has to do with demand.
There's a lot of popular knishes And if you pick something that's really obscure it's going to be hard
to find a buyer.
So those are some of the levers that can either make your sale easier or increase or decrease that baseline
of $20 per thousand that we've mentioned before.
Now you have to think about it why exactly would someone buy an account.
Well typically it's one of two reasons.
One they're getting buy in because they want to create their own account.
And this is a great way of getting a head start.
And the other one is that they're going to use it to promote another account or another product.
So if you've created something that say doesn't have a lot of post to work with is a low to say 1 percent
engagement rate.
That's a very good bedrock to build a business on.
With regards to the nice your end this is generally something that if you are wanting to sell your account
at the end of this whole Instagram journey you kind of have to keep that in consideration before you
start because there's certain issues that have a lot of demand a lot of people have figured out how
to monetize them.
So there's a lot of buyers for them.
There's other ones obviously that are just too obscure and the lack of buyers is going to drive your
price down some of the most common types you'll see are things like luxury that's just fancy things
people who aspire to be rich motivation usually just close with like a big strong man staring off in
the distance.
You have girls.
Yeah.
I mean that's a really popular one.
It's just attractive or in shape when you have things like pets.
There's ones that are dedicated to Entire just to dogs or cats or just two specific types of dogs like
one of my favorite accounts is a corgi account.
You also have cars.
That's one that is pretty popular a lot of people really like cars on Instagram such a visual platform
because of things like memes or people who post funny things with the one line at the top one line at
the bottom it's just usually for comedic value.
You also have things like travel.
Again obviously it's a very visual platform so great landscape shots very useful.
You also have things like fashion and also fitness as a big one too especially like weight loss.
That's a pretty big category.
I'd also say there's things like food and DIY crafts but those maybe aren't as popular.
It kind of depends.
Now if you do want to sell this is what my advice is use that Tony dollars per thousand as your baseline
and then use hype auditor to then adjust that up or down.
So now you remember heighth auditor that's how he check to see what the quality of an account is let's
just look at daily innovation inspiration and innovation station.
You get free reports for your own accounts you don't have to actually pay for this.
So if you look at mine we have a 93 out of 100 that's good U.S. based primarily second India third is
Italy and Indonesia and United Kingdom 79 percent are real people.
And we'll just use this to look at those things that we cared about before like.
So what is our engagement rate.
OK.
So 8.4 percent.
And that's compared to 1.5 percent for similar accounts in my space.
Then let's look at things like comments like the comments ratio is good.
Now I know this fluctuates quite a bit actually.
Sometimes my likes to comments ratio has been bad and it's just something I've been trying to optimize.
So right now it's good.
So again that's another reason I might be able to move the baseline up now the Nishi is kind of hard
to say.
I mean it's technology innovation.
So it's going to fit with a lot of business categories or gadgets or things like that.
But typically if I were to price this out I would take that Tony dollar based on an item I didn't increase
it quite a bit right.
I'd probably take that up to say like $35 because it's very high engagement.
We use our own content it's all original stuff and we have healthy followings that are for the most
part clumped in a good geographical regions as far as time zones are concerned we don't have a ton of
mass followers so we all like 20 percent or kind of questionable and I don't even know honestly how
those came to be.
Imagine those are from page shout outs from less than savory accounts.
MILLER I think you might well look at is reachability.
So eighty nine point seven percent of followers have less than fifteen hundred.
That's good.
Anybody who has more than fifteen hundred posts something the odds of them seeing your post are pretty
low.
So let's say you know I was going to do $35 per.
I'm at 21000 soon asking price I could start with maybe around $700 and it specifically $735.
That's generally the range I could start and then see how the interest is.
Now what is the ideal point to sell your account at.
Is it best to just make a bunch of five thousand person 10000 dollar accounts all those or to wait till
you're in the millions.
Again it's usually up to you.
Typically speaking though the larger the account the higher that baseline will start to move certain
looking a million dollar accounts.
I generally start revising that 20 dollar advice slightly up.
You start seeing the baseline closer to 30 once you get in the millions.
So that would suggest that you have some if you wait longer.
Also just keep in mind that the market for really small accounts is just weak.
I don't know why anyone would want to buy a 5000 person account given that there are two reasons why
people buy this is because they want a head start on their account 5000 is a lot or they want to drive
traffic from it to in another account.
Again 5000 is not a lot.
So as long as you're in say 15000 20000 range then you might actually be attractive depending on whoever
the buyer is.
Now if you do want to sell There's essentially two different ways that you can do this.
Now one is by posting it on an exchange and the other one is by doing an outbound strategy.
Now exchanges are pretty simple.
It's really simple just just google Bycel Instagram accounts because there's ones that pop up all the
time.
But the common or the well known ones are like social trade.
Fame swap epic in PC and Bycel shout outs.
Some of these we've actually seen an earlier section.
So for instance let's look at social trachea the list off on their front page what they have and platforms
useful because you can post whatever it is you're trying to sell.
So let's see like this one would be in the nice of weightlifting or fitness and this is a pretty small
account but you can see that they kind of follow that Tony dollars.
I mean they should probably price themselves at 120 and that's probably why they haven't sold yet.
But let's see.
This one's 11000.
That's.
Yeah.
OK they're pretty overpriced.
Let's see this one like 84000 for luxury vibe.
That's right on the money for basically 20 to one.
But you can see they you can post it here and then you can accept offers and you can just have someone
outright bias so you can see like six offers are currently pending it looks like a lot of people will
lowball it.
But anyway so you can use a platform to just post them online and then use that as a way to gather attention.
Here's one like player up dotcom.
It's just a forum where tons and people are just posting a lot of times they'll post their entire groupings
of one.
So like let's see active hot girls like we talked about before there's several people selling several
of those who's a luxury nice one.
That one's pretty obscure.
It's not a super common account.
You can see guns.
OK.
So they're getting a little more specific.
Dogs mimis you can kind of see that there's a reoccurring theme here.
And then right here is where they put the price for what they're asking for.
And then you can see if you actually click through you can see comments or people ask questions and
they you know answer them and they can kind of go into negotiations that way.
Same thing here with like APIC NPC.
It's the same age as a forum.
You post it and it's up to you to kind of engage with whoever reaches out to you and to negotiate something
by sell shout outs.
They work very similarly but they sell them into lists so you get listed and then someone has to come
in like click this list.
And honestly I think it's just because this is not a big focus of what they do on their Web site.
So those are some ones that you could use.
I would suggest diversifying as much as possible getting listed on all the platforms you can find it
is easily 10 or so that are worth your time that will generate plenty of interest.
Now the other option was to do direct messaging and that's just like are saying an outbound strategy
so what you would do here is you would look for accounts that are in your space that you have some evidence
that they've been buying accounts which you know what end up happening is you might see an account and
it starts posting one type of content.
Then one day it kind of switches and the bio link changes oftentimes that bilingual take you to another
Instagram account or point towards another one.
You'll notice that they'll start posting repeatedly from another one.
It's a pretty good indication that someone bought it.
And if you saw that well and you could reach out to that main account and see if they're interested
in buying another one.
Generally speaking I think an outbound strategy is probably a waste of time until you get into the millions
because at that point it's actually worth spending time and really looking for a good buyer and drumming
up your own interest.
And also there's a larger sales.
Like I said before typically happen in back doors when the direct message section.
So that's where that would be appropriate.
The last thing you can do which is pretty easy is just to change your bio link.
I mean you can change it to a page where it shows that the accounts for sale in this list that it's
for sale.
Again this might hurt your following your engagement rates.
Keep that in mind.
But do you really do want to sell it.
That's a great way of doing it as well.
All right guys hopefully we've covered enough about flipping accounts.
It's not really something I think to do with innovation station.
I think most likely when you do paid promotions or affiliate marketing I think.
But that might change you can follow along in the follow along section and see where I kind of go with
it.
OK guys see you in the next lecture.