Hey guys welcome back.
All right so this lecture what we're going to talk about is how do you decide what help you need in
your work flow.
OK before we set up a workflow we identify each step in the process.
We've already established to make our photos videos stories boomerangs whatever your media type is the
next task was then systematizing out a little bit and putting it into a project management tool called
Trello so that we can see how it works at a larger vantage point and we can see in a linear fashion
how well we're doing.
What happens first what happens second what happens.
Third and that helps us kind of keep track of the process.
So I really just want you to ask yourself two questions.
One where if anywhere are you getting stuck.
Or do you feel overloaded in your process.
Go back look at the list you made or go to your Trello and see you are a bunch of task getting stuck
in one specific area.
The second question is do you have a budget.
Now what we're going to do in this section is we're going to take each individual task group and then
see if we can get someone to efficiently do them.
And your budget is going to make a pretty big difference on this and you don't have much of a budget
than you're going to have to do a lot more.
You're going to have to oversee the process a lot more and you don't have to work with cheaper freelancers.
But if you have somewhat of a budget well then you can actually step away from this process quite a
bit and you can work with people who might actually be better at what the task is than you are.
So for example let's look back at my video workflow.
And like I said before I enjoy doing that first task group.
So that was not something I wanted to get help on.
Second one writing I thought actually was probably worth getting some help on.
So I want to get a writer for that.
The next one is searching for stock video Web sites and YouTube for clips.
And then the next one was editing.
Now I could set these up into two different task groups have one person do this one person do that.
Now the complexity gets a little more complicated when I do that just because now I'm juggling two people
although one person specializing on just finding the clips saves the editor a lot of time.
Editors are generally more expensive than people who just look for media clips.
However that would take a little bit more management time for me.
And then the last thing was just kind of administrative Is that something I want to do or is it something
that I could get somebody else to do.
So for me I wanted to have three different positions.
One was this one I'm writing to was putting together the edits and finding the clips and then three
was putting everything together and scheduling it.
So go ahead and do that yourself and then see what areas you think will make sense to see if you can
find someone else to do it.
Now let's talk a little bit about what type of help is generally available.
Let's say you're doing a themed account like I am doing well.
You know if you're doing quotes Well you can get researchers it's very easy to find people online who
are willing to search through the Internet based on some requirements or basic instructions you give
them and then put everything they find into an excel sheet or whatever.
So you call that research.
Sometimes we'll just call that administration support.
Sometimes you can even call it data entry people like that typically are on the cheaper end of the scale
depending on what kind of research you need.
Or you could go as low as $4 an hour and as high as easily $30 an hour if it's something that actually
takes some level of expertise.
Now if I was hiring someone who for instance was researching legal cases then I'd have to pay them a
little bit more because they actually have to understand the cases they find in order to return the
information that I want.
But if I'm trying to do something really simple like just find a clip that matches the description OK
then that's not exactly the hardest thing in the world to do.
Now there is in general a balance you're going to realize with freelancing.
The more time you spend overseeing the cheaper they can be.
You can save money if you offload more of the management more of the quality assurance on yourself.
And if you want to step back do less of that and just get someone who understands it pretty quickly
from the get go you're just going to have to pay more.
So if your budget is low that just means that you're going to have to spend a lot more time writing
out instructions and giving them detailed step by step instructions for how to finish whatever it is
they're doing.
So like I said researchers can range anywhere from a $4 an hour all the way up to 30.
And again it just depends on what you're trying to do.
Then we have administrative assistants also known as virtual assistants now a virtual assistant or just
someone who can do manual tasks for you.
Traditionally they got popular because people started using them to make phone calls and to schedule
appointments or to go through their email and get rid of certain e-mails or to do a lot of these rote
manual tasks that virtually anyone could do if say they practiced it for 10 15 minutes no virtual assistance
you can get these extremely cheaply you can get them as cheap as $2 an hour and you can also get ones
that are more skilled have actually some critical thinking skills people who can make decisions on a
fly who are also local to wherever you are especially if you're in the United States or like Western
Europe that can be helpful for time zone reasons but also language reasons.
They have a double kind of the convenience.
And I've seen them go as high as 20 25 dollars an hour.
Now the next hireable freelancer that's pretty common is what's called a social media manager and that
is actually kind of the same thing.
So that's really just a virtual assistant who just is familiar with using social media.
Typically if you have a virtual assistant you like working with you can just use that person and show
them very quickly how to use the social media platform.
These ones just come with the knowledge kind of pre-baked And so sometimes they know best practices.
But for the most part the really the same thing.
And so the cost to hire one it's roughly the same.
Now the next thing you could easily hire would be say like a writer.
Now writers are kind of hard to price out to be honest because just the way that industry the industry
works for writers is a bit kind of strange.
A lot of freelance writers are just used to getting paid per word or getting paid per completion or
per page.
They have a lot of strange ways of getting paid if you want to do it say per hour.
Wow.
Yeah you can find people say as cheap as if you're ok working with someone who's a non-native English
speaker for instance.
Cheap is like $4 or $5 an hour depending again how complicated the task is in the U.S. or anywhere that
speaks English natively then it's generally the lowest or as seen as probably $8 an hour.
And they can easily go all the way up to 60 dollars an hour.
And really just depends on what their skill set is how much work they have how in-demand they are.
Typically writers who are called copywriters they charge a lot more and they do a lot less writing.
Why.
Because while they're in charge of writing sentences and the sentences are in charge of conversion rates
on pages that can actually end up you know being a big difference and tens of thousands or hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
So the writers it's kind of hard to say this stuff that I'm doing for instance I don't think it's really
that hard to make a summary of a new invention.
It's a little complicated and we again like medical science breakthroughs that they have to repeat the
information correctly and understand what actually is interesting to highlight that as opposed to just
picking the top five things they can find and turning those into captions.
You can also pay them for things like pay per post.
Like for instance one person I'm working with captions we just had an agreement in their pay I'm paying
them I think $12 a caption.
It's not really something I'd want to do for the long term but for the very beginning when I'm building
up a big base of post that I can recycle later on I think it's fine because they're really good at it
and they're quick at it.
Now it's just a negotiated rate that is something you can actually do.
The last thing I'll mention are video editors and again those just range.
I mean you can get them as cheap as $8 an hour all the way up to again like $80 an hour if they're really
skilled at what they do.
The way we make this cost efficient is if we want to work with a cheap video editors then we give them
some training.
We find people who don't have experience specifically in what we're doing.
They don't have a lot of demand because our skills are still kind of premature.
And then we walk them through the process like we show them how we edited it and then have them mimic
that and then slowly over time learn how to improve it.
But if you wanted someone who from day one can just jump in and look at one example video and mimic
it and do fine.
And you don't actually have to give a lot of instruction.
You have to pay quite a bit more now for those you doing accounts that require like in person work say
you're hiring a photographer again and that can vary quite a bit.
You can have people who only charge on day rates or half day rates some of them only do packages and
some of them will actually do hourly.
So let's say you're a company and you want someone to walk around and take behind the scene shots for
your Instagram account.
You're going to post.
Let's say you use these image assets over the next Like month.
I mean you could pay them.
It really just depends where you are.
You can find a college student who is interested in photography has an OK camera and has screwed around
with it quite a bit.
You can pay them $10 an hour.
Are they going to be skillful at just kind of depends.
Again it just depends how hard the actual task is.
You give them lots of instruction and tell them take photos of this specifically don't take photos of
this.
This is what we want this is what I like to see.
Here's an example then they can be OK but they can also get pretty pricey.
For instance if you work with videographer's it's going to depend on whether or not they have to bring
their own equipment.
But people who don't have equipment usually charge a day rate of 200 to 400 dollars.
People with equipment certainly depending of its really nice equipment can charge easily from four hundred
to nine hundred.
And of course you can go below and above that but this seems to be the average range.
So keep that in mind when you're thinking about whether or not you want to find someone else to do each
step in the process for you can you afford it.
And are you willing to put in the time to train them and make sure they eventually get to the point
where they can do this without you watching over their back constantly.
Now the last thing I think worth addressing is the question of whether or not you should get a generalist
or a specialist now or a generalist is a concept meaning it's someone who can do a bunch of different
things and they're probably OK.
And a specialist is someone who is just really good at one specific thing.
If you're hiring specialists that's OK that means that they might be better at one specific task but
you have to hire and juggle and manage more of them.
But on the other hand with a generalist they have more experience with the breadth of the tasks so they
can see it from beginning to end and sometimes that has benefits but they won't have specific skills
sometimes.
So for instance let's say you had a virtual assistant that you really liked and you thought hey you
know do you well what you could do is you could train them on how to do the video editing if you think
it's simple enough.
OK.
So if they could do the video editing Plus the administration tasks Plus some of the moving stuff around
and research and finding clips Well that would be kind of a generalist.
The benefit there is that it's just more convenient.
You can have one person understands the entirety of the project and not just one tiny silo of course
with specialists.
You have someone who's really good at one piece.
But like I said you have to hire them in multiple sometimes in triplicate usually with a team of specialists.
You spend more time with them but the outcome is usually better assuming you actually pick the right
people.
The last one is really good at writing someone is really good at finding great clips.
His owner is really good at putting together clips and timing them.
Well then the outcome is going to be pretty good.