Hey Hey welcome back.
OK this lecture we're going to do is talk about how you can get a phone number to use for verifying
your account how to do that relatively easy.
Now I might show you two different ways.
One is using a app called burner just on both Android and iPhone.
And the other one is a web app called next IMHO.
Now there's a lot of other ways you can do this right.
If you guys find a better way of doing it definitely go for it and post in the group discussion that
you found it.
But this works for me at the moment.
So the first one is called burner.
Now it's just an app on your phone.
So would go to Berner OK and it looks like this.
Now the idea behind this system is that you can create a lot of burner phone numbers in a burner if
you're not familiar with that term is usually first like a burner phone someone or when you would buy
a phone and then use it for one specific thing and then burn it essentially get rid of it.
That's not something that just spies use.
There's a lot of legitimate uses for this.
My favorite use for using burner actually is Craigslist.
Any time I sell something on Craigslist I'd like to use a burner phone number so that it doesn't get
passed around a million random people.
And it's also easy for me to just burn it and delete it when I don't want to see messages about my item
any more.
Like when it sells.
But for our purposes it's also quite useful as well.
So what you want to do with download the app and you'll probably see a home screen that's a little bit
different.
It's all kind of works the exact same.
So for me I just kind of go up to this hamburger sandwich at the top and go to create a burner.
Now it gives you a bunch of options and it's a credit system so you have to buy credits from them in
order to set something up.
Like I said this is the easy way of getting a phone number it's not the cheap way.
You have a picture burner.
Unlimited standard text only mini burner.
Now we only need text messages and I can't imagine that we're going to need so many text messages that
we're going to be constantly reconfirming our account.
That's why I just go with the mini burner because it's only three credits and I think three credits
Italiens of being like a couple dollars.
So I would say I want the mini burner at three credits then I can enter a name.
This is just for your reference.
It doesn't matter.
I like to use a sweet keyboard to go like this until it comes out with a random word Yemenite cure and
then enter in an area code it doesn't really matter.
Just pick any three random numbers.
They're all going to be U.S. based.
The next thing we do is next mo and those you can use international numbers if there's some reason that's
important to you.
But I can just say to an 8.
OK now here's a list of numbers.
So pick one that you like let's say 2 8 2 0 8.
OK and once cost me three credits.
OK.
Now we have a new one.
I ignore all of these settings because none of this matters.
I just want to use it to get text messages so Yemenite is right here and has our number up at the top
case you forget it.
Now what I can do is take this number put it into our account.
So that's 2 1 8 0 8 2 1 5 and then Snit.
OK.
Now I didn't create my account with the phone number so it doesn't actually need to verify it with me
right now.
But if you create your accounts from the beginning using a phone number don't e-mail address it will
actually text messaged you to make sure that's a real phone number.
Now it might feel like why do we do all this set up get ready to receive these text messages.
Well because later on they will definitely ask you to verify it as soon as you start posting soon as
you do anything that might potentially look like it's automated.
They will start asking you this.
So it's easy to just whip open your burner app and do it right there.
And the other way of doing this is an app called Nexus now.
Now next mo is it's just what's called an API platform for Vonage which is just kind of the old school
version of Skype Skype for Skype and it allows you to kind of set up phone numbers and I think the idea
is it's for developers because they can use these phone numbers plus some programming to integrate phone
numbers like text messaging or auto phone calls and stuff like that into apps.
If you've ever used an app that sends you a text message at any given point you know what I'm talking
about every time you sign up for Uber it will text message you and and you send it back a code to figure
out that you're actually a human.
They use a platform very much like this.
OK so go ahead and sign up.
I don't need to show you the sign up screen.
It's pretty standard.
Once you sign up you'll find it Administration dashboard kind of like this.
Mean it's a whole bunch of gobbledygook that's not relevant to us.
We're just going to using it for one very specific purpose.
Now over here on the left we have a section that says numbers and this is literally all we care about.
You guys could go ahead and build applications on us to make your job your life easier but this is just
not important to us.
So we got to numbers and go to your numbers.
And for me I already have numbers so it shows me some.
But if you guys don't have numbers you won't see anything here at all.
You want to do those go down to by numbers and right here you can select whatever country you want.
You know if you create an account outside of the U.S. and rever it would make sense have a phone number
that's from where you are.
So the next thing says features s.m.m voice and voice.
Well you want either s m s or ESMA and voice doesn't really matter they cost the same amount.
Really we just want this so that we can verify our accounts.
Now type they kind of trick you here because they don't actually have any landlines.
They have mobile and they have toll free.
You don't toll free you want a mobile.
OK.
Now here is where you could enter in a number for let's say if I want a specific area code I wanted
one in Buffalo New York I'm pretty sure that's actually the US the area code for Buffalo New York.
But for me I don't really care right now so we just that search.
OK well I'll give you a jillion different options.
And the way this works is you pay them 67 euro cents.
I think I said that correctly.
Per month per phone number.
Right.
So if you had 20 accounts you'll pay like I depends on the exchange rate but it's probably like $11
USD per month.
So this is pretty cheap.
The burner was a little bit more I guess it's not necessarily monthly but they have expiration dates
so you have to keep remaking them unless you buy an auto renewing line in which case doesn't a monthly
charge.
So we just pick one of these.
So I could say by now what it will usually do is I'll ask you to put money in your balance and the way
that you do that is you just go up here to balance and I already have nine euros in it.
So what you can do is do it through pal or a card or whatever once you make a payment it automatically
add to your balance.
You can do.
I think the lowest value is 10 bucks.
But again if you're doing the strategy you're going to want to at least do $10 so that you can have
this one phone number re renew over and over again.
So you go back to this and just click buy.
OK.
Now that we have our buying we have it done now I'm good to my numbers and it's right there right at
the top.
Now the way that we get our text messages from this it's a little dinky but hey it works.
Take the number right here.
Copy it.
So we want to do is go to amass over here and go to logs search messages and then right here we go search
by recipient number and type in the number.
Make sure it has the same date that you're on.
And then you'll search and it should show you the text message.
Now again I'm not using this on my account so we're not actually going to get a verify message.
But you kind of get the drift right if you're signed up and you would say oh we sent you a text message
please verify it you would give them this number and then you tell them scrammed send the code and you
come here search for the log and then you'd find a verify code.
That's a weird kind of work around but it works.
So can only knock it.
OK so that's two different ways of getting a phone number.
This is something that you will want to upload to your account.
It will give your account a higher security profile and Instagram has a tendency to constantly keep
checking to make you verify your phone number especially if you're doing anything that looks like a
bot or looks too automated.
I guarantee you this is the first time you've done this you'll run into that problem to make sure that
you have this process set up at least somewhat.
Hey guys the next lecture we will go over.
How to make some logos and then how to put those into our Instagram account.
So you the.