Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, let's go over some real quick additional criteria
that will help you narrow down your list of possible
names. And this list I'm going to give you consists
of one do and then several please don'ts.
First up, you clearly know what your business does, and
probably know a decent amount about the space you're in.
Well, if you're stuck for a name,
here's a quick little hack that might work for you,
if it's possible. Now, think to yourself, "Who are the
biggest brands in my space?" Or, more specifically, "Who
are the brands in my space that
have large Instagram accounts?"
Not every big company is big on Instagram.
Generally speaking, magazines and online publications
are in pretty much every niche and they almost
always have big accounts, but other big
companies are there potentially as well,
and hey, there might even be some of those
themed pages we talked about before.
You know, those pages that aren't really owned by a
person or a business, but they just post things based
on some general topic or theme.
There are usually big Instagram accounts in every single niche,
I think the stat is 80% of businesses have an Instagram account.
So...
So, for example, let's say you sell travel.
OK.
What's the biggest account out there for
showing pictures of, say, landscapes?
Probably Nat Geo.
I mean, you could probably find a bunch of them.
What if you sell tools or machines?
Ok, I don't know.
Is there a big themed account that just shows
off interesting robots or processes?
Anyway, if you know some of these already, then good,
and if you don't, just try searching a little bit in
the search section of the app, and then see if you
can find some monster accounts.
When I say monster accounts, I mean accounts with
followers in the millions, or at least, you know, half
a million to a million, things that are
at least famous, everyone knows it.
OK, so when you find some of these accounts,
and trust me, it's a when, not an if,
ask yourself, "Can you use their name in your name?"
Now, specifically, can the first word in your name be the
same or similar to theirs. Now, why?
Because when someone goes and searches for that
monster account, and a lot of people do usually, as they
type the full name in,
you actually have a good chance of popping up as well,
potentially benefiting enormously from that free visibility.
So let's say, if you're in, like, the entrepreneurship space.
Well, this one is actually pretty easy.
If you put in entrepreneur as your first word, because, well, a lot of people go to entrepreneur.com, they're a big Instagram account,
they have 1.3 million followers,
so in that case all you have to do is just put entrepreneur
in your name, and put it at the front, to front load it,
so when they search for the .com, they'll
actually see you in the same list.
Let's say your niche is gadgets and tech products.
OK.
Try putting, let's say, wired as the first part of your name.
Wired is close to something like 700,000 followers.
Anyway, these are easy wins.
Now, obviously, make sure the name you're using
isn't so unique that you're clearly ripping them off.
I couldn't say, like, if I was showing off hotel spaces,
probably hard to put Airbnb in the first part of my name.
Let's say there's a theoretical account called Grand Hotels, you could get away with saying Grand Hotel and then something else.
The point is, if it's too unique, then
you kind of have copyright issues.
You might end up getting a cease and desist later,
and if you get popular enough and people start to think
your account is actually run by the other account,
well, that's no good.
Also, make sure that the account is relevant.
If you sell gravel, please don't put TheRockSeller, even though TheRock has 101 million followers at the time of this recording.
Yes, The Rock has more than three times as many
followers as Barack Obama and Oprah combined.
Now, don't be shocked if you can't make it work.
It's just nice if you can. Let's go over some don'ts
that might potentially save you
from being Instagram notorious.
Now, first off try not to use an account that already has
several running accounts that are a variation of your name.
It's OK if they're similar and you are
trying to ride off of a big account.
I'm talking about, like, let's say you were Cute
Cupcakes, and there was a cute.cupcakes and a
cute_cupcakes, and a CutestCupcakes, and all three of these accounts were active, frequently posting and had a lot of followers.
Now, you can tell if they're active but just going to
their account and then seeing when the last post was,
top left is the last post. When you click the last post,
at the bottom of the image you can see a time stamp.
Now, if you have a bunch of accounts that
are similar, but none are active or serious,
then in this scenario, it's not really a big deal.
People are going to search for you and you will clearly
show up at the top of your respective search.
The problem is when you have active competitors
that at the very beginning might be bigger than you.
So, kind of awkward when you do cute cupcakes,
and someone's looking for cute cupcakes,
but the one that's very similar has more followers, you're
going to get a lot of people going to that account instead.
So, check out your name copycats, and then make
sure they aren't running the show in search.
Here's a do, OK?
Keep it simple.
The fewer the characters, the better.
Say this with me. Fewer characters are better.
It's easier to remember Great Gadgets versus
Great Cheap Gadgets and Tools.
All right.
Next up, a tip, it's a don't. Don't get frustrated and just
put a random number at the end of your account name.
Don't be that 40-year old that still uses the account
sk8erkid77 with an 8, you know, for the "ater" part.
If someone searches for your name and you have
a competitor of the same-ish name,
they will show up higher on the list because
their name would be deemed more relevant.
Also, it just kind of looks tacky if you
just stick a bunch of numbers at the end.
Also, worth saying, don't use underscores or periods.
Yeah, a lot of people do that, but it's not a good idea.
Imagine you had to tell someone
about this amazing account,
Cheap Vacations, except it's cheap_vacations.
That doesn't really sound natural, and what is
an underscore? In that same light, don't use special characters,
they just make it harder to say and remember.
Don't be tempted to change your A
to an @ and your S to a dollar sign.
Just pick a different name.
Oh, also, Instagram can't display those anyway, so
even if you've got them submitted, they wouldn't
show up. And last thing, don't use repeating letters.
Yes, it's fine if you need to do two Os for the word cool,
but I mean, don't put like Instagraamm with two As and
two Ms just because you couldn't get the normal name.
It just sounds like you have a speech impediment.
You're either yelling the name, or you
just don't know what you're doing.
OK, guys. You got it? Try, if you can, to piggyback
off other accounts if it's available to you.
There are big accounts in your niche. Find them,
see if you can start with their name. If you can,
awesome, you can, move on.
Make your name as short and simple as possible.
Don't use special characters.
Don't use repeating letters, don't use underscores,
periods, or something with a random number after it.
Next up, we're going to talk about how I chose my
name, and then the two things you can do if you really,
really, really, really want a name, but it's taken.
All right, guys. I'll see you in the next lecture.