Hey guys welcome back.
All right.
So this lecture I'm gonna make a couple image posts in Canada.
That's my preferred way of doing it for innovation station.
If you are interested in this watch and follow along.
And if you're not don't I don't care.
You can also increase the speed of the video player if you just want to skim through it to the bottom
right.
You can go all the way up to X.
OK.
So we are back at Kanva.
So what I was going to do is one make a motivational quote poster an innovation post a quote Post and
the other one I was going to do it had something to do with one of the innovations that I wanted to
cover so I kind experiment with that.
All right so step one has always is just going to be going down.
Instagram post.
Now if I wanted to I could use one of these templates.
So since it's a quote I could use that one looks pretty good.
Man this one's pretty good.
That's a style I think I'm actually going to imitate this for one of them.
I'm going to copy this for you the one where I show off some type of innovation so I might as well actually
just do that one first.
So this is what I was thinking to take this background and swap it out with an image from a story that
found the story.
They use grapheme watches.
I don't even know some form of carbon to print things on food.
And you can turn the food into circuit boards.
I don't know why you would want to do that.
I think it's more like you could track food to table tracking would be interesting.
You know a couple of their applications.
So anyway I took this image and are just going to throw it in here.
So all I have to do is cook the background and image right here so it'll pop up right there.
You see it at four.
And then once it's done I can click it and it should just kind of wave it over here.
There we go.
He took over the background.
Cool.
OK.
And then this text right here is spartan saying.
And so what is probably going to do was put a sentence description of it and then I'm going to blow
the background a little bit more and then put our branding.
So what I'll do is change it to
the
way and accent.
You go to Moudry pedia and the braid Brad copyright or that in their bread.
You can read that.
That's kind of cool.
And then all I want to do is put in my logo down here.
I'm guessing maybe the outline of the logo at the top so I'll try that.
So I have to actually pull the icon and the text out of an image from the designer.
Just take a moment.
OK I know what done that I just have to upload images.
I did these two same time.
And here
now you can use the guidelines right here to make sure that it's center aligned.
It's actually pretty helpful it's really knowing it pops up.
But OK and then up here we'll put the actual icon to the
so that would be one way of doing it.
Well I want a center line this.
There you go.
OK.
So we take a step back look at it and I'm sure.
I love the logo being up there.
I can put this in a corner.
I could put it on both innovation station.
So it depends how much readability is important to me.
So I could probably shrink it make it more minor visually at least
and then.
Yeah I think that's fine.
I might shrink this a little bit more.
OK.
And then the question is to use a font as a secondary font or use the font that's there.
Probably in this case I'll use the font if I have it that's actually being used in the logo.
Because it was you boom to go.
And then I might do some resizing just to make it fit better.
So there I go.
So that might be one way of doing it.
I could also mess with this.
It's not all caps.
I wanted to and I also bowled it.
That's another thing is that it's an old I'd also tweak the spacing.
You notice how spaced out these words are it's kind of strange.
I can pull it back a little bit and the line height too is another one that seems a bit odd.
You can roll that back a little bit.
I don't know if I like having caps anyway.
OK.
So that's I think decent.
It's a little bit hard to read but that's about it.
You know I might if this is the case add another filter to this so I might filter it and then make it
low contrast So you see what's happening is it kind of fades of the background just a little bit that
can help like you can still see that it's toast.
You just don't need to see everything down here or you can add some other stuff that we had before.
I mean another way of doing this would be to out a blur.
You can just blurt out.
But personally I prefer if they can see what it is.
I don't know what an anti border is.
I guess it's more like pixillated it's an interesting effect in and of itself.
But again kind of hard to read.
So we will get rid of that weird effect that so I threw back the contrast and yet I think that's about
it.
OK.
So I think that's actually pretty good.
So what I would do is download that and now I have a post that we can post OK.
Let's move on to the second image so we can start another one by going back here and go do the same
thing that we did before Instagram post just in this way it saves it.
I mean there's other ways of doing it.
But I'm stuck in many ways.
What we do now is a motivational quote.
And so for this one actually I'm going to use the background that I had designed so I'll just upload
it as a photo frame that on there it'll snap fit usually if I needed to crop it croppings right there
works pretty simple.
You just hit it and then you can pick how are you going to crop it.
OK.
So that's already done for me.
And then all I could do is throw them the quote.
So I got a text and these already have a font I'm but this is how you do custom text you just pick one
of these.
So I might do that and then I went to Brini quote dot com.
There's a million places to get quotes.
I literally typed in innovation.
This one came up.
I kind of like this.
Dean Kamen is an interesting inventor made the Segway also makes prosthetic arms.
It's near and dear to my heart.
So put in his quote and get rid of the brainy quote thing.
In the break.
I don't know jack.
And we've got to go back to beento
let's make it want to read it.
So a lot of this just comes down to tweaking.
To be honest like you just said a lot of time messing with the alignment messing with the font size
and just messing with like spacing it just looks right to you.
There's no it's not much of a science to it.
It's also kind of based on preferences.
So generally one thing is that I wouldn't ever have contracted Why are spacing like this.
It's just hard to read.
So I hate sharing that a little bit and I think that's pretty easy to read but you should probably make
it larger.
Boy bullshit like the other one did you get size and just keep kind of tweaking it till we get where
we want to go.
OK so that looks fine.
I don't like the way this one little thing at the end is kind of a hanger on.
That's all that hard to read to see if I can.
OK that's better.
Usually you want to go for something it's symmetrical.
It doesn't waste a ton of space.
Shrink this just so not hitting the edges like that.
You can do custom font sizes.
Or you know the whole thing is that you won't be able to read the quote from a thumbnail but if it's
reduced much more than say like what's in your feed then I mean you can't possibly make it legible at
that point.
So OK there you go.
And then we will just copy and paste this to get another text online.
You can just do the same thing over there if you want it to just do things this way.
Then don't put his name
and then typically you would want to like change the weight of the font on your we want to
crime.
So to get a person saying it's not usually a big deal there.
That's the point of the post.
OK.
So I think this is getting better.
Last thing I want to do is I want to add in quotes like there's air quotes in the back sometimes of
quotes and one and two.
So what I'm going to do with this actually is just turn this white and then lower the capacity to the
point where you can barely see it.
So it would be annoying if I didn't lower the opacity.
But since I do it's like what.
Barely see it.
And that's kind of the point.
It's kind of like it's floating in the distance or something.
And then you put up here I personally I like when it overlaps a little bit.
Check the transparency setting that but on the other ones to make it match the seven
OK and last adjustments OK.
Cool.
Right so that works.
That's a quote right there.
You can read it.
It's easy to read got cool colors might all of that posting the same thing over and over again as template.
But this is a good one for if you're just in a jam and you want to just throw up a quote It's always
easy to do.
And it's helpful that I had a template made.
All right now we can look at the beautiful things that we've made.
This one quote very nice colors and this one also solid really good colors.
I think that's kind of catchy and then you'd want to read the caption or subscribe or something like
that.
These are pretty easy so I think this is a great strategy for filling in the gaps if you just need to
make something really quickly.
You saw that and that took me I don't know 10 minutes to make those two.
You can also show someone else how to do it.
We'll cover that when you can.
On a mission.
But anyway I like the output.
Next lecture.