All right guys, we're back.
Last lecture, we talked about what hashtags are.
They're just those words that have a pound symbol in front of it and they're used in social media to auto-categorize posts.
Some social networks like Facebook don't really use
them, because finding new friends on their platform
isn't really a big priority for them.
But for Twitter it is a big deal. Twitter invented
the hashtag actually, by the way. Since you
guys are from the future, just post in Slack
and tell me if Twitter is profitable yet.
I have a feeling future Evan won't be surprised.
Probably not.
Instagram hashtags are a big deal and one of the few ways Instagram gives us to expand the reach of our posts.
So how do we do it effectively
and without looking like an idiot?
Well, there are some quick rules of thumb
that are considered best practice.
Number one, should you use them to begin with?
Yes, dummy.
We just went over that, they're kind of important. Photos with hashtags get something like 20% more engagement on average.
Number two, how many can you use at once?
Well, at this moment you can only add
a maximum of 30. Them's the rules.
Number three is, how many should you use?
Ok, now this is a kind of a bizarre question that has been debated and continues to be debated pretty much everywhere.
It's probably the first question someone new to a Social Media Marketing Facebook group asks and it usually starts
a massive flood of comments all contradicting each other.
Some people say to use them sparingly.
Some say to use a medium amount, and some
say to just max them out, balls to the wall.
There are a few big studies that make the argument for each one.
There was a study by Track Maven, for instance,
that for some reason shows that something
like 15 hashtags is the perfect combination for
engagement, and that 14 and 16 are sub-optimal.
Go figure.
Well, I'm going to say no, I don't really buy this,
and just ignore pretty much everything that people
say about these things in general.
Now, the reason people say you should use few is
because it might look tacky if you use too many.
Later we'll talk about where they go and you'll learn
immediately that this is not actually a valid point.
So is there any reason we shouldn't just
max out the post with 30? As far as I can tell,
I've seen no evidence to suggest that there's an advantage
to not posting the maximum number of these things,
So that's what we're going to do.
30 it is.
Now, let's circle back to the point about where they go.
Now, Instagram originally wanted you to post your
hashtags in the caption,
so underneath every photo you'd actually see just a
chunk of hashtags or a weird sentence that's like
intermixed with them instead of words.
Now, that looks pretty much like crap, so naturally what
people started to do was just post them in the comments
instead. That way, your caption looks perfectly normal and the hashtag gaudiness is actually pushed down the post visually.
People started doing this and, well,
Instagram, like usual, didn't really care.
Fact: hashtags anywhere in your
post will categorize your posts.
You don't actually have to post them in the caption.
This is kind of a rookie mistake that a lot of people make.
So just post them in the comments,
unless you just want to look bad.
If you want to go even further and you really care
about the aesthetics of your post, then just post
the 30 hashtags in the first comment of your post
and then just manually add three more posts.
Why?
Well, because it will hide the tacky block of hashtags
and make your post look a little more legitimate.
Now, what do you post in these first three comments?
Well, you have some options, they're all kind of silly.
You could continue a caption or add another call to action,
but personally I just think it's just
too much work in general.
What I like to do is just post a bunch of dots.
So put dot dot dot in each post.
So it just looks like it's blank and you wouldn't actually want
to unfold all the comments, or, even weirder, post emojis.
Emojis, now remember, add color and personality,
so it's another way of sticking out just a little bit.
They're not just made for, like I said, Japanese teenagers.
You'll see me doing this in the follow
along sections, so don't laugh.
So how do you pick the right hashtags?
Well, how do you determine what curated
feeds you want your stuff to show up in?
Well, I kind of wish there was a specific answer to this,
but since we have virtually no data about these
things, we kind of just have to go off with what seems
to work. The best way to do this is to start by just
thinking of common adjectives of words
that relate to your post and your account.
If you post a photo of like, a marathon,
there are some obvious ones: #running,
#marathon, #competition, #hardwork, etc.
If you post a nice looking boat, the guess what?
You're probably going to put #boat, #ocean, #adventure,
#iownaboat, something like that.
How you expand out from there just comes
down to two things: visualization and research.
Now, when I say visualization, I mean visualize who you
think it is going to be using this hashtag to find new posts.
Remember, there has to be a reason to search for
that hashtag in the first place, so what is the reason?
If we were back in our marathon photo,
who exactly is searching for #running? People
who are probably obsessed with running.
That is pretty easy.
So the question then becomes, do you want
running enthusiasts to see your profile?
Is that the type of crowd you're trying to attract?
Well, it depends on what your
account is and what your brand is.
You want the most specific crowds you can, because
the people that fit your audience profile are going to
engage more, which means you'll have higher rates of engagement, which means blah blah blah, Instagram's algorithm
will actually like you.
What about #competition?
OK, well, who exactly would be searching for that?
Honestly, I'm not entirely sure.
Maybe someone looking for action
shots of sports or something like that.
Now, with every hashtag you use, ask the
question, "Who would be searching for this?"
If you're posting a photo of makeup, well, then hashtags like #makeup and #lipstick and #eyeliner kind of make sense.
What doesn't make sense would be #cute or #beautiful.
Now, the person searching for #cute is probably looking
for fluffy animals or floofs, and a person searching
for #beautiful is probably either searching
for landscapes or, yes, you guessed it, models.
With that being said, if you have a photo of the desert,
don't put #hot, because you know exactly what people
are searching for that one for. Now,
the more astute of you out there might have asked
out loud, "Why worry about the type of person using
a hashtag when you haven't even established
that anyone is searching for that hashtag at all?"
For instance, what's the point of analyzing
#bestideaformyaccount
if no one is searching for it to begin with? And
that's what brings me to the second part of picking
the best expansion hashtags,
that was that one thing called research.
You can research it, just go to the Explore tab
and type in the hashtag, you'll see it pop up in the
list if it has a following.
If it doesn't show up, then no one is searching for it,
and you just wasted your time and maybe your life.
OK, so that's the basics of picking the right hashtags.
We're going to get more in the mud
with this later in a later section when
we cover the tools that you use, how to rotate hashtags,
what constitutes a saturated hashtag, etc.
But for now, this is really all you need to
know to get in and get started posting.
Use 30, hide them in the comments,
use the obvious ones first and then when you expand,
you just need to be creative but also diligent figuring
out which hashtags have enough of an audience and at
the same time have the right audience for your profile.
OK, goodbye.