All right guys welcome back.
So this lecture we're going to do is go over five or six best practices associated using Instagram stories.
Now you watch this entire section and you're not entirely convinced about whether or not you should
use stories.
Well I don't necessarily blame you.
I think it's a kind of nice to have not necessarily a need to have.
Like I said before there are teams out there or accounts that focus on their stories more than their
posts and that's just because they find that it's easier to take advantage of that 24 hour and then
disappear kind of mentality of stories.
And also some people have just found that their followers respond to that more.
But for most of you I think it's worth trying and then seeing if it is something that is worth the amount
of effort.
As far as I'm concerned when I look at my analytics it's not like it's obvious that these are making
a huge contribution to our account.
But when I look at how much time and effort it takes it's just nothing.
So any little benefit I get from it I think is generally worth it.
I also think it makes the account look better because it looks like it's more active.
So the first best practice I would say with Instagram stories is being careful about not posting too
many.
Now when you think not too many you might think Oh he means don't post for a day or three a day.
No actually this isn't like posts with stories you can get away with a lot more because it's literally
just a click to move on.
But what you'll notice is if for instance you have more than 15 like the bar is much much higher you'll
find a lot of people actually end up muting you and that's not good or what'll happen is they'll see
so many that they're less likely to even view the ones that you have.
And they'll just click through it really really quickly and then it will end up happening is Instagram
will see that your completion rates are just going down or the steeply go down very quickly.
And so when Instagram shows their stories on the home page it's actually going to put it later on in
the list so it's even less likely that someone will even get to it.
So not too many.
But keep in mind too many is actually a lot right.
You could post 10 a day and that's perfectly fine.
Number two is trying to make sure that you have a point with it right.
It's one thing to just post something that says hey funny dog or hey this was funny.
You need to make sure that there's some point right.
Like when we post it because we want people to go look at our posts or if I post a poll it's because
I need information from them so don't post something that's just static content that's not going to
get a response or get them to go do something.
And the best way honestly to make sure that you do this is just to make sure that you have called actions.
Now a lot of people don't use called actions and it's kind of.
But I think it's probably the best thing you can do.
Add something at the very end that says you know like tell us if you like this.
What do you think.
Or get them to go to your page and actually post on one of the posts or do something like that.
You need some form of engagement to get them off of just kind of brainlessly clicking through if you
have too much of a passive and scream story strategy.
What you'll find is that your stats just kind of end up flatlining.
They don't really seem to grow and they don't really seem to die.
It just seems like you have a lot of people that is mindlessly going through it.
Number theory is you need to make sure that you're posting these right around the same time that you're
posting your actual post.
I don't mean that you have to do exactly what innovation nation does where we just like post something
immediately after we make the actual regular post.
What I mean is that you need to follow the same standards that you use with posting and that you need
to post when your audience is a week and during their highest engagement points and or.
Generically speaking.
9:00 a.m. 12:00 noon 6:00 p.m. I believe it was.
And then like 11:00 and 2:00 a.m. Those are those hot spots where a lot of people are active.
Of course it could be different for your followers specifically and that's why it's really important
that you sign up for some basic analytics like Arcano Square will just tell us when our followers are
most active.
The reason why this is important is every time you post a story it jumps the line and for the stories
list.
So if you're posting these say when your primary audience is asleep they'll still have it cued up to
watch it just by the time they wake up they'll have to watch like 10 sets of stories before they even
get to yours.
So it actually makes sense to use the same posting strategy with regards to timing for your stories.
Number four is really get used to using stickers that is just something that makes this so much more
worthwhile it's so easy to decorate something easily by throwing confetti on it or an emoji or a smiley
face or something like that.
That's the easiest part about this.
Don't try to treat this like you know you're making some beautifully designed Photoshop image you put
a lot of time into it and then put in your story.
That's kind of defeating the purpose.
Use emojis and the stickers to bridge that gap.
Well that being said also you need to focus on using location tags using hash tags stickers and even
mentioning people as well because that actually is what's going to take this from being a static strategy
of just getting your already followers to come back to your page which is fine.
But you can then use it to actually increase your reach.
So it's really easy just add a couple of hashtags to it just like you would a post and then all of a
sudden you know that in the analytics you're getting views from areas of the app that you wouldn't traditionally
have had.
So you're kind of chasing opportunity if you're not using these hash tags and tags and location tags
to get the stories farther out there and in front of eyeballs that haven't seen your account before.
And then the last thing I'll say is just make sure you get creative and mix it up.
Right there's a lot of opportunities here for your company.
So easy to just film something your employees are doing are behind the scenes cut.
It's really easy if you're an individual to just flip it open and talk directly to your followers say
what's on your mind say some lesson you learned today something like that.
People really do like that type of content.
Also don't be afraid to use things like user generated content.
Right if someone puts a really funny comment on your and scram post screenshot it put some stickers
on it and put a comment and then post as a story.
People really enjoy that stuff.
So just try to get creative people to get the most creative with these are rewarded the most.
Why.
Because if you actually play around with different formats and you actually make every single story
different you're just going to have a lot higher engagement.
People are going to predictably actually watch each one because they know that the next one could be
totally different than the one before and I admit this is something that we kind of rule we break with
innovation station we kind of keep it simple by posting the posts that we have.
If I was spinning a little more more time on stories I'd put a little bit more time into this but as
a themed account I generally think stories are not as important.
But I still obviously still think they're worth doing.
So that's it.
Get creative.
Honestly find things that you think are funny and rotate them take quotes from some of your customers
and throw it up there whatever it is you're doing at the moment could do a very quick 10 second clip
of it.
Throw some stickers on there and there you go.
All right guys that's it for now.
Those are the six rules or pieces of advice I've found work the best of course everybody's strategy
is a little bit different.
Do you guys have anything that's worked really well for you.
Make sure to post in the sac or post in the Q&amp;A and tell us why it worked or how you did it and we can
discuss it.
All right guys.
That being said Roland in the next section the.