Hey guys welcome back.
OK so let's round out what we were finishing in the last lecture by finishing the job post that we're
going to use for up work to find a video editor for our project.
Now remember I'm just filling this out as if I were hiring a video editor.
But the same rules and systems are going to apply to essentially whatever you hire whether it's a writer
and editor or a clip finder someone who actually goes out and shoots their own footage.
It's all going to kind of fall the same pattern.
You always fill it out with the what and the why and the how and the when and then you end with this
mysterious section called the extras.
The extras are where I like to put anything I couldn't fit somewhere else.
Right.
Anything you can think of that might be relevant like how you're going to communicate.
We're going to communicate through slack or what project management tools you might use anything you
can think that might be relevant I might tell them that there's a keyway process they have to go through
it might describe how they're going to communicate with me directly.
I might even give them a specific ask to put into their cover letter when they apply.
Now the main thing I put in extras though is what we call a trial.
Now when you're hiring people and keep in mind I have entire courses on outsourcing so if you guys want
to learn how to do this in a much more in-depth way or at least understand the background behind it
or a more comprehensive understanding of it then check those out.
But for now we're just going to kind of scratched the surface such that you can be proficient at posting
a job post but one of the things I found that is the most effective thing with hiring contractors is
doing a trial or trials.
Pretty simple.
You take whatever it is that are supposed to be doing and take one very small task of it and then ask
them to do it before you hire them.
Now there's obviously going to be a balance between what you ask them to do and what they're going to
be expected to do for their entire job.
So if if you're trying to make them make videos I would try to look for some tasks that I think will
only take let's say 30 minutes 30 to 45 minutes something like that.
I think you could do half of video in that.
So what I might ask them do is do a half video do collect videos for three mini captions that are usually
like four to six and assemble them together in this type of format.
And that's what I might ask them to do beforehand.
The thing with contractors is just that it's almost impossible to know whether or not they're going
to return something you like.
It's impossible to know at the very beginning whether or not they're just saying everything they think
you want to hear.
Or if they even have even the slightest understanding of what you're asking them to do.
So the best way to just get through that muck is to ask them to show that they can do it.
Now depending on the industry and what you're hiring for this is less common and sometimes more common
with writers it's very common.
They actually sometimes will just offer up a sample to begin with with video editors.
It's probably a little less common just because their work is more time intensive.
So in order to show you something of worth it could take them a lot of time.
Do they want to invest all this time if they're not going to get the job.
Typically the way I get around this is by offering paid trials.
So if it's one of those cases where let's say you're getting feedback to people saying they don't want
to do a trial it's going to take too much time.
Then you can say we can do paid trials.
And the way you would do that is essentially hire them all the same.
But you would set limits on their contract such that they can only work for a certain amount of time
and then that way they automatically get paid for it.
If you don't like it you can just in the contract there.
Now if you don't want to pay for the trial I mean you could certainly try to get them to do it for FREE.
Just keep in mind that's going to lower the number of people who respond to you or actually complete
the trial.
If they're doing a really big project in it a lot of people applying that I might say just do this trial
and it's not paid.
And I would get enough people to choose from.
But just keep in mind sometimes it's not always the case.
So in this case what I probably would have done is in this trial I would give them a very basic description
I mean even put this in a separate doc like a Google sheet or an Evernote doc and in that duck I would
say here's some video clips or.
Here are the actual captions for a video.
Here's the link to the stories you understand the context of it.
Please assemble these three captions together with matching media according to the parameters of the
job post and then send them to me and tell me when you're done.
It might actually take a little more management time from you but once they do this it's pretty much
impossible to hire someone who doesn't know what they're doing.
Right.
Because you have removed a lot of the uncertainty.
So anyway make sure you're using this as some kind of a mechanism just to see whether or not they can
follow instructions and deliver what they can.
You can even minimize this as much as possible.
I've even done trials where the trials just to answer a question and the message that they send to you
and they apply.
You'd be amazed at how many people don't read the entire job post.
And I just use that as a least a very weak filtration system for who I'd then go and actually look through
you want to spend your entire time looking through every single person applying because the simpler
the task is the more these contractors start to blur together.
OK so let's go back to our job right here and we'll just go ahead and paste in the post here.
Now if I were doing this for real I would have filled this out.
You know some of the sections aren't completely done and I would remove what why why how when.
But you kind of get the point.
So I put that in there if I had additional project files I might put them in here and this is a great
place if for instance I described a trial here I could put the video clips here or the captions here
that they're supposed to use in the trial.
Sometimes if I'm running a project and I don't have anything live to show them I might upload some video
files that I made that do match my standard and that's something that would be extremely effective here.
A lot of people will ask for that like hey have you made a video before.
At this point I have.
So I could very easily upload that.
Then what is it next.
OK then it says what type of project do you have one time project ongoing project.
I'm not sure to you what you want a one time project means that you know there's a deadline already
ongoing means it could end in the future you just don't know when.
And this is obviously I'm not sure.
So I typically say like ongoing project solely for this cause I don't know when I'm going to start content
production now.
Now we have our screening questions and these I think are extremely important.
What I usually put are just questions to make sure they are the right fit.
So if for instance I am requiring everyone to work in Adobe Premiere I might ask them a question what
video editing software do you use.
If they respond with Sony Vegas then clearly they didn't read the post or they're just not a good fit.
You can also just do things like ask them questions based on the job posts.
You can ask them generic things like how long have you worked on video editing.
I've done things like please link me to a video that is the most similar to the videos I was referencing
and the outpost one thing the video editors specifically is that they have a portfolio and they'll just
dump that on you.
And a lot of times it's 60 70 videos and you have no idea which ones are relevant.
I'd much prefer they pick one or two that shows directly that they can do the skills that I need them
to do and then show me that.
So you can select from suggested are recent.
Those are usually not very good or create your own questions so I might typos in there so I might say
link to a video you've made in the last two years I might put a time requirement on it just because
if they made this 10 years ago that means most likely it's just going to look out of date ten years
ago what was popular was not popular now so I want to make sure that these are active skills they're
using.
That matches the criteria of the video.
Yes.
That might be a little wordy but you kind of get the point now that I've added that I could add more
if I wanted to.
Usually I add to.
If it's a really simple task just one if it's a really big task where I'm going to be really picky about
who I hire I'll do maybe three.
And then let's see sometimes also even to ask them questions like What do you think of this video and
link them to a video and just see the reactions because sometimes I like to make sure that the person
actually has thoughts about it because that's very useful.
OK.
And the last thing is do you want them or have a cover letter now a cover letter is kind of a double
edged sword.
No that means is when they apply they're going to have to write something to you why they're interested
in the job what they've done in the past that's relevant it's just like when you apply to a job you
have a cover letter specifically addresses while you're applying this.
Now for me it's great because I want them to articulate why they care I don't want someone who is just
applying en masse to jobs didn't even know what they are applying to.
And then it soon became an issue as soon as I try to actually hire them.
But at the same time you might run into an issue where a lot of people will just give you templated
stuff a lot of times people just use the same cover letter.
Maybe they modify a couple of words in it and it's not particularly useful because what they're going
to do is just quote their portfolio which you could have seen anyway just by clicking on their profile.
So anyway I usually ask for a cover letter just because you know if they send me a template and one
I don't like it I can just use that as a filtering criteria.
And if they do actually send me one that's great.
I'm not expecting them to write some you know a thousand word essay I just need to make sure that they've
actually thought about it and know what they're applying to next.
Now what skills and expertise are most important to you.
Now typically what I do here is I'll pick a broad category specific category ones.
OK so if I'm hiring video editors I'll get something really broad like video editing.
OK.
Now the reason I picked is because now it's going to show up to anyone who is listed as video editing
but then pass that.
Now I want to get specific.
Right.
Like if I'm only using Adobe Premiere than I want Adobe Premiere specifically.
Now if you're into video editing you might not necessarily be in it.
There'll be premiere and even pass that I might ask for something that's really specific.
Like will say kinetic type Barfy.
Right.
That's a type of editing technique where they just have a lot of text that moves around a lot.
Very common in say like explainer videos.
OK so these are not absolutely required but I'm just saying that broadly you're into video editing.
Check this out and then pass that it's going to help you in Premiere.
And if you have skills in this all the better you can also do more generic things up here like motion
graphics or animation or even just video post editing or videography but those typically fall into this
category.
Don't ask me what the DNC video post editing and video editing is.
I'm not even entirely sure.
Anyway just trying to make sure you pick at least two of these.
Don't try to go over five.
I think they actually stop at around 6 so it doesn't really add any value.
If anything it looks like your job is too restrictive.
So if you're people will apply than it next then it's up to you.
You want USA only or worldwide.
I don't really care what region they're in.
You know if you're working on a project that was really important that you worked in the same exact
time and communicated and in order to make the product well everyone had to be in sync.
Then maybe you want to pick someone who's in the same time zone but for the most part I don't really
care.
This will get me more applications other than that you can set location preferences and I generally
find this pointless just because if I say worldwide but I prefer United States it doesn't make a difference.
No one's gonna see that and go oh they're open to world wide but I'm in Canada but they want United
States.
I'm not going to apply.
It's usually just ignored.
Ok you have visibility.
Anyone.
Only up or freelancers invite only invite only only works if you are literally going to spend their
time and go and find every single person that you want to apply to your job.
That's a waste of time.
This is also generally a waste of time unless for some reason what you're doing is sensitive and you
don't want to have all this information is out in the wild and indexable.
Keep in mind once you hire someone this is going to disappear.
So it's not going to be on google anymore but this does help with other people who are searching for
jobs.
So this will get you a little bit of a boost.
Again I only use this if I have something some kind of IP or confidentiality that I want to keep.
Then out here I can put how many freelancers do you need one or many.
Generally my strategy here is if I'm not sure if I want more or multiple click this OK and then I'll
put like 2 and the reason why is because if they put two or three people are more likely to apply.
I just say one and they come in they're like oh crap he's already got 30 applications that's just going
to act as a deterrent to people applying.
So I usually just say like two or three.
OK now here qualifications.
This would be kind of like where we were setting skills that we actually think are important.
But now this is just something that they can check on more thing to make sure they have the right skills.
I don't find this useful because people don't really actually read it so I just it.
Next the next thing is pay by the hour pay by a fixed price.
Now you guys are outsourcing courses.
You've probably seen me go over this section in over ten minutes just talking about the differences
between the two.
In this case we're really just doing hourly.
You could do fixed price and all you'd have to do is say it's a fixed price per video but the expense
is kind of frustrating because I don't know what the price of video at.
If you guys have a hard budget then that might actually be a good strategy if you only pay 20 bucks
of video then do that and say 20 bucks because people look at it I can do it for 20 bucks will not apply.
Saves you a lot of time.
For me I'm just doing hourly a lot of times what I do is do hourly and then as I figure out how long
it takes each person that I might switch it to a fixed price just so I can then contain my cost and
predict them.
But for the most part I was sick this way.
Now here you are going to decide what do you need do you want extremely great video editing where you
don't need to explain a lot to them.
Or are you OK with managing them more giving a more instruction and having them kind of learn on the
job and you pay less.
Or do you want something in the middle.
For me I generally go for the middle.
I like value personally.
It's nice to work with an expert.
You don't tell them much and pretend to give you something you are impressed by it but at the same time
they kind of hurt your bank account.
So that's kind of where I kind of Goldilocks land in the middle.
Down here is fine.
I just don't want to spend that much time managing them.
OK then you have how long does the project expect to last.
That's I mean pretty straightforward.
How long are you thinking to do this.
For me it's probably one to three months.
I like that and then.
Do you have time requirements now.
The way that they're trying to make you break this down is is it full time or is it part time.
Can they do this and a bunch of other things.
Or should they only be doing this and then this is I don't know.
I always picked that one.
Unless of course I was hiring one individual to do all of the videos.
In that case I might say I only want a full time person because if they're part time I might not be
able to rely on them.
So that's up to you.
Do you want hire multiple people part time you and hire one person full time.
It's just up to you.
Sometimes it's nice to work with one person at the same time.
It's hard to find people who are full time available and also you might have a time restriction and
when they start.
So keep that in mind that's going to definitely lower down the pool that you're looking for.
So I say I don't know yet.
Then next then you can review your post.
That's great.
OK.
And then when you are done with that you post job now.
OK so now what you going to do is hit this screen right here.
Now it's after you've seen your job post you can invite freelancers or you proposals and then you can
hire That's the general process.
Now here's where I really really strongly suggest you spend 10 20 minutes depending on what you're hiring
for.
If you just leave this up by itself and you go away it is a good chance you will only get like four
or five people will apply for the next 48 hours.
I sit here and I go to every single person and I just click invite to job and then it will automatically
take them to my job and send invitation and I just go down and I find anybody who's matching my profile
like if I'm ok with them being outside the country maybe their English is OK but they're a reasonably
priced person for a video editor then I might click that OK or maybe I want really really cheap editors
which if you know if you go on the long haul then that's sometimes the rate to go.
Then I could say $10 an hour and I want to make sure that my attention comes from people who are on
the $10 an hour range.
There are other filters here that can be pretty useful English level.
I don't really screw around with because they have to self-assigned their English.
So I've met a lot of native or bilingual English speakers who do not speak English very well earned
amount just means how long they've been on the on the platform.
Why does that matter.
Well because that means they care about the reviews or if they have no earnings in the account that
means that they could very easily just disappear if they have a bad experience or if they can't meet
your deadlines they're just not going to have that reputational poll that's and require them to come
back.
I mean things like Job Success.
I've got a lot of success of just all this.
Just knowing that not very many people are going to apply if I go like this.
But knowing that the people that apply are people that take their freelancing career seriously.
Some people just do it very much on the side when and if they have time and if they have a full time
job in addition to their freelancing that sometimes can get in the way and you have periods of time
when they disappear and don't like that freelancer type.
That's up to you.
I don't generally like working with agencies just because that means that there's a project management
layer and I'm paying extra for essentially the same work especially in this situation there are situations
where agencies are better especially if you need creative help or creative direction.
But in this case I don't.
Hours build in last activity are essentially kind of an extension of this.
It's kind of the same thing showing how active they are in the category sometimes if like so for instance
these are key words they'll use to search sometimes I'm searching for something it doesn't necessarily
fall within a direct category so I might say oh I only want people who match these keywords in this
specific category.
So friends is the like of us hiring someone for an outreach campaign.
And I wanted them to do research online.
Well if I type in internet research and then I don't pick a category it's going to find a lot of people
who only do internet research and they're not necessarily versed in marketing or versed in PR campaigns
or outreach campaigns that I might want to do is type in outreach and then specifically go and find
marketing as a category and then select that.
OK so that's typically how I use those.
Make sure you go and you spend some time clicking invite just to glance through these make sure they
fit your general idea.
Sometimes you know it's fine if you click on someone and bite them and you're like oh wait I didn't
want that person.
It doesn't matter right.
Who knows if they're going to apply and if they do apply you can kind of ignore them.
Unless of course they have a great proposal.
Keep in mind you can only invite I think it's like 50 people a day.
But my strong suggestion is if you want to hire someone quickly and to get some of the best proposals
that I think you should try to maximize that as much as possible.
Also keep in mind you're hiring multiple people in multiple jobs so blow all 50 on one job.
OK guys.
So with that being said next lecture what we'll do is we'll go over the post I used to hire the video
editors that I currently work with.
We can go over some of the conversations and some of the trials that I ran.
OK.
See the.