Welcome back everyone.
This lecture on machine learning knowledge most state of science rules are going to require you to understand
the various aspects of machine learning to some degree especially roles that have the word data scientist
or data science or product science or product analysis in them.
Now certain rules like a machine learning engineer are really going to be focusing on these concepts
both theoretically and in implementation and application.
So this ask us what different general topics you should be aware of and have an understanding of you
should understand what supervised learning is and how it's different than unsupervised learning or how
it's different than reinforcement learning.
And we should also understand the core algorithms of supervised learning things like linear regression
logistic regression support vector machines ran the forest came nearest neighbors accepter.
Then you should also understand unsupervised learning and how it's different than supervised learning
how it doesn't require a label a should understand the main algorithms surrounding unsupervised learning
things like Kamins clustering principal component analysis that Minch Naledi reduction ex cetera and
then depending on what different types of job positions you're applying for you may want to know about
specialized machine learning fields such as an LP or a natural language processing.
So if you notice that the opposition is going to be working with text data a lot you'll definitely want
to have the general principles of natural language processing down.
And then you also want to understand just things that relate to machine learning in general regardless
of what learning you're using things like model validation or K Foldes cross-validation etc..
So you're going to want to understand these basic concepts things like bhai's various tradeoff in the
sense the difference between L1 and L2 regularisation and regularisation school is in general.
And then maybe you'll also want to understand Bagni and boosting and how it relates to certain machine
learning algorithms such as decision trees or random force.
So you can definitely check out the extra resources we have linked to this lecture.
If you want different sources for learning this sort of material.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.