Welcome back to the solution for probability question number three.
So here are the questions a little different than the previous one.
It was what is the probability of rolling at least one four with two dice.
So let's think about this for at least one dice.
We need to think about which combinations are in the form either 4 and then some other roll some of
the roll and then four or you can get four or four.
So if we take a look at all the possible ways of rolling dice we end up realizing that when looking
for those combinations where either one of the dice the first one is a.
The second one is a four or both of them happened to be fours.
There's eventually 11 possible ways so that the answer is then 11 out of 36 probability that you end
up rolling a four Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.