Welcome to interview question number seven for probability theory OK here's the question.
Let's imagine you're given 10 coins and out of those 10 coins nine are fair coins.
But one of them is biased.
You were told that the biased coin has a probability of greater than 0.5 to be heads.
So overall when you're flipping that coin there's a greater than 50 percent chance of it being heads.
So it's biased.
The other nine are fair coins.
Let's imagine that you randomly grab a coin flip it three times and you end up getting heads heads tails
or h h t.
The question is based on that fact.
What is the probability that you flipped the biased coin.
So in other words was the probability that when you randomly grab the coin it ended up being the biased
one based on the fact that you flipped heads heads tails.
All right.
Best of luck.
I'll see you at the solutions.