Welcome everyone to the solution for probability.
Question number seven.
So just a quick overview of the question you were given 10 coins nine of which were fair and one which
was biased and you were told that the biased coin has some probability p greater than 0.5 to be heads
so that it's biased in the heads more often in tails and you randomly grab one of these 10 coins.
Flip it three times and you get heads heads tails.
What does a probability flipped the biased coin in recall from the notes in the lecture before the interview
question.
You have to solve this in terms of the probability p.
There's no way to just get a straight answer from this sort of solve the sexual problem.
You're going to need to use the base theorem and the Bayes Theorem.
Remember it describes the probability of an event based on prior knowledge of conditions that might
be related to the event such as the prior knowledge that one out of these 10 coins was biased.
So let's take a look at Bayes theorem here we can see that we have the conditional probability on the
left hand side.
So the likelihood of event a given that B is true is equal to the probability of the likelihood of events
B given that is true of times probability of occurring divided by the probability of be occurring.
And there is an expanded alternative that you can use in case you don't know some of these probabilities
directly.
You can plug more in.
So let's go ahead and work this out.
Basically we're going to do first is fill in what we know so we're going to be the stand for bias the
probability of it being the biased coin and h h t is going to stand for the probability of flipping
heads heads tails.
So we know that the probability of flipping heads heads tails given that it was biased is equal to the
probability of flipping heads times probability of flipping heads those probability of flipping tails
each of those given that it was a biased coin and then we know that the probability of the coin being
biased given the fact the flipped heads heads tails is going to be equal to the probability of heads
tails given that it was biased times the probability of it being biased divided by the probability of
flipping heads heads tails.
So now we're going to do here is plug in all of this stuff for probability of HHC or heads heads tails
given in the event that it was biased.
So here we go.
If we plug in those probabilities then we get something that looks like this is the base theorem.
And if you need to pause the screen I would recommend that you manually plug these in yourself to make
sure that you fundamentally understand these probabilities here.
That basically what we did is we just use Bayes Theorem and we plug them everything that we needed for
probability of flipping heads heads tails given the bias is true OK.
So let's go ahead and figure this out.
So what we're going to do is start plugging in one by one some of these probabilities in terms of p
so that we can actually get some sort of result.
So the first two are going to do here is plug in the probability of it being biased.
We actually know that exact number.
It's 1 out of 10.
So the probability of picking the biased coin is 1 out of 10 because it was one out of 10 coins.
The next thing we're going to plug in here will keep the original equation on top and we'll plug into
the bottom is the probability of flipping heads heads tails given a fair coin and that's just going
to be 0.5 to the power of three then the next probability we're going to play in here is a probability
of picking the fair coin that's just 0.9 because nine out of 10 coins are fair.
And then we're also going to plug in now some other probabilities given that the flipping of heads given
its biased.
So we did not actually know the exact number of the probability of flipping heads.
Given you have a biased coin though we are going to find that as Pete.
So in that case we can get p times p times 1 minus P So if we look back to what we're playing into we're
just flipping in or playing in heads heads tails for the biased coin which is P-P and then 1 minus P
for that tails.
And then finally we can plug in the probability of flipping heads heads tails given the biased coin.
And that's just going to be the same thing.
There are probably times probably times one minus p.
And so once you do that you can end up kind of collapse in this to try to get some more comments condense
terms here and you get something that looks like this piece squared times 1 minus p times are Point
1 over P squared times one minus p times 0.1 plus 0.1 1 to 5.
And if you want to start clean this up more and more.
But this is the basic idea of what you had to do at some point your interviewer here is probably going
to stop you and say that that's enough.
You have an understanding the main key things to remember for this particular interview question was
one you had to solve it in terms of P or in terms of some probability.
In this case we chose the probability of flipping heads giving a biased coin.
And more importantly you had to realize that you had to use the Bayes theorem or Bayes Rule.
So given those two things it becomes a relatively straightforward question if you are able to realize
is two fundamental things for solving this problem.
OK.
Hope you enjoyed that.
I'll see you at the next lecture.