Welcome to question them to for the statistics interview.
The question is the following.
A new quantum messaging system has a probability of 0.8 of success and any attempt to send the message
through.
So using this new quantum messaging system you have an 80 percent chance of success that your message
actually went through.
And the question is.
Calculate the probability of having seven successful messages going through out of 10 attempts.
And as a hint you may want to look at the binomial distribution to help you with this.
You can always check out the guidebook for the relevant links.
Again calculate the probability of having seven successes in 10 attempts.
Given that this messaging system has a probability of 80 percent of success in any attempt to send the
message through.
Best of luck.