Welcome to question of five for the statistics interview section.
So this question is the following.
The average life of a certain type of motor is 10 years with a standard deviation of two years.
If the manufacturer of the motor is willing to replace only 3 percent of the motors because of failures
how long of a guarantee should she offer the manufacturer.
So again you have a motor.
It's average lifespan is 10 years and has a standard deviation of two years and the manufacturer is
only willing to replace 3 percent of the motors because of failures.
So the question is how many years of a guarantee should they offer so you can assume that the lives
of the motors follow a normal distribution.
And as a quick note to fully solve this question you will need to do some sort of look up in a value
of a z table.
So if you're not familiar of Z tables You may also want to do a refresher on that because you need to
do certain things like Look some stuff up in the z table.
I want you to treat this as part of a take home task.
So feel free to use any resources you want.
Go ahead and look up normal distributions on the internet look up how to look up stuff in Z tables etc.
so you will need to do a little bit of that sort of analysis for this question.
It's unlikely that you're going be able to just do it all in your head or on a piece of paper.
You will need to do some references.
So again treat this more as a take on task.
This one's pretty tricky so we'll explain it a little more fully in the solutions.
Best of luck.