Welcome to interview question number four for product design and metrics so same situation here were
Google released that new version of their search algorithm did some may be testing engineers realized
that the new algorithm was returning less relevant results.
The two things that were occurring was there were more queries in the treatment group as well as advertising
revenue was higher in the treatment group.
So given the situation the next question is since the less relevant algorithm resulted in higher advertising
revenue should it be implemented anyways so kind of to reword that even though we have a search algorithm
that new algorithms returning less relevant results when we tested it with the treatment group it was
performing with higher advertising and people were making more searches.
So should you implement to anyway's.
All right.
Best of luck and I'll see you at a solution.