Welcome everyone to the solution for interview question and before the product design and metrics category.
So again same AB testing of that new algorithm.
However now the last question to be asked is since the less relevant algorithm results in higher advertising
revenue should it be implemented.
Anyways so this is a bit of an opinion question but in general you would hope that you would probably
not implement this new Algor of them and that's because the effects described here.
If we really think about them based on our previous discussions they're probably only short term effects
due to the problems with the algorithms and the outer rhythms ability to produce relevant results.
Lacking So we shouldn't sacrifice the long term potential of the site for a temporary increase in revenue
and searches and Google is probably best positioned to win in the long term.
When has the most relevant search algorithm and even though we're producing more searches and higher
advertising revenue with these less relevant results that's more likely a short term byproduct of less
relevant results being returned than an actual long term solution for revenue growth and more searches.
So I would suggest to not implement this and I believe most interviewers would probably feel the same
way you would never want to sacrifice long term results for short term gain.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.