Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for design of experiments.
Question number two.
So this question was asking how can we know if a sample is biased and what different kind of biases
should you be aware of when using a sample.
So let's start off with that first question how do we know if a sample is biased.
Well sometimes it's just impossible to know because of the way you actually got your sample.
If someone just gave it to you and you're not having any information about the total population it's
just going to be impossible for you to know.
But one way you can check if you do have some information about the population from what you've sampled
is for instance if you know the true mean of your population from which you sampled you can take samples
of your sample multiple times and check if the mean of these samples are normally distributed around
the true mean of the population.
And this is known as a form of bootstrapping.
Check out the resources for more information on bootstrapping.
But basically the idea here is you took your sample out of the total population.
You know the true mean of the population and which going to end up doing is constantly be taking out
samples from your sample.
So basically some samples taking the mean of that plotting and then eventually after you do this many
times you should see a normal distribution around the true mean of your population.
If you do not see that then it means that you have some sort of bias so if you see that the average
sampling mean your sample is way off from the truing of your population you probably have some sort
of bias in the way you selected your sample.
So now that we know that.
Let's go ahead and take a look at different types of biases.
So the first one is selection bias.
So this is when by some error you have excluded a specific part of the population.
So an example of this would be maybe you're trying to take a sample from which you're going to ascertain
the average weight of the United States population.
However it did selection bias you decide it's only sample from one state that could lead to some errors
because you're only looking at a specific part of the population instead of the population as a whole.
So other ways this could happen is maybe only a sample of a certain age group and you're trying to do
average across all age groups.
For the true population lots different ways to perform a selection bias.
It's really one of the most common biases.
Go ahead and check out the links in the resource guide notes for more lists of selection biases.
All right now measurement bias.
This one's a little trickier but basically what happens is when the method of measurement creates observations
that are different than the true value that's actually coming in.
So how can this actually happen.
Well for example let's say you're sampling from a stream of information and your sampling rate is lower
than the rate of change in the stream.
So you have some sort of device and you're taking information from it.
It's streaming.
And let's say every half second it jumps up to some high value and then after that half second it jumps
down to the average value.
So basically has this frequency jumping up and down jamming up tumbling down every half second.
But for some reason your sampling rate may be lower so you're maybe you're taking a sample every second.
So you're sampling at a lower frequency you're never going to see those high peaks which means you have
a measurement bias because your actual measurement is not what's true to the actual stream of information.
So this doesn't always occur but it's definitely one to be aware of.
So those are the two main types of biases we're going to cover in this lecture.
But definitely check out the guidebook resources for a great breakdown of the many other types of biases
that occur in experiments.
Selection bias is a really large umbrella term.
There's many different types of selection bias.
So there's a link in the guidebook there for you so you can check out the different ways selection bias
can occur.
There's really too many of them for us to just list them off here instead of the resource in the guide
book.
It's very helpful.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.