Welcome to interview question about three design of experiments.
So here's the situation.
Facebook is testing different designs of their user home page.
They have come up with 50 variations.
They would like to test all of them and then choose the best.
How would you personally set up this sort of experiment.
What metrics would you calculate and how would you report the results.
Keep in mind we're doing something that's a little different than just testing a Versus be here because
we're doing up to 50 variations.
So what kind of process should you use to set up this experiment.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture where we go over an example solution.