One of the core patterns that Spring Data makes use
of is the repository pattern.
In a nutshell,
the repository pattern is a persistence ignorant data access abstraction.
What this means is that rather than querying a database directly,
your application code will communicate with a repository interface instead.
Internally,
this interface will have an implementation with some data access code,
but from your application's point of view,
the repository that you work with will be abstract or
hide away all of this entirely.
Let's explain this with an example.
Typically when our application wants to query a database,
we do some sort of framework specific for accessing that database.
In this example where we have an SQL database,
we might make use of JPA to query it.
If we introduce a Spring Data repository interface into the equation,
it essentially wraps and abstracts our JPA access code for us.
Now our code will only query this data store via this repository interface.
And although not completely interoperable in all situations,
the repository pattern more or less means we're able to completely swap our
data store for something else without changing our code.
In this case, we've changed to Spring Data Neo4J,
which of course implements the same repository
interface as all the other modules, keeping the code which uses that repository close to the same.