Okay, before we start looking into Spring Data repositories in more detail,
we'll first look at a repository hierarchy and how everything
relates to each other across multiple modules.
The base interface is a repository interface,
which all other repository instances inherit from.
This is a marker interface with no methods,
just argument types for the entity you want to
persist and the ID class of the entity.
Below this is the CRUDRepository,
the one which is most used in Spring Data projects.
As the name implies, it comes with generic operations for creating,
reading, updating, and deleting entities.
That's then inherited by the PagingAndSortingRepository,
which again, as the name implies,
adds additional generic operations for paging and sorting the data,
as well as the original CRUD operations.
Whilst the free interfaces live in Spring Data
Commons and are used by all modules,
the remaining subinterfaces or implementations are module-specific.
It's these that will contain all the code specific to the module's database,
such as a JPA or MongoDB repository.
It's important to note that you're not going to be touching this code
yourself and will only be working with the interfaces provided in Spring Data Commons throughout this course.