Okay, so let's take a look at the base Repository interface.
It doesn't actually have any methods and is just a marker interface.
However, it takes two arguments.
The first is the type of entity to persist,
in other words a Java class, which is mapped to a database table.
All repository operations will take place on this entity.
The second is the type of the entity's ID class.
This might be a long, a EUID, or some other data type.
But as it will differ between different data stores,
it must be a generic type argument in order for the
repository to be completely generic itself.
Below the Repository interface, we have the most commonly used CRUDRepository.
This provides us with CRUD methods out of the box for our entities.
And some of the time this interface might be all our application needs.
In our example here, we have a save method for creating or updating entities.
We have a method for reading or finding entities by ID,
a method for deleting entities, and there are more.
Most of the generic CRUD operations you can think of live on this interface, making it very powerful out of the box often with little need to do much else.