In this demo,
we'll be working with the PagingAndSortingRepository to perform
paginated queries against our scheduled flights table.
We'll try different types of page and sort instances along the way and then
finally enrich our derived queries with paging and sorting.
To get started, let's navigate to our FlightRepository,
this time changing it so it inherits from
PagingAndSortingRepository instead of CRUDRepository.
If we step into the PagingAndSortingRepository,
we can see that it's a subclass of the CRUDRepository,
so we don't lose out on any of our existing functionality
while gaining two new useful methods.
These are a findAll method with a sort argument,
letting us sort our results, and a findAll method with a pageable argument,
letting us paginate our results.
Okay, let's create a new test called PagingAndSortingTests.
We'll run it with the SpringRunner and annotate it with DataJpaTest again.
Then we'll wire in our FlightRepository after which we'll create a setUp method,
which deletes and resets the database between each test.
For our first test, we'll keep it simple,
calling it shouldSortFlightsByDestination.
We'll create a flight which arrives at Madrid,
create a helper method in the process so it sets some
defaults for the rest of the fields.
Then we'll create two more flights, one to London and one to Paris,
and then save them both to the database.
Okay, now we can create our first sort query.
We can call findAll, but this time call Sort.by destination.
If it's not obvious,
this will mean that the results to findAll will be sorted by the field
named destination in ascending order by default.
Let's complete our test with an assertion.
We'll check that we got all three flights and then iterate
through them checking that the order was London,
Madrid, and then Paris.
Then let's run our test.
Great.
It's gone green, verifying our query worked as expected,
and we organized our flights into ascending order.
Now let's try a more complicated sort query where we sort by two
separate fields with the first field taking precedence.
We'll call it shouldSortFlightsByScheduledAndThenName.
We'll start by creating a flight to Paris,
this time creating an extra helper method that
allows us to provide a schedule time.
We'll then create an additional two flights.
So we have one flight to Paris now, one flight to Paris in 2 hours,
and one flight to Paris an hour ago.
Then, let's create two flights to London, one in an hour's time and one now.
What we can do now is create a sort query similar to before,
only this time we'll sort it by destination.
And if the destination fields match, then it will then be sorted by scheduledAt.
Spring Data is intelligent enough to know how to create a
query that sorts by a local date/time.
Finally, let's create our assertions.
We'll check that we have all five flights and then that
they return in the correct order.
Our flight to London should be first,
and then the one with the latest schedule time should be last.
Then we should receive our three flights to Paris,
again ordered by schedule time ascending.
Okay, let's run our test and see if it all goes green.
It does, verifying our more advanced sort query works perfectly.
Now we've experimented with sorting, let's try out some paging.
We'll create a test called shouldPageResults,
and in it we'll say 50 flights in a for loop.
To keep things simple when asserting,
we'll give each flight a destination which matches the valueOf i.
After this,
we can query a page or a slice of the total results using
findAll and passing in a page request.
We can do PageRequest., passing in 2 to request that we're on the second
page and 5 to denote that each page has a length of 5.
Rather than the response being a list again,
in this case a response is a page abstraction.
We can assert that it's working as we expect by verifying some of its fields.
We'd expect a total of 50 elements with 5 elements on
each page and a page total of 10, which is 50 elements divided by 5.
We can then assert that the page-content returns the correct elements.
We'd expect page 0 to contain destinations not to 4,
page 1 to contain destinations 5 to 9, and,
in our case, we'd expect page 2 to contain a 10 to 14 of element.
AssertJ makes this easy to check by using the extracted
method combined with containsExactly.
The destination field is converted to a list,
and we assert the list contains the given destinations in the given order.
Let's run the test and see if it goes green.
It does proving how simple it is to get started with paging.
We didn't need to write any special query,
only passing the page object with a couple of parameters.
Okay, whilst these two concepts have been very much separate so far,
what we can do is combine them together so we both page
and sort our results at the same time.
We can do this by copying and pasting our existing test,
renaming it to shouldPageAndSortResults.
All we need to do now is pass in our sort object into
our page request as an argument.
Let's sort by destination descending,
which should reverse the order of our elements.
We'll pass in 44, 43, 42, 41,
and 40 and then run our test to see if it's gone green.
It has meaning we can successfully sort both paging and sorting of our queries.
Great.
So far our tests have been dependent on the provided methods
within the paging and sorting repository,
but a use of these is actually optional as it's perfectly possible to make
these abstractions arguments to the derived queries too,
combining all three concepts together into one query.
Let's try this out.
We can first copy and paste our existing query,
this time renaming it to shouldPageAndSortADerivedQuery.
We'll then change it so we save 10 flights from
Paris and 10 flights from London.
Then we'll create a new findByOrigin method,
this time passing in London and our page request.
It's really nice that Spring Data is capable of this as it
further abstracts this from the underlying data store whilst
being as feature-rich as possible.
All we needed to do was add an extra field to our method.
Finally, let's change the parameters to our assertion and then run our test.
In this case, it's gone red,
and this was done deliberately as it's a common gotcha.
It doesn't recognize a page request class and instead needs the
pageable interfaces and argument instead,
which is what the page request implements.
Once we make this change, we can run our test again,
and this time it will go green.
And that covers it for this demo.
By now,
we're hopefully building up some knowledge of how powerful Spring Data can be when all of these concepts are combined.