In this demo,
we're going to try switching our project from Spring Data JPA
to Spring Data MongoDB as a proof of context of the generic
nature of Spring Data Commons.
We'll first change the required Maven dependencies,
switch our database from H2 to embedded Mongo,
remap our entities removing the JPA annotations,
leave our repository class untouched, the most important step,
and then verify everything still functions by running the tests.
Okay, let's start by navigating to our POM file and changing our dependencies.
We'll first go from spring-boot-starter-jpa to spring-boot-starter-mongodb.
Then we'll remove our H2 dependency as we're no longer
working with a relational database,
and we'll add a dependency on an embedded MongoDB instead as this
is what will now be required as our data store.
Thanks to the spring-boot-starter,
this will be spun up and torn down automatically during test just like with H2.
Once we've done this, our code will no longer compile.
However,
it's important to note it's only the JPA-specific code that has this problem.
Whereas the Spring Data code is fine as we've only worked with
shared interfaces in Spring Data Commons.
Let's delete the JPA annotations from our Flight entity and
change our ID field to a String data type,
which MongoDB prefers.
That's all we need to do here, but in doing so,
our tests no longer compile as they were using a long ID.
We can change our ID type parameter to a String in our repository,
and really that is it.
We've not had to change our repository methods,
import any MongoDB- specific repository code,
or do anything other than removing JPA and change the type of our ID.
Let's run all our tests to verify it still works.
They don't pass yet because we still have a data JPA test,
which requires Spring Data JPA.
All we need to do to fix this is change from DataJpaTest to DataMongoTest,
and then we can run our test one final time and see if they pass now.
They do,
only now we're connecting to a completely different data store
with a completely different query language.
If we navigate to our CrudTests, we can see that saving,
deleting,
and finding all work as they did before as they're common operations provided
by the CRUDRepository interface in Spring Data Commons.
Our derived queries also work, even though MongoDB as a document store,
and the queries generated will be in a different query language to before.
Also,
our paging and sorting repository works too because again these
are common abstractions provided by Spring Data Commons regardless of the underlying data store.