And that covers it for this module.
We've learned that in order to query data,
each Spring Data module makes use of the Repository interface.
This is a data store agnostic interoperable way of executing queries.
We will rarely have to write our own implementation code while
making use of repositories as Spring Data does a great job of
generating all the boilerplate we need.
Basic CRUD operations come out of the box through
the PagingAndSortingRepository,
while the bespoke queries can be derived from Spring
Data based on method signatures.
And the paging and sorting of queries are abstracted.
We can also fall back to creating custom
implementations of queries if we need to.
In the next module,
we'll be using Spring Data with the @Transactional annotation in order to learn how we can manage our database transactions with Spring.