Okay, in our first demo, we'll be creating a project using Spring Initializr,
a simple way of creating a Spring Boot application.
We'll then create a Java class, which maps to a database table.
And finally,
we'll create a small health check test to verify our application boots
and that we can write our entity to the database.
Okay, to get started with Spring Data, we first need to create our demo project.
As this will be a Spring Boot project,
the easiest way to do this is via start.spring .io.
Essentially, it's an online form,
which allows you to select some settings for your new
Spring Boot project after which you can then generate it
and download it in a ZIP file.
For example, you can choose a build tool here, such as Maven or Gradle.
We'll be using Maven for this project.
You can also choose a language, and, in our case, we'll be sticking with Java.
The Spring Boot version is also configurable,
but we'll stick with the latest, in this case version 2.1 .9.
Okay, for the rest of our project, we need to do some customizations.
Let's give our project a group ID, com.pluralsight,
an artifact ID, spring-data-overview.
Following this,
we can scroll down and pick some extra Maven dependencies to be added.
Doing it this way is pretty nice as setting up a POM with various starter
dependencies and plugins can be a bit cumbersome to do manually.
We can first search for Spring Data JPA as it's the Spring
Data module we'll be using for this course.
We don't need to include Spring Data Commons as it's a
transitive dependency of each module.
Then, we can add H2, the in-memory database that we'll be using during our tests.
And that's about it.
All we need to do now is press Generate,
and our project will be packaged into a ZIP file and
downloaded onto our file system.
After this, we can then import the project into our IDE.
Okay, so now we've imported our project, let's take a look at its contents.
Navigating to our POM file,
we can see that it inherits from the spring-boot-starter- parent,
providing us with managed dependency versions and plugins.
I'm not going to go into too much detail about this as its
better covered in a Spring Boot course.
Scrolling down, we can see the dependencies that we added,
spring-boot-starter-jpa and h2.
Spring-boot-starter-test is also added by default.
Now let's add one more additional dependency,
assertj, as we'll be using it for our test assertions.
An alternative, such as Hamcrest or even native assertions would be fine,
but I'm choosing AssertJ for personal preference as it
comes with some really useful assertions,
which we'll make use of throughout the demos.
Now that's done, let's navigate to our class file.
By default,
there's one single class file named after our project
annotated with @SpringBootApplication.
It comes with a default main method,
which will be executed when the application is started.
Again,
I'm not going to go into the specifics here as this is
covered in a Spring Boot-specific course.
Navigating to our test directory,
we can see this one Spring Boot test named contextLoads.
By default, it runs with the SpringRunner,
meaning that when we execute it,
our Spring Boot application will start up with a close to full context.
Let's execute it and look at the logs.
We can first see the Spring banner,
signifying that our Spring Boot application is starting.
We can also see log lines referencing that Spring Data is starting up,
for example bootstrapping repositories and,
at an even lower level, Hibernate is starting,
which is what Spring Data JPA uses behind the scenes.
The test has gone green,
which means our application and all its dependencies started successfully.
Okay,
let's start by creating a JPA entity that we'll use
during the rest of this course.
We'll call it Flight, and it will represent a scheduled flight.
This will map directly to a database table.
We'll start by giving it an ID field, the database ID,
an origin field, representing the airport that a flight starts at,
a destination field, representing the airport where it terminates,
and a scheduledAt field,
representing what time the flight is scheduled to depart.
Once we've done this,
we can map it with the JPA annotations to make it a managed entity,
in other words something that can be loaded and saved
into the database using Spring Data JPA.
Again, JPA is not the focus of the course,
so I won't go into the details of what these annotations do.
But essentially, we use our entity to make it recognized as a table,
an ID to denote a primary key, which, by default,
will be generated for us using a GeneratedValue annotation.
Finally, let's generate some getters and setters.
We don't need any more JPA annotations because it's
intelligent enough to figure out that the rest of the fields
map to database columns of the same name.
Okay, let's switch to our test and modify it slightly.
We're not going to use Spring Data at all here,
but we're going to use a Spring JPA EntityManager directly to verify that
it's possible to save and read our flight to our H2 database just as a health
check to know that everything's set up correctly.
Let's start by wiring in our EntityManager and then
renaming our test to verifyFlightCanBeSaved.
Our EntityManager is set up for us automatically by Spring Boot starter JPA.
Once we've done this, we can create an instance of our flight.
Let's give it some arbitrary data and then call
entityManager.persist to store it in the H2 database.
Once we've done that, let's create a query,
SELECT FROM Flight, which will read our flight from the database,
and then we'll create an assertion that our single flight has been returned,
and that it's the same flight as the one we saved.
We didn't bother overriding equals here,
so it's checking the flights are the same instance,
which they are as the EntityManager already has it
in memory from when we saved it.
We'll also make this a DataJpaTest,
which means that only a partial Spring context will be created
containing our persistence specific bean,
which is H2, our EntityManager, Spring Data repositories,
and so on.
This, in turn,
makes our test execute as quickly as possible as there's no
overhead of starting up things that we don't need,
such as a web server.
If you're wondering about creating our database table,
by default, it's created for us based on the JPA annotations.
So we don't need to create SQL to do this ourselves.
Okay, let's run our test and verify that it passes.
It does.
This confirms we can save our entity to our database,
so we're ready to get started by making use of Spring Data.
It's thanks to Spring Boot that this was so simple as the
creation and configuration of things, such as our EntityManager,
are all handled for us by Spring. This pattern will be the same across all modules of Spring Data.