So what have we learned during this module?
The first is that Spring Data is not a particular project,
but is instead a collection of data access modules.
Each of these modules implement Spring Data Commons,
which provides the core abstractions for data access with Spring Data.
It's a framework that heavily reduces boilerplate,
helping you deliver features faster.
There's also a gentle learning curve for each Spring Data module,
meaning you can get up and running quickly.
And the focus of this course will be Spring Data Commons to
help us build the foundation we need before working with a
specific Spring Data module.
In the next module,
we'll learn about querying with Spring Data by making use of the Spring Data repository interface.