Discourse implementing software architecture of a large-scale system is part of developer to architect
series, where the first course software, architecture and technology of large scale systems dealt
with concepts and principles of software architecture that govern large scale systems.
In the second part, which is totally independent of the first part and can be taken in any order deals
with the implementation part.
So if you have a software system and you have to evolve it into a large scale system, then what does
it mean in terms of continuous configuration?
Additional new components and technology?
So these are those kind of practical aspects that are covered as part of this course.
This course comes with a downloadable Corbis, which can be downloaded from Bitbucket.
We will use this course to build and run an end to end system.
We will take this code base or download this code base on a Linux virtual machine that we are going
to create.
We will create this virtual machine on Google Cloud using Google Compute Engine.
For those who do not feel home with Linux, need not worry at all.
In this course, we are not doing anything that is platform specific.
Most of the work that we need to do is already automated to save time.
You will need to know only very basic commands to understand the most of the code so that if you know
how to change the directory, how to list directly, how to view a file and how to execute a script,
then this should be good enough for you to follow this course.
It's only when you want to dig deeper yourself.
You may need to understand a bit of shell scripting.
But if you are an experienced developer and you have done a bit of scripting in any language on any
platform, then that too should also be a very easy task for you.
We will use this virtual machine as a workstation to build the code, add new features and run our system.
When we first ran our system on this machine, we will go over its components and get an overview of
its core and the technology that is used.
Once we have understood the different components of our system and the technology and the code that
it uses.
We will package all our components using Docker containers.
This will be needed so that we can deploy our system consistently every time as we are extending our
system.
As part of our system extension, the first thing that we are going to do is we're going to split our
services into multiple different specialized services so that later on they can be extended into microservices.
As our system is evolving into a distributed system, we will have to do routing related changes, so
the first thing that we will do is we will introduce a gateway service for which we will use.
Netflix also is.
Next, we will add Netflix, Yurek, our discovery service into our system.
Next, we will introduce in the next global insight into our system for load balancing, so this high
load balancing and for client side load balancing.
We will use ribbon load balancer.
Once we have taken care of routing related changes, then we can scale up our system, we can manually
scale up some of the components of our system.
As our system is growing, we will need better observability, better ways to observe our system.
As part of that, we will do centralized loading using ElasticSearch fluently and cabana.
Next, we will introduce centralised tracing using Wahlberg.
The last thing that we will do as part of observability is we will introduce Prometheus for checking
system Matrix.
Our next set of extensions will be to manage the high scale of data for that in order to manage raedler.
We will introduce caching and we will use risk for that in order to manage right load better.
We will use asynchronous processing using it every time you.
In order to further scale our system, we will replace our IDB IMS database with our distributed database
so that we can do data partitioning, and for that we will use Cassandra database.
Once we fully extended our system in order to deploy our system, which has become very complex, and
to operate this system, we will use Kubernetes for Kubernetes.
We will again use Google Cloud Kubernetes.
And there we will deploy our system as if we're running it for production.
As we evolve our system through different stages.
This is the process that we will follow at every stage.
We will look at the current solution limitation and then we will see how by using a new component,
we can overcome those limitations with those new components.
We will look at what different technology options do.
We have work or changes we will have to do?
What system configuration will be needed?
And then we will finally, Randi complete system.
We will repeat this process over and over again to achieve the final state of our system.
So this way, we will take a very hands on approach towards understanding software and solution architecture
of a large scale and distributed system.
We will learn about different architectural challenges, different technology options that are available
to solve those challenges.
We will get first hand experience and insight into some of those modern tools and technologies.
And most importantly, we will get hands-on with a system that has so many features of a truly large-scale
system.
So that's the overview of what we are going to learn.
Now, let's get started.