After taking care of Lead Lord by removing some Reed Lord from our database.
Now let's turn our attention to Right Lord.
So is there any way we can reduce the load on our database by taking care of the right look?
So asynchronous processing is one way we can therefore the Lord on the database.
What we can do is we can defer some of the transactions by putting transaction requests in a message
queue and performing those transactions when the database is not under heavy load.
So if you have something in message queue, we can defer its processing.
So that's the way asynchronous processing can help us in reducing load on the database.
So in order to do that, the first thing that we need to do is we need to identify those APIs which
are right oriented and hence we can execute them asynchronously.
So those APIs, which are right oriented in our system, they are ATA service and inventory service.
So that's when we create an audit.
We need to write that order and its line items to the database.
We also need to do that inventory from inventory database or whatever stuff the user is buying.
Whatever items the user is buying will have to dig that that inventory from the database.
So these are the two APIs which are used as part of Single Creator API, which do a lot of right related.
Now there is a read part to it, which is where user will send the request and we need to notify the
user that the order has been accepted or the order in their execution.
And then we again is synchronously processed the right part, which is basically execution of the create
order transaction.
So Create Order is one such example which we can decouple from the three part the query part, which
is where we just need to let users know that the order is being accepted and we will let users know
that the order has been accepted when we serve that order or possess that order in a messaging user
sent any order.
We will validated and we will put it into the messaging queue and we will acknowledge the user that
the order has been captured and we can associate that order with some status, which is that the order
processing is in progress and it is not yet confirmed.
So later on, what we can do is the order processing service, which is right now the part of the service
itself can pull these messages that we have saved in the message queue and can process these messages,
which doesn't have anything else but the order that needs to be processed.
So it will pull out those order messages and it will processed them.
And then it went right to the database.
Once it is done processing the order, it can use a notification service to notify the user that the
order has been processed.
So this is a typical create a workflow that we can break into two parts, read part and write part and
write part we can do asynchronously.
So the benefit of this approach is that the user part wherein user submits the order that finishes pretty
quickly with very low latency and that improves user experience.
The other thing that that is happening over here is because we are not doing the right part as part
of the user order capture transaction, the transaction or transaction time reduces or the failure rate
of this transaction will come down.
So that also improves the user experience.
Now, the part where we need to actually process the order that we will do is in going to sleep and
in case if system our databases and that high-stress, then we have this ability in our system that
we can process the order from message queue only when the system has some capacity.
So the orders which are coming from the user, we have no choice but to capture that.
We must have capacity to at least capture them and put the messaging queue.
But once these orders are in messaging queue, we can pull them out at our own pace that our system
capacity allows and accordingly, we can process them.
Now, the next thing that we need to look into once we decide that which API we need to make is synchronous.
We need to decide which queue or messaging queue we are going to use.