The last element of observability that we need to implement into our system is Matrix.
Now we have already centralised logging so we can analyze the system logs pretty easily and can make
sense out of that.
We have also centralized our base so we can find out which workflows are running slow and which are
the components which are making it slow.
Now the thing which is remaining is we do not know the health of our system.
As in if oil companies are open or if something is up, then was it consistently up or not?
Did it go down at any instant in the past?
So things like that, we would like to know.
We would like to know the request rate that that is coming to our system, what our system is handling.
We would like to know the resource utilization like CPU memory and possibly network, how much data
is coming in and how much data is going out, things like that, which will help us in predicting the
health of our system.
So this is our objective right now.
We will see how we can support reviewing of metrics of our system.
So for that, we have chosen a product called Prometheus.
It's an open source product and there are not many alternatives to this in terms of open source.
There are, of course, lot of monitoring tools that are available, but among their open source tools,
this is the most popular one.
This has been adopted by a C and CEF, which is an open source foundation which is responsible for maintaining
Kubernetes flew in the yaga, some of the open products that we have already used.
So this is something that we are going to use, and the way it works is pretty simple.
We will need to bring up Prometheus over it, then if we want, we can have a storage attached along
with this also.
But right now we are just going ahead with the simple installation.
What this Prometheus will do is it will reach out to different components that it needs to monitor,
and these components need to expose these metrics that Prometheus is interested in.
And these metrics should be exposed by our application components in a format in which Prometheus understand
those metrics.
So we'll have to do some modifications in our services to expose those metrics.
Similarly, we'll have to do some modification in our web application to expose those metrics.
There are certain components let's like load balancer or our database.
We cannot modify them.
So what we are going to do is we are going to start an exporter.
So let's have a postgres.
We will start an exporter, which will monitor progress and it will provide those metrics to Prometheus.