OK, so this is the current state of our system.
We have got multiple components now, and potentially each component can be scaled into many more number
of instances.
Let's say here we have shown two instances were product service.
We can potentially have been 50 or whatever number of instances that required.
The other issue right now we have is that we have deployed everything on a single machine, so we really
do not have a deployment strategy in place either.
Then we can do a deployment for testing our system where we can deploy everything on a single machine
and we can successfully tested every time.
But now, if we are to deploy this system for production, we have to take care of the scale of the
system, one due to the large number of components that we have.
Second, each component can have multiple number of instances.
And third is that each component is running in certain environment and we need to maintain that environment.
We need to reliably reproduce that environment every time.
Now we have seen how to do that with Docker images, but we need something on top of that because now
we are talking about an entire system on multiple machines.
So Docker alone will not be sufficient.
We will need something else.
So that is what our objective is right now.
We are looking for a tool which will allow us to deploy this large system on a very large scale.