So far, we have discussed how we can limit the load on our BBMAs by taking care of some of the load
through caching and by distributing the load over a period of time, by using message queue, by using
message.
You will not reduce the overall load on our database, but we will be able to distribute it in time.
So in spite of all these things, once our scale goes up, our teams will not be able to take up the
look, especially because the way our teams are designed, it is extremely hard for them to support
more than one terabytes of data, and in some cases, it can go up to five dynamite.
But generally, if that's the kind of data you are playing with, then IBM's will not be a good choice
and it will have limitations with scalability.
And the primary reason is that in Idlib BMWs, we are generally dealing with single instance.
Now we can improve the situation with IBM's a bit by adding read replicas to the single instance, which
we can call as master.
Because this master will be responsible for all the right load and whatever transactions are being done
on master, they'll be propagated to replica, and these replicas can be used for a read only queries.
So it will bring in some eventual consistency, as in the replicas, may not be completely up to date
with master.
So if you query the master in replica at the same time, you may get different results.
But with that tradeoff, at least one thing we will be able to achieve that.
And that's a problem with cash also.
It's a similar problem, so the way you deal with it is no different.
Or at least it makes the situation a bit better.
At least we are able to scale up the load, which is coming from read queries.
So that's what we get.
And the other thing that we get is higher variability in case if one of the replica or the master crashes,
so it gives most decorations, we can promote a replica as a monster and we can be back in operations
in some time after a delay because there will be some time that will be consumed in promoting a replica
to a master.
So there will be some delay, but it will not be that we are completely out.
So there will be a higher amount of availability as compared to a single instance.
But if we see this are right, Lord is still a problem because it is going to a single instance to this
single instance.
Master instance is responsible for the entire load that is coming from all our services.
So this will still be highly loaded.
And if the Lord of Great Lord, then this is still not a solution for us.
In that case, what we can do is we can vertically partition our system so we can partition them into
microservices architecture.
So this is true microservices architecture where we have done vertical partitioning.
Each service has got its own database and with this architecture, we can independently deploy and develop
our services apart from taking care of the higher amount of node, because now we have got multiple
instances that can take care of the load.
The two different colors over here represent one, let's say master, and the other one is a lead replica.
But from a right load perspective, we still have one instance serving a particular service.
Well, it's in this inventory.
So this deals with only one master instance.
But what we have achieved over here, at least we have four different masters.
In our previous situation, we only had one master for all our four services.
Here we have four different masters.
So this is a good approach.
The issue with this approach is that across the database now, we cannot have integrity constraints
because the data is being managed by different database machines.
There can't be any great egoyan's we cannot get as a transaction.
So if order service, let's say, needs to modify data, but in order IBM's and inventory IBM's, then
that's not possible.
Although we never started with that kind of design, but just letting you know that because now they
are in two separate machines.
So there is a hard constraint that we cannot do as transactions.
If this was just one single machine and we could have clubbed them into a single database, we could
have still achieved that.
But now here, it's not possible.
So we have lost integrity constraint.
We can't do 80 joints and we can't do asset transactions.
But what we can still get is within a particular database, let's say, if we are just creating the
tables which are there in order it BMW's schema, then we can do as a transaction joins and constraints.
So within a database, it's still not an issue, but across the database, we will have to embrace the
eventual consistency.
The other thing that we have over here is now that we have the complexity of maintaining multiple databases.
But I guess that's not a big problem because when you go to scale, you do not have many options.
Now that we have to deal with eventual consistency when we are dealing with multiple services, let's
report a transaction that's if would create order transaction.
We have to deal with inventory service and order service.
So here we have to deal with different databases.
Then in those situations, if we have to do those kind of transaction, the other kind of option becomes
very appealing is.
Distributed database, no distributor database here we can do partitioning at record level, so in our
previous case, we did partitioning vertical partitioning at table levels or some tables got into inventory
tables which were related to inventory and order related service order, serviceability tables.
They were located in order already beams and likewise for product.
And also there was separation of tables.
Now, in this particular case, what we can do is, let's say our order table itself is very large and
it cannot fit into one database.
So here we can partition the table itself.
So the partitioning is at a record level and this limit level that we can go for scalability.
Some of the benefits of this approach is that now we also get data replication as part of new sequel
distributed databases.
They manage it pretty well and there is very little setup that we need to do from our site.
If you want to bring up a cluster over a distributed database with replication, it's pretty easy and
we will see that how easy it is.
And if you have to do the same thing for another BMS, we would be reading manual for it.
If that is not something we usually do, then that's the kind of effort that is required for setting
up replication or even partitioning those databases these days.
They do claim our means that they can do some kind of partitioning.
So not a popular option, because why would you use to be a mess if you have to do partitioning in that?
So nevertheless, the point is that so some of the features like partitioning and replication, they
come out of the box in these databases and they are pretty easy to implement.
If we have to send a request to this kind of distributor database, we can send it to any instance or
outer over here managed by the database, and that will take care of the routing of the request in a
previous case.
Each service has to know which database is this or look, in this case, it looks pretty easy because
we have good distinction of responsibility across its services.
So the point is that here, let's say, if if there are multiple instances, well, as a product service
is dealing with multiple instances of product database, then product service will have to take care
of routing it.
To one of those instances, it will have to figure out whether it's the right requested to read request
and accordingly, it will have to choose an instance over here.
This is something that is seamlessly managed by the database.
Yeah, the benefit is that here we can create schema or demand.
If you want to add some columns, we can do that any time.
In fact, some of them will allow to create the tables also on the fly.
So those are some of deep disadvantage advantages of using distributed database.
The primary advantage is that we are getting data partitioning and there are a lot of other advantages
as well.
The the issue here is that we get limited indexing over here because mostly every record has to be addressed
as if we are facing a primary key.
We can have secondary indexes also, but they do not provide the kind of performance that we are looking
for.
So we have two designer schema sets that most of the stuff we can query using a key.
If you can think of that as a primary keys of that, that's the kind of limitation we put on schema
when we use a distributed database.
So that puts a limitation on query burden.
So the way you design schema over here is you first look at how you are going to query the database
and then you come up with this schema as opposed to in the BBMAs.
You can create this schema and then you can come up with any query burden.
So those are the tradeoffs.
So if you do not want to trade off everything, the other option that we have is that we can follow
an idea of a hybrid approach wherein we can use our PBMs.
For those services which need strong consistency, so does the burden that we can follow.
And for the services where eventual consistency is just fine, we do not need complex query joins and
all that stuff that we can use a distributed database.
So those kind of approaches are pretty popular.
In our case, what we are going to do is we are going to replace the only databases, Postgres databases.
With Cassandra database, so that that's what we are going to do in this demonstration, but the court
actually allows you to actually do something of this kind.
The debt is something that the court that we have can do.
But for this demonstration, we will just add Cassandra database and we will just focus on that.