The next component that we are going to discuss is services.
Services is where our business logic is going to site.
From this component, we have a few architectural requirements that we we're going to discuss now.
First is that our services should be interoperable.
What that means is that our services has different kind of clients relative.
We have an external client, single page app, which normally runs outside of our system.
And we have very applications line, which runs inside our system, so it's an internal plan.
Then there is a third kind of kind of let's say we have a communication between order and inventory.
So this order service needs to determine that a particular item is available in the database or not.
So for that, it will have to go through inventory service.
So order, so this becomes a plan of inventory service in this case.
So we need to support different kind of plans.
And for that, our services should be interoperable for interoperability.
We can use two different kind of mechanisms.
So one is our busy mechanism and the other one is rest based mechanism, which is an architectural style.
Now, our PC mechanism is that mechanism where a client and a server, they agree on it on an interface
and stubs and skeletons are generated and stubs are used by clients to make a call to this service.
So that kind of tightly captures a client and a service.
So our PC is not a very suitable mechanism for communication between, let's say, a mobile device and
a service.
Because we will need to have those stubs on that mobile device or their application in that tightly
couples these two client and so.
So this is not something that we are going to use.
What we are going to use is rest based communication, which is not tightly controlled.
It does not use RBC pay steps.
It is lightweight, so it is suitable for both application to application communication and also for
browsers as well.
So let's set the single page.
Application is a browser based application so it can easily communicate with services using wrist based
communication.
So rest is something that we are going to go ahead with.
Now, for internal communication between services, we could have used RBC also, because that is more
efficient generally are PCs which which do not use soap.
So our PCs like OPG are busy thrift.
They are binary protocols and for internal communication, they work pretty well and for external communication.
What we can do is we can host a service in between, let's say, some kind of routing service or gateway
service, which can intercept call rest calls and it can convert them into these groups or drift.
And it can thus act as a broker in between so we can have that kind of communication.
But for now, let's keep things simple and we are going to use the rest protocol between our client
and all our services.
Later on, if we need more efficient communication, we can go towards IBC for internal communication.
The next architectural requirement that we have from our services is that there should be independent.
What that means is we should be able to develop them independently.
We should be able to deploy them independently and that where we can scale both the development of services
and also we should be able to scale them by deploying them independently, by taking care of their individual
deployment needs related to scalability.
So there should be independent.
Now there are two choices that we have to make ourselves as independent.
One is service oriented architecture.
Now this does not give us full amount of independence because here so who says they get couple on two
fronts?
One is at the interface front because as part of this architecture, they used a common interface schema
which compiles them and they use common database schema that also compiles them.
Microservices architecture gets rid of this coupling here.
The way we design our services is we do not use any common interface schema.
And we also do not use common database schema.
So then we are going to designer schema.
We'll have to keep that in mind that ultimately each service should be able to work with its own schema,
which means that we should be able to do distributed transactions or something like distributed transactions,
and those can be eventually consistent transaction.
So things like that, we'll have to think about right in the beginning when we are developing our services.
The bottom line is that our database schema should be such that each service can have its own schema
and that can be holistic on a separate database.
The other requirement that we have from our services is scalability.
Now, in order to make our services scalable part of it, we already discussed that microservices will
promote scalability.
But that is another thing that we need to do is to promote scalability is that we need to make our services
stateless.
Now, if we make our services stateless, what it does is that whenever we want to increase the number
of instances of our services, we should be able to do that.
Something like this.
We should be able to add more number of instances to our services without worrying about this state.
Now, in order to make our services stateless, what we have to make sure is that we are not maintaining
any application state within our service instances.
We are also not maintaining our claim state in our service instances.
If we do not do that, our services will become stateless.
And what that means is that anytime we want to increase the number of instances, we just need to start
a new instance with the same code base.
And that's pretty much is the requirement for starting new instances.
So that will promote scalability.
So these are the three main architectural requirements that we have from our services.