Now, our system is beginning to look like a large scale system we have, and it acquired a few components
to our system.
And for each component, we can potentially have lots of instances.
So it's like this gateway service we have, for instance, is in production.
We can go up to 10 15 instances, depending upon the user load.
Similarly, for web application and similarly for other services that we have, in fact, there are
components like load balancing where we can keep primary secondary set up.
And for database, it is also we can have primary secondary setup.
So the point is we can have lots of components in our system and each component can have multiple instances.
So we have a system over here which resembles a large scale system.
And with that, we have some new problems now.
Those problems that we are going to discuss right now are related to observability.
So let's say there is something wrong going in our application and we don't know which component it
is going wrong in.
And users are seeing some errors.
Now we have to find out where the error is, then our best bet is that we will be looking for the logs
and whichever component just showing errors.
We will start our investigation from there.
So let's say our order service has some issue and that is one particular instance of that order service
where logs have that issue.
But we do not know that that order service has the issue or that particular instance is where the Schubert
recorded.
So now, if we have to debug this particular problem that a user has reported, then we'll have to look
for logs of many more components, which ever makes sense.
We are going to look over that and try to find out where that error is.
And this is going to be a big problem if it is a large scale system.
If it was a small scale system, it is something very trivial.
And architects will not have to worry about it.
But if it is a large scale system like this, then this is something that architects need to worry about.
So what is needed over here is some mechanism through which we should be able to find areas within our
system.
We should be able to audit our system.
So let's say a customer is claiming that some information was provided and we are claiming that information
was never provided.
Such a request never came to the system.
Then the only way to prove that is through logs.
So the logging becomes extremely important over here in case we have to audit.
But we can meaningfully navigate through these logs only if they are easily accessible, so we will
see what needs to be done over here.
But the point is that there are challenges like that.
And then if we have to analyze our logs to derive some information, which we call analytics.
So let's say we want to find out for how long users have connecting and when they're disconnecting and
things like that.
Security breaches will have to have been analyzed logs.
So things like that we have to do in a large-scale system.
We may have to take care of the latency so users are getting less, if bad, performance for certain
apps than we should be able to find out which component is responsible for poor performance of those
apps.
We should be able to find out quickly what is the health of our system?
Are there any components which are not up or they are performing badly?
We should be able to know what is the throughput of our system, what is the resource utilization of
our system?
Resource utilization will tell us if we need to add more resources or we are running with more resources.
So these are certain operations related things which are extremely critical for a large scale system.
So we have discussed certain things that we need to have in our system.
Now let's just give some names to those things.
So we will classify observability into three main items.
One is logging, either one is tracing and the third one is matrix.
So logging is about analyzing the logs that our application is generating.
Dressing is about getting further logs from the system, all that information from our system, that
how much time each API is consuming, and we want this information at function level.
We may not be able to put this for everything in our system, but at least four critical transactions
and a critical part we should have trace.
And then the third thing is matrix, which is important if you want to know the current health of our
system and how the future of our System Health looks like.
So we need matrix for that.
So these are the things that we are going to add into our system now.