OK, with that, we have simplified the configuration of our clients if they have to communicate to
our backend.
They can directly communicate with gateway service and that's the only service that they need to know
about.
Now let's turn our attention to a gateway service, or let's help some other clients which wants to
communicate with other services.
So in this case, gaping service wants to communicate with other services that are there in the system.
And then there will be some services in the system, which will also need to take help of other services.
So let's say this order service, when it is creating in order for a certain product, it needs to know
if inventory is available for that product, so it needs to communicate with inventory service.
So for that, this also needs to know the configuration related to inventory service on which host and
port inventory service is available.
So these are the two lines that need some kind of configuration to know about the host and port information
of all these services that they need to access.
Now that configuration, if we do a static configuration, it will look like this.
So here we'll have to tell gateway service to a static configuration.
That authorization service is located excellence or host and port.
Similarly, product service or service and inventory service.
So this kind of static routing configuration will do if we have small number of services and they have
small number of instances, so this will be perfectly fine.
There won't be any issues, but if we have, let's say, lots of services and all of these services
have lots of instances which will be the case with any large scale system, then there will be a lot
of services and lot of service instances to reach out to.
So in this case, that's a gateway service wants to reach out to product service.
Here there are three instances two for it to know about.
Now, if we look at this static configuration by just expanding each of the service to three instances,
then this static routing configuration, which was earlier looking pretty simple like this, has expanded
to pretty large configuration, and this can become extremely complex as new instances are added and
removed.
So this static routing configuration will not be suitable for a large scale system.
This is going to be a global problem, and we will see that during the demonstration that how we can
take care of this configuration.
But for now, the we can take it.
This has the configuration will become as complex as this.
So in order to sell this configuration problems for our clients, in this case, our clients of this
service and order service, if you want to simplify that, we make use of discovery service.
So what we can do is we can add a new component to our system in this case.
We have aided discovery service now.
Our discovery service does is that it provides dynamic configuration for the host and board information
of various services.
So let's have our authorization service.
When it comes up, we'll have to write a little amount of code and we will see that it's pretty easy.
It's very trivial to write that book, but some code has to be written for each service.
And by virtue of that code, with the help of that code, what will happen is later, when this authorization
service in the stands is coming up, it will register itself with discovery service, so it will need
to know about where discovery services are.
So as soon as an instance comes up, it will let Discovery Service know that it has come up on so-and-so
host and so and so forth.
And periodically it will also update discovery service with its heartbeat, saying that I am alive so
that their discovery service always knows what services are available on our coast and port.
And if they are alive or not.
So similarly, every service can do that and that their discovery service will have the complete information
of all the services that are available on service instances and their health.
Now this is something that get this service can take advantage of.
There's something even broader service can also take advantage of.
It can communicate with discovery service who know where inventory service is located.
So this makes our configuration job extremely simple.
Now, all we have to do is we have to add some code to our services and we have to bring up this discovery
service.
And this is all pretty simple.
So let's see in this demo how we can make this happen.
But before we go there, let's just also take a look at the different options that are available to
us for discovery service.
Now for Discovery service, there are a lot of out-of-the-box options available to us.
Some options are so little we're going to have high ship jobs council discovery service.
We can have Netflix, Eureka Discovery Service and there are some more.
For us, it's very simple because we are using Netflix tech and it provides a lot of solutions that
microservices will need.
So we have gone ahead with Netflix.
Eureka Discovery Service.
And because this is built on top of Spring Cloud, that will make it very easy for us to integrate this
discovery service into our system.
Now, all our services are already using spring framework and because we are using spring framework
and this Netflix Utica is based on spring framework, it makes this integration much easier.
Otherwise, we could have also chosen any other discovery service.
There is nothing fancy about Netflix Yureka service.
There can be some availability differences between different services, as in Let's say, if you have
a cluster of discovery, services in a few instances are not available.
Then different services can choose different kind of availability so they can choose consistency over
availability or they can choose availability or what consistency.
But in our case, what we want is that for our services to be highly available, we do not want our
discovery service to be a single point of failure.
We want our discovery service to be highly available because if our discovery service is not available
at great risk, others will not be able to download requests to our clients.
So if adversaries is not able to do that, pretty much all our plans, like our mobile application or
web application, will not be able to access our system.
Our system will be unavailable.
So this is a very critical component.
So in that sense, also Netflix Yureka is a good choice because it prefers availability over consistency,
so that's a very good choice.
And now not see how we can very easily integrate this service into our system.