The next item that we are going to implement as part of observability is tracing.
Now we have a large scale system over here.
And if some API starts performing badly, then how do we know which component in this system is responsible
for that bad performance?
So this is where distributed request racing comes into picture.
It helps us in pinpointing the exact cause of poor performance will be able to nail down which component
is causing the delay and how much delay that is causing.
So what we do over here is the sort of profile and monitor the system as a whole.
So we know there are various ways of monitoring and profiling single components.
But here the problem is different here.
The problem is we want this entire system to be profiles.
If a request which travels through this entire system through lots of its components, then which component
actually slow down the request?
That is what we need to find out.
So what needs to be done is that we need to connect the profiling information that is coming out of
each component and we have to connect it meaningfully so that we can know exactly in which API, which
component disclosing performance problem.
So that's what distributed request tracing is, and it is absolutely essential for a large scale distributed
system.
So let's understand what kind of architecture we need to have distributed request tracing in our system,
and then we will go ahead and actually implement it.