Now we will discuss that system components in a little more detail so that we understand what we are
playing with.
Let's first look at our Web application deployment architecture.
And we are interested in web applications, deployment architecture because that will decide the performance
and scalability of a web application.
So there are two ways in which we can deploy our web application.
One.
What we can do is we can host all these static and dynamic content on web server.
So this will host both.
The other way is that we separately host static content like HTML files, JavaScript files, image files,
video files.
So we hosted that on a reverse proxy or a web server and all the dynamic content this proxy to an application
server.
So these are the two ways in which we can host up that application.
Now, a few things that we expect from our web application is that our web application should be able
to manage both slow and fast connections.
So if connections, data storage, anything from the internet, they can be extremely slow.
We call them slogan actions and the connections that originate from the internet.
They are fast connections.
So that's it.
The connection between this web server and this absolute that is a fast connection and the connection
between this browser and this web server that is called as a slow connection because that connection,
the communication happens over the internet.
So we need special software to manage these slow connections, and the server has that capability,
so we hosted web applications which are exposed to over internet through web servers.
Then the next thing that we expect from a web server is serving static resources.
So web servers can serve all this static data largely through their memory.
They know how to cache static data and how to efficiently serve them.
So these are two very fundamental things that we expect from our web server.
Now, the other thing that we expect from our web server is serving dynamic content, and this is where
these two deployment models are different in the first deployment model.
Dynamic content and static content is both served by the web server and in the second model.
Dynamic content is served by application, server and web server in between proxies on the request web
server.
So that's why it is also called less reverse proxy.
There is a third capability that that is expected from web applications and that's not part of web servers
or observers.
There are generally separate process managers that are hosting along with with any web applications,
and their job is to start, stop, monitor and scale the application as in when the load increases.
So if an application stops for some reason, then it is supposed to restart it so that it will have
to monitor it constantly.
But this is not a capability that we are interested in right now because we are going to provide this
capability to Docker and Kubernetes that we will learn later.
But for now, what we need is the application should be able to serve static resources, it should be
able to manage connections and it should be able to serve dynamic content.
So for that, what technology options do we have?
Let's take a look at that.
Like, we already discussed that there are two deployment methods that are available and accordingly,
we can choose our technology.
So in the first option where we post both static content and dynamic content on a web server, then
we can choose between Apache Web Server and Engine X web server.
Now we're using Apache Web Server.
Then we have native modules available on about web server.
So let's say we want to run BHP.
Then we have module BHP available for generating dynamic content through BHP scripts.
Similarly, we can do the same thing for Ruby and Python.
So these modules are available on Apache.
The other popular web server is an X. There, we do not have these kind of native modules available,
but we can make use of passenger tool.
We can make use of this tool to run a ruby python or nor Nautilus could write on and inexpensive.
In fact, passenger also supports Apache Web server.
So if you want to run passenger on Apache Web Server, we can do that as well.
Now, this is a good way of a simple way of running of an application, but this is not a preferred
way of running a web application.
The preferred way is the second way where we have a separate web server for hosting static content and
a different server or an episode for hosting dynamic content.
The reason is that if we have these two modules separately, we can use different kind of servers which
are optimized for that particular purpose so we can use our web server, which is optimized as a proxy
server and optimized for hosting static content.
So let's end Enix's.
One said server, which is a very good proxy server or a reverse proxy server, in fact.
So here what we can do is all the static content can be solved by the engine index and all the dynamic
content request can be proxy to nab server.
And that's why it is called a reverse proxy.
So here these episodes.
We can use different languages on this episode to make our web application.
These languages will typically use a web framework to provide regular stuff that is needed to make web
applications.
A little MVC architecture is one of them.
And it is pretty important for that application these days.
So these frameworks will provide all the boilerplate code and MVC framework to run these web applications.
So we will generally see them in a combination that we will have a language combination with a web framework
that will run on an observer.
So we have various options that are available in terms of technology.
Let's take a quick look at that so we can make our web application using BHP.
It is a pretty popular option.
It's very quick to develop and easy to learn for developers.
So lots of web site that we see they are actually based on BHP.
We can use here either la1 framework or co-ordinator.
Both are pretty popular.
So BHP is a very good option for making general websites.
Then the other similar option is Ruby Options on Rails Framework.
And this can use an observer like Puma Unicorn.
Ultimate development is again very quick in Ruby.
It is not as easy to learn as BHP, but the development is pretty good.
So this is also something which is used heavily in making websites.
That's the next best option as compared to BHP in terms of the number of implementations that we see
over the internet.
One of the recent options is JavaScript on notice, so you can use JavaScript for programming out of
web application, it will run on expressed ideas framework.
It is very popular where we have to deal with a large number of clients because it uses event model,
asynchronous model for handling large number of clients, and it provides a very low latency response.
The only downside of Nautilus is that we cannot use it for web applications that have CPU intensive
work.
Now that option and a very popular option is Python on Django framework.
This is used for large sized web applications, and it provides very quick development.
So this framework is also pretty popular.
The that choices that we have is we can also use Java with spring framework to make a web application.
Generally, it is used for large sized enterprise applications.
The development is not as quick as if we compare it with Python or BHP or Ruby, but it provides it
makes very robust web applications.
But sometimes it can be an overkill because similar stuff we can do much more quickly with Python and
we can make large sized applications with Python Django framework.
The other option that we have is SB Darknet God, this is popular within Microsoft environment and is
something that can be used even on Linux operating system.
The framework that we have chosen for our application is by a tangential framework.
The reason is that Python, Django, we can confidently make large sized applications.
Lots of big implementations used Python, Django framework and the development is pretty quick.
If we compare it with languages like Java, so does the framework of our choice.
We could have used any other framework also.
Generally, these frameworks are chosen based on the expertise that is available.
But when you are dealing with very large sized web applications, then you may like to step out of your
convenience of making web applications by BHP and Ruby.
We will have to explore options like Biton and Java, and we have chosen by them because their development
is much quicker.
Now that we have chosen by jingo framework for our Web application.
So let's take a look at the architecture of Python Django framework so that we can understand the code
that we are dealing with now.
Python Django framework is basically an MVC framework.
MVC framework is nothing.
My model view controller, it provides separation of concerns in case of Python Django framework.
It is Gardiner's MTV framework, which is model, template and view.
Let's take a look at how this works.
When you're when we're using Python Django framework and as we discussed, we will host or our static
content on a reverse proxy server, and that reverse proxy server will rout all the dynamic content
requested by the engineers over Python Django.
So that will look at the URL that has been requested.
It will take that you are to where you are at a map and it will accordingly determine what view it is
going to use to serve that as a request.
Once it is decided, what view is going to solve this request?
This view then fetch the model from either a database or from a service, depending upon the code of
this view and then this view.
Once it has passed the data, it will decide what template basically what its HTML CSS template it is
going to use to show the results.
It will populate that template with the data that it dispatched ends, and once it has created that
its HTML dynamically, it will respawn back to the reverse proxy server.
So that is how Django Python framework works.
It's an MTV model here.
Viewer decides what has to be shown.
Model is basically data that has to be shown and template as basically the format in which the data
will be shown.
So this provides separation of concerns and is absolutely needed for a web application.
Apart from this, Python Django framework also provides out-of-box crud operations.
So let's say we are directly dealing with a database.
This framework can actually help us performing trade operations, basically create, read, update and
delete.
And this can also provide a UI for directly doing operations on a database.
Although we do not need this particular functionality because in the background, we are not going to
deal with a database in case of our system.
We will have services as a package.
So our web application, Python, Django Web application will not talk to our database.
It will actually talk to as database services.
When we are working this Python Django framework in development mode, we do not need to host static
content separately on a reverse proxy so we can host that static content on the Python Django Web itself.
So that simplifies the development.
We do not have to deal with multiple components to make a web application or to develop a web application.
We can do that on a single web server and that helps in speeding up the development process.
So when we are looking at our code that we are running in development mode, we will not see any reverse
proxy running.
But when we run this web application in production mode, which we will run, then we will run it on
Kubernetes.
We will also need a reverse proxy to host static content.
So that is our Python Django framework is structured.
Now let's see the code that we have used for their application.