Before we end this topic, let's quickly understand the gains of containerisation, so we containerized
all the components of our system as Docker containers.
The reason we did that is that by doing this, we were able to package our application components into
Docker containers.
In this package, they contained the operating system environment in which they are running, and it
has all the required software that they need.
It has the correct version and the correct software.
So whatever we have specified in Docker file that only goes into these Docker containers so that we
have a very consistent environment, we can replicate it very easily because it's dead and they don't
provide.
Similarly, we have documented our environment variables in Docker compose configuration and we can
use them whenever we are launching our containers.
If there are any environment variables that are needed for building images, we can supply them in the
Docker file itself.
So by using the Docker files, we could produce our components packaged within an environment in which
they are going to run.
Now we can consistently replicate them, we can take these containers from our dev environment.
We can put them into our test environment, test them over there.
And the same thing that we are tested in our development, environment and test environment.
We can even use them in production environment so that there is never any discrepancy.
That there is something which is working in dev environment but not working in a test environment or
vice versa.
So this gives us consistency in moving forward with the development of our system, which we will need
because right now we are going to deal with a large scan system, which is going to have lots of components.
So we do not have this consistency.
We can not replicate our environment consistently.
We will make mistakes and that is going to slow us down.
So this is a big step forward in moving towards a large scale system.
The other thing that we achieved is that in production environment, we can even control the lifecycle
of our containers.
We can start and stop them like we saw, and we can even ask Docker to monitor its liveliness and restart
them in case a container goes down.
There's a slight catch over here.
This is something that we would not like to do in production environment, although for smaller systems,
we can use this.
But we are talking about a large scale system here.
The Docker functionality is not adequate for this.
We will actually use Kubernetes and Kubernetes will provide us these capabilities.
So there is something, although Docker provides, but we are not going to use in production environment
that we will use Kubernetes capabilities.
So with this, we are done with the containerization of our system.
Now we will add more architectural elements to our system.