The first thing that we're going to do is in order to manage high amount of data loads, we will try
to manage lead load at services level itself by caching the data.
So if there is some data which is not frequently modified, but it is frequently read, then that kind
of data we can store it in a cache.
And each time a request comes to our services for such kind of data, we can serve that data to the
cache instead of going to the database.
So what that does is it frees up that database from those read requests.
So not only increases the performance of those requests because we are directly fulfilling those requests
from the cache, but it also frees up the capacity of the IDMs, which can be utilized for taking up
more write requests load.
So that's the dual benefit of doing caching.
Now, I'm forgetting one thing that we need to figure out is in our system, which are those services
where we can do coaching and among these four services inventory service in order service, there are
highly transactional.
They need the most current information.
They cannot work on stale information, so they are not candidates for caching.
But let's say this product data or let's say, user information data that is a kind of data, which
is, if, let's say, stale by a few seconds or by a minute.
It doesn't hurt us that much.
So this becomes a natural candidate for creation.
And this is the kind of data which isn't modified very often.
But any user who logs in into the system and tries to buy anything will go to these services will try
to fetch the data.
So there's the ideal data.
These are the services which are ideal candidates for caching.
The challenge with caching is that we need to get the data from the main source in this case, that
means sources ICBMs, we can often call it as an origin, basically origin of the information.
So in this case it is.
The database is the primary source of information.
So our challenge is when we put this data into the cache and then this data is modified in the database.
How do we refresh the cache?
There are various ways of dealing with stale data.
One way of dealing with the data is that venue modify the data in the database at that time.
You can repopulate decay.
So that is called dynamic update.
You can update the cache as in when we are adding or updating or deleting the data in the database.
So that is something we are going to follow in our case, which is the most suitable thing for us.
But there are other approaches also, so let's hope we can add time to live values.
So data later, if time truly value is five minutes for product data, then that data becomes still
in the cache.
It expires in the cache, and the cache will not solve that data after five minutes.
So his service has been fetch that data from the database and then repopulate the cache.
So that's how TTL values can be used.
And the other there is that we can run a batch process which can periodically look for changes in the
main source of data and can update the cache.
The different situations will require different approaches.
In our case, we will follow this dynamic data update approach, wherein every time we are modifying
or adding some data and database, we will refresh our cache so we will incrementally build Aakash and
we will update is, as in when our databases updated.
So that's the approach we are going to follow.