In order to create a virtual machine, we will open a browser and you will go to Google Cloud.
Will have to go to console the cloud or Google Dot.
Once we go there, we reach to our homepage where we have to select a project.
So I have created a project called A.W. Meanies, his next project.
If you are coming here for the first time, what you'll have to do is from this election, put it on
menu.
You will come to the screen and there you have a new project button.
All you have to do over here is you have to create a project with unique names so that that's pretty
much that you need to do.
One thing I forgot to mention is that you can use your Gmail I.D. to log in into Google Cloud console,
and if you come here for the first time, you will see this offer of 90 day dollars 300 free trial.
You can use it to minimize your costs on Google Cloud if you use it efficiently.
This should be more than enough to finish this course.
When you are creating a new project and you do not belong to any organization, this is the kind of
screen that you see all you have to do over here it is.
You have to select a unique project name and you can continue with no organization over here and just
hit the Create button and that will create deep project.
Once a project is created, then you can go to compute engine.
Here we can create an instance by clicking this create instance button.
We can give our instance name, let's say, look, station one.
That would be the Instance.new.
It should be located in the closest region, so for me, the closest is.
Yes, years old ones also like Selector Zone can be aging does not matter in this case, then we will
select the machine.
You basically need to select the machine type.
How many CPU's and how much memory?
So I'll select four CPU and 16GB memory.
Then the next thing that we select is was the kind of boot disk.
This is where we will select the operating system.
By default, it is Debian Linux, but we want Ubuntu Linux, so we will change this.
We will go here and we will change this to Ubuntu.
We can even go for Ubuntu Pro also.
Pretty much the same thing, except that also provide some support and some license cost.
Then the important thing over here is that diversion of you will do that we need you're going to go
for the latest version Ubuntu 21.0 for.
So this is what we have selected, apart from this, we can increase the disk size from 10 to 12 BGP.
This will make sure that we can store everything and select this one small disk is selected, then pretty
much all selections have been done.
The price of our machine is 123 dollars per month.
If it is used 24 hours for a month, then this is the price.
We can further reduce this price by going to management.
So let's open that.
Once we are in management, we need to look for pre-emptively, the recommended setting is off.
We need to make it on.
It has all four production machines, but here we do not require production capabilities.
We can set a tone and that way we can reduce the price by almost to almost one third.
So now it is forty one dollars per month, which is about point zero six dollars.
But.
So this is good for us.
And the only downside is that if Google shortage of machine, then Google can take away our machine,
which means that we'll have to restart our machine.
We do not lose any data.
We just need to claim new CPU and new RAM.
So that's not a big problem.
Whenever that happens, at least we are saving a lot of money by doing this.
OK?
With that, all our selections are done.
Let's go to create, button and create this.
Instance.
Are Virtual Machine is created with name WUIS or Workstation one, and it has got this external IP address.
In the next session, we will come back to this machine.
We will connect to it and we will do the.