The changes that we have to make to our services are extremely simple because we are using spring framework,
so let's order some of this.
All we have to do over here is we need to go to the configuration file.
And we need to instruct spring framework to enable Prometheus Matrix once we do this, then on the Port
eight zero eight zero, which is the standard port for replication on the server port itself.
The Matrix will be enabled and they will be available.
And there you are a call slash actuator slash Prometheus.
So that's something we will see when we configure Prometheus.
So but for now, this is the only thing that we need to do for our services.
So we'll have to do this for every service.
So let's say let's look at Getraer service.
Again, the same thing, and this is the only change that we need to do to enable Prometheus in our
services, so pretty simple.
Now let's look at our web application for our web application will have to install Django Prometheus
package so that installation instruction will go in our Docker file, where we are installing all other
packages for Django.
Then the other few things that we need to do, which are, again, pretty simple that there is you are
ill start be way, there are two you are to start pivoting in our web application, one where we have
all the application, you are as defined and there is another you are to by which actually imports this
previous.
You are registered to be.
And this is where we imported over here.
We need to also provide include the what is there that exported by Django Prometheus.
So we are going to import those URLs over here.
Then the last thing that we need to do is we need to let.
Django framework now that we have installed Django Prometheus and it is part of installed apps and in
middleware section, these are the two statements that we have to put in the beginning.
And indeed, and so does this one.
This last line.
Apart from that, we do not need to do anything.
This is pretty much what we need to do to enable Django Matrix, and these Django Matrix will be available
on the solo port itself on Django Application Board on Yulara Slash Matrix.
So we will see that when we get into the demonstration.
So for demonstration, we will go to our workstation machine.
So let's go there and get into the demonstration.