So let's first start with logging, so logging something that is potentially generated by each company.
So our web application will generate log gateway service will generate log authorizations of all these
services, they will generate log, in fact, database log also we may be interested in at times, but
not generally.
There are other ways of monitoring databases.
Databases will provide their own ways of effectively monitoring databases, but we are generally responsible
for the components that we are building into our system.
We may be interested in logs of load balancers as well just to see where, whether certain requests
are hitting load balances and if they're passing beyond the load balances or they are just getting dropped
from the load balance that itself.
All of our focus will mainly be on the application load that our components are generating, so that's
what we will focus on.
But generally, this applies to every component where there are logs and we are interested in those
logs.
So let's see how we can make sense out of those logs are challenge right now is that these logs are
distributed on multiple machines and for each component which is dead on a different machine, we can
have multiple instances which will add more machines to our system so we can easily have 100 machines
in our system.
So we need some way of centralizing the law because then only if we collect these logs and make a cohesive
log out of it, then only we can draw some meaningful sense out of it because same user request, same
user interaction, which may let it go on for five minutes that may be done on multiple services and
on different instances of each service or each request can go on different instances.
So we may have to collect all that information, which is distributed in our logs, and then only we
will be able to draw some meaningful inferences out of our logs.
So for that, we will need centralized logging.
Now, in order to achieve centralized logging, this strategy that we are going to follow is and this
is generally the strategy that is followed in any distributed system.
And that strategy is that on each machine there are application components are generating logs.
We will have some agent which will read these logs as and when they are generated.
So on a real time basis, it can tell that log or whatever other mechanism it can use, it will transfer
the log contents to a log collector.
So as these logs are being generated by an application, this agent, which will be running on the same
machine, will read these logs as they are being generated, and it will transfer these logs to a log
collector.
So we'll have to port this agent everywhere, wherever we have log files that that are of interest to
us.
So all these log files, we warned these agents to send to a log collector on a real time basis was
the job of this law collector is to get all these logs from different agents.
It should actually send these logs to a storage after processing them and giving them a meaningful structure.
This storage should be such where we should be able to analyze these lots of first requirement is that
it should be a permanent storage.
We should not lose anything in this storage.
Once a log has been sent to the storage and the second requirement is.
We should be able to analyze these logs, we should be able to retrieve them.
We should be able to find the information that we are looking for and we should be able to analyze it.
Then we need analytics component, which can actually read all the log information, and it can present
it in a meaningful way.
One of them would be that we should be able to create reports out of these logs, which are stored in
the logs storage.
So with that as a goal, now what we need to do is we need to decide on what products we need that can
help us achieving this.