So the two very popular open source messaging queue options that we have are Rabbit and Q and Kafka,
both are very good for high scalability.
But Kafka is particularly good when we are considering extremely high skilled.
Kafka is used mainly in streaming scenarios where the Lord on the messaging queue is extremely high.
That kind of or we do not see in Worldpay systems, there can be systems where there are queue loads
which are extremely high.
But that is rare.
So we need to carefully consider over here whether we are going to use it every time queue or Kafka.
The reason we need to be careful is that we can go for Kafka, for ultimate scalability.
But we may not need it, and we may in turn actually make some design compromises over here.
So let's talk about the first test.
Kafka is able to actually perform to extreme scale because it can horizontally partition.
It's cute.
So that gives a lot of scalability to Kafka, which means that the message sequence is not guaranteed
across partitions.
It is only guaranteed within partition.
So that's something that we need to take care of if we implement Kafka.
But that's not a big challenge for us.
The really the two problems that we need to consider over here.
The first one is that because Kafka is a horizontally partition system, it needs zookeeper, for instance,
instances to maintain their state.
Their clusters ignore the data that they're storing, but the clusters for that they will need zookeeper.
So that's just that's an additional system we need to maintain in our system if we go for Kafka.
The next most important reason is that Kafka and Kafka, there is no push message delivery, so if a
message comes took off, that remains in Kafka, tell the consumer by itself, doesn't Paul Kafka and
pulls that message.
So there is no push from Kafka.
We can only pull from Kafka.
Now that's good.
This constant calling is good in case of streaming loads, when there is very high amount of load in
the messaging queue.
But for moderate amount of Lorde's, which is typical of transactional systems, there may not be so
much law that bullying will be a desired thing to do.
So in those cases, the push from the messaging queue works reasonably good enough so that those ads
are design considerations one that we can avoid a zookeeper by using it every time queue and that we
do not have to constantly pull the messaging queue.
We can go for that every time queue, but we can always argue that if skills have to be extremely high
and we expect that that skill will affect our messaging queue, then we can go for Kafka.
For now, there is no real reason or compulsion for us to go for Kafka, so we are going to stick to
it every time you.