So here is the schema that we will implement in our PostgreSQL database.
So we have limited tables with a limited number of columns, which is just enough for implementing the
basic functionality that we need.
Remember, we do not want to create too much of business complexity.
We just want enough complexity to simulate all the architectural problems.
So let's take a quick look at the schema that we have.
So our authorization service basically works with user or table wherein we have ID, username and password
of a particular user primary.
He's the IED.
Then we have user all table here against an ID store also.
One user can have multiple rules, so user all tables defines that, and these two tables are only touched
by authorization service.
So no other service they product inventory will ever go in to authorization tables.
Now that brings clear card segregation for us.
So later on, if you want to separate databases, that's going to help us.
In any case, from design perspective.
Also, it is not a good design if other services, other business services start going in to the tables
that they have nothing to do with.
So that's table for authorization service now for product service.
We have product table wherein we have product I.D. product name in its price.
Then there is an inventory table, which is accessed only by inventory service.
So here we have product I.D. and how much quantity we have.
If we sell some product, then we deduct the quantity in this table and that is done by the inventory
service.
Now the other two services that we have are card.
So this is an artist service card service we have physically hosted in order service instance.
But these are two separate services and we can easily host them separately also.
But for convenience, we have put card service along with orders of is now in card service.
We have a is and for each card I.D. we can have multiple card line.
So basically we can store multiple products in that.
So each card line represents our product I.D., product I.D. along with the quantity.
So that's card service tables, then order service tables or a service.
What it does is it takes card and card line tables and it converts them into order.
So orders are structured as order table for header level information in case of PostgreSQL database
or table is actually named as auto master.
It is because order is a keyword in this school so we can't use.
We can't name a table as order, so the name of the the actual name of the table is or the master.
But it actually represents order entity.
So here we have header level information.
Who has pages, the order?
What is the order in the date of purchase and the status of the order?
The order line level details, meaning the product level details what products we have pages, what
quantity we have, pages.
Those details are there in order lined table.
So these tables, they have foreign keys to related tables.
So let's set this order table has got foreign key to the user ID, which is dead in use at our table.
Now we see this if we bought this data or schema to another sequel database, these foreign key constraints,
they will go away.
So we'll have to make sure to the application itself that the integrity of the data is maintained.
There are a few things which we will again lose if we go to nautical databases, and the most important
thing that we lose is this kind of index.
So there are two kinds of indexes over here, so there are lots of primary keys over here.
Each table has got a primary key.
When we declare a column as a column or multiple columns as part of primary key, that creates a unique
index associated with that primary key when we have to search a table and that search is not based on
primary key.
We have to create secondary indexes.
Now we go to nautical databases.
That is a concept of primary key.
It may not be called as primary keeper.
Primary key concept is there, so each record has got a key in which we can call it is primary key.
But they do not have a similar concept of a secondary index night secondary index in in an hour.
We can create on any column.
So if in our query we are doing, we are filtering our data or searching our data based on some column
values which are not part of primary key.
Then we can create indexes for them.
Now that's possible in our devices.
But if you want to do it in NoSQL databases, then there are features to do that.
But that's a very limited functionality.
It doesn't scale very well.
You can create those indexes sometimes in the as local indexes and in certain instances, or you can
do.
You can create global index secondary indexes as well, but that will require you to scatter and gather
all the data.
So bottom line is they don't perform very well or they are not adequate.
So the way they work in BMWs, we cannot do it in no secret databases so that we have to design our
schema in such a way that most of these searches are done through primary key index itself.
So our schema has to bear in mind that what is what will be our assessment and how our queries are going
to look like?
But if you do not want to get into their complexity and your data limitation in your data is not going
to be extremely huge, then.
Ari BMI's is the perfect choice.
You can you have flexibility of creating schema.
You can create lots of indexes.
You can do analytics on this, although you won't do that on an old deep database, but it is still
possible and you can do transactions on this.
So.
That's the reason we are going to start with IBM's database post-crisis current.
And then later on, we will also plug in Cassandra just to understand the complexities and the features
of no secret databases.