Now, let's take a look at our Web application code for that.
Even go to court repository and in the code repository, there is web directly when web application
code is located inside that there are two directories ABPS directly and BYU, a territory bulk of the
court, is located in ABPS directly itself.
Let's open this in page up, which is an ID for Python.
So if I open this code base in Punjab, there are various directories that are there in app directly.
Let's take a look at those directories.
So first one is static directly that we are interested in.
So on the static content that we were supposed to host on a reverse proxy server is located in this
particular directory.
When we are developing our web application at that time, we will need this data in our web server.
So that's the reason it is located in static directory.
When we host this application in production mode, we will take this static data and we will actually
host it on a separate reverse proxy server.
But the location is this particular directly.
Then the next thing that we are interested is in templates and the views stored be verified.
So only views are there and will start be file.
Let's just go back to our architecture of our replication.
So we said that any user that comes to our web application goes to a URL map and that decides a view,
and we will decide how to fetch the data and which template to show.
So let's go back.
So any request that will come will first come to this.
You already start by map you are in map this, you are.
A map uses regular expressions to map a you are in to a view.
So here if we get, let's say, orders in our you order that will get map to the order's view and those
views are there in views stored by file.
So this is the filing and this is the function name in that file.
So for orders, we will have to go to orders, function, interviews, views toward the light.
So this is used to be verified within that.
We have this order's function.
So this order's function does two things it will make a request to the backend.
All right.
So it will fetch the model by making a call to the services.
So that's what it is doing over here.
Once it gets that data, it puts their data into a template.
So here the template is app orders attachment.
So these templates are located in templates that are within their templates.
There is a directory app and within that app we have this artist or attachment.
So these are holiday templates are structured.
So let's say we are looking at ordered or natural.
So this will tell us how the HTML four order view will be created.
So this is the basic structure of our web application.
So if you are analyzing the Replication Corp, it has a very simple structure and a very limited number
of files and directories that you have to navigate to.
That is one more file that we often need to worry about, and that is this setting start by file all
the variables, global variables for all our debug or logging settings.
They are there in this particular setting start to be verified.
So let's say various these services and bind located that kind of setting will be dead in this setting
start by file.
So that's very briefly the structure of our code for that application.
Now let's move to the next component.