So in order to deploy this large scale system, we are going to take help of two things.
One, we are going to use public cloud and the other thing that we are going to use is Kubernetes.
Now let's talk about why do we need them?
First thing, we need a public cloud because in order to deploy this system, we will need a lot of
hardware.
So cloud is something which is going to provide us that hardware.
It will provide us network so that this system can communicate with each other and from internet users
can communicate with this system.
Then the third thing that cloud will provide us is a Kubernetes cluster, which we will need for using
Kubernetes.
So these are the things which are easily available on cloud.
Of course, cloud provides us compute resources, the network.
But one big thing we are using cloud for is school when it is cluster, because if you are to create
a Kubernetes cluster on our own, then it's not a trivial thing to do.
So that part will be solved by using cloud.
So then let's talk about Kubernetes now, why do we need to when it is, we need Kubernetes because
it will provide us automated deployment to a configuration so we can create configuration for all of
these components and we are actually going to do that.
And that configuration can be used for deploying our system on a when it is cluster on a public cloud
every time, and we can do it very reliably.
If it works for one time, then it works every time.
So that's the philosophy behind automating anything.
So Kubernetes is going to provide us that automation for deployment.
While it provides us the automation for deployment, it also provides us the life cycle services for
different components like we have to start, stop and restart them.
It will provide us command and user interface to do that.
We will be able to monitor our application.
We will be able to upgrade them and will be able to do health checks within our system is running fine
or not.
If there is any component which is going down or there are some instances of a component which is going
down, so all those problems can be detected through health checks and Kubernetes is going to provide
us that.
It will also provide us the networking capabilities, it will provide us DNS for all of all our components
so we can address them through these names.
And we will see that we don't need to use any IP addresses anywhere.
So the way we saw in Docker compose, we were addressing our components with names because Docker also
provides us a network which has got DNS in it.
So similar capability will be provided by Google.
And it is also it just that he had this DNS will extend to multiple machines with Docker.
We work with Docker network, we were restricted to only one machine.
Now there is a Docker swarm, which is used for deploying Docker applications on multiple machines,
but it is not as popular as Kuban.
It is so cool when it is was first such product and it is immensely popular.
So we are not considering Docker using Docker Swarm over here.
We will only use Kubernetes, so we were talking about networking.
So this networking will provide us how we can rotate applications of how a request to different application
components, how they can be load balance.
All those things are also something that Kubernetes will help us with.
It will provide us high availability.
So if any component goes down, Kubernetes is actually going to restart it.
If it is not healthy, it is going to kill it and it will restart it.
So these are certain capabilities that are a must for a large scale system.
If we do not use Kubernetes, then we will have to develop these capabilities on our own, which is
something which is useless now because we have something like we went at this and it's open source as
well.
Now, talking about clout, we have many good public cloud options like Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud
and Amazon IWC, all of them are fantastic options.
I like Google Cloud for the reason it's most economical and the way it provides automation.
I like that, so it's a matter of personal choice as well.
If you wish, you can use any other cloud also, but I will not be able to provide you instructions
for that.
So if you want instructions, you can stick to Google Cloud and see how we can use Google Cloud along
with Kubernetes to deploy this entire system through a configuration and in a very reliable manner.