So this is how our system is going to look like once we containerized every component of our system
by containerization, I mean that we package our component along with its dependencies and its environment.
So let's say this is a web application.
We have taken a base for that.
So it's a python.
It's a Python application.
So its dependencies are basically Jango and Python.
The software that is required to run this particular web application, and let's say this is running
on a Linux operating system.
So we will take our Docker Linux image of, let's say, Ubuntu Linux image.
So we will package them as a container image.
And this is something that we are going to see next.
So that you exactly understand what I'm talking about.
The reason we are going to do this is once we have this complete package of every component, it will
become very efficient and predictable and consistent to start and stop our system.
So the way we are developing and dealing with our system components right now, that is going to vastly
improve.
Let's take one of these components and understand what exactly I'm talking about.