Now, let's take a look at the programming languages and frameworks that we can use for building our
services.
The service is, like you said, they have business logic, so they will have a large code base.
So here's how our code is structured and how it is organized becomes pretty important.
So due to that reason and object oriented language will be better suited for handling of high large
code base.
Now, as business logic will involve a lot of algorithms, so they are going to consume high.
We expect that our programming language and framework utilizes CPU efficiently.
This is where compiler languages have edge over interpreted languages as they will offer better performance.
The next feature that we expect from our programming language is garbage collection, so any objects
that we are allocating there should be allocated by the language runtime itself.
So we have a lot of choices for writing our services.
We can write it in JavaScript, also on Node.js.
But this is not something that is useful for CPU intensive work, so this is not our choice.
We can use Python on Django Class Framework, but Python is an integrated language.
It can work well for midsize applications, but for large sized applications, a lot of algorithmic
work.
We are not going to go ahead with Python.
Then our choices are Java C-sharp and C++ C++.
The issue will be that we will not have garbage collection, so that's in some ways it is good because
garbage collection can slow down a programming language at times.
But more often it is a problem because it slows down the development process and creates a lot of issues
for maintenance.
So this is not going to be our choice.
Our choice is going to be Java, which springboard framework.
Java is an object oriented language.
It can do just in time compilation as well, so that makes it fast and it has automatic garbage collection
as well.
So the other choice could have been C-sharp.
If we want to build our system using Microsoft Technologies, then C-sharp could have been a choice.
But in our case, we'll stick to Java.
Once we have decided to go ahead with Java programming language as the language for developing us,
so this is our choice of framework as spring framework because it provides a lot of features that we
are going to use in our services.
So that's it.
We are going to use spring rest for providing a rest interface.
We are going to use spring data for accessing our database.
So this will avoid a lot of boilerplate code that we will not have to write.
The other thing important thing to note over here is that we are not using any Aughrim over here because
the database that we have right now, it's not IBM's.
But finally, we may not like to work with another dbus.
We may like to replace it with our distributed database like Cassandra.
So we are not fixing ourself, fit one database choice.
So we are not going to use Aughrim.
Another reason for not using an alarm is that we would like to take control of the queries that we are
making to our database.
So those are the reasons instead of using any quorum framework, we are using spring data framework.
The next thing that we have over here is Spring Corps, which provides us dependency injection, so
dependency injection is important for us because when we write unit tests, we can remove a lot of dependencies
component at component level and we can substitute them by their stubs and we can do the testing.
So that is a good strategy for building a large core base.
I don't think that it can do is if we want to remove a component which doesn't happen very often, but
the it gives us flexibility of doing that.
So let's say we want to change our database, then the dependency injection will just make it easier
for us.
So it makes us easier for us to do component level changes because we cannot inject components into
our system.
The other thing that spring frameworks provides us is springboard, and we will use springboard to create
sober processes.
So this springboard provides us various options of hosting our services on embedded tomcat or Embedded
Jedi.
So we have those choices.
So this is a very flexible and lightweight option, so we are going to go ahead with that.