Are what your machine is created with name W or workstation one, and it has got this external IP address.
Now we can connect to this machine using a switch.
I'm going to click this button.
So this will take a few seconds to connect.
In the meantime, let's get the link to Bitbucket, where our code base is.
So this is the link.
I'm going to copy it.
OK, so that's a big Bitbucket link, so we are going to go to bed bucket.
We have a jet repository over there.
So here we have our code base and the way to clone this is through this clone, where then we can get
the clone command from here.
I'm going to copy it.
Once it is copied, we can go back to our association here.
Right now, we do not have anything.
It is completely empty.
Widget is installed.
It came along with this Ubuntu image, so I'm going to make use of that.
So that space, the clone command that we got from the bucket.
So code, don't load it, it is there in this minister's next directly.
Now, the next thing that we are going to do is we are going to install some software, so this software
that we are going to install, so we need to install Python three notches, JDK MAVEN and Postgres database.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So for that, we will go into our code base, Mini says next year.
We have been directory where most of the scripts are.
So we will going to be directly if I list this directly.
There are two scripts over here.
One is installed as tools and the other one is install base tools.
So based tools are required for doing the build on this machine and test tools are required for running
our application on this machine.
So let's go ahead and run these two scripts one by one.
So this is going to take some time, so I'm going to oppose it and will come back once it is done.
So basic tools are installed now, the next thing that we are going to do is we are going to install
test tools, which will help us in running the application on this machine.
So this will include software like Postgres Database one, which is not required for doing big work.
When we run the application, we will need the database.
So this script is also going to take a few minutes, so I'm going to pause the video and will resume
it once it is done.
Now, test tools are also installed.
So the next thing that we need to do is we need to build our application and we need to create schema
of our database.
So we will first create this schema of our database as part of installation.
The database got created, it got created as a service.
It's up and running so we can all connect to it using its client, which is there in the.
Everything is part of the installation process itself.
So let's go ahead and first create this schema and then we will verify it by connecting to the database.
So let's first list the scripts that we have in this.
We have a script called Create Schema Dataset, which is going to run this group called Create Schema
Autodesk Cuit.
So let's just run this.
So this shows that the script has run and it has done fine.
It has created a new database called Worms, and it has created various tables and some indexes and
as part of this schema.
So let's just verify that the way we can do that is we can create a connect as Postgres user, so we
will do that.
And we are going to use be sequel, which is declined.
So now if I missed all the databases, so this is the database that God created or miss notify, we
can connect to this database.
Once we are connected, then I can list the tables.
So we have these tables that we wanted.
As part of these tables, there is a table called user art, which even has got a record in it so we
can check that
all of these tables are empty.
But this the only table which has got a single record and it has it has got a user record of user admin
so that we can log in into our system using this particular user I.D..
So that's what we have as part of our schema, let's just get out of this.
And now we would like to trigger our build process.
For that, we will go to the root directory of our code base, which is one level up here.
We have a script code based system dataset.
We will make use of this and we will trigger this script within our government call.
It will just be whatever we need to run this system.
So let's just go ahead and do that.
So I have triggered this build systems group.
It's going to take time, and this step takes a long time because it has to download a lot of Java libraries
from the internet and for that matter, even for libraries, for Python and for religious lines.
So there's going to take some time.
It can take about 15 minutes on a new machine.
Once you have done it on a particular machine and later on, if you do it, it's not going to make.
It's not going to take that much time because this stuff is already downloaded.
It is just going to update anything that has changed.
So we will let it run for some time, and then we'll post this video and we will come back once this
is done.
The builders, it unsuccessfully, as we can see, that we have got this success message generally.
This bill will not fail because we have done everything through scripts and we are not changing anything
over here.
So as long as the operating system version is fixed, the core base stays the same and we run the scripts
to install the software.
It is going to run perfectly fine, it's going to be perfectly fine.
So I has succeeded.
Now the next thing that we need to do is we need to run the application, but we are going to do that
after we take a backup of this machine and then we will run our entire system.