Now we will quickly take a look at the structure of our services called for that I will burn the code
repository in our code repository ministries.
Next, we will have to go to services directly.
This is where all our services are.
So admin authorisation discovery, gateway inventory order product, these are different services.
So let's open this code base in intelligencia.
So here, let's take a quick look at the structure of our code base.
So let's say if we go into any service, but before that, let me tell you that this is MAVEN project.
So this is the top level bomb nerd exemplified, which is supposed to be the individual projects that
are there.
So under this, we have sub project selected product as one service.
So we have this product also as a maven project.
So that's about how to build this and how to assemble this.
So this is all a maven project now going into a little more details about how the internal code is structured
for each service so we can go into Java directly here and here you'll see various directories.
So this service directly is where the frontend gold is.
Meaning the it's the entry point for all our APIs, so product services where all our APIs are implemented.
So let's say this is an API for getting product.
This is an API for create product.
So like that, we have these restful APIs over here.
Then there is product service agent.
This is an API for health.
Check whether our product services are alive or not.
So you will see this kind of patent implemented everywhere else.
Also, then the actual implementation of a service is dead in product service implementation.
So here we have decoupled this implementation from this restful interface.
So here there is no rest logic over here.
It's only pure business logic.
So the implementation is dead end and bill is fair.
Also, all entities are defined in entity directly.
Here we have only one entity, so.
It's a simple entity that we have defined then only core that is related to data exists that is dead
in the water.
In India, you will find two implementations implemented, one for Cassandra, one for Eskom, and we
can choose either Cassandra Database or Eskom database by configuring it in conflict.
Our Properties File, which is located in resources directly to this conflict or properties file, is
bid.
All the configuration is there.
So be it related to PredPol, be it related to database configuration, discovery service configuration.
All configurations are there in conflict or properties.
One important thing to note over here is the way this code is designed.
This is just a template conflict or properties.
The real source of this configuration will be environment variables.
If we have not defined any environment variable, then only our code is going to pick up the configuration
from configured properties.
But our main source of configuration will be environment variables, and we will see that why we have
made that choice.
So this is how all of the services are also structured.
So this is briefly how our code is.
We can use MAVEN to compile and build this entire code base.