In order to run our system on Kubernetes, we will first need to create Kubernetes cluster and we will
need a container registry in container registry.
We will keep these documents that we have created.
So there's nothing new that will have to do with these Docker images.
We will use those Docker images, but we will have to put them on Google Cloud's container registry
so that the Kubernetes cluster that we will create it will pull out these images from container registry,
and it will launch these images as containers on virtual machines, which will be part of Kubernetes
cluster.
These virtual machines will be part of something which is called as node pool, which is controlled
by a Kubernetes control plane.
So this control plane is the the operating system of Kubernetes, and it controls these nodes of more
pools.
So these more pools are really the virtual machines where applications run a replication run there as
boards boards encapsulate one or more containers within each port.
So right now, we can think of them as containers.
Kubernetes will pull out these Docker images, and it will launch these images on these virtual machine
called nodes as boards.
OK.
So with that now we noticed that first thing that we need is we need to create a Kubernetes cluster.
Then we also need Google Container Registry.
And then the third thing is that we need configuration.
So when Kubernetes will pull out these images, it will deploy them on these nodes as per this configuration.
So these are the three things that we need as a setup before we can actually run our system on cue when
it is.
So first thing that we are going to do is we are going to create a pool when it is cluster and we are
going to create the Google container registry and we are going to upload all the images that we have
created so far on this container registry.
So let's go ahead and do that.