Let's connect to our workstation.
OK.
We are connected.
Let's go to the project directly and then Dr. Demo's directly.
So right now, we need to do matrix demonstration.
So let's go there.
So these are the files that we have.
There are at least two files which are new over here.
Let's go over these files one by one environment variables.
We added an environment variable, which is needed for services to enable Prometheus Matrix.
And for that, we have anyway enable them in the code itself.
So that's not customizable as of now.
I'll see later on if I can make that customizable to an environment variable, but that's how it is
right now.
So these are the environment variables we need to have.
Then the next thing is that in Docker compose file.
So if we go through this file, we have.
After Yaga, we have added Prometheus Docker container over here.
So this important image from Docker registry.
This is Prometheus image exposes a port and it takes a configuration file as a parameter, and we have
kept this configuration file in the current directory.
So we have mapped it over here in the current directory.
So this gets mapped to the config file, which Prometheus will take as a configuration parameter.
So this is where we have done that mapping.
Now, apart from this, like I said that for Postgres database, it won't export Prometheus Matrix,
so we have put an exporter over there and to this exporter, we have configured this with the information
as to where database is located.
What is the username, password and database that needs to be monitored?
Similarly for ElasticSearch, also we have created a we have added an exporter.
So this is pretty much that we need to do to enable Prometheus Matrix.
There are configuration files that we need to just.
There is one thing I think I forgot to tell you over here.
There are two configuration files that we have added.
One is Prometheus, Dart, Weinman and inside Prometheus.
Well, we have also provided one more configuration file, which is will start via email, so that is
also available in the current directory Buddhists Docker image.
So let's see those two files so they are here in the current working directory Prometheus star acquirement
and we'll start by Iman.
Let's check them one by one.
First, let's check Prometheus via email.
This is the main configuration file of Prometheus.
Here we are telling Prometheus what to monitor, so we'll have to provide that as part of script config
because it is going to scrape the pages that each application will expose on these web pages only on
certain you are, you are you read.
Each application will expose these metrics, and I'll just show you after starting the application that
what I actually mean by that.
So there are configuration for, let's say this is for web application matrix.
Here we are saying that the it is available on so and so you are right, and this is the most important
information for services.
Either we can provide this static information that there are services allocated located or we can simply
point services configuration to your recorded history and it can determine from you recorded history
where exactly service instance is located.
So let's say we have four or five authorization service instances multiple product, multiple service
instances.
So we will not have to provide this very lengthy static configuration over here, and it is slightly
dynamic also when we discuss service discovery.
So it is useful to provide service discovery over here again.
The new array on which The Matrix will be available on services is this actuator Prometheus, which
we discussed some time back.
Now, similarly, we need to, apart from the replication and services we can monitor if our yaga components
are up or not.
So we have provided Target, says yougot Agent Yeager, Collector and Yegor, Griddy, and we have given
the where Yeager exposes these Prometheus matrix.
So Yeager does that on its own.
We do not need to do anything to Yeager, who export Prometheus Matrix.
Then we have certain databases over here in Postgres and ElasticSearch.
They do not export Prometheus Matrix, so we have provided exporter's for them and these are the targets.
These exporters are the targets over here.
The last thing that we have over here is that we have provided a rules fight that and we have provided
the location for the rules.
Now let's go and check what's there in the rules, while the whole site is basically for alerts.
We are using it for alerts.
We have specified two alerts over one alerts about if some instances don't, then we will get an alert.
We can hook it with an SMS or an email alert also that whenever an instance goes down, the administrator
or whoever is in the mailing group can get mail notifications or SMS notifications.
So that kind of configuration can be done over here.
All the mail notification and SMS notifications we have not configured over here.
That's something we need to do separately, but we have put some basic functionality over here, which
will provide us alerts on the UI.
So this is alert alert configuration in case of any instance going down.
And if for some API of the latency goes up by a certain fraction, then we will get an alert.
So this is another alert for that and how they are configured.
You can get that information from Prometheus documentation.
So that's the configuration part.
And now what we are going to do is now we are going to launch our system.