I have just started the work station instance.
Now I'm going to connect to it.
OK, we have connected to the instance.
Now, let's first see the configuration that we have.
And here we will go to them was.
Let's just find out if any Docker containers are running.
So there are no Docker containers running, so we are going to go.
So let's go into Discovery Service demo directly here.
Let's take a look at the data and verify it.
So here, if we look at this dart in, we file carefully.
We have done some setting for our web app.
We have given it a registry audit, which is our discovery service.
You audit so so that now our web can connect to this discovery service.
We have done this just to get the information out of our discovery service, and we should be able to
see that in our web app.
So it just a convenience thing.
It is not playing any role in.
The application is such the one that really matters to us is these settings where we have said Yureka
Client registered with you guys Drew and Yureka Client Fetch Registry as to who this should be used
by the clients, which needs registry information.
And this is for every instance that needs to register itself at the registry.
This should be used only bike lanes.
So ideally we should have bought this only with client instances like Gateway Service or reservist.
For other services.
It's kind of redundant now the service you are.
How does each instance know where you record service is located before registering itself?
Or it is were facing registry information?
So this is this heading which will tell the Yureka most important information and for the clients that
we have used within gateway service and or service.
This setting needs to be true and we will discuss this later on in the next section.
What this really means.
So these are the settings in the environment file that we have right now in the discovery service demo.
But let's say, if we go back to our previous demo, we did not have the settings where we look at that.
Here we had the actual routing information that we gave to a load balance area, but that where exactly
each service is located, so this will give is obviously located, is where I had been services located.
Similarly authorization user profile product or the inventory service.
So what each service we had given these locations as to where they are located.
But if we look at the current environment, find this information is not dead, it is absent.
The information that is there is about the registry service.
So all the clients need to fetch the routing information from Yureka service.
So that's the difference over here.
And that's the crucial difference that we have not provided any routing information.
Now what we expect is even though we have not provided any routing information, our system should work.
So now before we start this system, let's also look at our Docker compose file, where we have created
a new service for Yurek.
Also here does this service configuration that we have done for you recorded history?
So this is pretty much the same as any other service and the overriding options that we have provided
over here.
This is a registry and it is not a cluster.
So we have done this setting over here that do not need to register with Yureka and do not need to fetch
registry information.
And we have also given here the bullet information on which this unique registry should come up.
So this will start like any other service and when we run it over Docker compose, if the image is not
already built, it will also build the image.
Debate is done as part of the comprehensive build that we have done.
That will take care of that.
The Eurico registry is also there.
If we have not done this before, then what we can do is we can go to the main project directly.
And here we can do this
doorbell system and we can just ask for a big.
I'll post the video now and wait for the bill to complete.
OK, our bill is completed.
So this has gone through, so now what we can do is we can go into Dr. Demo's directly.
And we can do this, we build over here.
So whatever images are not built, it will ensure that those images get built and if something has to
be updated, it will get updated.
So now we check the darker images.
This would be you regret you stream it.
So now we have that.
Now we have all the images that we need.
Only thing that we need to do now is we need to bring up our system, so.
We do this Docker compose of minus D, this should bring all the services that are dead in the Docker
compose file.
So this will take some time.
This has started all these services and digitized what we can build on.
Probably, let's say, Yureka service or let's do that Docker container, or we can use Docker compose
command itself.
So this is also very much like a service, adult services that we had.
It's also a Springwood service.
It just that because that is it is.
We have got it from Netflix, Utica.
So this has started the job for now of direct service or it has started it teams, but it will wait
for other services for them to register with this.
So let's just check what other services are there.
I can just do DCP s.
So let's just check if gateway service is up.
Gateway service is also coming up, so it's going to take time, there are a lot of other services,
so this machine is going to share CBD with all of these services that we are trying to bring up.
So it's going to take some time.
So I'm going to pause the video and be able to come back once all these services are up.
So our great service has come up to just check there is at least one more service which is up.
So authorisation, so this is also up so we can begin checking so he can check two things, not one
if our discovery service is up or not.
The second thing that we can check is that if the system is working using this discovery service, so
if our system is working, it is it will work only because discovery service is doing its job because
we have not provided any routing information to the system.
So let's do one thing first.
Let's try to connect to our discovery service using the browser.
So we copy this IP address and we noticed that our discovery service is actually running on board eight
seven six one.
So we should be able to connect to that.
But because we are connecting outside of this Docker network, so we will use this IP address and the
port will remain the same as we are exporting this port and we are connected to this Eureka registry
and this Eureka registry has got information for all these services that we have registered.
And these are the names host and port of.
All these services that are registered with you recorded history.
So the service is discovery service is up.
Now we should be able to work with our system on.
So let's try to access our system.
That's connect to for 8000 right now.
That is our web application book.
So we are logged in into this because we may have to log in cookie if I sign up.
Now, if I try to sign in, this should hit the authorization service.
Why our gateway service?
So this works, that means our system is functioning fine.
OK, be able to log in.
So that means at least Gateway Service and authorization service are working in gateway services aware
of this authorization service by virtue of.
Discovery service, so there is no routing information explicitly available to upgrade service.
Now let's just check if all these services are up and running or not.
So services are up now here, because now we have a new discovery service, so our registry status button
will start working.
This is what I told you earlier that we did an extra configuration in our application to make it aware
of Yureka registries.
So now if I click this, this will fetch the registry information as a JSON and this is what we have,
and this is really convenient to see all the information that is stored in the discovery service in
the Yureka registry.
So let's say this product service, it is available on this particular IP address.
And if you see the IP address of admin service, it is different here.
There's the IP address, so this one is on two and the product service is on for.
So this way we get even know the IP addresses, but here we are calling services.
We are not using IP addresses, although that is an option.
But what we are doing is we are calling them through their host name because Bulker Network provides
us DNS service and here we call services within the Docker network using that name.
Then the Docker network will resolve that name to this IP address so we can work with names.
Names is generally convenient because names do not change.
And behind that, we can change the IP address.
But when we are working with our discovery service, we can even work with IP addresses because both
information are available to us.
OK.
So that's discovery service, which is up and running right now, and that's our system which is able
to work with discovery service so that inside demo of discovery service.
With this, we have integrated discovery service into our system.