Now, let's look at the code for implementing asynchronous processing in message queue.
For that, we will go to order service in order service.
There is a dependency in bombed out example for messaging client.
So this is the vision of the every time you claim that we are using and the exact dependency should
be somewhere over here.
This is the exact dependency for that.
We don't, you know, after that, let's look at the configuration that we will need to implement.
The message in Q4 that we will look at are considered properties.
Now, if you look at this, there are two set of flags over here.
So one is for asynchronous processing.
If we turn on this flag, then the order service will do asynchronous processing of oil, create order
requests.
Right now, it is set to false and that's why there is no is in as processing.
But going forward, we will set this to two.
Now, once this is set to true, then we need to specify what kind of queue we are using.
So there is one queue for testing within this code base, and that queue is called as local queue.
So we can use that when we are not using it every time queue.
But when we decide to use it every time queue, then we can replace this particular flag with it every
time you.
Once you provide data, every time you information, we can provide the host information over here.
So wherever the host is looking to export, information also has to be provided or any other information
that can also be provided over here.
Because the cure will restore order, so we have named the queue that we will create in reduced order
queue.
So now let's look at the code that is going to do asynchronous processing.
So for that, we will go to order service in service directly.
There is order service which has all the IPAs, the root level APIs of the service, and this service
calls the implementation service.
So this does not have any business logic.
It's just a wrapper for web service related code or restful service.
Related Good.
The implementation.
Is there an order service implementation?
Well, here we have to work to create order code.
So this is create order code.
Now in this create or record, what is happening over here is that it is looking at the guard and from
that it has created an order in memory and this is where the actual order processing is going to happen.
Here we are first.
Taking off this flag is in order processing, which is nothing but this particular flag that we saw.
So if this is said to to.
Did the secretary then order preprocessor in Cuba, the order and this order will go to the messaging
queue, if asynchronous order processing is not enabled, then we will directly send this order to order
post processor.
And that will directly process the order.
If asynchronous processing is true, then it will go to three processor and three processor will send
it to messaging, queue and messaging.
You will send it back to this order post processor.
So that is the loop over here.
Now, in order to better understand how this is, structure that just hit the court.
So this is for order published.
So we have to publish the order, the order.
So right now, we have that in order service implementation as we saw that for publishing in order for
sending it to Cuba, even handed over to order preprocessor object.
And this order pre-processed, Sarabjit, been handed over this order to or the producer or the producer's
job is to put this order into messaging.
But because we have two kinds of messaging.
One is local messaging.
You are text messaging you and the other one is that every time you.
So we have added an abstraction in between.
So this order produced that instead of putting this order into messaging queue, it will use this abstraction
in between, which will actually do the job of putting the order into the message queue.
But before we put this order to message queue, we will convert it into a serialized form into adjacent
form.
And in fact, the order and it itself will change that.
We will discuss how to just show you.
But this is the floor for publishing the order next.
When the queue receives the order, it will notify its consumer.
And again, we have added a consumer abstraction over here and you can do what it is not directly going
to order consumer because we have two different kind of queues.
So we are two different kind of consumers.
So this will come to market consumer.
So this is not a concrete glass, concrete glasses every time the consumer or local Q consumer.
So it will go to either one of them, whichever it is any of it, and that will hand it over to that
will end over the serialized order to order consumer or the consumer will convert the serialized order
into another object, and then it will give it to order post-processing, which will actually do the
job of creating the order and resolving the inventory.
If asynchronous processing was not enabled, then we would have directly given order to order post processor.
So this is how the code is structured, so he can see this over here.
So this is also this implementation and all these processes.
So this order preprocessor in order post-process, they are there in this processor package.
These preprocessor in post processor will send or receive the order from Q and that all that code is
regarded.
It related to that is that it q package.
So this Q package has two games of Q Local Q package and every time Q Q package.
But the interface for dealing with it every time you had local AMCU is Amcu produce that Amcu consumer,
which is what we saw here.
So this Amcu consumer and Amcu produce it is.
These are the interfaces and these interfaces are implemented either by an open bank or every time you.
Now we have disorder consumer in order to producer, as we see over here, this auto producer deals
with them to produce it.
So this auto producer?
Since the order, by transforming this order, so this order entity, it's sensitive to the messaging
by converting into adjacent methods.
And if we see this, this is not an order entity over here, we have converted this order into an MQ
order.
Now we have converted this order into an empty order that is, look at this and you order glass.
So this is a rebuttal glass on top of order.
So it has got an order inside this, which is what we really want to hold on to this glass.
Then we have this authorization or headed this authorization, Hader will be used by it.
Let's go back to consumer flow.
So once this civilized order is DC released by our consumer, it will have to call inventory service.
When this order goes to or the post processor, it will need to call inventory service and to call inventory
service.
It will need authorization.
So everywhere, wherever we were making rest was we were passing authorization hairdo along with A.B..
But here there is no HGTV protocol.
We have received this message from messaging.
So what we have done is that the authorization that will be required to call the Nest Full Inventory
military service will be put in to order object to sell this MQ.
That object so that we can use that authorization heard it to call messaging queue.
So that is what we have stored in your head.
This authorization, and the other thing is that we need to resume.
We have already gone through tracing.
So when we are tracing create order request, let's go to the publisher.
So this is a part of creating a workflow to create our workflow is being placed.
So when we publish this message to the messaging queue, then our press is lost.
So when the execution resumes from message queue, sending the message back to the order service, which
is actually a consumer also.
So from here, we want to resume our trees and we can resume arteries only if we have the context.
So all the press context related information that is required to resume the trace is stored in this
particular map.
And this is something that we also discussed when we discussed yaga tracing.
So these two things, additional things we are putting into and order apart from the mean order object.
So this is what is that important and that is why we have created this extra entity over here.
So this is pretty much how the order code is structured and it does asynchronous processing.
Before we finish this topic, that is one this last bit of how we are creating this producer and consumer
objects.
For that, we have to go to order new configuration file.
So this has been a messaging queue.
Configuration is dead.
Here we are creating two kinds of objects.
One is MQ producer kind of object and other one is MQ consumer kind of objects.
The reason we are creating this in the configuration is because depending upon what is the queue type,
we will create the type of producer.
So if it turns off David, every time, kill our producer will be every time you produce it.
Otherwise, it will be local and you produce it.
So similar stuff is happening for Amcu consumer as well.
So this object, depending upon what is the type of this environment variable, will be there every
time consumer or local, and your consumer or consumer will have to do one more thing that will have
to start a consumer trend which can actually listen to the rabbit and you so will have to go to it every
time to implementation.
OK, so this is that every time to consumer and here.
We are calling this method start consumer, which will create a callback of callback of this glass is
a wrapper class that every time to call back, which we have created over the.
This class implements deliver call of Rabbit and you, and it implements a method called handle method.
So this is actually the callback method handle is the is that method and this method, all it does is
it takes this consumer object and hence over the order object or the message object to order consumer
for processing the order.
Now, when we call the start consumer, this will create that callback.
It will put this order consumer to do that so that it can make use of this for the consumer, for order
processing.
And it will register this callback with the messaging queue channel.
So whenever there is a message from Rabbit and you rabbit and you will call this particular callback
and this callback will actually use disorder consumer object to process this order.
So this is how the complete asynchronous workflow is working with Rabbit.
And you know this, we are actually ready to run it every time queue in our system.
So let's go ahead and do that.