Like I mentioned earlier, now we are going to run out of application using Docker compose.
So let's go ahead and do that.
For that, we are going to use some configuration.
And this is the configuration that we are going to use.
So let's copy this configuration.
And before we use this configuration, let me explain you a bit what this configuration is.
So using this configuration, we are going to create a Docker compose configuration file.
We are seeing that we are going to use Docker compose version 3.5.
And then we are listing all these services.
These are Docker container services.
These are not the services of our system here.
Services is in the context of Docker containers.
So here, as part of these Docker services, we are creating a service cloud.
Then there's the name that we have given to our container, which is going to run our web application,
which is what we just saw, just that now we are going to be run and stop our web application Docker
container using this particular configuration.
So that's why we are trying to understand this particular configuration.
It is pretty useful because this is this will immensely help us in dealing with these Docker containers.
So as part of this work we have done over here is that we have specified how we can build our Docker
image.
So this section precisely tells how we are going to build this Docker image to test that the context
directly is Dot Web.
Here, Dart is the directory where the Docker compose file will be there and inside that.
So that is our Docker directory inside that there is a web directly.
Here it is where we will file Docker file.
So this is that configuration.
What is the new motor Docker file and any software that we want to copy on that image will be located
in this web directly.
So this is how we are going to build this.
And this will be the name after debate, and this will be the name of the Docker image that we will
use for running the container.
This will be the name of the container when we launch the container using this configuration.
It will be given a host name as web.
The network more is again hosted over here, and we are seeing over here that use this command Python
three managed or violence over to start this particular web application in development mode, and we
are actually starting this in development work so that we can get this data contained along with dynamic
content.
If you remember, we discussed this that in development work, we can host both of them on the same
web server.
Otherwise, we'll have to launch a separate web server for static content.
So we do not want to get into that complexity right now.
We will do it a little later when we get it to load balancers and reverse proxy.
That's where we will do this.
For now, we will use this particular development mode command to launch our web.
Applications of this command is actually going to override the default command that we have specified
in the Docker file configuration.
So this is how Docker composes.
Let's go ahead and use this configuration, so we will go to the parent directly.
And here we already have a Docker compose dart via email file, where we have already configure all
the components with whatever configuration we need.
It is already there.
But for our understanding perspective, what we will do is we will create a new file and let's call
it as Docker compose treated Dart VM.
And so this is a new file that we are creating.
We'll have to copy the contents from here.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Hopefully, this is copy.
So let's paste it over here.
OK.
Let's just save this one.
Get this via email finance whenever you are dealing with that.
Make sure that you do not have tabs in them and things like that can corrupt via email file, so you
have to be really careful with these by email files.
So best thing is to copy the configuration, which is which you have already tested.
So now let's stop the Docker container, which is already running for that.
What we will do is Docker, stop this container of it.
Then the next thing that we are going to do is we are going to remove this container altogether because
this will be present on our system as a dead container right now.
So if I see Docker container rails, it won't list anything.
But if I say Docker container rails minus here, it will list this dead container that was launched
using this and data blue using this A.W. web image and this web new.
So we will remove this container, otherwise we will not be able to recreate it.
So let's go ahead and do that, and the command to do that is government minus F and the container name.
So we removed it.
Now we are starting from a clean slate over here from this container perspective.
Let's first go ahead and build this container for that.
What we will do is we will use this command called Docker Compose now.
Docker compose is a pretty big name.
So what I've done is I have created assembling all B.C., right?
So this link was created during the installation of Docker.
That script created that so we can verify that.
So if I say let's minus in which DC, so it will tell us that this particular command DC, which is
a link, it is actually a link to Docker compose command.
So when I run DC Command, I'm actually running Docker compose, so it makes typing a little lesser.
So that's why I'm using this.
So if now we have to build a container image, then it is pretty simple.
With Docker compose, what we'll have to do is we'll say Docker compose minus f docker compose this
Docker compose file.
So if we are not using a file other than Docker compose start Weinman, then we do not need this particular
option.
But in this case, we have created actually a different file.
So we have to use this option.
Now the building is pretty simple.
What we will do is we will separate and if we say big, then it will build all the services that are
there in the configuration file, right?
Or if you just want to build one, we will give the name of that configuration and that the name of
the configuration was web.
So let's do that.
So this is this has rebuilt the image, the installation, and all was already done.
There was no change to that, so it will reuse the image that was already built.
So it bears images in layers and it can reuse those layers.
So that's why once you have already built atop that image next time, it is pretty fast.
It basically starts from the place as in the Docker file, where we have made some changes before that
it will reduce the layers that would already be OK.
So that's how you build Docker image using Docker compose.
Let's clear this.
Now we are going to run this for running this part.
We are going to do this.
We will say Docker compose up minus d minus these for detached more.
Otherwise, the application that will be that will run will run on this particular dominant.
And if we kill that terminal, that particular application will die.
Along with that, that particular Docker container will exit.
So we run it in the Densmore.
Right now, we want to run that container.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So it has started that we can check the processes that are running.
So we will say DC, CBS.
If you want to check the logs, games here are composed of our logs minus have web.
So this particular Web application has been lodged, this Docker container has been launched.
The logs are little different this time because we're used to different command this time.
OK, so what should happen now is that if we send a request to our web application, it should give
us a response, so we will send a response to start as you are it.
And we got backup response.
So that means our web application is running perfectly fine for that matter, if we want to connect
from our system using browsers.
So this is my workstation from where?
I am trying to connect to leadership.
I open a new depth.
But before I go there, let me get the IP address of the host on which we are running this Docker container.
So that's the IP address and port number is 8000.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So our web application is running, right?
It won't do anything useful other than this.
Correct.
Because there are no services or database of anything over there.
OK.
So that's pretty good.
We were able to connect to our web application from the workstation that we are working on.
You'll have to make sure that the port is open on the firewall rule that covers this particular host.
So there's the cloud machine on which are Docker containers, running rights, visiting machine.
So there is a firewall rule that we had created for this particular machine, and that firewall rule
should have eight thousand portals open if you're not able to connect to that port.
You see that browser is trying to connect and is not able to correct them.
You know that the port may not be open.
That firewall port may not be open, so you will need to go ahead and do that.
OK, so the next thing that we need to do now is that we need to start other components like our services,
our database as Docker containers, so the next thing that we are going to do is we are going to start
our services in other components as Docker containers.