Before we go ahead with the implementation, let's understand how Yeager will connect the different
test information that is coming out of different components.
So let's say we send a create order request and it goes through web application, Gateway Service Product
Service Order Service Inventory Service.
Then how is your connector going to connect these different traces, which will come out of these different
machines?
The way it happens is that Yeager keeps track of a request by maintaining certain IDs, and these are
going to span eight years, which are passed along the day context.
So let's first understand what means.
And then we will understand the context, and that will make it very clear how Yeager is able to do
distributed tracing across multiple components.
So the way it works is that when a request enters into our system, so let's say component error is
the first component, which is instrumented by Yeager Library.
So this receives a request, so it will create a unique I.D..
Now, this unique ID represents the timespan that this particular request will spend in componenti.
So that said, this is the time spent.
This request will spend in this component.
So it will create an ID called Span 80, which will correspond to this time spent that this will request
spend ID component.
Now, during this time span, this request will spend some time doing processing within component day.
But it can also make calls to its downstream services.
So what can happen over here?
It can make a call to, let's say, this component B. So now this request has come to Component B,
and now it is going to spend some time in component B. So Yeager claimed libraries are going to record
all these times whatever time requests are spending in these components, and these will be called Spann's
and the Web.
Yeager can connect these spans and do a trace is through these context information that it will pass
along with the request.
So the way it works is that this unique idea that we created spanned it is the context information when
the request is in component a when.
So this is the, let's say, this bad idea that was created.
So then this request is sent to Component B and because it has originated from component component B,
well.
Create a new, unique ideas, new or unique idea of its own span.
And it will append it to the parent spent.
So this will become the new context of requests of this request when it is in component B, when this
request is again sent to its downstream service or downstream component.
This whole information of these two span it is linked in one string will be sent to the component C
as the context.
So this will be the new spend that will be created in Component C and this unique span, it will be
added to this.
So if we look at this complete context information within a component, then that context information
gives us the complete lineage of request where it originated, where it went and from there that this
request has come to this particular component, so a complete trace can be deduced from context information.
In this context, information is in case of study Peter Greste.
It can be passed along with a step ahead as so in case of Yeager.
If you debug this, or if you look at this DHCP request, you will find that this is an implementation
information.
But I'm letting you know so that you know how this works.
So there is a header name called Wilbert Trace ID under that name.
This particular header value will be passed.
So obviously, this information will be different than the this information is passed to different components,
depending upon the lineage of the request.
But this is how each span will be recorded, so each band will have the complete lineage along with
it as to where this request originated from and where it flowed from, when it reached to a particular
component.
So when this request is in span than it is in E, then this span in EE knows that its parent is actually
spend it.
And because there is no parent of spend it.
So that means this was the first component that received the request.
So this is the way Jigar can connect.
All these span of press information from these individual spans into a cohesive single trace.
So let's go ahead and actually implement it and see how we can achieve this space by using Yaga in a
distributed system.