Now, before we go to our workstation for the demonstration, we need to increase the capacity of our
workstation because we have lots of components in our system now.
So we will need a bigger machine.
So what I've done is I have already started the machine.
You can go here and start, stop whatever needs to be done to have stopped the machine.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to edit it to increase the capacity of this machine.
So let's go ahead and go ahead and do that.
Here we can edit it.
So right now we have two CPU and 8GB of memory.
I'm going to increase it to four CPU and 16GB of memory rest, everything can remain the same.
So just need to make sure that dependability is on, so predictability is one that will cost will be
under control, so and we will save it.
OK, so the machine is updated now we can go ahead and start this machine.
So let's start there.
This machine start will take some time, so I'll stop the video over here and we will resume our demonstration
in the next session.