Let's get into a redemptive demonstration, so we have this machine, let's get connected to this.
While this is connecting, let me tell you that I have upgraded this machine, so if we go and look
into the properties of this machine.
And edit it if we look at this, the machine tirade right now is E-2 Standard, which has got eight
CPUs and 32GB memory here at CPU's is good for us.
We need that, but 32GB memory is a bit too much.
We do not need that much.
But because this machine comes as a standard machine, so we have taken this.
Otherwise you can go for a custom machine also.
Nevertheless, we have this machine and we expect this to perform a bit better from the previous machines
that we were using.
So now let's go to our connection.
So we have connected.
So let's go to our demos directly Docker demos directly.
Now, the demo that we are interested in right now is this number 10 is in the process.
So let's get into that.
These are the files.
First, we will look at in B file what we have ED over here is these flex order process.
Async is hard to do because we want this process to be asynchronous.
Q-Tip is that every time Cube and we have specified host for every time QC, every time Q itself.
So those were environment variables.
Now let's look at our Docker compose file in Docker compose file.
Let's start from the top.
The only thing that has changed over here is that we are rated a venue for rebuilding.
So that's a change from the previous demo.
Now going to the next change we have created to order service instances, so I'll just stop at that.
Yeah.
So here we are, so earlier we had order service as the order service now because we have created two
instances to give a flavor of multiple instances.
So we have named it as auto service one and the other instances, orders of these tools you now instead
of one consumer of our every time we will have to consumers.
So that's the change with our order service.
It works the way it has been.
Working order change now, the last change that we import is that we have created a rebate MQ container
over here, and this container uses this image from Docker registry that every time queue of management
version.
Now it exposes some ports, the last port is required one, five, six nine two, I think this one is
required for the administration console, but there is this other old one five six seven two which is
required for Prometheus audited all the way around that 7:02 is required for main console and nine is
required for Prometheus Matrix.
So because everytime you exposes Prometheus Matrix by itself, we do not need any exporter like we have
work for Radius, Postgres and all those components.
So here at every time, you will expose Prometheus Matrix by itself.
So that's our component configuration.
With that, we are ready to run our system.
So let's launch that.