Now, let us understand the court changes that we need to make in order to incorporate Cassandra into
our system.
So all of our services, they can actually use either Cassandra or both.
So we can use a mix of both.
Or you can just use Cassandra for everything or PostgreSQL everything.
So we have already seen usage of Postgres for all these services.
Now let's see how we can use Cassandra.
So let's go to order service and pretty much all other services they will use.
Cassandra exists in dissimilar way, so there is nothing unique about the service.
But when we look at our service, let's say we are going into the service, then we will need to go
into this deal or directory.
This is where our data accessibility record is there.
So here there is an interface called order to you.
This defines all the methods only database access methods for order entity.
Now this is implemented by Sequent for Postgres database.
And then this directly Cassandra.
The code is implemented for Sequent for Cassandra.
So both of them implement this same interface so we can use.
We can just switch to any of the implementation, either Cassandra or Sequent, depending upon the configuration
which we do over here.
So order Debbie configuration, if you go over there, this is there is conditionality on the beans,
depending upon what kind of database type it is.
If it is equal, then these Cassandra related beans will be created or if it is sequel.
So let's go a little down.
So let's set these beans.
This being it is required for Postgres database will be created only if database type is said to skew
it.
So this has only connection information.
So here we will let these beings know what the whole sport and schema name related information is,
so all their configuration will happen over here.
All the beans will be created over here and whatever configuration, environment, variables or parameters
they need that will be provided through this conflict or properties as usual.
So if Cassandra needs to know what hosts are there or court is there, what's these key marquee space
name in Cassandra schema name is called those actually key specs so that it will be configured over
here in a very similar way.
We did this for Postgres database so that state configuration bar.
Now let's see the DOJ implementation.
So this will be let's have this get out.
It will be implemented by.
DV order deal in sequel for both crass and borderline, do you focus on?
So let's go to Orlando, you.
It has Orlando, in case of Cassandra, because, like I said, we only have borderline people over
here, we do not have any master table, we have a normalized table.
So here the query looks like this.
Select star for getting up, getting in order.
Select Star from borderline, where user ID equals to this user I.D. So we are just building a string
over here and it is equal to this.
So it's very much like a sequence where we are fetching all the order lines, where user ID equals to
some value and the ID of an order also equals to some value.
So this is what we are doing over here.
Similarly, if we have to, let's say, get orders, then we have a similar rescue in select star from
Model Island, where user ideas could do this and we are not specified any authority over here.
So we will get all the orders for a particular user.
For use cases like this, we have set primary key, which includes user I.D. and Order I.D. So so that
we can fetch this through the primary key index of that is by default, only one index, which is primary
utility index in Cassandra.
At least we can see it that if you're coming from sequel background as security background, OK, so
this this is guitar it is now.
The rest is this is same order.
Basically, we are going to a bit lines over here, so each order will have multiple over the line.
So we are looping them over here and one by one, we are inserting these order lines.
So if these are the lines are already present, then they will be overwritten.
One thing to note over here is that we are giving this query an object.
So this is something that spring will take care of inserting this or creating insert query.
So we are from a borderline object.
We have created DB order or borderline.
We have created to mimic Cassandra Borderline Table.
So this DB borderline object actually represents the borderline entity in Cassandra database.
So it has got these attributes and it has got a primary key, which is DB order giving you a different
and it has got these three attributes User ID, then order, then borderline I.D..
So this is how we defined our primary key, and similarly, we have to define corresponding primary
key class over here.
So this is our spring stuff, standard spring stuff of accessing a database.
Now with that, the discovery will work that the object that we have created the borderline objects
out of Borderlines Cassandra operations or the Spring Cassandra databases will be able to insert our
data so that our insert is done now.
Remove water.
So there are different ways of doing this.
There is no fixed.
We are doing this.
Spraying provides multiple ways of doing this.
I have reliably followed of it, which I found easiest or which I found earliest.
It could have been any of those.
I didn't necessarily try to find the best way of doing it.
So this is just any way of doing it.
Similarly, you can remove orders from the database, you can truncate the all complete table and stuff
like that.
You can do what you will do in a normal year for an RDM.
So things like that can be done for Cassandra as well.
Now, one thing to which is distinctly different in case of Cassandra is that so let's say we are writing
multiple order lines, so we are doing this in a loop.
We can possibly run this as a batch operation, but the fact is that they will be inserted one by one.
And if the system crashes in between, then we may have to take care of the partial updates or something
which are not handed over again.
But this is something I need to handle.
So maybe in future versions, I'll try to see what's the best way to handle those kind of situations.
So right now, we have just a dress code for birthday, but we may have to write code for those edge
cases where the software process may crash in between, and that will result in partial of doing so,
things like that we still need to take care of.
OK, so that's the code for Cassandra in brief.
Now let's go and see Cassandra in action.
Let's run our system with Cassandra database.