Now, let's take a look at the core of how we can implement the catch, so let's go to product service
where the cash is implemented.
So if we go to the court, the first thing that we need to look into is cash configuration.
So it's a spin configuration file wherein what we are doing is we are we are doing two things.
We are creating connection to this case and we are creating a release template.
So this is a standard spring we like.
We are JTBC templates.
So similarly, this is this template to excess and it is and the connection is configured over here.
Whatever hostname or name, that kind of information that is required, it will come from the configuration
file.
So this is where we can specify that configuration.
In this, we have also specified a configuration called Radius Start Enable is equal to falls.
This configuration is useful in case we do not want to use it in this case, and for all the previous
demos that we have been using, this was enabled.
So this is how you disable or enable it, rest, whatever parameters are required.
They can be provided in configuration file and they can be ordered over here to provide it to the connection
factory.
So that is how we create connection to what it is.
You can take a look at it.
Then the next thing that we need to do is how do we access the cash?
So this one.
Is implemented in product service implementation.
So if we look at the functions and product service implementation, let's look at.
Get products by ideas.
So here first, we are trying to get products for those ads from the cash.
And then we are trying to determine.
Which products we were able to get from the cash if there were missing products that we were not able
to get from the cash?
Then we are trying to get those products from the database.
And once we fetch those products from database, we are adding them to the case.
And similarly, if you look at more simple function, get product for a particular idea.
First time to get it from the cash.
And in gas, if we do not find it in the garage, we are.
Fencing it from the database and then adding it to the garage so that next time NBA access to cash,
we do find this particular product.
That is how we are going to build our cash on this cash will get obliterated when we are creating data
and when we are adding products that API of ad product.
So if you see this ad product over here will also add those products to caps, so these products should
always be available in the garage.
So similarly, when we are modifying a product in the database, we will also have to modify any product
in the cache.
The things that we need to be careful about is that, let's say over here, if we modify the product
and just after that, if over here are so process crashes, then we would not have fight the product
in the cache.
So these are the kind of challenges that are there.
We can get stale data from the cache in that sense.
So this is the time to layer values become important.
So in case we were not able to modify the order, then these products, let's say we have set expiry
time is five minutes.
Then that will make sure that the product will not be stale for more than five minutes.
OK, so similarly, when we are removing products, we'll have to make the corresponding changes in
the cash.
That is one function or way here, which is get products now.
This is not directly implemented for the want of time.
What is happening over here is that we are trying to get sort of dysfunction, tries to get all the
products and we are getting all the products from cash.
If we are not able to find them in cash, we are finally getting them from the database and then we
are adding them to the cash.
Now there is an obvious problem over here that if the number of products are huge in our database,
that will not be able to hold them into our memory.
So we will need some kind of pagination over here and some kind of product varieties so that we do not
catch everything from the database.
And consequently, we will add only those limited products to the cash.
So there is something this is an area which needs an enhancement that is working right now because this
we do not have huge amount of data, but it is something that should change in the future.
So this is how a cache would be implemented.
Now we have seen this, that it is pretty easy to implement the cash, so now we will go ahead and bring
up our system with this great escapes.