Let's connect to our workstation to run our system with Cassandra database.
OK.
We are connected.
So let's first look at how we have created Cassandra image, so even going to Dr. Cassandra directly.
These are the historical files.
And then within that there is an image directly there.
There there are quite a few fighters.
I'll explain you the ones which are most important for us to understand.
First, let's look at the darker side.
Don't go to find what we are doing is we are.
Getting Cassandra image from Docker Iris Docker registry, then we are installing side doors, which
can help us for debugging, and then we are copying sardine files to Cassandra image from our local
directory and these files will be helpful for us for creating schema.
So this creates schema.
Sequel File will create schema insert data will insert some data into the database with which we can
start with in Docker, and three point second datasets will actually run just after the Kassandra container
comes up.
This file will be launched.
Because we have specified this file is darker and deep learning, so this this this is this is our entry
point and this will call this particular file in this particular file after running these schema creation
scripts.
It will called the normal at entry point or such file, which comes along with this ongoing image.
So whatever default, Cassandra has to run little to bring up the database and all that stuff that will
be done by this particular regular.
OK, so we'll see how it does not guarantee point second order sketchbooks in a week.
Then there are the jar file that we have copied for Prometheus to work.
So these are Prometheus related files that we have copy, and that is pretty much what we have in this
Cassandra image.
So we have just copied certain files.
And the main thing that we have cooperate and just tell you is this Docker entry point search and those
schema and data in session scripts.
So what this does is it looks for this environment variable replication factor if it is not set to anything
that it was set to one.
We would like to set this to trade because we are going to run Cassandra Cluster with three nodes.
We want our data to be replicated, at least on three.
Not so that if we lose one node, our data is still there on two nodes, and that's sure that is a quorum.
So that will allow us to do transaction.
And we will see that in a bit that even when we lose a node from Cassandra cluster, we'll still be
able to read and write to Cassandra Cluster.
OK, then we have Cassandra seed instance.
We want only one instance to create schema.
We do not want all instances to create schema.
So this is an indication to the to a container, if it is, if it is supposed to create a schema or
not.
So when we define container definition, we will see that one of the container, so we will create three
containers for three Cassandra nodes.
So Cassandra, one, Cassandra, two, and Cassandra D, and one of them will be referred to as schema
seed instance.
In case we do not specify that, then the default name is Cassandra, and this is generally useful in
the test systems.
But this particular statement is not useful right now.
Then there is a command for Cassandra Cline, who connect with Cassandra, so so that Cassandra Cline
can run this script, create Schema Dirt sequel on Cassandra Server or one of the Cassandra nodes.
So what this script will try to do is it will try to connect with Cassandra server process, and once
it is connected, it will use this command.
This particular command, which is defined over here.
So that schema gets created.
Now, the thing that we need to watch out over here is that while Cassandra database is coming up,
this may not be able to connect till it doesn't come up fully, so it will run in a loop.
And once the Cassandra database comes up, then this sequel sequel's edge line will be able to connect
to that, and it will be able to create schema.
So you can take a look at this, what exactly it does, and you can look at the demonstration, how
this works.
So this is how we'll be able to create schema.
So this is an automation for creating schema.
There's nothing specific to Cassandra.
This has just the convenience of creating schema ones.
Cassandra instances comes up.
Then the last thing that is happening over here is.
That we are launching docket entry point of the Cassandra image that we downloaded from Docker registry,
so whatever it is supposed to do, we will let you do that.
But before that, we will force her to run this particular function that we have defined over here.
And this is where we are launching this function and we are calling this function only if the host name
matches that schema seed instance.
So in our case, Cassandra, one instance would be seed instance, and this is where we want to create
this schema.
So let's just go ahead and see that, and that will make it more clear.
So once we go to container definitions, this will be more clear.
So let's move from here.
This was about Cassandra image.
Now let's go to the container definition, which will be dead in demos directly.
Right now, we are going into this demo 11 distributed DB.
So let's go there.
So apart from other files, what we need to pay attention over here is DOD Environment File here.
Database type is equal.
So this is an indication to our services that what kind of database we are using.
Then the other environment variable is Cassandra Horse.
So we have given prehistory here Cassandra one, Cassandra, two, and Cassandra, three.
So these will be the horse and our services can connect to any of those.
So let's say if Cassandra two goes down, they can work with Cassandra, one, and Cassandra, three
in case three goes down, they can work with one and do so.
Then we have specified port over here and the schema name will here, which is for MS.
OK, so that's about environment variables.
Now let's look at the container definition.
We have created volumes for Cassandra DateTime Cassandra logs, and we have created them separately
for each of the three instances that we are going to create.
So let's look at those three instances that should be dead at the bottom of this script.
OK.
So this is the first one, so if you look at Kassandra one.
The important thing to note over here is that, OK, so let's just talk about polls first.
So this is Cassandra's standard to which any plan can connect and seven zero seven zero four for Prometheus
Matrix.
So Prometheus monitoring can connect to this particular port to script Cassandra meetings, and we have
given JVM options.
So Cassandra is a Java processor, JVM, which sends over here.
We can tweak the memory over here.
If your memory is not enough, you can always come and increase this schema seared instance.
Like I said on one instance, we want to create schema.
We will run that script in that environment variable.
We have specified for Cassandra when we have not specified this environment variable for any other instance,
then replication factor is three and Cassandra seeds.
This is a Cassandra configuration.
This is not automation.
This is all nodes in Cassandra Cluster, which node they can initially connect to, who know about cluster.
So what other members are there?
If some node has to join a cluster, it needs to inform these Cassandra seed nodes, and they can also
talk to these signals to know about other nodes in the cluster once they know about that.
Then later on, they can directly communicate with those other nodes.
So this is setting, which is required only during this startup Nest.
All of the settings are pretty much these M, R and D point is not very different.
Second, data sets, which is a script which we are using to create schema.
So we look at Cassandra two definition.
It is pretty much the same, except that we did not have to do things like Cassandra seed instance or
replication factor over here because we are not creating schema over here, but we still need to let
it know which Nord actually connect to to know about the cluster.
So this is an initial setting that is required.
Similarly, we have Cassandra Trino.
So here also we have specified this Cassandra saves environment variable.
So that is how we have this define three containers.
Cassandra, one, Cassandra, two, and Cassandra, three, and they will form Cassandra Cluster.
So let's go ahead and run our system bit Cassandra cluster.