OK, so all our container images, they have been uploaded to Google Container to justify a new refresh
container registry.
It has all the images that we have created.
So now the next thing that we need to do is we need to create Kubernetes cluster.
So for that, let's go to.
Kubernetes engine, so this is Google, Kubernetes, Indian.
You will find this over here in computer, Kubernetes, Indian.
If you click this.
It will ask you first time if you are coming here, it will ask you to enable Cuban, it is here.
You can enable them and this is where you will come to.
So the first thing that we need to do over here is we need to create Cuban.
It is.
So here we have two choices.
One is gaze tinder and other one is to autopilot and create a standard.
One benefit of G.K. Standard is that you will really understand what Cuban industry is doing behind
the scenes.
To get standard in that sense is better.
But if you want more automation, then Autopilot is the choice.
There's a newer choice if once you have, once you understand how Cuban it is works, then this is a
great choice.
And it probably will also allow you to save some money because it will optimize the hardware that you
are going to need.
So over here we are going to go to Big Eastender, so let's click this configure button.
OK, so the first thing that we need to do is we need to choose a cluster name, so let's go ahead with
cluster one, whatever is over here, then we will create a regional cluster, meaning we will have
our system in multiple zones within a region.
So I'm going to select Asia South one.
This is the region where I am located, so I'm going to choose that.
Then pretty much we can live all the choices over here as the default.
Then the next thing that we need to go to is North Pole.
So we'll click on North Pole on the top level of North Pole.
We can give them to the North Pole here we will go with default pool, whatever default name is debt
and the size.
Let's keep it as one.
So I am going to rent out one machine in each zone, so it is going to be a powerful machine that I
wouldn't go.
The other way of doing it is that you can rent out more number of machines, which are less powerful,
so that's also perfectly fine.
But this is what I'm going to do for our convenience and during the demonstration, this will.
It will be easier for us to understand with lesser set of machines.
So I'm going to go with three machines in three different zones.
The rest we can leave it, as is the next item.
Next item that you can click is Nord's.
Whoever it is can run any container image, so there's a whole container, I think that is the going
forward container.
So you whenever you Docker images, they'll work perfectly fine with this container container on time.
And this container optimized operating system, there are other choices as well.
So let's say you can choose Ubuntu at Docker, you can choose this also, or we can leave the default
choice going his way.
Both of them will work, so it's just a matter of choice over there.
Then we have to choose a machine over here, the kind of machine that you will use.
So I'm going to create a custom machine over here in this custom machine I will choose.
Six CPU cores.
And I think, well, gee, we should be more than sufficient over here, so I choose to be quite a machine.
OK, then the next thing is the amount of disk space on each node, so 50GB should be more than enough.
So we will choose that and then we can leave all the other stuff is this.
So these are the only changes that I made.
One more important change we have to enable preemptively nodes.
If you don't do that, we will not be able to run pre-emptively nodes, which are much, much cheaper
than non-trivial nodes for so far for our Big Machine.
Also, we use pre-emptively nodes.
We will use these pre-emptively nodes for our Google when it is listed as well.
So it will give you a warning that it won't live more than 24 hours, which is fine with us because
we are going to save a lot because of this option.
So in that sense, this option is important.
Otherwise, it is not needed.
So once we have made all these choices, this all this stuff, we can live as this.
Another thing that you could have touched over here it is networking and security.
We could have created our own network, but we are going to use the default network.
That's good enough for us.
They are the same default network that we use for our machine as well.
So we are just going to go ahead with that.
So we are going to hit this great button once we hit that.
This will start Kubernetes cluster creation process, which will have three nodes.
So this takes time.
So we will let this run and when we come back, then we will see that the cluster is created.
OK, so our cluster is created, this is Kubernetes cluster, it is located in Asia, southwest region.
It has got three nodes.
It has got 18 Sybil's in total and it has in total 36 GB memory.
And it is distributed across three zones.
So we have to see that we can actually go to compute engine.
Where we normally have buried machine along with that, we also have three more machines, which are
part of G.K. Kubernetes cluster.
And these images are there in three different zones, so Asia's Holtmann Sea, Asia's home to an air
is just over the surface there in three different zones.
Now let's go back to Cuba in a decision.
We have our communities, clusters of our co-editors clusters ready.
We have to put workloads on this cluster, so this workload is empty.
I don't think there'd be a reported.
So is this services are also as expected and that's what I have to cluster.
So now, in order to host application on Google Cloud, we'll have to create services and workloads
here.
Services doesn't mean these services in our application context, but in Kubernetes Indian context.
So we will see what do you mean by that when we look at configuration?
But in order to deploy replication on this Kubernetes cluster, we'll have to create some configuration.
So in the next session, we will look at how we can write that configuration.