The next component that we are going to work on is PostgreSQL database.
So this is the configuration Docker compose configuration we are going to use.
So we will take a Docker file, which will use a Postgres image is slightly different.
This is a there's an image built on Linux container.
So like we have built our application, Postgres provides an image built on top of Linux, so we will
take that image.
On top of that, we will install PostgreSQL will.
In fact, we don't have to install.
This will come as a bundle if we take Docker Postgres image.
So the only thing that we'll have to do is that we'll have to create schema on that.
So let's quickly go ahead and do that.
So for that, we will go to Docker Postgres directly.
Here we have all the files that are needed on the image.
We have two scripts over here for checking readiness.
We will talk about this later.
But the one that we need immediately is create schema daughter Stuart.
So this is the file that we will use to create schema.
OK, so now let's look at the Docker file Docker configuration file for Postgres database.
So here, instead of just starting from Ubuntu, we are starting from Postgres image, which will get
downloaded from Docker registry.
So Postgres maintains these images over there.
And then the other thing that over here again, we can ignore that these are some networking tools for
debugging.
We can ignore them.
Then the important thing that is happening over here is we are copying create schema rescue and to are
directly from their Postgres DB when it starts.
It will apply this script so that schema will get created.
And we have copying some other script over there for checking readiness, which we will use later on
because in production, we may like to ping Postgres database to see if it is alive or not.
And this script will actually help us in doing that.
Yes, we are going to use it during Kubernetes, but it's there in this image right now.
So two important things over here.
We're starting with Postgres image and we are copying Create Schema Dot School in a direct way which
Postgres database will itself pick up and create this schema.
One thing that you may notice is that we are not given any command over here or and they point over
here to launch Postgres database.
The reason we have not done that because that instruction would have gone in the image of Postgres itself
when they would have created their Docker file, they would have given either an entry point or deferred
command that will start the Postgres database.
So we don't need to do that.
We can just do the customization that we need and are only customizations that we have to create schema
with this.
So pretty simple.
All we have to do is we will take that YAML file that we created.
It's one level above three, dear here.
We will also add the configuration for Postgres database, so we don't need to copy services that is
already there, that tag.
So we'll just copy this section.
Let's go and put it over here.
OK.
So we are done copying this, and this is the build information.
This one how to build this particular image.
And then there's the information which will be needed when we launch the container.
We are added to one new thing over here that environment variable.
This Docker Postgres image needs the user name and its password because it's going to start our database
with this default user.
And this is going to be the username and password so we can provide this as environment variables.
So now let's save this file and bring up first, we will build this Docker image B C minus F and Docker
treated very command.
And we want to build both.
So let's build this.
Looks like it is going to complete pretty quickly, so we will wait.
OK, so that's done, it's now doing other stuff.
They should also and pretty quickly, because there isn't much to be done, I think they are installing
those dance tools and calling and all those utilities.
So it's done.
So we did build using Docker compose.
Now let's run this Postgres database using this command up minus D Postgres.
So it seems it has created the container, let's just list the container, so we have two containers
now VEB and post-crash Butera.
So just to confirm what we can do is we can check the logs.
You see logs minus f PostgreSQL.
So if we check the log, then there's nothing wrong over here.
In fact, this scheme also got created so we can see those trace statements on a studio.
So it's done.
Our Postgres database is running, container is up, so we are done with progress.
Now let's move to the next component.