The first part of distributor tracing requires us to do instrumentation of our Web application and services.
So let's first see how we have done that instrumentation.
So this is web application.
What we have done over here is that it is setting start verifying where all the settings are there.
At the bottom of this file, we have provided configuration for the tracer and disk configuration provides
what kind of sampler we want.
We can have different kind of sampler, we can a probabilistic sampler or we can have this kind of sampler,
which is constant, which will always sample any request that is going on.
But in a production system, it may not be feasible to sample every request so that we can do either
random selection or certain percentage of requests, or we can use a sampler which is probabilistic
in nature.
There are adaptive samplers as well.
A lot of smart stuff there.
So that is something that we can choose while we are setting up the configuration.
Then the next theoretical thing that we set over here is that we let this client library know where
the agent is, right?
So generally the agent will be localhost.
In this case, we have particular agent because in our Docker setup, this is this will be the container
host.
So this can be set appropriately, whatever it is.
The point is that this host and Port of the Yaga region needs to be specified.
Then the other thing that we have provided over here is we have given the name of this application as
web.
So this will be reported in the press report.
So that's one big part of this setting.
And then the next part is that the functions that we have are APIs.
So APIs, we have to instrument.
We do not need to instrument each and everything, but those APIs, which we are interested in.
So let me show you this.
So this is a card API.
This does not have any instrumentation.
This starts with like a regular function.
But if I look at this product API, this start with a special statement call with tracer start spun.
Get product as fun.
So this is all we need to do to instrument this particular API.
We just need to begin this API with this particular statement, and this API will get instrumented.
So similarly, whichever function we are interested in, so let's say we are interested in or does function,
we have instrumented dysfunction as well.
Likewise, we have instrumented certain other functions also.
So let's say this create order.
It's a long running API in our system.
We have instrumented.
This has been so two things we have done.
One, we have instrumented these functions using these statements, three statements we have provided
settings file to created to set.
And the third thing that we have to do is when we create the Docker image for our web application,
we'll have to install open tracing and Yeager client dependency.
So that's all we need to do to get this thing going for our application.
Now, let's see, what do we need to do at our services and to instrumental services?
What we do over here is that first we include the dependency for that we have port dependency in Common
Library because it is included in every service.
So in bombed out example of Common Library if you go down.
There we have put this dependency of open tracing that is open tracing Spring Yaga cloud start started.
So this deep dependency that we have for this will include the Spring Cloud Yegor integration into our
project.
And what that means is every service will get instrumented.
So any function that our service exposes that will get automatically exposed or that will automatically
get raised.
So now what do we need to worry about?
We don't need to worry about Airbus, but wherever we are calling other functions.
And if you want to create a trace over there, then those are the places where we have to manually add
instrumentation.
So let me give you an example, and that will make it more clear.
So let's say this gateway is dead here.
This particular library will be in red like it will be included in any other service.
All we need to do over here is go to configured properties file, and we have to just say that tracing
yaga anywhere we like to set it up and we'll have to tell through the configuration that we're younger
age and dislocated its host and forward information.
That's pretty much the same thing we did in web application as well.
So there's something that we have done on gateway services.
Data services only has EBAs.
There is nothing fancy going on over there, so they will all get instrumented.
So similarly, that's a ordered service.
Now let let me before going to our service, let me show you products of its services again, a regular
kind of service.
In the sense that there are no asynchronous API, you were there, it's not calling any other service,
so that way it is not special.
So the only thing that we need to do over here is that we need to set these properties here, this property,
you're going to enable us to follow.
But we'll have to enable this to do to get this tracing going.
So there's the switch for Hugo tracing.
Now, this order service is special.
This is special for a couple of reasons.
And we noticed that this order service makes a call to inventory service.
So this is where we want to add certain explanatory statements.
We want to determine when did we actually call the duty service?
The inventory service API will automatically get an instrumented because we have enabled to over there.
But the point where we are calling in military service, we may like to add some extra statements over
there.
So that is one special point where we may have put out some port.
Then other special thing that can happen is that if we make this create order where we reserve inventory,
we make that part asynchronous and it no longer means synchronous.
Then also, we'll have to do special arrangements to transfer the context.
This context, we discussed that it is transferred to as typical.
But when we make our service asynchronous, where we will be sending messages to a queue and after some
time when service resumes by reading that message from the queue, then we would have lost the context
unless in that message itself, we save that context or something like that will have to do for asynchronous
services.
And that's something that we have done in case of order service.
So let's look at those two changes a little more closely.
That's the only thing that we want to understand.
If we do not have these special cases, we had actually good to go with this minimal configuration and
we will get distributed trays.
But we're doing certain special things over here just to know to what extent we can do this.
Distributed tracing, especially asynchronous flows, are important.
And I know we haven't discussed asynchronous flow in the context of this demonstration, but later on,
when we actually enable asynchronous flow, this will become important.
But because we are discussing distributed pacing right now, so we will discuss it anyway for asynchronous
flow.
So let's first look at our inventory client.
So here is the line that's in process directly.
There is inventory client.
So this inventory client is the client for which we have written quotes and reserve inventory.
There is an as strategic line if I show you that.
So this has declined and it's making a call to inventory service.
Right now, we had an order service.
We are making a call to inventory service and there is decline that we have put over here.
If we do not instrument this client, then what will happen is that the context information which was
otherwise dead will not be propagated to the inventory inventory service.
And the call that we will make to inventory service will not get connected with this particular request.
So here what we have done is we have injected the context into this particular strategic line so that
it can pass on this particular context to the inventory service.
So here we will retrieve the context from the tracer object and we will then inject this into our client
so that there is some implementation we need to do here.
We can take any line and because tracer code does not know what client we are going to use.
So we will have to create an adapter over here, which will do the job of taking those headers in a
serialized form.
And then it will add those items into the new client that we have created.
So you can take a look at the code.
Nothing very hard over here.
We just need to understand that ultimately this is the serialized form of context and this is somehow
we need to pass to the next service.
So this is all we are doing.
We are we have retrieved this from the current context that said from be, we are trying to call CE.
So we are in B right now.
We have retrieved this context and the claim that we have created in B for C, we are actually giving
that claimed this information.
That is the context that you need to pass.
So that's what is happening over here.
Rest all other places.
We do not have this kind of chain unless it is our gateway service or gateway service knows how to pass
these context because that's the job of gateway services.
Said out a service, so that service has already provided that implementation.
But let's it if this is a product service.
There's not going to call any of the service or doesn't need to do anything.
It will be instrumented and that's enough for it.
But in case of ATA service, which one which is going to call inventory service here, we'll have to
do something special for a client and that's what we are doing over here.
So now we understand this particular case where we have an SDP client.
What do we need to do to propagate trace context?
Now let's see the case of a message queue.
So when we are saving a message in a message queue, what do we do?
And when we are retrieving that message from a message in What do we do?
So here what we have done is this order consumer is the one which will consume the message and order
to reduce is the one which will produce the message.
So when we produce the message, what we have done is we are injecting this spam context, meaning the
trace context, which is that in this application, this request right now we are injecting into an
adapter.
And from here, we will extract it and we will put it into our message.
So this is where our messages basically queue order.
And this is where we will set the context.
So all we have to do is from the current trace object, retrieve the context and put that after realizing
that context for that and to message, you object.
And when we are retrieving this message at that time, what we can do is we can.
Extract this context from the message, and once we have extracted it, then we can create a new span
using that particular context so that where the new span that will be created in the consumer code will
get instrumented and it will get linked to the original context for which this order is being processed
or this consumer is doing processing.
So that way we can even instrument asynchronous flows as well.
So that's the core part of it.
Now, the next thing that we need to do is we need to go to our work station and then we will see distributed
tracing in action.
So let's go ahead and do that.