The next component that we are going to containerized is services, the services.
This is the configuration file.
What we are going to do is we're going to take a line Docker image.
On top of that, we will install Java and we will copy Java B, which are basically raw files over here.
So we will copy them and that will be our Docker image for services.
Now we will be one single image for all services.
So let's say we have authorization service, product service, order service and inventory service.
We will not be separate images.
What we will do is these separate water files, which are there for each module.
We will copy all of them on a single image.
So we will use this single image for all these services.
And how do each service instruct that image to run the right component or right service?
That will be to a parameter that we will pass when using command attribute over here and we will provide
the service name to this.
I just quickly show you how this works, but this is the configuration we have.
We have separated the configuration over here, so one configuration we have done just to base the Docker
image.
So this configuration will help in building the Docker image.
It's the same configuration that we have done earlier.
Also just that we have separated it for just doing one common bay for all these services.
And this is the configuration for running a service.
In this case, it has authorization service.
So similarly, we can configure other services as well.
So what we will do is we will copy this configuration.
One thing to note over here is that this services and these services above they are totally different.
It's just a coincidence that these two names are same.
If we would have named us, obviously there's something else, let's say microservices, then we would
have put microservices over here.
The services will remain as so, he says, because there does Docker compose services.
So hopefully we have copied this stuff.
So let me open the compose file.
That's based what we have already copied.
So this court copied and pasted over here, I'm going to save this, so we save the configuration information
for services as well, let me just verify that.
OK, so it has its authorization, so service has been configured so we can now do a bit.
But before I do it, let me just show you how to how we have configured this particular container.
So let's quickly do that.
So we'll go to services.
Here we have Docker file.
Let's take a look at this.
What we are doing over here is first, we are taking the Ubuntu image, then we have installed Java
over again.
And then if you see this, we have copied all the Iraq War files for all these services that we have.
So in one chart, in one image, we are doing this and we are going to reuse this image for every individual.
So this container?
Then these are this is for debugging.
We have copied.
We are going to ignore it for now.
And then we are copying Docker and 3.0 over here at a particular location on this Docker image.
Then we have configured entry point over here.
What this means is when we run this Docker container through this Docker image, then it will use this
particular Docker and $3.00 edge file to launch whatever we are launching in this script.
So now we can even take a look at this script.
Let me first test process.
OK.
So we see this.
We will have to go to image.
Let's read our Docker entry point test.
Let's take a look at that.
So this file has to be copied to the image, that's why it is dead in this image directly.
All it does is it looks for an argument if that argument is missing, it says that so this idea argument
is missing.
So basically, we need to provide an ID for the service that we need to not in this case, we are planning
to launch Autorizacion Service or the IED for that is art.
So we are going to post that for similarly for, let's say we are launching inventory, the Service
84 inventory services inventory.
So we'll have to pass that as an argument.
There are a lot of script statements over here.
We can ignore them for now.
They are mainly there for debugging purpose.
So let's say if you want to debug this container by attaching a debugger to this, then this will help
us in doing this.
That is Jim and DBA configuration for that, that are garbage collection options over here.
So we will take all these options.
And finally, the most important statement over here is we run Java application with these Java options.
And the Java final word file that we are using over here will be based on this service IDE parameter,
which is basically the parameter provided to this particular script.
So that is what we have over here.
So this first parameter, the first argument is basically the service ID that we want to run.
So configuration file should provide that.
So and it is indeed providing it.
So when we write command port, this is that parameter that will be supplied to our Docker entry point.
File.
So let's close this.
The last thing of interest over here is there should be a directory VAR over here, which is not there
right now.
Why am I saying that?
Let me open Docker file.
So if I open Docker, file this particular statement.
If we look at this, is trying to copy all these war files from this image war directly and it will
copy all these war files to us or directly on our image.
So we need all these.
Verifies that part of our service has been so we need to make sure that they are there in this image
directly.
So we need to copy that, but copy them, copying them will be painful.
What we can do is we have a script over here in Dakar, directly itself in Dakar bin directory.
If we go and we execute this script called Pull Our Defects, then it will pull all the artifacts for
that application, for single page application, for pretty much everything.
Wherever we are building a Dover container, we need a bailout defect.
This script will copy that, but this script copies it from staging location and that staging location.
I'll show you where that staging location is that is there in this road directly if we go to stage staging
directly.
This is where everything is supposed to be, but it isn't there right now.
What we can do is we can either run this script, it just pull artifacts in staging bin directory.
We can run that or that is a convenient way of doing this.
If we are in the project who directly at the top level there, we can use this base system dataset because
we have already done debate.
Can I just show you?
So this system data sets base is what we did earlier, which created all the artifacts.
But these artifacts right now are located in individual components so scored directly.
What we are going to do is we are going to collect all these artifacts and copy them and do staging
directly.
So once this build is over, then we can launch that other command.
So we'll wait for this.
So the bill is complete, and this is the command that we have used.
Now what we will do is, again, we will use this command, but with a different parameter.
Earlier, the perimeter was built.
Now we will use stage perimeter.
So this should copy all the artifacts to staging directly, so if we go to staging directly now and
check there are all these directories over here which would have built artifacts.
So let's say if I look at them directly, it has the web application artifact.
If I look at services directly, it has all the board finds that we need.
Now we need to copy these raw files to Docker container.
So what we will do is we will go to.
By the way, there is automation for all this in one chart with one command, we can do everything,
but I'm just breaking it down for you so that you understand what exactly is happening over here.
Even if you do not understand it fully, it's perfectly fine.
You can always go back to the script in the code base and check out what exactly is happening.
So let's go to the doctor directly now, Dr Bean.
And here we will call this artifact stored as dosage.
So now this would have copy the build defects in the services directory of Docker that just verify this
image war.
And all these word files are copy.
So that's good.
Now we are ready to build these services image.
So let's go one level up in the Docker Directorate DC minus f Docker.
This one is treated and the command is buried and we want to be.
So this is this will build a container called services, where that container is not for launching.
This is just for building our services.
So this one is going to install Java and probably some of their software, so it is going to take some
time.
We are going to pause this video and come back.
OK, so services image has got built.
Now let's just verify that we will do Docker images, so if we see over here, over here, we see A.W.
services to, the image has got big.
So now we're ready to run services.
So the command for that would be a game.
Up minus deep, and in this case, it will be Autorizacion service, because that that's what we're
running.
One more thing over here is that how the service has not there is our database located for that.
We have passed this information as an environment variable.
So this environment variable says database podcast host is located at localhost and it will localhost
host will work because right now we are using the network mode as host.
So everything, all the containers that are running right now, they are not in an exclusive network.
They are using the network that is present on this particular cloud machine on which we are working
on right now.
This is not something that we are going to use later.
We are going to create our Docker network, a separate network so that we can address each component
with some machine name, which is more realistic.
And we will discuss about that.
Why do we need to do that?
But all I am mentioning over here is this that this network mode host is temporary over here.
It works probably only on Linux.
It won't work on Mac OS that I know because I've tried that it doesn't work.
So there's not something which is recommended, but it makes it easier to learn to start work, to know
what is going on.
So now, once we are done with on this, then we will revisit this network and see how we can improve
that.
So that will be something quick, only nothing much in that, but it's still something that we need
to do.
OK.
So let's go back to our services.
Let's.
Run this command, and it seems there is some problem.
OK.
I think the command that I have used is wrong.
Well, let me clear this.
This is the command that I used, so it's sort of a minus state needs to remind us, have profile.
It's should work.
So this has created Docker container.
OK, let's list all the containers that are running right now to the Docker.
So this one is up.
If we see the logs, let's just check the log.
Or service?
So the service has come up.
There is one exception over here, but if you see this, this is related to iiNet address.
It is not able to find the address of this machine.
So the hostname of this machine caused by a Java dot net unknown host exception.
This is some problem because of Docker networking.
So this issue is harmless over here, so we are going to ignore it.
It was not worth finding a fix for this.
Why?
When done that, because there's not the network that we are going to use, but our service is running
right now so we can also test it.
But a better thing would be to bring up our single page application also.
And then there's the whole system together.
So that completes the launch of our services.
Now let's move to the next computer.