OK, so we have already created Kubernetes cluster, and the other thing that we have done so far is
that we have uploaded all our Docker images to Google Container Registry, so all that is done.
Now the next thing that we need to do is we need to look at the configuration.
So I've connected to the brain machine where we have been working our workstation.
So let's go to our project crew directly there.
We will go into Kubernetes directly and here we have certain scripts.
Plus, there are certain configuration files which are in config directly.
So let's look at them.
That's what's going to config directly.
Let's see what's there.
So there are further five directories in this EMV directly data directly monitor service use and scalar.
So these are different components.
Some of them are application components in some of them are not.
So let's say environment directly does not have any component related configuration.
It has environment related configuration, which will be applied to all of the components.
So data we have database filter components and monitor.
We have components related to observability where we have log in components like ElasticSearch, yaga
not given up and fluently.
Similarly, we have yaga for tracing and dramedies for monitoring in service.
We have got all these services that we have.
Our functional business services in UAV have their application, single page application and scalar
in scalar.
We have configuration to scale our system.
So one by one, we will look at these this configuration and try to understand how Kubernetes configuration
is done.
We will not look into each and every configuration, but we will look at all the representative configuration.
So first, let's start with environment variable.
So let's go into environment variables.
So here we have a certain configuration files.
One thing I'll do is I'll switch to my local desktop where I have these configuration files and here
different is Vector, so it will be easily visualized over here.
OK, so we'll go to config directly in this zero.
We directly the first file that we have over here is Namespaces Yemen.
So this is generally in Kubernetes.
You will divide your application into different namespaces depending upon which team is working on what
component.
So let's say you have a team which works on services so you will create a namespace for them.
So this is a namespace service that there isn't really any too much configuration over here other than.
What we are seeing over here is that we want to create it namespace and the name of that namespaces
service.
So that's all we are saying over here.
It's a pretty straightforward configuration file.
So similarly, for other components, a letter via a team which manages our databases that installation
their operations so we will create a separate namespace data for them.
The reason I have created these names business for myself because it's a large system and it really
becomes difficult to visualize all of these components together.
So if I can separate them out and see them individually as a group, then that improves the maintenance
part the way I can deal with these systems.
So that's my reason, and that is very much the reason for different teams because they do not want
to look at the components that are being maintained by other teams.
So that's the reason for having namespaces.
So how do we apply these namespaces to Kubernetes cluster?
It is simple.
What we need to do is we take this CubeSat.
Come on now.
The way to get CubeSat command is let's go to our workstations.
So if you go to.
Kubernetes is directly there.
Like I said, there are certain skip scripts.
So here there is one script called GCP install cubes he didn't attach.
So let's install queue obsidian.
This is our Kubernetes command line interface that we will use for our scripts to work, and we can
directly issue commands to cubicle to a cluster.
So this is how I think we will go over here which services should be restarted?
I think we'll go with the default option, whatever it is there.
So I'm just going to hear over here.
So I.
So this short installed capacity, and again, I'll go with the default option.
It's quite with that.
OK, so that then let's see if you can install the OK Uchitelle is now installed.
It is got installed in user bin.
So now this will help us issuing commands to Kubernetes.
What we do is, let's say we want to apply that namespace configuration to Kubernetes.
So what we will do is we will set you up still apply.
Miners have config and we will give it defiance instead.
In the end, we directly and I think that also starts with zero.
Yeah.
So that's the namespace.
Well, so this is what we are going to do.
The connection to the server host was, if you did, you specify the right poster board.
So there is one thing which I missed and that is how do I tell this CubeSat, come on, which cluster
to operate on?
So we will correct this for for that.
What we will do is we will go to Kubernetes cluster.
Well, we're here the first one, the default one is gustatory click that we will reach to the cluster
and over here we have to copy this.
You have to click this connect.
Button and menu item, and we have to copy this command, so there's the command to connect to a Kubernetes
cluster.
So we will copy this.
Let's go and copy paste it over here and execute this.
So now on a workstation machine, it understands which cluster to connect to.
So let's try executing this namespace configuration, let's try to apply them.
So one by one, it has created all the namespaces.
Now this was pretty simple and straightforward to create these names faces, let's do one more thing.
Let's apply a configuration file after that, and then we will talk about what was there in the configuration
file.
And if you see this, I have named these files with in a certain alphanumeric order.
So the namespace file will starting with zero and this file is starting with one.
And that means we want to execute namespace file first.
And after that, we want to execute config maps because there is a dependency.
This config map is will try to create environment variables, and these environment variables will be
for different name spaces.
So there is a dependency over here, so we have to follow the sequence.
And that is why these directories are named like that, not just these files, but even these directories
that just apply this.
OK, so this has applied the config file that you see that there is an automation available with us
to do this whole thing in one shot.
But I'm doing it in a phased manner just to let you know what we can expect from the automation.
What is it that automation going to provide us over here?
So that's the reason I'm not running this group.
Otherwise, we have this escape.
The name is.
Cube Deploy.
So we have a script to actually execute this command, so.
And that comes over here.
So cubes, it'll apply minus.
So there is some automation over here, we will talk about that.
It will become easier to understand this is the ones we know actually behind the scenes.
What exactly do you want to do?
So let's look at this config map file that we just applied.
So here we have a configuration and it says that for namespace service, we have created a config called
service config and we are calling this.
So there's config because we want this config to be used by US services and that's why the namespaces
service.
So here we have put all the environment variables in.
If you remember in Docker configuration, we had data and we file for Docker compose.
So whatever environment variables we had over there, we have put the same environment variables over
here.
So where we are supposed to find admin service, where it is located there.
Also, this is located so close up, whereas is the database what is a key space name for Cassandra
database?
What is the hostname for Postgres database?
So all those environment variables that we have seen so far is nothing new over here.
All that is that in this config mapped or YAML file.
Similarly, for that application, we have this web config, which is dead in namespace UI and the environment
variables that we need are listed under that configuration.
It's a Yamal configuration.
It's a standard way of writing Yemen files.
And the difference from the Docker data and we file is that there we were using notation that led to
service was equal to this environment variable.
And here we are using Coolen format.
The other thing which is critical with YAML files is that the amount of spaces that we are using over
here, those spaces should be according to the convention.
They should have the right amount of indentation.
And the other thing is that they should not have any tabs.
So if you have any tabs in your YAML file, it will not work.
So that's a very common mistake to not make that if you want your Kubernetes configuration to work.
So similarly, we have environment variables for Cassandra and Cassandra config, then for fluently
config, we have configuration, which is slightly different.
What we have done is, as you would have if you remember in Docker, we were supplying a configuration
file for flu and then we were supplying that at the right time.
The reason was that if we are to change anything in the configuration, we should be able to easily
do that.
So instead of providing any file to Kubernetes for fluid configuration, we have provided fluid configuration
file as an environment variable that that's the way we can look at it.
And this is how we have put it over here.
So this is standard Kubernetes configuration that that that we have used this part.
And from here, this is just the view copy pasted are fluently on file.
So this is specific to flu in this or whatever you are seeing over here, the highlighted push and this
is specific to flu.
And so whatever configuration we need to hear, the only change that we have made is that the host information
we have said that this only flu and whatever you are collecting, it has to be dumped to ElasticSearch
Typekit ElasticSearch.
We haven't made any change over there, but we will have to change this hostname depending upon configuration.
So we will see this why we have named this ElasticSearch post as ElasticSearch.
But this is something that we'll have to have, according to our configuration, will have to change.
This will ever take care of this.
So similarly for Prometheus, also, we were using a configuration file.
Here we have used their configuration file as an environment variable and this is being supplied to
Prometheus config as a data file called Prometheus toward why, amid much the same bit we have, we
were de-conflict.
And from here we have this entire Prometheus YAML file that we have copy pasted over here.
So this is the only complexity we have over here in terms of.
Of how we are inputting the configuration files, but it gives us a lot of flexibility.
If you see it a couple of times, it is not that complex.
But the other part where we are supplying environment variables, that is pretty straightforward.
So that is how we create vs supply environment variables to go when it is cluster.
The other thing that we have over here is that we have this secret map.
So if you want to supply any password so we can use this secret configuration here.
We can provide the password here.
I have encoded them as base64.
So from a security perspective, it's a good practice to apply your passwords separately from your environment
variables.
We could have done this in an environment variable itself.
So these two Postgres user inputs guess password we could have created as environment variables, but
we haven't done that.
We are using this secret map.
The reason is that when we see this on UI, it won't show us the password over there.
So once we apply it, anyone who is going through the system, looking at the configuration, they will
not know what actually was the password.
So once we apply it, we can just remove these files and this will be stored in Gujaratis configuration
and nobody will be able to see them through their eyes as to what the passwords were.
OK, so that's the reason we are using secrets.
It is very much similar to the config map of environment variables that we have just created.
The last thing is over here is resources.
So how much resource a particular application should consume is something listed over here.
So this kind of configuration is called as limited range.
Here we specify that any workloads that we will launch as part of namespace service, they should be
subjected to certain limits and those limits can be put on, let's say, sibiu and memory.
So these are the two important hardware resources that we want to control.
We do not want any component to consume an indiscriminate share of memory or CPU, so we apply certain
limits.
You know the thing?
So there is this part.
Default, so this is really the hard limit here you are saying we do not want a particular component
on which this limited range will apply.
It should not consume more than one CPU and it should not consume more than 768 and beat memory.
If it is me or if it is, maybe you can check that.
For me, the this works, and I consider it as 768 megabytes, but it can be slightly higher and they're
not sure what am I really stands for.
It should be close to that, but that's that's where it should be.
OK.
So similarly, there is another thing over here that when we are requesting these resources for a component
in this namespace, we are providing a guidance over here that this container will should we expect
it to occupy or consume, point to fire off the CPU.
And we expect it to consume 256 bit of memory.
So these are what we expect and these are what we what we are saying is limits that it should not consume
more than that.
So if it consumes more than that, then that particular component will be killed by Kubernetes and then
it will be restarted again with this hope that the next time they will not consume so this this can
be used for, let's say, in case there is a memory leak and some component disk continues to hog more
and more memory.
So it really becomes useful over there.
Similarly, if there are some dead threads which are consuming CPU unnecessarily or some process is
hung is, for whatever reason, is unnecessarily consuming CPU.
So these limits can be useful or whether these requests are useful for Kubernetes in scheduling your
container.
So it knows that this container will need this much of CPU and as much of memory.
It can look at the different nodes and what capacity they have, and accordingly, it can schedule the
containers or parts over there.
So we will look at what parts and containers are over here.
We already understand where containers are, but I have told you that boards are an encapsulation over
those containers so they can be seen as a group of containers working together for the same goal.
OK, so the point over here is that we can allocate some resources.
So how do we apply that to another?
These are four different files that we can.
We need to apply this configuration to Kubernetes cluster the way.
The easiest way to do that is that we have some automation over here, which is secure deployed.
We can let this script know which particular configuration file we want to apply, and we have seen
that already.
OK.
This is my local system, so I'm not going to do this over here.
Let's go to our workstation.
So this is where we used our earlier configuration.
If you see this, we did.
This cubes Ctrl applied minus F and we directly applied one particular configuration, right?
Now we want to do this for a group will have to do this for that many files.
So we don't want to do that.
Let's use some automation.
We have a script with us which will help us doing this.
We need to just point this to the directory where all the files are.
So in this case, I've given it this zero e and B directly and only files which are there in this particular
directly.
They will be applied.
I can write this apply command over here.
That's the default.
So even if I do not write, that will be applied.
In case I want to delete this configuration, then I can choose this extra parameter delete over yet.
But if I just want to apply it, I can either provide this parameter applied or I can execute it without
typing any apply because it is the default.
So I'm going to run the script now.
So what this is saying is that it is executing the namespace YAML file and that namespace monitor is
unchanged.
So this is unchanged because we already created these namespaces and there are no differences right
now.
If, let's say we add something to it, then that will get a blackbird because the script or configuration
is exactly the same.
So Kubernetes doesn't have to change, doesn't have to do any change to the existing configuration.
Now, similar thing happened with the config file.
It says that it is unchanged, unchanged, unchanged because we have already created this and there
are new changes in config map.
If I make any changes to convict map and I execute this script, then we will see that the configuration
got a blank.
And something similar to what we are seeing for Secrets Map because we haven't created that yet.
So this card applied got created.
Similarly, limit range got created.
So does the fact we are used to deploy script to execute this cube.
Ctrl Apply Minus have commands on all of the files, which are there in zero EMV directly.
So that's a small automation we have.
There are a few more things about this automation, and we will talk about that as we move along.
Now, let's see the outcome of this conflict map that we're obliged to be go to.
When it is injured menu, then secrets and conflict maps is where we can see this configuration, so
we can see this, that there is a Kassandra conflict and that got applied under namespace data.
So which means two things.
One is the data namespace and all these names.
Besides that we are seeing over here.
They got created.
And the other thing is that this Cassandra config got created.
So let's see what is there inside that.
So we see this it has got this data and under data, it has got these environment variables, and so
what should be the replication factor, what should be schemas heat instance?
We have talked about this when we discussed Cassandra, so we are not going to discuss them again over
here.
The only point I'm making what we hear is that whatever the environment, variables that we're put in
are config mapped or YAML file, they are over here.
We can ignore some of these config maps over here, you know, veo and created those config maps.
The ones that we have created are so did that auto generated for each namespace.
The ones that we have created, so let's say we have created this fluid, the configuration states over
here.
So if you look at here under data, we have this environment variable called fluid darkened and it has
got this entire.
File that we have copy pasted in our configuration, so similarly from its configuration would have
got created.
And if we look at the service config, we did see that was there, the secret entity.
So I think I clicked on secret.
I'm going back.
So for.
There's a secret contract for service namespace if we see this.
It has got Postgres password and Postgres user and like I said, here those are the values of those
environment variables, password and user.
They are not visible to us.
So this is this how you can enforce security.
You can keep your password and user user IDs secure by using secret config, so administrators will
not be able to see this.
Only the person who applied this configuration had that particular file would have access to that configuration.
OK.
Similarly, just this service config.
So for services, all these environment variables that we saw they got applied or would give.
So with that, we have actually created all these environment variables for our WHO when it is cluster.
So now this cluster is aware of all these environment variables that we have created, all these three
nodes which will run, they will have access to those environment variables so that one part is done.
Now, the next part that we have to do is that we have to.
Create workloads, so.
When we create a component, there are actually two parts to that.
One is the load balance of power to that.
So if we.
Take you to this particular figure.
So let's say if you have to call this get for service from this web application.
So in our Docker environment, we used Engine X to reach to any of these gateway service instances of
this.
Can we give us of Islam?
Goal is to get this of history.
Now, if we were to reach to any of these instances through this and Gen X load balancing.
Now over here, when it is white, says this load balancer out of the box, what it provides us is called
service was that service.
We can see it as a reverse proxy.
So strictly speaking, it's a reverse proxy.
You can also operate as a load balancer.
So it will provide us that load balancer and go when it is called set as a service and all the actual
component instances it calls them as workloads.
So let's say if you are talking about product service, then our product service instances, they will
be cordless workloads in Kubernetes and if we put a load balancer somewhere in between.
So let's say this gateway service has to call this product service.
Then there are so many instances of product service, so it needs some sort of reverse proxy in between
that it can call as a single point of contact and that there was proxy can decide which instance it
needs to decide which instance to make a call.
So this is load balancing or strictly speaking, this is the best proxy job over here, which is also
doing load balancing.
So this is something that Kubernetes will provide us.
So and Kubernetes calls this part as a service, and these actual component instances it calls them
will do.
So let's remember that and let's go to our Kubernetes cluster.
We see this over here.
Kubernetes engine menu.
There is workload part over here right now.
It will be empty.
There is nothing over here and then there are services in part, which is also empty.
So now the next thing that we are going to do is we are going to create these services and we are going
to create these component instances.
So all of these component instances we have to create.
So we will look at these configuration one by one, we will look at the representative configuration.
We will not be able to go to each and every one of them, but we can definitely look at the representative
configuration.
So let's look at the configuration.
Let's go to config directly.
OK, so let's go to.
The data directory first, what components do we have over here?
We have Cassandra was we are behind you.
And there it is.
So these are the four different components over here.
But before we go into these stateful components, let's go to some stateless components.
So let's say let's go to this service directly here.
What do we have here?
We have admin service configuration authorization service gateway.
So this inventory service, order, service and products.
And so these configuration are that.
Let's go to any one of them.
Let's go to product service.
What do we have over here?
So there are two parts to this configuration.
First part is service configuration.
This is Kubernetes service that load balancer part.
So here what we are saying is that this belongs to namespace.
So this and this is not Kubernetes service.
This is namespace service, how we are saying that this is Kubernetes service because we are creating
this configuration of kind service.
So that's why it is a service or a load balancer kind of configuration.
It is there in the namespace service and it has the name of this configuration is product service.
And this and this, the under spec is the specification for this service, which does it what it is
supposed to do.
So it does it that you are supposed to provide a Port 80.
And this should accept all the DCP requests and whatever TCB requests are coming to port it, it should
be directed to this target.
Port exhilarated zero.
So it is supposed to roll out all the requests to this target port.
And then there is a small configuration over here, which it's dense.
When you are routing a request, then press for that particular component instance, which is dead on
the same host.
If it is not available on the same host, then try some host, which is there in the same zone.
And if the that particular if the component instance is not available, beckoned instance is not available
in the same zone, then try to look for in the same region.
And if it is not available in the region, also then go to anywhere, wherever it is available.
So this is a slight amount of optimisation that we have done over here because we are running a regional
cluster over here.
Remember, we have the nord's of our cluster in three different zones, all these three nodes that we
have.
These are they're in three different zones, so that's why we put this optimization, but we can run
without this also the above.
Configuration is basic minimum configuration.
OK, so that is so this configuration, who entered the service.
Now let's talk about the workload part.
And yet we are providing the workload definition.
You're saying that this workload is off type deployment or deployment as a special kind of workload.
It creates parts for now.
Let's just see parts as containers.
And then I will tell you that part is not just a container, it is a set of container.
OK, so in the absence of any definition for a board, let's just look at part as a container.
So the deployment kind what it tells that you should start a certain set of boards to fulfill a request
and two days.
This replica configuration, we can tell how many boards we want to create or how many containers we
want to create.
If I say this as this will, when this configuration will be applied, this will create 100 such instances,
100 parts or 100 containers of this of some of its core products over.
So this these boards are they have a name or products of his parts.
Any name would have been given.
So under this theme, this deployment will be created and because it is a deployment, deployment means
a set of boards, generally stateless boards.
It is not used for stateful components, so deployment is a set of stateless parts and services are
stateless.
So we can say that we want 100 replicas of that.
What we have done over here is we have just said just create one replica over here.
I could have said I could have chosen any other number.
It is good enough.
I have chosen a number that I want to start with and we can go to higher number of instances and we
will do so by the virtue of auto scaling.
So we are not coding it over here.
We can hardcoded to whatever number we want, but we are not doing that over here.
We are starting with some minimum number of instances.
And then we will scale it up, according to the law.
So we will see this in some case, we will see we will modify to, let's say, three and we will see
that we will get those number of instances when we apply this configuration.
Then let's see.
What do we have next?
Next, we have is a strategy when we are going to update this.
What sort of update it should be.
So we are saying when we are building this component with a newer version of the Docker images, then
you should follow rolling update strategy, which means that the removal of one old version instance
add new version instance and then repeat that process till you have all removed all the old instances
and you are left with only instances with newer version.
So that's for Kubernetes agreed, and we will see that how that works, and all these things are important
because they ultimately become important during your operation.
So these are Kubernetes features that are being provided to us and are important for any architect,
because if you are architecting a system, you will have to ensure that how you are, how this system
will be operated in the production.
So although these operations will be carried out by the administrator team, but architects need to
know what kind of work Operation Steam is doing in the operations because that is how you will architect
your application.
You will need to know that if Operation Steam is following rolling update strategy, that means that
at any given point in time, you can have two versions running for same components.
Or, let's say, here it is, product service.
It is possible that two different versions would be running at the same time when we are doing this
rolling upgrade.
So let's say if we have 1000 instances and we are doing this rolling update, this update is not going
to be quick.
So for a long time, we will be having two different versions at the same time serving our customer
requests.
So when we detect our application, we need to be aware of that fact.
So that is the reason these things are very important for architects as well, and they need to take
care of that right from the beginning.
OK, so then how does Kubernetes create a particular container?
That is the portion that we are going to see over here and that is under this part spec.
Let's skip init containers for a moment.
Let's go to containers first under containers.
We are providing this information that Kubernetes is supposed to create a container with a name products
service container as part of this part.
So this part will have this container product service container.
And what image it should have that is being given by this particular configuration that up here, we
have certain variables over here that we will need to modify.
So we can't execute this.
We can't apply this product.
So this start Yamal as it is because we haven't put something, we haven't substituted the value of
this image registry port and we have just bought this as a placeholder over here because this image
registry part can change depending upon what environment you are working on.
So we are going to modify this of such variables.
We are going to substitute such variables to our automation before we apply these files.
This kind of thing we did not do in our namespace is in our config map spec because there we did not
need any Docker image.
But here we need Docker image and we want this the ability to change the port and without affecting
our configuration file.
So we have put a placeholder variable over here, which we will substitute later.
So here we cannot directly say cubical apply minus of product.
So this start Yemen without substituting the actual value.
And what do we want to put over here?
We want to put something like this over here, which tells this particular configuration what is the
actual part of our
part of the image from where we can get the vendor school in?
It can actually get the registry.
So this is what we want to port for image registry port.
So this is the the complete part of that image in Google Container Registry, and we also want to substitute
this Revision ID with Lindsey Vonn.
We can all support latest because we haven't given any versions to the core base that we have, so we
can use latest polls over here.
So that belonged to Luke.
So let's just undo this and get back to what we had initially with yet.
So this is how we have this is how the configuration file initially is at runtime when we are executing
this script, that script will read this this particular variable as an environment variable that we
will supply to our deployment script and it will substitute this environment variable over here and
then it will apply this configuration.
OK, so that was about these environment variables that need to be substituted over here.
So let's get back to our container definition, so for this container, we're told what is the name?
Where to get the image from any arguments that we need to supply.
And we are saying that if the image, every time we are recreating this container, it should check
whether there is a new image available in the container registry.
So we have said this image put policy as always.
Then we are saying that these containers should run at port eight zero zero.
Then we are saying that this should mount create volume mounts for defiance.
Now, if you remember, we created volumes in Docker, so it has exactly the same concept over yet.
We need to keep these files in certain volumes, which are outside of these parts, because if these
boards die, we will lose these log files.
So these volumes, they give us a way of specifying that certain locations within our containers in
certain files, they should be actually created on volume ones and not inside the container.
So exactly the same component, same concept that we saw in Docker containers.
So there's nothing new over here, except the fact that we will need to specify over here where that
volume on disk created in this case.
We have said that this volume mount should be created on this particular node itself, so this is a
way of keeping it as a way of specifying this.
Yet I have said that I do not want this to be permanent space.
So here it was not critical for me to store these documents, but for in case of database, we will
see this will have to provide a more robust configuration for these volumes to these volumes are related
to these volumes and we will see this a better way of specifying these volumes in case of stateful components.
So that that's one critical difference you can see from stateful components between stateful components
and stateless components, which we are defining as part of deployment kind of communities.
OK.
So that's the web.
That's pretty much all the basics for creating a container.
Now there are certain advanced things over here.
How does Kubernetes know that the container, which it has started, is actually healthy?
So for that, we have provided this liveness pro configuration or disk configuration will do this after
an initial delay.
So once it starts the container, it will wait for 180 seconds and then it will send an ADP request
to the spot status on the Sport Edge zero eight zero.
So this status is it will send a request to this container on this so and so astutely requested to install
part in port.
And if it gets 200 response or any response, which is less than 400 or 300, which doesn't mean any
error.
So let's say 200 is okay.
Two hundred one is created.
So if it gets its kind of responses, it will understand that the container is live and it is working
fine if it is not giving any responsibility after three tries.
We can configure that I configured that.
I'm using the number of reiterates that it will do as the default, which is three.
So first, try three times.
And if this container is not alive, if it is not giving good responses and it will kill the container
and it will try to recreate it.
So that's a brilliant feature that Kubernetes is providing us over here.
Similarly, we have this readiness group.
It is similar to Liveness, Brooke, but it has got a different function here.
We will send in request to the same and import, but we are starting this right after 60 seconds because
it is possible that just after 60 seconds are within 60 seconds, this would have come up and we do
not want to wait till one or two seconds to determine whether it is alive or not.
So in case this readiness probe fails, this is not going to kill the container.
They're not going to remove the container.
All it means is that services should not direct any request to this container because it is not ready.
Once this container gets a favorable response, it will change the status to ready, and after that,
only a service can send a request to this particular container.
So this is something that we have defined over here.
This is this.
Service, which is supposed to redirect only requests to these containers that we are defining as part
of broad definition.
So this is when a readiness probe is important, whether a service should allow the request to that
or not is decided by this group.
Whether a health service should kill this container is decided by liveness groups who will have to put
both of these groups look at.
Both of them are important for us.
Then the last thing that we have put over here is topological spread constraints.
So if let's have this particular and as part of this broad definition, if we create three boards and
we have three zones, then we want these three parts to be spread on and spread over these three zones.
So what we have done over here because we have created three different hosts for our cluster.
If you see this, this particular cluster has got if I show you this in compute engine.
We've got three different hosts over here, so they are in three different zone, the Zone C, A and
B, so we want these product service instances where they were being created.
They should be evenly spread.
So we have provided these topological constraints over here.
So competitors can't do a job of spreading evenly, spreading these product service boards that we are
creating or looking at.
So what we saw over here is that we created, we thought, Kubernetes how to create a container, so
asked her to create only one container as part of this for definition.
So in this case, this part and one container inside that so here part is as good as one container because
it contains only one container inside this and that sort of Berkshire container part should really have
only one container inside that, but there are cases where we will need more containers inside apart.
And I'll tell you when we need that, let's go.
Let's take the case of you a web application.
And if you remember in that application, I told you there are two parts one of the dynamic request
part and the other one is static request part.
So I told you that static request part.
We want to handle two Engine X, which is a reverse proxy and dynamic request Part B one to handle two
Python Django applications.
So for our web application, we actually need two containers working together in those two containers
working together form side one application.
So here when we are creating a web application bar over here, then we are saying that aspart of containers
we are we are providing you two containers, one for static content and is the definition for that or
that container we are to get image from.
What are the ports?
What are the environment variables?
We can, by the way, provide some environment variables override them over here.
So very much in Docker type like we can override some of the environment variables in compose, file
docker compose file.
Here we can do similar stuff in Kubernetes Yamal configuration files.
So this is one container definition as part of this part, and this is the second container as part
of this, this particular web application port.
So this web application part has got two containers running in it, and that's where it makes sense
to have ports running in, not to ports, to containers running in the same ports.
We create three parts of our web application.
Then these three ports will have six containers three for responding to static requests and three port
T containers with us wanting to dynamic request.
So that's give that should give you an idea of what a board is.
Port otherwise is a container.
But we noticed that a port can be a collection of containers as well.
So now hopefully you understand what a part is, OK?
And one more thing that within a port, any container can refer to the other container as local ports,
so that that's another set of information whenever you need that.
OK.
So without making it more complicated, I have explained to you how we have created product service,
port and product service to I told you how to create product service service, which is basically the
reverse proxy or load balancing for the service and a deployment which is actually a set of cards that
we can get how many ports we want to create.
We can specify here how many ports I want.
So that's the way to create component instances and services in Kubernetes.
So that is the kind of configuration we are provided in.
All, the configuration went over here that absolutely similar.
So also, this configuration files are simple, even monitoring part the same.
But let's first go to data.
Let's just understand how this is different from our services part.
So much of the configuration is exactly the same here, so this part is exactly the same.
Now let's go to the work part.
This is the only change over here, not the only change, but the fundamental change that instead of
defining a deployment over here, we are defining a state full set for deployment was a set of parts
and these parts should be stateless.
But if we want to create a state for parts which will be the case in case of any database, then instead
of deployment, we will create stateful set and this state will set the way it is and fullest that when
we create volumes for it, it will create a separate volume for each of the board.
So and that is important for the database instances relative in this case.
We have three replicas over here.
All of them will store their own data.
So this this data should be separate for all these boards so they can't work on the same data.
This is a distributed database, and each instance will have its own set of data.
So that's where this stateful set becomes important and it will create three separate replicas.
But they will all be stateful, meaning they'll have their own identities.
So we will see that it provides a stable identity to each Kassandra instance that it will create.
So it will name them as Cassandra zero Cassandra one Cassandra two.
Like that, and we can refer to these names.
But in case of stateless instances, it won't give any such conventional naming to the boards.
It can give any name to that, and we will see that we are supposed to routing the request to the service.
And so this can lead to any instance.
But in case of step, for instance.
So this should not lead to any instance.
We want the capability of the ability to be able to reach to a specific instance that is something which
is important for one set.
So those are the kind of differences that are there.
So just remember this that if you are to create a state full application, then you need stateful set.
So replicas help you by creating that many replicas over here.
So we want 100 instances of Cassandra, then we can change this to 100.
So that's the power of Kubernetes that you can create any number of instances with just a simple configuration
in an automated fashion.
So how you create containers, what we get there is absolutely no difference.
We also have liveness, probably here.
We have a really nice global widget.
So there is absolutely no difference over here.
We can provide environment to this, to this envy from.
So I think I forgot to tell you this in services component that if you want access to any environment
variables that we have specified in our conflict map, then this is the way to do that.
And if you want to directly define any environment variables over here, then we can do so.
So all the other things are here happening in pretty much the same way we did in Docker compose the
way we created containers over there.
That's what we have done over here.
In fact, I have created these configuration files by looking at the Docker compose file only.
So that is where I have derived this configuration.
Yes.
You'll have to adjust it in Kubernetes format, but that's something you will have to do.
OK.
So these volume claim templates here we are saying that create a disk space for each node.
Offsite is one GB, which can be used by our Kassandra container.
So we are creating.
We are giving a template for creating volumes over here and the volumes that this template will create
will be used by these volumes.
So anything that can handle containers is writing in Lib Kassandra directory will go to this particular
volume mount, and this volume mount is linked to the volumes that will be created by this volume clip
template.
So that's the automation we have put over here.
So that's pretty much the configuration for all of the containers over here.
That is slight difference over here.
Let it progress.
We have not created any stateful set.
We have created a board over here because we do not need four or five six instances of post-crash.
One instance is good enough, so we have directly created part over here.
Then the rest of the definition is exactly the same.
OK.
You can take a look at a detailed look at these components for redress on top.
We have created the continent in the same way we have just created any part.
We have not created any volumes over here because everything will be in cash.
If we lose this, we should be able to recreate or repopulate this cash, although we have said that
we want to persist.
But in this particular configuration, we have not done that.
Maybe later on, I'll do that.
So but for Cassandra and progress, I have created separate volumes.
So that will give you an idea if you want to do it for readers and every time you.
That's the way to go about it.
Similarly, we have created parts for that influence who indeed we have created a demons and demons
that is slightly different from other things.
I'll come to demons.
First, let me tell you that let's go to something else.
Let's say Yegor.
So Yegor had three components.
So you got agent?
Yeah, agent will be called by our services.
So we have created service load balancer for that.
Then we have created a demand set for Yegor agent.
And I'll tell you what, why we have created a demand demon set for it and why we have not created a
deployment like we have created for services.
So much of the definition is seems so far Yegor connected.
This is where all your agents were dumped, dead logs or whatever they says that they have collected.
And for that, we have created a service and then we have created a bark which will handle the workload
part.
So this will be created is pretty much the same.
And then we have Yegor query, which just takes care of the UI.
So does the service part of that?
And then the this is workload part of Yegor query.
So for that, we have just created a single park and we have to create multiple park multiple replicas
of that.
Then we can use deployment.
Now we have created a demon sec.
So think of this as deployment.
It's just that this demon said what it will do is it will ensure that we have only one replica on each
node.
So all these different nodes that are there three nodes.
So what this will make sure is that it will create each one is going to be created.
Yeager isn't as a demon hack, so one agent will be available on each note fluently also.
That is the case.
We will have that demon's head will make available one fluidly running on each node.
Now all the parts.
So let's say we are running 10 different parts on this particular node.
They need only one agent.
We don't need to create the agent in each part.
So we have 10 boards over here.
We don't need to put agent containers within those boards.
That will be a duplication.
We just need them at the node level or the host level.
So that is bit demon's head becomes useful.
It creates boards and at the node level.
So one part for each and that is what we want from our Yego region and flew in depart.
So that's something that Kubernetes provides us and we have used it over here.
So this is how the entire configuration is being already looked at environment.
I looked at data monitor service until we looked at.
There's nothing special about it.
Then the last one is scalar, no scalar.
We have provider configuration for auto scaling.
So let's look at this.
So this is scalar four, or we should really call.
This has horizontal part or auto scalar.
So because it will horizontally scale a service and this is something that we need for our stateless
components for full component.
We have Cassandra.
We have created a fixed number of instances.
If we have to increase them, we do not want that to be increased as part of auto scaling because we
discussed this during Cassandra setup that we can't adjust the number of containers dynamically so we
can do that dynamically.
But it can be a very dynamic decision that after five minutes, we weren't five in.
Now, if the next 10 minutes we want, then it can be that kind of decision with stateful components.
He can certainly change them once.
Right, and if that is going to be the lower profile for some time because it takes time for database
to rebalance data before that, we do not want to disturb the configuration of our databases.
So we do not use auto scaling for them so that we will do manual skilling.
And I'll show you that how to do that when it is will help us in doing that.
But if you want to set up.
Auto scaling for stateless components that can be done by Cuban by providing this kind horizontal bar.
Auto can here, what we have said is that it should be attached to a of kind deployment.
And the name of that deployment is kit vessel his parts.
It is saying that at any given time, this auto scales should maintain at least one replica, and if
load increases, then it should go up to three replicas.
And how does it know that the Lord has increased?
The hefty CPU utilization increases above 50 percent.
Then there will be calls that the Lord is going up and the audio's killer will act accordingly.
It should increase the number of nodes.
And according to this definition, if the Lord is wearing down, then it can even reduce the number
of instances.
But it won't go below many replicas when it is going up.
It won't go above Max, so we can provide any number of instances over here.
We can say 10 over here and we can even see 3000 if you have that much of hardware and that many requests
that you are planning to cater in accordingly, you can adjust these parameters.
Direct CPU utilization.
You wouldn't generally put 50.
Maybe you will put something like 70, but I put this as 50 so that I can show you this in the demonstration
that when we put load and if you go over 50, then the auto scaling will happen.
OK, so that's auto scaling part.
We have created this auto scanner for all our stateless services that we want to auto skip, and that
also includes heart valve application.
OK, so that is the configuration part now.
Next, what we will do is we will look into how we can deploy these components, so we have created
a cluster.
We have applauded all the images to our Docker file, sorry, Docker registry.
Now these three things are done container registry set is done, Kubernetes cluster setup is done and
we have application configuration in place.
The next thing that we are going to do is we are actually going to deploy our system right.
And then we will see how this system is ensuring higher reliability to us if something goes down.
How does it react to that if law goes down?
How does it react to that with the airport scaling?
And if there is any bug in our system, and if you have to do an upgrade in a production system in a
life system, then how Kubernetes is going to help us with that.
So these are very important things that architects need to worry about when it is fortunately provides
us all this solution to this out of the box and in the next session, we are going to be looking to
do that.