Now it's the time to start other applications, so let's go ahead and do that.
So this will pull the ElasticSearch image from Docker registry.
And then it will be the images that are related to ElasticSearch.
It will be given an image, it will be fluent image.
Right now it has started building, flew in the image and then it will start all the containers one
by one once it has all the images.
It will start the container, so we will wait till it starts all the containers.
In the meantime, I'll post the video and we will return back once oil continues on a.
There is some kind of time out message.
Let me just check if our machine configuration is fine.
OK, machine looks fine, it does you do standard for that school back.
So just try to restart this.
Hopefully this time it will start.
There are too many containers to start, so looks like there was some time out because of that.
Times out of then, I'll start again.
I haven't seen this area before, but let's see how it goes.
OK, looks like it has successfully created all the containers and all these containers would be starting.
So let's just list down all the processes that are there right now.
OK, so everything is up and on its way.
We can just check one of those services.
So let's just check Gateway service.
OK, so it is starting, it's going to take time.
So I'm going to pass this over here, and once this system is up, we will again start.
The video will resume from there.
OK, so get this service has started, it has taken a little less than three minutes.
Let's look at some of the service.
Let's have order service.
So there are some log messages on this gateway service.
Similarly, we expect to see certain log messages on order service as well.
These are all bootstrap messages when these services are coming up.
They are emitting some log messages which are going into the log as well as on Docker Studio.
So whatever is coming on Docker is TD-LTE is being redirected to fluently.
So when we are logging, we need to make sure that not only the log of our log that is logging those
messages to log once, but it is also logging them on stdout because here we are using Docker driver,
which will redirect this message on our studio to fluently.
So now we want to check all these messages that are coming out.
These bootstrap messages of these services, if they are reaching to fluently log collected or not.
So to do that, let's connect to flew in the container.
I think the spelling is wrong.
OK, now it should be OK.
OK, so these are the messages on fluent becomes Well, why do we have messages over here?
Just let's take a quick look at that, and then we will go back to these log messages.
So we had this fluent durcan.
So we said that any message that is coming to who indeed should go to ElasticSearch and should also
go to standard out of this fluently.
So this fluency daemon is logging out all these messages on its container studio.
So that is what we are looking at right now.
So if we look at these log messages carefully, so we see this that there is this message from Gateway
service, then there is this message from inventory service.
This one is from military service.
Then similarly, we have this message from the service.
And then the next one is admin service.
Then order a product service.
So that we have messages from all services coming to this event.
Messages from that would be coming here.
So all these messages are reaching Fluent Element, that integration is pretty good.
Now what we need to check is these messages, which are reaching fluency if they are also reaching ElasticSearch.
So to do that, check, we will access Cabana and that Cabana will connect to ElasticSearch.
And if we can see these log messages over there, then we know this, that these messages are reaching
ElasticSearch.
And if we do see them over there, then we will try to do some full text search of these messages just
to see how we can analyze these log messages on ElasticSearch.
So in order to help with our investigation of these log messages, let's do one thing let's create some
orders through our system, which will touch several other services, and we will try to see whether
all these messages we can see through given in ElasticSearch.
So let's create some order.
So for that, we will connect to our system.
Let's take this IP address.
Let's connect to our load balancer of the application, which is running on zero, which is the default
port.
So right now, if we bring these services?
They just see if they are all up.
OK.
They are all up databases.
OK, suppose this database is dead.
So looks like our system is good in good shape.
Let's go to data if there is any broader data right now.
There is no data, so let's create some data.
Every couple of seconds.
OK, now that the data is created, let's check for further details that stood at seems to relate will
get some data is created.
We can now go ahead and create some orders.
Let's go to products, so let's select this this quarter to.
That said, this two part.
Go to cart.
Then let's create order in as we have this order.
Let's create one more order for that matter.
Let's take some of the order.
So let's take this product number nine.
Let's stick two units of this.
Let's give orders.
OK, so we have two orders in the system, one for Test Voter two and the other one for this product
line.
Let's go ahead and check this in our cabana.
So we want to go to Cabana, we can go to monitoring and this will tell us that you are in fact given
us will collect this log in.
Cabana is trying to connect to our workstation at five six zero one four.
This board will be enabled by default through our firewall, so we'll have to go to our Firewall and
UPC network firewall and we will have to enable this, or we will have to edit the firewall rule, which
is go ending our default network.
So.
Yeah.
So there's the rules, so here we have had this four five six zero one, so I'm going to add that.
And they did let me save this.
This should take a few seconds for this all to be updated once it is updated.
Then we should be able to connect to Cuba now.
Looks like it was there in Brussels and for that matter, this has connected.
OK, so that's good.
Now we can connect to ElasticSearch.
So for that, we will go to discover now because we are coming here for the first time, it will ask
us to create an index better.
So when we go to create Index Britain.
We see this that there are there is one index which is already available over here.
And what is that index?
Index is nothing, but it's a database in ElasticSearch, so databases in ElasticSearch are called as
indexes.
Now this is one index created by fluently on this particular date.
So there's the index name.
Now we'll have to tell Kebano which index we are interested in, so we can probably select multiple
indexes over here, so we will give it a pattern.
So we are interested in indexes created by floor.
So that is what we have specified over here for when these start.
So all indexes created by fluidity.
And that is what we are going to select.
So here the timeframe is at time standards, the only choice of creative expression, so this index
is created.
Now if we go back again to discover, we should be actually be able to connect to that index, which
has our log messages.
So these are log messages.
Let me.
Hide this chart.
Okay, so this chart isn't it did so these log messages right now, what we see?
They are in raw form.
What we see over here is that there are certain features in these messages that were passed by fluently.
So whatever feels it was able to make sense of it has created them as separate fields over here and
the rest are big.
Log method, which is actually coming out of our application, is stored under this log feed.
So there are various views over here and we can even see them on the left panel.
So if we do not want to see it disappear, we want to see this in a structured fashion.
So let's say we do not want to see this containerized keyboard and there are many other fields like
that.
You want to just select the fields that we are interested in.
Then we can go ahead and do that selection over here.
So one thing that we are interested in is container name you.
So here we will be shown the container names, then we are interested in the actual log messages which
are coming under the lobby so that select that.
So this is very much like the log messages that we are getting from our application.
Now let's see if we did create any order.
So for that, we can do full text search and I can see processed order because this is something that
I know comes in log messages when an order is created.
So order.
So this is not this two times on two different times, and these are the log messages.
So once we have created an order of product name, we quantity two.
And once we have created order for this product to with quantity one.
So this is how we can do a full text search of the messages.
One more search, let's say we can do is we can take this.
Broader.
And we can actually search for this.
There are this desperate number to figure it out in our services.
So this will give us the results and we can see this event to get a service product service, even our
web application process this.
So wherever, whichever service, whatever process this test product, you will be able to see those
log messages.
So this kind of full text search we can do, we can do some search on these text fields also.
So not excuse these fields that we have isolated.
So let's say these container name is one such feed.
So if you just want to search in container name so we can say container name.
And then we can give you a container name, so let's say verb is what I'm interested in.
OK, so here there's going to search this only in this container name, so I'm getting now all the log
messages that have come out of this container of it name web, which is our web application.
So like this, we can actually quickly analyze are log messages.
So there are two very powerful things which are happening over here.
One, we are able to do full text search on our log messages that are getting logged.
And the other big thing that is happening is that we don't have to go to individual machines to do search
on these log messages.
All of them, they come to a centralized place and we can see them together at one place and we can
search them.
So this is how we do logging and log analysis in a large scale system.