So now let's go ahead and run the Cassandra cluster, let's run Cassandra cluster first.
It will take some time for Cassandra Atlas to come up, so let's launch this first.
So it's going to pull the Cassandra image from Docker registry, and then it will create a Cassandra
image.
So we will wait for that.
Once this is done, then this will launch only three nodes which are going to form our Cassandra cluster.
So once this image is created, then we will see the log files for.
These Cassandra containers, they will come up.
Let's wait for it.
OK.
It's done.
Cassandra Containers are also launched.
So let's just check
Cassandra one.
This is our signal, and this is where we are also going to create schema.
So let's look at this.
So if you see this here, a background process has been launched our script, which is trying to connect
to Cassandra one instance, but because it is not up yet, so it is not able to connect it and it is
retrying after every five seconds.
So once this Cassandra one instance server is able to do all its bootstrapping and its it comes up,
then this script will execute this script.
It hasn't executed yet, so we're still waiting for it.
This hour is still coming up.
We are seeing these log messages, OK, so we have got this message schema created.
This has come out of our group.
So our Cassandra, for instance, one Cassandra, one is up and it has created this schema.
Now let's see the log files for, let's say, Cassandra EC2 instance.
So Cassandra, two instances not where we have executed any script, but this instance also has come
up and it says joining.
So I think it would have joined the Cassandra team.
It will.
There may be a few exceptions here and there, but we will not worry about them till we do not see any
problems, so they try to communicate with each other.
And during these start up, we may see a few exceptions here and there related to connection.
So that should be fine unless we see that they are not able to talk to each other and we will see that
they will talk to each other.
So let's look at dialogue for Cassandra.
Three.
It seems Cassandra three is not up.
Not sure, I still need to figure it out.
Looks like Cassandra, three instances, not up.
So if I look at what processes are up, I think Cassandra three has exited.
So maybe did not see the seed, not by the time it came up.
Looks like it came up first.
So I'm going to restart this.
Now, let's check the log for Cassandra three.
So I think this is also up and probably has joined the ring, so no, no, that it is waiting for gossip
to settle.
So I think in just a bit it will join the cluster ring.
OK, so now it is joining the cluster.
So this should be just fine.
Now we have all these three instances that are running up now.
If you connect to any of those incidents, then we should be able to see that schema is created in all
of the instances.
Although we have created schema in only Cassandra one instance, so we will check that out.
Before we do that, let's just launch our systems of remaining nodes that are there, that let's just
launch them.
And once containers are created, we will let these system come up.
And in the meantime, we will look at the Cassandra cluster containers.
OK, so this is coming up.
We will let it run.
In the meantime, let's look at if there is schema definition created in all of these nodes.
OK, so let's first connect to Docker exec minus 80.
So this command we will use to connect to Cassandra one batch.
Let me just copy this command to execute at the top.
Not sure if it has visibility, but.
With this one copy pasting it here, don't get it.
We have time to connect to Cassandra one, and we will investigate all of this, so we are connected
to Cassandra one instance.
And now let's use secure asset utility present on Cassandra one instance.
So this is the Cassandra clan, which is their own Cassandra, one container itself, which we will
use to connect to Cassandra process so you can use secure Lesage.
And this has connected to Cassandra solo process on Cassandra, one instance.
So here are schema is Williams.
So we will use user base command to connect to that schema.
So we're connected to that schema.
We can see what our tables are there.
So these are the tables which are present on Cassandra one instance.
So they got created because we launched a script.
If you want to see data and lets a user out because there will be one report over the admin report so
that we can log in initially select star from the user.
What?
So this is very much like sequel user.
I think I did it.
A spelling mistake.
OK.
So there is right now one group over there.
There is a midnight email ID and password, and it has.
So this is one interesting thing over here that here we can specify a column as a set or, for that
matter, any other collection like hash map or list.
So this is something we have taken advantage of that so otherwise in in IBM's schema, we'll have to
normalize this and create them as different tools.
But over here we can create this has a sect.
So this is a useful feature.
We can take advantage of that over here because anyway, here our goal is not to normalize these schema.
OK, so looks like the schema is created.
If we want to see if there is anything in product, we can take that.
Certainly schema is there right now.
There is no data that's come out of this.
Let's see if the same thing got created on Cassandra two.
So we will use secure assets this time, but we will ask it to connect to other instance.
Cassandra, to instance.
OK.
So this one is now connected to Cassandra to node.
So let's use where MSI's came over here, and let's see if there is daytimes at our table.
Yes, there is.
And if we're to see tables over here, then we have same set of tables over here as well.
So let's exit out of this schema has got created over here also.
So let's get to to secure Lesage Cassandra Tree.
We are connected.
Now let's check what our tables are.
They're
all tables are there.
Now, let's check the time table.
So in product, there is no data right now in the user that should be data.
OK, so one data.
So we created schema only in Cassandra one instance.
And that data propagated that not only data, but the schema itself got propagated to all the enought.
So let's come out of this Cassandra one node.
OK, so we're back to our workstation.
Let's check what our processes are there right now.
If they are running this service has it has exited, PostgreSQL has exited.
We have an even order using it.
So we haven't launched that actually.
Now let's see where our system is right now.
We can, in fact, directly try to connect by by this time, maybe it would have come up to copy the
IP address over here.
The replication would have definitely come up.
So let's go to monitoring to see if other services are up.
Looks like all services are up.
Let's check our databases.
So database connection is also working fine.
So that's all good.
If you want to check if the database is up through Prometheus, we can do that.
You can go to.
Targets and see if.
Database metrics, Whatisit user database, Cassandra run Cassandra to this under a tree.
All of them are up apart from all of these other instances that we are tracking.
OK, so that's good.
That's one failure unrelated over here.
So that's related to Prometheus.
So it looks like Prometheus is not able to work for Eureka.
So our discovery so this we are not able to get Prometheus Matrix from.
So that's OK.
And that doesn't stop us from this.
I'll see if I can fix this net error.
But for other services, we are getting actually matrix.
So that's more important than that's happening right now.
OK, so our database is up, our system is up.
If you look at the data right now.
Let's look at product data.
It isn't that.
So what I'll do is I'll create data so this data will be created.
Let's.
Let's see if that's correct, too.
Cassandra, one instance and see if this data is getting inserted or not, so
OK.
So productize inserted in Cassandra one note it's sure to have similarly, Gordon cited in Cassandra
Blue Note as well.
You can check that.
OK, let's take us under.
OK, so it is there in Cassandra du Nord as well.
So that's good.
Replication is working perfectly fine.
Now let's do some transactions over here, so let's try to buy a product.
Let's add this two-part.
Let's go to cart.
This this product number three.
Let's create this order.
So this order?
Got created.
Now let's just check if we see this in Cassandra, two instances, let's connect to Cassandra to use
or miss select star from product.
Not products we want to check or the this time.
OK, so this borderline line is there, and Cassandra two similarly should be there in all other instances.
Also, we will take a look at that.
But before that, let's do a more important experiment right now.
So I'm exiting out of this.
So what I should do is out of these three Cassandra instances that we have.
Let's bring down one of them.
So what we can do is this is stop.
Cassandra, we can stop anyone of them.
Let's stop Cassandra one.
So our Cassandra, one instance has stopped, we look at that.
So, Cassandra, one instance has exited.
Now let's try to see if there is any impact on our.
Shopping cart, no, you can browse products, we can look at our orders, so everything is working
as usual.
In fact, if you want to buy something sort of this time, let's buy this product number four.
Let's add this to cart, and let's buy this.
So this order is also created, so now there should be new orders.
Desperate three and desperate a cold and borderline people, let's connect to let's connect to Cassandra.
Right now, we're inside Cassandra, two more.
Here we will use Cassandra Klein to connect to.
Let's first connect to Cassandra to itself, so we just as equal assets will connect to local hosted
said.
OK, so let's see.
If we have ordered it over here, so but.
What other data are over here, so these two different orders they got created?
Both of them are over here, so they won't be there in Cassandra, one instance right now if I see this.
Then that's come out of this.
And let's start.
Cassandra, one instance.
Now our hope is that by the time this data comes up, the data should be there in this particular database
as well.
So let's look at Cassandra.
Let's see what's going on over there.
The data is there and Cassandra Tree.
Because I have not used use awareness, use schema, so I'm going to directly quantify this.
OK.
So Cassandra three, also has got both orders.
Let's accept all of this.
Now, hopefully Cassandra one database has come up, so let's try to connect to that.
OK, so we are connected to Cassandra one node.
So this is connected to this cluster.
So this is connected to local host, we are on Cassandra one.
So that's good news or miss select star from Florida Line.
So this second order was in there when because under one instance wasn't there when this second order
was created.
But because this data was there, in other two instances, it got propagated even to Cassandra one node
which was absent when this transaction.
So our replication is working perfectly fine.
Even when a node is not available, our cluster is still able to work with the remaining two.
Not so this way.
This cluster remains highly available.
We can, in fact, bring down any of the nodes Cassandra one Cassandra to Cassandra, 381 of them.
And it doesn't matter which in order this, this cluster will remain available.
So that gives us very high availability with Cassandra.
And it gives us a very familiar interface like a school kind of interface to work with no sequel database.
So those were the things that we were looking forward to from our NoSQL database, which is Cassandra,
right?
Not with that.
We have incorporated Cassandra into our system and we are through with it now.