In this session, we are going to deploy our system on Kubernetes.
What we have done so far is that we have set up container registry.
We have uploaded all the images over there.
We have created a when it is clustered and we have seen the configuration files.
So now we will use these configuration files for uploading or deploying our system on.
Using it is.
So let's go ahead and do that, so this is the cluster that we have.
And now I'm connected to our workstation machine on Google, so.
So let's go to our project directory and then Kubernetes.
So here we have some scripts that will help us in deploying our system.
The first step for the deployment is that we will need to create volumes for our databases.
So we said that our databases need to store their data in a volume so that they remain.
The data remain permanent.
So first, we are going to make arrangement for that.
For that, we have the configuration files and volume directory.
So let's just look at my local directly to get a better view of this plans.
So let's go to volume.
It has got this persistent volume stored yammer directly.
Here we are asking Kubernetes to create an object of kind, persistent volume.
This persistent volume should have capacity of five GB, and we want this to be located on the local
level.
So this local that is highlighted over here.
It means that we want to create a volume of type local, which means that the cluster nodes that we
are using on that this storage will be resolved.
So we have these that we show you what I really mean by that.
On the compute engine, the three nodes that we have, the Cuban, it is cluster creation process was
created on these three networks.
This five GB of storage will be resolved.
So when all of these nodes, there are three of them.
So that that's what we are asking for and it will be mounted on some directly.
You can put any amount directly over there.
And this is our way of saying that create this on all the hostname and the value of the hostname we
are providing will a hit.
So it is right now as a variable called node name.
So we will have to really substitute it with the actual node name.
And how do we do that?
So we will see that there is another variable that needs to be substituted and that is node index.
And this is should be one, two and three so that we want to create three volumes disk volume one,
disk volume two, this column three.
So we need this variable to be substituted.
And we also need this variable to be substituted.
So after substituting, we'll have to run this three times so that we don't have to do this.
What we are going to do is we're going to run a script for this.
So let's see, what do I mean by that, that we'll have to run a script?
Let's first make sure that we are connected to the cluster so that all our Kulkarni and commands that
when we execute them, they connect to this cluster and execute.
OK, so let's look at the script that will use this volume configuration, and that script is cube volume
stored as it.
Pure volume sort of sets when we are trying to create volumes, when argument does not delete and it
does actually create, then what it does is and the creators actually default.
It goes into the volume directly where this file persistence volume or Yamal is there.
So it will use, said editor, and it will substitute the node name variable with actual no nib.
And the node index variable with actual value of deep also led to one two three, whatever it is.
So here, if you see, how do we get the Nord names, we are using this common CubeSat, it'll get nodes
minus or name.
So this is the command there that we are executing, so I can even show you that if I execute their
command over here.
It should give us all the names of on to these other names that this command will fetch.
And it will then loop over these nodes.
So we're here, actually, we are doing some substitution that did this.
We are removing this node slash from it because this has only the node name.
We have to remove this.
So there is a little bit of said didn't work over here.
So this is just to remove that signal.
Then once we get the only node names over here, then we are looping over them.
And after substituting these node names in node index in persistent volume start.
Yeah.
We are applying CubeSat and applying minus have come command on the substituted contents of persistent
volume start Yemen.
So that is what is happening over here.
I explain this because this is something that we will do going forward also with Cube Deploy File as
well.
So I'll show you that later.
But let's run this.
Let's create
this run cube volumes.
So this has run.
It has created persistent volume, disk volume zero, disk volume one and disk volume two on these respective
nodes.
So we reserve this space for our databases, and that was important because if we don't do that, we
directly start our application, then our databases won't start.
And if our databases won't start, then our application will not start.
So that then now let's start our cluster or before we start our cluster, let's take a look at the script
that we have for starting our cluster.
So we have this GCP, not GCP, this cube deployed or to let's first look at the parameters that it
need.
One thing that it needs is it needs to know what is the registry host so we can either provide this
as an environment variable outside of the script or if we have not done that, then we can uncovering
this and we can provide it over here.
So if it is EU, then you can put it as EU.
If it is Asia, U.S., whatever it is, you can accordingly enter this.
If you do not do any of that, then the default when you were here that it sets is Asia or GCR or Diageo.
And similarly, the default value for revision ideas latest in case you have not specified it.
The first part of this script really validates all of the arguments.
Then the next part of the script substitute, or it identifies the environment variables, and if they
are missing it, the whites default values for them.
In the last part of this script is where the real action is.
What the script does is it fetches all the configuration files that we have provided.
So let's say when we run this, let me clear this.
So the way we run this script is you deploy it, or as such, we will provide it directly.
So here we are, providing the directly config.
And by providing this, we are seeing all the YAML files which are there under this category.
They have to be executed in alphanumeric order and along with that, we can provide commands, apply
or delete.
If we do not provide any of them, then the default values apply.
And if you do not provide any, but then also they deploy the default value of all parties dart config
only, which has got all the files so we can simply run this and this should create our entire system.
So what this does is it takes all these.
It identifies all the conflict files in the conflict file, but that we have provided it loops on them
one by one.
And then in the end, it applies this command cubicle minus f on the file contents.
But before we give file contents to this, we have to substitute these this image registry.
But this is where Docker registry is located, and we have to substitute the Revision ID over here.
So once that is done, then we are ready to run this command.
Why do we need to do that?
I think I've shown you this before, but just to be sure that just see this, that's when any file and
you will see that it has got these placeholder variables image registry part and revision ID, these
can change.
So we are substituting them at runtime.
We could have hardcoded them over here and that would have made our script simpler.
But then we would have lost the flexibility.
So whichever way you prefer, you can do it right now.
The automation does not assume any hardcoded value again substituted.
So that's what we have right now.
So let's run this script.
So this scripture actually now create all the configurations that are there in the config, directly
in the conflict, directly via these directories under them.
They have these YAML files.
So all of them will be executed.
So let's just go.
OK.
So all of them were executed.
Right now, we do not want this horizontal part or the scalar.
We will need that later.
So in case if you are to delete something, the way to do that is you deploy and we will say over here
dot config and the directory name and the parameters delete.
So once we do that, these auto scaling or horizontal auto scales have been deleted, they won't be
applied to upwards.
Let's go to our.
Parts which will be there under workloads.
So if you see this, all of them are getting created right now.
Prometheus Radius, they are independent.
They got created first.
ElasticSearch board is getting created once it is created.
Only after that, Yeager part will be created and flew into.
Parts will be created because they have a dependency on ElasticSearch.
Similarly, services they will be created only after Cassandra and Postgres database is unavailable
because they have dependency on them.
Let me refresh this.
So are ElasticSearch still not up, that's the reason Yegor Collector Park is not running right now,
it is in initializing work.
You can go inside and see what's happening here.
If you click this, it will show you that it is not in the district and initialized, so it is just
starting it.
So now the question is how does when it is figured out, what is the dependency?
If you see this ElasticSearch board is running now very soon?
You'll see a good collector bought and flew when reports are also available.
Let me refresh this.
So while these are coming up, we will end the Cassandra report is also coming up, let me explain you
how this dependency will.
So now if you see that ElasticSearch board is up, fluid board is also up.
It came up pretty quickly, but only after ElasticSearch board became available.
Yegor Connector board is still coming up.
And you see this admin service boards or service boards, these are all the services or the service
boards.
They are actually waiting for these Kassandra boards to come up.
Now once Cassandra boards are available.
Let me go to Cassandra for.
So, Cassandra, part two parts have already come up.
And Cassandra, part two is coming up if you want to see what's happening there.
You can go to inside the bar and click on logs.
And this will show you actually what is going on over here, so you can look at these log files and
that will tell you what is going on over here, so this is still coming up, so it's going to take some
time to even go back.
And in the meantime, our system is coming up.
Let's understand how this dependencies manage now, it seems, because Cassandra, some of the parts
were available, they were ready.
So services also came up.
So this works beautifully over here, and this works because of a configuration.
And let me show you that configuration.
So we're going to confirm that the services were waiting for databases.
So let's go to any of the service.
That's the order service.
In order service, there are two in containers.
So there the question, I said that I'll explain this.
So now is the time.
There are two container containers in this unit.
Containers are special.
They are special in the sense that the main containers about which we discuss here, we have orders
of this container.
This is our main container.
This will not be started by Kubernetes in these containers are executed.
So the job of these containers is to come up and execute some command and then their job is finished.
Once they do that.
So what commander executing over here, they are running in a loop and they'll continue to run the loop
in the process is not available.
So this has worked great for Postgres in a container is doing similarly.
Wait for Cassandra is also running an infinite loop and this loop will end once it is able to connect
to Cassandra, and it will be able to connect to Cassandra once Cassandra database comes up.
So once these two init containers, they come up and they give a thumbs up that they are done.
They executed successfully, then only automated service container will be started.
So that is how we manage dependency.
So let's say for some reason, if this is dependent on ElasticSearch also, then we can bring in another
in a container to include ElasticSearch as well.
So that is how this dependency is managed and are clustered now should be fully up and running.
So with the help of readiness for a cabinet, this is able to detect that all of these services are
running.
There is also aliveness brought.
If that province, then that service will be declared that service or this workload will be declared
unhealthy.
It will be carried and restarted.
So if your workload, for some reason, they are getting killed and restarted again and again, you
may like to see the reason.
One Some of the times the reason is that the hardware capacity is not enough and they are not able to
come up in the time that we have configured.
We have configured 180 seconds for most of the boards, so they take more time than that to come up.
Then when it is, we'll kill them and it will restart them.
So that's something that we need to watch out for.
But if you have a decent amount of hardware, these services should be able to come in the workload,
the components.
All these component parts should be able to come up in one or two seconds.
So why not workloads are ready?
Now the question is how do we connect to these workloads?
So the answer to that is that we'll have to do that to services, and we kind of discussed this that
if get service has to connect to, let's say, order service, it will have to go through whoever it
is service component that we have created, which is order service or there, not the order service
instance or the service which is implementing it.
But the reverse proxy in between.
So when right now I'm saying so this, I mean, I am talking about reverse proxy.
So similarly, a web app has to exist gateway service.
It has to go through a reverse proxy service component.
So those reverse proxy service components we have created, but they work fine if the request is coming
from within the network in which these components are.
Now, if I have to connect from my desktop, so let's say if I have to open a browser and I have to
connect to Google Cloud for connecting to my system, then that would be that will require an internet
kind of access.
And for that, we need special arrangement in our services.
So let's understand that and then connect to our system.
So how does our system allow services to let internet traffic come in?
Let's see that.
Most of the services that you see that are defined as cluster IP, there can be contacted only by those
planes which are within this system.
So let's say we have to connect to gateway service and the IP address is this.
Let me try to connect using coal utility and board zero and status, but we will not be able to connect
because we are outside of Cuba and it is created by our network in which ports is right.
So we have to get into a port to be able to connect to other parts or services.
So let's go ahead and try to get inside a port.
So let's go to work, Lourdes.
Over here, let let's decide to connect to, let's say, web boards.
So the baby then entered inside their borders, tubes, hidden exec, it is very much like Dr. On.
And this is actually not the name of the address of this bar.
Let me forward that part if we get the actual name by clicking on that.
So does the actual name of the board will make use of that?
We're getting into the park over here, and we'll also have to get the name space over here, which
is you.
This won't work, I think the order of the arguments is.
Think it is a space that is required over here.
OK, so we have entered inside the container baobab container from here.
If I try to access the service, I can even use the name over here and I should be able to do this.
Well, could was obvious is not accessible because it's in namespace service and this web app is in
namespace UI.
So we'll have to add dart service to this now existence.
I am getting a response over here.
So what I'm trying to tell you over here is that here I can access my parts through the service button.
The client has to be there within the same network.
So I'm not in the same network if I'm trying to connect to internet, if I try to connect like this,
if I provide a you are a little.
I'm definitely outside of the school when it is network, so I need some way to get into this network.
So the way to do that is through a configuration, there are two configuration that will allow us to
do that.
Let's look at these configurations, so let's go into the config.
Let's say we want to connect to the web from internet, and we do want to do that.
So this service configuration that we see this here, we do not have clustered IP.
So if I look at I'll show you one of the component cluster IP is up.
So let's hear service and let's take inventory service.
So we see the service component of inventory service here.
This service is off type cluster IP, which means only those IP addresses claims with IP addresses that
are within the same network.
They will be able to access this service.
So that's what this cluster IP means.
And that's what we see over here if we look at different services.
This is what Lester IP means, that they are internally accessible, not the ones which I wanted to
actually access from the internet from my workstation.
I have configured them as port.
The other option that I had was I can configure them as load balancer or load balance that generally
will cost you.
So it is a good practice to start with no port.
And if your plan state is working fine, then after that you can convert it into load balancer.
Because once I convert it into a load balancer, Google will actually allocate a load balancer for my
system, and that will mean that I'll have to pay for that load balancer.
So it's better to start with more port.
Well, OK, so here the Northport is.
Instead of cluster IP, we have specified type as what port.
Later on, we will make it as load balancer.
But right now it doesn't work port.
And then I have specified Northport.
Then I'll also have to specify Northport.
In this case, it is three two one zero zero.
Now let's take a look at how this Northport Northport works.
So as the name indicates.
We can go to any note.
So let's go to the north in compute engine and get the IP address, public IP address, external IP
address of any of these nodes.
So let's pick up this note.
Let's copy this public IP, and let's put it over here.
Here we can use that Northport three two one zero zero that we just saw in our configuration and will
be able to connect to our application.
We can, in fact, choose any of them.
So let's hit this one.
We can pick up.
And we can connect to.
Using this new report.
So what this means is that this Northport is a mechanism where a Port Northport is opened on all of
these nodes, and we can use that port to get into our system to access services off type Northport.
So in this case, with this configuration?
Well, this new report, this Northport is tied up with this Web component in BABIP service.
So when we connect to this particular port, we are actually directed to this web service.
So that's what purpose.
And we have provided this Northport for.
Most of the components which require internet access, so let's go to Kubernetes engine and then we'll
go to services.
So they're their single page application at you, Prometheus.
Cubana for ElasticSearch and Yegor for tracing all of them, they have no port.
Let's hear their components if we are able to access.
Definitely, we are able to access you.
Wait.
It's close one of the debt.
And let's try to sign him.
OK, so we have signed it.
Right now, there are no products.
So we'll have to put some data over here, so what we will do is we will create some data, let's create
hundred users and find products, so let's do that.
Data, while this is getting created, it's going to take a long time to create this a little longer.
So this may actually time out.
You don't need to worry about that.
You can always check the data by looking at these tables.
OK, they're done.
Let's go back to OK, this this time, though, not a problem.
Let's go and check if the data was created.
So we look at user or table.
We go all the way down to the bottom.
Then we have about one hundred users.
Can you get this 100 user, which God created?
Let's go all the way up.
Let's check inventory data this is created in the end, so this also was created.
We have inventory for our products.
We are done.
So we have quite a few products with inventory over here.
Now we can test our system if it is working fine or not.
Let's add this desperate up to two cart.
Now get in the car and let's give the order.
It is in process right now.
It should have gone to messaging you.
If I look at orders right now, there is an order.
And if I want to check the messaging queue, how do I monitor that?
Come over here?
Click message you over here.
This will take you to message queue.
This is.
OK, so I am in now, if you see this in the last minute, this is the transaction that took place.
This was so one request came and it was published and then it was delivered.
So our message queue was working perfectly fine.
Let's look at our Yeager trace.
So let's look at the two order service we have created just now in order.
Let's look at this create out of one card.
Do we have the address?
So we have our address that shows us that dressing infrastructure is working fine.
Now let's check our last component, which is ElasticSearch.
So that also seems to be working fine.
Explode on my own.
And that's what we discover there will have to create an index pattern.
It's clear to you that if you see if Luann de Jager yago the service in Spain over here, that means
boats were in the that are active and they are putting their name to ElasticSearch so we can use that
data for log monitoring.
Let's create index on fluently because that's what we are interested in right now.
OK, so let's create the index patent, we have seen this before.
There's nothing new that I'm doing over here.
So we have all these log messages here, let's select message.
You can select level and also host name, which should be good for us.
So whatever is happening right now, whatever is getting logged in, our system is coming over here.
If I want to check that any messages which has any error.
So there was some error, so we were not able to get product.
I think this happened when initially our system didn't have any data and I tried executing get products
to you.
I going, I click get products.
And there was no data.
That's when this error happened.
And so this way we can use this logging very effectively to find out what is going inside our cluster.
So.
This way, we can look at the messages, if you want to see what orders were processed, we can do full
text search, all sorts of process order like that we can search.
So one order we a process that has shown up over here.
So this becomes important if you're getting any errors and you are.
Fortunately, ElasticSearch logging framework is working fine with your chart.
If your system is stable, then you should be able to solve those problems by coming over here.
So this becomes very important.
Otherwise, it's really difficult to get into each part and figure out what was the log.
You can do that, but it is very tedious thing to do here.
Log centralized, so it makes it easier.
And if there is any performance problem, we have this tracing solution with us.
So with that, we were able to access our entire system.
So one of our goal was this that we should be able to deploy our entire system on Kubernetes and it
should functionally work well.
So we have achieved that goal.
What we will do in the next session is we will look at some of these operational capabilities of when
it is like higher reliability, auto scaling and rolling upgrades.
So let's do that in the next session.