Now that all components are running, let's do a quick check for that.
We will connect to our cloud machine to connect through a browser using the ports on which our application
is running.
So let's say this is a web application on 8000 port because authorization service is running, so we
should be able to sign in now.
So we are able to sign it now.
Similarly, we should be able to access our single page application that's running on board it.
So that's how a single page application on Port 80, so book connections we are able to make.
It seems all our components are running fine.
So with this, we have democratized all components of our system.
They are up and running as Docker containers.
So this is the basic set up of Docker containers.
We still need to optimize it.
Our goal is that we should be able to run our system in such a way that it mimics a production system.
So we will need to fine tune our Docker set up a bit.
And next, that is what we are going to do.