Now that our system is completely ready, let's check some of the operational properties of our system.
So let's start with high availability.
Let's make sure that our system is highly available for that.
We will go to our workloads and these are our workloads right now already open.
So here this is our database that we are using right now, and that is Cassandra.
And what I'm going to do over here is that I'm going to remove one of the notes of this Cassandra database
and see if we are able to still work with our system.
So that would be the high availability test of our Cassandra.
Later on, we will pick up any service and see if they are also highly available or not.
But first, let's check out the database in order to do our test, what we will do is we will first
connect to our system.
Let's use our Web application.
This we will use for testing if the system is working fine or not.
So let's go ahead and delete one of the Cassandra notes.
No, this is actually the service, so I'll go back to work good.
You don't have to delete service.
We have to delete because one of the Cassandra board, so we are going to Cassandra boards.
And over here, do not make the mistake of deleting these stateful set or deployment.
I have done that once.
If you're not careful, then we may end up deleting that word.
We need to hear, delete or we hear this, that delete the one of the parts over here.
So we will randomly choose one of the parts.
So let's choose Cassandra one.
Let's hear Cassandra Parts one.
That's deleted.
Now, let's go back and check the status of workloads.
So Cassandra boards, they warning.
The reason is that one of the boards is down and it will be coming up.
So let's just check in the absence of one of the boards, be able to work.
Let's add this to part.
So our order got created, so there is no effect of.
The Cassandra for not being over there.
And the other thing that is going to happen now is that this cardinal is eventually going to come up.
So if he could work in the absence of one of the database nodes and the other is actually come up if
you want to see what exactly it is doing, we can go to Cassandra Boards one definition either we can
go to logs over here.
The other thing that we can do is we can take this forward name and we can get to the logs using command
line console using CubeSat.
So very much like Docker color, I can do logs.
Miners have the board name and namespace as data.
So this is going to give me what exactly this node is doing right now.
So maybe it has finished his execution and it would have joined the cluster.
So let me just check what is the current status of this part?
Look, it looks like all these parts are up and running.
If you want to delete any other part, it's a Cassandra Part zero two.
We can do that.
No problem.
As long as the other two parts which form quorum, they are dead.
Our database will remain available both for that read transaction and write transactions.
As we saw that we were able to view products and we were able to create order.
So one is read kind of transaction and the other one is right kind of conviction.
OK, so we saw that database unavailability of one node doesn't make our database available.
Our system remains highly available.
Now let's let's check out if our services are highly available or not.
Now, if I look at let me filter on the services.
I can put a filter on the space.
So right now we see this online services, they have got only one instance.
If you want to check their hiring ability, let's create more number of instances and then we will delete
some of them.
Let's do it manually right now.
We will scale.
Get this service to, let's say, three instances.
Later on, we will add auto scaling capability to all these services parts so that depending upon the
load, they will auto skip.
But we have not done autos.
We will manually scale just to get service because if the service is not available, nothing will work.
So we are going to scale this and we are going to remove some of the parts for gateway service after
scaling and then see if the address service is demonstrating high availability or not.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So let me give you this not OK.
In case you want to know the deployment, then you can say, OK, you couldn't get deployment and you'll
have to provide namespace or a namespace here as service.
So these are the deployment needs.
So the deployment name that we are interested in right now is geared to service boards.
So let's copy that.
So we are not going to create three replicates, it is dead in namespace.
So this.
Well, let's execute this command for scaling deployment.
This should scale up our geared resource nodes form one, which is right now showing as one or two of
the three.
Because we have selected three replicas of Wicket.
So this will take a few more seconds to actually come up.
We can check.
Get this over sports.
In case you want to see what these boards are doing right now, you can actually go into one of these
boards and over here, if you click logs, you'll be able to see what this is doing right now.
The other is, like I explained earlier, we can take the party and to command line.
We can check if we get to.
We all come online and let's make use of this.
And this one is in the service, so I'll change that.
So this is that our Web application has come up in 32 seconds, so let's kill this log.
Let's check the status of our workloads.
OK, so we're here if I see Gateway, so this deployment has got three nodes and all of them are ready.
So what we are going to do now is that we are going to going to get with of boards.
There are three parts running right now.
Let's randomly pick out two of them, so we will be left with only one part.
So let's remove this one first.
It's delete this.
That's deleted over here.
OK, then let's go to give us a response once again.
And let's choose one of them, see, one of them is terminating and one of them is coming up.
Let's remove some more ports this one.
Let's remove this.
Right now, we have removed two ports out of three.
Let's see if our application is working fine or not.
So I can access my daughter so I can have them card, go to card, create order and let's see, we were
able to order this book or not.
Yeah.
So this order got created and while this was happening, these kids of sports, what?
Some of them went down.
New ones were started.
So right now, if you see only one of the part is running and it hasn't released it, there are two
boards which are actually coming up right now, so they are not ready when it is will not send requests
to these parts which are coming up in their readiness.
Group says that it is ready then only so this will start to be directing requests to these boards.
So right now, we were working with just one part over here and we can see this.
That system I gave with service sports are auto healing, so we remove some of the parts.
We can think of that as a simulation for some crash and all those boards have come back again.
So even if our application components some of the instances, if they go down, it does not matter.
Our system remains operational.
So that's the higher ED ability property that we were able to achieve through deployment.