Introducing app promote college.
Over one year in the making and always updated over eight years of analyzing the app market.
Let me help you increase downloads even if you have a zero budget releasing the top experts favorite
strategies every month.
Welcome to the most comprehensive app marketing promoting and monetization course online today.
Mark stock a game designer author teacher and app market researcher.
The voting the last eight years to studying researching and analyzing the ever changing app marketing
ecosystem.
Are you spending a fortune on your app marketing but the sales and downloads are still not happening.
You have little to no money for at marketing and still want to learn how to score big an app promote
ology is a course designed for all app developers who seek the knowledge of experts in this field to
improve their iOS and Android app downloads rankings and revenue throughout the course.
We will cover the experts advice favorite's strategies and tips used to help them get millions of downloads
over the last year.
Because it's my goal to get you up to speed as quickly as possible will cover how to increase your downloads
and revenue.
Using a zero budget up to spending money is no issue.
Along with a s o strategies increase downloads overnice strategies easily get your apps seen in China
Russia and worldwide.
Know which type of ads are going to make you more money.
Which tools companies and services the experts use to be so successful.
Updated with fresh content and strategies every month free bonuses included to simply pick and choose
which strategies and tips to use to see faster results no matter what advertising budget you start out
with at the end of this course you'll be an app marketing genius while increasing your app downloads
rankings and revenue like the big companies while avoiding all the many costly pitfalls that tend to
sink 99 percent of every app developer out there today.
The app marketing ecosystem is always in a state of change.
Now you can stay ahead with the latest expert's strategies and score big downloads in the process.
So if you want more app downloads and make more revenue.
Check out some of these benefits.
Learn top experts secrets that work right now.
Get the freshest expert strategies as they become available.
Level the playing field with bigger app developers.
Get an upper hand at increasing your iOS and Android app downloads.
Here is what my students have to say.
Plus I'm including loads of free bonuses.
Thank you for your interest in app promote ology.
I hope you're as excited as I am.
If you're ready to learn more and sign up and enroll right now I'll see you in the course.