Congratulations on making it to Section 16 of the complete Android and develop of course here we're
going to be building our final big app of course which is going to be a clone of the very very popular
messaging system what's.
So is going to allow users to send messages directly to each other and then view the whole stream of
messages right there within the app.
Messaging Apps are some of the most popular apps around and although the market is quite competitive
if you can come up with a special feature or Inish you can start building users extremely quickly.
So as always as you're building the what's at play.
Be thinking about how you might make this into a real app that you could then get on Google Play and
start building the next big thing in messaging.
So enjoy this section and I'll see you at the beginning of the next and final section.