OK it's time to put everything together and connect the driver and the user.
So let's see how are we going to do that.
I'll start off logging in as the driver and show you a quick change that I've made so you can see all
the requests are five further away.
Now that's because I've updated the location.
So let's update the as location to minus point four and 52.
You can see of course those update automatically but we've now got a new field in the User class that
shows the location of the driver and that's required so that the rider can see where the driver is.
So that will be your first thing to fix and then
if we now log in as a rider then we see our usual rider page which of course is automatically updated
when the user moves around.
Now let's call in Aruba for a writer and then we'll cheat slightly by updating the request manually.
Just say logging on logging back in again.
So I'm going to select the user name of one of our drivers.
Is his location and then find the latest request.
It will be that top on there and then update the driver username to that username and then if we jump
over to our app and there we go.
We can now see that the driver is 34 miles away and we can see both driver and rider on the map just
like I did with the driver before.
And then as the driver gets closer and closer we can move the driver along and see it.
Update
say fifty two point five
as the driver moves in automatically updates on the app and then when the driver gets there it says
the driver is here and a few seconds later it resets and allows the user to call another.
But if they want to say that's how we want things to work there's quite a lot to set up then.
So as always feel free to watch mine fashion if you like but do try and have a go yourself.
Best of luck.
Go for it.
All right.
Well I'm going to start by looking in the view requests activity on the driver side and changing our
code so that the driver's location is saved because of course we'll need that to tell the rider how
far the driver is away.
So we've already got our code set up to update when the driver's location updates.
So we need to do is save that to our pass server.
So I'm going to say that right there in the User class for the driver themselves.
So we just need to get the current user.
And we're going to put a location variable and this is going to be a geo point.
So we'll create a new pass Geo point using location to get latitude and location.
Don't get long indeed them will simply save that in the background.
And we wouldn't even have a callback for that as we don't particularly need to do anything when it's
successful.
OK.
So let's just check that and make sure that that works that we can see the driver's location saved in
their use class.
And here we go.
So let's just update the location slightly and then
refresh our past dashboard.
And we should with any luck see a new location Jiya point.
There we go.
For our driver.
Excellent.
So the drivers point will now be updated as he moves around.
Now we just need to report that information back to the rider.
So if we remember right or activity looks like this it's a Google map with our caller Nouba button at
the bottom right.
And then look out at the top.
So if the driver is on their way we need a way to tell the user that that's the case.
So I'm going to bring in a text field.
Which will initially be blank but we'll use that to share information to the user.
So I'll call it in for text few.
So to do that will run a bit of code every few seconds which checks to see the latest status of request
and we have done this before.
But not for quite a while.
So what we need is a handler
called handler which is going to be a new
handler and we want to set that up when
the user requests a new EBA.
So let's create our handler.
And we want to post delayed and we want to post a new runnable which if you remember is a method that
we can run every second five seconds minute whatever we like.
So we put the number of milliseconds after the run method.
And I'm going to go for every two seconds.
I think that's about right.
Obviously longer would mean that we would use less of the user's battery but then they would get slow
updates as well.
And this is going to be called from a number of different places.
So I'm going to
call the method check for updates
and then we'll find out method up here.
So here we want to do a number of things.
And the first is to check to see whether someone has picked up this request or not.
Which we can tell by looking for the presence of a driver username in the request object.
So let's get the request object using pass query
pass objects and we'll create a query ponse query to get query on the request object and we want the
query
where the user name is equal to the current user name.
So past user get current user to get username and we want to find where he exists the driver username
OK and then we'll run our query
with a new find callback
and then we'll check to see if he is null and objects dot size is greater than zero.
Then we know that we've got a driver on their way.
So we're going to take the info text view
and update that with a user's information.
So let's create a text field code in fact text VI
and then we'll set it up in the on create method
find VBIED ID taught in free text for you.
So once we're here we're going to set in free text VI initially to just
your driver
is on the way.
One other change I'm going to make here is to hide the cool uber button
to stop the use of being able to cancel that.
But once the drivers are on the way and I'm going to do that with set visibility to view it invisible
OK.
And then because we want that to happen every two seconds.
We're going to set up Handler again
and I'll do that whether we get an error or not.
Once our query is finished
and then we've got one other place
where we want to check for updates and that's here when we started the activity.
And we've realized that there is a request active already
so we will run check for updates there.
And actually here we don't need the handler so we can just run check for updates directly and we'll
just have the handler there or that even in the check for updates method itself.
All right.
So let's see that an action
will need to log in as a new rider and we'll do a bit of cheeky poking around the past dashboard to
enable a request for a driver.
So while we're it
I'm going to select the user name of the one driver that has a location
that we go and then we'll make a new request and we'll once we check that it's working will assign the
driver to it.
OK.
So here we go.
So we're currently logged in as a driver.
So let's now log out
and lock back in as a writer.
And we'll call Nouba the way we currently are.
So that seems to have been successful.
Let's jump back over to our API and we should now get a new user There we go with just checking which
one that was It'll be the newest one that we go at the top there.
So now I'm going to update Dr. A user name and then jump back over and you can see that that has picked
up already.
So your drivers on the way and the button has disappeared.
Excellent.
So now we need to be a little bit clever and rather than just tell them that the drive is on the way
we want to tell them how far away the driver is.
So to do that we'll need to find a driver using a past query but this one is going to be a pass.
Use a query
and we want to find a user whose user name is equal to a driver.
Use a name that we've just accessed here.
So I'm going to use objects to get Siri to get that first object you could leap through but we can just
do it this way and we want see get a string and the string we want to get is driver
username.
So that will get the user name of the driver that's picked up this particular request and then run our
query
with a new
find Colback
and again we'll check if he is no and objects stock size is greater than zero then we can get the drive
location from the location go point in the user class
say let's create a pass Geo point or call it drive or location which is going to be objects don't get
zero we don't get past Geo point
and this is called location and then we want to know how far away that is from our current user.
And for that we'll need to get how users current location
so we'll use
our location manager
again checking that we've got permission and because we're inside a closure here we'll need to use rider
activity of this to refer to the activity.
So either that's the case or we have an API level less than 26 or 23 sorry.
Either way we're allowed to get the
location
and actually I don't want to request location updates.
I want to get the last known location and we've got some code to do that down here.
So
copy that down.
So we're getting the last known location.
And as long as it's not no we're going to compare it to drive a location to do that will need to convert
it to a geo point it will create a past year point to use a location which is going to be new past Geo
point using last known location.
Don't get latitude and last known location.
Get long edgy.
And then we can compare driver location and user location to get the distance.
We've already done that once before in view requests activity so let's find that Kate
and use it again.
There it is.
Copy that down and then back over to a writer activity
distance in miles this time is going to be from drive a location to use the location and then we wanted
to one decimal place and now we can update our code
to say something rather more useful than driving on the way we can say your driver is
distance one DP to string
miles away.
OK.
So let's take a look and see if that works.
We should now get a distance displayed to the right.
That's updated every two seconds.
And there we go.
We've got the driver is 0 miles away.
I don't think that's an error.
I think it's just because they have the same location.
So let's update that.
There we go.
So you can see that updated straightaway.
And let's just check when we update the drive location
if we change that to something like 54
then can see that that's increased 236 miles away.
Great.
So the final thing then is to show the driver's location to the user
and we'll do this here at the same time that we're updating the drivers distance and we'll use the same
code that we used in the driver location activity
so let's select
all of that and bring it over to our right or activity
and then just update the variable names here to show that we've using that Lyndon's.
So for the driver location we're going to want drive a location don't get latitude
and similarly drive a location don't get long and chief
for the request location.
We can use use a location up here.
So use a location don't get latitude
and it use a location don't get long get and then we'll set this up as before.
But here the position is going to be driver location let alone and the title will be driver location
and he We're going to request location.
Len and that will be your location.
And there we go.
So that should now update every two seconds with the driver and the user location.
One thing we need to now check
is that's when the user's location updates.
We don't want to update the map because we only want to update the map using our new update method rather
than centering the map on the user.
So if we have a boolean which we might call driver active we could test to see if that's false before
doing that update.
And then we can create our driver active Boullion which is false by default but then we'll set it to
tree
when we've verified that a driver is on their way.
That we get.
So let's try that out.
With any luck we'll now see in the distance that the driver is away but we'll see both the driver and
the rider nicely scaled on the writer's map.
And there we go.
Not the best most promising driver.
They are still almost 200 miles away but that is the behavior that we wanted.
Let's make our drive a little bit closer.
That's a minus point four and fifty two.
Let's bring our driver in if we change that.
Fifty two and have another look.
There we go.
That looks a little bit better.
Great.
So we're pretty much that the one small thing I want to add is to test whether the driver arrives
and then update the app accordingly.
So we'll do that when we've got the distance in miles here.
So we'll check to see if distance in miles is less than and I'll say no point no one.
I'll consider that an arrival.
Then we want to do something special.
Otherwise
we'll do what we did before.
If the distance in miles is very small then first we'll update Infotech fee and set the text your driver
is here.
And then we'll set up a new runnable.
In fact I'll cut that code
and put it there.
And also that
will move
the invisibility setting there as well.
So here we're going to give them a few seconds and make it five seconds to see that their drivers here
and then
after that time we're going to set the visibility back to zero.
We're going to set the text of the button to call and Uber.
We're going to set the quest active to be false and we're going to set driver active to be false as
well.
And as a final thing we're going to delete the request so that it's no longer active
and we've got that's carried here.
So let's create
a new quick query
and get rid of that one.
So that will remove all queries with that user name just in case there's more than one which they definitely
shouldn't be but this will tidy things up if there are and then we find in background with a new find
Colback
and if he has no will loop through the objects
like that and we'll delete them
that we can say let's just try that out.
Another option that rather than running that after five seconds might be to pop up an alert for the
user.
And then when they click OK resets everything.
But they should do the trick.
And here we go.
So let's gradually move our driver in point four.
Let's change our location to precisely 52.
So that updates nicely
and then we'll update
our driver location and I'll try to move things around so we can see this happening more or less live
get rid of the extended controls of the emulator.
Here we go.
So if we change this to no point 3 three then it gets further away.
That's not good.
What's also not clear and we'll have to check that in a moment so no point 3 to
we're still getting further away.
Let me remind myself what it was say 52 and minus no point for
say let's say No point 3 9.
There we go.
So we're now very close.
Now let's make it mine is no bueno for
then it changes to your drive it is here.
And after five seconds in sick it's back to cool in Aruba and the user can start the process there if
they want.
So just a couple of small things.
I think we'll get rid of the label your drivers here and then we'll also set the markers to disappear.
So first of lets get the info text view and set the text to empty.
And then also let's find where we update the map.
Here we go.
And we'll use a map.
Clear.
And there we go.
So that takes us to the end of our Uber app and there's always congratulations if you manage to build
at least parts of it yourself.
We do have a really complicated set up here with two different maps activities
I-PASS dashboard with user classes of two different types and also a separate request class as well
and a lot of things going on automatically either every two seconds or when the location is updated.
So there was a lot to this app and Welden forgetting this file.
You may be pleased to hear that we are going to move away from our park service social based apps the
next section and we're going to learn how to make our first proper android game.
And that is a clone of flappy bird.
So as always take a bit of a break.
Give yourself a pat on the back and then jump right in to the next section and I'll see you there.