As you are making the Notes app or following along to the notes that video you probably thought that's
the way we were doing things with shared preferences worked a bit but it was a bit of a fiddle to get
all of our data into there and then to update it regularly was a bit of a hassle and that's because
share preferences isn't really designed for that kind of data storage.
It is really designed for just one of variables that are stored and updated rarely.
So what's the way then of storing data in your app which is relatively complex which needs to be updated
regularly and maybe which needs to be searched queried in a certain way.
Well to do that in Android we use something good.
Su like su l is a server query language and it's a very standard language for interacting with databases.
If you've done any work on the web you may well have worked with Majeski well which is a slightly different
version and if you've never seen as you well before you might want to do a quick google introduction
to Eskew Well something like that is to get a little bit of background.
But of course I'll talk you through everything you need and we'll do it in a new project.
So I will call this database demo and all the usual settings we can be working completely in the console
here anyway.
So all we're going to do in this video is create a database and then create a table in that database
which will store some data and then we'll pull some data out from that table.
So it's all the basic stuff that you might want to do with the database essentially.
And as we go through the process it will become hopefully a lot clearer how these databases work and
what indeed they are.
All right.
So first off we're going to surround everything we do with I try and catch the Jemal exception
because there's lots of things that could potentially go wrong here.
Stage one is to create our database so we do this by creating a variable of a type as well like database
and I'll call it my database and then we open it from our current context to this and then we can do
this in a number of different ways.
I normally go for open or create database.
So this is handy because it will open the database if it already exists and if it doesn't then it will
create it.
So it does both jobs first in one command.
And I'm going to create a database of users.
So this is the name of my database.
Call it uses a couple of other settings we need.
Again we've got a mode just like we had with shared preferences and I usually go for mode private.
That means that it will only be accessible to your app if you want to share your data with other apps
then you might want to have a different mode.
But the vast majority of the time you're probably going to want mode underscore private.
And then we can have a special error catching method there.
But I don't normally bother with that.
I'll just put no
OK.
Now you have a database.
Congratulations.
The next step is to put a table in your database.
So if you imagine your database a bit like being an Excel file with lots of different tabs along the
bottom then the table is like one of those tabs.
So it contains a certain type of information.
So my database and we're going to execute some rescue el.
So now most of our code from now on is going to be Eskew well-coached which is a completely different
language to Java but it's one that's fairly easy to get the hang of.
So what we'll do is we'll create a table and we'll do that.
If it doesn't exist.
So the grammar there isn't great but you get the idea.
So we'll only create the table if it doesn't exist.
So a bit like this open or create database will only create the database if it doesn't exist.
Otherwise we'll open it and he will only create this table if it doesn't exist and the table name is
going to be uses to the table name doesn't have to be the same as the database name.
And generally they won't be the same.
But in this case it's probably going to be a database with just one table.
So it's both about the same sort of thing.
And then we have to specify the types of data that we're going to store in our database.
So I'm going to store the name and the age of my users say the first variable we're going to store is
name.
And this is going to have a type of var chaw which is basically a string.
It's a it's a string of characters char variables all put together.
So basically it's another way of saying string.
And then we can have a page which is going to be in.
And we then have to specify the number of digits it.
I'm assuming that's going to be no one in my database older than 999.
So I think it 3 is quite safe.
And then we're just closing that bracket there.
So we're creating a table if it doesn't exist the table is called uses and it has two variables in its
name and age name is Vachel which is basically a string.
And age is an integer with three digits.
Notice the capitalization then generally in Eskew Well we capitalize everything except for the specific
names of tables databases and variables and that just makes it a little bit more readable.
Believe it or not.
But notice also that Android studio is not passing out as well.
So you have to be a lot more careful than usual if you've got an era now as well then Android studio
is not going to tell us and we won't find out until the app itself is actually run.
And this Kemang just fails.
OK so now hopefully we've got our table.
So let's execute a nother skewl command and this one is going to insert some data into that table.
So basically we're creating a user.
So we're going to insert into uses and the variables that we're going to create for this user name and
age and the values we're going to give to them.
Rob and 34 just
every hour
so I notice that Rob has got the single
quote around it to show that it's a string.
We don't need that with the integer.
So very quick challenge then can you create your own su l statement which inserts your own data into
your database.
Go for it.
All right I'm sure you manage that.
I'm just going to insert one more item so insert into the user's name.
H.
And then values and we'll have Tommy I'm sure he won't mind me telling you his age.
There we go.
There were two people in the database now each with a name and an age.
Now it's time to get that data out of the database
so to do that we use what's called a cursor object and we normally use C to represent the cursor and
the cursor essentially allows us to loop through all of the results of a particular query and do something
with them.
So it will make more sense when we've got a query going.
So my database dots and then we want a row query and again we're going to use them as fuel to run our
query.
And I'm just going to select everything from the database so you select store staff everything from
uses.
And then if we want we can have a signal or a method which will cancel the query while it's in progress.
That's only really necessary if you're likely to have really big queries which we definitely don't hear.
So we can just put no ok then we need to get the column indexes for name and age.
And this is the main part that's different too if you've worked with as well on a web system for example
with my ask you well you don't need to deal with column indexes but we do here.
So what we'll do is creates an name index which is going to be the cursor.
See to get column index and that's going to be the column index for the name column.
And this just allows us to access those columns later on.
Similarly we're going to use each index and let's see don't get column index and H.
All right we're almost there.
Next we take our cursor and we move to the first result.
Which presumably is going to be
then we keep going we keep looping through the results as long as see is not know.
So if for example we didn't have these two lines in there and we run this card then C would be no right
from the start because there's nothing in the Users table but we are expecting this to happen twice
once for Rob and once for Tommy.
So then we just want to get the content of that.
So for now we'll log the name and we use Z for Kassa to get string.
And notice again we need to specify the correct data type
and we're going to get the string from fake name index
OK very quick challenge then can you get the H and printed to the locks.
For it
I'm sure you manage that.
So we're just going to log each and then see.
I get it.
And then page index that is of course an integer.
So we need to convert it to a string using integer to string and then brackets around our code.
And then finally we tell C to move onto the next
result.
And then that will loop round and round until it's all done and then it will stop and that's it.
So in just under 10 minutes or so that we've done pretty well we've created our database we've created
a table within that database inserted to users into it selected all the users from it and then got the
indexes of the various columns in the table and then we have looped through all of the results and printed
them to the logs.
I shouldn't say that too confidently until we've actually done it.
But I think we should be OK.
So we'll run that on the emulator.
But we don't really need to actually say emulator screen or we're interested in is the locks
changed inside
a lot of carry that lets just search for name first of all.
And then we get you've got sporangia which is from a test I did earlier and then rob and Tony
fantastic and then H.
There we got 34 and full
OK.
So you probably know what's coming.
I want you to preferably without looking at this although you probably need to look back once or twice
especially if you haven't worked with as well before.
I want you to create a database called events which will have the name of a historical event of some
sort along with the year that it happened and then insert to historical events and get the details of
them and put them to the logs.
Simple as that.
Go for
OK.
And you guys them so much the same as before.
Just a little bit quicker.
What creates How try and catch with an exception.
He and then will print a stack trace.
If something bad happens then we'll create as you like a database of cool events this time just to change
things up a little bit and we'll create it from the app context or open or create database
and we'll call it events private mode again and we won't have our lot or anything that
then we'll execute some asks yourself old
which will create a table.
If it doesn't exist and that table will be events.
Now once again don't be fooled into thinking the database names and table names are all the same.
You might well have a big database and then lots of little tables within it.
That's when things are very simple.
Often the database name and the table name are very similar
and we're going to have the event which is a natural
and the year which isn't it.
This time we're going to need four digits
for obvious reasons.
All right
now let's execute some minuscule
and we're going to insert into events
event and.
With the values I'm going to have end of World War 2 and 1945 mostly because it's one of the few historical
dates that I actually know
and then another one
to insert into events and then event and your family's
wham split up is what we're going to have this time.
We don't know who I am.
You must go and look them up.
And it happened very sadly in 1986.
And you can decide for yourself whether you think I had to look that data up.
All right so now we've got our data in there.
We now need to get it out.
So we're going to create our cursor see
who's going to be a real query.
And again we're just going to select everything from
the events table
and we're not going to need to cancel that query while it's happening we can just put in all that then
create our column indexes.
So we've got event index which is going to be see don't get column index event and same for your index
see get column index Yeah.
And we'll move to the first result in the result set and we'll keep going as long as C is not know which
will hopefully be twice
and then more log.
This time I'm going to put results
event so that I can do a nice easy search for them.
And then see get string
eventa next.
And
of course results.
Yeah.
See it gets through.
So you don't get it
index.
And we're going to convert that to a string in the usual way.
There we go.
All right.
Fingers crossed.
That should give us exactly
the results that we want.
So in a search for results this time
nothing yet.
Whoops looks like I do have an error.
Did you spot it.
Create table.
If not exists.
And actually while we're there I can see another one.
We need to close those brackets there.
So this is how easy it is to make mistakes with ask you could you get so used to the automatic error
handling.
All right.
As another small mistake.
Don't forget to move C to the next result.
Otherwise your results will go on forever.
And there we go.
You can see I've got definitely more than two results there.
That's because I ran it several times to fix my errors but that's fine.
It is all at least working now.
OK.
So that's how you create a database create a table in it.
If it doesn't exist in sets some data into it and then get the data out.
So there's infinitely more that you can do with databases.
And we're going to go into quite a bit more detail in the next video particularly with queries which
are really powerful ways of extracting data from databases.
So you the.