So in this extra we're going to see how to create local notifications.
So you're probably all familiar with notifications appear at the top of the screen somewhere and the
user can pull them from the top of the screen to Action them in some way.
They're really useful and a great way to get users back to your app and to give them some useful information
at a useful time.
So let's jump right in and see how we do it.
So with the usual settings
anti-rape I'm going to be working entirely in our main activity file here and entirely and on create
as well.
So this is going to be a very simple app that does nothing but create a notification for the user.
And then you can integrate that into your apps and create notifications whenever you like.
So we start off by creating our notification.
Simple as that.
And I'll call it notification and we use a new notification builder
and we do it within the application context.
And then we just set all the options that we want.
Just like we've done for several other builders over the previous videos and I'm going to set.
You can see we can set all sorts of options that I'm just going to set the basic ones.
So we'll start with content title
I'll have something in hand like that and then we'll have the content text
where you get a bit more detail.
You get the idea.
I'll set a small icon so this will be the icon that appears in the notification tool at the top of the
screen and you can use any image that you like for for this
then we're going to set the content intent and you can see this is a new class that we haven't come
across before called pending intent.
So essentially this is the way that we tell our notification what to do if someone taps on it.
So let's take a brief break from our notifications and create our pending Instead we'll call it pending
intent.
And we create it using pending intent don't get activity and then we give it a few variables.
First the application context.
Next we give it an ID number which is just a way for us to verify which intent or which notification
was tapped on.
So I'm just going to go for one and then we need an intent to actually run.
And finally there are some various Options settings that we can have at the very end that I'm not going
to put through so we'll just put it right.
So let's create this intense
so for us this is just going to be a new intent
which is going to happen within the application context and it's just going to jump to main activity.
So what we used to
there we go.
So now we've created our pending intent which really just links to our intent.
And you can imagine here you might want to add some various variables for the intent so that we know
and then we could check when the main activity class is run and that any of those variables were present.
And if so then do something like display that particular e-mail that the user tapped on or something
like that.
But now we can add our pending intent to our content intent.
So that means that when they use the taps on the content of this notification that means they the pending
in time will be run and the pending intent really.
As far as we're concerned just returns this I.D. and runs.
The intent here which opens the main activity class
OK we can have some buttons as well.
And for those we need to give an image.
So I'm just going to use I built him one from Android or drawable and then you could use any one of
these.
So I'll just use the chapt on them and then we give it the name of the we want to appear on the button
and then we give it another pending intent.
So in my case I'm just going to use the same pending intent as before.
But you'd probably want to set up a different pending intent either connected to a different intent
or that has a different ID or something like that so that you could tell that the users pressed the
chat button rather than just tapped on the notification.
You can add a couple of more actions there if you like but the final setting that I'm going to add is
the icon and we do that with set small icon.
And again I'll just pick a more or less random icon
that go for the app.
I come back
and finally then we build it.
So now we've got our notification.
We need to do is display it and we do that using the notification manager.
So we'll create one of those.
And this is going to be cast to a notification manager but we'll get it from the system service as we've
used a couple of times before.
And then we want the notification service
and then we simply display the notification so notification manager to notify.
And again we've got an ID number.
I'll just put a one again.
It doesn't need to be the same as that ID but just some number that allows you to refer to it or identify
it later on.
And then the name the notification that we want to display and that's it.
So let's run that.
We should now find that as soon as it runs we get a notification in the notification bar telling me
that my lunch is ready.
Let's take a look.
You can see it already actually.
So that's a little Android.
And if we come down you can see we get lunches ready getting cold.
And we can tap that button to chat and if we tap it it'll go straight back into our notifications demo.
Just like that we can all say swipe down to remove the notification
like that just in the usual way.
So that's it.
Simple as that.
Obviously you can then program your app to create these notifications whenever you want but this is
your basic code which will allow you to create a local notification and allow the user to do some actions
depending on how they might want to respond to that notification in the next lecture.
We'll see how to do remote notifications using pass which you can integrate into your social apps like
chat apps et cetera.
So you're then.