We're now moving on from images and animations to look at video and audio both of which are managed
in a very similar way in Android.
And believe it or not we can actually add a video to our app in just two lines of code.
So let's find out how we do it.
So we'll click our usual new project
call it video demo
and the usual evil options.
Now obviously to embed a video into your app you need a video to start with.
So in the next lecture there's a link to download just a demo video but you can use any MP for file.
Android usually will be able to play it but if it can't then just use the one linked in the next lecture.
So let's jump over to a video demo.
So we need to put our video in a place where Android can access it and the usual place is in the red
folder.
So what I'm going to do is control click or right click on the red folder and then reveal in Finder
that will probably be Windows Explorer.
If you're on Windows and then within the red folder you've got a bunch of those default folders we need
to create a new one so create a new folder.
In the usual way on Windows you can do it right clicking in Windows Explorer and then roll.
So this is for raw data like video.
So I'm just going to open up the desktop in the new tabs and this is where I've downloaded that video
from.
You can as I say use any video but this one should work.
And then we're going to get into the red folder.
Into the raw subfolder and then just drag that file in.
So there it is and then we can see the world folder up here it should update pretty quickly.
And within that we should now have our video.
There it is.
If for any reason it doesn't update you should be able to synchronize to force it to update.
So now we got our video.
It's just a matter of adding it to our apps let's get rid of our Hello world and then scroll down our
palette to get the video view well named.
So we just drag that in.
I'm going to go for a full screen video view.
There it is.
That's all you need.
Take a note of the ID.
So the DVR is video view with a capital V Second V and then what we need to do is assign them a video
to that video view and we'll do that in the uncreate method.
So our assignment will happen as soon as the app is run.
So the first line of code we just get the video view
so video view and I'll call it video of you and just our usual process of converting to a video view.
And we're going to find it by id resources.
Id DOT video if you
so now that we found our video of you we just assign the video to it and we do that using video view
to set video path makes sense.
Now this is not necessarily obvious because we have to get the correct path.
But as long as you get this right it'll be fine.
So we use Android dot resorts and then we use colon and double slash there.
So a bit like a web address but instead of WDW we've got android Daut resorts.
That's where we're getting our file from.
And then we use GET
package name to get the name of the package because that forms part of the path.
In my case I could just use video demo.
That's all the package name is.
But if you get package name then if for any reason you change the package later on then this will update
automatically.
And also if you've chosen a different name for your package then this will work regardless of what the
actual package name is.
And then we add a second slash or third slash sorry for our path.
And the final bit is the actual file that we want which is resources don't roar at my video
so slightly long path.
Hopefully that will kind of make sense as to where it might come from.
And then all we need is video if you start that's it
he said adding video to an app was complicated.
There are a few things missing I have to say from this so we've got video but we won't have any video
controls so this will just play the video and nothing else.
So when we just check that this is working will have some controls to it.
We should bear in mind as well that running video on the simulator is not great.
I've had quite a few crashes and especially if you don't have a lot of RAM on your PC you could find
that it crashes a lot and possibly doesn't even work.
So you can always run it on a real device if you want to test it out and you're having problems with
the emulator
Here we go video and there it is at the beginning of it.
And fantastic.
So that's playing the video doesn't look right.
But again it would look much better on a real device.
So now what we do is just add the controls
to our video and we do that using a media controller.
So first of all let's create a media control.
There it is.
We call it media control.
And it's going to be a new media controller.
And to define our controller we need what's called the session which is a combination of the context
and the session ID.
Don't worry too much about all of that.
We get it with the key word this.
So this will give us the session which we need to define our media controller.
Now you'll likely get an error but don't worry.
That's just because we have to import the media controller widgets
say widget and then media control the I've got an issue there because we've got two different media
control is imported.
I would definitely go for Android widget dot media controller.
That's definitely the one that works for me.
And then we just have to attach our new media controller to our video view.
And we do that using media control set anchor view and the view that we want to anchor our video control
to is video view.
So the video of you becomes the anchor of view for the media controller.
And then we set it up the other way round as well.
So we take video of you and we set the media controller to a media controller.
So we kind of sync things up both ways.
We set the view for the controller to the video view and we've set the controller for the view to be
heavy to the media controller.
And again that's all it is super simple so let's just run that and we should now find that not only
have we got the video but we've got our video controls as well.
And this will show us how far along in the video will allow us to scrub backwards and forwards as well
as
start stop pause et cetera.
Here we go.
Here's our video player.
You can see when I tap.
Now those are the controls that pop up.
So there's avideo and I tap and we've got the controls.
They do disappear after a few seconds you tap again to bring them back up and we can pause.
We can go backwards and forwards.
Etc.
It's a really simple way to add a video to your app in just a few lines.
Now you can also add online video here.
So if you go to MP for file or something that's hosted on a server somewhere you can access that and
that will actually get streamed to your app.
Now there are lots of problems with that and the emulator however.
So I haven't actually been able to get that working on the emulator but it's just a matter of adding
the the full path that's CTP and then whatever the rest of the link is and then you'd need to run that
on a real device.
Now for video that's as far as we're going to go in the next video we're going to move on to look at
all idio which uses a very similar system but the audio we're going to spend a bit more time looking
at how we can customize the controls with volume and just have more control over the set up.
We'll do that in the next video.
I'll see you there.