In the previous video we saw how to create text views and edit them to our heart's desire.
In this video we're going to move on from that to see how to add buttons.
And more importantly use those buttons to make our apps interactive so that the user can start doing
something you know app rather than just admiring our lovely text views.
So let's drag in a button.
I'm going to go for one that scented and a little bit underneath my great app text view.
So you can see we've got that default Android styled them.
If you've got the buttons selected you'll be able to do all the standard customizing like setting the
hour for changing the background etc. etc. just like we did with text views but I'm actually going to
ignore all of that this time and go straight to this new property called the on click property.
And what this does is it allows us to do something when this button is clicked and all we have to type
in here is the name of the chunk of code also known as a function or method.
We want to run when this button is clicked.
So I'm going to call it click function like that and you'll notice that I've used something called camel
case.
So we've got a lower case everywhere apart from this f function and this is our standard way of defining
functions and indeed variable names as well to use lowercase everywhere except for the first letter
of the second.
And if there was a third fourth fifth word and it just makes it quite readable without putting in spaces
or hyphens or anything nasty like that.
So I press enter to keep that.
So now I know that when this button is clicked the click function will be run.
What I haven't done yet of course is write the actual code for click function and that's what we're
going to do now.
So go back over to the Java folder.
And then the top option neither of the test ones and double click on main activity.
So we saw this first a couple of videos ago just to remind you it's got the package name at the top
and then a couple of default classes here.
Don't worry too much about me using the word class.
Think of it for now.
Just as a chunk of code will be looking at much more detail of what a class is in the next section.
So you've got two classes there for compatibility and to interact with the operating system itself.
And now just before we write our button code let's look at this in a bit more detail and see what's
going on here.
So it sense of the word public which is essentially a Java keyword to say that this class can be accessed
from anywhere within the app it's public.
And then it's a class.
So we use the word class to define a class and then it's called main activity and then it extends up
compact activity.
So that's the same as what we've got here.
And that just means that our main activity class which controls our main activity which is the screen
that the user can currently see.
And what we're saying with this extends is that the main activity will take the code for app compact
activity and extend it add some code to it.
So essentially that's a way of getting our backward compatibility into our main activity class.
And again don't worry too much about this.
This is quite high level Java code and we're only very much dipping our toes into Java at this point
but I want you to have a reasonable idea of what's going on in this boilerplate code.
Then further down we've got this override command.
And that's because what we're doing is customizing a method or function here called on create a method
or function again it's just a chunk of code.
And this one is called On create because it's run whenever the activity is created i.e. when the app
is run but this uncreate method is one that already exists and we're just adding some code to it.
And that's what this override message is saying.
So it's saying that we know that on create already exists.
We're not trying to recreate it.
We're just adding some code to it.
And then we've got protected instead of public which means it's only accessible to code within this
package.
Again don't worry too much about that.
It really doesn't matter at this point.
It's just the default state of the create method.
Then we have this void keyword which essentially means that this method does some stuff but it doesn't
return any information.
So you might at some point create a method that adds two numbers together for example and then that
would return the result of those two numbers added together.
But this method doesn't return anything.
It does just some stuff.
And then what is that stuff that it does well it sets up the activity itself using the saved instance
state.
So if there is I saved state for this app within the user's phone and it will restore that and then
finally it sets the content view using the dot layout dot activity main So are short for resources lay
out is this layout folder here and then activity main is the activity main axonal files are essentially
linking up the main activity with this particular layout.
So that's what's going on.
Again don't expect to fully understand every aspect of that but you very much will by the end of the
course.
All we're going to do is to create our little method to do something when the button is clicked.
So I'm going to start by creating my method as a public method so it's accessible from anywhere and
it's not going to return anything.
So I use the keyword voit and then I need to add the name of my method and I'm going jump back over
to activity main for example to remind myself what that was click function.
So I'm just going to copy that and paste it in.
It's obviously critical that we get the name right.
Otherwise when we press the button the app will try and run a function which isn't there and your app
will crash.
So now this function is called by the button and the button is a type of object called a view.
You may have noticed we had text views down here we've got Image views essentially a view is anything
that appears on the screen so a button is a view a checkbox has a view switches a view etc..
So over in my code to reflect the fact that this has been called by a view I'm going to create a view
variable and I create a view variable using View with a capital V and you can see that this is requiring
me to add a new class to my app which I can do using that shortcut which is old enter and then adds
the import statement for me so I can now run all the view related code so view with a capital V creates
a view and I'm going to call this view view so you can use any name you like there.
But the kind of standard thing is to use the name of the type of thing that it is.
So in this case it's a view a view with a capital V says I'm going to create a view and I'm going to
call it view with a little V.
And that view will refer to the button that called this method hope that makes sense.
Listen to it again if it didn't.
And if you're still confused again don't worry too much.
We're diving quite quickly into some Java code just so that we can get a feel for how it works.
But we will look at it in much more detail later on.
Now you notice I put in some curly brackets then they are the standard way in many many programming
languages to contain some code.
So this means that the click function will start at this curly bracket and it will finish at this curly
bracket.
So what we want our method to actually do.
Well there's not much we can make it do with the level of knowledge that we have so far.
What we're going to do is display some information in the logs so you remember we had these logs down
here.
We haven't really used them yet.
This is where we're going to start using them.
So to put a bit of information in the logs we use log with a capital L dot and then we've got a couple
of different letters that we can use say lock dot D E I V W et cetera and therefore different types
of locks.
So warnings errors etc. We've just got some information.
So I'm going to use a log dot.
And you can see that that top function which is what I'm going to be using is expecting a tag and a
message.
So I'm going to press enter to get the parentheses in there and then the tag is just kind of a type
of message that we're doing here.
So I'm just going to use info and then to give the actual message itself.
I'm going to add a comma and then button pressed like that.
And notice I've put both of those in double quotes because they're strings they're bits of text that
we want to appear in the Lokes and whenever we want to define a bit of text in Java or indeed in pretty
much any programming language we use double quotes to do that.
And then we're almost done but you can see I've got a little red wavy line here.
That's because I'm missing my semi-colon.
So Java requires semi-colons at the end of each line.
But now that that's done we should be able to run our app and press a button and have the button actually
do something.
OK.
There it is.
I'll just bring up the Lokes so that we can see the result hopefully.
And then let's press the button and there we go.
Hurrah.
Might not look like much but that's actually something very significant.
We've just created our first interactive Android app so you press the button and you get a response
in the logs don't worry.
By the way about getting all these other bits of info the logs often give a lot of info that we don't
really need.
If you want to look for a particular item in the logs then you can always use the search function here.
So if I look for button for example then I will only see the ones that I'm interested in and that can
be useful for filtering out all of the rubbish that you're not interested in.
OK.
So congratulations you built your first interactive Android app.
Now of course I want you to do it yourself.
So what we're going to do now is actually close this app down when to create a whole new app which simply
contains a button and then display something in the logs.
When that button is pressed so it's more or less recreating the functionality that we've got here.
But practicing recreating an app from scratch will get all those ideas into your head.
So the unclick function adding in the Baton creating the activity et cetera.
Definitely a good idea to give it a go yourself.
So you're recreating a new app from scratch with a button that then displays anything you like in the
logs when that button is tapped.
Best of luck.
The video and go for it.
K I hope you manage that.
Here I go.
So I'm going to close down the existing project and then I'm going to start a new Android studio project
and I'm just going to get through the process much as we did before.
I'm going to call this click demo or leave the company domain the same and the location the same next
leave all that as the default and we'll have an empty activity just as before.
Next I'm going to leave the activity name the same and then this will get created just as it did before.
And here we go.
So I'm going to bring out my project files.
It's already got mine activity selected.
I'm going to go to Raz for resources and open up activity main darksome else and every day.
So I'm going to drag in my button I'll just pop them and I'm going to change the text this time to click.
Me that we go and I'll get rid of the text here as well because we don't need them.
And one thing you can do is once you've got that set up is just run the app and then it will run nicely
in the background.
And then when you're ready to actually do something with it you can use the quick launch to run it very
quickly again.
So that's quite a neat thing to do.
As soon as you've created your app run it and then it'll be ready to run much quicker when you actually
need it.
So let's go down to the on click option game I'll call it something different now we'll just call it
button clicked on I'll copy that to keyboard.
So I've got it in the memory.
All right.
And then back over to the main activity the logs clicking in there.
I don't need them yet.
And then remember I write my code inside the main activity class but outside the uncreate method and
I'm going to create a public method which doesn't return anything.
It's void and it's going to be called button clicked.
And just as before it's going to be called by a view.
So I'm going to create a new view using View with a capital V.
I mean the old enter to automatically import the view class and then I'm going to call my button or
the element that called the method view with a little of
and I'm going to use curly brackets to define the limits of my method.
And finally I'm going to send a message to blogs using Logo.
And then I use old enter again to import the LOEG class.
So just to have a quick look at page you can see what we've imported there and if you do have problems
with the old Enter method you can just type in import Android.
Don't you tell Dot log.
And again I'll just call this I'll give it a tag of info and the message I'll give is the button was
clique's slightly different to before but the code is essentially the same rights that we gave you.
I hope you manage that.
Let's just check make sure everything is running
as needed.
So there we go.
Instant run has happens.
I will click the button and with any luck there we go.
The button was clicked.
So just down the bottom there click it again and you can see that working great.
Brilliant.
So now we got our first a bit of interactivity but of course infectivity at the moment is only one way.
The user doesn't actually see the results of this.
It's only appears in our logs and also the user can't do anything other than click the button itself.
So we're going to fix this first in the next video by seeing how the user can enter some information
and how we can access that information using a text field.
And then we'll follow one from that to see how we can give the user some feedback.
Display something on the screen.
All right so let's today let's get straight to it.
Text fields in the next video.