OK let's talk about expert app localizations strategies what I mean by Apple localization is your app
listing in the App Store is appearing all over the world.
Not everybody reads or understands English.
So if you want to be able to sell your apps say in China or Brazil which are two extremely big markets
China being the largest consumer of apps in the world you need to translate all your app elements into
whichever languages you decide to target.
You definitely need to translate your method data such as app title description and keywords.
Your app will also need notifications and any instructions or text to be translated as well.
You do this correctly and I've seen people's apps go from the cellar up to the top 10 in their category
inside of a few days.
You can find an inexpensive translators link in my bonus section one found at the end of this course.
So make sure to check it out.
Don't use any free translating software online as it always has errors in it and it winds up making
you look bad in the end and it will hurt your downloads when it doesn't have to.
Just by doing this you can double triple or even quadruple your downloads each and every day.
Important point here is if you're going to do this then do it right and it will pay off big time.
I like a company called El Loco Dotcom for my localization means it's worth the money to hire a human
translator here.
So be sure to check out the recommended link below and I'll see you in the next lecture.