All right let's talk about expert banner advertising tips find blogs and niche Web sites where your
potential audience is likely to be tried to buy banners through ad networks or directly from blog owners.
I recommend checking buy sell ads dot com first and look for relevant banners.
If the prices are too high try to buy banners directly from the site owners send them a screenshot of
their site with the banner you want to place in it.
Try adding a banner in a new location and they haven't been using making it look like an integral part
of the site itself is likely to bring more traffic.
Once you sign up for free simply do a search using the following key words.
For example iOS apps mobile apps Apple Android game apps and you will see lots of sites and the cost
of the ad what type of banner ads are available.
How many people will be seeing your ad at a given time as well as how many impressions each site is
selling.
Be sure to check the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.