Of course one of the major difficulties when working with watch or small screen size based apps is input.
And so if you want your users to be able to input some text into your watch app you're probably going
to want to use voice.
And that's actually pretty easy to set up and I'll show you how to do that.
Now say call this voice my usual settings.
The downside as is often the case of working on the emulator is that we won't actually be able to see
this in action but we can confirm that it will work and I'll show you how it would work on a real device.
OK so we do everything in main activity of Java and I'm not even going to be working with the layout
at all here so I'm just going to put everything in the on create method.
So if you've been paying attention so far you can probably imagine that if we want to go over and get
some data from speech input we're going to do that with an intent say let's create how you feel intent.
This is going to be a new intent and it's a recognize the intent and we want action recognize speech.
A few others that you might be interested in there but recognize speech is what we're working with here.
And then we need to put
an option in there.
And that is recognize the intent it extra language model.
And what we're trying to do here is just get free form text.
So I'm going to use recognizer intense thoughts language model for you form and you can see there's
a few other options that you might want to use the web search in some situations.
The free form is what we're going for here.
Then we start the activity for a result and the activity we want to start is high.
And then as we've seen before we give an integer which will then be returned by the speech recognizer
so that we can confirm which activity has come back to us.
How do we get the results then.
Well we use on activity result and it is that first one.
We've used this before.
You may remember when we're getting images from the user's photo feed for example.
So we do a very similar check so we check for Everquest code.
I can spell it right.
Being the same as the one that we sent in the first place.
And we checked that the result code is ok.
Then we get the results from Data is data available up here.
And that's actually in the form of a list of strings.
So we'll call that results.
And we get that from data using get string array list extra.
And we want to get recognize the intent start extra results
so that will give us an array of strings.
The only one we're actually interested in is the first one
so we call this text
this is going to be results don't get and then zero.
And that's it.
You can then do something with text such as displayed on the screen or use it in a text message or whatever
you like
and that's it super simple as I say we can actually use this on the simulator but we will see at the
very least that it does redirect to a screen to start recording the text to speech.
And then you can see it's got the Speak Now screen and it's waiting for me to speak which sadly it's
not going to pick up.
It doesn't use you or your local microphone to do that.
But if we were on a real device here then once we finish speaking it would jump back to our app and
we'd get the results right there.
So that's all it is.
That's all you need to do to integrate speech recognition into your Android where apps.