Now that we've seen how to make our app interactive using buttons and text fields we're now going to
see how to display information to the user on the actual app screen rather than just in the logs which
only we can see.
It's actually really easy to do.
Using something called a toast.
So a toast is essentially a small bit of text that pops up from the bottom of the screen much like a
piece of toast does from the toaster and then it will display that text and then disappear again.
And we can make one display very easily using the command toast.
And then you can see when I've typed in toast we've got the option to create a new toast.
We're going to press enter to select that option and then it gives us the code that we need to do that.
So to create a new toast we use Toast.
Don't make a text and then we need to provide it with what's called a context which is essentially where
the text should appear and we want it to appear on the screen i.e. over the main activity.
So we use main activity and then we use they don't this command to get the context for the main activity.
So it's a slightly odd thing to do and we'll both see some alternatives to that later on in the course.
But for now essentially we want it to appear on the main activity and to do that we use main activity
toward this and then the next instruction that we give it is the text that we want to appear when we
do the test so high then we can use anything you like.
And then we just decide at the length that the toast will appear for and you can see we can use Toast
length short or we can also use Toast length long.
Those are the only options we can either make it a very quick appearance or a slightly longer appearance
and then we use dot to show to actually make the text appear.
So let's just very quickly run that and see it in action.
And we should now see that high that text appearing up from the bottom of the screen.
And here we go.
So now I'm going to press this button.
And you can see Hi there appears and stays there for a reasonably long time but not loads of time so
this is obviously not for lengthy bits of text but just for quick bits of information.
So here's a mini challenge for you which is not the main challenge for this video but it will give you
a chance to manipulate the code that we've got there just a little.
Can you make it so that instead of saying hi there when we press the button that whatever text the user
has entered in the text field appears bare.
Instead go for it.
Did you manage it.
All you needed today was move the test code to after where we get the information about the added text
and then we've already got some code which gets the contents of the text field.
So all we needed to do was copy that and replace the hi there with that text.
So let's run it again and have a look now it should run fairly quickly.
Not exactly instantaneous but it's not too bad.
So now if I put hello or something there and then press the button then you can see that text appears.
It's worth noting that you can combine that string.
So whatever the user has typed in with some other text if you want to.
So if we wanted to put an exclamation mark on the end of whatever the user said for some crazy reason
then we would do it just like that.
So we get whatever they say and then we.
Plus an exclamation mark in quites again.
Just after it.
So this will now toast whatever they say but with exclamation marks after.
So let's see it in action.
If I type high then you can see we now get high with an exclamation mark.
All right so that's more or less all there is to toasts of course there's now a challenge for you to
put all of this together.
And the app that I want you to make is this.
So again very simple.
We've just got a little text for you then saying What is your name.
And then we've got a text field with name as the hint.
And then if I put my name in and click the button that says Click me it says Hi there Rob.
Simple as that but I will give you an opportunity to put everything that we've learned so far all together
and create your first truly interactive Android app.
Best of luck.
Go for it.
All right.
So here we go.
I'm going to of course start with a new project.
So I call this toast demo.
Oh the usual settings that we now are used to notice.
Hopefully that once you've got into the habit of creating a new project and doing the basic set up it
becomes second nature.
This is why I've asked you to do new projects each time because that process of creating a new product
is something you'll be doing so often.
It's great to get in the back of your mind as something that you can do pretty much without thinking.
All right.
So I'm going to start as usual over an activity main
and we're going to keep this of course pretty simple.
So we'll have some text.
What is your name.
And then underneath that we'll bring in.
Why not use the person name
textfield and that has name presented for us super It's got a nice way actually but I'm going to increase
it to all parents so that it's the full width that looks a bit nicer and then
we'll bring in our button
which I'll just say
click me.
And then on the button will set the on click.
I'll call it say hi.
And we're also going to need an I.D. for the name
I'll call it the name it text
and yep will update everything with that new ID
wonderful.
OK so that set up the user interface.
Now we just need to add our code in.
So again this should be more or less second nature by now.
We're going to create a public method that doesn't return anything called void.
I think I call that say hi but I'm going to just go back and check because my pool crash if I get it
wrong.
Yep.
And then we're going to create a new variable to represent our button and import the view class and
then we're going to create an edit text
and to import the class again and I'll call this name added text say the same as the ID and we're going
to find view by ID using resources dot ID dot name added text semi-colon at the end.
And then we want to convert that from a view to an added text
and then we need to do is to create outburst.
So I'm going to enter to create a new TOSed use main activity of this as the context for the text and
then we want
to say hi there.
Karma and then we want to get the user's name to that name and it text get text
dot to strain and I'll leave it at short this time and that should do it.
So let's check it out.
We should now find that when we click on the button then the app will say hi there followed by whatever
name we've entered in the box.
Let's say so here we go.
I'm going to enter my name in the box that everything looks nice.
We do need to make a small change that looks like name has actually been set as the default content
rather than the hint.
So we have to select it and get rid of it which isn't good.
So I'll just pop up in there and then click in the box and there we go.
Hi That web so that is more or less exactly what we wanted.
Let's just
get rid of we don't actually want the text name to be there.
But we do want a hint name and then if we run out again now that will work because we want it so rather
than having name as the text will have a name as the hint
and there we go.
That's much better.
Let's put Dave in the and we get high that wonderful.
So we now finally have that full interactivity.
The user can enter some data click to make some code happen and then we can give a response to the user
using a toast.
We're now nearly at the end of this first section but before we can make our currency converter app
we need to learn how to import images into our apps.
And that's what we'll be doing in the next video.