Something else that's pretty critical for watch to be able to do is send and receive information from
the user's phone.
Now what chaps generally are an extension of a phone app in some way so being able to send that data
back and forth is pretty critical.
Fortunately you don't have to worry about the bluetooth connection or anything like that.
That's all managed for you by Android.
You just need to write the code to send and receive the data changes.
So let's create a new project to see how that works.
Call it communicating with phone.
Now this time we're going to create some code on both the phone and tablet and an Android Wear device.
So we have a blank activity which is main activity and a blank where activity which is main activity
as well.
So once again we won't be able to get this actually working on the simulator unfortunately but I'll
give you all the code and this will work straight off.
Once you try it on real devices.
All right.
So here we go.
You can see now we've got two sections of app the mobile section and the web section.
Fairly obvious what they're for.
We're going to be working in the main activity files of both.
But this is a pretty reversible process.
Anything that we run on the phone and could be on the watch and vice versa.
So we'll start off on the watch or the Android Wear device imagining that we've got a user name that
we want to pass to the user.
So let's just get rid of this carry that we don't need.
So let's say we've got a strong user name which is currently Rob.
So say the user somehow is logged in on their watch and they are Rob and we want to communicate that
fact to our phone app.
What we would do is create a data map request which is just a way of passing data from the Android Wear
device to the phone or tablet.
And because we want to put some data we use I put data map request that puts data in that request and
this is going to be a put statement request dot create and then we need a path where the data is going
to be stored.
I'm just going to put something doing something generic like Slash data.
But if you were storing lots of data you might want to have a use a data folder and then an images folder
or something like that to separate up your data.
Then we take output data map request and get the data map from it and then on that data map we're going
to put a strain on that string of course he's going to be using name
and the key that we'll use for it is use name.
So be saving Raub under the string username and you saw that there were all sorts of options to put
the different variable types as well.
Then we create a put data request
call data request
which will create with put data map request dot as put data request.
So we've taken output data map request and we've converted it into a more generic put data request which
is the format that we need to actually send it in.
And then we create what's known as a pending result.
And this is going to have a type of data API Daut data item results and that first
which is a special class for transferring data between Android devices we'll call it pending result
and it's going to be equal to wearable Dorte data API to put data item and we need to specify the client
first which I haven't created yet so let's just create that it's just going to be a Google API client
to call Google API client.
So I will use Google API client and then they put data request
OK.
So I that more or less makes sense when setting up pending result equal to the outcome of this warbled
data API put data item request so where essentially in this bit attempting to do the data request and
we're setting pending results equal to whatever the result of that is.
Now actually I think that pending result is of the wrong type.
It's not broadcast receive it or pending result that we need.
We need a stay pending results.
Now you might be wondering how do we deal with this pending result.
How do we get the output of that because it might take a while to be transferred back and forth if the
phone is not connected for example.
Well to do that we need to implement some classes here.
And first off we've got data API Daut data listener and we've also got Google API client dot connection
callbacks and Google API client dots on connection failt listener.
So you can imagine all of these allow us to access or listen for events which would affect this pending
result here.
We're going to need some methods that get sued for methods
and we're not going to go into these in great detail but it's fairly obvious what they do.
So unconnected will be called when the connection between the Android Wear device and the phone happens
on connections suspended will be called when that connection is broken on data changed will be called
when this data request was successful on the phone and then on connection failed will be called if it
didn't change for some reason and something went wrong.
So that's how you process a data variable change from the Watch site.
We have to do a similar thing to receive that data request on the phone.
So let's now jump in and do that side of things.
Once again we need the same classes.
Here's I'm just going to copy that over
to import those classes and then that will instruct us to implement all the methods.
And then as before we create a Google API client
to work with the data and the data transfer and then we'll set this up here.
So this is going to be a new Google API client tot builder and we're building it within this context.
And then we're going to set a few options we're going to add an API which is going to be the wearable
API.
We're going to add a connection callbacks which will allow us to listen for
events like variables being changed.
We're going to add on connection failed listener
which is what it looks like.
And then we're going to build it.
So this allows us to manage all of that data.
If you're wondering why we didn't create that at the other end that's because we've not set this up
for receiving data.
We've only set this up for sending data and when you've got sending data you don't need this Google
API client set up in the same way.
But if we wanted to receive data on the watch which you probably would because you're going to want
to synchronize information between the phone and the watch then you would need to set up as well.
OK so now we've created the Google API client everything else we actually do in these methods down here
that we met before.
So first off on connected.
So once we connect from the phone to the Android device we add our listener and we do that using wearable
data API docs add listener.
And they listen to that we use the Google API client and then we're using the main activity when we've
added Our listener.
We don't need to do anything in particular on connection suspended but we might want to remove the listener
if we
wanted to.
Although will likely happen automatically.
The important method for us is this on data changed method which will be called when an item of data
is changed.
So how do we get that information on our phone.
Well you got a thing called the Data event buffer.
So that's where all our data is contained.
So let's loop through it.
It contains a bunch of data events which we'll call each of which will call event
like that.
And we're particularly interested in where the data has changed.
So we'll check to see if event dot net type is equal to a data event type changed which means that if
this event that we're looking at here is a change of data which is what we want then we want to get
the information.
So it will create a data item called lightsome which will get from event get data item and then we'll
check to see if item.
And then we want get you are I which is the location of the item and then the path which is the precise
location of the item and then we want to compare that to
and then we want to make that equal to the path that we set over here which will slash data
and that compared to method here returns a zero if it is the same.
Say if this is the case and the item is changed in the path that we're particularly interested in and
this is where paths might become useful because you might want to do slightly different things depending
on what type of data has changed.
So that's where the path would fit into that.
So if this is the case we want to extract the data that we've got and we do that using data map
to create a data map and we get the data map item from the data write him and the data item.
So we're going to get it from is item which remember we got from event which we got from the data event
buffer when the data was changed.
And we want to get a data map
that's it.
Then the very specific item that we want is the user 9.
And we would get that from data map get and then which is our variable type.
We want to string here.
And we want the user name string.
And then finally do something with username.
So if we want to change something in our app now that the user name has been changed we could do that
back but that's basically it.
So what we've done that is on the wearable device we've taken the use of the string rope and we've saved
it as a potato request and then we've received it on the other end using on data changed.
Similarly if you wanted to change something on the phone then you would just use this code on the phone
and this code on the wearable device and that's it.
As I say I can't run it on a simulator or at least if I do it won't do anything.
But that's how you work with data and transferring it between the watch and the phone.
And now we're almost there with our tour of Android web.
But we've got a couple of more things that I want to show you first and the first of those is another
important aspect of Android Wear and that is notifications.