Congratulations on making it to the end of this section of the complete Android develop of course in
this final video we'll be creating a basic phrases app.
So as I mentioned in the previous video we're going to set up a grid layout demo much like we did then
and then very simply how app is going to contain a number of basic phrases in a non English language.
And when the appropriate button is pressed then that will play the phrase.
So you can either use that as a tool when you go on holiday or as a learning tool to practice your basic
phrases in order to get these phrases.
I went to languages dot com and my app is going to be in French but you can use any of these languages
here and they've got some brilliant free MP 3s that you can download and use in your app.
So if you want to create a custom app then that's great if you just want to use the phrases that I've
created.
Just go to Android dev course dot com slash phrases towards it and then download that to your desktop
and then you'll see the basic phrases that I've extracted from the Empey theories on the languages dot
com site.
So it's a pretty simple app but there are a few subtleties to it.
I would definitely recommend that you do it yourself.
You might then want to see just the last bit of my video.
If you've been happy with the rest of it.
One thing we really want to avoid is having eight different methods created one for each button and
then running separately so you need to find a way ideally to avoid that and have a single method which
works out which button has been pressed and then plays the appropriate sound.
But I'll leave you to try and figure that out.
Obviously if you can't don't worry about it just watch my video and I'll show you how I solve the problem.
Best of luck.
OK.
Here we go.
I'm going to start with a new project.
I'll call it basic phrases
and then all the usual options that
and we're going to be copying the basic phrases into the app as well.
So I'm going to start with that.
We'll do that in the usual way by creating a new folder within rez
or new directory called Rural and then I'm just going to command click or right click and reveal in
Finder.
And there's the rest folder within it should be a row of folder.
And then I can take my phrases and just drag those in
there that will officially work slightly different in Windows but it's basically the same process with
just dragging in our files all the files into the wrong folder.
OK.
Sometimes if you shrink it and then enlarge it again there again.
So those are phrases that step 1 then step 2 now is to add our grid view.
So this is going to be exactly the same process.
So we agreed to lay out slightly different to a grid view and now let's add buttons.
We'll start with just the one anyway.
So let's do this fairly carefully.
Jump over to
the text.
So this one is going to say hello.
So we'll change the text to hello and then we'll just have all of the settings that we had last time.
So Android
out column zero and enjoy lay row is zero as well.
Android column right.
Wait sorry.
Is.
Android lay out.
Right.
Wait sorry.
What should be one.
And then
Android play out gravity.
Is Phil..
So that's the big one.
Which makes it fill the hole great view.
And then I'm going to change the ID to match
the name of the file and that's going to be important because later on I'm going to use the I.D. to
tell iPhone which file to play.
So that's my kind of clue as it were for how I'm going to set this up so that I know which file to play.
OK so now we just need to add another seven of those.
One two three four five six
seven.
I think that was seven.
So do this as quickly as possible.
We change this to a column of 1.
We'll make this one.
How are you.
I apologize in advance to any French speakers who I've translated these wrong for.
But I think they're basically right.
So that becomes how you.
And then we have of one column sirra
some very good evening
and then one one
one can be please it's quite nice you can see the app taking shape to the right.
As we're adding our Katib
columns they're ready to.
My name is
T.
Column One
do you speak
English
when you leave out very three columns.
Welcome
and it's like I did miss one off after all.
So this last one
will be high.
Live in
OK.
Here we go.
You can see that it's stretched out a little because of the do you speak English button BAM.
If we wanted to we can add in a special symbol which is essentially an HGL symbol which is an ampersand
and then a hash.
And then a 1 0 and a semi-colon which is just the H G M L code for n for a line break and then you can
see we get the line break in there and that looks a bit better I think rather than stretching.
All of these buttons to match that longer one there.
So that's how you change your buttons to have more than one line.
All right.
And so now we've added all our buttons.
You might want to change the color or do something a bit more fancy to them but I'm just going to leave
them like that.
So now we want to start getting responses when these individual buttons are tapped.
Now we could go back through design mode and click on them one by one and add an on click to each of
them.
But that's not particularly efficient.
Much quicker would be to add it in the XML
so Android on click
is a button tapped.
And I'm just going to add that to all of them so I notice that I'm adding a single method here.
A perfectly valid solution to this problem would be to add a different method for each
button.
But that's not particularly scalable.
We'll be creating endless methods if we had lots and lots of different buttons here and we might even
want to at some point feel these buttons programmatically rather than hard coding them in like we have
here.
And then we wouldn't be able to create again endless different methods on the fly.
So we're going to learn how to do it slightly neater way.
So now we need to set up our button taps method over in main activity or other
site as usual public Voyt
button tapped and it's going to be called by a view which we'll call you
and find out
I'm just going to log
button tapped.
True.
Just to make sure that everything looks OK and that everything's connected up.
What we're going to want soon after this is to work out which button was tapped.
And that's a slightly trickier problem to solve but we'll get that.
So just time that we get.
So that's connected up nicely.
Now if we just type in view here remember this view is the button that's been tapped on.
I can actually use a method called get ID which looks like it will be pretty perfect.
And that would give me the ID of the button.
But then you get a mysterious error here that this is actually an integer.
And so we're going to need to convert it to a string to be able to display it in the logs will use integer
to string.
And then let's run that there's definitely something strange going on because the idea is that we entered
we're not integers they were very much strings.
Let's see what happens then when we run the app now.
So button tapped and then you can see if we get this big long number that obviously we haven't entered
that's all.
So what's actually going on there is that this ID is a number within the app itself which it used to
refer to this button but it's not the same ID that we actually gave the button which is slightly confusing
but we can still use it to get what we want.
So let's see how we do that.
First of all let's just create an integer called ID which is going to be equal to the ID of the button
that's just been tapped.
When I say Id that I mean this long number not the ID that we entered for it then we'll create a string
which we'll call our ID
which initially is going to be empty.
And then we're going to attempt to find out ID of the element that has been tapped into the button that's
been tapped.
And if we can we'll set it to our ID and then we use the dot get resources don't get resource entry
name and then ID
and that will give us the ID for the object which we want to set to our ID.
So now let's give that a try.
This should be a string so we don't need to convert it
so we can just display it straight away.
So this essentially get goods into the resources and gets information about the object that was tapped
on and we can use that to get the particular ID that is the one that we entered for the Boston
let's just bring that up.
Fantastic.
There we go.
So I live in.
Welcome.
Do you speak english etc.
Pretty.
So now we've got the ID.
It's just a matter of playing the sound which in theory is simple but we're going to get a little complication
here.
Let's just set it up as we would normally do.
So we'll create a media player
variable which will call again player.
And normally we would use Media Player to create and then we would use this for the context and then
we'd use something like our DOT roar.
Don't say you speak English.
And then we'd use player.
Don't start the complication here of course is that we don't know which file we should play and we can't
just replace this with the our ID string because this is not a string This is a particular object within
our rule but don't panic.
There is a way around it.
What we can do is get yet another ID for this particular resource for the results that we want to play.
And we can get that using it was also ID.
So we're creating an integer called results ID which is going to be an integer that we can we use to
refer to one of these sound files and we get that using get resources Dart's get identifier and then
we enter our ID which is the identify of the particular file the location of it.
So it's going to be in roll.
And then we need to specify the package name.
Use this command to get identify of other packages.
And the easiest way to get the package name is just to bring up the logs.
And it's that string that come out example taught for me Percival Dart's basic phrases
obviously it's very important you get that right.
And then
instead of using our role to refer to a particular file we can just use resource ID which tells us what's
going on there and how this is stored within the Android system.
So when we type our role Daut halo that's actually returning an integer.
And that's one of those long integers that we saw which refers to an object or a file within the app.
In this case the Hello.
And for a file.
All right.
So fingers crossed if we've done everything right they should play the correct sound when the button
is tapped.
And we gave
fantastic
and that's it.
So the complications really well not so much around the layout or the buttons they were just around
this getting results IDs et cetera.
But if you do things this way can save a lot of creating eight different methods having to assign the
same method to each individual button for example.
So that's it.
Feel free to play around with this app and make it even more exciting and useful.
And then when you've done that take a quick break and let's get straight on with Section 5.