So here in the final video of our Android Wear tour I'm going to show you how we can customize.
I watch face on Android Wear and it's actually pretty easy to do an android studio because as I watch
face
templates include it and you may have noticed it either here.
They we get
so I'll keep those the default for now.
You can choose analog or digital probably digital is easier to work with initially to customize.
So we'll start with digital and all I'm going to do here is just run you through the code and show you
how you might want to change a few things depending on how you want your watch face to work.
So here we go.
You can see we've got instead of our usual main activity we've got my watch face as our main class and
all I'm going to do is just run the one through the content of my watch face.
Explain roughly what it's doing.
And that would give you all you need to start customizing and changing your own watch faces.
So here we go.
We've got first off the typeface so you could imagine First off if you want to change the typeface to
anything else you could do that there.
Couple of other settings here.
The update right.
So unsurprisingly the update right here is every second which is probably about right.
But if you wanted to say I don't watch kind of a watch you might want to do that every tenth of a second
or something else.
And here we've got a message ID which is a number that is passed to our various updating methods.
When the time is updated and we've just got to lines of code to create the new engine to update the
time this then gets the time zone which is passed to the app via the broadcast receiver and then sets
m time appropriately This sets and register time receiver to initially fails to be created later.
And then we've got a couple of paint variables paint's allow us to create 2-D graphics so you could
just have a simple single color there or you could create patterns and store them in these paint variables.
But one for the background and one for the text the ambient billion tell us whether we're in ambient
mode which is generally fainter and less battery intensive and full interactive mode.
We've got the actual time variable which is actually now deprecate but still in use here.
The updated version is actually doesn't say that it is Greggory in calendar.
If you want to keep your watch up to date you should upgrade that used Gregorian calendar instead of
time.
And then those are the offsets for x and y for our actual watch display.
Almost then this final one as you can see there is a special setting.
If the display supports fewer bits for each color in MGM and be a mode.
So if it's true anti-aliasing will be disabled.
All right so now we've got our familiar create method.
So this essentially creates the watch face or watch face style builder.
And then we've got our usual sets of options.
So we've got card peak mode.
So essentially what notifications are going to be allowed and the default there is peak mode variable.
I believe only shows important notifications but you could change that if you want it.
We've got the background visibility and you can play with that to see what the various modes are show
system UI time.
So there's a system clock on the screen.
Most of the time you probably wouldn't want that piece to be displayed on your clock as well.
So that's usually centerfolds.
And then we build it then we get some resources for the watch face which we're not really going to be
using here.
And we set the y offsets to 90 pixels we create a new page for the background which is just a single
color whatever the digital background by default is.
And similarly for the text in color which is whatever the digital text color is and then we've got our
time is created there as well.
Now we've got some different methods so undestroyed this happens when the watch faces closed by the
user.
So it just removes the messages.
So just to clear clear the cache essentially is what's going on that we've got a method for creating
the text paint which sets the typeface and the anti-alias.
If we're using it as well as the color right moving on we go on visibility changed here which is called
when the watch face becomes visible or when it ceases to be visible.
So when it becomes visible we register receiving the updates and time and get the time zone and we set
the time to now.
And when it becomes invisible then we unregister that to say again saving battery power.
And it also starts all stops the timer as necessary.
This method just registers the receiver to get the user's time zone and this unregister the receiver
for it.
Again we don't want to be listening for a time zone change if we're not active.
This method is another way to get whether the screen is round or square and it's on a apply window as
it sets.
We can actually use this anywhere.
And in this method you can use the Boullion is round which you get from insets is round and that will
return true if it's round or falls if it's not.
So this allows you to set the X offset dependent on the screen shape and also the screen size as well
using get dimensions.
OK almost them on properties changed is called When we go in or go out of ambiant mode and this just
updates em low bit ambient to keep track of that.
So it knows where we are with regards to ambient mode the on time tick is called every minute in ambient
mode to update the watch face and the default here is just invalidate which invalidates the canvas causing
the watch face to be updated in ambient mode.
We've got a fairly straight forward on ambient mode changed so this will happen when the ambient mode
is changed.
And it just checks to see if we're in ambient mode or not.
And updates settings accordingly and then invalidates the canvas so that the watch face will be redrawn
the draw method is the main one that you're going to be working with.
And this is the method that draws the watch face in ambient mode.
So if you wanted to create for example a watch that counts down to Christmas or something like that
then this is where you would read to the logic for that.
So time gives you the current time and then Currently you can see we're just formatting the screen depending
on whether we're in ambient mode or not.
And if we're in ambient mode we're just going to show the hour and minute.
And if we're not in ambient mode then we're going to show the hour minute and second.
So it's these numbers that you would want to play around with if you wanted to have a different time
or display the time in a different format.
So for example we wanted a dash instead of a colon there and we would just change it like that.
And then it draws the text using the offsets and the text paint variable that we've seen and then this
one just updates the timer if necessary as it says if the time isn't running that it starts them off
or stops it.
It shouldn't be running but he's
this one then updates the time more often.
If we're in interactive mode.
And finally this part handles the messages to update the watch face or not depending on the time and
the mode etc..
So there's a lot of stuff that you probably won't need to mess around with there.
The main thing if you are interested in watch faces that I would start off looking at is this on Draw
method and just take a look at what editing that does.
But you might also want to play around with layouts and images and that kind of thing.
If you actually want to sell or distribute a watch face then it's usual usually styles that people are
particularly interested in.
So that's probably what you're going to want to play with most.
So let's just very quickly see how we initialize this watch face because it's not just the same as running
an app.
Once you've run the app on your device you need to select it as a live watch face.
So first off to something to notice is in the Android manifest.
We've got a label.
My digital and that is the name that appears on the list of watches.
So if you wanted to make that something custom you could do that down here in strings SML.
So that's currently my digital if you wanted to change it.
Rob is what face or something like that then you would do that there.
So here we get to get our watch face up we need to go back to the main home screen and then long press
and then you can jump through.
We actually got a couple of my digitals there from my testing earlier.
So let's just select one of those and say that's the one that we had before so you can see we've now
got the dash instead of a code where I changed it then.
So there you go.
That's the basics of how to edit a watch face.
And that takes us to the end of our tour of Android where I hope you've enjoyed it.
And I'll just redirect you back to the Android documentation which is a great place to go.
It's got instructions on creating such faces and sinking data.
So all of the stuff that we've talked about but in a bit more detail and showing you some of the features
that that I haven't included here.
So I hope your brain is whizzing with brilliant ideas for wearable apps.
As always don't be afraid don't worry about it.
Just put something together.
Test it.
See if people like it.
Best of luck.