OK let's talk about YouTube channel creation experts strategy here.
I can't stress this one enough to everybody who sells apps needs a YouTube channel.
I don't have to tell you.
YouTube is the second largest search engine on the planet potential millions of new fans can find your
app there and you can send them the masses from the YouTube right to your app.
Period.
The payoff can be quite big here.
So it's a must try putting your YouTube channel right inside your app perhaps having these videos people
can watch inside your app only help you increase your time spent in your app that increases social engagement
remember.
Plus here are YouTube videos can appear in organic Google search youtube videos are more likely to be
shared among friends because people like videos versus reading plain old boring black and white text.
Your youtube videos and channel can be set to be monetized as well.
Here's a strategy tip add subtitles in different languages to your videos to garner more downloads.
YouTube is the way to go here and it can't hurt.
I would also like you to add your videos to Dailymotion dot com and the ammo dot com or Vimeo.
Be sure to check the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.