Android where is Google's smartwatch platform.
Well it's still pretty early days for smartwatches.
It's a market that's bound to go quickly.
And if it's anything like the smartphone market Android is pretty likely to take it over.
So in this section we're going to be looking at Android Web 2.0 which is planned for release in the
autumn of 2016.
You don't need any special software to develop for Android where you can just do it all with an android
studio and I'm going to show you how in this video we'll look at how great a basic Hello World app for
Android where and run it on the simulator.
So within our studio we get to file new projects and then as you've probably noticed we have the option
to create an android where project I'll call this Android where demo
and we've always used the phone and tablet option so far.
But this time we're going to switch to Android where as usual you can choose the various different options.
I'm going to go for five point.
OK so MS compatibility but as always if you want to use any of the particular API that come with six
point seven Boito then you need to choose die's OK.
Now as with our Android apps we can choose the default activity.
So you've got an always on where activity.
A blank one a notification Google Maps and a watch face.
So we're going to be going for blank where activity for the moment and then next we'll leave those as
the default options.
And finish while that setting up we will need an Android Wear device to test this on.
So let's create one in the tools Android DVD manager.
Remember we did this right back at the beginning of the course and DVD is an android virtual device
and we need to create a watch device.
To test out our apps on so we create this in just the same way that we did before.
But of course we're going to choose a web device this time and it doesn't matter too much which ones
you choose but I'd recommend having a square and a round one available.
So I'm going to go for that top square device and then click next.
And again you can choose any version you want.
I'll just go for the one that I've already got.
That is lollipop.
And as always you can customize the device IFAB it if you like as well.
I'm just going to leave that as it is and click Finish.
And there we go.
Let's quickly do another one to create a round device so I use that bottom one then the next next and
finish.
So we now have two Android Wear devices and heads out Android Wear Dema app.
I'll just run it in the background.
So we'll start with round and well that's lady let's have a quick look at the files that we're used
to seeing.
So we've got our Android manifest
which looks pretty similar to what we're used to seeing.
We've got this new feature of Android how it's like.
Watch of course but the rest is fairly familiar in the Java section.
We've got code that again is pretty similar to what we're used to.
We've got our main activity which is sending activity and we've got a specific text view here which
is part of our default lay out.
And then we've got our own create method.
We do have a new variable type of watch view stub which will go into and see exactly what's going on
there in the next video.
For now that notice that we've got three different lú files this time.
So we've got the primary lay out which you can see them unfortunately in the preview it doesn't show
you it in a watch which is a bit of a shame.
But the main thing really is to notice that we've got two different activities or two different layouts
at least for rectangular and round.
And in our case in this demo app and the round activity we've got a text with a halo round world in
the middle and then in the rectangular you can see we've got hollow square world which is at the top
left.
So you can have different layouts very easily for round and square watch faces.
OK let's take a look.
A TV guy you can see the Android Wear emulator is coming to life.
You might notice though that I do have an issue down here saying that there's not enough memory to run
that particular CD.
So that's worth being aware of when we go to the manager.
We might need to edit DVDs and give them more memory so to do that we show advance settings.
And then we can choose the amount of RAM here let's go for a pretty big 2 4 8 2 gigabytes of RAM should
be enough
and then click Finish.
And then the same thing with the square device.
So advanced settings and then the same thing with the round device say edit show advance settings and
will change the RAM to 2.
I for I
had finished now let's run again.
On the round device and there we go you can see the halo round a world text in the center of the screen
there.
And then we can also run the app on the square emulator or Android where Square and then if we move
over to see that emulator you can see it's currently running Android Wear itself
and then in a moment how app will pop up
and there it is how a square world.
The top left of the screen this time.
So that's the basic idea of how we run Android apps.
We have our main activity before and then we've got our rectangular and round activity layouts in the
next video.
Then we're going to dive a little deeper into how the watch stub system works and how we can build an
app that's customized for each shape of device.
I see that.