So welcome again to Section 4 of The Complete Android and develop of course they join in the section
will be working with animations making a game and working with video and audio.
But for now we're going to revisit layouts because they are such a fundamental way of making your app
look good.
Developing the Android means that you have to be ready for many different screen sizes and resolutions
flexible layouts are the best way to do that.
So let's dive right in with a button I've created just a blank app here.
So if we drag our button in as we have seen before we can send to the button in the Senza of the app
and that will be in the center of the screen regardless of screen size.
We can also position that relativity for example that label that we can position it at the top right
or a certain margin from the top again from the center or similarly bottom right bottom left et cetera.
If I popped it down there and it would be aligned to the bottom left of the screen regardless of how
big the screen was.
This is it because it's within a relative layout.
So everything is positioned relative to everything else.
Now you may have noticed this text tab down at the bottom of the page which actually gives you the SML
code which describes that layout and how in Android studio to we can edit the code and we can see the
layout update with it.
So so far we've been dragging and dropping and changing properties from the Properties menu on the right
there.
But we can do all of this with code.
So for example this is the code that defines the text view in the top left.
If I change the text here to help Rob that we'll update the text itself.
Similarly this code defines my button if I changed the width to
if you remember we can change the width to either match parent fill parent or wrap content.
OK for Phil
parents and we can now see that the button is stretched out all the way across the screen and we can
do a similar thing for the height if we wanted a massive button for some reason as try this time.
Match parent can see we still get the auto predicts well just like with coding then that will stretch
the button out all the way across our screen.
So let's experiment a little if we get rid of the loud alignment code and then we'll change the width
as well-packed to wrap content and the height.
And let's see what happens.
So the button will just display itself over the top of the text then.
So say we want to change that to be aligned just below the text field.
We can do that by dragging it down there.
And then let's see what that looks like in terms of text.
We're now
have a Lao guide below the text view.
And it's also given an ID to the text so we can refer to it as well.
One advantage of using the text
method to work with layouts is that it's very easy to create copies of existing objects and then just
edit things so we could change the ID to to you for example and maybe we want this to be below.
The first button and you can see we've now got a new button.
Obviously we could have just dragged the New button but have we had lots of complicated formatting or
layout here with this button.
We can recreate that very easily just by copying and pasting the text and then editing it to behave
as we want it to.
So really this is just a quick introduction to seeing that there are two ways to work with design on
Android we can either do the drag and drop method as we've been doing so far or we can create items
and edit them using code.
Generally speaking the code method is more powerful but the design drag and drop method is generally
quicker if you just want to create a quick design so it will mostly be working on the drag and drop
view.
But you may prefer working with the tech especially if you've worked with SML or similar languages before.
Ok now I'm going to give you a quick challenge.
I would like you to see if you can create a layout where these two buttons are next to each other but
centered in the middle of the screen.
So a bit like an OK and a cancel button centered in the screen next to each other.
Now it might be tricky.
So don't just give it a couple of minutes.
See if you can figure out how to do it.
Go for it.
Did you manage it.
Probably trickier than you thought it was going to be.
It's one of those lay out tricks that's actually quite difficult.
One way to solve it is to have a third invisible item in the middle and then position those two relative
to that one.
But with Android we've got a much better way to do it using a horizontal linear layout.
And this is the first of these layouts that we'll look at.
So let's drag in a linear layout and see what it looks like.
So in itself a layout is just a box.
But then when we start dragging things into this box such as a button
then the first one positioned itself as would expect top left.
The second one will position to the right of the first like that.
And that's what linear layout is designed for simply to have things in a horizontal line.
Now if we change the width
to wrap content and we'll change the height to wrap content as well.
Then we have a a layout or a box essentially that contains our two buttons and I can drag them around
I select my layout and I can then send to
my layout
like that.
And now those two buttons will be centered regardless of the screen size.
So if I have a quick click on a Nexus 10 there we go.
You can see they're still centered relative to the whole screen but then left and right.
So it's great for things like OK and Cancel buttons that you want to be centered but next to each other.
All right.
So we've got a vertical linear out there as well which is exactly the same just for vertical lists of
objects rather than horizontal ones.
And then these other layouts we're going to be looking at later on in the course so feel free to play
around and experiment with layouts.
But the main thing going forward from this video is to be aware that we can use both text that is SML
and the drag and drop method to create and edit our layouts depending on which one we prefer or is best
for that particular job.
And to be aware that we can use some layouts especially linear layouts to contain small groups of buttons
or text views or whatever it is to be aligned in a certain way.
All right that was useful.
Now we're going to move on and see how we can work with animation in Android.