For the final app we're going to create in this course.
I've chosen the hugely popular messaging app WhatsApp.
As always we're going to be replicating the core functionality which is the direct messaging system
unlike Instagram and Twitter that we've cloned so far.
What's app allows you to message individual users directly.
And of course see a stream of your conversation with each individual user.
So that's the plan.
And as this is the final app we're going to build I'm not even going to show you the app in advance
so I would encourage you to just sit down and aim to replicate that functionality completely on your
own.
So start with the A.W. what our server set up create your luggage use a list and then set up the chat
functionality.
At this stage in the course it's something that you should be able to do really in a couple of hours.
As always though if you want to follow along and watch how I do it you're very welcome.
So give me a moment to pause the video now before I get started.
All right.
Well I'm of course going to begin at AWOS dot Amazon Dot Com to create my path server instance so I'll
lock myself in at the same time I'll jump over to Android dev of course dot com slash pass project dot
zip
to download the past projects.
Ok I'm going to be using AZT
with the elastic Computing Cloud and I'm going to launch a new instance
from the AWOS marketplace
searching for pass
selects choose the you micro instance
and launch and then launch.
And as usual I'm going to create a new key path
which I'll call whatsapp keypad.
And then launch instance.
Okay.
And then we'll open up that instance page while the instance is setting itself up will jump over to
find way to find the pacifist art project which has now been downloaded and expanded for us.
So I'm just going to rename that to what's app and then open it up in Android studio in Android studio.
So file open.
And then is the desktop.
We can see what's app.
Excellent.
So now that's opening up with great efficiency we can now come back and see our AWOS instance click
connect use our Java S-sh client from within the browser and then for me the key path is slash uses
slash.
Rob Percival slash desktop slash whatsapp keypad.
PM
And I want to store that in the browser cache.
So I did have to type it in next time your key path of course will be the location wherever you've saved
that file that you downloaded.
And here we go.
So now we logged into the server.
So let's change directory to apps slash POS slash HP Dokes
and then open with vim VI the text editor the file server.
J.S. and that should then open up a file and allow us to access the app ID master key and server you
RL.
OK so let's check back either in Android studio.
I open up what's app project and open up our whatsapp project and we're going to start off in Stata
application to put in our app settings.
Jump back over to our S-sh session.
Start with the app ID.
So copy that paste it in then the masticate copy that paste that in.
Now interestingly I've got a different format for the server you are at this time.
Before I paste that in I'm just going to check it over in Firefox.
And see if it works.
It could be just a different way that the AWOS instance was set up.
But that doesn't seem to be collecting so I'm going to go back to my 82 instance and get the u r l from
here.
And try that out.
There we go.
So I'm not sure why it didn't give me that for you.
Well in the S-sh session I'm going to use the Amazon one that we're more used to that we go.
And from here it should be pos.
Let's now run the app and make sure everything is connected as we would like.
And there we go.
Can See that's been successful so we're looking good.
Let's just jump back over it see the past dashboard make sure that that's appearing correctly then and
there we go with our example object.
So everything's connected up right.
Okay.
Time to build out log in page let's get rid of example object code and also comment out enable automatic
user.
And now it should be pretty familiar.
I'm going to get back to the original logon and sign up system using the same form but a different mode
for log in and sign up.
So let's start with our text fields
just track that in in the usual way.
So this will be our user name and it text and the hint will be
your user name
and we don't want any different text them
and then
we'll have a password underneath
which will be a password edit text with a hint of your
password and then a button
which will initially be signed up which will send to
changed the text that you sign up and the lake will be.
Sign up looking
and then finally will add a text free
which up it underneath the button.
So you get a little bit and the text that will initially be all logging
and the so-called toggle logging mode
textfield when I should add the text sign up to the Boston
we get.
So let's get sign up working.
First of all we'll go over to the main activity doc Java and then write our public
Foyt sign up logging method.
So first we'll get the username and password fields to edit text
will have our user name edit text.
She's going to be an edit text.
We're going to find it by its ID
order Heidi.
Don't use a name at it.
Text same password
password edit text
and view by ID or an ID dot password.
Added text then we get to create our past user
which will be a new pass
use up and then we're going to and then we're going to add the user name.
So that's going to be username added text doc get text and we're going to convert that to a string.
Similarly with the password we use password edit text doc get text dot to stream
and then we'll take our user and we'll sign them up in the background with a new sign up Colback
which checks for an error
and if there's no error
find out we'll just load that user signed up
and if that is we'll display that to the user.
And we do that with we don't get message OK.
So let's give that a try.
We should now be able to put in a username and password and sign up a user when the button is tapped.
And here we go.
We're looking it except of course
I've forgotten to make those fill with
the lists just change those to match parent.
And now let's do first a test without a username password.
Excellent.
So we've got that error.
We need to get rid of that first bit again but that's no problem.
And then let's create a rope with one two three four sign up.
So with any luck that one was successful I have a quick look at the Lokes.
Yep.
A signed up.
And then if we are tempted again
we should get an error message account already exists for this username.
Super
electricity a quick fix to get rid of that first part of the error message.
As you remember we do this with substring.
And then we want to start the first space so that we don't get message to an index of.
And then space and there we go.
So now let's allow the in mode.
So what creates a boolean
called
logging made active which will initially be votes
and then we'll check to see if logging made is active and if it is the user in and if not we'll sign
the user up
that will need the added text either way.
So just add them.
Now we just need to make it so that they all log in text is clickable and we're going to do this a different
way to how we did it before.
So rather than using an on click listener we're going to view all the properties of the text field and
we're going to look for clickable
which is downhere
and we're going to select that to make it true.
And then we're going to set an on click method just like we do for about an
down of a quick
several toggle logon mode.
All right so now we'll create
our toggle log in
mode method.
Using public voyde called by the text field.
And just to make sure our new method works.
That's just a quick log.
I call it mode called.
So just a quick check to make sure that when we tap on that button something happens and here we go.
So now let's tap all log in and you can see we get mode toggled.
So that other method for making text views clickable works fine.
So let's get rid of the log and check.
First off to see if logging mode is active
and we'll consider ourselves in sign up mode.
First off.
So if we're in sign up mode then logging mode active will be false.
So we need to change log in mode active to true so now we're going to be in loggin mode.
We want to change the bottom text to logon.
I'm not certain I gave the button an ID.
Let's have a look at patentee
let's give it a better idea.
And that's
Logan.
Sign up button.
So we're going to need our button either way.
So let's create a new button.
Log in sign up button.
Which is going to be a button using find view by id and then just remind myself what I call that button.
The idea doesn't seem to have saved let's get back to your properties
and logon sign up button.
And then here we can now bring that in that will also need the text view
which I called
Tabo lot in log in my text be very sensible to go log in my text FYI.
And this is going to be a text view V by ID or ID dot toggle logging mode text.
OK.
So if we're switching to logging mode then we need to change the button text
to logon
and we need to set the toggle logging mode text.
Tea or comma sign up.
And if we're going the other way we then need to change log in mode active to false because we're moving
to sign up mode which means we want to change the log in sign up button text to sign up and we want
to change the logon mode text view to say or log in.
All right so that should now work fine.
We just need to add the code to actually lock the user in so we can do this sort of with past user.
So we're going to log in in background
and then we need to pass a username and password and a callback so the user name is going to be username
added text or get text to string and the password is going to be password added text dot get text dot
to a string and then the callback is going to be a new logon callback.
And again as before.
We'll just check to see if he is no.
And if it is we'll log
have a user is logged in
and if it's not shared the user error message
and I'll just copy the toast command from down there.
All right so let's give it a try.
We should have now a completely working log in and sign up form and here we go.
So tap or log in and we can see that that's changing nicely.
So let's be in logging mode
and attempt to log in as me
and with any luck we should see on the logs that were successful we use a logged in.
And of course if we try to log in with the wrong password we should get a nice error message.
Aha.
Now something interesting that we just got username password and that was because in this case we didn't
get the Java Lang parts at the beginning of the message so we should add a quick check to see if that
Java part is included.
And only then get the substring.
So let's write a quick bit of code to do that
will create a string called message
which will initially be equal to a dot
get message
and then we'll check to see if
message will convert our message to lowercase.
So we don't have to worry about whether the J in the Java is capitalized and we'll check to see if this
contains
what Java
and if it does then we'll update message with the substring Vashon
and we'll do the same thing.
Down here.
Great.
So let's just quickly test that in action and then we can move on.
To our use a list here we go.
Let's try signing up with a user name that already exists and you can see if we get that proper error
message.
And similarly with the logon again we get invalidly username and password this time.
Great.
So just one tiny thing we've got Paul start a project up there which I want.
So let's set the title
to whatsapp logging.
OK.
And that takes us to the end of this first video in the second video.
We'll see how to add the user list and get ready to send and view messages.