This section we're going to be building a clone of Twitter.
Hugely popular social app where you can follow people and read everything they care to share with the
world.
That's part of my aim to get you increasingly independent as an app developer.
I'm just going to show you once after we get a build and then I'm going to wish you good luck as you
do your best to build as much of it as you can.
As always though if you have any problems I'll lead you through it and you're very welcome to just follow
along with the videos if you'd rather.
So here's what we're building.
It's a fairly familiar looking screen but you can see we've just got a single sign up Logan bottom which
has a slightly different way of allowing users to log in.
Essentially what's going to happen is when a user signs up or logs in it will attempt to lock them in
and if it's successful it will lock them in.
And if not they it will attempt to sign them up.
So it's not necessarily a great way of doing a log in system because if someone missed types they use
a name that it will just sign them up with a new user name rather than telling them that they've got
something wrong.
But it might work for them and it's a slight change from what we've done before.
So that's how we're going to do my logging for this.
And then once we log in you can see we've got a user list here.
So these are all the users on the app that are not my user.
And crucially we can select and de-select users here and our past server will keep track of which ones
are ticked so that we know who our current user is following.
And then we've got our menu here.
So with obviously great logout button they're fairly straightforward but we've got a tweet button as
well which will open an alert dialog here and allow the user to send a tweet
something fairly mundane like hello there and then press send and then it will say that on the Passover
and tell the user that the tweet has set and then a final part of the up is when the user wants to view
their feet.
I can view the tweets of people that they are following those tweets are displayed in date order and
you can see we're using a slightly different structure for the list view there and I'll give you a hint
you'll need to use something called a simple adapter rather than an array adapter to get your data to
display like that.
But I'm sure you can figure that out with a little bit of googling.
Time now to post the video and create this Twitter app.
Best of luck.
Go for it
to one of the purposes of these final couple of apps is to show you how quick and easy it is to create
a relatively complicated app with password.
And the skills that you've learned so far in Android studio will jump over to easy to
launch.
Instance
and then AWOS marketplace pass
pass ever powered by bit nomy
choose the teacher you might cry review a launch and then launch.
I'm going to create a new keypad called Twitter
keypad
save that and then launch instance K and we get to go
and while that setting up I'll to Android dev cos dot com slash pass project dot zip and I would recommend
downloading a new version of this each time because it does get updated fairly often so each time you
create a new Passover project just download another copy of the past projects and then when that's downloaded
we can jump over to Andrews studio.
And file open.
Actually I'll just quickly rename the folder passivist art project to Twitter
and then we'll find it on the desktop.
There we go and open that up
and then back over to Firefox to log into our past seven instance I clicked connect to use a Java S-sh
client and then put in the keep up with this a few times now.
So it should be fairly familiar uses replaceable desktop and then Twitter keypad.
PM will store that in the browser cache so we don't have to type it in next time and they launch S-sh
client.
And here we go.
So we're going to change directory to apps slash pass slash H.T. docs
and then we're going to use vi to launch the text editor and we're going to edit server Daut J.S..
So now we could apply the master key and server you Arel start with the server you are el and also quickly
jump over into Firefox and load the past dashboard OK and then back that to Android studio and let's
find a starter application.
There we go.
So we'll begin by pasting in our server make sure we don't forget the trailing slash at the end there
get the masticate
and pasted it in for the client key and then the app ID
and we gave
so well run the app in the background to make sure we're connected.
You pass that everything's working OK.
And a quick change I'm going to make is just disabling the automatic use of that because we're not going
be using that here.
We're going to have a proper logon system and there we go.
So I passed it was successful.
So we're looking promising.
Let's do a quick refresh of the past dashboard and make sure that everything is synchronized.
And there we go.
So we've got our example object with the string.
And number perfect.
So now we're going to build our log in page.
So let's zoom in and we'll start with
a plain text field
which will make for width get rid of the text
but we will have a hint
which I'll call a username and we'll call this user name at it.
Text
OK them will use a password that it takes to go underneath that
which will have a hint of password and we'll call password and text
all rights and then we'll have a button
and we're just going to have a single button for sign up and logon and we'll see how that works in a
minute.
Just make sure it scented
and then the final thing we need to do here is to get that on click and I'll call it Sign-Up log in.
All right.
So now back to main activity I'm going to update the title First off
so I'll use set title
and I'll call it Twitter logging.
And then we'll create the method for signing up for logging in
which you'll be called by the bank view.
And this time I'm just going to attempt to log in straightaway.
So we'll get the text first off.
So start with username and text which is going to be added text.
From File view by id Zeus's dot ID dot username and text.
Same for password
like an added text
by its ID that Id dot password added text and then we can attempt the log in first of all.
So we're going to use Pownce user to log in in background and the username is going to be user name
and it text don't get text string and the password is going to be password added text.
Get text dot to string and then we'll have a callback which will be a new logo and callback
OK.
Then we'll check to see if he is no.
Then we'll just log
that we did
else will attempt to sign the user up to do that we'll need to create a new user.
So the first user parse user is going to be a new parse user and then will set the user name to the
user name and text.
Don't get text talk to string
and then password
is password at a text called Don't Get text talk to string
and then we'll take up as user and sign them up in the background with a new sign up Colback
and a game will check if he is no
more log
in I signed up
else will display an error message to the user.
So a toast
and the message will just use the past message so that's a dot
get message.
All right.
So let's take a look.
Note that this isn't necessarily the best way to set up a set up or log in screen.
It's very quick and easy but it does have the downside that if the user tries to log in but mistype
their username then instead of giving them an error message it will
try and create a new account for them with the new user name which might not be what they want to do.
So I wouldn't necessarily recommend this method.
For production apps but it is quite a nice simple one and worth being aware of.
OK so here we go.
Username and password.
Oh I forgot to change the password to for with
so I will just change that.
But for now it's to a test.
So we'll have Raub password.
One two three four.
Sign up slash logon so should sign that user up every day.
Sign up.
And then if I do it again I should log the user in one form.
Let's just have a quick look and see what error messages we get.
If we don't enter a password you can see that we did get a friendly error message password can be missing
or blank but it has that nasty Java Lang et cetera before it which we don't really want.
So one way to get rid of that is to split up the message by a space.
And we want essentially everything after the first spites and we can do that with what's known as a
substring.
So if we get e don't get message and then we'll use a substring which allows us to start at a certain
point in the string.
And we want to start just after that first space.
So we need to know where that first base is and we can do that using a target message index of.
And then we want to get the index of the space so let's have a quick look at that.
And here we go.
So if I try and sign up or log in with a blank username and password.
There we go.
We get a nice message now and the password is full with as well.
It's a little bit of a boring screen.
I think I'm going to quickly add in the Twitter logo just to brighten it up a little bit.
So we're going to Google Images
Hello.
That we gave that one went perfectly and it's a good size as well.
We're going to control click save images and then rename it.
It's just Twitter logo.
We go over to find the old Windows Explorer and Windows copy Twitter logo with Kamado Control-C and
then back over to Android studio into the drawable folder.
And paste.
Oh I've still got a leftover Instagram logo.
I'll delete that
k and then we'll just leave everything down a little bit by bringing in our image.
Okay.
And there's my Twitter logo
superb.
I'll just give that a fixed height and maybe 100 deep is lovely and then I'll change
the first edit text so that it aligns to the image view.
Rather than the top of the screen so I use Android lay out below.
And we haven't said an ID for that one yet said it's quickly to that it's image view
and we go that should move everything down.
After I get rid of a line parent
as just reduce the top marginal bits
username.
There we go.
I'm happy with that.
That looks like a perfectly nice logon screen.
Great.
That's a very quick in and sign up screen for out what's app.
Now we're going to go on and allow users to view the other users that are on the platform and follow
or follow them.
We'll do that in the next video.