OK let's talk about expert forum posting strategies here.
I always do a search for your niches forums and Google for example your niche plus forums in the search
field.
Now register for the ones you see a lot of traffic you can eyeball this by simply looking over all the
replies.
If you see high numbers that's great.
You can also go to Alexa dot com and copy and paste the forms you are l and see where it's ranked and
who is likely to visit it.
By looking at the demographics for that site now read the rules for posting my tip here is provide questions
or if you can help someone out even better get your feet wet by answering other people's questions or
asking your own for about a week or so you want to set up a presence of trust on these forums first
then add your app store your arrival with a call to action to your forum signature.
And that's where you promote your app from.
Don't just sign up to a new forum and post.
Hey I would like it if you checked out my new app.
You can download it right here.
That's a no no.
You'll wind up getting banned on day one.
Be sure to check out the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.