Congratulations on making it to the end of Section 5 you've covered a lot of material now and I hope
that there were a few challenges but you managed to overcome them over this section.
We've covered now downloading material from the web as well as timer's lists views try and catch and
a lot more.
So it was a pretty meaty section and there was a lot to learn.
I hope you've been developing your app along the side and you're really in a position now as well to
get on freelance or web sites or even go to friends and family and see if they want a simple Android
app built and you've got a lot of skills now to put something real that could be could be used and put
live on Google Play together.
Again it's not about making huge amounts of money.
It's about getting practice and getting something.
Life is no substitute for that for getting feedback as well as enjoying it and feeling good about what
you're doing.
So try and get something live something real and as quickly as you can.
And of course I'll see you at the beginning of the next section.