This is a very important part of a process.
This is where you have your best chance at selling your app to all your potential users browsing the
app market.
This works just like the meta description tag for a web site.
It's not searchable so you don't have to overpacked it with keywords.
This should be around three or four sentences.
Google Play allows 80 characters for a short description of your app and up to 4000 characters for its
long or full description.
Apple allows 4000 characters for its description section remember only the first 580 characters will
be seen until the viewer has to click on the More button.
The first three lines of your apt description are super important.
That's because people looking on a desktop or tablet get to see only the first three lines of your description
plus your app icon and first one or two screenshots.
Therefore place your most important words here first for example place any awards you may have one or
top reviews here.
Everybody just isn't going to read your entire description.
Tips for both Apple and Android.
The full fold put the most important information before it.
List the benefits and features.
Never use HVM Ill never sound too technical speak in layman's terms so everyone can understand.
Include a call to action to make people feel they need to have it.
You can say download now to enjoy pull that psychological trigger.
Include some social proof to help convince people how cool your app is such as awards or reviews.
Places always at the very top your apps description will constantly be evolving.
So when you get solid reviews you'll want to add those here.
Now if you want to see what your description will look like before you release your app to the store
please use a software called app snippet preview.
OK I'll see you in the next lecture.