Now that we've got the basic idea of how Android where apps work we're going to see how we can adapt
them to a different watch faces as well as making our first simple interactive Android web app.
So as we noticed in the previous video we've got something called a view stop here over in the main
activity java file and we can see it again if we look in the activity main layout file.
So if we look in the text version you can see we've got an android support wearable view which few Stabb
here.
So a stop is essentially a container which will contain.
In this case one of two layouts either the rectangular layout or the round layout and you can see both
of those are referenced here in the x m l.
So the stub essentially detect the shape of the user's watch and displays the rectangular all round
lay out respectively the rectangular and round lamps themselves are all pretty straightforward and full
of things that we're used to things like text views.
The one thing to notice which is different from what we've had before is that we can have the same ID
for a text free for example in the rectangular and the round layouts.
So here the idea of this text view is text and here it's also text.
So before we've had to have different ideas for every object but with Android where we have the same
ID.
Or we can have the same ID in the rectangular and round layouts than that so that we can in our code
access those user interface elements with a single find view by id rather than having to look for different
objects in the different layouts.
So as I say the stub works out which shape of watch we're working with and then inflates the appropriate
layout either rectangular or round.
You might be wondering how we establish in code which lay out we're working with.
And there's a number of different ways to do that.
But the simplest that I've found is to give layouts an ID.
So for example here we've got our linear layout
so I can give that an ID
of Rex
layout then with the round activity I could give that an ID of round lay out the once we've done that
we can detect which layout is in use by looking for for example find view by ID.
ID dot wrecked lay.
And if that's not no
then that means
we've got a rectangular layout
and if it is
then we've got round roundabout
with a T on the end.
So let's just give that a quick try.
We're running it's I believe in the
square I mean that's the one that we use most recently so we should see in the Lokes
rectangular layout when it launches.
And there we go just scrolling up there you can see a rectangular layout Ceiba.
So time for a quick challenge for you and this will be making your first interactive what you app is
going to be very very basic.
Well we're going to do is create a new project or a new app and we want a button on each of the layouts
which when the user presses it it shows them via a toast whether they've got a rectangular or a round
screen.
So not a particularly useful app one that will test to make sure that you've got the idea of how layouts
all work together.
OK.
So simple app with a button in the middle that when you press it it tells the user via a toast whether
they've got a rectangular or round watch go for it.
All right well I'm going to start Of course with the new projects
and I'll call it square or round.
Should you be rectangular around about square or round will the Android Wear link where activity and
the deeper options.
So here we go.
I'll start by putting in the button to the rectangular activity.
So it works in just the same way as normal Android development.
And for the square activity you can see we've got linear layouts here a vertical linear layout.
So by default the button will just appear immediately below the text there.
So I'm going to get rid of the text and just have our button.
There we go.
And because it's the only interface element we're going to have I'll call it button and I'll change
the text to show.
Watch shape.
OK click will also be show watch shape
and then because I want exactly the same button in the round activity I'll just copy the code from the
text of the SML and then pasted in.
In fact I can just replace the text view with it.
But I might do this time is dragging its to the center so that it's completely centered in the round
watch.
All right.
Now it's time to write it a little bit of code.
So the button had an enclave of show watch shape I'm going to get rid of the textfield now as we're
not using that anymore.
And then we'll create our method show watch shape
which just says with normal Android caused by a view the button
and then we want to detect what shape the watch has.
So I'm going to assume a rectangular shape.
So my message by default is going to be rectangular.
And then I'm going to go to the round activity
give the relative lap that an ID
of round lay out and then we're going to look for the existence of the round layout.
So if find V by ID Card ID dot round lay out is not now then we'll change message to round
and then either way we'll toast.
So create a new taste in exactly the same way as with normal enjoyed with the message.
There we go.
Simple as that.
Let's give it a go.
We'll start on the round device see if it gets it right.
And there we go.
So let's tap the show.
What shape button.
And you can see we've got round appearing there that that looks as desired.
Let's just go back.
Stop that and run it on the square
device and make sure that that works too.
And here we go.
So now of course the buttons at the top.
But again if we tap it we get the correct shape of the watch face excellent.
So that's the basics of how we create apps that display and work differently on different shapes in
the next video we're going to be building a rather more useful app called people counter.