OK then why well I'm of course going to start with a new project called it people counter and we'll
be creating it for where devices with a blank where activity
and every game I'm going to begin with the round activity and create out lay out that and I'm actually
going to keep the halo real world pattern but I'm going to change the text initially to the number zero.
And let's see if we can find a nice big
suitable textile and a quite big enough.
I don't think so let's go into full details and make Kerrin text size
twentieths pay.
So I'm going to change that to 40 Yes.
There we go.
And then I want to add in two buttons.
So we'll have a reset button at the top.
And we'll be if your properties to change the ID that back to reset button and the text to reset and
the on click method to reset as well.
And then the other element I want to add in is a button.
This one is going to be in the center and the bottom of the screen and this is going to be the one to
increment the count up.
So call it plus one button on click is going to be plus 1 and for the text I would just use plus one
like that.
OK.
So that's the layout for the round activity.
I'm going to copy
those three items in the text VI and then paste them into
the rectangular layout but then if we have a look they won't look quite right because of this vertical
layout that we have the linear layout.
So I'm going to change that to a relative layout
and get rid of the orientation.
And then let's have another look and you can see that looks much better.
So now what we said at the top and plus one at the bottom and the number in the middle
OK.
So now I have two main activity dog job and in fact we don't need to do anything here.
In the on lay out inflata listener everything's going to be in our own methods.
So let's create first the plus one method so public void plus one
will be called by a view.
And we're going to need a counter variable.
So I'll just call that counter which is initially 0 and plus 1.
Well that's going to add one to the counter and then we're going to want to update the label and text
to be
and set the text to counter.
But we're going to need to convert to a string.
Count that we get and then
we've got reset
which will simply set the counter back to zero and then take out X-Fi And once again set the text to
counter.
I could really just put zero in there as well.
And just before we run that we will need to set the integers to strings or integer dot to string
for each of those.
And there we go.
So we'll run that on the round watch fast and then we'll check that it still looks good and works on
the rectangular watch.
Obviously this is a relatively simple app compared to the sort of thing that we're used to building.
But the point is that we can build pretty much anything we want on the watch.
We could also build on the phones or all of the skills and techniques that you've learned so far in
the course you'll be able to apply to Android Wear as well.
So let's take a look.
Plus one excellence I can count as many people as I like them and then reset sets it back to zero.
So very very simple let's just have a quick check.
I'll stop that and run it on the square which emulates.
And here we go.
So again it looks good.
A quick check of functionality and wake it together.
Fantastic So I hope you enjoyed that one.
It should have been fairly straightforward for you in the next few videos.
We're going to dive into some of the more specific features starting with cons and then looking at lists
voice input and notifications.
So lots to learn.
I'll see you at.
Working with cards in the next video.