Firebase is a service owned by Google which is in many ways quite similar to pass server.
It allows us to do things like database storage authentication and also messaging notifications and
analytics.
Now while I'd recommend using past server if you just need the database features because that server
is self-hosted and so can't be affected by for example Google deciding to shut down firebase as Facebook
did with pass firebase is a great service and you might want to try using it.
It's also a prerequisite for using Google's AdMob platform.
So this idea I'm going to show you how to set up an app with the firebase.
And then in the next video we'll see how to add ads to a firebase app.
So first off we need to create an account on firebase.
So you get a file based on Google dot com and log in with your Google account and click get started
for free.
Firebase does have a pretty generous frita.
But of course you will need to start paying if you use large amounts of data so I'm going to create
a new project and I'll just call this firebase demo project
choose your country and then create project.
And there we go.
So we want to add firebase to our Android app and to do that we need a package name.
So let's quickly jump over to enter a studio and create a new project for this demo.
So we'll call it firebase demo app
and just in case you missed it there a package name it can be calm don't rub Percival dot firebase hap.
And I've been using Google that but will go down to a lollipop.
Doesn't really matter.
I will support more devices in this demo app and then set that up as usual.
And then we can jump back over to firebase
and say Come Rob Percival
fire base
demo app.
There we go.
If you want extra security you can use a signing certificate but we'll just use the package name for
now.
That then allows us to download a Google services Jason File which we can put in our app directory
which contains all the settings that we need to connect to.
Firebase.
And then as it says there we can just check and make sure that Google services don't tell you some is
in the right place it should be in the app directory.
So if we tap on project and then in the dropdown here at the top there select project expand that and
then we get out Google services as some file is in there.
So I'm just going to try Ragatz
inti the app folder
and there we go.
So now it's in the app folder in the right place
so well click continue.
And then we need to add two lines to how build cradles.
So first look at the project level build cradle.
This will allow us to use the Google services Jason File and the Google services that it uses.
So back to android and then open up the first build a cradle file for the project and then we'll add
in under dependencies.
There we go.
Com dot Google dot JMS and then Google services 3.0 point zero.
Obviously if that version number has changed then use the version specified by firebase and then we'll
add the plug in to the app level build cradle
so that so that when there so to the very bottom of the file we add apply plug in and then come Tokiko
that JMS Google services and then we also need to add the firebase modules themselves which we do in
the dependencies section here.
And we use compile and then come dot Google dot firebase and colon firebase core flybys hyphen core
and then nine point four point zero.
And we also need if we're going to be using the database which we will do just to check that everything's
working OK.
We use kohm.
Google doc firebase
colon firebase Ifan database colon.
Nine point four point zero.
And then we click sync now and that will add those plugins and dependencies to our app.
And now that it's done we can write a little bit of code in the main activity and we'll just write a
very simple bit of code which will connect to the database and save an object for us just like we have
on past server.
So to do this on firebase we start off by creating a database reference
which I'll call deep breath.
And this is going to equal the firebase database don't get instance don't get reference that will get
the database created as part of your firebase app and then we'll just create a simple map which will
link strings to streams and I'll call this values.
So it's just an object that we're going to store in the database.
And this is going to be a new hash map
then will set some values.
So values don't put on something like name Rob.
So we need and then to say that to the database we use D-B ref dot push and then set value.
And we can just use values like that that will save it in the database but we always like to have a
callback so we know it's been successful.
So we're going to create a new completion Lisner which just like with pass server gives us the default
uncomplete method.
And again we can do as we're reasonably used to something like a database error equals no
log
safe successful
else log.
Save failed.
There we go.
So you can see the logic is quite similar to the Passover.
One quick change we're going to need to make before we run that is to add the internet permission so
that uses permission.
Name Is Android permission dot Internet that we go.
So we'll run that on our device and as it's running I'm going to make a quick change on firebase now
the default on firebase databases is that the user has to be logged in to be able to save anything because
we're not going to go as far as user authentication in this small introduction to firebase.
I'm going to change those rules so I'm going to tap over there where it says rules and I'm just going
to change the not equal t t equals C
and then publish.
And that will mean that the user doesn't have to be logged in to read and write to the database
OK.
So let's have a look.
It's launching the activity.
And you can see save.
Successful.
So as with Percival Let's have a quick look back on the database and you can see we've got an object
that's an object ID and if we open it up you can see we've saves the name.
We're up super.
So if you want to go further with firebase then I just start with the documentation there and work your
way through creating some basic apps.
But we're going to go to look at how we can use firebase as a basis for AdMob.
I'm putting ads in our apps which is a great way of generating revenue particularly on Android and we'll
do that in the next video.