We're now going to move on from list views and look at times which will allow us to consider some rather
more complicated Android concepts such as threading handlers and Ronalds.
So don't worry too much about those.
We'll explain them when we get them.
But for now let's create a new project called time a demo.
So we actually saw Timon's a few videos ago in the previous section but we didn't look at them in much
detail so that they're very useful.
They allow us to delay the running of a particular activity whatever that might be and do it say two
or three seconds in the future which we're going to use a lot in the next couple of apps.
There are lots of different ways to make timers in Android.
I'm going to show you two of them here.
So one will be used primarily to run a certain bunch of code every second and then the other will be
used as a countdown to a particular event.
So let's jump straight over to main activity took Java because we're not going to be adding anything
to the user interface in this video.
So you guys are in on create.
We're going to start by creating a handler and I'm going to call it handler and it's going to be a new
handler
and make sure you use Android OS and Levante to get the right framework.
So our handler does a couple of things but one that's relevant to us here is allows chunks of code to
be run in a delayed way.
So possibly every second every five seconds every 10 minutes.
However you want to do it and the handler controls the timing of these events or chunks of code.
Now these events or chunks of code have names themselves and they are called runnable.
So we normally call them just run and say our run runnable is going to be a new runnable like that.
And you can see that we've got the default code set up for us.
So in here insert code to be run every second so it's overriding the default run method I can think
really of runnable as being methods that can be run every second or every five seconds or whatever.
So once you've entered your code that you want to be run every second you then have to give it instructions
to run that every second and it's the handler that takes care of that.
And what we can do is händler top post delayed and then we want to post this.
So in this context this refers to the Runnable here the run method and then the number of milliseconds
that we want delayed if we wanted to run every second then we wanted to be delayed every thousand milliseconds.
So we got quite a complicated chunk of code there but just to run through again what's going on we've
created a handler which can control the timing of certain methods.
We've then created one of those methods which has a special name called a runnable and then we've added
the code to be run every second and then we use the handler to run this again one second later.
So then each time this is being run it's being instructed to run again as a second later.
So this will essentially run every second say let's just do a simple log post
runnable has run
a second must have passed.
Simple as that.
And then we have to actually initialize the Runnable in the first place which we do in a very similar
way to how we made it run.
One second later we just use händler dots post and then run.
And that will then execute the Runnable right from the start.
And then as soon as that's run the first time then it will cool it's run the second time and keep on
going forever.
So let's take a look.
We should find now that this is posted to the logs every second
we run it in the emulator even though we don't actually need to open the emulator this time.
Everything that we're interested in will appear in the logs that we can so it's running every second
fantastic said that's more or less all we're going to say about cannibal's for now.
But I'm going to show you another way of
doing time as an android.
I'm just commenting that out so I won't run the second time.
The other useful way to do a task Reguly is to use a countdown timer so let's see how they work.
We'll create a new count down time up and then we need to give that to numbers which is the number of
milliseconds until the countdown has run out and the frequency with which we want the counter to tick
down.
So if we wanted to count down for 10 seconds then we would use 10000 for 10000 milliseconds for our
whole countdown and then 1000 for the time for each tick as it were.
So this is you are then going to count down from 10 seconds to zero or and then we add our code for
our countdown timer which is going to create two methods.
So the first is on tick.
So this will happen every time we get a tick.
So in our case every 1000 milliseconds or every second
and that will receive a variable which is a long which is essentially a big integer and we'll call that
milliseconds until done because that's what it is.
So this method here will give us this variable milliseconds until done that we can use if we want to
and the other method we can use is public FOID on finish.
And not surprisingly that will happen.
When the countdown is finished.
Whereas this one happens
count down
is counting down.
So in our case it will be every second and this will be off to 10 seconds.
They I'll just put in a semi-colon at the end.
So just to see what this is doing.
Let's just quickly log
this is going to give us seconds left and then we can get that from milliseconds until done Eva 1000
because that will give us the number of seconds left rather than number of milliseconds.
And then we will need to convert that to a string and we can do that using string and then dot value
of
and that will then convert our long to a string and allow us to log it.
And then just so that we can see how it looks.
We'll log
count down timer finished.
And then finally we just need to start that which we do using dot start.
So hopefully that makes sense what we've done there.
We've created a countdown timer that will last for 10 seconds and tick down every second and then each
tick it will log that.
And then at the end we get 3 to 1 and finally count on time a finished that we get.
And the advantage of this is the countdown time object is then destroyed when it's finished.
If you only need it temporarily then a countdown timer is probably preferable to using a handler like
that which will continue to exist even when it's finished.
OK.
So that's where we're going to do for now with countdown timers and handlers and run tables in the next
video.
We'll be using countdown timer specifically to make our time app so you can.