The final thing we need to learn about before making our notes app.
And a very useful technique in general is how to create an alert or kind of pop up window over the existing
app screen and that's fairly easy today.
So we're going to do it with a new project which will be an alert demo usual options.
And here we go.
So hungry working in main activity Java and we'll create alert in the uncreate method.
So it's fairly straightforward to set up an alert.
We use a new alert dialog builder
I'll go for the Android version.
The context is this i.e. the main activity and then we set all the options.
So we might start by setting the icon
and we'll use Android resources toward drawable dot and then if we use I see you can see there's a whole
range of icons there depending on what
you're last for.
I'll go for the dialog alert.
So this is just sort of telling them that there is something important to do.
Then we'll set the title of the alert.
So this is going to be one of those confirmation Alas that says Are you sure you want to do this and
then OK or Cancel.
So I set the title to.
Are you sure.
And then we'll set the message.
So this is a bit more information underneath the title.
I'll send that to you definitely want to do this
and then we'll set the positive button to have a text of.
Yes.
And then we're going to set an on click listener for this button.
I need to do something when the button is pressed.
This will be a new dialog.
Interface and see on click listener is predicted for us there.
So when the item is clicked for now we'll do a test
saying it's done of course nothing is actually done but that's where we would write code to do whatever
it is that the user has confirmed.
They want us to do.
And then we'll set a negative button.
Which will just say no and we're not going to do anything when the no button is pressed.
So I'm not going to have an on click listener for the negative button.
And then show who we are.
I do need to add in no just to say I don't want anything to happen when the no button is pressed.
Other than the dialogue to go away.
All right.
So let's give that a try.
And see what our alert looks like.
And here we go.
So there's a nice little pop up and you can see everything else is now darker and clicking elsewhere
makes the alert go away.
And then which is run that again.
See what happens when I click the Yes button actually clicking no.
Just make the alert disappear.
And here we go so that we want to do this.
Yes.
And you can see a nice menu.
It's done fantastic So that's how we do alerts.
I'm going to set you a quick challenge now to combine the menu adding skills.
The alert dialog build up knowledge and permanent storage going to create a simple language preferences
app which looks like this.
So when we first open the app we see an alert dialog asking us what language we'd like.
And then the purpose of the app is really just to save the user's language preference.
So if we choose for example Spanish then that is saved permanently and you can see selected there and
or just proved to ourselves that that is indeed saved permanently by closing down the app and opening
it up from the app drawer.
It is at the top.
And you can see Spanish has been saved.
So we've used the dialog and permanent storage but we've also incorporated the menu.
And now if we want to change our language we just tap on a new language and that updates there.
And once again just to prove to ourselves it is saving permanently if we open up the app again.
Then it saves that users preference.
So it combines everything we've learned so far in this section.
Time for you to build it for the video and if you go.
Best of luck.
All right.
I read that one well I'm going to start by beginning a new project
I'll call it language preferences and all the usual settings.
Lú wise it's going to be very very simple the only item in the
main screen of the app will be the text view saying what language we have selected.
So first off when the app is run for the first time we want to show an alert to the user to pick a language.
So that's one of those in we'll create a new alert dialog builder
around the main activity.
And we'll set the icon that we'll use Android or drawable Heisey and I'll go for Speak Now just for
a bit of variety.
We're talking about language
so we'll set the title to choose a language and then we'll set the message to which language would you
like.
I do realize it's not ideal to ask the user to choose a language in a particular language.
So you might want to add say a Spanish translation here but I'll leave it in English.
Keep things simple and then set the positive button which is just the right button to English
and we'll have a new.
Let's not and we're going to want to set the language to English here.
I think it would be useful to have a method to do that so that we're not duplicating code when we set
it to either English or Spanish.
So let's have a method called Set Language which will require a string called language.
And for now here we'll just set language to English and then similarly We'll set the negative button
to Spanish with.
I don't like Lessner which will simply set the language to Spanish and then we'll show how a dialogue.
OK so what we want to happen on the set language front.
Well two things really we want to save the language permanently and then display that on the text view
in the app.
So first of
all use shared preferences
you're familiar with this now.
So I put in the package name and context DOT made private and then shared preferences at.
Put string language and we want to set it to the language that has been set.
There we go.
So now with saved that permanently.
Next we want to just customize our layout very slightly.
I'll do that in the text VI again for a bit of variety.
So we'll have to set an ID for our text free.
I'll just call it
text free and initially I'll have it be empty.
And then over in my activity here we'll create a text field called Text VI which is going to be a text
view which we get from fine view by id thought Id text V and then will set our text view.
To have a value of
language.
Great.
Now I'll just run that to save time later.
You may have noticed the one issue we're going to have is that we don't want this dialog to pop up if
they've already set their language so
let's restore this from shared preferences and see if there's a value and we'll only display the alert
dialog if there isn't one.
So I could create a whole new shared preferences but that seems a little wasteful.
So what L.D.
is create the variable outside
the two methods.
And then I'll set it up in
on create and then we'll only need to set it up once
so then we'll create a string
language
and this will be equal to the shared preferences get string and the string we want to get is language
and the value if there isn't any value set will just be an empty string.
So then we'll test to see if
language is an empty string.
And if it is we'll to supply the dialogue.
All right.
So that should now behave as we want.
Except it won't display the menu part yes.
But let's take a look.
And here we go.
So we have the alert.
Excellent English and English is selected prelim.
Now one thing I have noticed is if the language isn't empty we should add
the code to update the text.
So again let's to avoid duplicating code will define the text view up there.
And then we'll set it up
in the create method so it will be accessible from anywhere.
And then
we'll just set the text of the text view to the language.
So now if we run the app again you should display the selected language
when the app starts and there we go.
No dialogue this time.
Just the user's preference.
Super.
So now the app is working as we want.
Except we want to have the option for the user to change the language later on via the menu.
So let's add in
directory
every go and then create a new menu file and call it something else if you like but I'll stick with
main menu
and then we want to add an item with a title of
English.
Whoops ideally spelled right.
And an ID
of English.
And then
copy and paste that
to give a Spanish option
great.
So now let's just add in
our own create options menu code which will require all menu inflator
which will call menu inflator and will create it using get menu inflator and then menu inflator inflates.
And we want to get the menu using our top menu top main menu and we want to associate that with this
menu.
And finally on options item selected
we want to run that code but not return it.
And then this time or use an if else statement just for variety's sake.
You're very welcome to use the switch is probably a bit neater.
So if item darte get item ID is equal to our DOT ID dot English.
Then we want to set the language to English.
And that was a capital A
and then else if item does get to my day is equal to our ID taught Spanish
will set the language
to Spanish this time again for variety's sake.
Return true for this app.
We're not testing what is returns that really doesn't matter.
It's neater in many ways to just return True but if you.
You could always return true return true and then return false.
If we get to the end of the method right so let's take a look.
We should now be able to update the preference with the menu and that of course will be saved permanently.
Here we go.
So we've got our menu tap on it will select Spanish.
That's been updated.
That looks good.
So let's use a double click to shut it down and this time I'm going to run it from the Android app draw.
So it will scroll down to find language preferences.
There it is and you can see the preference has been site wonderful.
So I hope you manage that but combined everything that we've learned in the last three videos they're
now going to build our first big app of this section and that is our notetaking app.