OK I'd like to discuss expert app screenshots strategies and with a favorite screenshot tool of mine
apps screenshots are just as important in the visual description of your app as your app icon.
Believe it or not for those not lucky enough to be featured or noted under new noteworthy then it's
your screen shots that your user will look at first.
After finding you in the app search results the user will base their decision on your first screenshot.
99 percent of the time the other 4 screenshots still need to be eye candy and matter but the first is
by far the most important here.
Please get a video.
No more than 1 minute long showcasing your app and have it next to your app store screen captures.
The video helps to get you more downloads.
Notice all the top apps have a video for their potential customers to click on and view.
Why is that.
Well people always love and prefer watching video over static pictures.
Screenshots are very important as far as the real estate goes along with your app icon.
Now with that being said you need to grab the attention of the potential user first and foremost.
Then you need to address what exactly makes your app different from your competition.
What makes it stand out in other words.
Lastly I want you to include a bonus or a coupon code to give them an incentive to want to download
your app.
That's like your call to action which you always need to do.
Now here are some tips for both Apple and Android.
I want you to localize your screen shots then try to add an explanation arrow or tips etc..
Always keep it clear and simple though and show what a user can do inside your app.
Highlight your most popular and most needed features here.
Don't bother showcasing splash pages here.
Show the inside of your app.
Also convince users that your app is exactly what you're looking for and always split Hastur apps screenshots.
So be sure to check out the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.