Let's talk about app category strategies the app category may be less important than your title or description
but that doesn't mean you can pass over it.
Please note that Apple will review your app and check to make sure you choose the best category that
really matches your app.
If not it will be rejected.
Sometimes the choice isn't very obvious so you can add your app to two categories so cycle through all
the different categories and choose the one that really fits your app the best.
If you're choosing two categories for your app compare the apps that are in the top five of both of
them and choose the group that has less competition and make that your primary category.
OK I'll see you in the next lecture.