So now we've got our background and our bird and our bird moves just how we want him to be up and down
like that wonderful.
The next thing to add is the chooks.
So here is a quick challenge for you.
Can you add the troops using top tube and bottom tube so that they are the top one coming down from
the top like that.
And the bottom one coming up from the bottom so that there's a certain gap in the middle of them.
Good luck.
I hope you managed it.
And here we go.
I'm going to start by creating textures for them so we can have a texture.
Called top tube and a texture called bottom and cheap multi all the cheap stuff together here.
So I took cheap he's going to be a new texture for cheap energy.
And bottom Chib is also going to be a new texture.
But of course this time from bottom cheap PLG
very good.
So now let's have them in and we'll add them here where the game state is not zero.
So the game is active.
So I will need to start a batch
then I'll just have the patch and come on there as well.
And then as before we need batched dot draw and the texture up I'll start with top tube.
Now let's think about where we want to put this so we want the x coordinate first.
So the top Choop we want the bottom left to be around here.
So if there's the center of the screen we want to shift it up by half of whatever the gap is going to
be.
So the gap between the two keeps there.
So if that is the center of the screen we want to shift it up by half of the gap and left by half of
the width of the tube.
So that will keep it central.
So we get the center of the screen which we get from GDX dark graphics it's get with.
So that's the width of the screen.
Divide that by two to get the center of the screen and then we want to subtract the width of the cheap
so that top Chib dot width get with divided by two.
So that's the x coordinates the y coordinates is fairly similar.
We're going to get the GDX graphics don't get height and we want to divide that by T.
And we want to add half of the gap.
Now the gap is something that we might want to alter to make the game easier or harder.
So I'm going to create that as a flight
and I'll start off with it at 400 and see how that works out.
So we want half of the gap there we go.
And we didn't specify the width and height because we can just use the full width and height of the
sprites themselves and then very similar for the bottom Chib.
So the x coordinate is going to be exactly the same.
So GDX dot graphics dot get with over two.
And we'll use bottom Chib even though they both have the same width.
It doesn't really matter.
The y coordinate is going to be a bit different because for the top tube we wanted the bottom left to
be around here for the bottom of the bottom left is actually going to be way off the bottom of the screen.
So we're going to want to get to the center.
Then subtract half the gap to move half the gap down and then subtract the height of the tube to take
us to the bottom left of the tube which is going to be way way down here somewhere.
So we get that using GDX graphics don't get height over to minus
captivity and minus.
Again the the height of the tube
say bottom Chib don't get hiked.
And just before we run that we're going to have one issue here and that is that the back ground is drawn
after the chooks and because the background is full screen that's going to be on top of the tubes so
you won't actually see the tubes at all.
So that's not great.
So what I'm going to do is actually begin the Bache
right at the beginning here and then we'll do the background first and then we'll just use the same
batch here to draw the troops.
So then we're drawing back ground first and then the troops and then the bird.
The bird is never going to be on top of the tubes anyway so it doesn't really matter.
But even if it was we'd probably want the bird to be in front of the tubes.
So I'm happy with that ordering.
So a quick summary there.
The order that you draw these in is the order that they will be displayed or lay it on the screen so
the later ones will be in front of the earlier ones.
Let's have a look.
And there we go.
There's out.
Wonderful.
So happy with that.
And I'll keep that distance as 400 for the moment when we play the game we might just tip it that looks
all right to me.
Now next thing we're going to need is to randomize the position of the Jews.
We don't want them to be central every time we want them to shift up and down.
The tricky question is how much do we want to move them up and down.
We want to use the full height of the screen really but we obviously don't want them off the top of
the screen.
I think what I'm going to do is consider this to be half of the gap and then say another hundred for
that bit there because we don't want that bit to be off the screen I don't think either.
So then the maximum amount that we want to move them up from the center point is going to be half of
the height of the screen which would take them right to the top.
Minus half of the gap and then the hundred for this top bit here.
So that was half the height of the screen minus half of the gap.
Minus one hundred.
So let's set that up.
So that's going to be maximum Shoup offset.
So the amount it's moved up and down and that's going to be a flute
and we'll set loops are actually want to set that up here.
And then we'll set it here as well so Max cheap offset.
As I said was going to be half the height of the screen.
So GDX graphics don't get height over to minus half of the gap.
So gap over to minus 100.
And then we're going to need a random number generator to generate a random gap.
So let's set that up and have a random random generator
bring that in.
So down here what I'm actually going to do temporarily is create a new random number every time the
screen is tapped and then we'll just see that it's it is randomly moving up and down.
But then will move that cage to some way better later on because we don't want to move the pipes every
time the screen is tapped.
In the final game.
So let's have a flight
cheap offset
and we're going to set that here.
So cheap offset
and we want a random generator.
I don't think we've actually set up a random generator so let's do that here.
It's just going to be a new random.
And then we want to create a flight from that random generator and remember random generator next float
creates a random number between 0 and 1.
So first off we want to not have a number between 0 and 1 but we want to have a number between a half
and minus a half because we're working from the center of the screen here.
So I'm going to take my random number generator and subtract not point five from it.
I need to specify that that nought point five is a float.
So that's the types are not a problem.
So now we've got a random number between 4.5 and mine is no point five.
We want to multiply that by the kind of scale factor as it were.
So remember we wanted our maximum value to be half of the top of the screen minus half of the gap minus
one hundred.
Now we've already got a half here because the maximum of this is 1 1/2.
So if we get the top of the screen that's GDX graphics don't get height and then subtract the gap.
So this will mean that if this has a maximum value of a half then the maximum value of the whole thing
is going to be half of the height minus the gap which is almost what we want.
But we wanted it to be half of the height minus the gap minus 100.
So we're going to need to minus an extra 200 there because remember we're multiplying by half here.
So this will give give us a maximum possible value of this time to a half months this times a half man
that times a half and a minimum value of the negative of all of that.
So in short we're going to go from the center of the screen and we're going to move up to around there.
So the top of the screen minus the gap minus 100 pixels OK.
So that's our Chib offsets.
So all we need to do is add that to each of the y coordinates here.
There we go.
So that will shift it up or down depending on whether the random number here is more or less than a
half.
So now every time we type that that should give us a new Chib offset so we should see these troops moving
up and down with each tap.
Let's take a look.
Here we go.
So first tap.
Excellent.
And then one before look at that they're shifting up and down perfectly and they're not going too high
and they're not going to look wonderful.
OK.
And there's my bet.
Right.
So I'm very happy with my chips.
The last thing that we're going to want these chips to do is move to the left side.
Let's set that up.
I'm going to create a cube velocity
and try this out.
I reckon H.E. velocity of 4 should work out about right and then we're going to need to keep track of
the cheaps x coordinate because that's going to change as it's moving left.
So I'll call that Choop X
and then initially we want to set Choop X to be this value here which was our initial x coordinate.
So that's cheap X now.
And same with this one.
And then let's see what happens if each time we decreased D-Backs by 4
and actually what I'm going to do is again reset Chib x each time we tap just so that we can bring that
back into the middle and get a good look at it when we want to.
Here we go.
So we'll tap and there it is moving.
And what I think is a perfectly good speed to the left wonderful.
So now we've got actually more or less behaving as we'd like.
What you're probably thinking is how are we going to create more than one cube.
Well the way I'm going to do it and as often the case is lots of solutions to these problems is I'm
going to have four sets of tubes so top and bottom and I'm going to move them from the right to the
left.
And then when they're off the screen to the left I'm going to change their x position so that they jump
back to the right of the screen and that will look like an unlimited infinite set of cheaps coming from
the right to the left.
But actually there's only four of them and I've chosen four just because if you were applying this on
a big screen then you might be able to see lots of cheaps or once on the screen we could probably get
away with three or maybe even two but I'm going to go with four just to be safe.
And I'm also going to put them half a screen with a part and if I do that then we shouldn't have any
problems with missing tubes or not enough troops to display to the user.
All right.
So let's have a couple more variables whoops up here.
So I'll have a number of tubes as a variable and that's going to be for.
Oh yes I forgot to actually use my cheap velocity here.
And rather than fix that let's call at Chib velocity great.
So the number of jobs is for.
And also distance between groups you don't have to put these up here but it just makes them very easy
to edit later on if you decide that the game is too easy or too difficult or you want to change it in
some way.
So here we can set up the distance between tube's as I said half the width of the screen.
So GDX art graphics don't get wet.
Divided by T.
OK now let's create these cheeps.
So some of these We're going to need to change them slightly so we're not going to have just one Chib
X now we're going to have four.
So I'm going to make this an array of flights.
And so this is going to be a new
float array with a size of four.
In fact we could use
size number of chips and it doesn't like that because I need number of cheaps to be an integer.
That's fine.
There's no need.
No reason it needs to be a float.
OK.
Similarly the offsets are going to be different for each pair of cubes.
So let's make there is an array as well.
OK.
So then down here we're going to set up our troops.
So I'm going to do this with a full loop so we'll have an AI which starts at zero.
It carries on as long as it's less than the number of troops and each time increments
say for each pair of shoes.
Initially we want to set their x coordinate and their offset.
So let's now bring our code out.
They just touch method and into they create method.
So instead of Choop offset now we're using Chib offset by
and some sheave X we want to be Chib Hex.
I and so that first one the offset that's absolutely fine as it is because we want each one to be random
but for this one we don't want each to have same x coordinates.
We want for now the first one to have that x coordinate because we wanted to appear in the middle of
the screen so we can see it straight away.
But later on we're going to want to add to that so that the first one is off the edge of the screen
but for each one we're going to want to multiply by the distance between the tubes.
So the first one is going to be in the center.
The second one is going to be half a screen away because distance between the tubes is half a screen.
That one's going to be a whole screen away and the fourth one is going to be one and a half screens
away.
All right.
So that should now create the necessary cheeps.
So let's now display all of those tubes.
So I'm going to copy this for a leap because I want exactly the same fully paid.
There we go.
And instead of Chib X we want you back I and Chewbacca I again.
And then we're still using top bottom cheap they don't change from one to the other.
But Choop X does.
So we're now working with D-Backs.
I and we also want Chib offset.
I rather than just cheap offset
OK.
So with any luck that should now display for us all with random offsets.
So up and down from the center and they should move steadily from the initial position to the left.
Here we go.
Let's have a look.
There we go.
Wonderful.
OK so I'm happy with that.
The one issue that you may have notice of course is that the tubes are disappearing.
They're moving to the left in them and not doing anything else.
As I said we need to do a check to make sure that when they get off the edge of the screen then they
are shifted back over to the right of the screen.
So we'll do this a check here.
So if Chib x y
is less than now we need to be a little bit careful we can't just use 0 because then it will magically
move over even when it appears on the screen there.
So we actually want to use minus and then the width of the top tube or bottom G-B doesn't really matter
which we use.
So that will make sure that it's off the edge of the screen because it will have gone to the coordinate
down here somewhere which is one tubes with to the left of the screen definitely will be fully off the
screen.
By this point.
So if that's the case we want to shift it to the right and to do that.
We're going to take Choop X Y and add to it well we're going to want for half screen with this because
that's the total distance between our troops.
But in the general case that's going to be a number of tubes multiplied by distance between ships.
So that should shift it over to the right the correct amount so that it can then come back in again.
And then if it's not off the edge of the cheaps of the edge of the screen sorry then we'll move it to
the left as we initially planned.
Okay well that's compiling.
I did think that perhaps the tubes were slightly too close together.
So let's just try changing that to instead of half the screen with would change it to three quarters
of the screen with just a C doesn't really matter.
But I think that'll make the game a little bit more playable.
OK so now we've got one t three four.
We're going to get another Chib we are.
There's the fifth one and Brillion.
So those chips are now coming thick and fast all the way
William.
So now we've got our troops we've got them hopefully a reasonable distance apart.
The main thing obviously that the game is not currently doing is any kind of collision detection.
So we obviously want the bird to see if it hits the tubes for the game to be over.
And that's what we're going to do in the next video.
See you then.