K now we're going to discuss expert strategies uncross promoting with others.
I don't advise you to use this strategy.
Why.
Think about it.
You really don't want to send people out of your app to another app because this winds up hurting your
social engagement which leads to lowering your AppStore ranking.
Therefore use this with caution if you do choose to do so for example.
So if you already have other apps available you can use them to promote the download of the new app
or use apps belonging to partners of yours.
There happens to be companies specializing in this type of cross promotion between apps.
They are known as cross-promotion networks C.P. and for sure a few are free and some are paid and you
can learn more about cross promoting.
Here at Flury apps circle and tap joy see the links at the end of the lecture Flury analyzes more behavioral
data from mobile apps than any other company.
According to Flury and they in turn help the app marketers build a high quality audience Flurry's serves
video banners and interstitial ads using the most advanced targeting technology in mobile today to increase
installs campaign Aro and retention across promoting your own apps is always free with Flury now interstitial
in this context means in between.
So it's an ad that is displayed before or after an expected content page.
Now tapped joy uses a fresh new way of engaging in mobile advertising that increases maximum value for
app developers while attracting new consumers through what's now called reward based advertisements.
This benefits the app developers consumers and advertisers tapped shoy was born in 2007.
This platform has since skyrocketed.
There are now more than one billion devices activated 450 million mobile customers and over 270 five
thousand plus active apps and 2 million plus ad engagements.
So be sure to check the recommended links below and I'll see you in the next lecture.