Hi guys and welcome back to this course on MLP.
I hope you are super excited because I am because finally we will be able to build on transformer and
the way we will do that is that we will implement our own very own translator just like Google Translate
for instance before we go into that's just a quick look at the plan of attack for this section first
we will have to deal with the data processing of course as always.
And after that we will be able to build the whole model starting with the whole embedding and positional
encoding phase that we saw earlier which is the first like the first step.
The first layer of the whole model then we will dive to the whole attention mechanism so first with
these scaled stack products which is the the core of this whole mechanism and then this will allow us
to build this civilly the multi attentional sub layer which will be the core for everything else.
After that we will write the code for the whole encoder.
Same thing will go for the decoder and we will finally be able to write the code for the for the transformer
that will be ready to to work and to be trained then goes this very phase like the training phase.
This will take about a few hours but no more.
And just believe me in a few hours you will be able to have a performing translator and we will see
that in the last phase the evaluating phase where we will give some homemade sentences to one translator
just to assess how well it performs.
So this was for the plan of attack.
Before we start coding of course we will need to get the data.
The data are used to take our a whole corpus of English sentences translate into French.
I picked this language because this is my native language.
It was of course easier for me to develop the the model and to assess how it works.
You can of course speak any language you want.
So I took the data from the euro Parliament's European Parliament that higher they have a really rich
corpus in many languages.
So you just have to take this in your favorite search engine and go to these websites stayed empty and
you see that right here they have a lot of pairs of languages.
So this one the French English one and once you don't know it it's all you have to do is to unzip the
whole folder and you will get those files.
The European poll English and the same one translated here.
So those are just the same corpus in two different languages.
Those two additional fighters don't come with those these four.
I will just quickly explain what they are.
These are just a quick lists of characters of words that are usually followed by points in the in the
language without being forced ups.
So what I mean by that is that you can sometimes find Mr. for instance followed by points.
That doesn't mean that it's the end of the sentence.
And later in the data processing the took an amazing face.
We'll have to split a sentence into several words and we don one can either to thing that each point
is the end of the sentence for instance if a sentence says that something happened at 10:00 a.m. this
this will be written a dot and dots.
This doesn't mean that those are full stops and that the sentence needs to end so this file we will
use it in order to pinpoint the points that are not full stops.
I will provide this file to you.
You can Don on this as resources or you can write your own if you use different languages even if you
don't use this Don where we are the performances will not be so bad it's just to increase the quality
of the inputs but doesn't make a huge difference.
Once you have all these files the best way to have access to your personal files in Google collab is
to go through Google Drive.
So just go to your personal drive megafauna with your data for instance former drag and drop all the
files here and yeah everything will be set up to start coding.
So now that everything's ready I hope you're super excited.
Let's start coding and see you soon.