Hi guys and welcome back to this tutorial.
We are finally here ready to evaluate options later.
We have build the model we have trained IT AND NOW LET'S SEE HOW IT WORKS.
Indeed we really have to do these spots because it good accuracy during the training doesn't mean that
our translator works well.
Quick story time while I was making these calls I spent almost a week trying to make this evaluation
part work because I just didn't know why.
But although I had great accuracy during training the translator didn't work well.
Whatever the input I gave him.
He just kept giving me a sentence with the same word repeated like 20 times.
And it's just that in the scale that product forgets the minus sign that was not supposed to be the.
And basically what he did is that's it multiplied the mask by zero instead of minus infinity.
So the Look AHEAD mask wasn't applied and the decoder allowed itself to have a look at the future words
instead of guessing them.
So that's just an example of why we really need to test the translator by ourselves.
So let's stop right now.
We will start by creating this this function evaluates which will take us inputs a sentence in the string
format and as output will give the translation but encoded so a sequence of numbers corresponding to
the took a nice version of the translation.
So let's define evaluates which puts which takes input sentence as inputs and that starts by encoding
this sentence.
So input sentence equals
a NISA English doubts and codes in sentence.
And as we have been doing this since the beginning we need to add the starting token and the ending
token so let's adhere vocab size
English minus one minus two so for the start tucking in here.
The cup size English minus one for the ending token last thing we have to do is to simulate the batch
dimensions so.
So let's create Inc.
Inputs equals T F tax expenditures in sentence along the first axis which is the axis that s corresponds
to the batch here we are with our encoder inputs.
Now we have to create the decoder input which will also be the output of the Dakota.
So output which is also the decoder inputs will at the beginning just
just be distorting tucking.
So capsize size French this time minus two just realized that there is a e right here.
And again we want to simulate the botching the budget process here we are.
Now what we want to do is to make several iteration of the transformer because each iteration of the
transformer will give us one new wood.
So as we so if we give the decoder a sentence of length let's say 10 we will get as outputs a sentence
of the same length but it will be shifted.
So the first word which is the starting token will disappear and at the end of the sentence we will
have the next predicted words.
So let's make a loop and we don't want this group to be longer than the max length that we decided before
so the Q all o output sentence would not be long longer than 20 words
we don't need to skip the index here.
So we don't care about that s just make a loop that will not be longer than March 10th and apply our
transformer to encode and call the input Dakota in goods which is exactly the same hour as our goods
its output of course something here and as we all know training right now we say forced to the training
perimeter.
So the job out is not applied here.
Now we have the outputs of the transponder which let's recap the dimensions here.
It's one for the batch size which gives one sake length which is the length of the output so far.
And the last dimension lookup size are for each element of the sentence so far we have a vector of size
vocab size and for a given index in the vocab size the higher the number the higher the probability
that it is the would we are looking for so as we said we just want to take the last words of this predictions.
So projection Q will be predictions that we only keep here the last words of the second dimension which
represents the sequence the sentence basically anyone to keep the whole vector so all the numbers for
each index in our vocabulary.
Now let's get the index of our next words the way we will do that is other said the higher the number
the higher the probability that is on next word.
So the tool we need to use now it's just an odd Max.
So predicted here will be t efforts our max of our prediction applied to the axis minus one because
this is along the last axis that we want to apply these hallmarks Max and as our indices need to be
integers we will cast this t after the costs to make sure this is in the right format.
So in thirty two.
Here we are.
We have the index of our next words.
So all we have to do is to add this new index to our outputs which are also the encoder inputs so outputs
equals T F dot com cuts outputs and predicted i.e.
in these concatenation is made along the axis minus one because outputs huge just the sequence of numbers
that represents our sentence there is just one situation we need to handle is that if all turns Fama
says that the translation is done it will just predicts the next token being the ending sentence stuck
in.
So there is this case that can happen if predicted i.e. these equals to vocab size F R minus 1 which
is the ending token for the French language then it means that the translation is done so we can just
right now return and return outputs but we don't want to return the output like this because we added
a dimension that was supposed to simulate the batch so we will just squeeze these firsts which just
means that we would get rid of the first dimension that doesn't represent anything useful for us outputs
axis equals zero.
So we get rid of the batch dimension.
Ok so here we are our output should be ready to be returned by the function so you just get out of the
soup and we do the same thing here.
Return return to efforts squeeze of outputs axis equals zero.
And here we are are evaluating functions that takes as inputs.
The string sentence and produces the encoding version of its translation.
Okay now we are almost done.
We just need our final wrapper.
If I may say so which will be these function translates takes a sentence as inputs.
This sentence being a string we can divert we apply the alternate function right here so we can get
our outputs as being evaluates of sentence
we want it to be and we all want it to be a 10 so we want it to be an empire array because it's easier
for us later to deal with it's just realized how those brackets we we don't know why.
So we have the outputs but as we said this is an encoded version of the output so we have now to decode
them.
Let's say that all predicted sentence is equal to take in either a French that decode and we don't want
to try to decode all of the numbers is among these numbers.
We will have other tokens like this talking talking so we will not decode the whole sequence.
We will loop over all our numbers for AI for AI inputs but only if I is lower than vocab capsize if
ah minus two.
So now we are sure that we only kept the numbers that corresponds to real words.
And now we are done.
So we just have to find and function with some fancy printing.
Let's remind the user what was the input.
So Prince inputs that formats and let's put the sentence the input sentence right here.
And finally we give the user the translation of the sentence he wanted to get
the formats predicted.
Sentence here out so it should work.
Guess you're ready to try outs this final version of our translator so let's go.
Let's see if it works well.
Let's try to translate.
For instance a simple simple sentence like this is a problem we have to solve.
For instance
is that the same mistake I did before.
Let's hope it's the only one
and of course I did the same thing like.
This is a problem you have to solve predicts in translation.
Set up a device with which is the perfect translation of this one.
Trust me if this is not your native language these words will well let's try another one.
This is really
sorry for what.
For too.
Let's try this one sit on this remote game of salt which is again the perfect translation.
OK so that's it.
We have a fully performing translator made from scratch.
Collect collected.
I was super excited to do this.
I remember a few years ago I was wondering how it was possible and I never thought I would be able to
do my own translator.
But here we are.
Of course it could be much better if you try some complicated sentences.
It might not be accurate.
But first the training phase was quite short.
I think this is something you can train for days and days and it was to improve.
Also are our data sets was maybe it would be light and quite biased because this is only Parliament's
discussions so a lot of aspects of language are missing of course.
So a lot of room for improvements if you want to play with it's just go.
We'll have a lot of fun trying to make it even better.
Hopefully it's have fun with this transformer and see you soon.