Hi guys.
And welcome back to this email because we are finally at the last parts of the CNN implementation which
is the evaluation parts.
So let's just see you right now how our model performs on new data.
So we will get results as being the outputs of D.C. and then that's evaluates.
And we will give these methods the test inputs this time.
So this inputs tests labels and we would give him the budget size the same we used for the training
so much batch size and we will simply print results to see the accuracy that we can get with new data
that haven't been seen before.
OK.
Perfect.
It's it's data that has not been used for the training but we still have the same kind of accuracy which
is 0 point 8 which is pretty good knowing that we can still improve the model by making an optimization
of the hyper parameters.
So that's pretty good but let's let's have a little bit more fun and try to well together sentimental
analysis on homemade sentences on own sentences.
So let's do that by calling our model on an A and B.
That's a great we will talk a nice sentence and input sentence and let's start with the really simple
one just to to try it like I love you for instance which of course for most of us should convey a positive
or positive sentiments.
So training equals false.
So we don't apply the drop outs and let's make it an end by so we don't get to tensor that is hard to
read.
Yeah.
All right of course let's run it again and we get s yet O point seventy three so that's of course positive.
So that's normal.
Let's try the the opposite.
Okay.
Very negative sentiment.
So that's that's also a good point.
Let's try with something a little bit more maybe complicated like I wish we'll never have to do that
again so we don't have of use words like like or love or hate in this one so let's see if you'd understand
that it's OK.
He definitely understand that it's a really bad thing that we don't want to to do something again in
the in the future.
So that's pretty good.
Let's try it last one.
You also funny OK.
That's actually really positive.
So I guess if if someone tells you that you are self funny it would mean that they are more into you
than say I love you.
That's interesting.
But anyway we had good results on the on the test data and it seems to work pretty pretty well on our
own sentences of course the data that we used is far from perfect.
It's just some tweets we don't have a lot of them.
It's a certain kind of language in a certain way.
As always for data sets and depends on what you want to apply your model to you have to get data that
fits your task or your purpose.
So be careful that that's.
But for just this example and just to show that our model works perfectly well.
This was a good data sets.
So anyway I hope you liked it and hope that you will have some fun with the model train with the data
all even the classification task that was it for CNN applies to MLP.
See you soon.