Hi and welcome back to this course on MLP.
I hope you are ready because we are about to write the most important part of our transformer which
is about the attention mechanism.
Let's just have a quick reminder of how it works with the paper.
So here on the right you can see the general structure of the melt head.
Attention layer that we will build later and here the detailed scale that predicts attention.
That is implemented right here.
If we remember well we have entries queries keys and values that each represents a sentence a sentence
of being a matrix.
Because at this points after the embedding we have the first dimension that corresponds to the sequence.
So the different words.
And the second dimension corresponds to the embedding so here is how these care product works.
I read the I wrote the mathematical formula right here.
So let's start writing the scales that predict function.
So let's define this one.
Def scaled dots projects attention.
We will have as entries the queries the keys the values and the mask Musk can be the Look AHEAD mask
which is the one that doesn't allow the decoder to see the next words all of the padding mask that we
will see later that masks the zeros at the end of each sentence so the first thing we will do is the
products that we see right here in the brackets.
So let's say that product equals T F that's much more queries keys and we don't forget to transpose
Trump sorry transpose B which means that the second matrix will be transposed equals through.
Now what we need before we compute this scale is to get the value of decay.
So we will call this keys team for dimension equals T F that casts T F that shape keys.
So we get the full dimensions of the keys and of course we take the last one because the last dimension
corresponds to the embedding.
And this is what we are looking for.
And we used to have that cast because we want this number to be afloat.
Now we can scale this project so scaled projects equals projects divided by T F that math.
That's as Q all t kissed him now there is the phase that we don't see in the formula but it's quite
clear here in the paper
these masks that they say optional because they don't consider that binding face.
But we will use the mask anyway.
But just to make sure we add this little condition if mask is not known.
So if there is a real mask to apply then the best way to apply this mask is to multiply by minus infinity
because we will apply a soft Max next.
And what a soft Max does is that it puts all the values of a vector between zero and one making sure
that the sum of all those values equal one.
And so before the soft Max if a number is really really low like minus infinity in theory it will become
a zero after the s Max.
And this is why we want to do because we don't want this process to pay attention to the zeros at the
end of the sentence.
So if after these scaled products we have zero it means that it will not have any impact later.
So applying minus infinity right now means after the off Max to have zero which means that there is
no impact later.
So we can't of course say that it will be equal to minus infinity.
But the way we do this is that we just add adds really low numbers so mask times minus ten to the nine
for instance.
This is a really low number and we are sure that after the s Max it will be equal to zero which is what
we are looking for now that we applied the mask.
Let's make the lasts mathematical computation TAF the math more and we want to multiply this results
from the soft Max.
So soft Max scaled projects and we apply the soft Max along the plus axis because when we will then
multiply it by V.
This will simulate many debt products.
And the important thing is that for a given vector V the vector we use in the left right here corresponds
to weights which means we want their sum to be equal to 1.
So that's why we apply this off Max along the last axis like that.
And this is multiplied by the values that we had as inputs who we are.
We have all sketched Doug for the attention function that is ready to be used.
So let's return the results.
Return
attention and that's it for the scale that product attention that is ready to be used for the military
head.
Attention sub layer.
This is exactly the topic of the next session.
So see you then.