Amazon Keyspaces is an Apache Cassandra‑compatible database service.
It has a lot of the same features as DynamoDB, so let's go through those.
First off, it's a managed serverless service,
so you don't have to install, maintain or patch softwares and servers.
You can also choose from on‑demand capacity mode,
which will automatically scale up and down to meet demand, or
you can select provisioned capacity mode,
which helps you optimize for price when you have predictable loads.
Whether you choose on‑demand or provisioned mode,
you'll get consistent, single millisecond response times whether you have
small or large datasets or high or low query volume.
Storage is also managed,
so you have virtually unlimited space, and continuous backups
enable point‑in‑time recovery, so if you decide you want to see
what your data looked like 10 days ago, you can do that.
Data is also encrypted by default.
Keyspaces is a good choice if you're looking to run your Cassandra workloads in the cloud.