Amazon DocumentDB is very much like the other services
we've covered in that it's a managed, highly available,
low latency, fault tolerant, self‑healing service.
You can easily scale the cluster up and down, there are continuous backups,
and you can encrypt the data with keys you generate
using Amazon Key Management Service.
The key feature is that DocumentDB is MongoDB compatible. This
allows you to use existing MongoDB tools and application code
with a managed cloud service. DocumentDB makes it easy to store,
query, and index JSON data.
This allows you to persist the data using the same document model
format used in application code without having to perform transformations every time you read or write data.