Historically,
ledgers were used to keep track of information that
needed a verifiable history of changes.
For example,
a financial account could just show you the current balance, but what
if the balance was different than you expected?
You'd want to know what happened to arrive at that
current balance or what was the history.
While far from foolproof,
older ledgers employed a few measures to preserve data integrity.
For example,
writing in pen instead of pencil made it difficult to remove or change an entry.
The books were usually locked up in a safe when not in use.
The handwriting style of different individuals could sometimes,
but not always, be detected, so if an unauthorized person tried
to change the books after hours, it could be easy to detect.
Modern systems no longer rely on handwritten books as
systems of record, but how can you solve the problem of
data integrity in cloud systems?
Some systems create audit logs using a traditional database.
These can be error prone, hard to scale, and they are not immutable.
Given the right conditions,
the data could be changed or deleted without detection.
Blockchain solves the immutability problem,
but adds additional overhead since it operates on a
decentralized model best suited to maintain a single
record for multiple untrusted parties.
Amazon Quantum Ledger Database, or QLDB, is a fully‑managed ledger
database owned by a central trusted authority.
By using a central trusted authority instead of a decentralized model,
QLDB can perform operations much faster than other blockchain networks,
making it easier and less resource intensive to scale, in
addition to providing predictable completion times for
operations. As a managed serverless service,
you get automatic scaling, high availability, and continuous backups.
QLDB has a document data model that allows you to store structured or
semi‑structured data that you can then query using particle,
which is an open source SQL‑compatible query language. QLDB creates an
immutable and transparent ledger of every change to your data.
In other words, every operation is stored and cannot be changed,
and you can view the entire history at any time.
That history is cryptographically verifiable,
meaning you can always verify the integrity of the ledger
and detect if something you're looking at is different than
what was recorded in the ledger.
QLDB is a good fit for financial, manufacturing supply sourcing, chain of custody, and other system of record applications.