If you have a database in production,
you're also going to need databases in test environments.
Some important requirements to consider when you're designing your test
databases include freshness of data from production.
How up to date does your test database need to be?
This will determine how often you need to refresh
data or rebuild your test database.
Completeness of data.
Do you need a test database that's the same size as
production or can you validate features with a small sample
of production data, for most cases,
then only use a full copy of the database for
performance‑related testing? Time to build.
Are there time constraints for refreshing or building your test databases? Does
your design meet those time constraints? Cost, how much do you have budgeted
for test databases? Scaling down instance sizes,
using less data, and automatically shutting down instances
outside of testing hours are all strategies to manage cost with
test databases. Finally, complexity.
How complex is your solution to create and maintain test environments?
Sometimes organizations are willing to compromise on other requirements
in order to reduce the complexity of the solution.
Amazon CloudFormation allows you to model and provision groups of AWS
resources by treating infrastructure as code, or IaC.
This helps you know exactly what is provisioned and how it's configured.
Since its code,
you can make new versions to track changes as your infrastructure evolves.
CloudFormation is a great way to automate the creation and maintenance
of your database environments, and in particular,
test environments that need to be frequently refreshed and
rebuilt. By provisioning your database and supporting AWS
services in CloudFormation,
you can ensure consistency across test environments and even make it
possible for developers to quickly and easily spin up their own copy of the
database. When they're finished using it, CloudFormation makes it easy to
tear down all of the resources that were created so you're not getting
charged for things you aren't using.
Excellent! You've seen some of the database migration
tools that AWS provides and supports,
including Amazon Database Migration Service,
AWS Schema Conversion Tool,
and then you also have the option to use native database tools.
If you have large amounts of data to transfer,
you can leverage AWS Snowmobile or Snowball to speed up the process.
You saw the importance of ensuring your migration meets any downtime
or maintenance window constraints,
and you also reviewed some important constraints to consider
when designing databases for test environments,
including freshness, time, cost, and complexity.
Finally,
you saw how CloudFormation can help you represent your infrastructure
as code so you can automate database deployments and ensure
consistency across your database environments. Join me in the next module where we'll discuss managing and operating databases.