Performance is going to follow a similar theme as monitoring and
troubleshooting, in that depending on your database type,
you're going to have different options available to you for performance
optimization. For instance‑based database services, simply increasing
your instance type or size adds additional CPU,
RAM, network, and disk capacity.
In some cases,
this strategy of increasing instance size is about as complex as you
need to get in order to meet your performance needs.
For many managed services, you can choose from on‑demand capacity mode,
which will automatically scale up and down to meet demand, or
you can select provisioned capacity mode,
which helps you optimize for price when you have predictable loads.
With provisioned mode, in some database types,
you can experience errors or delays when you've exceeded
your provisioned capacity. Depending on your application,
this may or may not be a big deal,
but it is something to be aware of when choosing a provisioned mode.
Another performance consideration is to determine if you're database is
read‑heavy or write‑heavy, meaning, are the majority of query operations
performing reads of existing data or are queries writing new information
to the database? For read‑heavy databases, the option to add additional
read replicas can help lighten the load on your database. For write‑heavy
databases, you may employ sharding to distribute the load across machines.
Let's take a look at each of those strategies,
keeping in mind that there is some overhead associated with both
read replicas and sharding, so be sure to test and verify the
benefits for your particular application.
You can think of a read replica as the same data copied to multiple machines.
A read replica contains up‑to‑date information for the database
and is only used to process read queries, so nothing is written
directly to these instances, they're all updated from the same
source database. For example,
if your overall system is experiencing 1000 queries per second and
you have four read replicas to service the load,
then each read replica can effectively handle only 250 queries per second,
instead of a single instance handling all 1000 per second. Depending on
your database performance, distributing a smaller query volume across more
instances can lead to faster response times than letting a single instance
handle all of the load. For some database services, adding read replicas is
a fairly simple process,
so understand how the database service you are using handles read
replicas if that is something you may need. You can think of sharding
as copying different data to multiple machines.
Sharding involves splitting the database across different machines
based on a shard key in order to distribute the load.
The idea is that if you have 100 queries trying to write to the database,
what they are trying to write will be in different parts of the database,
residing on different shards on different machines, such that no
single machine has to handle all of the load.
How you partition or split up your data can have a
drastic effect on performance.
For example,
a poor partition strategy could actually make performance worse by
sending the majority of traffic to a single instance rather than
distributing it across multiple instances.
Depending on the database type you use,
you may need to define partition and sort keys,
so be sure to understand first,
your data, what attributes most evenly divide up that data into
fairly equal parts, and second, access patterns, how does your
application read and write data,
and are there predictable patterns you can use to optimize your database setup?
Indexes are another key part of database performance. Again,
depending on the database type,
you'll have different indexing options, but the general idea of indexes is to
identify common operations and make those faster to execute by performing some
work ahead of time in building and maintaining an index. For most systems,
indexes will also take up more disk space,
so that is a trade‑off you may have to consider when creating indexes.
Speaking of disk, for database types that allow you to choose disk type,
there are definite performance implications.
Let's look at the different disk types available. Elastic Block Store, or EBS,
Elastic File System, or EFS, and Instance Store.
We'll talk about the features of each, but again,
depending on the database engine you're using and your application,
some of these may perform better than others.
Elastic Block Store,
or EBS, is the most common type of storage for EC2 instances, with
some instance types operating on EBS only. With EBS,
you can create an SSD‑based volume or an HDD‑based volume.
SSD‑based volumes are divided into two categories.
First, general purpose.
These are a good mix of price and performance for many types of
transactional data, and are the default EBS volume type for EC2
instances. Based on volume size,
you will be allocated a certain number of IOPS that are burstable
beyond the limit for a short period of time,
but may be throttled down to your allocated limit.
Second, provisioned IOPS. These are best for latency sensitive
transactional workloads, where throttling IOPS would be problematic
for your app, like a transactional database.
To get the highest performance from provisioned IOPS,
the volume must be attached to an EBS optimized instance type.
HDD‑based volumes are also divided into two categories.
First, throughput optimized.
This is good for frequently accessed throughput intensive
workloads with large data sets and large IO sizes.
Second, Cold HDD.
This is the lowest cost volume designed for less frequently
accessed workloads with large cold data sets.
Elastic File System, or EFS, is a managed NFS file system.
It's highly available and scalable, and automatically grows
and shrinks as you add and remove files.
This automatic scaling allows you to pay only for what you actually use,
whereas with EBS,
you must allocate all of the space you think you will need to a volume,
and you pay for the size of the entire allocated volume
whether you fill it with data or not, and whether it is running or not. With EFS,
multiple instances can access the file system at the same time, but again,
this may or may not be a good fit for your database engine,
so you'll need to verify that for your application.
Finally,
some instance types include instance stores. An instance store
provides temporary block‑level storage located on disks that are
physically attached to the host computer.
Instance stores offer some performance improvements for
frequently changing data, like buffers,
caches, scratch data, and other temporary content that is
replicated across a fleet of instances.
These are definitely used to optimize some database applications.
Data in an instance store is ephemeral, or,
in other words, it only persists during the lifetime of an instance.
If the underlying disk drive fails,
the instance stops, or the instance terminates,
then the data in the instance store is lost,
so make sure you have another source outside of the
instance store for persistent data.
Note that for instance reboots, the data is preserved.
Congratulations.
You've seen monitoring options,
including CloudWatch and some database service specific
tools like RDS Performance Insights.
You've seen a variety of common database issues and how those may vary
depending on the database service you are using.
You also covered several performance optimization strategies,
including increasing instance size,
provisioned versus on‑demand mode, read replicas and sharding,
partitions and indexes, and different disk types available based
on your performance requirements. Join me in the next module, where we'll cover applying database security.