Well come back in this unit we're continuing to work on your camp.
But we have some important features to work on.
So I think in my opinion this is where things really start to come together.
We start to integrate full crud for campgrounds and comments.
Plus we start to add in user authorization which we haven't talked about yet and we get a lot more complex
logic going.
So let me show you.
Our end goal now.
So I have a version open here.
I only have two campgrounds in here for now but there's a few features I want to highlight.
First is that if I sign up under a new account first of all we've now styled the forms a bit.
So we'll be getting to that soon and I'll sign up as carrot face and password.
As always it's just password.
First thing you might notice I get a little message now successfully signed in.
Which is great.
I'll show you how to do that.
And if I were fresh that message goes away.
So it's what's known as a flash message.
I see it one time but I don't constantly see it.
The other thing I'll show you is that we have two campgrounds and for each one currently there are no
buttons that say edit or delete campground.
And that's because this campground was created by Charlie Brown not carrot face.
If I went and added a new campground or use this image from an splash and we'll call this grassy plains
or something like that.
So Grassi and hit submit and we check out grassy plains.
You can see I now have the option to edit that campground and I don't have that option for anything
else that I didn't create.
However I'm signed in as right now so I'll add in some exclamation points.
Click Update and you can see that it updates.
So we'll be working on that.
And we'll also be working on doing the same thing for comments and we'll also be working on updating
our landing page so that it looks a little bit nicer.
And we also have this fade effect where it changes background images every five seconds.
The first thing that will do is focus on campgrounds edit and delete.
So I'm actually going to stop this server.
This is the solution.
I don't want to be working in there so I'm going to back out and we're working inside of the 10.
So CD into 10 and then I'll show you what we have right now.
Start the server and the fire fresh.
We have four campgrounds.
No edit buttons no delete buttons we can add a comment.
Do you need to be signed in of course.
We don't have a styled form at all or landing page needs work.
So we have we have some stuff to do.
But as I mentioned these next few videos is where I think stuff really starts to come together.
We start to give our users a better experience where it kind of goes from being a silly toy.
I didn't say that but but maybe some people might think it's a silly toy up to something that's a little
more useable and a little bit more legitimate.
So in the next few videos we're going to be working on a bunch of features starting out.
We're going to add in credibility for campgrounds.
Right now we have our campground index page right here.
We have a show page.
We don't have update and edit and we don't have destroy.
So that's what we'll be doing to start.
And then we'll work and go at the permissions or the authorization after the fact.
So to start.
Anyone can delete any campground.
Anyone can update any campground.
Then we'll go and fix that afterwards.
OK I'll see you in the next video