OK so I have one more exercise here and this one is optional.
It's only if you want some extra practice with numbers and strings and doing some simple math and prompts
and cancel that log the way that it's going to work.
It's a age calculator that asks you for your age in years.
So like 50 and then you enter 50 in and it will tell you roughly how many days you've been alive.
So it's very simple logic.
It doesn't actually account for what day you were born on and what month it is or report year it is
now all that it does is take the number that you give it like 50 and multiply it by three hundred and
sixty five.
And if you want to get fancy there's a simple way to include leap years that also in the solution.
So here's a quick demo of how it works.
I'll refresh the page and it starts by asking me for an age.
So enter 5 and then it tells me five years.
It's roughly one thousand eight hundred twenty six point to five days.
And that's it.
So go ahead and give this one a shot and then I'll be back with the solution.
And just a few seconds