For your for loops problem said I'm going to have you do the exact same problems that you did for the
wildlife's except you're going to rewrite them with four loops.
And the reason I'm having you do this is not because I'm having a hard time thinking of other things
to write with loops but it's important that you can translate between the two.
We're going to use both of them throughout this course and in a lot of cases you can use one or the
other.
So I want you to be able to translate.
So for this exercise it's the same exact problems.
Just use a for loop.
So just to jog your memory on the actual problems so you should have four different sections in your
output separated by a consul dot log and the four sections correspond to the four problems.
So the first one print all the numbers between negative 10 and positive 19 the next one print all the
even numbers between 10 and 40 and then all the odd numbers between 300 and 333 and then all the numbers
that are divisible both by 5 and three between the number five and 50 which we see down here.
OK.
So go ahead and give this a shot and what do the solution in the next video.