OK.
So it's time for another exercise here.
This time we're doing something slightly different.
I'm going to give you a bunch of data for Pokemon.
Actually the three starting pokemon for the original Pokemon games does not matter if you have no idea
what I'm talking about.
If you absolutely hate Pokemon doesn't matter I'm giving you the data.
Basically we're going to take this data and you're going to turn it into a table like this.
So this table is a chart.
It has an image for each Pokemon and name a type and what each Pokemon evolves into.
So for instance Bulbasaur looks like this.
He says she is a grass slash poison Pokemon and bubble saur evolves into Ivey's or and this is a link
to the Ivy store poker decks or Pokemon Wiki Web site.
So again if you have no idea what those words mean at all that's fine because you have all the data
.
So this is more about taking the data that I'm giving you and translating it into a table.
So again the data we have a name we've got an image you are l we've got type and then evolves to is
both a name and a you well remember to make a link.
You need some text to show up but you also need the whole row that you're linking to.
All right.
So go ahead give us a shot.