OK so the next thing that I want to do here is actually get us building our own forum so I can go ahead
and open up sublime.
I have a new file.
Call it whatever you want.
Mine is formed that HMO going to add my skeleton in their boiler plate.
Give it a nice title like form demo and then I want to start.
Remember we have the form tag and then we have the input tag.
We start with the input so let's play around with some input tags first.
So let's just add a few here will do text.
What color is my favorite Let's try radio and let's do password and say that let's go ahead and open
it up in Chrome and you can see we have four different inputs.
So this is text.
This is color.
This is a radio button.
And this is password.
So again you can always go to M.D and to see all the possible options for inputs.
It's quite a few.
But what we're going to go ahead and do is build the simple log in form that we've seen.
So although we really need there are these two inputs text and password.
And then we're also going to want a button and we have a few choices for buttons.
We can do this create a button tag and click let's say submit here.
But what can also do is make another input with type equals submit and you'll see the refresh.
They look identical and they're not going to do anything in this case.
So we have a user name which is what will go here and then we have our password but it's not really
clear to a user just someone who's encountering this form for the first time.
So there's a nice attribute called placeholder that we can add and what placeholder will do.
It takes some text so I'm going to go ahead and add placeholder ECOs username placeholder because password
and it's just going to be the text that is temporarily filling the input before the user alters it.
So we end up with a small typo here place holder.
We go we end up with username and password.
So let's go back.
I'm just going to add and each one here just say log in.
Here's our form.
Although technically it's not a form yet it's not a foreign tag it just looks like a form to us.
It's two inputs.
Let's go with input.
Type you submit just so that we can really hammer home this point that the type attribute can drastically
change what input does