OK.
So it's time for yet another exercise here.
And in this video we're going to work on creating a tic tac toe board as you can see over here on the
left and this board obviously doesn't do anything.
We can't do any logic there and actually complete the game until we get to the javascript unit.
So the first thing that we need to do is talk about how this is actually structured.
So I'm going to let you try and do this on your own but the first thing that I want to show is that
this is a table here.
So this is a table with three rows and then in each row there are three tiers.
So one two three four five six seven eight nine.
And then what we've done is given them a whit of 100 pixels and a height of 100 pixels and then we've
selected we turned on the border.
So for these middle elements there's a left and a right border left right left right and then for the
short the middle horizontal elements there's a top and bottom border top and bottom top and bottom.
So I want to let you try and do that on your own first and then in the next video we'll do a solution
as we go over together