All right welcome back.
So we're going to go ahead and get signed up for cloud nine and set up our initial environment so I'll
click on sign up on the cloud 9 home page and then I'll fill out the information here.
So I'll do learn with Colts and my e-mail here learned with Colts at gmail dot com and then I'll put
in my password here and then we'll click on I'm not a robot.
And then we need to select all images with pizza.
I think that's it.
There we go.
Not a robot.
And now we'll create our free account.
The next thing you'll need to do is check your email and click on the verification email that they send
you.
And then once you've done that we can go to our dashboard.
This is our dashboard here.
We can upload a profile picture and we can also look at a demo project that they've given us.
So I'm going to just look at that for now.
We're not going to touch anything or we're not going to make anything new here.
So now that it's floated Let's take a quick tour of some of the features.
So they have a little read me file that explains a few things but the first thing I'll show is that
on the left side we have a file tree.
These are all the files and directories that we currently have on this demo project workspace.
So if we wanted to you could click on Ruby and here's a ruby file and I can double click and that will
open up the file here just like if I had dragged the file to Sublime Text.
So this is one way to open a file.
We'll also be learning how to do it from the command line.
Later in the course which brings me to the next point which is the command line down here or the terminal
is here so we can resize this window and this is our terminal where we'll type terminal commands.
So one of them is clutter.
And what that does is it just clears everything away.
Just like clear does in the javascript console although this is not Javascript.
So I can type commands in here.
We'll be talking about some of the more important commands in the next few videos.
But for now just know this is our terminal we can type terminal code in here start our server run our
apps.
And this is our file tree over here.
And this is our text editor.
So this is sublime basically that's all we're going to do with the demo project.
So let's close out of that.
Now let's click on Create a new workspace and then we'll give our workspace a name so I'll do web dev
.
Boot camp just like that and we can give it a description if we want and we'll keep it public and then
all that we'll do down here is select node.
So this is a template which will give us all of the tools or almost all of the tools that we're going
to use preinstalled.
So when we click Create workspace it's going to take some space on a machine somewhere else a computer
and the server and it's going to install node.
It's going to install some other tools something called NPM that comes with node and we'll have it all
ready for us in just a matter of seconds.
So I'll click on Create workspace
and there we go.
We now have our own web development environment set up and that's it.
And if we wanted to check that it works correctly.
Let's open up the terminal and make it a little bit bigger and what we'll do is in here let's type a
simple command node dash V and all that this will do is ask node which is one of the things that it
should have installed for us.
It will ask node what version it's currently on.
We can do the same thing with another tool called NPM dash VI which is again asking for the version
.
And as long as we see something here then we're good if we saw something like.
Command not found node or command not found.
NPM then that would mean that they're not installed.
But this shows that they are installed for us and that was you know a matter of one click two clicks
maybe.
And we waited a second or two for our environment to get set up and we're good to go now.
So this is all we need to do actually.
One more thing that will have us do so that we are all consistent in our folder structure is I'm going
to go ahead and delete these folders here so we can right click click on delete and click on yes and
we'll just delete all of them inside of webdav boot camp.
So we'll delete again yes we'll delete this file package that Jason
do that for the read me file just like that and then will also delete the server file.
Don't worry we'll be creating a bunch of new files and folders for every lesson that we do.
So that's all we needed to do.
We now have everything set up that we need or almost everything will have to install a tool here or
there as we progress.
But we have everything we need to get started.