Hello everyone and welcome to the low serving section throughout this section we are going to talk about
tens of flow serving which is one of the most powerful libraries out there to put a deep learning model
into production.
It is going to handle a lot of stuff in the background for us and we are going to leverage that power
to create image classification API and put it in production using this library.
It is extension of the terms of flow library itself which makes a lot stop easier.
Let's take a few minutes to talk about the library.
The first question we need to answer is what these tens of low serving as I mentioned the tens of flow's
serving is an extension of the terms of flow library.
It is there to provide a multiple services around the model itself.
For example comparing all models version control of the models A B testing and many more putting model
in production can be really complicated but to overcome this problem we are going to use terms of flow
serving library after we train our model that has a flow serving is there to provide all around the
model which is much bigger than the model itself how it all comes together and how it works will be
much better explained in the code where you will see all the magic happening but the highest level overview
is like this on the one side we have a train model it could be any model that we train so far in the
course then we have a tensor flow serving the library that takes that model and creates a whole infrastructure
around it and then we have an application on the other side.
Some other developer came and has written a Web application or a mobile application and the middleman
here between you and that developer is the tens of low serving it creates a very simple connection between
a user facing application and a model that we trained let's explain what these tens of low serving in
more detail is all of the client server architectures we have the client side which could be a web application
mobile application or even an I.T. device.
On the other side we have a server which is here to handle a hard core stuff that couldn't be handled
on the client side.
What you see right here is an overview of the task that we are trying to solve in this module of course
we have a certain picture of a dog and we want to put that image of a dog for a model which is located
on a server and only thing that we expect from a server is a prediction is that a cat or a dog what
we need to do on the client side is we need to take a picture create a request of it a boss request
since we are sending some data to the server and that's all what we have to do on the client side on
the server side.
However it is going to take that picture from the request and put it through the model and spill out
some prediction after that's done.
It is going to send those prediction in the form of a response to the application and that's all what
we have to do as you can see it is not that complicated because the developers from the tens of low
serving handled a lot of stuff for us.
Therefore you will see that at the end of the day it is very straightforward to make a very cool scalable
service of your model in the previous section of the course.
We put the model in production using flask framework or the python.
It worked and it worked really well.
Why do we need a tender flow serving instead of a flask.
For example since it is a much simpler to be honest than the tens of low serving well scalability is
a very big issue when it comes to the flask.
It is made to handle some things but when it comes to millions of users it is not good.
It could be good but we would need to write a lot of stuff from scratch.
It is a bare minimum to put something on the web scalability is not an issue in the terms of flow serving
it is made for us to handle millions or even billions of requests.
Google is using it daily for multiple of their products such as Google Translate Google Maps and so
on due to its scalability and its use for millions or even billions of requests.
It is a must to have a low latency in parallel.
It can serve multiple clients and that is not what flask is able to do.
These are two major issues flask cannot handle natively and that's why to flow serving.
Is there on the other side.
We have the issue of handling multiple models flask is capable of doing that.
It is not that difficult to make it work.
But scenes that tend to flow serving is made for that use case as well.
That is one more advantage of the terms of flow serving over the flask.
Apart from everything we mentioned so far that tells a flow serving also handles multiple versions of
the same model.
It could be pretty messy to handle.
Free models for free different tasks that has 10 different versions of each model.
As I mentioned before flask is capable of doing that but not on the same level as it has a flow serving
I would say that these four are the main advantages of the tens of close serving in the next three days
or we will focus on the explanation of the tender plus serving architecture if you have more if you
have any questions or comments so far.
Please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen a nice tutorial.