Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the last week.
So we loaded our data set for Apple stocks.
But now before we proceed to the training gloop let's define the model in a few hyper parameters to
use the first hyper parameter is the window size.
Let's define window size is equal to 10.
That means that we are going to use 10 previous days to predict the current one in the previous sections.
We used word epochs and in the reinforcement learning that is same as episode.
So we need to define how many times we are going to run for the whole dataset or the whole environment.
In this case we'll say episode is equal to 1000.
The algorithm is going to run very slowly.
So we want to wait for all of them to pass then we'll specify 32 for the batch size and in the end with
data samples is going to be equal to land on data minus one.
Since we are trying to predict the next day we can't use the last one.
So let's say you look at the cell and our hyper parameters are defined.
Now it's time to define our trade there but let's call it trader and that is going to be equal to our
class.
A trader if you remember it takes a lot of arguments.
But since we defined the action space to be free as default and the model name to be a trader by default
we won't change that so only thing that we have to specify is the state's size.
And for us that is our window size execute a cell and it is going to take some time to define the model.
And here we go.
We are ready to go to the next step.
Let's track the model structure before we end this year.
To do that.
Right.
Trader dot model and there's always dot summary execute a cell as you can see we have three layers as
we defined 30 to 64 and 128 units the output layer has only three units for our by stay and sell actions.
And that's our model in the next video we are going to start by defining our trading loop.
It will take two videos because the code is a bit longer but it is going to be very exciting to videos
if you have any questions or comments so far.
Please post them in the comments section otherwise I'll see in the next tutorial.