Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In the previous video we have completed the setup process of our environment and install all dependencies
for this project.
And in this video we are going to input all of them input our data set and prepared for tens flow transform
library.
But before we jump into data set pre processing stage of this video let's talk about the few libraries
that we are going to use for this project.
The first one is temp file which is a native title library that we don't have to install and its job
is very simple creating temporary files for logging purposes then we have pandas.
And as always we are going to use it for loading and working with CSC files the first library extends
the flow.
We will use it to create some variables then we have our tensor flow transform and this tends to flow
transformed.
Beam is here to create context for Apache beam.
That is a great thing that is happening in the background for us.
The Apache Beam is a whole infrastructure of tools that are used for faster computation and pre processing
since it is very complex.
We are not going to talk about it in this course.
The tensor floaters forum is using that in the background.
That's all what you have to know so far but I'm going to provide a few links for you.
So if you're interested in learning more about Apache beam to use it in your day to day project besides
the flow transform you're welcome to use those links then we are going to input from the future.
Our brain function if we are using Python do it is more suited for us to empower these so we can use
a simple brain function from the Python free as well.
And lastly we are going to import a few things from div dot metadata the data set metadata to create
meta information about data set and the data set schema which will help us in that process.
We will discuss that in further detail down the road for now execute the cell and now we have all dependencies
at our disposal the data set that we used in the previous section is the one that we are going to use
in this section as well.
The pollution data set of the city of Belgrade to access it in this notebook as well go to this arrow
and then files.
If you don't have it already in your system upload it in the same way as you did in the previous section.
In my case it is already there but again if you don't have it there click on upload.
Select the file that you downloaded from the resources of this lesson and upload it simply there.
The first part of our dataset pre processing is to load a data set with pandas so let's write data set
equal to BD that read CSB.
And as always we have to specify the name of a file that we want to load.
In our case that is pollution small dot we execute a cell to remind ourselves.
Let's see what columns we have in our data set.
So let's bring the first five rows of the data set.
And as you can see we have a data column and we have four features that will describe the whole dataset
since we are as a stamp of data pre processing.
The data is not that important.
It will be important down the road but at this stage we can drop it.
So they drop it and create a variable called feature that will hold all columns except a date column
right.
Features equal to data said the drop in the drop function.
We have to specify a few things.
The first one is the column name.
And in this case it is simply a date then.
The second argument is to specify access because in our data set columns are separated by commas and
organize in this way.
The axis is equal to 1.
So let's execute the cell and we are ready.
We have our features.
Let's visualize the first five rows as we did previously to see if all features are there.
And as you can see we have everything here except the date column which is what we intended to do and
the last thing that we have to do in this tutorial is to convert the data set from this fracture to
the list of byte and dictionaries.
The reason for that is the tensor flow transform library the way that we are going to use it.
In this section requires Python dictionaries as inputs.
We are going to convert this data frame into the list of Python dictionaries where each row is going
to be a separated python dictionary.
The keys are going to be names of columns and the values are going to be values the conversion is easy
to achieve and it's only one line of code.
Let's define dict features variable that is going to hold our Annual structure and set it to list.
And in this list let's provide our features and call a built in function to dict in the brackets.
We need to specify a first argument called Orient since we want each row to be separate dictionary.
We need to specify that the reference is to look for is that index.
The Orient argument determines the type of values and the type of the dictionary.
In our case an index is used to determine how to convert this data frame to dictionaries.
We will end up with a structure like this.
Column value and that is what we want.
So in the brackets specify an index.
We need to specify these dot values and execute the set.
Let's visualize the first two rows to see how it's structured.
And as you can see each row is a separate dictionary where keys are column names and values are still
values and that's it for our video and data says pre processing.
We are ready to use tens of floaters for for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I see in the next tutorial.