Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in this video.
We will complete the whole dataset pre processing project but before we jump into the code we need to
discuss a few things that the tensor flow transform library lays down on a Apache beam backend.
And the reason for that is simply because they want to create scalable data set transform pre processing
library they achieve that by using Apache beam the Apache Beam is a whole infrastructure on its own
and it can get really complex.
So we are not going to explain it in great detail since it's not the cause.
The main on the other hand I encourage you to visit the documentation site and seek more readings on
the topic of the Apache beam.
You can build a lot of exciting applications around the Apache beam itself.
Let's go together for these notes that I provided for you and see what we have there.
We have a few arguments dict features as you know that is our dataset converted to Python dictionaries
and again interlaced then we have a data metadata which represents a meta information about each column.
With that we have in our dataset.
And lastly we have our pre processing function that we created in the previous video and we are going
to use that on top of our dict features to create our normalized data.
Now we will talk about the special syntax that is used because of the Apache being as you can see here
the result is equal to data to pass.
So some data that we have to pass to serve the function and then it is followed by this pipe which is
the special syntax that we are talking about here and after that we need to specify where to parse the
data.
So in most cases it is going to be some function.
There are a lot of reasons why they choose this syntax instead of standard Python syntax one of the
reasons is because this transformation of the data needs to be a scalable away and it can be really
complex really fast.
There are a lot of things that can be stacked together.
For example you can normalize data from 0 to 1 and then again normalize it by extracting meaning from
it.
For example let's break down our case that we are going to do in this video.
We have our results that are transformed data set and transform function after death.
We have to specify what data to pass.
Somewhere that data in our case is the features which is our data set and the information about the
data set itself.
So our metadata.
Lastly we need to specify where to parse the data set from the Apache being back and we are using this
analyze and transform data set.
Function it has two parts.
As you can see analyzed pirate is there because we are using metadata as well.
And then this transform is the part where we use our pre processing function to create normalized data
set.
The only argument in this function is the pre processing function that we wrote.
Here is the final syntax.
If we follow the syntax they choose the first output or result are transform data then transform function
the transform function is our pre processing function.
So we don't need it here at all then the data to pass.
In our case the features and data metadata.
Then we have this pipe which is our special syntax and where to parse the data as we said where to pester
data.
Well in our case analyze and transform data set build around our pre processing function.
I know it's a very weird syntax and to be honest I never seen it before it took some time for me to
get my head around it.
So be patient.
Try to practice it as much as possible and you will get there.
The final function is called data transform.
It doesn't have any arguments and we are merely going to write with DFT beam that we imported in the
very beginning.
Then create context in this context is very important because of the Apache beam.
This is the way Apache being works.
It creates context and tries to pre process or prepare data in that context.
As you can see it's optional but it's a good practice to put them up.
Their argument for it.
We are going to use this temp file library that imported at the very beginning.
So right from that library M.K. the temp which is shorter for make directory temporary and call it it
is going to create temporary directory for the context in store all warnings in all logs while the data
set pre processing is happening in that context.
We are going to call our weird syntax line from our notes so you can simply copy that line from the
notes and paste here our output is transform data and our transform function.
But as we said we don't need these function anymore and that is all equal to our inputs since we have
defined that above those inputs.
We don't need to provide them as an argument for to this function.
We could obviously do that but it's not necessary.
Followed by this special syntax pipe and then we are going to call our analyze and transform data set
function that is going to be built around our pre processing function and that's it.
Now we are done with our context and our pre processing.
And as you can see one part of our return data is called transform data set it consists actually from
two parts our data and metadata so you can split it to two different parts transform data and transform
metadata.
You can send that to be equal to our transform data set and that's pretty much it.
We unpacked it and we can now print it out to how well we scale our data since for the printing part
of this function.
We are simply using a for loop.
I'm going to skip to the part where I've already written that.
And welcome back.
This is our for loop which is going to print out all of our outputs.
We are going to run for each example in our data set at this point.
Doesn't matter if you use landfall transform data or dict features since it has the same number of samples
then we are going to say Okay print out the current one of the raw data from our dict features and transform
data.
That's pretty much it.
If this was the part of the pipeline you would return your transform data.
But now since we are just doing the pre processing we are going to simply print it out let's call it.
And are you ready execute a cell and as you can see it is working.
There are a lot of warnings happening in the background.
Everything is scaling and now we have our results printed out.
Here for example we have a raw data for forty four point thirty eight.
But here transform data is minus eighteen point fifty eight then we have this zero point twenty eight.
And so on at this point everything is automatic so we don't have to do anything manually anymore.
I hope you understand everything here.
If you have any questions please.
I do encourage you to ask us if you need any help on your project for example and also I encourage you
to read more about Apache BMC index since it is going to take some time to get used to this index that
we used in this video.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next video.