Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video we talked about the base model
loaded in memory.
And now we have everything at our disposal.
Now it's time to freeze the base model which is also the goal of this video when you try to train your
model for a specific task and you don't freeze the base network it is going to change its initial weight
as well.
And that is not what we want.
We want to take those learned features on the image net for example and apply them on a custom task
and only train custom layers that we are going to add on top of these bays network to achieve this.
We are going to freeze all layers in our base network and only train a few layers that we are going
to add.
You can freeze the network in a single line of code and it's very easy to do just right base model that
we defined before dot and choose trainable said that to be equal to False and that's it.
That's all what we have to do is to freeze all layers in our base network to prevent them from changing
their initial weight if you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.