Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're going to wrap up.
We're back propagation.
All right.
So we already know pretty much everything we need to know about what happens in the neural net.
We know that there's a process called forward propagation where information is entered into the input
layer and then it's propagated forward to get our white hats our output values and then we compare those
to the actual values that we have in our training set and then we calculate the errors then the errors
are back propagated through the network in the opposite direction and that allows us to train the network
by adjusting the weights.
So the one key important thing to remember here is that back propagation is an advanced algorithm driven
by very interesting and sophisticated mathematics which allows us to adjust the weights all of them
at the same time all the way to adjusted simultaneously.
So if we were doing this manually or if we were coming up for a different type of algorithm then even
if we calculate the error and then we were trying to understand what effect each of the weights has
an error we'd have to somehow adjust each of the weights independent independently or individually the
huge advantage of back irrigation and this key thing to remember is that during the process of back
propagation simply because of the way the algorithm is structured you are able to adjust all of the
weight at the same time so you basically know which part of the error each of your weights in the neural
network is responsible for.
Now that is the key fundamental underlying principle of back propagation and this was why it picked
up so rapidly in the 1980s and this was the major breakthrough.
And if you'd like to learn more about that and how exactly the mathematics works in the background then
a good article which we've already mentioned is the neural where networks and deep learning is actually
a book by Michael Nielsen.
There you'll find the mathematics written out and it will help you understand how exactly this is possible.
But for now for our purposes it from an intuition point of view the important part is to remember that
that's what back propagation does.
It adjusts all of the weights at the same time.
And now we're going to just wrap everything up with a step by step walk through of what happens in the
training of a neural network.
All right.
So step one we randomly initialize the weights to small numbers close to zero but not zero.
We didn't really focus on the initialization of weights during the Egyptian tutorials but the weights
have to start somewhere and they're initialized with random values near zero.
And from there through the process for propagation back irrigation these weights are adjusted until
the error is minimized until the cost function is minimized.
Then step to inputs.
The first observation of your data sets to the first row into the input layer each feature is one input.
So basically you take the columns and put them into the input nodes.
Step 3 for propagation from left to right.
The neurons are activated in a way that the impact of each neurones activation is limited by the weight
to the weights.
Basically determine how important each neurones activation is then propagate the activations until getting
the predicted result y hat in this case.
So basically you propagate from left to right.
You go all the way until you get to the end and you get your way ahead.
Then compare the predictor result to the actual result.
Measure the generated error then you do the back propagation from Rachel if the error is back irrigated.
Update the weights according to how much they're responsible for the error.
Again you are able to calculate that because of the way the back propagated by approximation algorithm
is structured the learning rate decides by how much we update the weights learning rate as parameter
you can control in your neural network.
Step 6 repeat steps 1 to 5 and update the weights after each observation that is called the reinforcement
learning and in our case that was stochastic gradient descent.
Or repeat steps one to 5.
But update weights only after a batch of observations so batch learning it's either a full gradient
descent or badge gradient descent or mini batch gradient descent.
And Step 7 when the whole training set pass through the artificial neural network that makes an epoch
redo more epochs.
So basically you just keep doing that and doing that and doing that to allow your neural network to
train better and better and better and constantly adjust itself as you minimize the cost function.
So there we go.
Those are the steps you need to take to build your artificial neural networks and train it.
And these are the steps that you will be taken to get you've had learn in the practical tutorials.
Wish you the best of luck and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.