Welcome to the next section of this course.
In this section we start creating like Project two and we start looking at Excel driven data.
So we are now finished.
Reply Project one And so it makes sense to avoid making further changes to this project so that you
can refer back to it at a later date.
Will be cop in the life project one framework the intention of using it as a basis for life project
to.
This way we avoid having to go through the set up stages and have realistic tests to work from.
Luckily, Eclipse makes it easy to copy and paste a project using a different name.
So we are going to explore how we can use Excel to pass data into our tests.
This is a variable world scenario, but we may want to use Excel to define variables and then use asset
values in our tests.
For example, we may have a spreadsheet with test username and password data and we may want to feed
the username and password combinations in a log in web page.
Luckily this is possible using a Java API named Apache Player and I'd explain more about this in the
next lecture.
So this is a brief diagram to try and explain what I'm trying to achieve here.
So we're going to have an Excel spreadsheet containing email address and password combinations, and
then I'm going to create a test class for the log in page.
When I run this test, I expect to retrieve the data from the Excel spreadsheet, and Selenium web driver
would then pass that data using the browser of our choosing.
So this is an example of the Excel spreadsheet I'll be provided.
So it has a simple email address column and a password column, and then we have sets of email address
and passwords which we're going to use to pass into the log in page of the store.
So let's create a live project to.
On my screen I have eclipse open and we can see live projects, one, which is all the framework we've
done in the previous lectures.
And because we know this project is working and the framework is well designed, it's good to keep it
in its current state.
For you to refer back to.
This is the reason I'm not adding these new sections to Project one and why I'm creating a new life
project.
So I'm going to collapse live Project one and I'm going to left click it and on my keyboard I'm going
to press control C and control the to copy and paste it.
You'll see that project name has been provided as Life Project two and I'm going to keep this as is
and click copy.
This whole Dang Creek Live project, too.
And until it's fully loaded, you may see some errors, but hopefully it will go away in a few seconds.
So Life Project too is a separate project from my project one, but live Project two is a clone of live
projects one.
So we have all design classes from the previous framework.
So this is what we're going to be using from this point.
So now that we've created Life Project to move on to the next lecture.