Welcome to the next section of this course.
This section is dedicated to Maven and this lecture provides an overview and explains how we should
use Maven.
So what is Maven?
Maven is a powerful build management tool.
It is the most common build management tool for Java.
It uses a concept called POM, which stands for Project Object Model.
May even makes our life much easier.
And this is because it can take care of the framework structure can retrieve dependencies for us, remove
in the need for us to retrieve jars ourselves.
And it comes with many useful plugins.
So here is a sample maven project structure and you can see that at the highest level is the project
followed by a pond, for example, where we store our dependencies and then it has a source folder which
contains mine and test.
And I'll explain this in more detail in later lectures.
So the main purpose of the POM file is to list all dependencies we need in our project.
Maven will then retrieve the dependencies for us.
So do you remember back when we imported the Selenium Jar file?
Well, now we can add a reference to the Selenium jar and version number in the file.
A maven will go and find, download and install the Selenium jar into our project for us.
So how do we find dependencies?
We can find dependencies by using a website called MV N Repository.
This is a library of all dependencies that were available.
And in the example I have search for selenium Java.
So this is what you'd often see when you click on a dependency on VM repository.
So if you look on the left hand side, these are the version numbers of this particular dependency and
those marked as red are not officially released versions, so they're still in an alpha state.
But below that, we have stable versions.
And if you look to the right hand side, you'll see usages.
And this is how often the version has been used by another dependency.
So if we look on this slide, this is when I have clicked on a particular version.
So I have clicked on Selenium Java version.
3.141.59.
And you can see that there is a tab for Maven and that lists a dependency.
So what I can do is take that dependency code and place it into my POM file and then eclipse using maven
will download that dependency for me, which is similar to as if I downloaded and installed an external
jar file.
So inserting dependencies into our palm.
So this is an example or a screenshot of a POM file that I have used in a previous project.
And you can see that there's two dependencies here.
One for Selenium Java and one for Test and G.
So we can add a number of different dependencies into our project.
And Maven will take care of the downloading and installing of that dependency for us.
So the steps that we have ahead are to download and install Maven.
Crater may even project into Eclipse.
Review the structure of the MAVEN project.
Demonstrates how we can easily import dependencies into our project.
Run a simple end to end test using some of what we have learned so far in this course.
So I hope this has given you a good overview of Maven and in the forthcoming lectures would explore
it in more detail.