So let's start setting up everything we need for this course.
So we're going to look at the Java development kit.
So what is the Java development kit?
The Java development kit, also known as the JDK, is one of three core technology packages used in
Java programming.
The other two are JRA, which stands for Java Runtime Environment and JVM, which stands for Java Virtual
Machine.
The JDK allows developers to create Java programs that could be executed and run by the jury and the
JVM.
The JDK contains everything we need to write and execute Java programs.
So what is the Java runtime environment?
A runtime environment is a piece of software that is designed to run other software.
The JRA contains two Java class libraries, the Java class loader and the Java virtual machine.
The class loader is responsible for correctly loading classes and connecting them with the court.
Java Class Libraries.
The Java virtual machine is responsible for ensuring Java applications have the resources they need
to run and perform well in your device or cloud environment.
The job is mainly a container for those other components and is responsible for orchestrating their
activities.
So what is the Java virtual machine?
The Java virtual machine has two primary functions.
It allows Java programs to run on any device or operating system, and this is known as the write once
run anywhere principle.
The second is to manage and optimize program memory.
In short, the Java virtual machine is how we run our Java programs.
We configure the JVM settings and then rely on it to manage program resources through an execution.
So in a nutshell, JDK is for development purposes where Java is for running the Java programs.
The JDK and Java both contain the Java virtual machine so that we can run our job a program.
The JVM is the heart of Java programming, and it provides platform independence.
JDK is a superset of the Java and contains everything that the Java contains.
Plus tools such as the compilers and debug is necessary for developing applications.
So you may have heard of Open JDK and Oracle JDK.
So Open JDK and Oracle JDK are implementations of the same Java specification.
A key difference between the open JDK and Oracle JDK is the license and release cycle.
Oracle JDK is aimed towards an enterprise audience, whereas open JDK is a free and open source implementation
which is widely supported and used.
In this course, we'll use the open JDK specifically version 11, as it will be identical to the Oracle
JDK for our needs and does not require a commercial license.
If you'd like to read more about the JDK, you can do so using the following link.
So why use open JDK version 11 specifically?
So we are going to use open JDK 11 because it is an open source reference implementation of version
11 of the Java SC platform.
So some tools that we're going to use, such as Jenkins for continuous integration, which is something
we'll go through later in this course.
But it relies on you using a particular version of Java.
So if we look at the Jenkins requirements, you can see highlighted that Java 11 runtime environments
are supported, whereas Java 12, if you look at the bottom, is a not supported version.
So this is why we are using a specific version of Java in this course.
So let's begin the open JDK installation.
So on my desktop, I'm going to open up Google Chrome.
And I am going to search for the following term.
JDK space.
Java space.
Net.
And the following results should be shown here.
And this is a link to JDK dot java dot net.
If I click on this link, each presenter page looks like the following.
So this may be slightly different to you or what you're seen in your screen.
And this is because I recorded this in 2020.
So the important part is he reference implementations and we're going to select version 11.
This should show the following page.
And if we look on the left hand side, you'll see a menu and we're looking for the archive link.
And if we click this, it should present a page like the following.
So these are all the different releases in the archives section.
And if I scroll down, you should see version 11 .0.2.
And this is the version that we're going to be using for this course.
So you can see that there's downloads for Windows, Mac and Linux.
And because I'm using Windows, I am going to click on the zip link, which will begin the download.
So I'm going to pause this video until that completes.
So now it has finished downloading.
If I click on that download, you should be shown a shove in folder option and if I select that, it
will take you to location of where that file has been placed.
So I'm going to move over this window and I'm going to close the browser window, and I'm going to simply
drag that zip file to my desktop.
So I'm going to be downloading quite a bit of content for this course.
So it makes sense to create a new folder, which I'm going to call resources.
And this resources folder is where I'm going to store things such as downloads or when we generate reports.
It can all be found in this folder.
So I am now going to double click on my zip file.
And I'm going to drag the content, which is the JDK into my resources folder and it will unzip it to
that location.
So as this unzipping will take a moment, I'm going to pause the video.
So the unzip in is now complete.
So what I can do is close this and I can now delete the original zip folder.
And if I double click on my resources folder, you'll see the unzipped JDK 11.02 folder.
So this is all we needed to do in this lecture.
In the next lecture will start setting the environment variable to make use of this open JDK.
Thank you for watching.