Welcome to the next section of this course.
In this section, we'll be focusing on various scenarios.
So what's covered in this section?
I will demonstrate how you can interact with various elements and scenarios found across the web.
Will mostly be using the elements found on the automation test encoder UK website.
Lucy, a whole host of commands, such as locating elements and interacting with them.
Send in data to forms, how to deal with alerts, dealing with radio buttons and checkboxes and much
more.
So this is an example of us covered in this section, and the upcoming lectures will focus on each of
these.
So we'll build in the core skills.
So our aim is to build core skills that is important to automation testers.
Once we have gained a good level of core skills, we'll move on to constructing a framework using various
technologies.
So we've already seen the basics and take a look at set up.
Now we focus in on core skills and after this section we move on to construct in a framework.
After we've done that, we then look at some additional subjects.
So let's make a start.