Welcome to the next section of this course.
So this section is going to focus on more advanced features available in Selenium Web driver.
And we're also going to explore some more complicated websites and how we can interact with them.
So this lecture and the next is going to focus on a travel website.
So what is the problem?
So some websites have quite complicated designs and the degree of difficulty in being able to interact
with elements can vary.
A prime example of a fairly complicated group of elements is the input fields that you often find on
travel websites.
These are often difficult because of validation rules.
Because of predictive text.
Difficulty to read the dom.
And no easy to use locator.
So my plan or our plan is that we're going to review a travel website called easyJet.
Understand how the flight search panel works.
Understand that the from end to flight validation moves.
Practice how to select a result by using visible text.
And we're going to discuss the approach that we need to use.
So let's begin.
So the first thing I'm going to do is take a look at the website to see how it functions.
So I'm going to open up Chrome and I'm going to search easyJet.
And the first result should be to easyJet dot com.
So you should be presented with a website similar to this.
And the main focus is on this flight search panel.
And we had the ability to enter a from location A to destination the parts in and return in dates and
also selected the number of passengers that will be flying.
You can search for flight results based on these criteria.
So you'll notice that London Gatwick is pre-selected in the from filled.
And if I select the two fields and type in the character of a.
I'm presented with results that begin with my that fly from London Gatwick.
Sir.
Note that there's Aberdeen and Agadir in Morocco.
If I changed the from location to London Luton.
And then search for the character of again, you'll see there's different results.
So that flight to Morocco is no longer available.
But instead I can fly to Aberdeen, Alicante.
And the reason for that is that depending on where you're flying from.
There's only certain destinations you can fly to based on flights from that particular airport.
So what I'm trying to test in this particular example is as me as a user, I want to come to this website
and in the from field I want to type in the value of London.
And you can see that there are a number of airports within the London zone.
So after Typekit in London, I want to be able to select a particular value based on the visible text
that is presented to me.
So I want to select London Luton.
So I am going to search for a phrase that has Luton in its name.
So the approach that I will be using here is type in London to get the results of all the airports that
are in London zone.
I then need to store all these results in a list.
And then need to loop through that list to search for one that has gluten in its name.
And when I have selected that particular results, I want to click it so that London Luton appears in
the from field.
So this is good practice.
So we're going to be using a list, we're going to be use in a loop, and we are likely going to also
need to use an explicit weight.
So let's begin.
So as we're in a new section of this course, I am going to right click the source folder, select new
and then select package, and I'm going to give this new package a name of section zero eight and then
click Finish.
I'm then going to right click that new package, go to new and class, and I'm going to give this a
name of l01 under school travel.
Website.
P.
T.
One.
And I am going to select public static void main and then click Finish.
So this will creates a new class.
So to save time, I'm just going to copy the set up code from our chrome demo class.
So I'm going to highlight these lines.
Control C on my keyboard to copy it.
And then I'm just going to paste it here like so.
And then I can close the Chrome demo class.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is update the address.
So I'm going to copy easy jet.com forward slash end.
And paste it like so.
So I am now going to save this class.
And I am going to try running it.
Because I would like to show you something before we begin.
So you'll notice that when I first come in to this website, you're presented with a cookies panel.
And we have the option to let me choose or accept or cookies.
So you didn't see this before?
Because I had visited the website in the past.
But when a new session opens this website, we need to handle these cookies panel.
So if I right click and inspect the acceptable button.
And if I get to select it all and select it.
You'll see that the element is then presented to you.
So this pattern has an I.D., which is a unique property.
So I am going to copy the I.D. and I'm going to go to Eclipse and I'm going to write Driver to find
elements, buyer I.D. and then I am going to pay that value.
Then I am going to click that button using the Click Command.
So now if I say this class.
And try running it again.
We should see that I cookies panel will be closed.
As shown.
So now we can begin using or testing against the from field.
So we'll begin writing this code in the next lecture.