Welcome to the next section of this course.
In this section, we're going to look at other advanced topics of selenium web driver.
In this lecture, we're going to look at Chrome options.
The Chrome options class can be used to set a number of browser options to Chrome when a test is triggered.
For example, we can use the conventional code to maximize the chrome window and we've used this code
throughout the course so far.
This is where I use driver dot manage.
Dot window, dot maximize.
But instead we can use chrome options by writing something like the below.
So I'm using the chrome options class and creating an object called options.
Then I add arguments to the options object such as start maximized.
Then when we create the driver instance, we simply pass the options object as a parameter.
So why can we why should we change this?
Why not use chrome options?
The reason for that is that we have Chrome options.
We have a number of different choices that we can select.
For example, if I wanted Chrome to open in incognito mode, then I have an option to do that.
So let's try this out.
So as we started a new section of this course, I am going to right click the source folder, select
new and then select package and create a new package called Section zero nine and then click Finish.
I'm then going to go back to the default package and copy the chrome demo.
So control, seal my keyboard.
And then going to left click the new package in control V to paste it.
So now I need to rename this class, so I'm going to right click it.
Select refactor and then rename.
And I'm going to call this 1l01 since this is the first lecture of this section.
Understood.
Underscore chrome options and then click finish.
Click Finish again, and then it will be renamed.
So I'm going to double click this.
And now I'm going to begin writing code.
So here you can see I have driver don't manage the window don't maximize.
So I'm going to remove that because I'm going to use Chrome options instead.
So to use chrome options, I need to use the chrome options class.
So I am going to do this above the Web driver object creation.
So I'm going to do it here and I'm going to write Chrome.
Options.
Options equals new chrome.
Brackets and a semicolon like so.
So if I hover over chrome options, you see, I've got an option to import it from selenium.
Then the error goes away.
Now I am going to add arguments to the options object.
To do this, I'm going to write options.
Thoughts and arguments.
Then in the bracket song we use double quotes.
And I'm going to use two dashes.
Start.
Dash.
Maximized.
Like so.
And then it was semi-colon at the end.
So now I need to pass this object as a parameter here.
So I'm going through our options.
Our.
And I'm going to save this class.
So now if I try running it, let's see if the chrome window opens.
Maximized.
And you can see that did.
So let me try another option.
So I am going to copy this line.
Like so.
Instead of start maximized.
I'm going to write in.
COG Nieto like so.
So if I say this class again.
Let's try running it.
And you can see that chrome this time has opened up in incognito mode because of the black windows.
So that's how easy it is to say options to Chrome.
All we need to do is use the Chrome options class to create an object.
We then simply add arguments to not object, and then all we do is pass the object as a parameter.
When we create the driver instance.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And thank you for watching.