Welcome to the next section of this course.
In this section, we're going to focus on something called Jenkins.
And this video is going to give you an overview of Jenkins.
And in the future videos, I'm going to show you how to install it.
Set it up and use it.
So what is Jenkins?
Jenkins is an open source continuous integration server.
It is capable of orchestrating a chain of events to help to achieve a continuous integration process.
For example, we can show you our tests run at a particular time, such as on a daily, weekly, monthly
or even yearly basis.
Jenkins handles the time and intriguing of tests for us, meaning the automates when our tests are to
execute.
Jenkins is open source and it's entirely written in Java.
It's a widely used application with around 300,000 installations and is growing daily.
It is a server based application and requires a web server such as Apache Tomcat.
Jenkins became so popular because it can monitor repeated tasks during development.
For example, if your team is developing the project, then Jenkins can continuously test your project
builds and show you errors that may have arisen.
Jenkins is not only used by automation testers, but can be used for various development activities
such as building, testing and deployment.
So what is continuous integration?
During continuous integration and after code commit, the software is built and tested immediately.
In a large project with many developers.
Committees are made several times each day.
With each commit, the code is built and then tested.
If the test passes, then the build is tested for deployment.
If deployment is successful, then the code is pushed to production.
This commit build test and deployment is a continuous process, hence the name continuous integration,
also known as continuous deployment.
So on this slide, I provide you with the basic process flow of how we can use the Jenkins tool.
So imagine that we have installed Jenkins and we configured it to run all our tests at 2 a.m. every
morning.
When 2 a.m. is reached, the tested and executed.
And once those tests are complete, it would then generate a report which we can then review.
So this is a basic process flow of how we can use Jenkins in our framework.
In this slide, I've highlighted the key job requirements in order to be able to use Jenkins.
So the first red rectangle highlights the version of Java that is supported.
So as you can see, Java eight is supported by 3264 bits.
And also Java 11.
If you look at the second rectangle, you'll see two versions of Java that are not supported.
So this is anything older than Java eight.
Java nine and ten are not supported and leverage Java 12.
So in our framework we actually use in Java 11.
So we're okay to proceed.
So that is a very basic overview of Jenkins.
So the key thing to remember is that Jenkins is a tool that we can use to schedule our jobs to run at
a specific date or time.
So if you'd like to read more about Jenkins, then you can do so at the official website which is found
that w WW dot jenkins dot io.
In the next few lectures will start downloading and installing.
JENKINS And by the end of this section, you'll be very familiar of this tool.