In this lecture, we'll be creating the objects class.
So two steps ahead are we are going to create an objects class that will store the objects related to
the test store.
Log in page.
We wouldn't create this under a new package stored under the source main Java folder.
We will be creating new fields of methods within the objects class where the fields restore the locate
to value and the methods will return.
Locate a value by accessing those fields.
So this is a screenshot of the log in page and those pointed out all the elements that we are interested
in.
So let's try to sell.
So on my screen I have a clips open and I'm going to be using the MAVEN project for this work.
So the first thing I need to do is to create a new package which is going to store our page objects.
So I'm going to do this in the source main Java folder, and if I expand it, you'll see there's an
existing package that we've used previously.
So I'm going to right click that source main Java folder, select new and then select package.
And I'm going to call this new package page.
Objects like so.
I'm then going to right click that package, select new and then select class, and I'm going to call
this class.
Test store, log in page and then click finish.
That class will then open.
So the first thing I'm going to do in this class is initialize the web driver variable.
So I'm going to write Web driver driver like.
So I'm then going to create a constructor.
To do this, I'm going to use public test store login page and in brackets.
And inside those brackets, I'm going to use Web driver driver.
And then outside that, I'm going to have an open and close embrace.
So I need to import web driver from selenium.
And those errors will now go away.
Inside this constructor, I am going to use this dot driver equals driver.
So I'll explain what this constructor does when I demonstrate the running of the test.
In brief, all I'm doing here is providing a web driver driver parameter which will get initialized
at the time I run the test and then that value unknown updates this with the value that's provided.
So the next thing I'm going to do is use some new code, which you have kind of seen before in the past.
So remember previously when we use use in driver find element by and then using something like CSS selector.
Well, now, what's I'll be using is by.
And I'm going to provide a variable name such as email.
Equals bi dots.
CSF selector.
And I'm just going to provide empty quotes for now.
So this is similar to what we've seen in the past.
We're expecting a locator value here and that locator value will be stored in its variable called email.
So I'm going to do the same by simply copying this line.
Two more times, but for the second time, I'm going to call the variable password.
And in the third example, I'm going to call it log in button like so.
So what I need to do now is find the locators for these three variables from the log in page of the
test store.
So I'm going to open up Chrome.
I'm going to go to the automation testing website.
And I'm going to click on the test or button.
And then I'm going to click sign in, which is the page that will be focusing on.
So I am going to right click the email input field and inspect.
And if I open up random ops velocity, you'll see that I'm provided with access locator.
So I'm going to simply copy that.
Go over to eclipse and paste that value like so.
So now this email variable now stores a reference to this locator.
So I'm going to do the same for the password.
So I'm going to get to select at all.
Click on the password input field and take this top CSA selector.
And I'm going to place that.
Yeah.
And then finally, I need to get one for the in button.
Or a sign in button.
And I am going to simply copy that.
And paste it like so.
So now we have free variables that point to three different locators.
So the next thing that I'll be doing is I'll be creating some methods and these methods will be returning.
I, for example, drive a dot, find elements, and instead of providing the locator values in these
methods, they're going to reference these variables.
So the first one is going to be public web element.
Get email.
And in open and close embraces and I need to import web element from selenium.
And getting more is expected in a written statement.
So I'll be right in return.
Driver thoughts?
Find elements.
And as you can see, email has already been populated for me.
So all I require is a semicolon.
So this is return driver.
They'll find element and it's going to use this variable here which stores the value by access selector
and improvised locator value.
So I am going to create two more say public web elements get password.
And this is going to return driver.
They'll find elements.
But this time I'm going to be passing the password variable.
And in the final one, public web element.
Get the log in button.
And it's going to return driver.
They'll find elements.
And it's going to provide the log in button variable.
So that is our class complete.
So the main things to take away from this is that we're storing the locator values in this class and
we assign them to an A to a variable such as email, password or log in button.
So what we'll be doing is that's where we'll be creating a test class will be cool in these methods
such as get email, get password and get login button to be able to access those locators.
I hope you found this interesting.
And once again, thank you for watching.