In this lecture, we take a look at some common concepts and functions.
So first off, do not worry.
The following slides may seem fairly scary or won't make sense.
This is expected at this stage.
What I explain here will be repeated and demonstrated time and time again throughout this course.
By the end, you will confidently understand the concepts very well.
For now, all I'm doing is introducing you to the common features and functions.
So let's take a look at some browser set up code.
So the below code is commonly used.
In basic terms, this setup code allows us to write instructions to the browser.
For example, to go to a particular website.
The example below uses the Chrome browser, but I'll show you later how we can tweak the set up code
for both Firefox and Edge.
For now, just scan over the below code and I'll explain it in more detail in the next few slides.
So first we have systems that set property.
The set property method of Java assistant class sets the property of the system use in a key.
When using Chrome, we use this property using the key web driver doc chrome driver and pointed to the
chrome driver key which is the driver.
What we are doing here is telling the system where to find the chrome driver.
Chrome will look for the driver using the value of the web driver, not chrome driver key.
So if we look at the below code in the first double quotes, we're providing the key web driver, dot
chrome, dot driver.
And in the second quotes, we are providing the path to where the chrome driver resides.
So let's look at implementing in a driver object.
So examine the below code and for now know that web driver is an interface driver is a reference variable.
Chrome driver is a constructor.
New is a key word.
And New Chrome driver initiates an object.
Web driver is an interface, and all methods which are declared in the web driver interface are implemented
by the respective driver class.
This is Chrome driver in our case.
Basically we are creating an instance of the web driver interface and casting it to the chrome driver
class.
We could then access methods by using the object name driver.
We can perform various tasks such as opening a browser window, expand the driver window, visit web
page, interact with elements, and then close the browser.
Alternatively, we could write.
So if we look at his image here, here we are creating an instance of the chrome driver class.
The problem with this approach is that this would mean we are limited to using Chrome Driver, which
is no good for cross browser compatibility.
We need a flexible concept that allows us to switch to other browsers.
The reason we use the Web driver interface is so that we can switch to other browser objects by simply
changing the constructor such as web.
Driver driver equals new Firefox driver or web driver driver equals new edge driver.
We also have driver don't manage that window, not maximize.
So here we are.
Access in methods using the driver object.
Driver dot manage returns an instance of the underline implementation of options interface where you
can access the browser's menu.
Driver dot managed dot window which further return interface for managing the browser window.
The window interface has a method called maximize which can be used like driver dot manage dot window
to maximize to maximize the driver window.
So this lecture has given you an introduction to some of the most common concepts that we use when using
Selenium Web driver.
Again, do not worry if you find it is hard to follow.
I'll be using similar codes several times throughout this course, and by the end of it you'll be very
familiar how to set it up and why we use it.