Welcome to the next lecture.
In this lecture, we'll be taking a closer look at the Apache dependency and would also download and
install the dependency into our live project to.
Apache spyware is a popular application programming interface that allows developers to create, modify
and display and message office files using Java.
It is an open source library developed by Apache Software Foundation, allowing developers to interact
and modify Microsoft Office files.
Apache POI comes bundled with classes of methods to convert user input data or file into MSC office
documents.
Apache Po y contains classes of methods to work on only two compound documents of an office.
The only to follow type is primarily associated with Microsoft Office by Microsoft.
Only stands for Objet Lincoln and Embedded, which is the format used for Microsoft Office files.
Two key components from Apache.
Why we are interested in are HSF, which stands for horrible spreadsheet format, which is used to read
and write to excel as formats, which is the old version of Excel and Access as F, which stands for
Excel spreadsheet format, which is used for the more modern dots Excel ASX formats.
So we'll be focusing on the Excel format, which is the new Excel formats released in 2007.
It is the most common type of Excel file and it has over 1 million rows.
So what will be code in?
It will be for the new format of Excel.
So we're not interested in the old Excel format, which is the old version of Excel, which is less
commonly used these days.
So if you wanted to read more about the Apache components, you can do so by visiting the following
neural.
The highlighted row is the component we need to use.
Interact with the dots, excel s x file type taken out of the MAVEN artifact id which is this poi xml.
So we'll be sauce in our dependency from the end the end repository websites.
And the dependency will be downloaded is highlighted on my screen.
So the key thing is, is that there's multiple Apache pure white dependencies, but the one that we're
interested in is the one that's got the ark type by de poi hyphen XML, which is the one we need to
use in the modern day version of Excel spreadsheets.
Celeste installed a dependency.
On my screen.
I have a clips open and you can see I have live project to expand it so I need to go and find the Apache
PWA dependency and add it to my pom file.
And this pom file belongs to my project to.
So I'm going to open up Chrome and I'm going to search for ambient repository.
And then the first result would be to MBM repository dot com.
And here I'm going to search for.
Apache prior.
So you see a number of results here, but it's very important you select the right type.
The one we need is this one here, which is why if an example, if we click this link, you'll see the
latest versions.
So I'm going to use the latest version available is time of recording, which is 5.2.0.
I'm then going to copy the maven dependency.
But they're in control.
See on my keyboard and then I'm going to add it to my pom file.
If I go down, this is the dependency section.
So I'm going to add it at the bottom just before the close in dependencies tag.
If I press control shift in for my keyboard, it will form a code for me.
They're going to save this file.
If you look at the bottom right hand corner, you should see an installation has taken place.
So now it completed.
We have now added the Apache pillar dependency to our project.
So one other thing I've spotted in this poem.
If we scroll right to the top is that because we have copied I have project two from my Project one.
This file is still referring to Projects one in this name.
So I'm going to change that to my project two and also the artifact I.D. I'm going to change the Life
Project two and then going to save this file.
And that's all the updates complete.
So we've now added the Apache pillar to our Life Project two.
And so in the next lecture, we're going to learn about what this test is going to involve.