In this lecture, we take a look at the different types of wipes available in Selenium Web driver.
So the first one is called Implicit White, and the implicit white will tell web driver to white for
a set amount of time before it throws eight.
No such elements exception.
It continuously posed Adam looking for a specific condition and it implies a common up to time limit
for all cause in a session.
The default wait time is zero, but will be set to longer if used.
For example, we can set the white to wait for 10 seconds until it froze the error exception.
Implicit weights are set globally.
This means you set an implicit white once in a test, and if an element can't be found, web driver
will wait until the global weights limit in real world world terms.
I found that this weight isn't used very often.
Next, we have explicit ways to express it.
White Command instructs Web driver to whites until a certain condition occurs before proceeding to the
next step.
Setting an explicit weight is important in cases where there are certain elements that naturally take
more time to load.
Explicit ways is more intelligent but can only be applied for specified elements.
In order to declare explicit weight, one has to use expected conditions, which I'll explain further
when we cover explicit weight in detail.
Explicit weights are the most commonly used weights in my experience.
The last one is known as fluent whites.
So the fluent white command instructs the maximum amount of time for selenium Webb driver to wait for
condition to be met.
It also sets the frequency of how often Webb driver will check to see if the condition is met before
throwing a element.
Not fat, not visible exception.
Flute lines.
Look.
Looks for web element repeatedly at regular intervals until time out happens until the object is found.
Fluent white commands are most useful when interacting with web elements that can sometimes take more
time than usual to load.
So the flu of mice, in my opinion, are not used very often, but there are some cases where they are
ideal.
So the main difference between implicit and explicit ways and these two of the most common to type of
whites, in my opinion, the implicit white set globally, whereas an explicit way is set to element
level.
So what that means is we only have to set one implicit white in the code.
But for explicit whites, we need to set that against each element that we're looking for within the
code.
So there could be multiple explicit ways within our test.
An implicit white is applied to all elements.
Whereas an explicit white applies only to that particular element that we've set against.
Implicit weight does not require setting a specific condition, but the explicit weight must always
specify expected conditions on the element to be located.
Implicit weights are best used when all elements are loaded before the duration time set.
But an explicit way is best used when an element tends to take a while to load.
So I hope this gives you a brief overview of the different type of weights in Selenium.
And in the next few lectures we're going to go through each one in detail.