So before we embark on a journey to learn selenium Webb Driver I think it's important to reflect back
to understand Selenium history.
So in early 2004, Selenium was conceived by a full works engineer named Jason Huggins.
So the first version of selenium was known as Selenium first mode of operation or Selenium core.
Jason was working on a time in the expenses application and realized that testing the application using
server callbacks and different browsers was slow and troublesome.
Jason created a tool named the Java script test runner that enabled him to test the web application
by interacting with the client directly.
This meant he could test the web application with speed since server callbacks were no longer required
and tests could be conducted almost instantly.
In later, 2004 came second mode of operation and this is known as Selenium RC.
So Jason started demo in the test hall to his colleagues and was blown away by the positive feedback
and responses.
A fellow ThoughtWorks engineer named Paul Hammond saw the demo and discussed making Selenium open source.
Paul started working on a second mode of operation whereby selenium could be remote, steered over TCP
IP, enabling instructions to be written in common programming languages like Java, C, Shop, Ruby,
Python and others.
The version of Selenium went on to become known as selenium remote control, often referred to as selenium
or C.
In 2005 came the transformation of selenium r.
C So in 2005, someone called Dan Follett and Nelson Sproul made an offer to accept the series of patches
that would transform Selenium r c into what it became best known for.
Originally Selenium ozone was two processes on an operating system.
The script running the test and the browser itself.
The new patches introduced a third process that sat in the middle of the two and allowed more than one
machine to be involved in the execution of Selenium tests.
This included tests being scripted from, say, Windows and being executed on a mac machine using Safari
browser.
In 2005 to 2006 came Selenium idea.
So Shinya Kass Itami from Japan wrote a Firefox plugin that brought the Selenium first mode of operation
into an idea.
The idea allow the user to record, edit and play back selenium scripts.
This offered users a way to get up and running with automated tests in very little time and with very
little overhead.
It required no programming knowledge to use, but is still capable of a lot.
There are, however, some disadvantages by using it.
For example, there is no reporting and test scripts are more subject to ongoing maintenance.
In 2007 came Selenium web driver.
So another ThoughtWorks engineer named Simon Stuart had been working on a different web testing tool
called Web Driver.
Web driver was different as it did not rely on JavaScript and instead used a client for each browser
that was written from scratch.
Each browser type, for example, Chrome, Firefox or I8 has a dedicated driver executable that allows
instructions to be sent to the browser via the operating system.
Web driver offered the number advantages over selenium.
See, for example, features between programming languages was consistent between different browsers.
In 2008 came Selenium Grid Support Works employee Felipe Henry Gou created Selenium Grid that allowed
Selenium r c to be used in expanded capacity.
Selenium grid is a smart proxy server that makes easy to run tests in parallel on multiple machines.
Selenium grids uses the hub node concept where hub assigns jobs to nodes when a suitable node is found,
i.e. operating system browser matches the tests request.
On this slide, I give you a summary of the key Selenium major releases.
So in 2009 was when Selenium one was introduced, and this was the first version consisting of Selenium
ai.d Selenium RC and Selenium grid.
In 2011 was selenium, too.
And this is a tool that makes the development of automated tests for web applications far easier.
It represents the merger of the original Selenium project with the Web Driver Project.
Selenium also got deprecated since the merge, however, was used for backward compatibility.
In 2016, Selenium Free was released.
And this is an extended version of selenium too.
It is inherently backward compatible and does not involve selenium or c.
The new version came along with several bug fixes and increased stability.
Browser vendors provided their own version of browser executables, and these are sometimes referred
to as browser drivers.
In 2021 Selenium form is released and this is a new version of Selenium that uses complete W3C protocol
adoption and introduces various other features.
So I've designed this course using a very late version of selenium free.
And my reasons for this is that this version is very stable, is still uses the W3C protocol and it
is by far the most popular version of Selenium has been used in the industry at the time of recording.
Selenium four is backward compatible, so new enough.
Everything you do in selenium free will work in selenium for.
There may be some minor differences, but I plan to explain those differences and show you how to upgrade
in a later section of this course.
So I hope this lecture has given you a good understanding of Selenium history.
Let's move on to the next lecture.