In this lecture, we take a look at parameter rise in global variables.
So what are we trying to achieve?
We're trying to achieve a way to say global variables in an external location so that they are easy
to update.
Our test would then retrieve these global variables so they inherit any changes to the values.
This will prevent the need to update individual test cases, meaning easy maintenance.
So let's take a look at the design overview.
So first I'm going to create a properties file and I'm going to call this conflict properties.
And inside that file it will contain a key and value pair.
So if we look at the one highlighted in red, the key is u, r, l and the value is w.
WW dot website dot com.
I'm then going to amend our classes to observe this conflict of properties file.
Anent amend the methods within those classes to make use of the key and value pairs from the conflict
properties file.
So if we look on the right hand side I'm using driver dot gets but instead of coding in a hard coded
value to a website, I'm passed in the key from the properties file.
And so what I expect to happen is that the value.
W WW dot website dot com is passed to the parameter in the method from the properties file.
So two steps required to make this improvement is to create a properties file in our project.
I men need to create key and value pairs in the properties file.
For example, u r l equals a website.
I then need to amend our Java classes to make use of properties and file input stream.
So this is how we can pass the data from the properties file into our classes.
Then I need to amend our methods so that we can receive and use the value from the properties file.
We can then change the URL in the DOT properties file to observe the method to see how it inherits the
change.
So let's implement this improvement.
So the first thing I'm going to do in Eclipse is create a new package for Section 12.
So I'm going to right click the source folder, click new, and then click package.
And I'm going to give it a name of section 12 and then click Finish.
I'm then going to right click that package, click new and then click class, and I'm going to give
this class a name of l02 as this is the second lecture in Section 12 underscore.
Log in and then click Finish.
And that class will now open.
So what I need to do in this class is to set the set up code, to initiate the driver, to open up the
Chrome browser and expand the browser.
And also a simple test which will use the automation test or home page to select the log in link and
enter an email address and passwords and then try logging in.
So as we've done this before and instead of writing this manually, which will take some time and you
would've seen it, I'm going to expand Section 11 and I'm going to simply open up the Lecture nine annotation
Part two class, which contains the following.
So I'm going to take the reform effort code, the before suite code and the web driver driver line.
And on my keyboard, I'm going to use Control C to copy it.
And then I'm going to go back to my log in the Java class and I'm going to paste it in between the braces
like so.
So the only difference I need to make here is that instead of before method, I'm going to change this
to at test.
And I'm going to need to import the test annotation from Test and G.
So very quickly the before sweet handles the set up of the browser and the test itself goes to the test
store home page, clicks on the log in link and into an email address and password and then clicks on
the sign in button.
So what I want to do here is, well, I'm using driver Duquette and hardcoded an address.
I instead want to use a properties config file to pass that value.
So before I do that, I am going to minimize Section 11 so we don't get confused.
And I'm also going to close the lecture.
No annotations, part two from Section 11.
So now I only have the new cross open.
And I am going to cut this line here.
And I'm going to handle that instead in the before sweet annotation code.
So the next thing I need to do is to create eight properties, a conflict properties file.
And I can do that by right click in the Section 12 package, click in New and then click in other.
And you'll be given a number of folders here and you need to find general and expand it and then select
file.
And then click next.
So with the new package highlighted, we need to provide a file name.
So I'm going to call this l02.
Com fake dot.
Properties.
And then click Finish.
And that file would then be listed under the package and will be open on screen.
So here I need to provide a key and a value pair.
So I am going to provide the value of all the key of you.
Well, and it's going to equal a value of the URL, which I am going to get from the test store home
page.
So I'm going to copy that address.
And I am going to paste it like so.
So euro, which is the key, equals the address to the test or home page, which is the value.
I'm then going to save this file.
And I'm going to go back to my class.
So now I need to make my class use the conflict of properties file to pass the value using the key.
So to do this I am above the driver.
Don't get method again to make some space here and I am going to use a class called properties.
So we have a capital P properties and I'm going to provide an object name of prop equals new.
Properties.
With brackets and a semicolon.
And you will see it as an error on the properties.
And if I hover over it, I'm given the option to import it from java or util.
And that terror will now go away.
So the properties class represents a persistent set of properties that we can store a load from a stream.
So the next thing I need to do is use another class called file input stream.
So the following stream makes it possible to read the contents of a file as a stream of bias in Java.
That we can then use with the prop or the properties object.
So I'm going to write file input stream and I'm going to give an object name of data.
Equals new file.
Input.
Stream.
And in brackets it was semicolon.
So if I hover over follow input stream, I'm given an option to import this from Java IO.
And if I hover over new follow input stream, you'll see that I need to add an argument.
So what I'm going to do here is add double quotes and I need to provide the location of this conflict
properties file.
So if I right click it and go to properties, you'll see I'm given a location here.
And if I hover over that and highlights it and in control C to copy it.
I can then paste it within these double quotes.
And then if I hover over the red line again, you'll see that I need to add a froze declaration.
And once I do that, he ever goes away.
So this file input screen object requires a parameter value which simply contains the location of this
conflict properties file.
The next thing I need to do is use the prop object.
So the properties object.
And if I do a full stop here, you'll see that I'm given access to a number of methods.
And what we need to use is a method called load.
And you can see load expects an input stream.
So if I select that, you'll see that in practice it's already provided the data object, which is the
full input stream object.
And if I hover over this red line, you'll see that I just need to add another free declaration.
And that era will now go away.
So we are loading the data.
So the file input stream object into the prop properties object.
So the next thing I need to do now is use the key and value pair from the conflict properties file.
So I'm going to remove this double quote value and the double quotes itself in driver dot get.
And instead I'm going to use the object.
And on use full stop.
Get property.
And expect a string of a key.
So here I am going to use double quotes and I'm going to provide the key from the config.
The properties file I'm interested in, which is u.
R l.
And so this year oral matches the key you're oral from the conflict properties file.
So why expect to happen here is that the driver don't get method will now go retrieve the value of this
key from the convict properties file.
So I expect it to use this and pass that value to the driver.
Don't get method.
So if I say this now.
And try running it.
Let's see what happens.
So I'm going to right click zero to log in.
But Java run as a test in G test.
And you can see it's gone to the test or home page.
So one that has proven is that we were able to create a conflict properties file and set a key and value
pair.
And in our class itself, we was able to access the key and values from that file.
And we've used it in our test and in our case we've passed the value to our driver docket method.
So what this means is that going forward, when we have a number of classes instead of hard code in
utero, we can instead pass the value.
So why or when would this be useful?
So imagine if you're working for a company and they have a number of different environments, such as
a 81 and a 82 system.
That you are well will be different for each of those systems.
So if you've hardcoded your values in your classes, it would mean you'd have to go through every single
class to update the driver or get method.
But by using this method, all we need to do is simply update the value.
And then that value will be passed to all our classes if we use the prop, not get properties and then
pass.
You are okay.
So that is why we do this.
It's for maintainability and for our code to be flexible and configurable.
So I hope you've enjoyed this lecture.
And once again, thank you for watching.