So let's create a life project one.
So in Eclipse, you'll see that I have the free projects I've created previously.
I'm going to be creating a new project called Live Project one, and I'm going to create it through
Command Prompt.
So I'm going to minimize the clips for now and I'm going to open up File Explorer and then from my desktop,
I'm going to go to my resources folder.
And this is where the workspace folder resides.
And if open that, these are the projects I've created so far.
So I'm going to copy the path to the workspace folder.
I'm then going to open up command prompt and I am going to see day and pace that path to change directory
to it.
I'm then going to open up Chrome and if I type in Maven CMT, the first result should be to Apache the
org to the Maven in 5 minutes web page.
So this is where if I scroll down I'll find the create in a project section and there is a command here
which I'm just going to copy.
I'm then going to open up Notepad and I'm going to Pacer here.
So I need to make some adjustments to this command.
So from my group, Heidi, I am going to use UK AE the automation testing.
So this can be whatever you'd like it to be.
So you don't need to use the same value to use it and then need to update the artifact I.D..
So I'm going to call this project live.
Project one.
I'm then going to copy this full command and go back to command, prompt and paste it and then I'm going
to select Enter.
Maven should then create its project for us.
And I have build success, which means it's been built successfully.
So I am going to go back to File Explorer and in my workspace folder you'll see that there is now live
Project one.
So I'm going to double click it and you'll see a source and pom file.
So I am now going to copy this new path.
And in CMT I'm going to use a C D command to change directory into that new life project one.
So remember, I need to create the two new files so I can import this project into Eclipse.
So to do this, I'm going to go back to Command Prompt and I'm going to type in m the N.
Eclipse, colon, eclipse, and then presenter.
And you should see another build success.
And in File Explorer, you should see a class path and a project file.
So these are the two that we need to import our project into Eclipse.
So now I'm going to go back to the clips I'm going to file and I'm going to select the import option.
Then you should see a Maven folder, which if you expand.
And you can select existing MAVEN projects.
So if I select next.
I'm then going to browse.
And I'm already in my workspace folder.
So I'm going to select Live Project one and then click Select Select Folder.
And you see that so identified the pond, for example.
And if I could finish.
We should see that project is now imported into Eclipse.
So that's how we've just created our project and we've been able to import it into Eclipse.
And in the next lecture we'll start editing the POM file using the dependencies that we need.
Thanks for watching.