So this lecture is an introduction to the job of programming language.
So what is Java?
Java is the one of the most popular programming languages in the world.
Java was originally developed by James Gosling at Sun Microsystems, and it was released in the year
1995.
It is intended to let application developers at once and run anywhere, meaning that for compile Java
code it can run on all platforms that support Java without the need for RE compilation.
Java applications are typically compiled to bytecode that can run on any Java virtual machine regardless
of the underlying computer architecture.
Java is now owned by Oracle.
After the acquisition of Sun Microsystems in the year 2009 and 2010.
Java boasts over 3 billion devices, uses it, and Java is also an object orientated programming language.
So the core principles of Java are it must be simple, object orientated and familiar.
It must be robust and secure, it must be architectural neutral and portable.
It must execute with high performance and it must be interpreted, threaded and dynamic.
The Java uses.
The Java is used for mobile applications, desktop Google applications, web based applications, enterprise
applications, scientific applications, gaming applications, big data technologies, business applications,
distributed applications, and also cloud based applications.
And to some people's surprise, the Android mobile operating system actually uses Java at its core.
So some ideas used by Java developers on Eclipse Intelligence, Apache, NetBeans Code Envy and a popular
idea used by students is called Blue J.
And the reason why students use Bluejay is because it gives you a visual explanation of how objects
interact with each other.
So I hope this lecture was a good introduction to the Java programming language.
Let's now move on to the next subject.