So I have lived Project one open in Eclipse and the first step is to download the extent reports dependency
and add it to our POM file.
So I'm going to open up Chrome and in Google I'm going to tie up extent reports and the end and click
search.
So the first result should be this which is extent reports for selenium.
Com dot relevant codes.
So if I click this, you should see the following.
But this is an old repository for the developer.
So if I go back again to the results, you'll see that the second one is for com I even stack which
is their latest repository.
So if I click on this.
And then if I click on this extent reports link, it will show you all the latest versions.
So at the time of recording this video, version 5.0.8 was the latest.
So I'm just going to select this and I'm going to copy its MAVEN dependency.
If I go back to eclipse and open up my pom file.
If I go down, you'll see that this is my dependence.
U.S..
So I'm just going to add this as a last dependency like so and if I can hold control shift and f it
will reformat the code for you.
So you can see.
Com even stack extend reports 5.0.8.
And if I save this, you'll see that dependency will start downloading and install it in the bottom
right hand corner.
So I'm going to pause this video until that's done.
So now just finished installing.
I'm going to close the poem file.
I'm now going to create a new class for our extents manager and I'm going to do this under the base
package.
So I'm going to right click select new and select class, and I'm going to call this class.
Extent manager.
And then click Finish.
This would end open the class.
So the first thing I'm going to do is extend the base page.
So I'm going to write extends the base page like so.
You see it as an error under extent manager as we need to add the constructor.
So above the constructor, I'm going to start writing some new fields.
So I'm going to write these, and then I'll explain what they do as we come to write in the methods.
Public static extent reports and I want to call it extend reports like so.
And at the end of that line, a semicolon.
So if I hover over extent reports, you'll see I'm given an option to import it from extent reports
from com even stack extent reports, which is a dependency that we added.
So if I select that, the error then goes away.
The second field is going to be public static.
String.
And I'm going to give this string a name of extent.
Report prefix was semicolon at the end.
And the third and final field is going to be public.
Static.
And I'm going to use Fred Local.
And then in points he brackets inside that I'm going to add extend test.
And outside that pointy bracket, I'm going to give this a name of extend test.
Equals new Fred local.
Empty pointy brackets, empty round brackets and a semicolon.
And if I hover over extent test, you'll see I'm given an option to import that.
And that everything goes away.
So these are two free fields we need in this class.
So underneath the constructor, I'm going to begin writing my first method.
So this first method is going to be responsible for checking to see if this extent report fraud is a
novel value or not.
If it's an old value, it means it's not in use.
And so what this method is going to do is it's going to call another method which will be responsible
for setting up the extent reports.
So I'm going to.
Right here.
Public static.
Stent reports and on call this method get reports round brackets and an open and close embrace.
Inside this method.
I'm going to use an if statement which is going to take this field.
To see if your equals equals in no value, then open and close embrace.
And then I'm going to right set up stent reports.
And around bracket.
And in double quotes, I'm going to give a name of live.
Project one with a semicolon.
So there's an error on the setup extent report because this is referring to a method that we haven't
yet created.
So this error will go away once we create that new method.
After that close embrace, I'm then going to right return.
And I am going to return this filled here extent report.
So I'm going to simply copy paste it with a semicolon.
So I'm now going to write the second method.
And this second method is going to be responsible for the actual setting up of the extent reports.
So it's going to create a new extent.
Report object is also going to create the reporter object and then it's going to assign the reporter
to the extent reports.
So I am going to write public static extent reports.
Set up extent reports, then round brackets.
And inside those round brackets, I'm going to add a parameter of string test name and then open and
close in brace like so.
So this sets up extent report is the same as what I'm defining in the first method.
So inside this new method, I'm going to write extent reports.
And this here matches this filename here.
And it's going to equal new.
Extent reports.
Round brackets and a semicolon.
So this is create in the extent reports object.
And it's a sign in that value to this field here.
Next I am going to use the reporter.
And so we need to use the extent.
Spark reports a class.
And I'm going to give it a name of spark equals new.
Extent SPARC reporter.
And this takes a argument.
So around brackets again and inside these round brackets, I need to define a location where the report
is going to be saved.
So as we've seen previously, I'm going to use a system property to define a start in location of the
project directory and I can do this by simply write in system dot get property.
And inside these new round brackets, in double quotes, I'm going to write You suck the air.
So this will get me a starting location of live project one.
Outside that first close in round bracket.
I'm then going to write the following.
Plus.
And in new quotes.
Forward slash report.
Then forward slash again and outside those quotes another plus.
And I'm going to reference another method name, which is a method we haven't yet created.
So it will come back to this what is going to be an error until we do create this other method?
And this method is going to be called extent.
Reports.
Prefix underscore.
Name.
And it's going to take a parameter and it's parameters going to be called test name.
So I am going to add the carriage return there just so you can see on the screen what I'm typing.
Then after that, I am going to add another plus symbol.
And in double quotes, I'm going to write dots h l like so.
And at the end of that line, I'm going to simply add a semicolon.
So extent.
SPARC reporter has an error and then if we hover over it, we've got the option to import that.
And that area will then go away.
So the only other error we have is this method which we have yet to create, and we'll create that in
a little while.
So all this code is doing is is creating the extent reports object is creating a extent spark reports
who object and that takes an argument of a location of where the report is going to be created.
And that's simply going to be crazine it from the user directory, which is live project one.
And then it's going to create a new folder called Report.
And Inside the reports is going to use this method to get the name of the report, which takes the argument
of the text in them, which provides in a method.
Don't hate him.
So it's going to be great.
I hate him.
I'll file.
So the next thing I need to do is attach the reporter to the extent reports and so I can do this by
writing.
Stent reports.
I felt the dots.
Attach.
And you should have a method of attach.
Reporter.
Which belongs to the extent reports class.
So if I select that.
You'll see that there is a null value inside the brackets.
And so I'm going to change that and replace it with spark.
And spark is what we've defined here.
So I'm going to stop this video here and will continue in the next lecture.