So now what I need to do is if I go back to the website.
If I type in London.
And the results now appear.
So we're still in all these results in the list.
So what I want to be able to do is look at each of the results to find one that contains Luton in the
name.
And when one is found I want to select it.
So it appears in the from textbox.
So if I go back to the code, we've already done the hard work.
We've created a list called Origins, which stores all the results.
We then use A for each loop to iterate through each value in that collection.
And at the moment, we're printing out the result or the text of each iteration.
So what I'm going to do here instead is remove this line.
And I'm going to use an if statement.
So I'm going to write if.
Origin.
Dot get text.
DOT contains.
The value of Luton in opening close embraces.
Origin.
Dot click.
So what this is doing is that the for each loop is going for each single.
Each one of these values in this list.
And each time is going to check to see if the origin so the value of that particular iteration.
If the text contains the value of gluten.
And if it does, it will kick it.
So if I explain it from the website.
So if I search London, that loop is going to search each one of these results.
And each time it's going to check to see if luton's in name.
So it's not in this one.
So I expect it to move to the next one.
So luton's not within this one.
You'll move to the next.
This one here contains Luton.
So I expect it to click it.
So let me try saving this.
And let's see if it works.
And you can see that Luton was selected.
So if I try change in our code.
To look for Southend instead.
So if I go back here and change this to South Southend and now save my code and try running it once
more.
Let's see if it works.
And you can see that London Southend was selected this time.
So this code is very powerful.
It's dynamic and it's been designed in a way that it can handle any value that you provide to check
against all those values or results in that list.
So but code in this way, it allows you flexibility and it means that your code is more easier to maintain
and it can actually provide better functionality in terms of what you're trying to test.
So I am going to change it back to Luton for now and I'm going to save it.
So one thing I did notice when I wrote this code before I recorded the lectures is that sometimes you'll
find that the web page does not load the results in time.
So if I go back to the Web page, so when London is typed here.
Depending on the website performance or your network connection.
There can be a slight delay before those results appear.
And to avoid that messing up our test.
What we can use is a weight in selenium.
So this is a perfect example of when we can use an explicit white.
So to do that, I'm going to make a slight amendment to our code.
So at the moment I have list origins equals drive a dot find elements by it.
So I am going to change this and I'm going to make a slight adjustment by using a explicit weight.
So I'm going to write equals.
New Web driver, white.
And then I'm going to write.
Or open and close in brackets.
I'm going to pass the driver instance, then a comma, then the amount of time that I want the whites
to wait up to in seconds.
Then I'm going to do a stop, a full stop at the end of it.
So you can see where Driver Waits has an error, and that's because I need to import it.
So if a hover over, you've got an option to import it from selenium.
And on doing so that ever goes away.
So if I remove that dot again and retype it, you'll see I now have access to a number of methods and
I'm going to use the until method like so.
So inside the brackets, I'm going to use expected conditions.
Dot visibility and make sure to select the correct one here.
So I need visibility of all elements located by.
So if I'm present on that one.
You'll see it's now displayed.
And so what I need to pass within these brackets is the bonus.
Yes.
A selector and the value.
So what I'm going to do here is if I put a carriage return here, you should be able to see it a little
bit easier.
And I'm simply going to copy.
All this so up to.
Starting from boy and up to the first close in bracket.
I'm going to cut it.
And replace the null value like so.
And at the end of this line, add a semicolon.
And you can see the errors go away and it's been accepted.
So now I'm going to delete this line here.
Okay.
Some of the white space.
So now our code is ready to go.
So I am going to save this.
And try running it again.
And we can see no errors.
So this here, this white will handle if the results are ever delayed.
So the test won't complain about an error.
It will wait up to 20 seconds for those results to display.
And what that means is your tests will not be affected by any delay of the page loading or any network
issues you may experience.
So we have covered quite a bit in these lectures.
I hope it's given you some good practice and experience of understanding how we can formulate test when
we're dealing with quite complicated conditions.
So I hope you enjoyed this, and I'll speak to you in the next lecture.