So before we start configuring Jenkins, it's important to understand how you can operate.
Jenkins when you restart your machine or if you shut down your computer.
So when we've installed Jenkins and run Wharfedale, you'll see that command prompt in the background
is continuously run in Jenkins for us.
So if he wanted to stop Jenkins from runnin in command prompt if you hold down control C on your keyboard.
You'll see that it will stop.
Jenkins for us.
So if I was to go back to the Jenkins dashboard and refresh the page.
We should find that the session has now been closed.
And so what we need to do is restart Jenkins and we do that by following the exact same approach, by
running the war file.
But this time we haven't got through the admin set up or install the plug ins again.
So what I would need to do is simply go back to the location of where my Jenkins Wolf is residing.
Copy that path again.
And in command prompt.
If you're not already on in this path, you can simply see they go back to it and then we just run the
command again.
Java Java Jenkins dot war.
And on doing so, you'll see that it once again will start running.
Jenkins for us.
So if I go back now and refresh this page again.
You'll see that I need to log in, which is going to be the credentials I set up during the initial
set up.
And on doing so.
We're taken back to the dashboard.
So that's how you can stop and restart Jenkins.
So now that we're on the dashboard, as do some configuration, so you'll see an option for manager
Jenkins for select that when in provided with the following options.
And I'm going to select global tool configuration.
So the first step that we need to do is add a JDK to our Jenkins profile.
So I'm going to select Add JDK.
And the following will appear.
So I'm going to antique install automatically because I'm going to point Jenkins to my job.
A home, a location.
So if I open up another command prompt window.
And type in the command java python version.
You'll see the version of open JDK that we currently have installed, which is 11 .0.2.
So I'm going to copy that and I'm going to use that as the JDK name.
This Java home location is the location of that open JDK, which we know from our environment variables.
So I'm going to open up the environment variables.
And if I double click on this Java home environment variable, I'm going to simply copy that path.
And I'm going to paste it like so.
So that's telling Jenkins where our JDK resides.
So I'm then going to click Apply.
And that will say that certain.
If I carry on scrolling down, you'll see an option for Maven.
So we need to do something similar.
So again, I'm going to click Add Maven.
This time I'm going to antique the install automatically.
And I need to provide a name, a maven, even home.
So in that same command prompt window, I'm going to run the command MVA in.
Lengthen the.
And if I press enter, it will tell us what version of Apache maven we have installed.
So I'm going to copy that and paste as the name.
And if I go back to those environment variables.
I'm simply going to double click the MAVEN Home Environment variable and take the variable value.
And I'm going to pace that like so.
I'm then going to select the player.
And then save.
So that is the configuration that we needed to set.
So in the next lecture, we're going to create our first Jenkins job, and we need to add some further
configuration to the job, which I'll show you how to do.
Thanks for watching.