In this lecture, we explore some of the most common web driver methods.
So when we initiate the driver object, the blue methods are then available to use.
And I'm going to go through two key ones in the next few slides.
So first we have to get method.
The syntax it is is get an in brackets.
We provide a u of l.
So for example, drive it or get it in brackets and then double quotes.
And then we provide a you are aware of a website.
The purpose of this is that it will load a new web page in the current browser window.
Next we have gets current URL.
The syntax for this is get current URL with brackets.
An example is driver don't get current are.
And the purpose is that it will return a string represent in the current goal of the web page.
Then we have get title.
The syntax is simply get tighter with brackets.
An example is driver don't get title.
And the purpose is it will get the title of the current web page.
It returns the title of the current web page we've lead in and trained in white spaces stripped out.
Or now if one is not set.
Next we have find elements.
And so this is a common method that we're going to be using often throughout this course.
So the syntax is find element and they move in brackets I'm using by.
So an example is driver find element by dots and I'm using CC selector.
In the next set of brackets and within double quotes, I'm then providing a value of hash primary button.
So this is a unique idea of an element on a Web page.
The purpose of this is to find the first web element using the given method.
And it returns the first mentioned element on the current page.
If an element cannot be found, then it will throw a no such elements exception.
Next we have find elements with an s.
So the syntax is fluent elements and again we use by.
An example is driver find elements by and this time use an x path and in the next brackets and double
quotes, I'm providing a different take.
So the purpose of this is that it will find all elements within the current page using the given mechanism.
So it's going to find all elements that use the div tag and it will turn a list of all web elements
or an empty list if nothing matches.
Next we have the closed method.
The syntax for this is void to close.
An example is driver doc close.
And the purpose of this is that it will close the current window.
Or if there are multiple windows then it will close the current window which is active and then quits
the browser.
And then finally we had the quit method.
The syntax for this is void quit.
An example is driver acquits and the purpose of this is that it quits.
The driver instance close in every associated window which is open.
So this has been a brief overview of the most common Web driver methods.
We are going to be using them frequently throughout this course.
And by the end of this course, you'll be very familiar of how we use them and why we use them.
Thanks for watching.