In this lecture, we take a look at the test engine XML file.
So what is the test in XML file?
This file is at the heart of test engine.
The This file has many uses, but the main purpose is controlling what should run.
The content relies on XML tags that we use to control what should run its execution.
The content of the file follows a well structured tag hierarchy.
And the test engine example is often placed at the project level of our project.
So where does the test inject Jake Semaphore reside?
In this example, the test in G example has been generated and resides at the project level.
We can in amend the test, inject small file to control what packages or classes or test methods should
run an execution.
This is all done using very simple example codes which are demonstrate later in the following lectures.
So here is an example of the content of a test and XML file.
So you can see that I have sweet tags, which is the name of the suite, and inside it there are test
tags.
And inside that there is class tags with a class listed.
So when I run this test in XML file, it will run this particular class.
So let's look at an example of this.
So in Eclipse, I am going to create two new classes that I'm going to use to demonstrate how we can
use the test in XML file and in the following lectures we'll look at more detail of how we can use the
test in G file for flexibility.
So the first thing I'm going to do is simply copy and paste the lecture from the last one holding this
new one zero free a.
And I'm going to call it test in G, x, eml and then click.
Okay.
And then I'm going to open that class and I'm just going to keep the same structure, but I'm just going
to rename the methods and the output.
So I'm going to call this one method one.
And I'm going to change this.
Hello world from method one.
I'm going to change this one method to.
And it's going to be hello world from method to.
Then on the end to say this class.
And then close it.
Now I am going to copy and paste it and call this sec 1l0 free B and it's got the name of test engine
and all to click.
Okay.
And here I'm just going to change this one.
It's a method free.
And change that to free this one for and change that too for like so.
And then I'm going to say this class to.
So now what I'm going to do is right click on the package and if we go down, we can see we've got a
test n g option and we've got an option to convert to test then G.
So if I click on that.
You'll be shown the following.
And then if I click Finish.
You'll see that testing file has been created.
And if I double click on that.
You'll be presented maybe with a page like this, and if so, you should see a source tab.
And if we click on that, you'll see the actual example.
So if we look at the XML so far, you can see that it references free classes and this particular one
is the one from the last lecture.
So I am going to remove that.
Leave in just the two new classes I've created.
It's 11 zero Friday, and that was every freebie.
And if I save this now.
And enclose this XML file.
If I right click the XML file itself and go to run those tests in G suite, let's see what happens.
So that has now completed.
And if we go to the console.
You'll see that four tests have run and there's four passes.
And if I go up.
If you can see the output, it says Hello World for MiFID free for one and two.
So by using this test SML file, we are able to trigger all the tests that we require in one go.
So if I open up that file again.
And change the ordering of this.
So, Nat, now the ice file or the class runs before the B class if they'll say this now and try running
it again.
Let's see what happens.
And you can see Hello world from method one and two and three and four and those have been run.
But calling in the classes we've just created.
So this test is run followed by this.
And then in the second class, this was number one, followed by this.
So by creating that test testing XML file, we have the ability to run a number of tests in one go.
And in the real world, where you're likely to have, you know, tens or hundreds of test classes,
this gives us the ability now to run tests based on what we are trying to do, for example, in a regression
test.
You may want to run 50 out of 100 test scripts.
And that is now possible by using the test engine XML file.
So that's all I want to cover in this lecture.
And in the next lecture, we'll take a more in-depth look at how we can control what tests are on.
Thank you for watching.