In this lecture, we take a look at selenium web driver architecture.
So the following diagram provides an overview of how we can use Selenium Web driver to communicate to
a browser driver for which communicates to an actual web browser.
So if we look to the left hand side, we can see selenium language bindings.
And these are programming languages that we can use to develop our test scripts.
Once those test scripts are developed, we then need a means to communicate those test scripts to a
browser driver.
And this was achieved by using a protocol.
The browser drivers themselves is what controls the actual web browser.
So for example, Google provide chrome driver and chrome driver is an executable file that can be used
to control the Chrome browser.
And this is achieved by using HTP over CTP server.
So when run in a Selenium test, web driver needs to establish communication with the browser.
To do this, the browser and web driver have to use a set of rules that they both must share and respect.
Imagine two people having a conversation.
It's fundamental.
They both know and understand same language.
It's the same in automation.
So automation needs a common language.
In this case, the language is called a protocol.
Each browser has its own driver that knows the protocol and makes the communication between web driver
and the browser possible.
The protocol that Web driver has been running for a long time is called the Jason Wire protocol.
However, starting with selenium for this protocol will no longer be supported.
Although there will be some scenarios where selenium still provides mechanisms for people to use the
former protocol.
This legacy support provides backward compatibility to organizations that can't run their cases using
the new protocol.
The new protocol is called Web Driver W3C.
It has received the endorsement of the World Wide Web Consortium, who are an international community
that works to develop Web standards.
The creation of this protocol started a long time ago and has finally become a standard.
W3C is fractionally different from the original protocol.
The major differences are around how you can create a new session and how you can do element interactions
using the actions API.
Since Selenium version 3.8, we have been hearing about both the Jason Wire protocol and the W3C protocol.
The main change is that in Selenium version four, only support for the W3C protocol will be provided.
However, there should be little to no impact on developers since those modifications are at the wire
protocol level and not at the API level.
The Wave driver API will remain stable and constant and is actually expected to enrich the API going
forward.
Since Chrome Driver version 75, Chrome has been using the W3C protocol by default.
So if you've written any tests in the past, chances are you already use the new protocol.
So the developers of different browsers have agreed to adopt the W3C implementation, which would result
in consistency between different browsers devices and also provide stability.
The protocol has been developed with stability at the core.
It's expected test cases written in selenium will be much more stable.
The command API has been improved, offering a new variety of actions.
As a response to the modernization of browsers and devices means you can do things like multitouch,
press two keys at the same time, zoom and various other human like behaviors.
So to conclude this lecture, the implementation of the W3C protocol should not generate major problems.
The new principal is expected to give great benefits in terms of consistency and stability of the tests
in different browsers.
The Web driver API will be updated, adding modern actions.
So I hope this has given you a good overview of the Selenium architecture.
Let's move on to the next lecture.