In this lecture, we learn how to manage cookies.
So what are cookies?
Cookies are messages that web servers pass.
Your Web browser when you visit Internet sites.
Your browser stores each message in a small file called cookie dough.
Text.
When you request another page from the server, your browser sends the cookie back to the server.
These files typically contain information about your visit to the Web page, as well as information
you volunteered such as your name and etc..
Cookies are used to maintain sessions between the server and the client.
The below commands can be set by using driver.
Don't manage.
We are able to add return or delete cookies based on our requirements.
So let's take a look.
So first, let me walk you through the test.
I'm going to open up Chrome.
Go to the automation testing website and I'm going to click on the test or link, which will take you
to this page.
Now, what I recommend, if you're following along, is to sign up and create a dummy test account that
you can use specifically for those of you that are following along.
The reason for this is if you use my account at the same time of another user, you'd log each other
in and out.
So I am going to sign in.
And if you're going to create an account, click on this no no account button and you can sign up with
some dummy data and just remember the credentials.
So I'm going to go back because I've already created a account and I'm going to log in.
So you can see that I'm now signed in as test.
So I'm going to go back to the my store home page.
And I am going to click a product and I'm going to add it to my cart.
And click continue shopping.
So you can see that there was one item in my cart.
If I close the browser.
And then go back.
To the automation testing website and then click on the test store.
You can see that the item is still in my cart.
And this is done by using cookies.
So cookies know that I am the same user and it maintains the session.
And if I it right click and inspect this page.
And click on.
Applications had.
And then click on the cookies button.
You'll see the cookies that are on this website.
So if I try and delete that, press the shop.
Cookie.
And enclose his panel and refresh my page.
You'll see that that item has now been removed.
So this proves that my session to this web page is maintained by cookies.
And because I've deleted that cookie.
This website no longer knows that I am the same user.
So I am going to minimize this Web page for now, and I'm going to open up the clips and I'm going to
create a new class by copying and pasting the class in the last lecture.
Call in this new one l0 free.
And I'm going to give it a name of cookies.
I'm then going to open up this class.
And I am going to delete the Chrome Option section and the set capabilities and Design Capabilities
section.
And I am going then remove the option parameter from the chrome driver like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do is get the.
Home page or at the store home page address.
And I'm going to Pacer in the get method.
So I now need to go to the store home page to source the locators.
I need to carry out this test.
So on the test or home page, the first locator I need is the sign in button.
So I'm going to right click it, inspect it.
And I'm going to go to runner up the Lost City, and I'm going to simply get this one here and copy
it.
So instead of going back and forth to Eclipse and this Web page, I'm going to open up a notepad and
I'm just going to make a note saying sign in link and then paste in the locator there.
So once I click on that sign in link.
It will take me to this log in panel.
So I am going to inspect the email textbox.
It's run across velocity and just get at first.
Yes, a selector and make a note, say an email text box and paste that.
And then I'm going to do the exact same for the password.
Passwords, text books.
And so once I log in, so I'm also going to need the sign in button.
So let me get that.
Sign in button.
And then once I do sign in, so I'm going to use my test account.
So once I am presented with this page, I'm then going to click on this clothes link.
So I'm going to right click and inspect it.
Coach Brennan Velocity.
And I'm going to use link text, so I don't know what these two characters are.
This is just based on how the website has been designed.
So I'm just going to copy it.
And I'm going to like close link.
But I'm just going to delete those two characters at the front of that because I don't need that.
So where we're using link text here.
I'm just going to make a note of the link text locator.
That should work fine.
So once I click on this close link on Presenter Buddy's this page.
So I'm going to right click the first image.
And I'm going to get that.
So yes, I select about.
It's the first product.
And once I click on that first product.
They'll take me to this page.
So I want to click on Add to Cart Button.
So I'm going to right click and inspect it.
And I'm going to take the.
First one.
So add to cart button.
And then when I add to Cart.
Its eight shows the following panel.
So I'm going to select continue shopping.
So I am going to take.
This one.
Continue shop in button like so sardines are all the locators we need in order to write the test.
So I am going to minimize the browser and I'm going to use this now to write my test.
So I am going to write driver the find element by the set selector.
Double quotes and a semicolon.
And I'm going to copy this line a number of times just to save me some time.
So in that first one, I am going to open up Notepad and take the first selector for the sign in link.
And I'm going to paste it.
And as it's a button or link, I'm going to click it.
So for the second one.
It's for the email address.
A text box on the sign panel.
So I'm going to paste that.
But as it's a text box, I need to provide a value.
So I am going to use same keys and I'm going to use the test account that I've created.
Test at test.
Dot com.
So here, use the email address you've signed up with.
If you've created your own mum, if you're following along.
So in the next line of code, it's for the password textbox.
So I am going to Pacer here and I'm also going to have to send the value.
So I'm using keys and the password that I've used for my test account is test one, two, three.
So next is the sign in button.
And as this is a pattern, I'm going to need to click it.
And on the next line, it's for the clothes link.
So remember, this is not CSI select.
It is time because we're going to be using link text.
So a link text, double quotes and I'm going to place clothes.
And because it's a link, I need to click it.
So I'm going to use the Click Command.
So I'm just going to copy a couple more of these because I know I need a few more than this.
So next is the first product.
So I am going to pay sat here.
And the product is an image I need to click.
So let me use a click command.
Next is the add to cart button.
So I'm going to pay sat here.
And as is the button, I'm going to click it.
And then finally, is the continue shop in button.
I'm going to paste that here.
And as it's a button again, I'm going to use the Click Command.
So before I run this, I am going to add some frayed sleeps just to slow the test down so that we can
see what's happening a bit better.
So I am going to add 1/2 between each of these steps.
So now I'm going to say this.
And try running it.
Let's see what happens so far.
So it's gone to the asylum page.
It's provided an email address and password.
It's logged in successfully.
Click the clothes link clicked image one added it to cart and then it closed the panel by clicking on
the continue shopping button.
So you can see that there is an item now in my heart.
The cart is shown one.
So I'm going to close this.
And I'm also going to maximize the driver because I know the browser, because I noticed the browser
wasn't maximized.
So I'm just going to do driver dot manage thoughts.
Win, though, not maximize, son.
Right.
So you've noticed that there is a item in my cart.
So now what I'm going to do is I am going to delete all the cookies after I've added that item.
So I am going to write driver, dot manage.
Thoughts.
Delete all cookies.
So if I do this now, let's see what happens.
So it's maximized the browser.
This time it's logging in.
Just click on the Clouds link.
Click it on the first product and adding it to the cart.
So it seems to have frozen.
So let's go to a clip to have a look at the console to see what the error has reported.
So design elements is not intractable.
So I suspect the reason for that is, is trying to click on the continue shopping button before it's
loaded.
So here would be an ideal situation to add a white.
But as we've already covered whites and it's not the purpose of this lecture, I'm just going to add
that extend that Fred don't sleep to 3 seconds instead.
So let me just say that again and try running it one more time.
So again, is logging in.
It can the clothes they think they can product adding it to the car.
This time it's clicked continue shopping and if you look at the cart is Scott one item now.
But if I was to refresh the page now.
You'll see that cart has zero items in there.
And the reason for that is that we have deleted all the cookies.
The cookie that was track in my user session has been deleted.
And so now I it's been signed out as a user.
So just to prove that works, let me comment in sli now save it and run it one more time.
And this time what I'm going to do is I'm going to refresh the page.
And prove to you.
That's my session without deleting those cookies is maintained.
So I haven't run the delete all cookies come on this time.
But if I click the refresh page.
Notice how it knows that I am the same user.
So by simply using this driver, Dot managed to delete all cookies.
I'm able to delete the cookies of my test.
I hope you found this lecture useful.
Thank you for watching.