In this lecture, I go over some maven terminologies.
So it's important that we understand some of the key maven terminologies that we are going to use in
the upcoming lectures.
Understanding these terminologies is essential when creates and maven projects.
I'll be covering the following groups with the artifact I.D. and version.
Group D will identify your project uniquely across all projects.
So we need to enforce a name in schema.
A group said they should follow Java's package name rules.
This is to use a reverse domain that you control because this will be unique to you or your company.
For example, if I look on my vienne repository, I can find all dependencies that have been developed
by Selenium HQ because I can look up their group by day.
So this screenshot shows a number of dependencies that are owned by org dot selenium HQ Selenium such
as Selenium, Java, Selenium API and Selenium server.
As I own the domain w WW dot automation test encoder UK.
I might use the following group by D UK ae the automation test in.
If I worked for an organization called the made up company and they own the domain W WW dot the made
up company dot org then I might use a group by the of org not the made up company.
So if you don't have your own domain, don't worry.
This is more for when you work in a company in the real world that need to use and prior to this naming
convention.
If you're just following along and don't have a domain, you can just use any value locally.
Next up is the artifact guy de.
So you need to think of the artifact I.D. as the project name.
It can be whatever you choose it to be, but it must consist of lowercase characters and no unusual
symbols such as dollar or percentage.
If I was going to create a new Maven project to create a weather system, then I might set the artifact
idea as whether.
If we then combine the groups into an artifact I.D., then we might have the following.
So the red part is Mulgrew pointy, and the purple part is my artifact I.D..
So the following slide highlights the artifact I.D..
So all three of these is provided by.
Org dot selenium.
HQ dot selenium.
But they provide artifact guides for Selenium, Java, Selenium API and Selenium server.
So these are free separate projects provided by the same supplier.
Next up, his version.
So if you decide to distribute your MAVEN project, then you would release it under a particular version
number.
The main version, types and explanations are shown below.
So the major version is shown on the left hand side and we would use something like 3.9.
Minor versions would use something like 3.9.1 or 3.9.0.
So I hope this was a good overview of some of the key Maven terminologies.
And don't worry if you don't understand some of this, as will be using it, and I'll demonstrate it
in the next few lectures.
Thank you for watching.