In this lecture, we take a look at how we can send data to elements such as forms.
So how do we send data?
So we use a command called send keys.
And we've seen a couple of examples of this already.
The same.
His command emulates a user sending data to an element like a textbox.
For example, enter in John in the first name filled.
This command takes a parameter value, which is a value that gets sent.
This could be useful if you want to test the form, not those found on contacts pages.
So an example of how it uses command is driver defined element by name and in the first set of double
quotes is the selector value in only using keys.
And then in double quotes I provide the value of John, and John is the value that will get sent to
the elements I'm sending it to.
So let's try this out.
So the first thing I'm going to do is open up the clips and instead of creating a new class and define
an order set up code again, I'm going to simply highlight the class in the last lecture press control,
see and feel my keyboard to copy and paste it.
And I'm going to change the name of this new class to L zero Free Lecture three and I'm going to give
it a name of send in.
Later and then click.
Okay.
This will create a new class.
And if I double click it, the new class will open.
So I am going to delete this bottom line as I don't need it.
And I also need to change this driver thought jet method to point to a different page on the automation
test and website.
So if I go to Automation Test Encoder UK, I'm going to be using the Contact US form test page and here
we have a simple contact that's form.
So I've copied the URL and I'm going to paste it.
Update the get method to the new contact us form address.
So this code or simply open up chrome, expand the window and it will take me to the contents form page.
So I need to provide data for these fields.
So if I click on the page and then click Inspect, this would open up the developer's stores.
If I go to the Random Monstrosity tab and then user select the tool, I'm going to click on the first
name filled and this will provide some select the values that I can use.
So I'm going to use this first use as selector, but I don't believe I need the full selector value
in order to focus on the elements.
So I'm going to select the pencil icon, which will now place the selector into this textbox here,
and I'm going to delete his highlighted part.
So all I have left is this input.
Take the name of the first name.
If I press into my keyboard, you can see that only one element has been found.
So although of shorten this selector, this selector still only finds the one element that I'm looking
for.
So I'm going to copy that selector when I go back to Eclipse.
And I'm going to write some comments in my code just to gather the selectors before I actually write
the code itself.
So two Ford slashes in Java would imply a single line comment.
And then I'm going to paste the selector value for the first name field as shown.
Now I am going to go back to the automation testing websites and I'm going to get to select the value
for the last name filled by using the exact same method.
I'm going to use a pencil and I'm going to shorten this process selector.
I'm going to confirm that.
Still, any funds?
One element I selected into my keyboard.
And then I'm going to copy it.
When you go back to Eclipse and I'm going to write another comment to paste that locator.
And I'm going to do the exact same with the email address.
Again shorten in the selector.
Precedented to confirm one single element.
Get a copy that and paste it below.
And then one final one for the last text field, which is the comments.
And again, only one element is found.
So I've got a copy that.
And I'm going to paste it as my final comment.
So these are the four selectors for the text fields.
So now I'm going to write code to start using these selectors.
So I'm going to write Driver the find element by dot CSA selector.
And then in double quotes, I'm going to provide the first name selector.
So I'm going to simply copy and paste it within double quotes.
At the end of this line, I want to send data, so I'm going to write dot, send keys and then within
double quotes.
I'm going to provide the value, which is going to be the first name value I want to send to this text
field.
So I'm going to write John.
On the second line, I'm going to do exactly the same thing.
So I'm going to simply copy.
And pace the line above.
But instead of input name, first name, I'm going to use a second selector.
I'm going to replace the value within the first double quotes.
And he said that in my name, John, I'm going to change this to I'm going to use the name Smith.
So we were smart.
So then I need to do the same for the email address.
So I'm going to copy the line above and paste it.
I'm going to use a selector for the email address field and replace the one in the double quotes.
And instead of the name Smith, I'm going to replace this with an email address value.
So I'm going to write John Smith.
At.
Test dot com.
And in the final one is for the text, the textbooks message.
So again, I'm going to copy the line.
I'm going to replace the selector value.
And instead of the email address, I'm going to send a random comment.
So I'm just going to write.
This is a message.
Full stop.
So we have now written the four lines, a code that uses different selectors in order to identify the
text fields in the contact as form page.
And I provided values for these by using the same key command.
So for the first time, I'm sending John last name, I'm sending Smith email address, I'm sending John
Smith for test dot com and for the message I'm sending, this is a message.
So I'm now going to say this class and I'm going to try running it.
Let's see what happens.
So you can see that that data has passed that a form and it's worth correctly.
So that's how simple it is to send data using send keys.
Thank you for watching.