In this lecture, I'm going to show you the code that we need in order to interact with the Chrome browser.
So the first thing I'm going to do is open up Eclipse.
And under the default package, I'm going to right click select new and select class.
I'm going to call this class chrome.
Demo.
And I'm going to select public static web main and then click Finish.
So you'll see that the class has been created and that new class is now open.
So we're now in a position to start writing some code.
So the first thing I'm going to write system the capital S.
Dot set property and this is where I need to provide a key and the value.
So in these first couple quotes, I'm going to write Web Driver Dot.
Chrome.
Dot driver.
And the value is going to be the path.
So the chrome driver.
XY file.
So if I open up file explorer.
And if I go to my desktop and then look at my resources folder and then look at driver V1, you'll see
this is where the chrome driver resides.
So what I'm going to do here is get the path to this location.
So I'm going to simply copy this.
And then I'm going to go back to Eclipse.
And I'm going to paste it in those second double quotes.
Like so.
So this will now point to that folder location.
So the only thing I need to do is add two more bank slashes and then reference the chrome driver file
name.
So I'm going to a chrome driver to see.
On doing so.
This was established the full link to the location of the chrome driver file.
So we had the key.
And in the second quotes, we have the location of the chrome driver.
So you may have noticed that when I copied the path from File Explorer, there were single back slashes.
Yet when I place that path in Eclipse, no single backslash is replaced with double back slashes.
This is because a single backslash in Java represents an escape sequence, whereas a double backslash
will print out a backslash as would use in a path.
So let's write our next line of code.
I'm going to write Web Driver.
Driver.
Echo's new chrome driver with round brackets and a semicolon.
So you'll see there's two errors here.
If I hover over Web driver, you'll see I've got an option to import it from selenium.
And it's the same for Chrome driver.
And you'll see that the two imports appear at the top.
So we can now use this driver variable to call chrome driver methods.
So for example, if I make some space here, I can write.
Driver dots manage.
Dot window dot.
Maximize.
So when the Chrome browser opens, this line will maximize the Chrome browser window.
I'm then going to write.
Driver Dot get.
And here I need to provide a string, which will be an address to a website.
So within the double quotes, I'm going to write hij types colon.
Two forward slashes.
Then w w w dart's automation testing.
Echo dot uk.
I'm then going to save this class again to file and save.
If we then right click the class and select run as and Select Drive application.
Let's see what happens.
So you can see that the Chrome browser has opened and is going to automation test in the code UK.
So this proves our code works.
And it also proves that our code has been able to identify and interact with the chrome driver XY file.
So to prove this, let's change the path location.
So instead of driver underscore one, I'm changing it to driver underscore v2 which is a folded.
It doesn't exist.
If I then save and then try in this class.
Let's see what happens.
You can see it as an error in the console and the error states the driver executable does not exist.
So this proves that our earlier code was interacting with the chrome driver.
And it was able to do this by interacting with the chrome driver in this location.
So that is everything I wanted to cover in this lecture.
In the next lecture, we'll take a look at the Firefox browser using the gecko driver.