In this lecture, we take a look at explicit ways.
So the below process flow tries to explain how explicit whites work.
And if we start here.
First thing we do is we initialize an object using the web driver white class, and that object takes
two arguments.
The first is the driver instance, and the second is the time out duration, such as whites up to 10
seconds.
We then use the object to set an expected condition.
And that expected condition could be a number of things because there's a number of expected conditions
we can use.
But an example of one is visibility of all elements located.
And what that means is that condition will check to see if an element is available on the page.
The test then starts and the browser navigates to the page and the page begins to load.
The test, then searches for the element using the locator and then it checks to see if the expected
condition is mate's.
If it's not, then it checks to see if the time out duration has expired and if it has it when the test
am from an error.
But if it hasn't, it'll once again go through the loop to see if the condition has been met.
If the condition has been met, then the test proceeds.
So when used in explicit ways, we must import the following expected conditions and web driver weights.
We must then initialize a web, a weight object and an example below.
Of course, this object weights.
And I provided to arguments the driver instant and the amount of time I want the white to white, which
is 20 seconds in this case.
So if I use an explicit white command.
The Web driver is instructed to wait until a condition is met before proceeding to execute the code.
Web Java White by default calls expect the condition every 500 milliseconds until it returns successfully.
Sex and explicit whites is important when our case is where certain elements take more time to load
and others in order to declare explicit whites, one has to use expected conditions.
And some example of these expected conditions are below.
So we have elements to be clickable, elements be selected, visibility of and so on.
But you'll find in the real world you probably only use a handful of the same type of expected conditions.
So that below code creates a new web tribal white object called white and sets two parameters the driver
object and a time out time of 20 seconds.
We then set the expected conditions of the weight to use, of visibility, of element located methods
and provide a locator to a button.
If the button is found, then the test will proceed to try and click that button.
So let's see this in action.
So the scenario that I'm going to use in this demo is exactly the same as last lecture, where we're
going to wait for the loader to finish loading before trying to click on the button.
So I'm going to go straight to Eclipse and I'm going to simply copy and paste the class in the last
lecture, but I'm going to call this l04 and I'm going to give it a name of explicit
white like so, and then click okay.
I'm then going to double click on that class and I'm going to remove the implicit white code from last
lecture.
Like so.
So we know that we need to use the whites before we try clicking on that button.
And so I'm going to show you how we can use an explicit white.
So the first thing I need to use is web driver wise and I need to give a object name.
So I'm going to call it white equals new.
WEBVTT Driver White and in brackets.
So this takes two arguments.
The first is the driver instance, which is this here
and then following a comma.
The next value is the duration of the time out, so the maximum weight.
So I'm going to set this as ten for 10 seconds.
So as you can see, Webb drive a has an error.
And the reason for that is we need to import it.
So if you hover over it, you should see web drive a whites import option and if we click it.
That area now goes away.
The next thing we're going to do is now use this white object.
So if I write white an adult, you'll see that I'm being given some options and I'm going to select
until.
And then within those brackets of until if I use expected with a capital A and in conditions if I follow
that with a full stop, you'll see I have access to a number of methods and expect the condition I'm
going to use is this and I'm going to select the one of visibility of element located.
So if I select that one.
The following should show.
Now what this will take is the selective value, the locator value.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to simply copy this from below.
So this is going to locate the button.
So I'm going to copy it and replace now with that value.
And at the end of that line, just need a semicolon.
So I think I have one too many brackets.
I'm going to delete one and you'll see that error goes away.
So what we're doing here is we're using Web driver weights and creating an object where we where we're
providing the driver instant.
And also set in a time, maximum time of 10 seconds where they're using this object here.
Using you two until and then we use and expect the conditions and there are a number of different expected
conditions that we can choose from.
But a common one that's often used is visibility of element locate it.
So that's going to check the visibility of the element and it's going to be checking the visibility
of the element that we provide the locator for, which is the button in this case.
And then what is going to do is going to check for that condition.
And if that condition condition has been met, it will then move on to this line here.
So let's save this now and give it a try it.
And you can see that button was clicked.
And if I go back to Eclipse, you'll see there's no error here.
So you might be asking yourself, what's the difference?
And why do we need to use a explicit white over an implicit white?
And the reason for that is and this is the key difference is explicit ways are set against each locate
each element rather than global.
So for example, I could have two different elements on a web page.
Well, I know one of them might take 15 seconds to load where a second one might may only take 5 seconds
to load.
If we set an implicit weight of 15 seconds to account for the maximum white time of that of one of those
elements, then it means that all elements will have up to 15 seconds to load up.
And that might be a problem in a test because if there are multiple elements taking longer, so up to
15 seconds when they should take less time, such as 5 seconds, the test is not going to pick that
up because there's going to be a window of up to 15 seconds for it to load on every single element within
the test.
We've explicit, explicit whites.
We set the whites for the individual element itself.
So, for example, I can set this one here to wait 10 seconds, and if I've got another element which
takes 5 seconds, then I can use another explicit white for that particular element.
That's an important detail to remember, and that's why explicit ways are far more common than any other
type of weight in selenium.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And in the next lecture, we'd start looking at fluent whites.