In this lecture, we're going to create a properties file which is going to store our global variables.
So I'm going to store this properties file under a new package, and I'm going to call that package
resources.
This resources package will store the resources we need in order to create our framework.
So it's going to contain the properties file.
And I'm also going to store the base page, which I'll write in a later lecture.
So this is going to be created under Source Main Java.
So I'm going to right click that folder, select new and select package, and I'm going to give this
package a name of resources, and then I'm going to click Finish.
So on that new package, I'm going to right click select new and then select other.
And then under general, I'm going to select file and then select next.
I need to provide a file name, so I'm going to call this config dot properties and then click finish.
And that config, the properties file will now be listed under that new resources package.
So this is the file open.
So I'm going to create two variables.
The first one is going to be u, r, l, and it's going to equal and it's going to equally automation
test.
Then home page.
So I'm going to copy that address.
And paste it like so.
I'm also going to create a second variable and this is going to be called browser.
And by default, I'm going to set it as chrome.
So that's all we need to do here.
And then when we start creating the base page in the next lecture, we'll start using these variables.
So I'm going to save that file.
And that's it.
Complete.
Thank you for watching.