In this lecture, we look at the importance of using a base page class.
So a base page class can be used to store our reusable code.
So the problem we still face is that even though our code flexibility has improved, we still have repetitive
code in our Java classes.
For example, we still have code that initializes the driver in every Java class.
This goes against the dry principle, dry standard for don't repeat yourself.
We need to think of a way to place our common code into a separate location so to our classes can access
it when needed.
This will make our code more maintainable since any changes made to the common code will be inherited
by our classes.
So this is a design overview.
So as you can see, we have a conflict of properties file that contains key and value pairs.
We can use these values by sending them to the base page.
So in the base page we would have public methods.
And in this example, I have a public method called get driver, and this method will initialize the
driver based on the browser value from the DOT Properties file.
We also have another public method called Get your URL and this method will get the URL value from the
properties file.
What we can then do is create our Java classes so our test classes to extend the base page.
So this will mean that we will gain access to the base page public methods.
So we no longer need to initialize the driver in the test classes themselves and the same forgets in
the URL.
Instead, what we can do is simply call the base page public methods to retrieve those values.
By doing this, you can see that our code is simplified.
So this is an example of a log in test and it no longer contains the code to initialize the driver or
to get the URL.
All we simply do is call the methods such as get driver and get you able to get those values for us.
This is all made possible by looking at line seven where we use the extends keyword to extend the base
page.
So let's implement this improvement.
So the first thing I'm going to do is copy and paste the properties file from last lecture.
Calling this new one also for conflict properties and it contains the same key and value pairs.
And then going to right click the package, select new and select class.
And I'm going to call this Class l04, underscore base page and then click Finish.
This wouldn't open up the new class.
And this is going to be our base page.
So I need to add some new fields and then I'll create some public methods.
So the first field I'm going to create is public static.
Web driver.
Driver.
And I'll need to import web driver from selenium.
The org.
So take note.
I've used public and static, so public means that this field will be accessible from other objects
and other classes outside of the base page.
And the static keywords domain objects will share the same web driver driver field.
It will share the same instance.
So don't worry about this too much now, because I'd explain it in more detail in the framework section.
But the next thing is I am going to create my first public method, which is going to be called public
web driver.
Get driver.
In brackets and an open and close embrace.
So get driver will have an error because he's expecting a return statement.
And I'll be handling that in a moment.
But this public method is going to be responsible for initializing the driver.
And we've already done this in our L0 free log in class from last lecture.
So I'm going to copy from this point up two properties prop.
And I'm going to copy that.
And I'm going to paste it inside this method.
So you'll see there's an error here because I need to add a froze declaration.
And there's still an error because it's still expected in a return statement.
So I'm going to add that return statement at the bottom here.
So I'm going to right turn driver.
And this references this field at the top here.
So one other change I need to make is, well, we have copied this this code from the last lecture.
I need to change this here.
The reference, the new conflict or properties file.
So I'm going to change from l0 free to l0 for two point to this file.
So that is the first public method complete.
The next thing I'm going to do is create another public method to get the URL.
So I need to create a new field.
And this field is going to be called private.
String.
You are well.
And outside of the get driver method, I'm going to write public string.
Get u r l.
And what I'm going to write here is u r l equals.
And so this your role is reference in this field here.
So I'm again going to need to use the conflict properties file.
So I am going to copy these lines here from the get driver method.
And I'm going to paste it like so.
So now I'm going to write you URL equals prop dot get property and inside the brackets I'm going to
use double quotes and I'm going to get the key of you.
R l.
You'll see that there's an error here, because I need to add a pharaoh's declaration again.
And the final thing I need to do is add the return statement which will return u r l like so.
And you'll see that all errors will now go away.
So to run through this quickly again in this method, I again need to access the key and values from
the conflict properties file.
So if we use these lines here to gain access.
And then reference in the film.
You are well at the top of this class and it's going to equal prop which is this object.
Don't get property.
You are well and you are well.
Is this key here?
This thing and retrieve this value.
Is then going to return that value to the URL filled which is referenced here.
So I have now created two public methods in my base page and I am now going to save this class.
And I'm going to close these other ones.
And I am going to copy the l0 free log in class from last lecture and paste it in this new one.
l04 Log in.
Lincoln to open it, and you'll see it contains the following.
So now I am going to get rid of all the code in the before suite.
So I'm going to delete it like so.
And I'm also going to delete Web driver driver.
So you'll see that there's errors here.
So the first thing I need to do in this class is extends.
l04 underscore base page.
So this class will now extend the base page.
And by doing so, you can see that the driver is no longer ever been.
And the reason for that is, is because issues in this driver filled.
So if I try run in this test, let's see what happens.
And you can see that the testers average straight away.
And if we go up, we can see no points to exception.
So the reason for that is I need to call the public methods from the base page to initialize the driver
and to get the URL.
So I'm going to do this.
At this point here.
So I'm going to write Driver.
Equals get driver if brackets at the end and a semicolon.
And you can see there's an error there because I need to add a froze declaration.
So the next thing I'm going to do is again use driver, but this time I'm going to use dot get.
And inside those brackets, I'm going to get you as well, which is the name of the other public method
from the base page.
So now if I save this class.
And try running also for login again.
See what happens.
And you can see Chrome has opened and it ran the test successfully.
So let's try creating another class.
So I'm going to simply copy and paste the URL reserve for log in class.
Keep in the name.
Also for log in to.
So this second class will be identical.
It again extends the base page.
I'm then going to close these classes and I'm going to open up test in G the example.
And I am first going to change this to reference the first logging class.
So therefore log in.
And then I'm going to copy and paste this line below.
And changes to log in to.
I'm then going to save this file.
And I'm going to right click and run it as a test in G Suite.
So you can see that the first test has run.
It then opens up a second browser window and it runs the second test.
And if I go back to Eclipse, you'll see that two tests have run.
So this proves that our test classes can share the resources from the base page.
So as long as those classes extends the base page, it will be able to access the public fields and
code public methods.
So the one final thing that I'd like to do here is create one more method which will be responsible
for taking screenshots.
So if you remember back to Section nine, we actually covered this in the Ellsberg Force Screenshot
lecture.
And this method here is what takes screenshots.
We then use a second method to retrieve the timestamp that we use in the screenshot file name.
So I'm going to copy both of these methods.
And I'm going to paste it near the end of my bass page class.
And then going to close the other class.
And inside this space page class, I'm actually going to remove the static keyword.
Because this is no longer required.
So in my base page now I had the get driver method which initialize the driver, get your URL which
gets the URL.
And now I have take snapshot which takes a screenshot and timestamp which generates the timestamp which
we use in the file name.
So now I am going to save this base page and I'm going to open up l0 for login from section 12.
And I'm going to amend this class to take a screenshot.
So I'm going to make some room here.
And all I'm going to do is use this method name.
So I'm going to paste it here.
And then in brackets, I need to provide a web driver instance.
So I'm going to write driver.
So if I go back to the method, you'll see that this method requires a parameter of web driver.
So that's why I'm pass in dry over here is pass in the driver instance to this method.
So now if I save this.
And try running it.
See what happens.
So far return to eclipse.
It says the test has passed.
And if I go back to my base page and look at this method, you'll see that these screenshots are being
stored at this location.
So if I minimize this and go to my desktop and then go to my resources folder and open up this screenshots
folder here.
You'll see that there's a screenshot.
And that is a screenshot from that particular test.
So what we've done there is we've simply called a public method from the base page and passed the driver
instance in order to take this screenshot.
And this method calls this timestamp method to generate the time stamp which we used in the file name.
So I apologize for this lecture being quite long, but I hope you found the concept of a base page useful.
It's an important topic to understand, and I hope that I'm given a clear explanation.