In this lecture, we take a look at job variables.
So what are the variables?
Variables?
Store data, values.
There are a number of different variable types in Java such as string, which is used to store text
values int which is used to store integer whole number values including negative numbers boolean.
And this can be even true or false char which stores a single character such as an uppercase a or lowercase
a floats is thoughts floating point numbers, for example 10.99 or -10.99 and then its double which
is like float but has greater range of precision but requires more storage.
So let's try it out.
So in this lecture, I am going to show you how to declare a variable and how to assign value.
In the next lecture, we'll take a look at the data types in more detail, and I'll provide a demonstration
of how we can use the different types of data types.
So all I'm going to do in this lecture is copy and paste the class on the last one, and I'm going to
call it l05 and I'm going to give it a name of variables and then click.
Okay.
So I'm going to double click that new class and remove the code from the last lecture that we don't
need.
So all I'm going to do here is, is, is create a string variable and I'll do this a write in s t i
g the capsule s go get the string in name.
So I'm going to call it dog.
Great.
With a semicolon.
So I have just created a variable who does not breed, which is of type string.
Now.
If I wanted to assign a value to dog breed, I need to use the equals sign.
And that equal sign is used to assign values to the variable.
So if I use double quotes now.
And signed a value of poodle.
This dog breed variable will now contain a value of poodle, so it references a value in memory which
points to a value of poodle.
So that's how we assign values to variables in Java.
So in the next lecture I'd expand with more examples.
The key concept to takeaway from this lecture is simply how we can create variables and how we can assign
them values.
Thank you for watching.