So let's conclude Section one by going over core support so you can get help if you need it.
So I encourage people to have discussions with other students as this is a great way to share ideas
and approaches.
There are a number of ways to code, so someone might have an entirely different approach to another
person.
If you think you can help another student, then feel free to offer advice or a solution to their problem.
This enforces repetition, and repetition is great to reinforce your learning.
This is also a form of revision, as you'll be rethinking of how you did something.
It's likely that your question has already been asked and answered before.
Udemy provides a Q&A section for each course and lecture.
This has been improved and now accepts words and phrase searches.
You can also go to in a particular lecture or search questions from the whole course.
So this is a demonstration of the Udemy Q&A section.
So each lecture has a Q&A link under the video, and if you click it, you'll be presented with a page
similar to what's shown.
You then need to decide whether to search using the full course or in the current lecture by selecting
one of the two options.
You are then able to enter key words or phrases to perform a search.
And if you click enter, it will never return.
Results match in those keyword or phrases.
So I am searching for how to identify it.
And it's found 298 related questions which either contain those key words or phrases.
If you then select the question, you'll be taken to the question page and it's here.
You'd often find discussion and a solution to your question.
It's very common to come across code errors when learning a new technology.
They don't be put off as it happens to all of us on a regular occasions.
Look at the code.
Ever log and identify the key words from the error message.
So in this example, no such elements exception, web driver and Java are the key words.
We can in search for these keywords using a search engine like Google or Bing.
And you'll find that it's more than likely someone has asked for help on this area before and a solution
is already provided.
This often saves time.
Each coding lecture from this course will have code attachments for which you can download.
Use these code examples to compare to your own.
I recommend you try coding along in each lecture.
If you come across an issue, then download and compare your code to the course sample code.
Try to understand why the issue occurred.
If you still can't find an answer, then leave a new question on the lecture you'll have in trouble
on.
Make sure to highlight key words in a title so that others can find the question in the future.
I will answer questions as soon as I can.
And remember, debugging and practice helps you learn.
I picked up a lot of my knowledge by learning to debug errors and to learn from my mistakes.
Finally, ratings and reviews really help give this course exposure.
If you like this course, then I would really appreciate a positive review.
This will enable me to spend more time dedicated towards improving this course and to work on new content
in the future.
Finally, thank you for enrolling and I hope this course meets your expectations.