In this video we look at why frames.
So what is that?
My frame.
iFrame is short for inline frame.
It's a component of a terminal element that allows you to embed documents, videos and interactive media
within an existing web page.
Think about the many websites that embed YouTube videos.
They most likely do this by using embedded codes that use an iframe to reference YouTube video web page.
This will give the impression that YouTube video is part of the web page that you own when in reality
is simply a portal to the original YouTube content.
So let's look at the code below.
So on the left hand side, the user is presented with a video.
But if we look at the code itself, we can see that the embedded code is actually surrounded in iframe
tags.
And if we look within those iframe tags, we can see there is a source and that source points to the
actual video that may exist on a different website.
So let's look at a web page that has in my frame.
So I'm going to open up Chrome and I'm going to go to the automation test and website.
And if I click on the iFrames link, it will show you two examples where videos or in other websites
has been embedded inside a web page.
So in this top wireframe.
You can see that actually it's in my frame pointing to automation test in itself and I can use the websites
as if I was actually on the main page.
And if you look at the second wireframe, it's actually points to a YouTube video.
So what I'm going to do here is right click the page and view page source.
And if I look through this HTML.
You'll be able to see iframe tags.
So here's the first one.
And here is a second one.
The second one is that a YouTube video?
So you can see that the YouTube video has an iframe with a source and it points to youtube.com.
So if I go back to the automation testing website, you can see I can also right click the video and
copy video.
You are well.
And if I open up a new tab and paste that URL and in search.
You'll see that it's take me to the actual video where the video is hosted on YouTube.com.
So what's important about my frames?
So the important thing about time frames is that you can't interact with wireframes directly through
the web page.
So if I was writing a test on this iFrames Web page, and then during the test I wanted to click on,
say, one of these buttons within an iframe.
We can't do that directly using streaming web driver.
We have to use a method to switch to the iframe to be able to interact with it.
And then once we've finished, we need to switch back out to the main content.
So the important thing to remember is that we need to switch selenium web drivers, focus to the content
within the iframe itself and then switch back.
Once we've finished.
So I'm going to give you a demonstration of this in the next lecture.
But for now, I just want you to understand what wireframes are and how we need to handle them in terms
of switching focus to them.
Thank you for watching.