So now that we've created our base page, let's look at ways of how we can improve it.
So I'm going to copy the base page of Last Lecture calling this new 105 base page.
So if we look at this code here, we're set in a properties object and a file input stream object.
But notice how we're also doing the exact same in the get URL method.
So we are repeating ourselves, which doesn't comply with the dry principle.
So a better way to handle this is to use a constructor.
To use a constructor you write public and then you simply pass the class name.
Then round brackets and an open and close embrace.
I'm then going to cut this code here and I'm going to paste it like so.
And if I add a froze declaration.
That era will not go away.
But notice how I've got an error here and I've got an error here.
And the reason for that is this method cannot see this prop object because it belongs to the constructor.
So instead I need to create a field which is going to be private.
Properties prop.
And that means I can they can get rid of this properties reference.
Because this will now reference the filled.
By doing so.
Notice how those errors go away.
And that's because this method can see this field.
So if I go to the early section I'm in, I'm going to remove these lines here like so.
And again, this method will reference prop, which is this filled here.
So if I save this place, page.
And if I copy and paste also for login.
Change in two Ellsbury.
Five Logan.
So this is just a simple test.
So I need to change this to.
There are five.
Notice.
How is now an error?
And if a hover over the error, it says add constructor.
So if I click that, it adds the following code.
And so what is code does is that because we extend in the zero five base page and because there is a
constructor in that base page.
It then instructs us to use another constructor.
So this is the same as this class is name, but it uses the super keyword.
So that super keyword means to call the constructor in the class extends to.
So by adding that super keyword and saving.
That era now goes away.
And if I was to now run this log in test.
You should see that the test runs perfectly fine.
So that proves that by using a constructor in the base page to handle the properties of file input stream
and in amending our test the code a super constructor, we was able to access the configuration file
to get the driver and get URL.
So the second improvement I'd like to show you is to amend these direct ripoffs.
So currently I'm using a directory path using the C drive and a file structure that is specific to my
local machine.
The problem with this is that if I was to export this project and someone was to import it using a new
machine, they would have a different local directory structure than what I'd have.
And so the project wouldn't work.
Now to get around this issue, we can use a system.
Properties set in soda instead uses the highest level of the project as a starting point.
So let me demonstrate this to you by amending the following stream.
So I'm going to use a system.
Dot get property.
And inside the brackets I'm going to enter user dot dot r.
So what this set in here means is that it should start at the highest level of the project structure.
So I'm then going to add a plus sign.
And then double quotes.
Now inside these double quotes, I'm going to enter the remaining path to point to this file.
So if I right click this file and go to properties.
If we look at the highest level of the project Explorer, the starting point is a intro folder and that
is mentioned here.
So I am going to get the remain remain in part the path to the file name I acquire.
And I'm going to copy that.
And I'm going to paste it in those double quotes.
So it's very important that you use the same structure that I've used here.
So don't miss, like, the back slashes.
Otherwise, you'll get errors at runtime.
But to very quickly run through this again.
This here means to start here and in the plus source, which is this folder.
Section 12, which is this package.
And then it's going to look for this file name, which is this here?
So I'm going to finish this by entering a closed bracket, which is a closing bracket from this one
here.
And then I'm going to enter a semicolon.
And because I no longer require this line, I am going to delete it.
So to prove this works, I'm going to save this.
And I'm going to run the l05 login test again.
A right click in selected run as a test.
And you can see that it was able to get the URL and it was able to access those values in the conflict
properties file.
So that's proven.
This approach works.
So we can use a similar approach to handle the parts to the drivers.
So the issue is currently that I'm storing these drivers on my local desktop under a driver v one folder.
So what we can do is import these drivers into our project and then reference those drivers using the
system.
Get properties.
So I am going to right click the source folder, select new and Select Package, and I'm going to give
it a package name of drivers.
So that drivers folder is now up here.
So I am going to go back to my resources, drive av1 folder and I'm going to copy that and I'm going
to pass those into the driver package and then you'll see them listed here.
So now these drivers belong to our project.
We can use system, get properties and then point to those drivers.
So I am going to make some room here and I am going to use system.
Dot get.
Property.
And again I'm going to use user thought.
These are.
And then I'm going to use plus.
And in in double quotes.
I am then going to reference.
So we're pointing to this.
If I right click and go to properties on the chrome driver, see.
So this is a starting point.
So I am going to copy the remainder like so.
And I'm going to paste it in the double quotes.
And then I need to finish that with a closing bracket and a semicolon, and I'm no longer required as
here.
So I'm just going to copy same line and replace the get co-driver.
But changes from Chrome driver.
To Gecko driver.
And the same for the edge driver.
So instead of chrome driver, it's going to be.
Edge driver.
Then I'm going to say this face page.
And then I'm going to try run in the zero five, log in, test again.
To see if that works.
And you can see the Chrome browser opened.
And the test worked perfectly fine.
And that was using.
The system, get property to code, use a directory which is available here, then it looks at source
drivers and then it uses used chrome driver XY.
So now if I exported this and someone else imported it using their own machine, the project would work
fine because where we use in system get property user directory, it will be consistent and the same
if they imported this project.
So those are the two improvements I wanted to demonstrate to you.
So this is an improved code in a practice where we've used a constructor to handle and prevent the need
for repetitive code.
And we've also used a user, the air system property, to point to the highest level of the project,
which will allow our project to be exported and work with our issues on another machine.
Thank you for watching.