Now that we've created a new Web driver instance class, let's make changes to our base page.
So the first change I'm going to make to this base page is to move this line here.
So this is where we define in the Web driver driver variable.
But in our previous lecture where we created the new class, we've defined this line here, which is
using Fred local web driver driver, meaning that the base page line is no longer required.
So I'm going to delete it like so.
The next change I need to make is to describe the method.
So this is where I was originally initialized in the driver.
But as we're also doing this in this new web driver instance class.
It means that we no longer need this code here.
So I am going to delete most of the content but keep the get driver method.
And the reason I'm keeping the get driver method is because when it's called, I now want to return.
Using the new Web driver instance class.
If I add a dot here, you'll see that I've got access to different methods.
So I'm going to use the get driver method and add a semicolon at the end.
So when this method is called in the bass page class, it will now return web driver, instant stock
get driver, which is a method that belongs to the new web driver instance class.
Here.
And as we know, this new method uses to create driver to initialize the driver that we require.
So we also have public stream get you are l and we don't need to make any changes to this particular
method.
But if I go further down, we have a method called take snapshot which is responsible for taking a screenshot
when our test comes across an error.
But we can see that there's an error underneath driver.
And this is because I've deleted the driver variable at the top.
And so I need to make a change here.
So instead of the driver being defined, I'm instead going to call get driver.
Which is a method defined here.
So that's all the changes we need to make.
The only other method we have is time stamp, which simply generates a date and time that we use when
we create the screenshot file here.
So now I've made those changes to my base page.
I'm going to save it.
And in the next lecture, we'll start looking at the next class that we need to amend.