So in this lecture, we're going to create our base page for the project.
So the first thing I'm going to do is right click the source main Java folder, select new and then
select package.
And I'm going to give this package a name of base.
So this is simply going to be a package where I'm going to store my base class.
So I'm going to right click that package, select new and then select class, and I'm going to give
it a name of base page like so.
So this base page is going to contain very similar codes to what we did in an earlier lecture.
So I'm going to expand the intro folder, go to section 12 and in Open Up Lecture Firebase page and
you'll see all the code that we've written before which handles initialization of the driver.
It uses the config properties file.
And it also gets you a URL such as the automation test and website address and takes a snapshot.
So rather than point in all this code manually by hand, I'm going to simply copy all the methods and
the fields, and I'm going to copy those and I'm going to paste it inside my new base page class.
So you'll see that there is an error here.
And this is because I simply need to rename this base page.
Like so.
And you'll see that there is no other errors in our.
But remember that in this we were pointing to a config file that was specific to section 12.
So I am now going to minimize the intro package or project, and I'm going to close the lecture firebase
page from the earlier lecture.
And instead what I'm going to do is now amend this base page so that it's relevant to our new life project
one.
So the first thing is to get the directory of the new configuration file.
So I can simply right click the configuration file.
Go to properties.
And like we've done previously, we know that where we use user dots, the air is going to take us the
highest level for the project, which is live projects one.
So I need the following path that comes after that.
To which I'm going to copy.
And I'm going to paste in these quotes here.
So this will now point to this configuration file.
The next thing I need to do is also get the driver locations.
And so I need to import these drivers into my project.
So I am going to create a new package which I'm going to right click Source Main Java, Select New and
Select Package and I'm going to call this drivers and then click Finish.
So the next thing I'm going to do is go to my desktop, to my resources folder and into my drivers folder,
and I'm going to copy those drivers.
And I want to go back to eclipse with the driver's package highlighted and press control V $2 drivers
in that package like so.
So these are the lines of code where we initialize the drivers.
So if I quickly review days we use in user directory which is the highest level.
And then it's looking at the source folder.
But as we use in Maven, we're going to need to change these directory paths.
So I'm going to simply right click chrome driver XY, go to properties and after Light Project one,
I'm going to copy the remaining path.
And I am going to simply replace this like so.
And for the gecko driver, I'm again going to paste it.
Changing chrome driver to get co-driver.
And then for my age, I'll just copy like so.
And then we had the Mercedes driver also listed.
So we've set our config file and we've also corrected the parts to the drivers that now belong to the
project.
So if I scroll down, you'll see that there's also a path that is to model at my local machine level
where I'm storing screenshots.
So another thing that we can do here is create a new folder to store these screenshots that belongs
to the project.
So I'm going to expand its target folder and you'll see there's nothing, nothing currently there.
So if I right click target select new and select folder.
I'm going to create a new folder called Screen Shots and then click Finish.
If I right click the screenshots folder, go to properties again, I'm going to locate Live Project
one and I'm going to copy the part that follows that like so.
And then I am going to update these double quotes to contain that new path.
I'm also going to add two more tax slashes.
And remember, I need to copy the user directory part.
So that the project knows or this method knows to use the project level as a starting point.
Like so.
So this is now our code for our base page.
So this is all we need at this point.
And we're going to start making use of this space page as we start constructing our tests.
Thank you for watching.