So in this lecture, we're going to run our first job.
So if I go back to the dashboard, you'll see that there is a new row here.
And this is the name of the first job that we've just created.
Good job one.
If I select the name of Job one, it will take me to the job one page and I have a number of options
here.
So I'm going to try run in my job one by selecting this build now button when doing so.
We should see a new rather appear here on the build history, which is number one as it's the first
time we've done in this job.
And if you look over here, you'll see two bounces just opened up and they run in my tests.
So again, we're using parallel execution.
So it's running two tests at the same time.
So let's just wait for this to complete.
So now let's complete it.
Sometimes Jenkins gets stuck, say a few refreshed page.
Your seat is being updated, but it has a red x.
So that rate X is expected.
And that's because one of my tests purposely fails.
So if I select that hash one.
It will take you to the following page.
Well, we've got an option for console output.
If I select that this is similar to the console that we have in Eclipse.
So if I scroll down, we should see that two tests have run, but one failed.
And if we look further, we can see that it failed because of an assertion error.
We're expected a $45.23 to be provided, but found 4524.
So to add remove item basket test found as we would expect it to.
So that's how we run.
We can run our first job.
So the good thing about Jenkins is that if you do ever come across Evans, all you need to do is select
this build history.
So this is number one because it is our first time running a job.
But if I was to build again, you'll see the second one has now appeared, and that would do exactly
the same as what we just did last time.
But for each of these instances, we can then review the console output.
So if you do come across any other errors, it will be a matter of reviewing the console output to try
and understand why it failed.
Another useful thing is that if we click on the job again, we can look at the report output.
So if we go back to the council output.
And scroll down, you'll see that we should have a location where we can look at the report that has
been generated.
And this is found here.
So it's saying if we go to the Jenkins live project, one Target or Fry Reports voter, we should find
that report.
So let's take a look at that.
So I'm going to go to that location.
So.
Jenkins like project one.
If I go to test output, you'll see an index file.
If I double click that.
You'll see that there is a report here which is showing that my test has failed and one has passed.
And reasons why that failure occurred.
So that's how we can run our jobs in Jenkins.
Thank you for watching.