In this lecture, we're going to create a new class in order to create code which will interact with
the Firefox browser using the gecko driver.
So in Eclipse if I double click and open the chrome demo class from last lecture.
Much of this code is going to be very similar to what we need.
So I'm going to close this class and we have it still highlighted.
I'm going to simply copy and paste it by using the control C and then control V on my keyboard.
On doing so I'll be asked to provide a new name for a new class.
And I'm going to call this fire.
Fox.
Demo.
And then click.
Okay.
And then you'll see Firefox demo dot Java has been created.
And if I double click that class, you'll see that open.
Sudan are a few things we need to change in this new class in order to interact with the Firefox browser.
The first is this set property line where we need to change the key and we also need to change the path
to the driver.
So if we follow this path and look in file explorer.
We can see that all the drivers are located at the same location.
So all we need to do is change the driver name.
On the second line, you can see that we're also using Chrome Driver.
So this is something we also need to change.
So let's start making the changes.
So on the set property line, I'm going to replace Web Drive Adult Chrome driver with web driver.
Dot Gecko driver.
And in the value set apart location.
I'm going to change chrome driver to gecko driver.
On the second line, I'm going to replace Chrome driver with with Firefox driver.
But note that the second F fox is lowercase.
If we then hover over Firefox driver, we've got an option to import it from selenium and on doing so,
that red line goes away.
And if we look at the imports at the top, you'll see the Firefox driver has been added.
Also notice we've still got the Chrome driver listed and since we're not using that in this class,
we can simply highlight and delete it.
So the rest of the class can remain the same.
So we can use driver dot manage window maximize to maximize the Firefox driver and we can also still
use a driver to get methods to go to the automation testing website.
So let's save this class and give it a try.
So I'm going to right click Select Run and Select Drive Replication.
Let's see what happens.
So you can see that the Firefox browser has opened up and it's expanded the Firefox window.
So you may remember back from an earlier lecture where I very briefly explained the use of the Web driver
interface.
So here we use it in our code.
And currently web driver driver equals new Firefox driver.
So this driver could be anything.
It could be a Firefox driver.
It could be a chrome driver.
Or it could be an edge driver.
And the reason for that is because driver is the type web driver.
So how he could write this as well is Firefox driver driver equals new Firefox driver.
And if I say this class and try running it, you'll be accepted.
But the problem is, is that if we wanted to try to change a driver, chrome driver and import chrome
driver.
You'll see they won't be accepted.
And if you hover over the error, says type mismatch.
So this is why we use the web driver interface.
If I change this back to Web driver.
You can see that driver now equal chrome driver.
So this helps support cross browser testing.
We're able to easily change the driver type and we can do that because we use the web driver interface.
That is everything I wanted to cover in this lecture.
In the next lecture with take a look at the Edge browser and driver.
Thanks for watching.