In this lecture, we look at the importance of using a good naming convention.
So consistent names.
Imagine you had ten test classes but only want to run methods that are aimed at testing a tablet like
an iPad.
You can very easily do this by using testing groups and we cover groups later in this course.
But you could also use a consistent method name to.
For example, look at the below Java method names and you'll see some of these start with tablets.
Others start with desktop and the remaining ones start with the word mobile.
If we want to run just the tablet related methods, then we can do that by simply amending our test
in XAML file.
We can use the include takes to run methods that have a particular value in the name.
For example, if we look at the below code, you'll see to I've used a method tags and then inside the
Memphis tags I've used the include the take and I've provided the name of equals tablet dot Asterix
and that Asterix employs a wild card.
So it will look for anything that has tablet and if in after in the name.
When we run this code, I need the methods that have tablets in the name will execute.
The Asterix acts as a wildcard character, meaning anything following the tablet were then will run.
This is useful because it gives us flexibility in being selective in the tests we choose to run.
So let's look at an example of this.
So in Eclipse I am going to copy the last class that I have available and paste it.
And I'm going to call this new 1l06 because we in lecture six and I'm going to give it a name of home
page like.
So I'm going to click.
Okay.
I'm going to double click top in that class.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to rename these methods.
So the first one I am going to call desk top.
Underscore.
Log in.
And the second one I am going to call desk top and the school.
Adds item.
And this third one I am going to call tablet underscore log in.
And I am going to create two more methods.
And I am going to call this one here.
Tablet add item.
And I'm going to call this one here mobile, the score log in and I am just going to change the name
of the system out message for each one of these.
So I'm going to say this is desktop login.
This one here is going to be desk top.
Add item.
Tablet login.
Tablet.
Adds item.
And the final one, mobile.
Log in.
Like so.
So I am now going to save this class.
And I'm going to open up the testing XML file.
So what I'm going to do here is update the class name.
So currently it's looking at section 11, which is the package name.
Dot an in the class name.
So I am going to Minister l06.
Underscore.
Home page like so.
And instead of exclude, I am going to change it to include.
And the name I'm going to give.
His desk top.
Dot Asterix like so.
Now, if I save this and try running it, let's see what happens.
If that's the console.
You'll see that two tests have run and if I go up, you'll see the output is desktop ad item and desktop
log in.
So if I go back to class, it has run this method.
And this method and the reason it's done so is because this has desktop in the name where these ones
do not start with the name desktop.
So if I was to go back and change that to mobile.
And then save and try running it again.
You'll see there's only one test that has run.
And that is mobile login.
And that's because this method is the only one that starts with mobile.
So this is why it makes sense to think about the method names that were provided, because if we wanted
to, we could edit our tests in G file to use the wild card feature to be selective on what methods
to run.
Thank you for watching.