In this lecture, I'm going to create a new class called Hooks.
And the Hooks class is going to be responsible to store the before test and after test annotation code.
So if I look at my project and because we've made changes to the base page in the last lecture, you
can see that my add remove test and autocomplete test has errors.
So we're not going to worry about the errors for now as in a later lecture will start correct in these.
But if I was to open up one of these classes you'll see that is here.
I had the before test and after test annotations.
And if I open up your the complete one, you'll see that that code is also defined here.
So I'm going to handle that code in a new class.
So under the base package, I'm going to right click select new and select class.
And I'm going to call this class hooks and then click Finish.
So the first thing I'm going to do to this hoax class is extend the base page using the extended keyword
followed by base page like so.
And if I hover over the error on the hooks, it says I need to add the constructor, which will use
a super keyword.
After the constructor, I'm now going to use the at before test the notation code.
And right following method public.
Void set up.
And inside this method, I'm going to use the method.
Get driver.
If brackets.
Dot.
Get.
Get you out.
So I'll need to import that before test annotation from test then g.
And you can see this two errors here, because I need to add the Pharaoh's declaration.
Once I do that, those arrows go away.
So what this method here will do sat before each test.
This set up method will be called and it's using the get driver method from the base page.
Which is this method here.
And this method is using the web drive instance.
Class calling this method.
Which thing calls this method?
So it can be quite confusing, but hopefully if you keep reviewing this code it will start making sense.
But what we're doing here essentially is creating a well maintainable framework.
So all we need to know is that for each test, this set driver driver method will be called and it's
going to get the get you are well using the get your old method.
Which is his method here.
So all it means is that before each test.
It's going to get the URL that we have defined in the config the properties file, which is the home
page of automation test in the code UK.
The next methods I'm going to use.
So I'm going to use it at after test sanitation.
I'm going to write to public void.
Tear down.
So this method is going to be called after each test.
So I'm going to import the after test annotation from test in G.
And inside this method, I'm going to use the Web driver instance class and I'm going to call the method
clean up driver.
And that is the method that simply cleans up the session.
So that's all we need to do in this hoax class.
So I'm now going to say that.
And I appreciate that this can be quite confusing as we are use in various classes here.
But follow along and hopefully this will begin making sense.
But for now, let's move on to the next class.