In this lecture, we're going to create our page objects.
So the first thing I'm going to do and the source main java is right click select new and select package.
And I'm going to give this package a name of page.
Objects.
So this is where we're going to store our page object classes.
So I'm going to right click that select new and class, and I'm going to give this class a name of home
page and then click Finish.
So I am going to create the page objects for the automation test in home page.
So I am going to get objects for all the elements that I may want to interact with in my tests.
So I am going to go back to Eclipse and the first thing that I am going to write here is a new public
field of type web driver, and I'm going to call it driver.
And I would need to import web driver from selenium and that error will go away.
The next thing I need to do is create a number of fields which will reference the locator value.
So for example, I am going to write by and I'm going to give this variable a name of toggle.
And it's going to equal.
Buyer and then the typeof located I'm going to use.
So you'll see it as an error on the buyer.
And that's because I need to import it from selenium.
And this one here will go away once we finish writing the code.
So I'm going to go back to the home page and I'm going to get locator for this toggle button here.
So I'm going to right click it and then click Inspect.
And then if I go to Reynolds Velocity, you'll see that I'm given a number of selector values.
So I'm going to take this CCS selector toggle.
So I'm going to copy that when I go back to Eclipse.
And I'm going to write thoughts, success selector and in double quotes, I'm going to place a value.
The next one not going to create is by.
And it's going to be the home.
Page link and it's going to equal.
So if I go back to the website and press this toggle button, I want to get a selector for this home
page link.
So I'm going to get Select Tool and Select Home Page, and you'll see that there's a number of values
I can use here.
And this link text one looks like a simple value to you, so I'm going to take that.
So here I'm going to write by link text and I'm going to place that value like so.
And then going to do a crate.
Another one and this is going to be for the accordion link is going to equal buyer linked text.
And if I go back to the website.
And select the accordion link.
I'm simply going to take that link.
Takes the value like so.
And I'm going to paste it in the double quotes.
So this is the concept that I'm following.
I'm creating a number of variables that are based on the elements that exist on the home page.
So this will mean I'll then be able to use these elements or these variables when I start construct
in my tests.
So I'm going to do one more just to demonstrate that once more to you.
So I'm going to do a browser.
Taps link equals boy.
Linked text and in double quotes for go back.
I'm going to select the browser tabs link button.
And I'm going to copy the link text and paste it like so.
So rather than bore you showing you this again and again, I've already written this code which I'm
going to simply copy and paste.
So this code will be available to you as an attachment on this lecture.
So I'm just going to override that like so.
So these are all the locators that I have sourced from the home page of the automation testing website.
The next thing I need to do is create a constructor.
And to do this, I'm going to write public.
And again, I need to use the class name which is home page.
Fill up my brackets, then open and close embrace.
So inside the brackets of this constructor, I'm going to provide a parameter of Web driver.
Driver.
And inside the construct itself, I'm going to write this thought driver equals driver.
So what this means is when I create an object based on this home page class, I have to provide a web
driver instance or an object.
The constructor would then use that to update this variable here with the object that I've passed.
So this will make more sense when I demonstrate it to you.
But the next step now is to create public methods, which will then get the value of these locators
and these on the public methods that we can use in our test using the page object model.
So the first thing I'm going to write is public.
Web element.
And I'm going to call this one get toggle.
And brackets and an open and close embrace.
And if a hobo hover over a web element, I'm given the option to import it from selenium.
So get toggle is expected in a return statement.
So I am going to write here return.
Driver.
To find elements.
And inside those brackets I am going to provide the toggle variable.
The semicolon.
So I need to do this for each of these fields.
So I'll demonstrate one more, and then I'll just copy the predefined code that I have available to
me which you can download.
So I'm going to write public.
Web element.
Get Home page link.
And again, an open and close embrace.
Return driver.
Find the buyer.
And I am going to provide the home link like so.
Semicolon at the end.
So I'm going to do this again for each of these.
But rather, like I said, I'm just going to copy these to save you some time that I want to bore you
too much.
I'm just going to copy these.
Up to that point.
And I'm just going to paste it below.
So you can see that it's home page.
Objects class now contains variables for all the useful elements that exist on the home page of the
automation testing website.
And then use a constructor to pass an object.
And then these public methods simply go and return the value of these variables.
So this means that in my test I can call get home page link and this method will provide the link or
the value of the home page variable, which has been defined here, which contains a value of the selector
or locator.
So this is the first page object created.
And I hope it's been useful to you.
And in the next lecture will begin creating another page object for the next web page.
Thank you for watching.