In this lecture, we take a look at Java data types.
So in Java you have primitive and non primitive data types.
A primitive dating site.
Specify the size and type of variable values.
It has no additional methods.
There are eight permitted data types in Java and these are byte short int long float, double boolean
and char.
Known primitive data types are called reference types because they refer to objects.
The default value of any reference variable is no.
Whenever you pass a non primitive data type to a method, you are actually passing an address to the
object where the data is stored.
Examples of known primitive data types on string classes and arrays.
Now, if you think back to the last lecture.
I declared a string variable dog breed and assigned a value of poodle.
That value of poodle is actually stored in memory and Java references the memory location to get that
value.
So for primitive data types, this table demonstrates the data type, the size and the description.
So if we look at byte, it has a size of one by it and it can store whole numbers for minus one two
eight 227.
So I'm not going to go through all of these, but take notes of float.
So Float is for bonus and it stores fractional numbers and is sufficient store in 6 to 7 decimal digits.
If we look at double to double was similar to float, but it's actually double the size of float.
Eight bullets and double also stores fractional numbers.
Bear has a higher range of precision, so sufficient to store up to 15 decimal digits.
So let's try out the different data types.
So in Eclipse, I'm simply going to copy and paste the class in the last lecture.
I'm going to call this l06 for lecture six, and I want to give it a name of theta.
Types.
Mexico, okay.
So if I double click that class.
So I have already declared a string value and as I've demonstrated that already, I'm going to keep
it.
So the next data type home gets demonstrated is indeed and I'm going to call this event variable number.
And I'm going to assign a value.
Of ten.
And you see that's accepted.
So where you're seeing yellow lines under these variables is simply because we're not using the variables.
Where it states local variable number is not used.
So we can ignore those there is.
If I changed that number value to point one, you will see it as an error.
And the reason for that, as demonstrated in the slides, is that ends can only store whole numbers
between a specific range.
So the next one I want to demonstrate to you is Boolean.
Now I'm going to call this flag.
So a boolean can only store a true.
Or a false value.
It can't store anything else, so I can't buy it.
For example, ABC.
As it won't be accepted if we go over the error.
It says type mismatch cannot convert stream to boolean.
So the next one I want to demonstrate is Char and I'm going to call this variable letter.
And it's going to equal I.
But you can see it as an error.
And if we hover over it, Java thinks that this value is a string and the reason for that is char values
need to be surrounded by single quotes.
And when I do that, you'll see that it's accepted.
The next one I want to demonstrate is float.
And I'm going to call this sample.
And it's going to equal 1.1 to 3.
You're seen as a never there.
And if we hover over it, we've got an option to add cost float.
Or alternatively, what we can do is add an F at the end of that line and that will tell job at this
value is a float value.
Foster.
Remove the F.
And instead choose the cost option.
You see eclipse will place float there and that's telling Java as well that its example variable is
a float value.
The final one I'd like to demonstrate is double.
And I'm going to call it the example.
And it's going to equal 1.231, two, three, four with a semicolon.
So with doubles, we don't need to declare a character value at the end of it or at any cost in.
But as explained in the slides, Dubbo has a higher rate of precision and can contain accuracy of higher
or more decimal places.
But the downside is that it takes it requires more memory.
So I hope this is a good lecture to introduce you to the different types of data.
And we'll be using these as we progress through the course.
Thank you for watching.