In this lecture, we take a look at the poem file and we learn how we can import dependencies.
So notice how upon a Maven project being created, a poem file is automatically generated.
We can now add to this pom file using dependencies found from a website called MVM a repository.
All we have to do is add a dependency sample and perform a project update.
So remember from earlier in this course when I downloaded the Selenium Java and the test in G jar files,
I then imported those into my project in Eclipse.
But now all we need to do is use the website MBM repository to find test n g in selenium java and it
will provide us with a example that we can use by placing into our POM file.
A maven will take care of fetch in those jar files for us.
So this is an example of a pom file.
So this is what the default pong file looks like.
And you can notice on 910 and 917, there's dependencies.
Tag cell.
And on 911 and 916, there was a dependency.
And the default dependency that comes with a POM file is j unit.
So we can remove J unit if we don't require it or we can add more dependencies.
Based on the technology we intend to use.
So I intend to use Selenium, Java and Test Engine Maven project.
We need to source the dependencies from M.V. and repository become.
We simply search for selenium, java and test then g and decide on the version that we want to use.
We are then shown the MAVEN dependency XML, which we can simply copy to our clipboard.
We can then add the dependency, the pace in it into our POM file.
So let's start doing this.
So before I go and download the dependencies, let's first prepare our project.
So I'm going to be using the MAVEN Project from this point onwards and you'll see that there is twofold
is here source main Java and source test Java.
So we are going to place our test classes under the source test Java folder.
And if I expand it, you'll see there's a default package here.
And if I expand that, there is also a default Java class called APA test.
So I am going to right click that package, select a new and select class.
And I'm going to call this Class l06.
Underscore home and then click Finish.
So if I open up that class now, I'm going to prove to you that I don't have Selenium Java installed.
So if I used.
Webb.
Driver, driver and try.
Imported wave driver.
You'll see that I've got no options imported.
So that's because we don't have Selenium Java installed into this project.
So what I'm going to do now is open up Chrome and I'm going to try the N repository and then click Enter.
And the first result should be to end the repository become.
So at the top, I'm going to search for Selenium Java.
And if I search, you'll see as a result from org dot selenium.
HQ dot selenium.
So I'm going to select that, which would take me to the following page.
So this is the Selenium Java dependency.
And you can see here there's a number of different versions that we can use.
So at the time of recording this, Selenium four is in an alpha and beta state, so there is no official
release yet.
But the last stable release is a version 3.141.59.
So I am going to select that version and it takes me to the following page and you can see at the bottom
here is a maven tag and there is some example provided.
So I am going to copy this using control C on my keyboard.
And if I go back to eclipse and open up my PNG file.
You'll see currently in the dependencies tags is a default dependency of j unit.
So I'm now going to paste that selenium Java dependency underneath like so.
And a little tip which is useful in eclipse.
If you hold control, shift an F on your keyboard.
It reformat your code for you.
So now I have the selenium java dependency in my pom file.
And when I save this file, take notes at the bottom right hand corner of my screen.
So you can see that Maven is build in my project with that dependency.
And now if I close this pom file.
And if I save this Java class.
And hover over Web driver.
You'll see that currently I don't have an option to import it, but if I close that class and reopen
it.
You'll see this time I've got an option to import web driver from selenium.
So that proves that I'm able to download dependencies by simply updating my POM file using the dependency
code that I have retrieved from my VM repository.
So I'm going to do the same for Test n g.
And the first result is from org dot test nj.
And if I click it.
You'll see there's a number of versions.
So I'm going to use the latest version.
7.4.0.
And again, I'm going to take the Maven example.
And copy it and I'm going to paste it below the Selenium Java like so.
So now I am going to save this POM file and again it will download the dependency for me and now test
energy will be within this project.
So if I save this for now.
And if I created a new method.
So I'm going to call one public.
Void.
Test and G.
And now if I use assert.
You'll see that there is a class the test n g daughters present.
There's also the one for J unit, and that's because the POM file also contains J unit dependency.
And since I'm not going to be using my units, I'm actually going to delete that and then save it.
So the purpose of this lecture was to show you how we can source dependencies and how we can place them
into our project by inserting the dependency in our POM file.
And then if we save the POM file and if we save the class, women are able to access those technologies
that we've downloaded.
So if you ever do come across a problem where you believe your project's not updated, you also have
the option to go to project and use the clean function.
So what this would do is that it would rebuild your project and it will redownload dependencies for
you.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And thank you for watching.