Before we take a look at ex parte locators, I feel it's important to understand the document object
model.
The document object model, also known as the DOM, is a document that stores objects of a web page.
The web page is retrieved by the server and the browser then generates a dom of the page.
You can use the objects from the DOM to make changes to a web page using JavaScript.
Students often get confused between understanding the difference between HTML and the DOM.
For now.
Just remember the html document and the DOM are not the same thing.
H.
HTML is the standard markup language for creating web pages.
HTML stands for Hypertext Markup Language and it is a text document that has the extension dot html.
It describes the structure of a web page.
It consists of a series of tanks, and the document is a structure where the symbol tag is the parent,
followed by two siblings, which are head and body types.
And additional tags often go within the parent takes is shown.
So we have small takes.
And inside those small tags, we have head and body takes.
And inside those head and body tags we could have in attacks such as title for the head or h one and
P tags for the body.
The document object model treats a HTML document as a tree structure where each node is an object representing
a part of the document.
When a web page is loaded, the browser creates a document object model of the page, which is an object
orientated representation of a simple document that acts as an interface between JavaScript and the
document itself.
This allows the creation of dynamic web pages.
We can then use JavaScript to add change over the move and the elements within the page.
Change this a styling of elements react to existing events or create new events and much, much more.
On this slide, I provide a process flow to try and demonstrate how the document object model is generated.
So a browser requests a web page.
The server then sends the HTML web page and RSS to the browser.
The browser then generates a document object model of the web page and renders it to the screen.
So let's see the dome in action.
I'm going to open up Google Chrome and I'm going to go to the automation test and website.
And then I'm going to click on the Buttons link to the Buttons page.
So I'm going to right click this page and select view page source.
On doing so you'll see the following document.
And this is the HTML source of the Web page.
So if we look at the top, we can see there is a symbol tag.
And if I go all the way to the bottom, you'll see there's a close in simple tag.
And inside those shell tags is an open in head tag and a in head tag and an open in body tag.
And a close in body take.
So this is the structure of the Web page.
So this is the actual hate mail itself.
If I close this and then press F12, it will open up the chrome developer tool.
So this panel here represents the document object model.
So this is a nodes and object representation of the web page.
If we look at the document object model and if I close down all these nodes here, you'll see that there's
an open in and close in h html tag similar to what I showed you when viewing the html source.
If I open up the head tags, you'll see there's an open in and close in head tag.
And if I do the same for the body, you'll see an open and close in body take.
And inside these tags are additional nested elements that we can see here, such as dips.
So when you view in a web page through a browser, you actually view in that web page through the document
object model.
So this is an important concept to understand.
Because when we use X path locators as our demonstrate in the next lecture, we're going to use the
document object model structure in order to focus on elements of our choosing.
So to prove to you that we use in the document object model, I want to write a command.
So this command is going to be written in the console.
And it's going to be written in JavaScript.
So before I write that, come on, I'm just going to get to select a tool and select bottom one.
So this command is going to be interactive with button one.
And you can see here is the HTML highlighted in the document object model.
So this command is going to focus on bottom one and it's going to remove it from the document object
model.
On doing so, the bottom will disappear from the web page.
So I'm going to write.
Var the variable.
My ob j said my object is going to equal.
Documents dot get elements by d.
And then in brackets and double quotes, I'm going to provide the idea of bottom one, which I know
is BTN underscore one.
And then a semicolon at the end of that line.
And then I'm going to move on to the second line and I'm going to write.
My O.B. j thought to remove.
Round brackets and a semicolon.
So before I press enter here, take note of the highlighted h html in the document object model and
also look at bottom one over here.
And you can see that that element has now been removed.
So this is how we have dynamic web pages on the Internet.
We're not actually changing the simple structure.
We're changing the document object model which is represented and what your view in through the browser.
So by writing that JavaScript command, I've actually removed that button and that button was removed
from the document object model for which we view in through the browser itself.
If I were to right click the web page and go to view page source.
You can see that.
But someone is still present.
So this proves that the hates HTML of the web page is not affected.
But it's not what we're actually viewing through the browser.
What we're viewing through the browser is the document object model representation of the web page,
which uses the HTML document.
So I hope that's given you a good overview of the document object model.
Let's look at X Path locators in the next lecture.