In this lecture, we're going to look at some additional features, specifically periodic test triggers.
So Jenkins allows us to control when our test should trigger automatically.
For example, we can say our tests are run every minute, our day, week and so on as it's highly flexible.
An example where we might need this is when a company may want to run regression tests out of working
hours.
For example, early morning.
Instead of someone being available to trigger the tests at 2 a.m. manually, we can simply set Jenkins
to do this for us.
If we click on a Jenkins job, i.e. job one, we then have the option to set configuration.
Then we need to find the build periodically checkbox which we need to take.
This would reveal the following panel.
So this is where we can set the date or time.
Jenkins uses something called a chronic expression to set the date and time.
A chronic expression is a string comprising of five or six fields separated by white space that represents
a set of times normally as a schedule to execute some routine.
An example of a chronic expression is 30 zero free and a free asterix, which are separated by spaces.
This tells Jenkins to run the build every day of every month of every year.
At the 30th minute of the third hour of the day, using the below set ins.
So 30 represents minutes.
So for every 30 minutes.
The oh three represents the hour.
So this is the hour in the day.
They month which is the first Asterix is the day that we want the test to run.
So in Asterix represents it wants it to be every day.
And it's very similar for month.
So just simply means the month, which can be a value of 1 to 12.
So if I selected Die Mum of one and mum for one, that will mean that on the first day of January,
on the first hour, so free I am at the 30 minute mark.
So at 3:30 a.m. I'd want the test executed.
The final Asterix represents day week, so we can use an additional set in which can be a value of 0
to 7, which represents Monday to Sunday.
So if we wanted to run our tests hourly, we can define the following expression.
So in that first value, we can also provide a height value.
And this stands for to run every hour of every day.
If we wanted to use a specific time.
So for the second value, we could provide the number one.
And this tells Jenkins that we want our test to run every day at one time.
Luckily, Jenkins gives you some hints when entering a chronic expression.
So if we just used five Asterix, as it tells us that we are going to be run in our tests every minute.
So that's every minute of every day of every week of every month throughout the year.
So chronic suppressions can be quite hard to understand at first, but good practice.
And by using these expressions, using the patterns of the find should make some sense of it.
So let's try this out.
So if I go back to Jenkins and if I click on one, I'm going to select Configure.
And if we scroll down we should see build periodically.
If I select that, this is where I can insert a chronic expression.
So I'm going to write asterisks five times, and each asterisks is separated by a space.
And if I click apply.
You'll see that Jenkins also provides a hint saying that we're going to be running every minute.
Psychiatric safe.
And now what I should see is Jenkins triggering my test every minute.
So I'm going to pause this video a might for the first minute and then come back.
So the first minute has been reached and you can see that automatically the job has started executing.
So again, I'm going to pause this video and wait a further minute.
Once has completed and here we have on the next minute, the next test is executed.
So this was representing the test for the second minute.
So this will continue running until we set up a was.
So this is a good way of how we can run our tests automatically.
One set in a very simple set in the configuration.
So this will continue generating my tests every minute until I change that setting.
So rather than this building up, I'm going to go back to configure and I'm going to simply antique
build periodically and save.
This is just to prevent flooding of tests being triggered.
Otherwise, we're going to find a long list of jobs.
So I hope this lecture has been useful to you.
And thank you for watching.