In this lecture we take a look at Java operators.
So what our job operators.
Operators are special characters that carry out operations, variables and values.
For example, the plus symbol.
The notes to form in addition.
The minus symbol denotes the form of subtraction.
The Asterix symbol denotes to perform a multiplication and so on.
There are different types of operators, such as assignment operators, arithmetic operators, air quality
and relational operators, logical operators and more.
Simon.
Operators are used to assign a value to a variable.
So if we look at this example.
Here we have created a invariable call total and assign a value of two using the assignment operator
equals.
Arithmetic operators are used to perform mathematical operations like addition, subtraction, multiplication
and division.
So if we look at the example.
Here we are.
Perform an addition by adding two together, number one and number two and assigning the outcome total.
So here total equals number one, which contains a value of five plus.
Number two, which contains the number of ten.
So total in this example will equal 15.
Equality in relation operators, the former type of check, but determining if something is true or
false.
For example, is two equal to free.
The answer would be no.
Is ten greater than five.
The answer to that would be yes.
So on.
There are a number of these type of operators, such as it is less than is more than equal to not equal
to more than or equal to.
Or less than or equal to.
Logical operators operate on Boolean expressions.
Too frequently used logical operators are.
And which stands for and so the and symbols two of them are used the declare an and operation.
And two pipes which stand for all.
For example if we look at line for.
If two is less than free and five is more than two, then it would execute the code.
In the second example.
So annoying.
If two is less than three or five is less than two, then execute the code.
Let's see some examples.
So in Eclipse I'm going to copy and paste the class in the last lecture and I'm going to call this l0
seventh lecture seven and I'm going to give it a name of Java operators.
Then click.
Okay.
So I'm a double click and open that class and I'm going to remove this code.
So what I'm going to do here is create a number of methods and I'm going to demonstrate the different
type of operators so that you can refer back to in the future if you wanted to.
So I'm going to create a method called public.
Static void.
Assign ment.
Operator.
Like so.
So inside this I'm going to declare an end to variable and I'm going to call it NBER one.
So I am now going to assign a value to that variable.
So NPR one equals five.
So you've seen in previous lectures that I've actually assigned this were available like this on the
same line.
So it is possible to do something similar like so it's acceptable.
But in this example I'm doing, I'm going to do an alternative way.
So all I'm going to do now is use system.
That's out of print.
When?
And I am going to copy that variable.
Like so.
So this will be printed out to console.
So the next example that I'm going to show is an arithmetic operator.
So again, I'm going to write public static void.
If.
Tech operator.
Like so.
And I'm going to write in this one.
I'm going to declare free into variables.
So it.
In one.
And it's going to equal two.
INT int two.
A.K.A. equal for.
An end result.
And that is going to equal zero.
So now I'm going to write results.
Equals int one.
Plus int two.
And again I'm going to use system.
Throw out the print out and.
And I am going to pre-print site.
I'm going to print the result variable.
So what I'm doing here is up in this result variable is going to equal into one, which is two.
Plus two equals four.
So I'm expecting a result of six and that should be printed in console.
So the next example is I'm going to create a method for a relational operator.
So I'm going to call it public.
Static void.
Rail operator.
Like so.
So in here I'm going to create two ints variables int.
Number one.
And that's going to a ten.
And in number two.
And that's going to equal value of five.
So here I'm going to use an if statement.
So don't worry about understanding if statements because we go I'll go through it in more detail in
a later lecture.
But for now, just follow along.
So here, what I'm doing is.
Well, sign number one.
A value of ten.
A number two, a value of five.
Here, I'm using an if statement to check to see if number one is greater than number two.
If that's true, then this line here will output to console.
If it's not true, then this line will output the console.
So I'd run this in a moment and hopefully make more sense to you.
So the next thing I'm going to do is go down further is I'm going to demonstrate use of a logical operator.
So I'm going to write.
Public void.
So public static void.
Logical.
Like so.
So I am going to make some rabbit meat movies down.
So I'm going to create free into variables so I equals to.
And B equals for.
And it see.
Equals ten.
I'm then going to create two boolean variables.
Some are called S one result one.
And this one I'm going to call result two.
Like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do is use an awe operation.
So.
Result one.
Equals.
I.
Right up be.
Or which is declared by two pipes.
See.
Is greater than a.
And I'm simply going to use a system.
Thoughts about the print when.
And I'm going to output the result of results one.
So let me explain what I'm doing here.
So I've created free variables A, B and C, which contain different values.
And I've got a Boolean variable called Result one and a boolean called Result two.
So in this first logical test, result one.
So because it's Boolean, the default value of a boolean is false.
And what this is doing is, is check in using a logical operator.
If I say if two is greater than B, which is four.
Or C which is ten is greater than.
I.e. which is to.
So one of those true.
This one here is because C is ten and it's more than eight, which is two.
And because I've used the all operator here, it means because one of these is true, this boolean will
be turned from false to true.
So I expect the result of true in this particular test.
So let's try an example of an and operator.
So for result two.
Equals.
I is greater than be.
And.
If C is greater than I.
Then system got out of print line.
So I'm just going to copy that.
But instead of result one, I want to output the result.
So.
Two like.
So what I'd expect here is where we use in and in this example.
We're checking to see if A is greater than B, so is to greater than four, which is not.
And because we use in and out statements have to be true.
So we know this one here is false, but C is greater than eight.
A ten is great and two this side is true.
But where we use and operator both at East Sides need to be true results.
So result two I expect to return false because this site here is not true.
So let's try running these methods.
So before I run this test, I need to declare why I need to trigger these methods to run.
And I can do this in the main method.
So here I'm simply going to copy.
The method names and place it within mine like side semicolon.
And I'm going to do that for each one.
So if you remember to a previous lecture.
I've I've explained that the main method is a starting point of a Java program.
So we have placed the method names in main.
When I run this this class, it will then trigger each one of those methods to run.
So I'm going to save it.
I'm going to right click and run.
Job application.
And here we had the results.
So if we look at this first method, so I have assigned INT number one a value of five.
And I'm printing out that results of that variable and we can see five in the console.
In the arithmetic operator, I've declared free integer variables in one equals two.
In two equals four and result equals zero and a result equals in one.
So the value of two plus into which the value of four.
So then two added together is placed in the result variable and equals six, which is correct.
In this further example, I've declared two integers.
It's a number one equals ten and int and into number two equals five.
So I'm use an if statement to check to see if number one, which equals ten is greater than number two,
which is five.
And because that's true.
This line here has been printed so we can say number one is greater than number two, which is what
we were expecting.
So in the final example.
So in this logical method, I've declared free integers A, B and C of values two, four and ten and
of create two booleans result one, result two.
So result one equals and it checks to see if i.e. which is equal to two is greater than B which is four.
So that's false.
But because we use in an operator, it means only one of these has to be true.
So in the second test, we're checking the safe value of C, which is ten is greater than eight, which
equals two.
And that side is true.
So because we use a newer operator and only one of these has to be true.
This is why true has been outputted in console.
If we look at the second example, so result two equals i.e. greater than B, which we know is false
because A's two and is less than B, which is four.
But the important difference here is we use in the and operator.
And the end operator requires both arguments to be true.
In order for a true result to be outputted.
So although this is false and this one here is true, we need both sides to be true in order to get
a true result.
And that's why force has been outwitted here.
So I hope this lecture has been useful and I appreciate it quite a bit to take in.
But you'll gain more experience in this as we progress through this course.
The hopefully is at least giving you some insight to how we can use different operators in Java.
Thank you for watching.