In this lecture, I briefly go over some of the available test annotations that we have available to
us.
So first off, I'd like to say, do not worry if some of these are difficult to understand because in
the next few lectures I demonstrates use in some of these.
So in automation test, then we have the X Test annotation and this is often written in front of the
method to imply the code is a test.
So we've seen a couple of examples of this already in our previous lectures.
We also have the act before method which allows the method to execute before the execution of each at
test method.
The after method is executed after the execution of each act test method.
The method annotated with acts before class who executes only once before the first test method in that
class is invoked.
The at off the cross annotation will be executed only once after all the test methods of that class
have been invoked.
The app before test method runs after the apps before sweet annotation.
The app before test could be used to create initial data prior to run in other test methods, whereas
after test annotation will run after the other tests are complete.
We also have the apps before sweet annotation, which is often used to set up and start the Selenium
web drivers.
The after suite annotation is often used to stop the Selenium web drivers.
So what I'm explaining to you here is that we have different tests and g annotations available to us
and these allow us to control what code to run based on the order that we set.
So how can we use these annotations?
So here I'm demonstrating how we can use the before sweet and after sweet annotations.
So I might use the before sweet annotation to set a code block to set the driver and open the browser.
Then once before Sweet has completed.
The code will name run any methods that have been set within ACT test annotation.
Then.
The code will look and execute a method that has been set with an after suite annotation.
An example of this might be to close down the session and exit the browser.
So what I'm doing here is using test and annotations to set order execution in my code.
So the before suite would run first in this example, followed by any code that has been declared with
a test notation, then followed by anything that has been declared as an after suite notation.
So it gives us control.
Testing annotations provides us with an additional layer of control.
We can trigger code to run at a specific time.
This is useful if we need to do things before or after an event.
For example, we most likely will always want to close the browser after our tests have completed,
and so we have an invitation available that will trigger the code at a specific stage in the process.
So I hope this has been a good introduction to some of the annotations available in test testing and
would explore some of these in the forthcoming lectures.
Thank you for watching.