So let's add assertions to our test.
So I'm still using the data from Google one and two.
And I'm going to be tested to see if the user is able or not able to sign into the websites.
So for this first survey data.
Which is this email address and password.
I know that they can sign in.
And in doing so, they can see the your account page.
And they had access to the sign up button.
I think I mentioned in a earlier lecture that I was going to use this H1 title in your assertion, but
I thought of an improved way of doing this.
So to explain what we're doing in the code quickly, this is where we provide the email address of Rogue
One and the password for Mode one.
We then attempt to click the submit button and if the user signs in, I then want them to click the
sign out button, which appears on the your account page.
So it's at this point, which is ideal for an assertion.
So I'm going to riot.
Try.
And then I'm going to cut this line and paste it here.
So it's going to try to click the sign out button.
And if he can do that, I then want to use extent reports to log a past message.
Sam gets right extents manager.
The past user has sign in.
So after Trier you also have to add a touch statement exception.
And here I'm going to write extents manager dot file
user could not sign in and I want to force the test to fail at this point.
So as I know that is first user is a valid combination.
I expect this code here to run.
If I go to devote to data, we didn't get as far as click in the sign out button.
So we simply enter the email address row two and a password for MOTU and try clicking the submit button
to lock in.
So if I simply copied his try catch method.
Apace it like so.
Is then going to try to click the sign up button.
But as we know, the road to data is not valid.
That's when I expect this code here to run.
So before I attempt this first, scroll up to the top of my class because I've copied this class from
another.
You can see it is extents.
Manager Locke is referring to another class.
So I'm going to change this to shop, log in, test, and then I'm going to save it.
Then I'm going to try running it.
Let's see what happens.
So if I go back to Eclipse and let it finish.
You can see the test has failed.
And if I refresh the project.
You can see the report has been generated.
If I look at that report.
Notice what it's written.
Started shop log in.
Test.
User has signed in.
Which is offensive this year for the first data.
And then it says user could not sign in and this outputted a message was failed the test.
That's because on the second rotator.
Because they can't sign in, they're unable to click the sign up button.
That's why this has been triggered.
And we can also see a screenshots here showing authentication filed.
So that is how we can use Apache Wire to access data from Excel and use it within our test.
There are a number of improvements we can make to this code.
I wanted to demonstrate the concept to you.
I hope you found it useful.
And thank you for watching.