In this lecture, we're going to create our second page object class.
So we've already done the home page.
And if I go back to the website, the next page that we're going to be looking at is the test store
home page.
So this will be the second page that will be interacted with when we construct our tests.
And on this page you have the option of different products to select.
So I am going to base this second page object on the elements from this page.
So if I go back to Eclipse, I'm going to right click the page objects package, select new and select
class, and I'm going to give this class a name of shop home page like so and then click Finish.
I'm then going to open that class.
And this is where I'm going to begin writing my code.
So remember, like the last lecture we need to add public.
Webb.
Driver.
I would have to import that from selenium.
The next thing to do is to source the element locators.
So we need to think of all the elements we'd want to interact with on this page.
So the first one that I'm going to get is this first product here.
And in fact, I'm going to get locaters for all these products because I plan to use these in my test.
So I'm going to right click the name, go to inspect.
And then I'm going to go to annual philosophy.
And you'll see there's a list of selectors I can use.
So the most suited one I can see here is link text.
So I'm just going to grab that.
I mean, go back to Eclipse and I'm going to write by.
And I'm going to call this variable product one equals.
Buyer dot link.
Text and I'm going to pay earlier.
We have a semicolon.
So I'm going to do the same for by.
Product two equals.
If I go back to the website.
And if I right click the name the second product and inspect.
And again, go back to Red Rocks velocity.
This one has a link text of hummingbird printed sweater, so I'm going to copy that.
And I'm going to write by link text and I'm going to provide that value.
So I'm going to do the same for the remaining products, but I'm not going to show you this as this
is going to bore you and I will predefined the code which you can download.
But before I copy the code into this class, let's do the next few things I would have had to have done
if I was creating this class by hand.
So I need to create a constructor.
So I'm going to write public and then provide the class name of shock.
Home page.
And in brackets, an open and close embrace.
So I've misspelt downloaded an error which I am going to remove an error then goes away.
So I need to provide in the parameters with driver driver.
And this is identical to what we did in the last lecture.
So this is something that's going to be consistent in all our page object classes.
And here I'm going to write this.
Thought driver.
Driver.
And the next thing to do is to start creating our public methods.
So public web element.
And I'm going to call this get prod one.
Our need to import web element.
And this is simply going to return.
Driver the fine element.
And then I am going to provide this field.
Put product one was semicolon.
So if I copy that and place this below.
I'm simply got to change this to product two and put up one.
Is instead going to point to this variable like so.
So I would have done the same procedure.
I would have gone back to this website and I would have.
Right.
Clicked on this name, this name, this name.
And for the rest of the products, I did those in this section as fields and then create in methods
that will point to those fields.
So instead of showing you this, which would take time, I've already written this code for you, which
you can download, so I'm simply going to copy.
From the bottom to the Web driver filled at the top.
And I'm just going to paste it.
Like so.
And as you can see, it contains the exact same what just showed you up to this point.
So by all means, if you would like to practice governance source locators and write this code yourself.
Otherwise you have the option to download it.
So this is the second page object class done, and in the next one will do the next page.
Thank you for watching.