In this lecture, we take a look at browser tabs and learn how to handle them.
So what is a browser type?
Browsers allow you to have more than one window open at a time.
For example, a one time you might be looking up something on a search engine while on the other you
might have a news website open.
If we want to interact with another tab using Selenium web driver, then we need to instruct the driver
to switch to the window.
Driver don't get wind windows, handles, returns.
All windows tabs handles.
Launched and opened by the same driver instance.
The return data type is a string value and we can store all the values returned from the driver, get
windows handles into a collection that we can then use to iterate and switch to the tab.
Let's try it out.
So before we begin writing code, let me first walk you through the test.
So I'm going to click on the browser's tabs button on your automation test and website, and it will
take you to this page.
Here you see an open button, and if I click it, it opens up a new tab.
And if I go back and click it again, it opens up another one.
So what I want to do in this test is go to this Web page, click on this open tab button, and I want
to click it free times to open up free additional tabs.
And then once I do that, I want to switch to each of these tabs.
Once I've done that, I then want to return to the browser.
MindTap.
So I'm going to go go to Eclipse and I'm going to copy and paste the class in the last lecture hall
in this new 107 for lecture seven.
And I'm going to give it the name of browser tabs like so.
I'm then going to open up that class and I'm going to delete all the codes up to the driver.
Don't get method.
So the first thing I need to do is get the address for this Web page.
So I'm going to copy it.
And paste it in the get method like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is I'm going to use a four loop to press that browser tab or
the open tabs button three times.
So I'm going to do this by using a four.
INT I equals zero.
Semicolon I is less than free semicolon.
I plus plus an an.
I'm going to use open and close in braces.
A name gun to use driver dog find element by x path.
So just use an x path this time just to change up a little bit.
So I could have used a CSA selector.
So I'm going to leave empty quotes in that bracket for now, and I need to click on that button.
So I'm going to use the Click Command.
So I'm going to go back to that Web page.
Right click on the button to inspect it.
And then I'm going to up Open Runner X Velocity and I'm going to use X Path this time.
So I could copy all this.
But I do not believe that's all necessary.
So I'm going to edit the x path.
And I'm going to move everything.
Up to the input element.
So I'm going to add another forward slash.
And it's going to be looking for an input where the value equals open tab.
And as this is a button, so it's an input and it's got the value of open tab within it.
So I'm going to copy the X path.
Go back to clips and paste that value here.
And just to confirm that path works.
If I were to press enter here, you'll see it's only found one match and it's highlighted the bottom.
So I'm going to say this class for now just to see what happens.
And you can see that it's opened up three additional tabs.
So it's gone to this web page and presses button free times.
So the next thing that I'm going to do is I am going to use a Java connection and I'm going to use an
ArrayList this time.
So we've covered ArrayList, ArrayList in the Java section, so I'm not going to spend time explaining
it.
But he's is just one of the most common type of collections that that people use in Java.
So I'm going to write a write list and it's going to store values of strings.
And I'm going to give this ArrayList the name of Windows Handles.
And it's going to equal a new array list storing strings.
And brackets and a semicolon.
So inside that bracket, I'm going to use the driver instance dot.
And I'm going to use a method called get windows handles with an at the and.
Like so.
And you can see ArrayList has got an error underneath it.
And if I hover over it, I've got the option to import it from Java util.
And then he ever goes away.
So all this is doing is it's creating a new ArrayList object.
And is going to store by using the driver instance.
It's going to get the windows handles.
And Windows handles is a unique I.D. for every open browser window.
Each one of these has a unique Windows handles I.D. and the Windows handle is a string value.
So the next thing that I'm going to do is I am going to print out the total number of items stored in
that collection.
And I'm going to do this by simply using system dots out dot prints and.
And I'm going to use some double quotes to output some text.
So I'm going to write there are space and outside the quotes I'm going to use the plus sign.
And I'm going to use Windows and those.
Dot Soyuz.
And then I'm going to use another plus symbol and I'm gonna output some more text.
Tabs open.
So any system.out.println.
This is just simple.
A text I'm outputting, so it's just going to explain what the value is.
But is this here where an actual value is being retrieved?
And all it's doing is is going to win those handles and it's checking to see how many values are stored
within that collection.
So if I save this now and try running it.
Let's see what happens.
If I go back to Eclipse.
You'll see that it says there are four tabs open.
So this driver they'll get windows handles has retrieved the I.D. for each open window and stored it
in the Windows Handles collection.
So the next thing I'm going to do is I'm going to use a for each loop.
So I'm going to do this just below here.
I'm going to use for.
And it's going to be the time string.
I'm going to call this item.
We have a colon.
Windows and doors.
In an opening and close embraces.
So this is a for each loop.
And as you know, we need to specify the data type that's been iterated through.
This value here can be anything, but we still is is looking through the collection.
So this is the same name.
So this is going to go through each individual value within that collection.
And for each one of those iterations is going to execute the code within the loop.
So in here I'm going to write driver dot switch to.
Dot window.
And I am going to simply pass item.
So each time this code runs, it's going to pass that value.
Yeah.
So let me try running this code.
But before I do, I'm going to slow down the test a little bit.
So I'm going to use a red dot sleep.
And let's do it for one and a half seconds.
And I'm going to save it.
And I'm going to run the test.
So you can see that the driver has switched focus to each open browser window.
And it was able to do that because we're storing the windows.
Handles are open into a collection.
And then we use an A for each loop to go through each value in that collection, to go and click each
one of those windows handles by passing the already.
Each time it goes through or executes the for each loop.
So the final thing I need to do here is to switch back to the main tab.
And I can do this outside of the for each loop.
So once the for each loop has finished executing.
So it's gone through all the values in the collection.
It will then execute the following code.
So I'm going to write driver dot switch to dot window.
And you can see that it takes a string parameter.
So what I'm going to do in these brackets is pass the collection's name, the windows and doors, and
then if I use a dot, I can use an ArrayList method called Get.
And it takes an INT as an index value.
So I'm going to pass the index value of zero.
Because if we think about it, the ArrayList is storing.
All of the open windows IDs.
And in the first value within that array list is going to be the main window tab, which is index value
of zero.
So if I pass the index value of zero here, I expect the focus to switch back to the main tab.
So I'm going to say this.
And I'm going to try running it.
Actually before I do, let me just add a Fred dot sleep just again to slow it down so we can see it
working.
So I'm going to save.
I'm run.
And let's see what happens.
It's a switch in fruit.
Each of the tabs.
And then it goes back to the main tab.
So that is pretty much browse the tabs.
And I hope you found this useful.
So the main thing you need to remember about browser tabs is that the Windows Handles method will retrieve
unique string IDs for each window.
And then we can switch to.
Those window shades.
And then we can interact with that particular tab.
And then when we're finished, we can switch back to the main tab.
So thank you for watching and I'll speak to you in the next lecture.