So at this stage we have now set up the extent manager class and now we've also amended the listeners
class and also made a slight change to the base page for the screenshot method.
So we're now in a position to start amending our tests.
So I'm going to open up and remove item basket test.
And in here we can start making some changes to use the log in that we've set in the extent manager
class.
So at the top here inside this add remove item method, this is where the test begins.
So I'm going to write extent manager.
Dot log.
And I'm going to add a message here.
And I am going to write starting.
Add the move item basket.
Test.
And I'm just going to add free docs at the end.
So this log is a method.
From the extent manager, which is to log an information message.
I'm then going to scroll down a little bit more.
So at this point here we are going to the shop home page and then we're clicking on product one.
So underneath shop home page equals new shop home page.
Underneath here I am going to riot.
Extent manager.
Dot.
Pass.
And I'm going to write another message here and say, reached the shop home page.
And this dot pass method refers to a pass message.
So we can add to our tests as with like depend on how much you'd like to report in the actual extent
report itself.
So if I copy this line here.
And if I scroll down a little bit more.
So at this point here, for example, I can pass that message again.
And instead I can say reached the shop product page.
And so these messages will be reported when the code reaches each of these points.
So you'll see that at this point here I'm select right in option dot select by visible.
So I'm select in the size which is M for medium.
So underneath this I could write.
Have successfully selected product sites.
And underneath this one, I could write.
Have successfully.
Increased quantity.
And then underneath this one is where I'm adding the item to the basket.
Soccer.
Right.
Have successfully added product to basket.
So you can add as many of these logs as you desire.
So I think that's enough for this at this point here.
So I'm just going to say this class.
And then I am going to open up the other class, which is all a complete test and I am going to do something
similar.
So like the previous one, they add remove item basket.
I am going to copy to extent manager dialog.
Start in message.
And I'm going to paste it here at the top.
But instead of add remove item basket.
I am going to replace that with this test name.
So if I scroll down a bit more.
At this point here, I'm going to the test store homepage so I am going to write extent manager dot
pass.
And inside that I'm going to write.
Have successfully
reached.
Store.
Home page like so.
So I'm just going to add a few more these messages.
So here I'm going to say I have successfully.
Clicked on the product.
Underneath this one I'm going to add have successfully.
Reached.
Shop.
Product page.
Underneath here again.
Has successfully.
Selected.
Product size.
Has successfully.
Increased quantity.
Added item to cart.
I think I'm going to add a few more in this one.
So here.
Have successfully reached.
The shopping cart page.
Have successfully.
Selected.
The.
Promo.
Button.
I'm just going to add one here.
Successfully selected the check out button.
And I'm just going to add a couple more.
So underneath this one, so this is where we start entering the customer's information.
So have successfully entered customer details.
This section here.
We're entering the delivery information.
Entered delivery info.
Here we select in the shipping method.
Selected the ship in.
Method.
And here I'm going to have successfully.
Placed order.
So those are the logs that I'm going to place into the autocomplete test.
So I'm now going to save that.
And I just want to go back now once we've done those logs to the add remove item basket test.
So if I scroll down, you'll remember we have an assertion here where we check in the total amount and
we're looking for a value of 4520 free.
So the issue that we have here is that because we we have an assertion there could be two results.
A pass will fail.
But how can we do that?
Because we don't know until the test executes whether to output a pass or fail or log.
So what we can do in that case is that we can use a tri catch statement.
So I'm going to make a slight amendment to this line here.
Why use in try to catch.
So I'm going to write try.
In an open and close embrace.
And then what I'm going to do is cut this line.
And paste it like so.
So it's going to try to see if the total amount equals that amount.
And then if it does, then I want to use extent.
Manager thoughts pass.
And I'm going to write the total amount.
Matches the expected amounts.
And then we can use catch.
And we come right assert that fail.
And then inside those brackets, I could write a message saying cart amounts did not match the expected
amount.
Comma it found an outside those brackets.
The quote sorry.
I'm going to add the plus cart.
Which is the cart object.
Get.
Total amount.
Don't get text.
And then after that, if I had another plus, if I do this on a new line so you can see it better.
I'm going to write.
Double quotes again with space expected.
And then I can simply copy this amount here, which is the amount which was expected.
Every semicolon at the end.
So you can see it as an error on the catch.
And that's because when we use a catch statement, we need to write.
So because it's an assertion try to catch on camera assertion.
Ever.
E like so.
So what I'm now going to add after this.
Is extent manager the fail.
And a message of.
The total amount did not match the expected amount.
And this foul method is referring to the one from the extent manager class.
So I'm just going to add this comment back up to top here.
So.
And that is the changes that were required to this class now complete.
So I'm going to save this.
And then in the next lecture, we're going to start or try and generate our first report.