So so far we've created Web Drive, for instance, class, which is responsible for setting the driver
instance using local.
We've created the Hook's class, which stores the acts before test and off the test annotation code,
and we've made changes to our base page based on the changes we've made.
But these other two classes.
The next change that we need to make is to our page objects, and the changes I'm going to be making
is going to be identical for each.
So I plan to show you one example of the changes I'll be making.
And then you would ever have the choice to mainly update each new page objects.
Or you can download the code from this lecture as I will update or upload the updated page object classes
for you.
So I'm going to open up one of these classes.
So I'm going to open up a shopping cart or Java.
And our code company contains the following.
So the first change I'll be making to this page object class is that I'm now going to be extending the
base page.
And on doing so, there'll be an error.
And that's because I now need to import the base page to this class.
Next, you'll see an error under the constructor.
So this Webb driver driver parameter is no longer required.
So I'll be the lead in it.
And this line here is also no longer required.
So I'm going to replace it with the super keyword, since because we're using the base page now, we
need to use a super keyword to the base page constructor.
I need to add a phrase declaration to de constructor and that error then goes away.
The next change I need to make is the same change for each of these methods.
So before the return statement, I'm now going to write this thought driver equals get driver, which
is a method.
And on doing so, I'll need to add a froze declaration.
So to explain what we're doing here as we now extend in the base page, this is what we called a super
keyword in the constructor.
And then in each of these methods, I'm using this driver.
So this driver is referring to this driver here.
And it's equal in get driver, which is a method that belongs to the base page.
So this method then uses the web driver instance class and it calls the get driver method.
Which is this method here.
And as we know, this method is set in the thread.
But check and see if it's a no value and if it is and includes the create driver method which initializes
the driver.
So I need to repeat this line in every method.
So I'm going to quickly do that.
So those are all the changes that were required to this class.
So we need to make identical changes to all the other page objects.
But just to go over what we did here, we simply extend to the base page.
On doing so.
We then needed to update the constructor to use a super keyword because of the base page constructor.
And then for each the methods we use this driver, which is referred to this variable at the top here.
And it's equal in a method called get driver, which belongs to the base page.
All the other code remains the same.
So as I said, if you'd like to have some practice and update the remaining page object classes, please
go ahead.
Otherwise, you can download the updated code from this lecture.
Thank you for watching.