So we're now in a position to generate our tests to see if a report gets generated.
So what I'm going to do is right click my testing file run as a managed test in G suite.
So let's see if the code generates.
So you can see that no tests were run.
And the reason for this is that there is a slight tweak that I need to make in my code and it's to do
with the listener's class.
So if I open up the listeners class, you'll see that on the on start method I've used extents.
Manager They'll create test contacts.
Host So this is an error in my part.
What I should have used is context dot get name again like so.
If I save that now.
And try running again.
Let's see if that resolves the issue.
And you can see that the Chrome drivers have opened and the tests are running.
So now that's completed.
If I go over to my left hand side here.
You can see it.
I've got a report folder, but it's nothing inside it.
So if I right click and click on refresh on the project.
You'll see that there is now a report listed there.
And if I right click and go to properties.
And then click on this icon here.
It'll take me to the location of the report.
And if a double click it.
You'll see that the tests are now displayed in this report.
So I've got two tests here.
So this first one is the add remove item basket test.
And you can see there it was pass in.
But it reached a failure.
And that's because the cuts amount totals did not match the expected amount.
And you can see that the screenshot has also been attached which of a click.
It will show you the exact point of where the failure occurred.
If I click on this second test, this one refers to the start in or the complete test, and you can
see that all those messages that I added have been placed within the report itself.
And this one passed.
If I click on the second tab, which is the exceptions page, you'll see where the failure has occurred.
And it's to do with the first test, which is this one here, which is add remove item basket.
If I click on this third tab, you'll see that we've given some useful information.
Such as?
Such as the start time of the test and the end time the one has passed, one failed and you'll see all
useful information listed here.
If I scroll down, you'll see a system environment where I've got a name as tester value my name.
And you may remember this was defined when we're setting up the config in the extended manager's class.
So if I close this report.
And go back to my framework and open up extents.
Manager.
Let me just show you what happens when we change some config here.
So instead of theme got dark, I'm going to select theme dot standard.
And then instead of my name, I'm going to write John Smith.
So if I save this.
And try running the test.
Inject smell again.
Let's see the differences.
So again, those tests have completed and if I go up and refresh the project again.
You'll see that second report has been generated.
And more importantly, it hasn't overwritten the original report.
That's because we're using the date and time to differentiate between the files.
So that's the importance of using the date and time in the name of the file or the report.
It is generated and that's done by this method here.
So for right click and go to properties on that second report and then try opening it.
Let's see the differences that I've made based on change in those config settings.
And you can see used a different theme.
And also if I go on to this third tab.
You'll see that John Smith has been entered here based on the change that I made to the extent managers
class.
So that is how we can set up and implement extent reports into our framework.
I apologize for it being quite confusing as there is a number of code changes we need to make, but
hopefully the end result was worth it.
If you have any issues during this set up or if you find then that you extent reports are not generated
as expected.
I've attached the code files to these lectures, so the best thing to do is to compare your code to
the code that I have written to see if there's any differences.