Before you continue on with this lecture, it's very important you've updated your page object classes.
So I've already done this in my framework.
For example, if I open up my homepage class, you'll see that this too extends the base page.
The construct has been updated and I've also added this line to each of the methods.
So if you haven't already updated your page objects, please do so.
So now I'm going to be focusing on updates in our test classes.
So I'm going to open up the autocomplete test and our code currently looks like this.
So you see that there is a number of errors that have been highlighted.
And if I scroll to the top, you'll see that I still have my before test and after test notation code.
So we know that we're now handling this in the Hook's class.
So what I'm going to do in my test class is highlight this code and delete it.
The next change I'm going to make is I'm going to change extends base page to extend its hooks.
And I need to import that.
Like so.
And that era then goes away.
So what it means is my autocomplete test will now extend the hooks class.
And this hoax class contains a before and after test annotation code.
But the Hook's class also extends the base page.
So that base page contains code that we're familiar with.
Sonata.
I've updated that I need to focus on these driver parameters.
So as we've updated our page object classes, you'll know that we've updated our constructor, which
formerly had a parameter of web driver.
Driver.
So now in a class, in our test class, now that we created a new home page object, it was expected
a driver object to be passed.
But as we updated our constructor in our page objects classes, we no longer need it so we can simply
delete driver.
In doing so, you'll see that another number of errors will be highlighted here.
But do not worry.
This is simply because we need to add a pharaoh's declaration.
And I'm going to add an Ohio exception and all those errors now go away.
So this is all the changes we required to our order.
Complete test.
So I'm going to simply say that.
And in the next lecture would then focus on the add remove item basket test.
Thank you for watching.