In this lecture, we take a look at how to handle radio buttons.
So what is a radio button?
Radio buttons allow a user to select only one of a limited number of choices.
Radio buttons are normally written in radio groups where a collection of radio buttons describe a set
of related options.
The group is defined by showing the same name, value and on the image on the left hand side.
You see, the option one is ticked, and if I was to choose option two, it would take option one and
would take option two.
If we look at the h timo on the right hand side, you will see that each option shares the same name
value and this is demo priority.
So how do we interact to radio buttons?
All we have to do is find the locator for the option we want to select.
We don't simply use the dot click command, for example Driver the find element by CC selector and I
provided a class name in this example and all I do is simply use a dot click command.
So let's try this out.
So before we start writing code, let me first walk you through the test.
So I'm open up chrome, I'm going to automation test in the code UK and I'm going to drop down link.
And what we're going to focus on is this radio bottom section here.
So on page loads, no options are ticked.
And if I select option one, you'll see has been checked.
But if I select option two, that focus then shifts to option two and so on.
So only one option can be selected at a time.
So the first thing I'm going to do is right click and inspect the page, and then I'm going to go to
the runner philosophy panel and then using the selected.
So I'm going to focus in option one like so.
And you'll see that runner x velocity has generated a number of selectors.
So I'm going to minimize this Web page for now, and I'm going to open up the clips and I'm simply going
to copy and paste the last class from the last lecture.
And I'm going to call this new 1l0848 and I'm going to give it a name of radio buttons and then click
okay.
And I'm going to double click on that class to open it and simply remove the code from the last lecture
that we don't need.
So the first thing to do is to update the address.
So I'm going to open up the web page, copy the address, and then paste it to replace the existing
one.
Right.
So.
So the first thing to do is if I go back to the Web page.
So I've already focused on Radio Button one, so I'm going to copy a selector.
So I'm going to choose a second one.
And I'm going to go back to the clips and use in a comment.
I'm going to post it there.
I'm going to do the same option to.
And I'm going to do the same for option three.
So now we have our selectors so we need to write to use these to click on them.
Options is driver dots find elements by the CSF selector double quotes for now and then doc click.
And what I'm going to do is simply copy.
Without the two forward slashes the selected value for one.
And then all I'm gonna do now is copy that line a second time and a third.
And for that second line, I'm going to copy the second selector.
And for that third one, I'm going to copy the third selector.
Like so.
Now, when I demonstrate this to you, it's going to be really fast.
So I'm going to use a phrasebook sleep line again just to slow it down a little bit.
So I'm going to slow it down by 3 seconds before it moves on to the next line.
And then I'm going to use another friend.
Don't sleep.
So it slows it down again before it moves on to the next.
So that's the code.
And I'm going to say this class.
And then right click and then run it and see what happens.
So on page load, it's really clicked.
Option one.
It's now moved to option two.
And then it moved to option free.
So the code is fairly simple.
All you need to remember is when using radio buttons is to use a dot clip command to select the value.
Thank you for watching.