In this lecture, we take a look at JavaScript.
So what is JavaScript?
JavaScript is a programming language that allows you to implement complex features on web pages.
Think about the number of websites you have visited.
There has dynamic content, for example, interactive maps.
Content is displayed and changes after the page is loaded.
Messages appear after an event such as form validation.
Various other scenarios.
And it's very likely that JavaScript is used to make the page come to life.
So what are the advantages of JavaScript?
So for one speed, JavaScript tends to be very fast because it's often run immediately within the client's
browser.
Simplicity.
JavaScript syntax was inspired by Java and is easy to learn.
Popularity.
JavaScript can be found across the web and with the introduction of Node.js, it's increasingly used
on the back end.
Server load JavaScript is processed client side and so it reduces the demand on servers.
Which interfaces.
JavaScript can be used to create features like drag and drop and components such as sliders, all of
which greatly enhance the user interface and experience of a site.
So what are some of the disadvantages of JavaScript?
So one copy client side security JavaScript code is executed on the client side, so bugs and oversights
can sometimes be exploited for malicious purposes.
Because of this, some people choose to disable JavaScript completely.
But it's very rare to come across a website that has has JavaScript disabled.
Browser support.
So even though server side scripts always produce the same results, it can be different between browsers
and they may interpret JavaScript code differently.
However, this has greatly improved as JavaScript has evolved.
So on this slide we take a look at IAX.
So it stands for asynchronous JavaScript.
An example.
It makes it possible to read data from a web server after the page is loaded.
This makes it possible to update a website without needing to reload the whole page.
The sending and receiving of data is performed in the background.
An AI plays a key role in making Web pages dynamic.
S.M. h ttp request object.
So the small CTP request object, also known as x, h r are used to interact with servers.
You can retrieve data from a URL without having to do a full page refresh.
This enables a web page to update just parts of a page without disrupting what the user is doing.
The XML CTP request is used heavily in Nyack's programming.
So in this slide, we take a look at Nlex process flow.
So if an event occurs in a web page, the page is loaded and a button is clicked, for example.
An ex hate object is created by JavaScript.
The ex h r object sends a request to a web server.
The server processes the request.
The server passes back a response to the Web page.
The responses read by JavaScript.
And the page gets updated by JavaScript.
So if we look at this Web page, it just gives some contents of the protest flow.
So at the start, a button is clicked on a web page at point to H.
HTML request is sent to the server using XML hasty http request object.
At point free.
The server process processes the response and sends a response back at point four.
Response is sent back to the browser and at point five JavaScript processes to return data and updates
to web page content.
So I hope this was a good introduction to JavaScript and in the next couple of lectures we'll go over
how we can use JavaScript.
We've been Selenium tests.
Thanks for watching.