In this lecture we go over some other useful maven CMO commands.
So we've already seen MVA in test.
But just to recap, it runs all the tests classes.
We then have the option to run a single test class and we can do this by using MVNO hyphen capitalized
D which stands for define and then I use a keyword could test and the equals the class is name.
I then use the test keywords at the end which would then trigger it.
We also have the option to run multiple tank test classes.
So this is exactly the same except for after the class name demo test one I use a comma and in OP avoid
another name of the next class.
We also have the option to run a single test method from a test class.
So to do this, we again use margin hyphen D and use the test key word equals the name of a class.
But this time we use hash and then we provide the method name.
And then again we just use tests that the end of that line.
So this will trigger a particular method inside a class.
We then have the option to run all test methods that match a pattern such as test checkout with an asterix
which acts as a wild card.
So if we look at the command, Marvin Hyphen day test equals demo test two, which is the class name.
Harsh taste.
Check out you've been Asterix.
So what this will do is that it would look at the demo text to class, and then it would try and identify
methods that have test checkouts in the name and any other following characters.
The final example is to run all test methods that match a pattern of test checkout and test play.
From the demo test one class.
So in this example we use a very similar command to MVNO and the test equals demo test one which is
a class name, hash test, check out Asterix.
So it's looking for methods that start with test.
Check out.
With a plus sign.
Test pilot airstrikes.
So this command is going to look for methods to have test checkout in the name or test pilot in the
name.
So let's try a few of these out.
So on my screen I have command prompt open and I'm already in my project directory.
So the first come on, I'd like to show you is to run a particular class.
So I'm going to run the l08 profile class.
And to do this, all I need to use is NBN.
Hyphen and day and then test.
Equals and then provide the class name to our zero eight underscore profile.
And at the end of that line, I'm going to enter spice and use the test keyword.
So if I press enter now, let's see what happens.
And you can see that one test has run and it has run the l0 eight profile class.
The next.
Come on.
I'd like to show you is to run multiple classes at the same time.
So this is the exact same command.
Except for after the first class name.
I'm going to enter a comma and without a space I am going to provide the name of the second class.
So l07 underscore.
Sure.
Fire.
And then with the test key word at the end.
So if I press enter now, let's see what happens.
And you can see that two tests have run.
So it's run both of those classes and each of those classes contain one test each.
So the next example, I am going to show you how we can run a particular method inside a test.
So before I do this, I'm going to open up the l0 eight profile class.
And in this existing method, I'm going to remove this line and I'm going to enter system dot out but
print out end.
And I'm going to output a message saying this is from the test entry method.
I'm also going to copy this and paste it below so that I have a second test.
The method here.
And I'm going to call this second method example.
And I'm just going to update the message to replace test and G with example like so.
So I'm now going to save this class.
And enclose it and go back to command prompt.
So the command that I'm going to use here is M.P. N, F and Capital D.
Test equals l08 underscore profile.
But to call a particular method, I'm going to use hash and I'm going to provide the name of the first
method, which was test energy.
And then going to use space.
And then use the test keyword.
So if I press enter here, let's see what happens.
And you can see one test has run and you can see it as a message has been outputs here and it says this
is from the test energy method.
So that's how we know.
That this method here was targeted.
So now if I wanted to do the same, but for the other method, all I need to do is the exact same command
but replace test and g with the other method name which was called example.
If I press enter.
Let's see what's output.
And again, one test is run and he's got a message of this is from the example method.
So that's how we can target a particular method in a class.
So the final come on, I'd like to show you is the use of the wild card character.
So I am going to use the exact same command, but instead of provided the whole example method name,
I'm just going to provide aid with an asterix.
So what is this going to do?
It's going to look at the zero eight profile class and it's going to look for method that begins with
age and has any other characters following it.
So as this method here starts with a, I would expect this one to run.
As this method starts with t, I would expect it to be excluded.
So let me try running this to see what happens.
And you can see that the expected method has run successfully and this is proven from the output message.
So I hope you found this useful.
And this is the end of the Maven section.
So we've covered quite a bit, but our hope from the end of these lectures, you've now gained a good
understanding of how we use Maven and more importantly, why we use Maven.
So I'll speak to you in the next section.
Thanks for watching.