In this lecture, I'm going to update the add remove item basket test.
So our code company looks like the following.
So the changes I need to make in this class are very similar to the changes I've made to the autocomplete
test.
The first change is to delete the before and after test annotation code.
The next change is to change.
Extends base page to extends hooks.
And I need to import that.
I then need to delete the driver parameters as we no longer need this based on the changes we've made
to our page object classes.
But there is one issue.
So in this test, we've used a Web driver weight and this is an explicit weight.
And the Webb type of weight is expected in a driver and a duration to be passed.
So if I went home, control my keyboard and open the declaration of Web Drive.
Wait.
Your see is expecting a driver to be passed and a time out in seconds.
Now the problem we have with our code and because we've removed the driver instance from this class,
we cannot pass this.
So we need to think of a different way of how we can provide the driver object and the duration.
So a way we can do this is by adding a method for the web driver weight in our base page class.
So in my base page class, I'm going to scroll down to the bottom of my code and I'm going to make some
room.
So I am going to write a new method here and it's going to be called public.
Static void.
Wait for elements.
Invisible.
And this method is going to have to arguments.
It's going to sort of have a first parameter of web element elements and we have a comma.
I'm going to provide a second parameter, which is going to be int timer.
And then going to add a open and close embrace.
So I'll need to import web element from selenium.
And on doing so, the error will go away.
So in this method itself, I am going to define the web driver weights.
So I'm going to write Web Driver White and I'm going to give this object the name White equals new web
driver white.
And this is going to have to be arguments here.
So I am going to provide get driver, which is a method name followed by a comma.
And here I'm simply going to pass the time, a parameter defined above.
And a semicolon at the end of it.
So our need to import web driver weight from selenium.
But you can see it as an error under the get driver method.
So if I hover over this, you'll see that it's got change.
Get driver to static.
And the reason this is happening is a mistake on my parts.
So if I go to the get driver method here, you'll see that it's not static when it should be.
So I'm going to correct that by adding the static to the get driver method.
You'll see that is still a never here, though.
But this time, if I hover over, it is simply saying to add a froze declaration.
And when I do, that terror thing goes away.
So I'm going to explain what this method does in more detail once I finish writing it.
So I'm going to add one more line underneath this, and I'm going to write the following.
Wait.
So I'm using the white method to add to the white object that defined above.
Not until.
And in brackets expected conditions.
That invisibility of.
Which is a method name and I am simply going to pass this elements parameter here.
And at the end that line a semicolon.
So if this is confusing, don't worry.
And we did go over explicit ways in the weight section of this course.
But just to give you a further explanation here, all I'm doing is using a method in the base pace class
to take care of the weights that I need in my tests.
And this method takes two arguments, which is a web element and a timer.
So I'm using or defining a weight object here of web driver weight.
And if I hold control my keyboard and open the declaration of this particular web drive weight, you
will see this expect in a Web driver driver to be provided.
And a timeout in seconds.
So this is what I'm providing here because this set driver.
Uses this method here, and we know this method uses the web driver instance class that gets the driver
object.
And so that's what's been passed to this web tribe, white.
The second argument is the amount of time in seconds, an excuse in this parameter here to know what
time to wait.
So what I'm going to be doing now is I'm going to be using this method in my add remove item basket
test.
So I'm going to save this by space page class and I'm going to go back to my add the move item basket
Now in here.
If I scroll down, you'll see this is the code to be amended.
So I am going to delete these two lines and instead I'm going to use that new method I've just created.
So here I'm going to simply go to the base page and copy this method.
And I'm going to paste it like so.
So this method needs a bracket here and it takes two arguments.
So I'm just going to place x, comma x here for now.
Because it's good to recap on what we're trying to do here.
So and this part, the test, we would be at the following stage.
So we'll be on the shopping cart page.
And what we want to do is we want to delete this item.
But we need to wait for this item to be deleted before we take the total price.
And you'll be able to know that by going through this code to see what exactly we do in up to this point.
So I'm waiting for the element to go invisible.
So for this element here, it's going to be.
Before we check on that price.
This is why I'm using explicit white.
So in my code for this first argument, I need to provide based on the method and elements.
So I'm waiting for the second item in the cart to be deleted.
And if we remember or if we look above, you can see that I'm using can't get the lead item to click.
So I've already defined a cart object here which is based on the shopping cart page object class and
I've used that cart object to get the lead item to which is finding the locator for that item to test
to be deleted.
So I am simply going to copy cards and get delete item two and paisa as the first argument.
So that's simply using the cart object and it's getting the locator for the element that would delete
item to.
In his second argument.
I need to provide the weight, so I'm going to simply define a value of ten for 10 seconds.
And then all I need to do at the end of this line is add a semicolon.
And you'll see like the previous or the complete test that there's a number of errors here.
And this is because I simply need to add a froze declaration.
And on doing so.
We should see that those errors go away.
So this seems like a bit of a bug in eclipse if I save this.
You'll see those areas have all gone.
So I have now used a method from my base page to handle the explicit white.
And based on that method, it requires two arguments a web element and a timer.
And that's why it when I defined it in my test.
I provided the carts that get the leads.
Item two, which will get the locator for this here.
And ten is the duration in seconds.
The wait is to wait.
So this is good because it's flexible.
So if I ever need a similar weight in another test, all I need to do now is use this method again.
So this is all the changes that they needed to make in this class.
So I'm going to save it and I'm going to close it.
And those are all the changes we've acquired in our framework.
So in the next lecture, I'm going to try running our tests.