In this lecture, we take a look at Java if statements.
So what's our if statements?
If statements execute the block of code within the if statement if the condition is true.
If statements are used extensively in programming.
The most common type is a standard if statement, but there are also else statements.
ElseIf statements and switch statements.
Think of an if statement in the following way.
If the number ten is greater than the number nine, then the condition is met and the code within the
statement is to execute.
Let's see some examples.
So in Eclipse, I'm going to simply copy and paste the class in the last lecture and I'm going to call
this l0 nine and give it a name of if.
Statements like so click.
Okay.
And I'm going to double click and open it and I'm going to remove all the code apart from the static
with my method.
Like so.
So my plan is to create three methods.
The first is going to use a standard if statement.
The second method is going to use an f l statement.
And the third method is going to use.
And if else.
If our statement.
So let's write first one.
So I'm going to write public.
Static.
With.
If example.
And inside this I'm going to write if I do it in brackets.
Ten is greater than nine.
Execute the following code system.
Dots out of print and.
Ten is greater than nine.
So.
So the next method I'm going to write is public static void.
If.
Example two.
And inside this one I'm going to use.
Owner crate two ins so it.
Our.
Equals 13 an int midday equals 12 like so.
So now I'm going to write an if statement so that if.
Our.
Is more than or equal to midday.
Then execute the following code.
So I'm just going to copy the system in our print line from the one above.
Paste it here and I'm going to change the comet itself into.
Good.
After noon like so.
But here I'm going to write else.
And then another open and close braces.
And I'm going to copy this line.
And I'm going to write.
Good morning.
So what is code is doing?
I'm creating two ints ones in our variable which contains a value of 13, and the second is another
int variable called midday the value of 12.
The if statement is checking to see if our SO the value of 13 is greater or equal to midday, which
is 12.
And because it is, I'm expecting System.out.println line to print.
Good afternoon.
If I change our from 13 to 11.
Then because our is no longer great or equal to midday.
I wouldn't expect this code here to execute.
Instead, I would expect to execute.
This would say good morning instead.
So I'm going to change it back to 13 for now, and we'll run it in a moment.
In the third method, I'm going to create public static void.
Chuck Norris if.
Example.
Free.
And inside.
So I must see brackets at the end that I don't like.
So.
So here I'm going to create free integer variables int.
Our equals.
19.
ENT midday equals 12.
An int afternoon.
Equals 18.
So here I'm going to use an f l cif l statement.
So I'm going to riot if.
Our is more than or equal to midday.
And using a logical operator.
I'm going to stay and.
Our is less than or equal to.
Afternoon.
Then open and close embraces.
Wanted to execute.
So I'm just going to copy the system outline.
System.out.println.
And it's going to be.
Good afternoon.
Hey.
I'm going to try else.
If.
In an open and closed in brackets.
Our.
It's more than or equal to.
Midday.
And.
Oops, sorry.
Inside the brackets.
And.
Our is more than afternoon.
An open and close embraces again.
And this time I want to prince out.
Good evening.
And then at the end the decision I'm going to write ls and open in close braces.
So in this line, I'm going to use again, systems or out of the print line.
But I'm going to print the value of.
Good morning.
So to explain what this code does.
So I've declared free into variables.
One called our the value of 19.
Another called midday with a value of 12.
And another called afternoon with a value of 18.
So the first if statement checks to see if our SO if the value of 19 is more than or equal to the value
of midday, which is 12.
So that is true.
The second logical operation is checking to see if our one, which is 19, is less than or equal to
afternoon.
Afternoon equals 18.
So our is more than the value of the afternoon verbal.
So I do not expect this to print out.
So the next one is the elusive statement.
So again, check and see if our is greater or equal to midnight, which it is and then is checking to
see if our is more than afternoon, which I believe it is as well.
So in this case, I expect this value to output the console for this method.
If never, these two were true.
So if the if statement wasn't true and the elseif wasn't true, then it would revert to this line here
and it prints out.
Good morning.
So now we're ready to run this class.
So like the previous examples, I'm just going to copy the method names in a public static void method
like so.
Enough outside the class.
Let's check the output.
So in his first example.
So this one highlighted.
I've used a simple if statement to see if ten is greater than nine.
And if that is true, I want it to print out this line.
And that's why ten is greater than nine has been produced here.
In the second effort.
So this one highlighted I've declared two integer values hour, which is 13 midday, which is 12.
And I'm using an if statement to see if our is more than or equal to midday because it is because s
15 and midday is 12.
I expect it to output is line and that's why good afternoon has been printed.
In the third example of declared free integer variables.
Our meta in afternoon and I'm using an f elseif l statement.
So the first one is check and see if our is greater take with the midday which is and our is less than
or equal to an afternoon, which it's not.
So I do not expect this line here to execute.
The LCF is then checking to see if our is greater or equal to mid-day, which is and if hour is greater
than afternoon.
Which is to ask why I expect it to output this line.
And if we look at the console, that's the law that has been printed.
If you have been coding along, then I recommend you play around with this code and try to produce different
outputs.
The hope this lecture has been a good introduction to Java if statements as it be used if statements
quite a bit in the future.
Thanks again for watching.