In this lecture we continue with the test in G annotations, but this time I introduced the before method
and after method annotations.
So before I start writing code, let me first walk you through the test that I'm going to write.
So I'm going to use the test for Home Page and I want to click on the sign in link.
And then provider email address and password and then sign in.
This one inside me in and take me to the signing welcome page where I want to click on the clothes link.
This will then take me to this page.
And then once I've been taken to this page, I want to sign out.
I then want to close the browser window and exit the session.
So to do this I am going to add or introduce the before and after method and rotations.
So I am going to simply copy and paste the class in the last lecture call in this new 109 annotation
part to.
Then double click to open it and you'll see that this is the code from last lecture where we've used
before suite to handle, to set up the test notation to handle the actual test and the after suite to
close and quit driver.
So this time I'm going to introduce at before method.
And I am going to create a new method.
Public void.
Sign in.
And if I hover over before method, I'm given the option to import it.
So in the before method, this method is going to be responsible.
For clicking on this sign in button and then provided an email address password and then sign in is
also going to handle the euro.
R Well, so in my comment code I've used the test notation to take me to the web page.
So I'm going to cut that and paste it in the before method.
Annotation.
So the method called sign in and I am going to get this test or home page URL and paste it in here like
so.
So once I've done that, it will take me to this page.
So I need to find a selector for the sign in button.
So if I right click and inspect it.
And then go to Ragnarok Velocity.
I'm going to take this second sister selector.
So for some reason, this first one doesn't work well.
And I think it's because of how the Web page has been designed.
So if you're following along, make sure to select the second cursor selector.
And I'm going to write driver dot find elements via CSA selector.
That's.
Pace that value.
And as I say, Link, I need to click it.
That would then take me to this page, but I need to get a selector for the email address password and
the sign in button.
So I'm going to right click on the email address textbox and inspect it.
It's Ragnarok Velocity.
And I'm going to take that first one.
Mike So.
And I'm going to try driver find elements by a selector and place that value.
And as is the text field, I need to send values sung using keys and I'm going to use my test account
name, which is test at test dot com.
And if you're following along, please use your own test account and test password.
So I am then going to go back to the web page and use a select at all to focus on the password textbox.
And I'm going to get that top one.
And I'm going to write driver the find element.
Buyer Set a selector.
Pacer value and then use the send case.
And my password for this test account is test 1 to 3.
And then finally, I need to focus on the sign in button.
And I am just going to copy that top one.
And I'm going to write driver thought find element set a selector.
And as it's a button, I need to click it.
So once I've signed in.
So if I go back to the browser and just quickly sign in for you.
It would then take you to this page.
So I need to right click and inspect on this close link.
If I go back to Ragnarok Velocity.
So I'm going to take this link text.
And copy it.
And I'm going to do this in the test annotation.
So before method is simply take me to the well and is handling the log in a code and the test annotation
is where I'm actually going to click on the close link once I've been signed in.
So I'm going to let driver fund element by link text.
And in double quotes, I'm going to provide that value.
And I'm going to remove those question mark symbols.
I don't know why those appear, I think is just based on how the Web page has been designed.
And then I'm going to click on that link.
So that will now.
Take me to this page here.
And once I've reached this page, I want to click on the sign out button.
So if I right click and inspect.
And again, go to Red Rocks velocity.
I'm simply going to take this top one.
And I'm going to handle this in a after method.
So I'm going to look at after.
Meffert.
I'm going to create a new method public.
Void.
Sign out.
And I'm going to write driver but find elements.
But sir says selector and pacer value and I want to click on that sign up button.
So I need to import the after method.
And then that is complete.
And then the after suite is simply closing and quitting the session.
So I'm just going to add a few more things here.
So at the end of the before method, I'm going to print a message to console.
So I'm going to use system dots out of print end.
And I'm going to write a message of user has logged in.
I'm then going to copy that.
And paste it after this line.
And I am going to write user has clicked the close link.
And I'm simply going to copy one more.
And I'm going to paste it at the end of this line.
And I am going to write a message off user has.
Locked.
Out.
So the one other thing I'd like to do is also add some Fred sleep's just for demonstration purposes
so you can see what's happening.
Otherwise it will execute too quickly and you won't see it.
So I'm going to add a Fred dot sleep here.
And I'm going to add froze declaration.
And I'm going to do the same for this after MiFID.
Like so.
So that's our code complete.
And there is one other thing that we could do.
Just in case the web page takes a little while to load.
And that's to use an implicit white.
So I'm going to add an implicit weight in this before.
Sweet.
And I'm going to do it after the maximized line.
So I'm going to write here, driver.
Don't manage thoughts, timeouts, thoughts, implicit weight.
And hey, I need to provide a value of how long to wait.
So it's going to be ten.
And it's going to be at the time.
Unit dot seconds.
So I've used an implicit white to wait 10 seconds before it froze in error.
And as it's an implicit weight.
This will be global for the whole class.
So this is our class now complete.
So I'm going to write, file and click Save.
And close it and I'm going to double the test engine example.
I'm just going to update it with the new class name.
It's EL zero nine.
Part two.
An insider's.
So now I'm going to right click the test, inject smell.
And run it as a test in g suite to see what happens.
So it's opened and expanded the browser window.
Is click the sign in link and provided values.
Sign me in is click the club's link.
And then it's going to sign me out.
And then it closed the session and we can see in the console.
It's run one test and it's passed.
And if I go upwards, you'll see the messages users logged in, clicked the close link and logged out
has been outputted in the console.
So that is an example of how we can use the before sweet before method.
The test annotation, the off the method annotation and the after suite.
I hope you found this useful.
And thank you for watching.