In this lecture, we're going to create our next page object class.
So we have just created the shop product page, which is this page here.
So as a user, I may want to enter or add this product to my cart, and I can do this by pressing this
button.
And the forum panel will be displayed.
So this is the next page that I will be creating locators and methods for.
So I'm going to go back to the clips and I am going to right click page objects and create a new class
and I'm going to call this class shop content panel.
And then click Finish.
So again, like we've done previously, the first thing I'm going to do is write public web drive up
driver.
Again, important Web driver.
And now I'm going to begin, Chris, in the fields.
So the first field that I'm going to create is the continue shopping button.
So I'm going to right click it and inspect.
And on doing so if I go to velocity.
You'll see that I'm given some options here.
But again, I think this would be a good opportunity for us to see another customer locator.
So if I look at the dome, we can see that the button is listed here.
So the main thing I want to do here is I'm going to use an X path, but this time I'm going to use the
text method, but I'm going to use it in combination with a method called contains.
So contains when used in combination with text to allow us to search for some of the text.
For example, just a search will continue instead of continue shopping.
So to write to write to located like this, I'd write the following.
The two forward slashes.
And then it's a baton element.
As displayed here.
Followed by a open in square bracket.
And I'm going to write contains.
And then a round bracket.
Text.
We've been open and close in around Brexit.
Coma.
And in in single quotes, I'm going to provide some of the name so I can write, continue or continue
shopping or SEO Anti.
We can use a number of different combinations.
So I'm just going to write continue like so.
Then outside of the single quote, I'm going to add a closing round bracket.
And then a closed in square bracket.
And if I press enter on this.
Notice how the element has been located.
So we've used containers and we've also used the text method and we've provided some of the value.
So the full value is to continue shopping.
We've just provided continue and because there's no other element with a name of continue on the web
page, that's why only one of one elements has been located.
So I couldn't even reduce that.
The C.R.A. and presenter.
And you'll see that only that one element matches that value.
So I am going to leave this as continue and I am then going to copy this locator and I'm going to go
back to Eclipse and I'm going to run it by.
And I'm going to give this a name of continued.
Shot in Baton.
And it's going to equal buyer x path in double quotes.
I'm going to provide that locator.
The next one I'm going to go and find.
Is the proceed to check out button.
So this is what the user will click to proceed to check out.
So if I inspect that item.
And go to Redbox Velocity.
You see that there's various values that we can use there.
So there is one thing I've noticed with random velocity, and sometimes it provides a locator with a
unknown, a character such as this question mark.
So a workaround that we can use is simply copy in this.
And I'm going to write by.
Check out checkout button equals bi link text.
But when I provide that value, I can simply remove that character and this locator will work fine.
So I'm going to add a semicolon now.
And those are the two fields that I need.
So the next thing after that is to create the constructor, which is going to be public shop content
panel.
And inside those brackets, I'm going to provide a cab driver.
Driver?
And I've noticed once again I've spoke shop from I don't know why I keep doing that so I'm just going
to move to.
So here I am going to write this.
But driver equals driver, as we've seen many times now.
And as there's only two fields here, I'm just going to write the methods.
So public web element get continue shop.
Button.
And he's going to simply return driver that fund element.
And I'm going to return.
It's filled here.
And again, you need to import web elements and that goes away.
But a second one, I'm going to create a public web element.
Get check out.
Button.
And this is going to return.
Driver not find element.
And so when you got check up on Mr. Death, which is fine.
So this is the pay page objects we needed for the shop content panel.
And as there is only two buttons here, this is all that we will be required.
So thank you for watching.
And I'll speak to in the next lecture.