In this lecture, we begin to look at some JavaScript methods.
So we can access elements by using JavaScript.
The easiest way to access a single element in the DOM is by its unique hidey.
We can grab an element by we with the get element by the method of the document object.
So this image is a screenshot of the console window.
So where we access the developer tools by pressing F12 or right, click it and inspect it on a web page.
We also have a panel where we can insert and write JavaScript code.
So in this example, I'm using document dock element by ID and I'm passed in the ID value of content.
So I'll be showing you these in the demonstration towards the end of this lecture.
Access in elements by class said the class attributes is used to access one or more specific elements
in the DOM.
We can get all the elements with a given class name with digit elements by class name method.
We can also access elements by tag.
So another way to access multiple elements on the page would be by its HTML tag name.
So we can access that element by tag, by using the get elements, by taking a method.
Accessing elements by query selector.
So another useful method is document the query selector.
The document method query selector returns the first element within the document that matches the specified
selector.
We can pass a class or an ID using this method, using the hash or the dots prefix.
So in the example in the diagram, I'm passing an idea of content.
So let's try some of these out.
So I'm going to open up Chrome and I've gone to the automation test and website and I'm going to click
on the Buttons page.
So on here I had either press F12 or right click and inspect.
And this opens up the developers panel, which we've seen a number of times now.
But notice at the top there's an option for console.
And if I select that you're presented with a console for which we can write JavaScript code.
So I'm going to minimize this a little bit like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is I'm going to get a element's or return an element using JavaScript
code based on the ID.
So if I use a select, that's all and click on button one.
We can see it as an idea of button underscore one.
So I'm going to copy that.
And I'm going to go back to the console and I'm going to write some JavaScript to use that I.D..
So I'm going to write a document.
Dot get element by date.
And then I open and close in bracket only use single quotes.
And I'm going to pass that value.
At the end of that line, I'm going to use a semicolon.
Now that is JavaScript code we use in a JavaScript method here and if I press enter.
You'll see that it's returned back an element.
So this means he's found the match and if a hover over it, you can see the bottom.
One element has been highlighted on the left hand side of my screen.
So let's try another example.
So I'm going to close this panel.
And I'm going to go to the accordions page.
So on this page I'm going to right click and inspect and I'm going to get to select it all and click
on the accordion.
So you can see that there is free elements that have the same class of accordion header.
So I am going to use this class name.
And again, I'm going to go back to console.
And I'm going to write some JavaScript that uses elements by class name.
So I am again going to write document.
Don't get elements by class name.
And then in brackets.
And in single quotes, I'm going to place a value over a semicolon at the end.
And if I click enter.
You'll see that I've been provided with free values.
And if I expand them.
You'll see the free elements have been returned.
So that's how we can retrieve elements by class name, by using the get elements by class name method.
So I'm now going to close this developer panel and I'm going to go to the calculator page.
So on here.
Each one of these button elements is the same type of element.
So if I right click on inspect and select one of these buttons.
You can see it's an input that is a tight button.
And if I open up these table data type tags, you'll see that there's other buttons inside them.
So what I'm going to do here is take note of the input tags and I'm going to go to console and I'm going
to write document.
Thoughts get element by tag name.
And then in brackets and single quotes.
I'm going to pass the tag Empower.
Semicolon and press enter.
So you can see a similar collection has been returned with 18 values.
And there are a number of input tags on this page.
So if I expand this and hover over these.
Oops.
Sorry.
And hover over them.
You'll see that they're being highlighted on the page.
So that's how we can get all elements on a page by using the get elements by tag name method.
So I'm going to close this and I am going to return to the accordion page.
So I'm going to do one more example, and this time I'm going to use the query, select the method,
and what I'm going to do is select this header and use JavaScript to interact with it.
So I'm going to do this by right clicking and inspect them.
I'm going to focus on that hate to Heather.
And we can see as a hate to element of an idea of content.
So I'm going to go to console and I'm going to write.
Document Dot.
Query selector.
And then in brackets.
The single quotes.
I'm going to provide that I.D..
It was content.
And I'm going to use another method which is code in a HTML.
Now that is going to equal.
And I'm going to equal.
It's a hello world.
It was semi-colon at the end.
So what do you think will happen when I present you?
Let's try it.
And you can see that the hate to element text has changed by using JavaScript.
So I was able to select using the query, select the method.
The hate to element by side they.
And then I used the method of inner turmoil.
So it's the inner HTML of the H two element.
Was to equal the value of hello world.
So I hope you found this introduction to some common JavaScript methods useful.
And in the next couple of lectures, I'll show you how we can use JavaScript within our Selenium tests.
Thank you for watching.