In this lecture, we explore the testing group's.
So WhatsApp groups, they are a powerful way to group tests together so that we can run a specific group
of tests at a time.
For example, say we had a handful of tests we want to run during a smoke test and then wanted to test
in more detail during a regression test.
We can assign a group to the tests that make up the smoke tests and do the same for those that form
the regression tests.
This way we can amend our test engine small file to only run the group of tests that meets our requirement.
So let's take a look at the following example.
So I have a test energy example file.
And I've assigned a group to the add item to basket and check out classes so I can amend my tests in
small file to only run the smoke group, which includes these two classes.
I can then amend the text in simple file to run the regression group of tests, and the regression group
includes the log in ad review.
I do that since basket.
Check out and check our order.
So this is how we can assign groups to different classes, and then we can be selective to run a particular
group by amending our Test and G example.
So let's try this out.
To demonstrate the use of groups.
I need to reuse classes from the last lecture, so I'm going to use the ones from lecture free.
So this class is Lecture Free II, which simply had two methods method one and method two.
And they both outputs in a simple message console.
And we also had free B, which was method free, a method for which also outputs it.
A simple message to console.
So I am going to copy l zero free a and paste it and call in this new class l10 a test energy example
and I'm going to do the same for the free B class call in this one L10 ten B test energy example.
And they are now both listed here.
So in this second one, I am going to create one more method.
So I'm going to copy method for.
And paste it.
And I'm going to call this new method five and I'm just going to change the message to console two,
method five as well.
And then I'm going to say that class.
So if I open up today, you'll see there's two methods here.
Method one and method two.
And I'm going to assign groups to each of these.
So on the line of test, I'm going to write here, I'm going to open and close brackets.
And inside there, I'm going to write groups equals.
And then prices.
And inside those braces, I'm going to add double quotes and I'm going to write Smoke.
And then after that double quote or not use a comma and I'm going to use double quotes again and write
regression.
So I am now going to copy that line and paste it to the second one.
But this second one is only going to contain smoke.
So method one has groups equal smoking progression, but method two has groups equal smoke.
So I'm going to copy this again and open up the ten, be a class and I'm going to do the same for this
one.
And for this one, I'm going to paste it.
But this one is only going to have.
Regression.
And this final one is also only going to have regression.
So save both of these classes.
And then I'm going to open up the test engine XML.
So the first thing I need to do is update the class tags to list those new to classes.
So on I remove this.
I'm going to change that to L ten.
I underscore test and g x, you know, like so.
And I'm going to copy that line.
And paste it again for ten be.
So this testing example now points to these two files.
And the next thing I'm going to do is.
Make some room under here.
So within suite.
Underneath suite.
I am going to introduce some new takes.
So I am going to use the take of groups.
Like so.
And inside those groups tags, I'm going to use one.
And inside those run tags I am going to use include.
And I'm going to provide a name.
Equals.
And I am going to write inside those double quotes smoke.
Then outside.
So after the double quote, I'm then going to use a forward slash and appointee bracket.
So this has now we have now finished writing his test inject smell.
So I'm going to save it.
But before I run this, what do you think's going to happen?
So let me try running it and let's see.
And you can see a total of free tests for run and free of past.
And the reason for that is I've included the smoke group.
And if I look in that first class, you'll see this one has been set with a group name of smoke.
And so this one.
So that's two in total.
And if I look at the second class, you'll see only this one has a group smoke.
And that's why only free have run.
So in my tests in g small file if I was to change smoke to regression.
And save and try running it again.
Let's see how many run this time.
And you can see that for one this time.
And if I look at a first class, this one has been set with a group of aggression, which is one in
total.
Two, three and four.
If I look upwards, you'll see that MiFID five was printed.
Which is this?
Method for which is this one, a method free.
Which is this one.
And method one from the other class.
Which is the one that was set.
The group name of regression.
So that's how we can use groups in our code.
We can quite simply add groups to the test annotation and set a group name.
And then we can amend our test engine simple to use the groups run and include tags to be selective
in what group of tests we'd like to run.
Thank you for watching.