So we're now ready to try and run our test.
So I'm going to do this in two ways.
I'm going to run our tests sequentially like we've done previously.
And then I'm going to try running it in parallel execution.
So I'm going to open up my test, injects small file, and from when I attempted it last time, I already
had the parallel execution code here.
So I'm going to cut this and I'm going to add a comment.
And just pace that line like so.
Just so I can store it.
So I can copy it after.
So in his first attempt, I'm not going to use parallel execution just to make sure our tests still
run in the usual mode that we've used previously.
So I am going to save the test, inject simple file, and I'm then going to right click it, run as
test suite and to see what happens.
So our tests seem to run fine, even though we've made various changes to our framework.
You can see from the results two tests have run one pass and one failure.
And that failure was expected because in our tests the expected total value didn't match the true value.
So now that works in the standard way.
Let's try it with parallel execution.
So I'm going to open up the test, inject small file, and I'm going to cut the parallel equals tests
and thread count equals two and I'm going to pass that into my sweet take like.
So I'm then going to save this test, inject some old file and try running it again.
So when I run this, take note of the two browsers open up at the same time.
So notice how to browse have opened and if I flick fruity so you can see that tests are processing at
the same time.
So this proves that with Fred local and the changes we've made to our framework that we can now run
more than one test at the same time without issue.
So once this test completes, let's take a look at the results in eclipse.
And you can see that the suite again ran two tests, one pass and one failure as expected.
So that proves the changes we've made to our framework has made it parallel execution compatible.
This is a big advantage to speeding up running tests.
Thank you for watching.