In this lecture, we take a look at test energy parameters.
So what is testing g parameters?
Testing g parameters are the arguments that we pass to our test methods.
There are two ways we can pass parameter values, and this is by using parameters or data providers.
This lecture focuses on parameters and we look at data providers in the next lecture.
So test entry parameters are used to pass data into our tests at execution.
For example, we can send a U, r l address or an email address or username or various other pieces
of data.
So this slide provides a visual explanation.
And if you look to your left hand side here, I have a test in XML file and inside that test injects
HTML file.
I have a parameter set and the parameter is called you are L and the equals a value to a website address.
On the right hand side, I have a class called log in test and saw inside my test case.
I am expecting a u r l value to be provided from the parameter.
So the test testing XML file is going to send the parameter value.
So you are well equals web address.
So that web address will then be sent to the log in test class.
Well, expect in a URL to be provided.
So let's see an example.
So before I begin, let me just walk you through the test.
So I'm going to be using the test store website and I'm going to be using the sign in page where we
need to provide an email address and password.
So traditionally I've been using send keys.
I've been sending a hard coded value that I provide.
So this time I'm going to use test energy parameters to provide or pass the value of the email address
and password.
So if I go back to Eclipse, we've already done something similar in our lecture.
Nine Annotations Part two So I'm going to copy and paste class and call this new 111 for lecture 11
and I'm going to give it a name of parameters like so.
So in this class I've used before method and after method.
And the reform effort was handling the signing in.
So instead of the before method, I am going to change changes to test.
So that becomes a test case.
And I do not require this one, as if simply locks out the user and the after method.
Sorry.
The previous one actually clicked on the close link and the after method signs the user out.
Soneva.
Those are required.
So in this.
All I'm doing is setting up a new Chrome browser and it's going to expand the window.
And this test now is going to handle the signing in.
So it's going to go to the test or home page.
It's going to click on the sign in button and it's going to provide an email address and password.
And then it's going to click the submit log in button.
So as you can see at the moment for the email address, I'm using the same keys and I'm providing a
value for which I'm providing in double quotes.
And the same for the password.
I'm using same keys and providing a hardcoded value.
So this time I want to use test n g parameters to pass these values here.
And I can do this by first opening my tests.
Inject small file.
And so from the last lecture, I had to group some and remove the group's tags.
And I am going to remove one of these class lines because I only want to focus on that one new class.
And so I am going to simply update the name of this two points in a new class.
So l11.
On the school premises.
So this now points to this class.
So at the top of this test in g xml file, I am going to use parameters and I can do this by using a
parameter tag.
And then I need to provide a name.
So this is the name of the parameter and I'm going to call this first one email.
They're not going to add a space and I need to provide a value.
So I'm going to use the value keyword.
Equals and in the value of the email address.
So this is going to be test at.
Test.
And at the end of that line, outside of the double quotes, I'm going to use a forward slash and a
closing bracket.
Then I'm simply going to copy that again.
And I am going to paste it below and I'm going to change the name for the second parameter.
It's a password and the password value that I'm going to send.
Is Test one two free.
So that's what I need to do in the test engine.
Small file.
So I'm going to save it.
And then I'm going to close it.
So in the actual parameters class, I need to make a few changes.
So the first thing I need to do above the ACT test notation is use an ACT parameters annotation.
And inside of this, I'm going to stay outside of this.
I'm going to use brackets.
And inside those brackets, I'm going to use braces.
So an opening and close embrace.
And I am going to provide, in double quotes the name of the first parameter, and this was email.
And then outside of the double quotes, I'm going to use a comma and I'm going to provide the second
parameter name, which was password.
So you can see it as an error underneath parameters.
And if I hover over it, you'll see I'm given options to import it.
So make sure you import the one from test n g, which is the top on my screen.
So these can be a different order.
So make sure to select the test.
N.
G one.
And that era would then go away.
So this email address matches the parameter from test in g file.
And the second parameter passwords matches the second parameter from one test in G file.
So once I've done that, I then need to amend the method.
So I need to provide parameters in the actual method name itself.
So when I've got sign in, I've got brackets.
And inside those brackets I need to provide values.
So the first one is going to be string and I'm curious email.
And then I'm going to use a comma and provide another string and call this one password.
So now when I'm sending keys and providing a hardcoded value in double quotes, I'm now going to remove
that.
And instead I am going to use email.
Which match is this?
And for the password.
I am going to use password lights like so.
So now I'm ready to try and run this.
So let's see what happens.
So I'm going to run it from the test.
Inject small file.
Unless see how this test proceeds.
So you can see that it provided values there.
And if I run it again.
So I'm going to slow this down so that you can see exactly those values being entered.
So I'm just going to add another friend dot sleep here.
Unless I had one of 5 seconds.
And I am going to add another one after the password has been entered.
So I'm going to save this and try running it again.
So it's gone to the sign in page and it's provided a email address.
And it's provided a password.
And then it signs me in.
So those values.
Email address and password.
Ah.
From the parameters here in the method name.
But these are populated by using this parameters annotation and these parameters annotation will go
and fetch the data from the test.
In example, parameters that have a match in name and the values are these which get provided and sent
to the test.
So to prove this works, let me change the email address to.
Hello.
At test dot com.
So if I say this test injects ammo file.
And try running again.
Let's see if that value now gets sent across.
And you can see halo at test dot com was provided in the email textbox.
And so this user won't be able to sign in because the email address and password is not a correct or
valid combination, so that there has proven that we can send values from our test engine Excel file
to our test and we're able to do that by adding parameters tags into our test injects email file where
we provide a name of the parameter and the value.
And in the actual class itself, we may need to set a at parameters annotation above the test annotation,
and then we need to provide the value of the board, the name of the parameters which match that from
the tests.
Inject small file.
We then need to amend the method to use parameters.
And so I have created a string parameter of email and password and these will get populated with the
data that's been pulled through from the test, injects a nail file at execution.
I then use these parameters in must send case command so that email address is matching the value of
that parameter and is the same for the password.
So this means we can amend the testing parameters as we please and they will be sent to the test that
are used in those parameters.
So why would we use this instead of using hardcoded values in send keys?
Well, think about in the real world where you might have tens or hundreds of different test methods,
you might be use in an email address and password in all of those tests.
And if you've hardcoded those values, it means that if you ever wanted to change the username or email
address and password combination, you would have to go through every single one of those methods and
update them manually.
But by using parameters, it means that I can set the value of these parameters once, and then I can
reuse these parameters in as many methods as I need.
So from a maintainability point of view, I would only have to update the parameters in my test in G
file instead of going through all new methods and updating each of the same keys manually.
So that is the big advantage of using test g parameters and I hope he found this lecture interest and
useful.
And once again, thank you for watching.