In this lecture, we continue with part two.
So before I start writing code, let's first look at the main methods of the JavaScript executable in
detail.
So the JavaScript execute interface provides two main methods.
These are execute script and execute async script.
The main difference between these are that scripts executed with async must explicitly signal they are
finished by invoking to provide a callback.
This callback is always injected into the executed function as a lost argument.
So don't worry if this doesn't make sense in nearly all cases will be used in the execute script method.
So using the JavaScript executable, the below code is usually used where making use of the JavaScript
execute interface, we are referencing the interface and assigning a driver instance to it.
We then use the execute script method.
You need to provide a script and an optional argument.
So here I'm simply using the JavaScript execute to create an object name and it's going to equal JavaScript
execute and the Java instance, I then use that object to execute a script and this is where I provide
the script in the parameters.
So let's try this out.
So before I begin writing code, let me first show you what I'm trying to do here.
So I'm going to the Automation System website and I'm going to use a contact dust form.
So I am going to provide values each of these fields.
Then I'm going to click the submit button that using JavaScript.
So I'm going to go back to Eclipse.
And for those of you who have downloaded the code from the last lecture, you can just copy this one.
Otherwise, just copy the browser tabs class.
So I'm going to copy and paste that cool in this new 111 JavaScript executable part two and then click.
Okay.
I'm then going to open that class and delete everything up to the driver.
They'll get method.
So the first thing I'm going to do is get the address for the contact that contact us form.
To replace the current one in the get method like so.
The next thing, what I'm going to do is get locaters for these four techs fields.
So you've seen me do this a number of times in the past.
So to save you some time, I've simply written this already for you, and I'm just going to copy it
into my project.
So the first one is simply for the first time field men, the last name, field, email, address and
name for the comment text area.
And I'm passing the value with James to the first name Smith for the last name James at test dot com
for the email address.
And this is a sample comment.
So the first thing I need to do here and I import this is import the boy from selenium and those errors
go away.
So if I say this class.
And try running it.
Let's see what happens.
So you can see those fields have been populated.
So what I'm going to do now is.
Go down a couple lines and I am going to use something called a web element and I can use the web elements
by using web.
Element.
I'm going to give this web element a name and call it submit.
Equals driver find element by CSF selector and double quotes.
So this web element has to be imported from selenium and that area will go away.
But what I can do here is by using a web element, it creates a variable or an object which will store
a locator to an element.
So I am going to go back to the contact us form and I am going to right click and submit the inspect
the submit button and I'm going to go to run the box velocity and I am going to get the second CC selector
for that submit button and copy it.
And then going to paste it in those double quotes.
So this submit variable will now store.
A reference to the selector to click on the submit button.
So what I could actually do is write.
Submit thoughts.
Click.
And you can see that that's accepted.
Because this variable submit stores the locator for that submit button.
So I can just reuse that variable and then add the click command at the end of it.
So let me just show you that work.
Working.
So you can see the summit bottom was clicked.
But I want to use JavaScript, so I'm going to delete this and I am going to write the following.
I'm going to write Java script.
Execute her.
And I'm going to give a object name of J.S. equals in brackets.
Java script executable and outside those brackets.
I'm going to pass a driver instance with a semicolon at the end.
So this is a object of JavaScript executable, and I've called it J.S. and it simply equals the JavaScript
executes in brackets.
And then I pass a driver instance, which is this instance here.
So the next thing I'm going to do is write.
J.S. So I'm using that Java, execute our JavaScript, execute object, dot, execute script.
And you can see it takes a it takes two arguments, a string and an object.
So I'm just going to leave double quotes for the first parameter.
But for the second one, I am now going to pass that submit object.
Mike.
So.
And at the end of that line, I'm going to write a semicolon.
So I need to provide a value here.
And how I can do this is by writing arguments.
Square brackets.
Zero.
And then use the command click.
The brackets at the end.
So I'm going to explain arguments in a moment, but just take note that this is JavaScript I'm using
here.
And I am passed in as a second argument.
The object name which contains the selector for the submit button.
So if I save this.
And try running it.
Let's see what happens.
And you can see that submit button was also selected, but this time I use JavaScript.
So say I wanted to.
First fill in this form and then click the reset button first before submitting to submit selected to
Submit Button.
So how would I do that using JavaScript or how would I do that?
Using the execute script command.
So what I can do is I can create a novel web element.
And I'm going to call this one reset equals.
Driver the fine element by CSF selector and in double quotes.
I'm going to go back to that Web page.
Focus on the reset button and then copy this CSA selector.
And I'm going to paste it in the double quotes like so.
So now I have two web elements Objects Submit, which contains the selected to the submit button and
reset, which contains a selector for the reset button.
So how can I use both of these in the execute script command?
So what I can write is a comma.
Arguments.
But this time in square brackets, I'm going to write one dot click like so.
And in the second arguments under the comment comma and I'm going to pass the reset whereby elements
like so.
So these arguments are like a list.
So argument zero, which is the submit I want it to click.
Then argument one which is the next argument?
I want to click it.
But at the moment I'm thinking the submit button before I'm clicking the reset button.
So I am going to swap those two around.
So I'm going to first select the reset button and then I'm going to select the submit button.
So the reset button is now argument zero.
And the summit button is argument one.
So I am going to save this.
And I want you to watch very carefully because it happens really quick.
But notice that the form gets filled in and then the reset button is selected and the form entries are
deleted before the submit button has been selected.
So that happened really fast.
But notice that I've been taken to an error page and it says All fields are required.
So what this proves is that those text fields were empty.
Before to submit button was selected.
So let's see it one more time.
So did you see that the reset button was selected and those fields were cleared before submit button
was triggered?
So that proves that I was able to send two JavaScript commands.
By using the execute script.
So that was quite difficult to explain.
And we've seen quite a few, you know, new concepts here.
But I hope you understood how we can use JavaScript within our Selenium web driver tests.
So really the code is quite simple.
All we need to do is use the JavaScript, execute to interface and create an object which equals JavaScript
executable and then pass in the driver instance.
We then use that JS object and we use the execute script command and pass a command in the first double
quotes.
So the first argument and then we use a comma.
To pass the actual argument or the object which contains the locator for the element we want to interact
with.
And in this case, I've passed two separate arguments or two separate commands and passed two separate
elements to interact with.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And once again, thank you for watching.