In this lecture, we take a look at four H loops.
So what is it for each loop?
It starts with a keyword for like a normal for loop.
But instead of declaring an initialize in a loop counter variable like the int equals oh, in our last
example you declare a variable that is assigned same type as the base type of the array, followed by
a colon, which is then followed by the array name.
Is commonly used its rate over an array or collections class, for example, whenever you list.
So this might not make sense at the moment.
But let's see an example.
In Eclipse.
I'm going to simply copy and paste the class in the last lecture, call in S1 l 11 for lecture 11 and
I'm going to give it a name of for each loop.
Like so click.
Okay.
And then I'm going to double click and open it.
So I am going to remove the for loop from last lecture.
And the first thing I'm going to do here is I'm going to create an integer, right?
And you do this by right in in T and then square brackets.
And then I need to give the array a name.
So I'm going to call it numbers.
So an array is a collection.
And so what this means is I can store a number of number values in this integer array called numbers.
And I can do this by write in equals and then open and close embraces.
And then I'm going to add two, comma four.
Coma six.
Coma and eight.
Like so.
And at the end of that line, I'm at a semicolon.
So what this means is that this array called numbers is going to store four integer numbers two, four,
six and eight.
The next thing I'm going to do is use the keyword for.
And then in brackets I'm going to write int number.
Then the colon and then the name of the array, which is numbers.
At the end of that line, I'm going to create new braces and inside the foil for each loop.
I'm going to write system dots out dot print n and the value that I want to print is number.
So very simply.
Again, I've created a int array called numbers and I'm storing four integers in that array.
I'm then using a for each loop and in the first part the brackets I've declared an int called number.
And then I've used a colon.
And then as a second part of that bracket, I've added the name of the collection, which is called
Numbers.
And then what's going to happen is it's going to go through each one of those values in this collection
and print out line and provide the number value.
So that number is going to change after every iteration based on these values here.
So let me say this and try running it.
And you can see their every single value has printed.
So it's iterated through.
Each one of those values in the numbers collection and printed out.
So what is the key difference between a for each loop and a follow?
So you may remember from the last lecture when declaring a fallout, you have to declare how many times
you want the loop to run.
Whereas with a for each loop I can add to it.
For example, if I had ten, 12 and 14.
I don't have to make any changes to the for each loop because if I run this again now.
You'll see that those additional values have been accounted for.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And thank you for watching.