In this lecture, we take a look at data provider.
So what is testing?
Data provider.
Data provider allows us to send more than one set of data to our test cases.
For example, say we had free username and password combinations that we wanted to test with the log
in functionality of a website.
You might think we need to run the test individually three times for each test combination.
Luckily test n g provides functionality using the at data provider annotation to send more than one
set of data at execution.
Will be stored in our sets of data in something called a multi dimensional array.
This will be an array that stores object pairs, for example, an email address and password.
And if we look at the below image.
You'll see that this consists of two columns column zero and column one and four rows.
So row zero to row free.
Now IMO zero in column zero I might store my first email address and in row zero column one I might
store my first password.
And in row one column zero, I might store my second email address and in column one, row one, I might
store my second password.
Old men use the row data.
So both column zero and column one, which contains the email address and password.
In my test at test execution.
And then I'll send row one for my second test execution.
So I'd explain this more as I provoke provide an example later on.
But for now, just know that I'll be using multi dimensional arrays to store objects which will contain
values.
So this is a screenshot of some code where I am using a multi dimensional dimensional array.
So don't worry if this appears confusing, as it will become clearer when I demonstrate the use of this.
But the key thing I want you to know from this is look how I've split the data into sets.
So dataset one, dataset two, and dataset three.
The first number in the square brackets refers to the row number, and the second number refers to the
column number.
So in data 0000 column zero I'm still in the value of test that test outcome which is an email address.
And in the second one, so wrote zero column one I'm stored in a password value and those two will make
up my first data set.
And in my second example I'm use in row one column zero and it store in test that test dot com.
And in VO one column one I'm storing my second password and these two will be combined to make up my
data set to.
So.
How does it work?
We need to use the data provider annotation when writing code to set the multidimensional right in our
test class.
We then assign data to particular columns and rows in the multi dimensional array.
The test engine example doesn't require any special tags.
We simply run our tests, and the tests were executed until all data sets are exhausted.
So let's see an example of this.
In this demo, I am going to use the store log in page and I'm going to send free sets of email, address
and password combinations to log in at test execution.
So I'm going to go back to Eclipse and I'm going to simply copy and paste the class from the last lecture.
Calling this new one l 12 and given a name of data provider like so.
And then going to open up this class and most of this class is going to remain the same as the previous.
But the first change I'm going to make is leads in this parameters line.
I'm then going to create a new method which is going to start setting up the multi dimensional array.
So the first thing I'm going to do is use the at data provider annotation.
And if I hover over that, I'm given an option to import it from Test and G.
So the method that I'm going to create is public.
Object with a capital O.
Followed by two pairs of square brackets.
Then I'm going to give the Mefford a name and I'm going to call this Get Theta.
Followed by round brackets.
And in an open and close embrace.
So you can see it as an error underneath the method name.
And this is because I need to add a return statement, which is something I'll do in a moment.
So in the first line of this method, I'm going to write object.
And then two pairs of square brackets.
And I'm going to give it a name of data.
Equals.
New object and again, two pairs of square brackets.
And at the end of that line, I'm going to add a semicolon.
So in this here in these square brackets is where I need to set up the size of the rows and columns.
So I need three rose.
And two columns.
And once I enter that, the error goes away.
So under this I am going to add my first data set.
So I am going to add a comment just so I know, and I'm going to call this data set one.
And to set the date a set of one, I am going to use the data object that I created above.
And two square brackets.
And in his first one, it's going to be ro zero.
Column zero.
And the value that I want to store in this location.
Is an email address and it's going to be test two at a test dot com.
It was semi-colon at the end of it.
In the next line, I am going to use data again.
And square brackets.
But this time it is going to be road zero again.
But this time, column one.
And in this location, I'm going to store my first data set password.
And this is test.
One, two, three, four, five.
So just to let you know, I've actually created a second account on the test store called test to test
dot com and it actually has a password of test one, two, three, four, five.
So I do expect this to be a valid combination.
So I am going to do a couple of carriage returns and now I'm going to start my dataset to.
So rather than writing this out from scratch, I'm just going to copy these two lines.
And I'm going to paste it here.
But instead of row one evo zero, I want it to be row one and the same for the second line.
So row one, column one.
So in this first one I want to store a email address of taste test dot com.
And I want to use a password of test.
One, two, three.
So that's going to be stored in row one.
Column zero is going to be the second email address value.
And in row one column one is the second password.
So once again, I'm now going to copy this.
Here changing is the data set free and instead of row one, column zero, I want to use row to column
zero.
And for the second line, I want to use row to column one.
So this here, I'm going to provide an email address and password that doesn't exist so I can call this
anything I'm just going to call it doesn't exist at test or com.
And I can write a password of exes.
So I don't this will not be a valid email address and password combination, so I expect it to fail
in this one.
So let's have free data set up.
And at the end of this, I'm going to add a return statement.
So I'm going to write a return and I'm going to provide data.
And a semicolon.
So this data refers to this object.
And we've used this object to create datasets.
So the next thing I need to do is I need to amend my test case.
So after that test I am going to add round brackets.
And inside those round brackets I am going to write data.
Provider.
And notes that data is with a lower case D and provider starts with a capitalized P.
And it's going to equal in double quotes.
The method name, which is get data.
So why expect to happen here is where we we provide in an email address password and click any submit
log in button.
I expect this to run free times using the data provider method.
Get data which contains free sets of data.
So I expected to use this on the first attempt, this on the second and this on the third.
So the one thing that I need to do here is that each time I run the test, you try logging in.
I need to then sign out so that the next data can input the next set of data.
So you may remember from the annotations part to lecture.
We actually saw an out in this after method.
And I do that by using this code.
So I'm simply going to copy that.
And I'm going to add that code at the end of this.
So all this does is it's going to lock in using that first data set.
And if it successfully logs in, it wouldn't log out ready for the next set of data and so on.
So I have now completed my code and I am going to save the class.
And at the close, both of those I have open.
So I'm going to run this on the test g file.
So all I need to do here is update the class name to lecture 12.
Data.
Provider.
And so this now points to this class.
So I'm going to save that test in G file and then I am going to run the test to see if this works.
So you can see that test to test dot com was entered.
And then a password of test.
One, two, three, four, five.
And then it sends me in.
And then signs me out.
And then the second set of data is use test that test dot com.
And a password of test.
One, two, three.
So inspired.
And then signs me out.
And on the third attempt it uses doesn't exist that test dot com.
If a password of x is.
And because this doesn't exist.
It says authentication failed.
This one enclose the browser.
And if I return back to Eclipse.
You'll see that it's reported a failure.
And the reason that failed was because data set free did not contain a valid email address and password
combination.
So this is quite confusing.
But hopefully I've explained it in a way where it's kind of broken down.
How we can use data provider.
The key thing is it allows us to send multiple sets of data.
Instead of having to write multiple test cases.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And once again, thank you for watching.