So the good news is we only have three more page object classes to create before we can start writing
our tests.
So as you're now familiar and comfortable with the approach that I'm using, I'm going to go through
these final free page objects in a faster speed.
So we've just created one based on this page, and the next one we need to create will be based on the
addresses tab.
So the only way we can access this tab is by filling in some dummy information here.
So I've selected Mr..
I'm going to test.
Test and I'm going to provide an email address.
Now, you don't need to provide a password or date of birth, and these are optional fields.
So what this will mean is if you do provide a password, it will save you account.
So if you are returning customer, you can then sign into the website.
So I also need to take this agree to terms and conditions.
An impressed continue.
But the problem is here is I've used this email address before, so if I select continue, you'll see
this email is already used.
Please choose another.
So I'm just going to use test one test dot com and then click continue.
And then this will then move me on to the addresses section of the page.
So this is where I need to start capturing some information here.
So notice that the first name and last name has already been saved because we entered this in the previous
tab.
So we need to get selectors for some of these fields.
So you could skip the optional ones as we do not need to provide values for these, but there are some
that are mandatory such as address city, state, etc..
So all I'm going to do here is get locaters for all these fields, including the checkbox and the button.
So I'm not going to show you these one by one, as we've seen a similar process before.
But what I will do is show you how to create the class so that you have a consistent name to what I'm
using.
So I'm going to right click page objects, select new and select class.
And I'm going to give this a name of order form delivery.
And then to finish.
So in this class, all I'll do is write very similar code to what you were saying before.
So I have this pre-written for which you could download.
So I'm going to copy that and I'm going to paste it here.
And there's errors because we need to import the classes.
And once that is done, we then have the locators which refer to these text boxes and dropdown menus.
Also the checkbox button and the continue button.
And you can see this all listed here, but they've been named appropriately so you'll see that I've
added first name and last name here.
Which wasn't really required because it was predefined.
But a customer may want to choose to change their first name or last name on this page.
So that's why I've added those two fields.
So please feel free to write this code manually.
Otherwise you can download the code from this lecture.
Thank you for watching.