In this lecture, we take a look at a test.
Energy depends on method.
So what is it that depends on?
Method is a test energy attribute that we can use to trigger method only after another method has passed.
We set the method to depend on another.
This method would only execute once the former has executed successfully.
This can be useful for when we might have a scenario where we might need to wait for something to happen
before proceeding to the next step.
So here is a visual example.
So at step one, I go to a website sign in page.
I then enter a username, an email address, and then enter a password.
But I only want to enter a password once the username or email address has been entered, so the first
step won't execute until the second step has passed.
So let's see an example of this.
So in this lecture I am once again going to use the login page from the store website.
So my plan is to create three simple test cases.
The first one will simply enter email address value.
The second test case will enter a password value and the third test case will click the sign in button.
I'll then use the depends on methods within my code and I'll demonstrate the output and the effects
of using it.
So I am going to go to Eclipse.
I am going to right click section 11, select new and in select class and I'm going to call this new
class l 13 underscore depends on methods and then click finish.
So this new class would then open and rather than manually write setup code.
I'm just going to open up data provider and copy the before sweet code and also the web driver driver
line.
So I'm going to click Control, see on my keyboard and I'm going to paste it like so.
So that next thing not I'm going to do is I'm going to use driver don't get to go to the URL.
So I'm going to open up the web page and copy the URL.
Go back to eclipse and right driver dot get in double quotes.
I'm going to take you out to the Web page.
So the slight thing I've done differently to other lectures is that I've placed the driver that gets
in the default suite.
So this means that the browser will go to this web page before it starts executing the text annotations.
So now underneath this, I'm going to create three simple methods.
The first one is going to be called public void.
Enter.
Email.
Open and close embrace and I'm going to use driver thought to find elements via CSA selector.
And I'm going to open up the Web page.
Right click and inspect the email address text field.
Open up red rocks velocity and simply take this first selector.
And I'm going to pay in the double quotes and as it's a textbox filled, I'm going to use send keys
to provide a value.
And I'm going to pass test at test dot com like so.
And for demonstration purposes I'm again going to use Fred built sleep.
And as a sleep free seconds, just so you can see what's happening when I demonstrate the running of
this code.
So I'm going to copy that method.
And I'm going to paste that below and I'm going to call it Enter Password.
And I need to get a selector for the password textbox.
And I'm going to pace that here.
And I need to update the value that I'm sending to the password value, which is test.
One, two, three.
And then finally, I'm going to copy this one more time.
And this is going to be click.
Button.
And then I'm going to go back to the website.
Focus on the sign in button.
Got to take this first.
Yes.
A selector.
And I'm going to update the value.
And instead of saying keys as a button, I need to use dot click like so.
So there's one thing I need to do here before I try running this and try to think what that is.
So what I need to do is use that test notation.
And I need to import that from Test and J.
And I need to set one of those at the beginning of each of the methods.
So I'm now going to save this class.
And then I'm going to right click run as test in G test and let's see what happens.
So he's gone to the sign in page.
A in an email address.
It's entered a password.
But it hasn't selected the sign in button.
Have a thing quite at his.
If I go back to clips, it says that free tests have run them free of past and if I scroll up you'll
see is pass click button pass enter email and pass enter password.
So it has run all free test cases.
But the issue is to do with the ordering of execution.
So the click button test executed before the email address and password.
And because the button was clicked before there was an email address or password, it didn't log me
in.
So what I'm going to use on this click button is the depends on methods, and I can use this button
right in a bracket.
And Martin depends.
On methods we've been at the end.
Equals.
Open and close embraces.
And then use in double quotes.
I'm going to copy the enter password method name and paste it like so.
So now this method should only run once this method has finished executing.
So let me say this.
And try running it again.
So again, it's gone to the log in page.
Enter an email address.
Sensitive password.
And this time you selected the sign in button.
So that is how we can use that depends on method.
Attributes allows us to run a test only after the successful execution of another test case that we
provide.
I hope he found this lecture useful.
And once again, thank you for watching.