This lecture is an introduction to object orientated programming.
So what is Opie?
Object orientated programming is a method of computer programming that uses objects.
An object is a piece of code that lets you create many similar pieces of code without actually rewriting
the code each time.
This is achieved by first writing in a class which is essentially a blueprint of the object.
Then you can easily create an instance of the object, which is basically just one particular version
of the object built from the class blueprint.
So say we had a dog class.
Think of this as a blueprint.
The class contains two fields dog name and dog breed.
We now create an object for the dog class and provide values for the dog name and dog breed fields.
We set the dog name to equal buster and dog breeds equal Yorkshire Terrier.
We then create another object using the adult class.
This time we set a dog named to Charlie, and the dog breeds a poodle.
We met.
We now have two objects with different properties based on the same dog class blueprint.
So if you look at the diagram below.
At the top.
I have a dog class and the two boxes below are objects of that class.
So an object is an instance of a class, an object one.
We had Buster and Yorkshire Terrier in object to.
We have Charlie.
That's a poodle.
And these are both based on the dog class.
The four principles of object orientated programming are encapsulation, abstraction, inheritance and
polymorphism.
So first, let's have a look at encapsulation.
So what does the word encapsulation even mean?
It's the action of enclosing something in or as if in a capsule.
Pretend we have a program that has a few logically different objects which communicate with each other.
This is based on the rules defined in the program.
Encapsulation is achieved when each object keeps its state private inside a class.
Other objects don't have direct access to the state.
Instead, they can only call a list of public functions.
For example, public methods.
So if we look at the code on the right hand side here, I have two objects object one and object two
and they are both an instance of the class two.
Object one has two fields, dog name and dog breed.
And here are the values.
An object two has the same fields and different values.
Each one of these objects has methods.
So I want you to imagine these fields as private fields.
But the methods are set as public methods.
So object one cannot directly change the value of object to lose fields.
So object one can't change the dog name or dog breed directly in object to.
This is because we almost always set fields in a class as private.
Instead, we create getter and setter methods that can retrieve or manipulate the values of the object
fields.
So object one might call the method set dog name and provide a parameter to change the name.
This is a scheme in how we designed that code to work.
So objet one could have access to the public methods of object two.
And so if object one was to change the name of object to an object one might set.
Corner method, set dog name and provide a value.
And because this method is public, it name is coded to update the field value of object to.
So next we have abstraction.
Abstraction hides the internal implementation details of a program.
Abstraction shows only the essential attributes such as public methods that can be called and hides
and necessary information, such as the actual code of how the method works.
It helps reduce programming, complexity and effort and is one of the most important concepts of OPI.
Think of your mobile phone.
It's a very complex device in terms of the technical details of how it works.
But from a user's perspective, it's fairly easy to use.
For example, if you wanted to increase the volume, you just click a button.
But internally, software interprets that input a main increase voltage to a speaker.
Next is inheritance.
So some objects can be very similar, but often they're not entirely the same.
It would make sense to use common lot logic, so it only has to be written once but can be used by other
classes so that it can inherit the logic.
This is where inheritance plays a key role.
Attributes and methods that are common between two objects can be written in a superclass where a superclass
inherits these properties but a subclass inherit these properties.
This way.
We only need to write a common code once in the parent class as it can be reused.
The word extends is used where subclass extends superclass.
So if we take a look at this code at the top, I've created a class called Vehicle.
So vehicle is a super class.
It has a string field called Mike, which has been assigned the value of BMW and it has a public method
called Ref which simply prints out a string value of one.
Of then created a second class called Car.
And core is a subclass and extends the vehicle superclass.
So the car cross has a Philco model which has been assigned the value of free series.
Carr also has a method called Get model which simply returns the value of the model filled.
Now, in this first class, I create a core object.
So object is the name of the object and it's based on the cost car subclass.
Now use in that car object.
I tried to call the rev method.
Which belongs to the superclass vehicle here.
I then use system to print mine and use in that car object.
I return the mike by calling the make field from the vehicle superclass.
And using the call object again, I call the get model method which belongs to the car class.
So because the car subclass extends vehicle.
The car class or any objects based on the car class will have access to all public available fields
and methods in the vehicle.
Superclass.
And that's why if I run this test class, it produces the results.
Vroom.
Which is from the rev method in the superclass.
BMW, which is from the make field from the super class and free series, which is from the car method
get model which returns the model filled value which is free series.
Now, that may seem quite complicated, but I assure you during this course, you would learn exactly
what this is.
Next we look at polymorphism.
The polymorphism is derived from a Greek word, which means many shapes.
This is closely related to inheritance, but has a few key differences.
Inheritance is a concept related to code reuse, whereas polymorphism is approach to expressing common
behavior between types of objects that have similar traits.
Subclasses, also known as child classes, can define their own unique behavior and yet share some of
the same functionality of the superclass, also known as a parent class.
Imagine we have an animal superclass and two subclasses dog and cat.
What might be common property properties between a dog and a cat.
They might both make sounds.
But does a dog meow or does a cat woof?
The answer is no.
At least I hope not.
So although both animals can make a sound, we need to account for the differences.
But the two between the two types of animals.
So if we look at this code, I'm going to basically explain it, but we will see an example of this
when we come to code in.
But I want you to take into account is that there is a class called Animal and this is a superclass
and it's got a public method called make sound, which makes a sound by.
Next.
We have a class called Dog which extends the animal superclass.
But the dog class has its own method called make sound.
And it prints out a value of wolf.
So finally, I have another class called Test.
And in test, I am defining a object name called Benji.
So this is based on class animal.
It's called Benji by equals a new dog class.
So although Benji is of type animal.
It actually is quite an object of type dog.
Now if I use the Benji object and call the make sound method, it prints out woof.
And that's from the subclass dog as shown here.
But if I change Benjy to equal new animal.
So the object is now based on the animal superclass.
If I call Benjy, don't make sound.
This time it prints out back from the animal class.
So what?
That showing is that we can change the form of the object.
So here equals a dog object, behave equals an animal object.
And each time we call make sound, it's actually printing out different values based on the form the
object is or what class it's based upon.
So what is the difference between inheritance and polymorphism?
So inheritance refers to using the structure and behaviors of a superclass in a subclass, whereas polymorphism
refers to change in the behavior of a superclass in the subclass.
So we've covered a lot of content in this lecture, and I wouldn't be surprised if many of you are confused
or still unsure about what we've covered here.
But the key thing I want you to take away from this lecture is the four principles of object orientated
programming.
If you're still confused or unsure about what we just covered, that's fine and expected.
But as we progress to the next few lectures, hopefully things will start to make more sense when we
use code examples.