Now that we've created our paid object classes, we're in a position to start constructing our tests.
So the first test is going to be called or the complete test, and this can replicate a user go into
the automation test in website.
Scrolling down to find the test or link, and when they click it, they'll be brought to the test store
home page.
This user is then going to select item one.
They're going to change the quantity or so the size to medium.
They're going to change the quantity to two.
And then they're going to add the item to CART.
This wouldn't even bring up the funding panel.
The user would then select.
Proceed to check out.
On the shopping cart page.
They're going to select, have a promo code.
And they're going to enter promo code of 20 off.
And when they added, it would deduct 20% from the total price.
They then select the proceed to checkout button.
And they'll be taken to the personal information page.
Don't enter dummy data here and then click continue to be taken to the address page without enter dummy
address information.
Then then proceed to the shipping method page and select shipping method.
By finally going to the payment page and selecting the payment method where the order will be placed.
So this is replicating an end to end test.
That's a user will do if they were to buy an item from the test or website.
So to begin, we are going to create a new class for this or the complete test.
And as it's a test, we're going to create this under the source test Java folder.
Here we have a default package called automation testing, and I'm going to simply reuse this package
by right click in selected new and select in class.
I'm going to give this class a name of order, complete test, and I'm going to click Finish, which
will open up the class.
So the first thing I'm going to do in this class is use the extensions keyword.
And it's going to extend the base age.
If a hover over a base page, I'm given an option to import it and that import would be listed here.
You'll now see that there's an error and the other complete test.
And if I hover over that, it says that we require a constructor.
If I add that constructor, that then adds the following code.
So remember we extended the base page and if I open up the base page, this base page contains a constructor
and this constructor gives us access to this conflict of properties file.
So that's why we need to add this construct the hill and that's why it uses the super keyword which
calls the constructor from the extended page, which is the base page.
The next thing we need to do is use test n g annotations.
So I'm going to use at before test.
So this will run before the test.
And underneath that annotation, I'm going to create a new method and I'm going to call it public.
Void.
Set up with brackets and an open and close embrace.
So if I hover over before test, you'll see I'm given an option to import it.
And that error then goes away.
So this setup method is going to be responsible for two things.
It's going to nationalize the driver object, and it's also going to get the URL from the conflict properties
file.
So I'm going to write driver equals get driver with brackets and a semicolon.
And if I hover over, get driver over, I need to add a declaration and that ever then goes away.
So where is this driver coming from?
So where we extending the base page, you'll see that we have a public static web driver field called
driver.
So we have a flow into this driver filled.
We then use in get driver, which is a method inside that base page.
And this method is responsible for initializing the driver object and expanding the window and exit
onsets in an implicit way of 10 seconds.
The next thing that we need to do in this test class is use driver to get an inside that gets inside
the brackets.
We pass in a method name of get URL.
And this, again, is a method that belongs to the base page.
And this method simply goes to the conflict up properties file.
It looks for the key URL and it retrieves the value, which is the automation test in website address.
So that is our set up and before test completes.
The next one that we're going to use is after test.
And I'm going to give this new method a name of public void.
Tear down.
Sadistic tear down method is going to be responsible for simply closing the browser and set in the driver
field back to No.
So I'm going to import off the test from test n g.
And here I'm going to simply write Driver Dot Close, which will close the browser session.
And then I'm going to write Driver Equals No.
So remember, this will only be called after we've finished with the test.
So driver equals now is simply set in this field here back to a no value.
The next film we're going to do is use one more test in G annotation, and this is at test.
So this method here is going to be the method that contains the contents of our actual test.
So I'm going to run.
It's public void and I'm going to give this method a name.
And I'm going to call it end to end.
Test like so.
And then brackets and an open and close embrace.
So I need to hover over test imported from test and G.
And that era then goes away.
So the first thing that I'm going to do in this test method is to use the home page, page object.
So remember this home page page object refers to.
The Automation Test in home page.
And this is where we have a number of locators for various elements on this page.
So to use this home page class, I'm going to write home page and I'm going to give this object.
The name of home equals new home page and in brackets, followed by a semicolon.
So if I hover over a home page, you'll see that I'm given an option to import home page from the page
objects package.
In doing so.
You'll see the home page has been imported here.
And that terror has now gone away.
But there's also another error after the new homepage line.
And if I hover over it, it says I need to add an argument.
So if I go to the home page.
Page objects.
Remember, we've written a constructor here.
And this construct those expect in a driver object to be passed.
So this is why we need to provide the driver instance in these brackets.
So this is now pass in his object, this driver instance and this driver object has been initialized
in a before test setup method.
And the driver also gets the neural.
But this driver, which only comes from the public static Web driver from the base page.
So by passing it to this object.
This object now would know that we're dealing with this driver instance four, which we can use to interact
with elements from the home page.
So the next thing I'm going to do is use at home object.
And I am going to use a method from that home.
Page.
Object class.
So I'm going to write thoughts get.
Test store link.
So this test or link is referring to a method that belongs to the home page page object class.
And if we go down.
We'll find that method.
Which is listed here.
Get test or link and is return in.
Driver don't find element and it's providing a overpass in a field name, test or link if we scroll
up.
We will see that text or link is listed here and it contains the following locator.
So this locator is a locator for this link here.
So all we're saying in our test.
Is to use the home object and it's going to use the get test or link which gets a locator for that test
or link from the home page.
And we want to carry out an action against it.
So I'm going to use dots and I'm going to use the click function.
So what he simply says or what it means, it's the go to this home page.
Find this test for elements and then click it.
And it should then bring us to the test or home page.
So the next thing I need to do is use another page object and I'm going to use the shop home page class.
And I'm going to give the name object name of shop home equals new shop.
Home page.
And at the end of that line, a semicolon.
So again, I need to import shop home page.
Which is this page object class.
And again.
Equals new shop home page.
There's an error because again I need to provide the driver object because in shop home page and with
all our other page object classes, we have a constructor that is expecting a driver to be passed to
it.
So now that I've created the shop home object, I could then use methods from the shop home page class.
So if I go back to my browser, I want to click Products one.
So all I'm going to use is the shop home object.
And I'm going to use a method, some use dots, and then I'm going to call the method name, which is
get prod one.
Once I locate that product one, I then want to click it.
By doing so, I expect this product to be clicked and to be taken to the following page.
So hopefully you can see the concept that I'm following here.
I'm using the page objects to interact with each individual page, and I'm able to interact with those
elements by using methods that belongs to that page object class.
So I'm going to stop this lecture at this point and we'll continue building our test in the next lecture.