So this time, let's take a look at the concept of polymorphism.
So I'm going to copy and paste the class in the last lecture calling this L15 for lecture 15.
And give it in the name of Polly.
More polymorphism like so and click.
Okay.
Right.
So I am going to delete.
All this content from the last lecture and also clear out the main method like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do outside of the last race is create a new class, and I'm going to
call this class.
Animal.
And open and close embraces.
And inside this, I am going to have a very simple.
Method called public void.
Make sound.
And this is simply going to you system.
Dot out Prince Helen.
And inside those double quotes, it's going to make you sound like a sheep.
So outside of this class, I am going to create another class and it's going to be called doc and it's
going to extend.
The animal class.
In open and close embraces.
So this is going to have a method similar to animal called make sound.
And this time, sir, if I just copy this and paste it here.
This class as it's a dog is going to make a sound of woof.
And then below this, if I just copy this class and create another one.
And I'm going to change the class name to Cat.
Again, extends the animal class.
But the sound this class makes is meow like so.
So have free classes, an animal class, a dog class which extends animal and a cat that extends animal.
An all free have to make sound method for each implementation that makes a different sound based on
the animal type.
So in the main method, I am going to do the following.
So I am going to riot.
Animal.
Benji equals new.
Like so.
And then I going to use Benji.
And use the make sound method.
I'm then going to reuse Benji.
But this time I'm going to change it to equal a new instance of the dog class.
And then again on the news.
Benji does not make sound.
Then finally, I'm going to use Benji again, this time to equal a new cat instant.
And I'm going to use Benjy.
Don't make sound.
So let me first save this class and then let me just talk you through what I've done here.
So I've created a new object called Benji.
And this is an object which is based on an instance of the animal class.
I then used the Benji animal object to call the make sound method.
I then reassign the Benji object to be an instance of the dog class and then I use the dog object to
again make sound.
And now I do the same for Kat.
So I reassign it as a cat object, and then I'll call the Mike Sound method on the cat object.
So let me output let me run this class and see what the output is.
And you can see that free outputs have been placed by wolf meow.
So the key thing to remember here is that we have reassigned the object to be of a different type of
object based on another type of class.
So Benji was originally an animal object, but then I reassigned it to be a dog object and then called
the makes our method and the same for the cat.
But each time it did so every time are called make sound is outputs a value that corresponds to the
individual class itself.
So you got to remember here that polymorphism means many forms.
And it occurs when we have many classes that are related to each other by inheritance.
Polymorphism uses those methods to perform different tasks, and this allows us to perform a single
action in different ways.
So what we're doing here by using Benji don't make sound when Benji is a dog object is that we're calling
the makes our method in the animal class.
But it outputs a value.
So outputs worth which belongs to the dog class itself.
So the dog and cat classes had their own instance of Mike Sound.
But because we're using make sound here, the output or the value that's produced by the make it sound
animal class method corresponds the value corresponds to the individual classes themselves.
So the dog and the cat classes had their own implementations of make sound.
But when we called those objects.
We actually call in the method make sound that belongs to the animal class and the output is what corresponds
to those subclasses, dog and cat, because their own instance of make sound holds different values.
So this is polymorphism and like inheritance.
They are quite tricky subjects to cover.
But all I want you to take away from this lecture is to know that polymorphism means many forms, and
it occurs when we have many classes that are related to each other by inheritance.
The purpose of polymorphism is code reusability so we can reuse attributes and methods of an existing
class.
When you create a new class and that we have access to the animal class in this case because we use
the extends keyword.
So I hope that at least makes some sense and I'm not expecting you to understand is completely if this
concept is completely new to you.
But what I will say is that it is polymorphism like inheritance or key principles of object orientated
programming.
And in Java.
So we'll see more of this later on in this course.
But for now, I hope at least it's giving you a basic understanding of polymorphism.