So let's continue building this test.
So so far we've gone to the home page of the automation test and website and click the test or link.
On the test or home page.
We then selected product one, the next page.
The report two is this page here, and this is the shop product page.
And we have built a class which contains a locators and methods that would trade those locator values.
So on this page, I want to change a size to medium.
I want to increase increase the quantity to two.
And I want to add the items to my cart.
So I am going to create a new object using the shop product page.
I'm going to call the object shock product.
And it's going to simply equal a new shot product page in the brackets.
I'm going to pass the driver object and I'm going to add a semicolon at the end.
So I need to import this into this particular class.
On doing so, the error goes away.
So remember, the first element we want to interact with is a dropdown menu.
And if you remember back to earlier in the course, I taught you how we interact with these type of
elements.
We need to use the select clause.
And we do this by writing Select the Capital S.
And I'm going to call it option.
And it's going to equal new.
Select.
And in the brackets, we need to provide a locator.
So if a hover over, select an import it.
That ever goes away.
But there's still an error on his second part.
So what I'm going to do here is use this shop prod object.
And then I'm going to call a method to get that locator.
So if we look at it, we have an option to get size option.
And all that will do is it will retrieve the value of size option which contains this locator here.
So by doing that I can then use the option object and I can call it a number of different methods on
it.
So I am going to use a method of select by visible text.
And then by doing so inside the brackets and inside double quotes, I can simply pass the value to I
want to select, which is m for medium.
So that should select the sites.
So the next thing I need to do is increase the quantity.
So I want to buy two items to do this.
I'm going to use the shop prod object.
And I am going to add a dot.
Oops I spun out wrong.
So shop prod and if I add a dot I have access to a number of methods and I'm going to look for one called
get quant increase.
So this will find the increased quantity button.
And what I'd like to do as a user is click it, which will increase it from 1 to 2.
The next thing I'd like to do is add those items to my basket.
So again, I'm going to use the shop object dot to get.
And I am looking for add to cart button.
And again, I need to click this.
So I am going to demonstrate this test up to this point.
So before I do, just for demonstration purposes, I'm going to add afraid dot sleep to slow down the
tests so you can see what values have been selected and I'll delete this once I have run the test.
So I'm going to say this.
And I'm going to right click all the complete test and run it as a test in G test.
So let's see what happens.
And you can see that all the values that I wanted to select happened and added to and items to the basket.
So if I go back to the website, we can see that this is the next page we need to interact with.
So if I look at my page objects, we know that we have a page object we can use, which is shop content
panel.
And if we look at this is simply contains two locators and two methods to access those locators.
So in my mind test, I am going to create a new object on that shop content panel.
So I'm going to write Shop Content Panel.
And I'm going to call this see panel equals new shop content panel and I'm going to pass the driver
object.
And if I hover over an important that terror then goes away.
So I am going to make a little bit of room here so you can see what I'm doing.
So I need to simply select.
Proceed to check out.
So if I use that new object, see panel thoughts get used to.
I have got a method called get checkout button and all I need to do is click it.
By doing so.
This should then bring us to the fore page.
And so this is the shopping cart page.
So what I want to do here is select, have a promo code link which will then open a checkbox and a button.
I then want to pass a promo code of 20 off and then I want to select the add button which should deduct
20% from the total price.
Once that is done and then want to select the proceed to check out button.
So if I go back to clips and look at my page objects, see what one I can use.
So I have here.
Shopping cart dot java.
And if openness you see that as various selectors, I have methods to access these selectors.
So have promo code, for example, will select the promo code link.
So I am going to go back to my main test and I'm going to create a new object using shopping cart.
So I'm going to write shopping carts.
I'm going to give it a name of cart equals new shopping.
Can't.
And I'm going to pass the driver.
And again, only two important.
And those errors wouldn't go away.
So the first thing I need to do is select this, have a promo code link.
So I'm going to use the cart object along use dot get.
And I have a method here called get have promo.
And I'll need to click that link.
Amendments.
Use that cart object again.
And this time if a right gets.
I can see that I have a method to get promoted.
TextBox.
So this will get the locator for the textbox.
But as this is a textbox, I need to send the value.
So I'm going to use the send keys method and there is a promo code on the store that you can use to
20 off.
And that would deduct 20% off the price.
The next thing after entering that value is I need to click.
The ad promo button.
So I am going to use cards again.
Don't get.
And I have a method here of promo add button.
And I need to click this button.
So that should handle again ten of the promo code.
So the next thing I'd need to do is select.
Proceed to check out.
So again, using the cart.
Object don't get.
You see, I have a method of get proceed checkout button.
And all I need to do here.
Is cricket.
So I am going to add another friend dot sleep before I click that button just so you can see the test
run in.
So I am now going to save this again and try running it to see what happens.
So it looks like we have an issue here.
So if we go back to Eclipse.
And scroll up.
We can see that we've got an error.
If I scroll down to the bottom, actually, you'll see that there's one failure.
So if I scroll up, you'll see the details of this error.
So it says that, well, it seems to be implying something wrong with this.
Proceed to check out locator.
And it says at the top here, no such element.
Unable to locate element.
Method selector proceed to check out.
So this occurred on the shop content panel page.
So if I open up the shop content panel page object class, you'll see that it contains two locators.
So this is the one that the ERA is complaining about.
So this is good that this occurred because this happens regularly when we construct tests.
Very rarely do we get locators that work perfectly on the first time.
So I'm going to go to the shopping content panel page.
So if I go back one.
And can't.
So if I go back.
And.
Add another product.
This is the pages complaining about and unable to locate this.
Proceed to check out button.
So if I click it and inspect it.
And go to Ragnarok philosophy.
So this is the elements that I said we didn't need the question mark like them.
So it's possible that we do need this.
So I'm going to try copying that again and going back to Eclipse.
And pasted that value again in these shop content panel class.
So all you concede I've done is added that question mark like on.
So if I save this page object now.
And go back to my test.
Let me try running it again to see if we can proceed further.
And you can see that time it was selected.
So that confirms that the issue was to do with the locator.
And the good thing is using this page object is that by simply updating the locator in the shop content
panel page object class.
My taste didn't need to be amended.
And that's because we are using methods that belong to the shop content panel page object to retrieve
this locator.
So if we came across a similar issue where we had a number of different test classes and we find that
one of the locators had change, for example.
All it would would require us to do is find the page object class and simply update the locator.
And that change will be inherited by all of our test classes.
So this is the beauty of the page object model.
So our test seems to be working as expected now.
And if I go back.
And click proceed to check out.
If I delete this item added.
So we only have the two remaining.
So if I replicate AD in a promo code.
And then proceed to check out.
We then reach the following page.
So this is where we enter our personal information.
So I am going to stop this video here and we'll continue with developing this test in the next lecture.