In this lecture, we're going to construct our second test.
So let me walk you through what will be tested.
So we're going to go to the automation test and website, began to locate the test or linking click
it, which will take us to the store home page.
I want to click the first product, which is the Hummingbird Printed T-shirt.
I want to change the size to medium and I want to increase the quantity to two and then add it to the
cards.
Yes.
Wouldn't show you the summary page.
But this time I want to select the continue shopping button.
You still keep him?
Keep me on the product's page.
So I want to then click the home page link.
And when I'm taken back to the test or home page, I want to click the hummingbird printed sweater,
which is product to.
For this product.
I simply want to add it's a cart.
And then I want to proceed to checkout.
And this will take me to the shopping cart page.
So the main functionality I want to test here is deleting a product and ensuring the total amount reduces
to the products that remain in my cart.
So take a note at the total which currently reads 7396.
I then want to delete the sweater from my basket.
And notice how the total has reduced, which is the price of two T-shirts and the shipping fee.
So when I delete the sweater, I want to then check the total price to make sure it matches 4524, which
is the amount I'm expecting.
And I can do that using a assertion.
So this is going to be our test.
So I'm going to go to Eclipse and start writing this test in Eclipse.
Under the source test java folder.
I'm going to right click the automation test in package, select new and select class and I'm going
to give this class the name of at the move item basket test and then click finish.
The first thing we need to do is extend the base page.
This wouldn't allow me to import it.
And in the error would appear here.
And this is because we need to add the constructor that uses a super keyword.
We didn't need to add methods for these before test and after test annotations so we can simply open
up our class from last lecture, which is the order complete test.
And we could simply copy DS into our new class.
So next we need to start writing our test method.
So I am going to use the ATS test notation and I'm going to give this method the name of public void.
Add the new item.
So on needs need to import the test notation and that error would then go away.
So remember, our test, at least for the beginning, is very similar to the order.
Complete test.
So in this autocomplete test, we go into the automation tested website and we locate in the get a test
or link and we click on it.
On the shop home page.
We then get in product one and click on it and this will take us to the Shop Products page.
Then we going to select our options.
So we're going to set the size to medium.
We can to increase the quantity by one.
And then we're going to add those products to our cart.
Next, the shopping content panel page appears in this test.
What we did was we click the get check up button.
So the key difference in our new test is that we want to select the continue shopping button.
So up to this point, our tests are the same.
So I am going to copy.
From that point upwards like so.
And I'm going to paste it.
Into our new class.
So now I'm going to use this C panel object.
And if I select if I write thoughts and then write it, you'll see that I've got an option to get continue
shop in button so that will get the locator to the continue shop in button on the shop content panel
page.
So I am going to use that and I'm going to use a click command to click it.
On doing so.
This will take us back to this product's page.
So as I'm on the product's page, I need to reuse the shop product object as this object is for the
shop product page.
So I am going to copy this.
And my thoughts.
And so I'm going to find what I need to find is the home page link.
So this home page link is this link here.
And when I click it, it will take me back to the store homepage.
So I am going to write here.
Dot get home page link and I want to click it.
So as I'm on the shop home page, I need to reuse the shop home object.
So I am going to use this and then right gets.
But this time I want to get product too.
And that product too is this sweater product here?
When clicked, it would then take me to the sweater product page.
So on get product to I want to click product to.
And then what I need to do this time is use the shock product object again.
As that shop product object is for the products page.
So I don't want to click any options here.
I just want to simply add it to Cart.
So I'm going to write thoughts, get add to cart.
And then I want to click that button.
Once I have done that.
You'll see that the content page appears again.
But this time I want to click proceed to check out.
So I'm going to go back to the clips and I'm going to reuse the C panel object.
And I'm going to try to get and you can see I've got get check out button for which I would want to
click.
On doing so they should then take me to the basket shopping cart page like so.
So at this point, I'm going to save this class and I'm going to try running it to see if it works,
as we would expect.
So although that test executed really quickly, you should have seen the tests functioned as we expected.
He added The first item it continued shop in it went back to the store, homepage is selected the second
product and then it added the second product to the cards.
And then it took us to the basket page.
So we are now at this point here.
So what I'd like to do next is delete this second item, which is the sweater.
So to do this, I'm going to be using the shopping cart page object.
And if I double click and open it, you'll see that I've got two locators here which hard to delete.
So delete item one and delete item two.
So these correspond to these two delete icons here.
So we can add more to this page object.
If we wanted to test the deletion of more items.
So I'm going to go back to the add remove item basket test.
And because I haven't used it yet, I'm going to create a new object of the shopping cart page.
So I'm going to write a shopping cart and I'm going to call this cart equals new shopping cart and I'm
going to pass the driver object.
On, then need to import the shopping cart.
And then we can then use this object to interact with this page here.
So I want to select this delete item for the second product.
So I'm going to use cart dot to get the lead item to.
And I simply want to click it.
This should then delete the item.
Like so.
So the next thing I'd want to do is use or check this total price to make sure it matches $45.24.
So here I'm again.
Going to use a cart.
Object don't get.
And if we look down, you'll see I've got a method for get total amounts.
So this total amount is simply.
A locator that gets the text or the value of this particular element here so far as to right click this
and inspect it.
And Red Ragnarok philosophy.
You'll see that locator card.
Total value is here.
So I'm going to go back to my new class.
And we obviously get total amount method to get that element for the total.
If I write dots here, you'll see that I've got a number of other methods and the one I'd want to use
is this one called Get Text.
So this all it does is it gets the visible text for the element.
And now at the end of that line, I'm going to use a semicolon.
So what I'm going to do, just for demonstration purposes is that I'm going to use system dots out dot
prints and then.
To print out the value of that element in the console.
And then once I demonstrated this to you all, then include use it in an assertion.
So I'm going to save this class and I'm going to run this this class again.
So let's see what gets output into the console.
So if I scroll up.
You can see an amount here.
Butter equals 73, 96.
And what I was expecting was 45, 24.
So what do you think happened here?
So what happened is that this code to take the total amount executed before the deletion of the second
item had finished executing.
So how can we resolve this issue?
So what we can do is use a web driver white.
So after I've deleted item two, I'm going to use an explicit white.
So I'm going to write Web.
Driver.
Wait, and I'm going to call you object white.
Equals new web drive up white.
And I need to pass the driver object and duration, which I'm going to use 120 milliseconds.
So I need to import web driver weight from selenium.
And at the end of that line, I'm going to add a semicolon.
So now I am going to use that weight object.
And then I'm going to use the until method.
And inside these brackets I'm going to use expected.
Conditions.
Thoughts?
And then I have a number of conditions that I can use.
So I want to use a condition called invisibility of.
So what invisibility of Czechs is that?
It waits until this.
Whatever element I supply is invisible on the page.
So when I click the delete button for the second product, it would only continue, execute, execute
in the test.
Once the visibility of that product is no longer shown on this page.
So I'm going to use that invisibility of.
And then inside those inside those brackets, I'm simply going to pass the cards object.
Dot get delete item two and that get the item to is simply the method that locates the second delete
icon.
So now if I run this test again, let's see what happens.
And if I scroll up.
You'll see this time the expected amount has been placed in console.
So by using this web driver wait, it waited until the second item was deleted and was no longer visible
before it continued to check the next line of code.
Which is to get text.
So I'm going to leave this lecture at this point.
And in the next lecture, we're going to add an assertion to ensure that the amount is as we expect.
Thank you for watching.