So in this lecture we take a look at Java classes and objects in more detail.
Classes alongside objects at the heart of object orientated programming.
Think of a cross as a blueprint.
While an object is a real instance of that blueprint.
For example, we might have blueprints that describes the properties of a house.
And this is like a class.
We then might actually build houses based on the blueprint, and each one of these will be a new object.
The class might define the properties of the house.
For example, it will have windows and doors, but each object based on the class might set the number
of windows and doors.
So look at the class on the left.
This is a blueprints for basic house.
There are three fields.
Number of doors.
Number of windows.
A number of bedrooms.
There is a constructor to set the object that attributes.
There are no free methods which simply return the number of doors, windows and bedrooms.
So if we look at this diagram on the left hand side, we have a class called House.
I then create two objects house one and house two.
And if we look at the fields and properties of house one, you'll see that it has two doors, eight
windows and three bedrooms.
Where Object two has free doors, ten windows and four bedrooms.
So although these objects are instances of the class house, the objects themselves can have differing
properties and values.
So let's see an example of this.
So I thought it'd be a good opportunity for us to use a new idea just for this lecture.
And then it's up to you if you wish to use it going forward for some of the Java videos or for some
practice perhaps.
So in Google, I'm going to type bluejay.
And the first option you should be given is to bluejay or talk.
So if I click that link, you'll see that we've got options to download it.
But at the time of recording this video, version five is the latest version, and I do know that there
are a few bugs that are being worked on to be fixed.
So what I recommend to do is click on previous versions or source code and find version 4.22.
And here you have your install options.
So I'm using windows.
So I am going to use the Messiah installer and that will begin the download process.
So I'm going to pause the video here until that's done.
Sinatra has finished downloading.
I'm going to click the installer.
And then it should start the installation process.
So I'm just going to click next.
Next again.
Next.
Leave the default path as the as the value shown.
Click next and then click install.
And this will begin the installation.
So again, I'm just going to pause the video.
And then you should see the following screen that says the installation has completed.
So now I'm going to click Finish and I can close the browser.
So on my desktop, you should say on your desktop you should see a Blue J icon and if we double click
that, it should open up bluejay.
So you can see here there is a house class.
And the reason for this is I've already written this house class for you to save time, taking you through
me writing the code.
So if I double click on this class, you'll see the code that I have written.
So like I showed you in the slides, I've created free private fields of type integer for number of
windows, number of doors, a number of bedrooms.
I've created the constructor and provided free parameters, and it's parameters of windows, doors and
bedrooms.
And then when I create is class and, and set values for for this constructor, it will then place those
values into the fields.
Then below I have free simple methods and these are getter methods.
So it's returning.
Forget windows, the filled number of windows and the same for doors and bedrooms.
So I am going to close this now.
And what I'm going to do is if I right click and click new house, you'll see the constructor is telling
me to provide values.
So a number of windows I am going to write ten.
Number of doors on the right free, a number of bedrooms on the right four and then click.
Okay.
And you'll see on this bottom panel, this is an object panel.
So if I create another object, so for a second house, this one's going to have 12 windows.
It's going to have four doors.
And it's going to have six bedrooms.
And click.
Okay.
So these objects if we double click these.
You'll see that you'll be able to see the values of those fields now.
So the constructor has placed those values.
And is assigned those values to the fields of that particular object.
So if I double click this one as well, and we'd have these side by side.
I try.
Just minimize that.
So look at house one and then look at house two.
So by using the constructor, when I create the object and then assign values to those parameters of
the constructor, and that constructor will then create or it will it will assign the values up, avoid
to the fields of that particular object.
So I hope that's a good visual representation of how objects function.
So if we go back to Blue Jay, this is the class and these are the objects that we create, the object
instances of that class and each object, although they are familiar or a similar in terms of what fields
and what methods they have, the actual values themselves that we assign belong to three object.
So if you ever wanted to use this idea for practice, if you want to create your own class, all you
need to do is click this new class button.
Select the type of class that you want.
So we're mostly going to use class anyway.
And then you need to provide a name such as what should I call it?
Call.
For example, an organic.
Okay, you'll see a class, a car class is being created which if you double click.
You're provided with some default sample code.
You simply delete that.
Then you can write your code here.
Once you've written your code, if you click the compile button, that will then check to see if there's
any syntax errors.
If there isn't any syntax errors, you'll get a label saying no syntax error was found.
And then if you close that panel and right click that class, you'll be able to create an object instance
of it.
So this is a really cool idea.
And you and it used to be used when I was studying computer science at the time, and I'm sure it's
still used today, but it's really good to get a visual representation of how objects and classes interact
and how classes interact with other classes to.
So I hope you found this lecture useful.
And thank you for watching.