In this lecture, we take a look at Java arrays.
So what is an array?
An array is a collection.
Think of it as a basket which can hold a number of eggs, but instead of eggs it can hold strings or
ints or any other data type.
An array is easy to declare but is fixed in size based on what you set.
The below code is creating a string of right and assigning four string values.
The array has been called names.
And if we look at this code I've written string followed by followed by square brackets, which implies
I'm creating an array and I've called it names.
And nines equals new string with square brackets.
So it's creating a new string array.
And in braces, I am providing values that I want to store in this array called names.
So in the first table quotes, I provided the name Steve, followed by comma and double quotes.
Emma.
Comma, John.
Comma.
Amy.
So these four string values are going to be stored in this array of strings, and the array is called
names.
So an important thing to remember is that index is in Java starter index position zero.
So I expected Steve in the first value will be placed in an index position of zero in the names of right
followed by Emma, who would be in position one and so on.
So let's see an example.
So before we begin, you may notice that I've added a new class here from the last lecture.
So although we use Blue J I.D., I've also created the same class in Eclipse just so that we maintain
our lecture ordering in.
So if you if I show you this, it contains pretty much identical codes.
What we wrote in Blue Jay, but in Eclipse, we don't have the functionality to create a new object
in the way we did in Blue Jay.
Hence why in the static void main method of declared a new object and also printed out the values of
the fields.
So following on from that.
So for this lecture, let's create a new class called Lecture 17.
And I'm going to give it a name of.
Arise like so.
And then open up that class.
If I delete all the code from the previous lecture.
Just leaving the static void main method.
So what I'm going to do here is I am going to declare an array and I'm going to do so by writing string
and in square brackets and call it names equals new string.
Square brackets.
And then.
After that, I'm gonna add open and close embraces.
And in these braces, I'm going to provide string values.
So in double quotes, I'm going to add the name State.
And then after that double quote comma.
And another set double quotes for Emma.
And the same again for John.
And a final one for the name Amy.
And then a semicolon ended that line.
So now I am going to print the values of that array and I'm going to do this by the system.
Draw out, not print.
Out end.
And inside the brackets, I'm going to call the name of the race.
So names and in square brackets.
And I'm going to enter an index value of that array.
So I am going to simply copy and paste that.
Three more times.
But I'm going to change the index value for each one.
By incrementing it by one.
So I expect that this first line where it's using the names array, Ray, it's going to retrieve the
index value of zero.
And because Steve is the first value to provide it, I expect Steve to be in position zero.
Emma Position one.
John Position two and Amy in position free.
So if I save this class and then try running it.
Let's see what's output.
So you can see there, Steve, John and Amy has been placed in console.
So that's what correctly.
So the key thing to remember about an array is that an array is static in size, so the length is fixed
based on the object of the array that we create.
So if we wanted to add new values such as a additional value at the end of Amy after the object has
been created, we can't do that within our code, but we can use alternative collections such as an
array list, which is more dynamic, and it's something we're going to explore in the next lecture.
So the array is the most basic form of the collection in Java and there are a number of other differences
between other collections.
But that is the main reason is that the size cannot be changed once the object of the array has been
created.
So I hope this lecture has been a good introduction to race.
Let's move on to the next lecture.