So in this lecture, we're going to add an assertion to check the total amount to make sure it's the
value that we're expected.
So to use an assertion is very simple.
We just use the asset class and I'm going to use a method called assert equals.
But a very important point is to make sure that you select the method that belongs to testing and not
the one that belongs to G-Unit.
So if I double click this test in G one.
And if I scroll up and look at my imports, you'll see that the test energy asset class has been imported.
So that's how you know you selected the correct method.
So this method assert equals expects two values.
This is the actual value and this will be the expected value.
So the actual value is going to be the value of the tanks as retrieved from the locator.
So I'm going to simply just use the cart object where we get in the total amount and we get in the text
of that element.
So I'm going to copy that and paste that here.
In the second argument, we need to pass the amount that we're expected.
So we know on the website we're expecting 4524.
So in double quotes, I'm going to write dollar 45, got 24.
So I am now going to save this class.
And I'm going to try running it to see what happens.
And you can see that my test has passed.
And if I scroll up the amount that's been outputs, it's a console is 4524, which is expected amount.
So now if I change $0.24 to $0.23 and try to save it and run in this class again.
Let's see what happens.
A notice.
This time, a failure has been output.
And the reason for that is and if we scroll up to see what the error says, it says expected 4523,
but found 4524.
So the actual value which he got from the website, the web page is 4524.
But for the expected value, I wrote 4523 and because these two didn't match.
That's why the assertion submitted a failure.
So I'm going to change this back to 24.
So this is the end of this test.
And so what we've done in this test is that we've mimicked a user added items to a cart, and then on
the cart page delete in one of those items.
And we've also check to make sure the amount is the amount that we expecting after that deletion has
taken place.
So if you wanted to practice and write your own tests, I highly recommend it as it would be really
good practice for you.
But in the next lecture we look at the test, injects a small file to see how we can execute both our
tests at the same time.
Thanks for watching.