In this lecture, we're going to use a test engine small file to execute both our tests at the same
time.
So I am going to highlight the first class how to control my keyboard and then select the second one.
And then I'm going to right click, go to test energy and select convert to test energy.
And then go and click finish and this will generate the test injects and I'll follow in my project.
And then going to double click it because I need to make some amendments.
So I am going to copy the test tags and I'm going to sir below like so.
So in this first test, I only want to run one of the tests, which is the ad to remove ice and basket
test.
And in the second test, I'm going to remove the add remove item basket, leaving just the order complete.
So I need to change the names of the tests so they don't match.
So I'm just going to call this test to.
I'm then going to cite this and enclose it, and then I'm going to simply right click run as test in
G Suite and let's see what happens.
So the first test that's executed is the add remove item from basket test where we add and then delete
an item and then check the total price.
Once has finished.
The browser reopens for the next test and this is where we enter doing an end to end test until we purchase
an item.
So you can see that two tests have run and both of them have passed.
So that's how we can run both our tests using the test g xml file.
Thank you for watching.