In this lecture, we take a look at Java lists.
So what is an ArrayList?
And ArrayList is like an array.
Well, one of the key differences is that the ArrayList can be resized.
The ArrayList size will automatically expand if there isn't enough room when adding new elements into
the collection.
ArrayList can be found in the Java util package.
We add the values to an ArrayList using the dot add method.
We remove values from the ArrayList using the dot remove method.
We can retrieve a value from an ArrayList using the dot get method.
So let's see an example.
So in Eclipse, I'm just going to copy and paste the class in the last lecture.
Calling this new one L.A. teen for Lecture 18, and I'm going to give it a name of ArrayList like so.
Lincoln.
Open up that glass and remove the content in the main method.
To look like so.
So the first thing I'm going to do is type A, right?
List and in pointy he brackets the need to define the type of data that I'm going to store in this ArrayList.
So ArrayList with pointy brackets of string.
Then I need to provide a ArrayList name.
So I'm going to call this animals and scans equal new write list points brackets to define the type
again and in round brackets in a semicolon.
So if I hover over a list, you'll see I'm given an option to import it.
And on doing so.
The errors go away.
So the next thing I'm going to do is start adding strings to the animals array list.
And to do this first I need to use the name of the ArrayList.
And then when I pressed dots here, you'll see that I'm given access to a number of methods, and the
method I'm going to use is ADD.
And I'm going to provide a string value within these brackets.
So the first value I'm going to set is Cat.
Then I'm going to do the same for Second Valley.
And this second value is going to be dog.
And I'm going to add one more.
And this is going to be a stilted.
Like so.
So at this point I have created a new animal was an object which is of type ArrayList and the values
we are going to store in this ArrayList is strings.
I've then used animals.
I've called the ArrayList name Dot Add, so adds a method that belongs to ArrayList and by using ADD,
I can add values to the ArrayList.
So I've added free string values cat, dog and lizard to the animals array list.
So the next thing I need to do is print out the values.
So rather than using like an index value added last lecture, I'm going to get some practice use in
a for loop.
So I am going to write for an end in brackets.
I'm going to use int I equals zero.
Semicolon.
AI is less than animals thought science.
I plus plus and in open and close embraces at the end of that.
So that for loop as we've seen previously I've set an interval and and it's got a value of zero.
The condition, though, is to check to see if I.
So what the value of this i.
It's less than animals the size.
So Animals is the name of the ArrayList collection.
And this dot sized method checks to see how many values has had been added to the animals array list.
So I expect this to be free because we've added free values in sweat.
So it's a way that we can it's right through the values within ArrayList by using an approach like this.
Then we have a semicolon and then we have a simple line plus plus which will increment after each iteration
of the for loop.
So once I have done that, I am going to use system dots out dot prints and.
And inside this.
I am going to use.
Animals, which is the name of the ArrayList.
And then I'm going to use a method called get and you can see get takes a parameter of INT, which refers
to the index value.
So you can see.
Well, I'm using I already in this for loop.
I can simply pass that as the index.
So if you think about this on the first run, if I zero and I is less than animals, I get added to
plus one.
When this code executes this I value is going to change every time the four loop loops around.
So that's all I need to write now.
So I'm going to save this class and try running it and see what the output is.
And you can see Cat, Dog and lizard has been printed to console.
So that's worked.
So say I wanted to add another value now.
Say if I wanted the animal to add.
And I provide the value of horse.
If I save the class again and try running it.
You'll see that for Lupe.
Take care.
Takes care of the additional value.
And the reason for that is the size of the ArrayList has increased by me adding one.
So if I wanted to remove a value from the ArrayList.
I could do animals thought to remove.
And then it takes an index value.
So if I wanted to remove index value zero, for example.
Let's see what happens.
So if I say this.
And run it.
You'll see cat has been removed because Cat.
Is Index zero on creation.
Dog Phobia Index one lizard phobia index to horse will be index free and because removing index zero
value cat and gets taken away.
That's why only free values have been outputted.
So I hope this has been a good introduction into a real ES for you.
And the key point to remember is an ArrayList can expand as we need, whereas an array, once the array
object has been created, cannot be expanded.
Thank you for watching.