In this lecture, we take a look at Java lists.
So what is a list?
A list is a collection of elements in a sequence where each element is an object and elements are accessed
by the index position.
ArrayList implements the list interface, which also means ArrayList is a subtype of the list interface.
The primary difference between list and ArrayList is that list is an interface and the ArrayList is
a class.
So if we look at a diagram, the array list class actually implements the list interface in Java and
the list interface itself actually extends collection.
So let's look at the below code again.
So this code is pretty much similar to the one in the last lecture.
But a key difference here is is I've imported Java due to that list and where I had before ArrayList
string animals.
I've replaced it with the list interface.
So list string animals and it equals a new ArrayList string, which is valid because ArrayList is a
subclass of the list interface.
So why are less useful?
We can store web elements, objects in a list which which can be useful when we write Selenium code.
So if we look at the below code, I've actually created eight objects called Foo, which is a type list
and it's going to store web elements.
Then I use the driver, find the elements and the elements has an asset and meaning.
I may expect them more than one value and I'm use them by see, assess selector and provide in a class
of red icons.
So if there was a number of elements, say five elements with the eye, with the cross of red icons
on a web page, I would then expect the list object called FU to store a list of each one of those web
elements.
So let's go and see an example.
So in this demonstration, I am going to just show you how we can change ArrayList to list by using
the code from the previous lecture.
But later in the course I will show you how we should use the list interface to store various web elements
when we're dealing with more than one element that has a similar attribute, such as the same class.
So for now, all I'm going to do is copy and paste the class in the last lecture.
And rename this one.
L 19 for lecture 19 and I'm going to call it list.
I mean, going to double click and open it.
So here I abuse ArrayList.
So if I changes the list like so.
Onion have to import it and I'm going to select the Java util one.
And in doing so, if I now save this.
You'll see that this is a valid change.
And the code operates as we would expect and similar to what we did with the very list.
So this is just proven that we can use the list interface to equal ArrayList because ArrayList is a
subclass of the list interface.
So this lecture is fairly simple, but the important thing to remember is that will be used in lists
to store web elements later in this course.