In this lecture, we're going to learn how to take screenshots when one of our test failures.
I'm going to do this using listeners.
And earlier in the course I covered the eye test list, the interface.
So this is what we're going to use in our framework.
Under my resources package, I'm going to right click select new in select class and I'm going to give
this class a name of listeners like so.
So this class needs to extends the base page and it needs to implement.
The owner test listener interface.
If I hover over the base page, you'll see that I'm given an option to import it.
Before hovered over the eye test listener.
You'll see there isn't an exact match.
The reason for this is that this class can't find the test engine dependency.
And if I open up my -- file and find the test in g dependency, you'll see the scope has been defined.
So this was brought across when I copied this dependency over.
So we don't really need this scope dependency.
So I'm going to simply delete it.
And if I save this file.
And then go back to the listener's class.
You'll see that now I'm given the option to import it, meaning the class can now find testing.
So you can see there's an error on the underneath listeners.
And if I hover over this, you'll see that I need to add the constructor because we use in the base
page.
So the next thing that I'm going to do is use a method that belongs to the I test list, the interface.
If I hold down, control my keyboard and select my test listener, you'll see the number of methods
that we have available.
So I'm interested in this on test failure because when a test fails, this is when this method will
be triggered.
So I'm going to copy this and I'm going to paste it into my class like so.
But I'm going to change default to public.
So the next thing I'm going to do is use a try a catch statement like so.
So China is what's going to be tried first when this effort is called.
So I'm going to it here.
Take.
Snap shots, which is a method that belongs to the base page.
And in the brackets, I'm going to use this result.
Which is the test result of the test that cause the method.
So it makes sense in a moment once I show you so I'm going to use results.
Dots get and is a method to get the name.
You can see, though, once I've added a semicolon, that is an error here.
And it says Change Method Takes Snapshot Web Driver to string.
So if I open up my base page and look at a take snapshot method, I've actually made an error here.
So I've used web driver.
Web driver here.
Really, what I should be using is a string.
So I'm going to changes to string and I'm going to change.
Web driver to name.
And here I'm going to change Webb driver to driver like so.
Once done, there should be no errors.
So I'm going to save my base page.
And I'm going to go back to my listeners class and you'll see that that era has now gone away.
So because we call in take snapshot.
Which is this MiFID here.
It's now expected in a string to be passed.
And this is why I am using result.
They'll get name.
So result is quite simply the test.
Result of the test that's been executed.
So if a test failure was to occur, this test result will contain the test that's currently being processed.
I then use this result to get the name and that will get the name of the test.
The next thing that I'm going to do is once I've done that is I'm going to use a catch.
And in brackets, I'm going to use exception eight and in the open and close embrace and I'm going to
use a dot print stack trace.
So that's.
Is this list not completed?
So I'm going to save it.
And I'm going to close these classes.
So we need to do one more thing.
So for every class that uses the high test listener, we need to define its listener in each of those
test classes.
So if I open up and remove item basket test, we add this line after the imports.
And what you need to add is that listeners.
And then brackets.
And then this will be the location of where the follow is.
So it's in my resources folder.
And then I need to do a full stop.
And then listeners like so and at the end of that thought class.
So you'll see it as an error on the listeners.
And then I've got an option to import this from Test G.
So all I need to do now is save this class and I'm actually going to do the same and copy this line
in the order complete test so that this class also uses the list, this class.
And I'll say that also like so.
So we've done pretty much everything that we need to do is by adding this line, we're saying that we
want this class to use this list, this class.
So when this test is run in.
And if a failure was to occur, this on test failure method would be triggered.
And that particular test result will be stored in this parameter here.
We then trying to take a snapshot by using the method from the base page and we use in this result here
to get the name of the test, which is typically the name of the method.
So once this has been triggered, it will use this method from the base page.
And the Take Snapshot method simply takes a screenshot.
And it stores it in a destination phone location, which is going to be the screenshots folder here.
So what we need to do is we need to make sure one of our test fails.
So in this ad remove item basket.
You may remember that we use an assertion.
So remember, the test itself should find a value of $45.24.
But by changing this to 4523, it should result in the test failing.
And that's when the listener should trigger the test failure method.
So if I was to say this class.
And now try running it.
Let's see what happens.
So we can see in the console that a failure has been reported.
If I scroll up.
It says the expected amount doesn't match the actual amount.
So if we look at my screenshots folder, you'll see there's no files listed.
So what we need to do is right click the project and click refresh.
On doing so.
The PNG file has now appeared.
If I right click this and go to properties.
Name.
Copy.
Location.
Path.
And open up a browser and pace value.
You'll see the screenshot.
And notice where the screenshot was taken.
It was taken at the point of the test where the failure was identified.
So because in the test I change your assertion to search and look for 4523 because a match was not found
and 4524 was found instead.
It failed the test and this is when the screenshot is taken.
So that's his.
The test proven that screenshot has been taken.
Thanks to the listeners.
So I hope you have found this useful.
And thank you for watching.