In this lecture, we take a look at Java Fruits.
So Multi-Threaded is when two or more tasks execute concurrently within a single program.
A freight is an independent path of execution within a program.
Many friends can run at the same time.
And every Friday in Java is created and controlled by the Java Lang DOP Fred class.
So how to create a frat in Java?
There are two ways.
We can extend the fret class and override the run method, or we can implement the vulnerable interface.
So if you look at a diagram on the top example, I'm extending the friend class.
In the second example, I'm implementing the run table interface.
If the class extends to class.
The freight can be run by crates in an instance of the cross.
We didn't call the start method.
So in this example, I extend Fred.
I create a new object of this class I'm in.
Then I use Fred Dot's slate dot starts.
And then that starts the execution of the friends.
If the class implements the vulnerable interface, the thread can be run by a pass in an instance of
the class to a Fred's object constructor, then call in the Fred Start method.
So in this example, I implement the vulnerable interface.
I create a new object of the class.
I then use Fred Fred's object.
So it creates a new object of Fred.
And then I pass the object of the class I'm in as parameters to the Fred object.
I then use the friend object start method to start the execution.
Just because friends are starting in sequence, it doesn't mean they'll be executed sequentially.
Friends execute in parallel, not sequentially.
The order in is determined by the job, a virtual machine and or the operating system.
So in this particular example, I'm extending the thread class.
And I'm using a phone loop to run several times.
And I'm executing a friend each time for loop runs, which outputs a number which is determined by the
value of ion for loop.
Each time this execution runs, I will change to one, two, three, four, five, etc. and so I expect
the output to be placed in console.
But you'd think because a four loop runs in sequential order, so on a increments by one each time that
because the threads are executed in parallel, you can see the output is not actually in the order we
would expect.
So instead of 1 to 5, we have 012435.
So the execution of Fred for actually executing completed before Fred three.
So let's see an example.
So I'm actually going to demonstrate three different examples to you in this lecture.
So for the first example, I'm going to extend the class.
So I am going to create a copy and paste the class in the last lecture calling this one l.
21 i.
And I'm going to give it a name of Fred.
Extend.
And click.
Okay.
So I'm going to double click to open that class and I'm actually going to remove everything apart from
the void main method.
There you can see that there's a yellow line and icons here.
And this is because we're not actually using these classes.
So I am going to remove those like so and that will get rid of the error.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to create a new object based on this class.
So I'm going to copy the class name and paste it here, and I'm going to give the object the name of
Fred.
And it's going to equal a new instance of this class like so.
And then going to use that, Fred, that object called Fred.
And I'm going to call a method called Start.
I've made an error.
So the first thing I haven't done here is extends.
Fred.
So once I do that.
If I use a thought.
Now, you see, I've got a method called Start.
So then I'm going to use a simple system thought out.
Not print end.
And I am going to print here outside.
Of a friend.
We were semi-colon.
I'm then outside this this brace.
I am going to write to public void.
Run.
Open and close embraces.
They're not going to simply copy that system, outline and paste it within the method.
And I'm going to change outside to inside like so.
So to quickly explain what I've done here, I have created a new class which extends to Fred.
Fred Superclass.
Of them created a new object, which is an instance of this particular class I've created.
Then I use that object to code, the START method, and that start method belongs to the Fred class.
I then output a message sign outside of the friend.
Now because we extend in the friend class, we need to override the run method.
So that's why I've created a new method here called Public Void Run.
And what I've done here is outputs a message to console, say, an inside of a friend.
So what we need to do or what happens is that we are overriding a method that belongs to different class.
And this is what actually will execute use in friends to console.
So if I save this class.
And try running it.
You'll see them.
Both messages have appeared.
But it's actually the public void run which is used in the FRED functionality.
So this could be quite tricky.
So hopefully the next couple of examples will make it clearer.
So the next example is I'm going to show you how to implement the vulnerable interface.
So I'm going to close this class and I'm going to simply copy and paste it.
And I'm going to call this 121 P.
And it's going to be Fred implements.
I'm like, okay.
And then going to open up that class and I'm going to clear the console by pressing this button here
in Eclipse.
And instead of extends I'm going to change this to implements and instead of Fred.
I'm going to change that to run up all.
Now, the first thing that I need to change here is I'm going to get rid of this line for now.
So I am going to use Fred.
And I'm going to call this friend object equals.
New right.
And inside the brackets, I'm going to pass this object instance of the class so I'm in.
I'm then going to use that object thread object.
And if I do a dot here, I'd have access to the start method.
So that's all I need to write in this particular class.
So this is just an example of using the implements vulnerable interface.
So if I now save this class and try running it.
You'll see a similar result to the last class we demonstrate demonstrated.
So this is how we can use the implement run label interface.
So if I close this class now.
And I'm going to create a third class, so I'm going to copy and paste the one we just created.
And I'm going to call this new one L 21 C And instead of fried implements, I'm going to call this fried
ordering.
So.
So I am actually going to remove all the code.
Apart from the void main method and I'm going to change implements fundable to extends.
Fred like so.
So in the main method, I'm actually going to use a four loop, so I'm going to write four.
INT I equals zero.
Semicolon aia is less than six.
Semicolon I plus.
Plus.
Then open and close embraces.
So inside this loop, I'm going to write New Fried.
And inside brackets among the price of empty double quotes.
Plus, I like so.
And at the end of that line, instead of a semicolon, I'm going to add some new braces.
So inside of this, I'm going to create a new method called public void.
Run and then open and close embraces at the end of that line.
And inside this method, I'm going to use system.
Dot out the print lend.
And inside the brackets, I'm going to use double quotes.
Fred.
In a space outside of the last double quote.
Plus.
Get a name.
Plus double quotes add a spicier.
And ends up running a semicolon at the end.
So then if I go to not the first closing price, what about after the second closing price?
I'm gonna use dot starts.
Like so.
So to explain what I'm doing here in this class, I'm extending the friend superclass and in my method.
At the time this class executes, I'm using the for loop, which will run five times.
And each time the for loop runs, it creates a new fried object.
And then I override the run method.
And the run method will output a line or Fred to get name.
So get name gets the name of the friend instance and it says plus running then outside of the fried
braces.
I call the stop method, which is the method that starts the execution of the friends.
So I'm going to say this now and I'm going to try running it and let's see what happens.
So you can see in this example the phrase executed.
And it's run in order.
Zero one, two, three, four, five.
So let me try running it again.
And again, it's run in order.
But let me keep trying until it doesn't.
And you can see in this example that the order in output was not sequential.
So what that proves to us is that the friends are running in parallel, not sequentially.
Because if we look at our code, we use an A for loop.
So oil is only incrementing by one.
After each pass through the loop.
So where I equals one, for example, you would expect one to output and then you'd expect the loop
to run again.
Where I would equal to nine, you'd expect two to be output in order.
But because we use in friends, the execution happens in parallel.
So these are all executing at similar times.
That's why the ordering is not sequential, as you would expect.
So this is quite a tricky subject to explain, but I hope that from this lecture you've at least gained
a basic understanding of how friends operate.
The key thing to remember is that friends allows us to execute processes in parallel.
This is often used to speed up the execution of a program.
So I'd like to thank you once again for watching, and I shall speak to you in the next lecture.