Hello, I'm Fernando Medina Corey, and welcome to module two,
Up and Running with the Serverless Framework on AWS.
In this module,
we'll cover some of the installation steps for the serverless framework,
some differences you might see between operating systems,
and how to get set up with an AWS account if you haven't already.
Then we'll look at the serverless framework's application model,
where we will learn about functions, events,
resources, and services, and how they work within the serverless framework.
After that, we'll review some serverless development basics,
including required configuration, how to deploy our code,
and how we can think about testing it in the future.
Toward the end of the module, we'll deploy our first project,
a scheduled email reminder using AWS SES and Cloud Watch. So let's get started.