Hello, I'm Fernando Medina Corey,
and welcome to my course on the serverless framework.
In this module,
we'll be deploying a text notification website with a serverless HTTP API.
In this module, we'll learn about serverless plugins.
We'll start with an overview of the serverless plugin model
before taking a closer look at serverless-finch,
a plugin we'll be using to deploy static websites to AWS.
Then we'll learn about serverless APIs.
We'll overview all the components that make up a serverless API on AWS,
but we'll also take a closer look at one of the key components,
the AWS API Gateway.
Finally,
we'll take an in-depth look at some of the configuration
required to make these HTTP APIs function.
After that, we'll get ready to create our module project.
We'll get set up with Google Recaptcha and Twilio,
which we'll need for the project.
We'll scaffold out a service, review our function code,
configure our API endpoints, and finally,
we'll deploy the project to AWS.
So let's get started.
Let's take a look at how the functionality of the serverless
framework can be extended using plugins.
The serverless framework is merely a group of
plugins that are provided at the core.
These come together to create a set of functional commands for the terminal.
But what can plugins do for us?
Well, they can extend the utility of existing commands,
or when we want new functionality entirely,
we can create new plugins.
And each of these in turn give us more command-line options and functionality.
External plugins are added on a per service basis and
are not usually applied globally.
If you want to work with a plugin,
make sure you're in your services root directory,
and then install the corresponding plugin with the help of npm.
We can install plugins on a service specific basis with npm install.
If the purpose of the plugin is to augment the development process,
we probably want to save it as a dev dependency,
as shown here with the --save-dev flag.
The next step after installing the plugin is to set any
configuration that may be required for it to work.
At a minimum, this usually includes creating a section of our serverless.
yml file that specifies the plugin name,
and may also mean we need a custom section to specify specific
configuration details that the plug-in uses,
but we'll look at specific examples of this in a moment.
Let's take a look at serverless finch,
the serverless plugin we'll be using in this module to deploy
a static site frontend to our application.
The first thing we'll need are some pre-made static site files,
including HTML, CSS styles, and imagery.
To save us some work,
I'll be providing us with a template website that you'll be able to use.
With this,
we'll be able to start testing our site locally to make
sure it looks and works as expected.
Then we'll use the serverless finch plugin to move the static site
files to AWS S3 and set them up as a static website.
At that point, the website will be available to the internet at large,
and any users who'd like to see it will be able to access it.
We'll get into the details of using serverless finch more during the demo, but for now, let's take a look at serverless APIs.