In order for the website front-end to do anything meaningful,
we'll also need to create an API that the front-end can
interact with to send and receive data.
Let's take a quick look at how the serverless
framework allows us to accomplish this.
The serverless framework helps us create serverless APIs by managing all the
components that we might need in order to create them.
The first thing that a serverless API would need to
deal with is an incoming HTTP request.
In order to handle that within the AWS ecosystem,
the serverless framework uses the AWS API Gateway.
API Gateway handles all these incoming HTTP requests to its web endpoints,
and then passes them along to lambda functions.
Those functions can use managed resources ranging from backing
databases to identity management services,
or other logic to process those requests as needed by
the application and return a response.
Because API Gateway is a core part of the
serverless APIs that we're using on AWS,
let's take a quick look at what it is and how it works.
AWS describes the API Gateway as a service that enables developers to create,
publish, maintain, monitor, and secure APIs at any scale.
So why use the API Gateway when building your serverless applications?
Well, first,
the service makes it super easy to create REST APIs for
both web and mobile applications.
These APIs are fully managed by AWS,
making them easy to scale and removing a large amount of
the overhead required to secure them.
That's not to say security isn't something that you
have to consider when creating an API,
just that AWS takes care of some of those layers for you.
API Gateway also easily integrates with AWS lambda,
and the serverless framework seamlessly handles this integration for
you without having to dive into too many of the detailed
configuration steps that would otherwise be required while working
directly with the AWS services themselves.
Another nice thing about the API Gateway is that the
pricing is completely dependent on the usage.
One million API requests are included with your first
year of using AWS under the free tier, and as of August 2017,
you're only charged between $3.
50 and $4.
25 USD per million requests.
Keep in mind,
there is also a charge associated with the amount of data
that you transfer with the API Gateway,
which at low levels of use is usually between 9 and 14 cents per gigabyte.
Finally, if you'd like to cache information,
you can also pay roughly between $0.
02 and $0.
04 per gigabyte per hour across a selection of cache sizes.
Now let's take a closer look at what configuration
we'll need to use in our serverless.
yml file in order to get our serverless APIs functional In our serverless.
yml file, you'll need to specify functions as usual.
In this case, we have a serverless function create,
which has a lambda handler and a folder called pets.
The filename would be create.
js, and the function inside that would be called create.
If this seems a little abstract right now, don't worry too much.
We'll be taking a closer look at configuration just like
this during our demo for this module.
Now the way we set up our API is by specifying HTTP in the event section.
All we need to define there will be a path,
an HTTP method, and the cross origin resource sharing,
or cors, setting.
In this case, we'll enable this,
because we want to be able to use the API from other domains
other than the one that AWS creates it within.
This configuration would allow us to deploy an API
endpoint that accepts posted JSON and passes it along to
a lambda function for processing.
So what if we wanted to retrieve specific information from our API?
In that case, we might need to pass an ID value through the API,
so it can pass the ID to a lambda function,
and then run a lookup on the other end.
In these cases, a few things would change.
First, we'd need a new serverless function in the pets directory,
in this case, in a file get.
js, we'd use the function get.
We also modified the endpoint path from the previous example,
and add a required id parameter in curly brackets.
The API Gateway will pass this value along,
and we'll use the id value to look up the pet within the backing dataset.
We'll also need to make sure the HTTP method would change to get,
which is the expected method for retrieving data in a way that
would cause no change to the underlying service.
When your API requires additional access to external services,
you may also need to manage environment variables.
Within AWS, environment variables can be set once in the serverless.
yml file, and then referenced within the function code of a service.
Here's an example of how you'd make an access key value
accessible as an environment variable.
We'll also see how to load these values into our function code within the demo later in the module.