Now let's take a look at how we can install Node on Windows.
The easiest to do this is probably to Google for Node version 6.
10.
3.
On the Node page for this version,
there'll be a download link if you scroll down the page.
Depending on your operating system, you might need a different installer,
but we'll be using the 64-bit Windows Installer.
After the download is complete,
open up the Installer and go through the installation steps.
When the installation is complete,
you should be able to open PowerShell or the Command Prompt and enter in
node -v to see the version of Node you've installed.
If you want to confirm that Node is working,
simply type in Node and hit Enter,
and enter in some JavaScript code that will be print
something to the console like this.
You can exit out of Node by pressing Ctrl+C twice,
or following the instructions provided.
You can also check the version of npm that you've installed with Node.
If you've installed in npm successfully,
you should now be able to install the serverless framework.
You can do this with the npm install command.
Use npm install serverless -g.
This should install serverless globally,
then you can check the version of serverless that you
have installed with serverless -v.
You can also use the sls command,
which will substitute for any serverless commands that you enter in.
So in this case, you'd use sls -v.
Now let's move onto installing the AWS command-line on Windows.
There are a few ways to install this.
I'd suggest looking up the AWS documentation for
installing the command-line on Windows.
The easiest way to install the AWS command-line on Windows is
probably to use the provided MSI Installer.
However,
if you'd like to be able to update the command-line more easily more frequently,
then I'd suggest looking into how to install it with PIP,
as this will be able to install and upgrade the
command-line package more frequently.
After you've installed the AWS command-line,
you can check the version with aws --version.
Once you've confirmed that it's installed,
you should use the aws configure command and enter in the
credentials that you got from the earlier steps.
As always, if you need additional clarification on this,
you're welcome to look at the installation steps in my earlier course, An Introduction to AWS Lambda.