Now if we go back to the terminal,
let's take a look at how we can install the dependencies for this project.
First,
just double-check that you have the correct version of npm and Node running.
You can use npm --version to see the version of npm.
You can also use node --version to see the correct version of Node.
You should be seeing Node version 6.
10.
3 and npm version 3.
While it is possible that you'll be able to install the
dependencies correctly using a different version,
I'd suggest using these just to keep our system
requirements as identical as possible.
As with any npm package,
you'll be able to install your dependencies using npm install.
This will reference the information in the package.
json file.
This should install our dependencies fairly quickly,
as the only dependency we're really using is the UUID dependency that we
looked at earlier when reviewing our function code.
Now you're ready to deploy your application.
So go ahead and use sls deploy.
You could also use serverless deploy.
When this is completed,
you should see a variety of endpoints that have been created by the framework.
You should also see that these functions were created
in accordance with the endpoints.
Go ahead and copy down the API URL,
because we'll be using that to test the API in a moment.
Now let's take a quick look at the AWS console.
I just want to show you that our DynamoDB table is created as expected.
Now let's scroll down slightly and go to the DynamoDB section of the console.
Then we'll click on the tables tab.
When we load up the tables portion in the DynamoDB console,
we should see our table name.
If we scroll to the right,
we'll see the total read and write capacity of that table.
In a UNIX environment, you can test your API using curl.
You can use -X to specify that you want to test it with a POST request.
Then you'll paste your specific API URL.
Next,
you'll add in the --data flag and then use the single
quote and add JSON that looks like this,
and another single quote in order to specify the data that
you'll be passing along to the API endpoint.
After you hit Enter, you should see a response that looks something like this.
This means that your data was posted successfully,
but let's go ahead and check on that in the AWS console.
In the AWS console,
you should be able to navigate to the table that you created previously.
After doing that, go ahead and take a look at the Items tab.
On the Items tab,
you should see that you've just added an item successfully to the table.
If this wasn't successful,
I'd suggest double-checking the format of the data that you're passing in,
and also making sure that you have the correct API URL from the
results of the serverless deploy command.
You can always run serverless deploy again, and then copy down those API values.
You can also use Postman in any environment in order to test your API.
You can get Postman from getpostman.
com, and use it on any mainstream operating system.
The first thing you'll need to do will be to change the GET dropdown to POST.
Then you'll paste in the specific API endpoint that you were using
with the curl command into the section here.
After that,
you'll go to the headers section and specify a content type of application/json.
Then you'll go to the body section, select the raw button,
and make sure that you pick application/json from the dropdown menu.
Now we'll enter in the JSON without the single quotes,
and in doing this,
we'll be able to add another entry to our database by pressing the Send button.
If we scroll down slightly, we'll also see the results from the API.
This should also indicate that we successfully wrote our data to DynamoDB.
But let's go ahead and open up the console one more time in that Items tab,
and also take a look after refreshing the page.
As you can see, we've successfully written a second entry to our database.
Now let's take a look at the next portion of our module,
in which we'll be looking at how we can test and debug our CRUD applications in AWS.