It's really important to have concrete demonstrations of what
you've learned after finishing a course.
You can use these to showcase your knowledge to current or future employers,
or just generally be proud with what you've built.
So let's take a look at some of the serverless framework projects
that you'll have built by the end of this course.
In our Up and Running module, we'll be building out an email reminder system.
The reminders will be triggered by scheduled events.
These events will activate our lambda handler function.
When the function is triggered by a Cron event,
it will create the email and send it at that specific time.
When the function is triggered by a rate event,
which runs in regular intervals, but at a specific time,
it will create and then send another email.
To send emails, we'll be using AWS's simple email service,
which we'll cover in the module.
In the next module,
we'll be creating a website for The Woof Garden to
send and receive text notifications.
This will involve deploying a static website on AWS that includes a
submission form and a Google recaptcha validation.
The website will submit form content through our serverless HTTP API,
and have that content processed by the handler function.
That function will first check the Google recaptcha API to
make sure that the recaptcha is valid.
If it isn't valid,
the function will return and serve us an error back to the website.
If it is valid,
it will process the remaining form content and use a stored
environment variable to make a call to the Twilio SMS API.
This will then send a text message to the cell number specified on the website.
In the module after that,
we'll be creating our own serverless API to manage
CRUD operations for a PET database.
There will be multiple lambda functions in order to
manage the creation of new entries,
reading specific entries and listing all entries out,
updating existing entries, and deleting old entries.
All of these operations will integrate with a DynamoDB service
resource to store and manage the data persistence.
So let's take a quick look at what we've done in this module.
We now know more about the serverless landscape,
and how the serverless framework fits within it.
We also know how infrastructure as a service infrastructures
interact and relate with the framework.
And we're hopefully excited to build our new projects
and skills throughout the course.
In the next module,
we'll be getting set up with the serverless framework on our machines,
and we'll write and deploy our first serverless project. See you soon.