Now let's get started on installing our dependencies on Ubuntu.
The first thing you'll do is use Bash to run the Ubuntu install -bash script.
That should set you up with nvm, the Node Version Manager, on Ubuntu.
Once you're done with the install script,
you'll close that terminal and open a new one.
Now we can use nvm to install the version of Node that we want,
using nvm install 6.
10.
3.
Then you can check the Node version with node -v.
You can also check the npm version with npm -v.
When you see the version shown here, go ahead and continue.
Now we can install the serverless framework with npm install
serverless -g to install the serverless framework globally.
When the process completes,
you can check the version of the serverless framework
that you have with serverless -v.
You can also use the sls command to substitute for the words serverless
and any of the commands you use with the framework.
Try it now with sls -v.
Now let's install the AWS CLI.
The easiest way to do this is to check first if you
have PIP installed on Ubuntu.
You can do this with pip --version.
It should come with most installations of Ubuntu.
If you do have it, you can use pip install --upgrade --user awscli,
and this should install the most recent version of the AWS CLI for you.
After it's installed,
you should use aws configure to set up the AWS access keys and AWS secret keys that you got in the earlier part of this module.