Now that you're all set up with the serverless framework and your AWS account,
let's get started learning the serverless application model.
Every serverless framework application has the same components.
They have functions,
which execute code in response to specific events that trigger them.
Now these events can be anything ranging from an HTTP request,
a scheduled event, or a specific infrastructure provider event,
like an AWS S3 file upload.
Serverless framework applications also frequently use resources.
Resources are other infrastructure components that your application depends on.
An example of a resource in the AWS infrastructure could
be something like a DynamoDB table, or an AWS simple storage service bucket.
In order to keep all of these moving parts straight,
the serverless framework has a concept of services.
And these services encapsulate your functions,
events, and resources,
so that you can logically separate them from other services.
While it's more than likely that within one full-blown
serverless application you'll have many services,
this really helps to organize everything that you're doing.
So let's take a look at some of these concepts in a little more detail.
Now when we say serverless functions,
we mean something specific depending on the infrastructure
provider the framework is interacting with.
We could use offerings like IBM's Open Whisk,
Google Cloud Functions, or Microsoft's Azure Functions.
But in this course, we'll be relying exclusively on AWS Lambda,
the serverless function equivalent of the other service providers.
What events you can use in your applications also
depends on the platform that you're using.
In AWS, you can trigger functions with events from the AWS API Gateway,
scheduled events like Cron,
from file uploads or changes that happen in AWS S3 buckets,
from CloudWatch logs in AWS,
and from updates of things like DynamoDB tables or even from
IOT devices and things like Alexa Skills.
The most commonly used serverless resources are
things like we mentioned already, like DynamoDB as a serverless database,
and S3 as a file storage service.
However,
you can also have any other AWS resource that can be
described in a cloud formation template.
Now this can be anything ranging from CloudFront Distribution
networks to speed up delivery of files to your users,
or an Amazon Cognito User Pool to manage the users of mobile applications.
And the serverless framework documentation describes a service like a project.
It's where you define your AWS Lambda Functions,
the events that trigger them, and any AWS infrastructure resources they require,
all in a file called serverless.
yml.
Services all share a similar set of characteristics.
All of them have the same logical structure to organize your entire code base.
Services also have a single configuration file that shares the
same structure inside of that configuration file.
Services that require REST APIs also all share the same
endpoint URLs for those endpoints.
And finally, each service shares the same resources amongst its functions.
So we've kind of hinted at this,
but let's look at what's actually in each of these services.
Also services contain a serverless.
yml file, which is the main configuration file,
and defines all the configuration for our service.
They also contain all the function code that will be
triggered in response to events,
as well as any of the dependencies that the code may require.
But let's take a look at an example to see this in a little more detail.
In a simple Node.
js service, we might see two files, serverless.
yml for the service configuration, and handler.
js, which actually contains the function code.
In a medium-sized application with multiple services,
we would see several directories for each service.
Now each of those services will have serverless.
yml configuration files, and in this example,
The Woof Garden pet service interacts with the pets database,
and that database would be a resource required for this purpose.
This service would also have all functions used to
perform CRUD operations within the handler.
js file.
Keep in mind that function code being in a file called
handler is purely by convention,
and this is convention that we'll be breaking later when you
split up CRUD operations into multiple files.
All dependencies for this function live within the node_modules folder.
There's also the package.
json file used to specify the node dependencies required for the service.
Another service in this application used for reminder notifications
would have a completely independent serverless.
yml file, different function code in handler.
js and more than likely different dependencies.
Now let's take a closer look at each of these application components.
The serverless.
yml file contains all your configuration for the service written in.
yml.
Now.
yml is fairly easy to learn,
but for the most part we'll just be modifying existing examples.
So don't worry too much about this.
The first set of things configured by serverless.
yml is the service itself.
It defines a name for the service,
determines which provider and runtime this service will be using,
and specifies files or directories that explicitly should or
shouldn't be included when packaging the function code.
It also defines any resources required by the service.
In this example, we see it defining an imaginary users table,
defining the structure of the table,
and determining the level of read and write capacity
that we should provide the table with.
Critically, serverless.
yml also defines all the functions within the service,
the events that will trigger them,
and any configuration required for the functions themselves.
Each serverless function in AWS' Node environment has an event,
a context, and a callback.
The event object contains data passed into the
function from whatever event triggers it.
Most often,
functions will process the event object and determine
how to act from that information.
The context object contains a variety of information about the function,
such as the function's name, the function memory limit,
and the log group name for the function.
It also provides a method to get the remaining time left for
the function before timeout would occur.
And finally,
the callback is used to pass back information to the function caller.
Many serverless functions make use of dependencies
to enhance their functionality.
These dependencies can be anything from snippets of
custom code included in the same folder,
to full-blown npm packages.
These npm packages can also be serverless framework plugins that enhance
and extend the functionality of the framework itself.
Okay, we've covered a lot of concepts,
so let's quickly visualize everything before we start
developing our own serverless services.
First,
let's think about a service responsible for CRUD operations on some database.
Now, every service is a shared configuration file,
so we'll imagine this as the structure of our service.
And in this case, we'd have several functions,
each one to manage different CRUD operations.
We might also require specific libraries to work properly with the database.
In order to trigger these functions,
we'll likely need to have some sort of web form to create new entries.
These forms would send events through the AWS API
gateway and serve as our events.
And finally,
we might have a database resource to store all this information for our service.
In another example where we're creating a reminder service,
we'd have the same structure for our configuration and our service,
but we might only have one function.
Now, the function might use fewer libraries,
and have a different set of events on a schedule
rather than associated with an API.
Finally,
it might store email reminder templates in a
different kind of resource entirely, such as AWS S3.
So you'll start to see that while the types of
applications can differ substantially,
you'll generally have the same structure and
underlying concepts behind everything.
So,
now that we've got a strong understanding of the
concept used by the serverless framework, let's take a look at how we can develop our applications.