Okay,
so now we know what software packages are and how to use them in our repository.
Let's figure out what are upstream repositories. CodeArtifact can have
something called upstream repositories, such as npm.
These can be external repositories such as npm, or
internal ones such as your own.
You can have multiple upstream repositories which contain multiple types of
software packages and assets, and they can be shared throughout your own
domain. CodeArtifact will pull these packages into your own domain to manage
itself, and will never push any of your private packages to external
upstream repositories. And, just like with our own software packages, when
using upstream repository,
you cannot recreate an external software package with the
same name, as this will throw an error,
which is a good thing and stops duplication.
You can set upstream repositories in a dashboard or by using the CLI.
Okay,
so now we have a basic understanding of AWS CodeArtifact upstream repositories,
let's take a look at how to set one up. In this demo, we're going to cover the
following components in a little bit more detail.
We're going to take a look at adding an upstream repository to our
repository, and then we're going to have a look at installing a
package from an upstream repository.
Okay, so in our final demo, let's have a play with some upstream repositories.
So here I am in our globomantics‑repo. I'm going to hit Edit, and then I'm
going to select an upstream repository. I'm going to use the npm‑store, and
then I'm going to update the repository to then use this one as an upstream
one. Cool, that was successful, so let's jump back over to our Bash window,
and then in this Bash window we're going to install the very simple code
package called alphabet.
So we'll install alphabet, and now what's going to happen is npm is
going to install through our repository using upstream public npm
repos, this software package called alphabet, and it's then going to
store it inside of our repo too.
So let's do that now.
There we go, alphabet was installed.
Okay,
so let's jump over to our editor now, and we'll see that our alphabet
module, our alphabet software package has installed. Awesome, so let's
take a look at that in the dashboard.
If we refresh our repo, we should now see an alphabet package alongside our
custom globomantics‑package. And now in here we will see that's also
installed our alphabet package ready for us to use.
So there we go, there's an example of using an upstream repository and
installing an external package through the upstream repo.
Pretty cool, huh?
Okay, let's have a quick recap.
We just covered software packages and assets, how to add them,
list them, delete them,
update their versions, and then we took a look at upstream
repositories and how to use them with our own repositories.
Whoa, that wasn't so bad, was it?
Now you're well on your way to be experts on AWS
CodeArtifact, but before you go,
let's take a look at where to go next and have a look at some inspiration.
So, what's next, and where can you go from here?
I would suggest looking to automate as much as possible of your
software engineering lifecycle, and to start to really implement and
include as much DevOps methodologies as possible.
There are a couple of other AWS services that tie into CodeArtifact really well,
such as CodeBuild and CodePipeline.
Why not try to use CodeArtifact in one of your CodeBuild
builds? Werner Vogel's is the CTO of AWS.
He has driven and pointed AWS in innovative directions and
made sure they're ahead of the market curve.
As you can see from this quote, he says,
security is everyone's job now, not just the security teams.
All developers have to be security engineers.
He believes that to reduce risk to your services,
we should all be security conscious, and one benefit of using AWS CodeArtifact
is that it allows you to add software packages to your repository that have bean
audited and vetted for use within your software.
Well, that's it. All finished, I promise.
Why not head over to the Discussion tab to see how everyone else got on,
or maybe try the test I put together on what you learned today.
Anyway, it's been an absolute blast, and if you're on Twitter,
why not give me a follow and send me a Tweet?
I always love to hear feedback from my viewers. My name's @JoshuaGEdwards.