Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to discuss the print operation and how to get data from the user using the Input comment.
All right.
These kind of you know two concepts they are very kind of important because that's how you get to you
know like develop a python code that can interact with a user.
They can actually print something to the user and get data as well from the user.
Okay which is pretty interesting.
Now we can actually take you know kind of you add code to the next level and do like greaney Fun stuff
with it.
Okay so now we are at two a.
Which is in the concept section and we are covering the print operation and how to get user data as
well.
Right.
Let's take a look.
So let's assume that we wanted for example to print let's say you know like a welcome message to to
a user.
What I could do is say okay X equals two whatever value then you open your open double quotes and then
you say okay let's say welcome to python on.
Great.
Right.
So you have done here that you find available and you put basically these kind of characters within
that very case if you're on that.
And if you actually go here and say X what's x that will tell you Okay that's actually x contains Welcome
to my course.
If I wanted to get the type actually of X right you didn't cover that yet but are going to been covering
the future if I show that it would show you its actually string.
S T R stands for string.
So now we know that there is an integer which is you know kind of if you put let's say X equals 10 we
know that there is float.
If you put let's say X equals let's say 10.5 For example when there is a fraction an element or here.
If I wanted to show shortest string value which is kind of a series of characters you get Again the
objective of this.
Basically section is not to convert the strings because we're going to have a separate section completely.
Just converting strings and all the same methods.
But here I wanted to simply show you how can we print beida on the screen.
So to print data on the screen we're going to use to confuse the print case we're going to do print
open parentheses and then you get a list X..
Which means of asking Python to actually plot or print whatever the value of x to the screen.
If I did that then you would find that the actual text you'd welcome to Python course without the double
quotes.
This is very important actually just containing what's in between here.
We're going to be printed to history Alright.
Okay great.
That's pretty much how can we print data just print up a bracket and just print whatever you get.
So the next consider that I wanted to basically introduce some of the format method.
OK let's assume that one or two yes print data on the screen.
Let's see.
Welcome to python of course.
But I want it little say to specify a name.
I wanted to say welcome.
Let's say Mitch for example to python of course or welcome let's say Ryan to a python course the welcome
whatever whoever he is.
Okay how can we do that.
How can we kind of you know this kind of break of that trained and insert data in between.
In order to do that we're going to use the format method simply to do this.
Let's take a look.
Let's assume that it wanted to print for example a welcome message based on a specific name.
Okay so going to say a meme I'm going to put let's say whatever name you can insert your name forwards
in Peter's is going to insert Mitch for example.
So he's going to define a very record name and put Mitch into it.
Right let's run it and let's view what's inside anning for it.
It tells me actually there is much inside me.
OK sounds good.
Now I want it to print a welcome message too much to do that I'm going to make it print.
Open brackets apprentice's and then I'm going to do here.
I'm going to say Okay double quotes as it were done before and write your welcome message we're going
to say welcome and I don't need to put something because no need to put the name I'm going to show you.
How can we do that.
Welcome something key to this let's say python on course.
OK.
The whole idea here is I wanted to print something in order to do that.
Python has what we call it format format method.
OK what you could do here is that you can put kirrily brackets.
OK so if you put these brackets.
OK.
It's kind of a way that telling python that okay you print whatever message.
Welcome to this python course here.
Cake and whatever.
Here in this county bracket just put something in there and then appestat along just kind of separately
using a different method.
It's all quality format method.
OK OK it looks strange but once I tried it it would show very well.
Sure that's actually pretty simple to do here.
Going to the god dot format.
Okay so after the Colts see Dot format.
They're going to open parenthesis again.
I'm going to pass along whatever name that I wanted to list here.
So this basically what I'm saying telling Python to do is escape welcome within the brackets just pass
along the mean whatever values just come here and put it here in these two really brackets and they
continue along and say Okay to this by some quotes and that's it.
OK let's run it.
And you would say that's actually that's exactly or expecting.
Welcome mecham this thing course if I go here and say let's change it to let's say Ryan for example
and that did on that and there will say this.
You're welcome Brian to this python course.
Perfect.
What's even interesting is that you can actually use the fortinet method to print numbers as well so
I can say Okay welcome for example.
You know like or say for instance my name is Ryan for example and I am let's say 20 years all of 25
years or whatever.
Let's see how can we do that.
So what we could do here I mean to say okay print cake or print printing these and what we could do
is say okay double quotes and say Write whatever you want.
My name is an open croner brackets because they need to list here's something I'm going to show it again
after the format Okay.
And I am whatever the result.
Okay.
So now I know they're going to print are going to do something here.
Right.
And then a spatz Along something here.
So I'm going to use a format method to actually do this with this.
Dot format right.
I'm going to open parentheses.
I'm going to pass along.
I need two pairs in Maine and they want to pass an age as well.
So I'm going to pass a name or eight N bracket comma.
I'm going to say person on the H but it then in the the agent.
So what I could do to go here create in you again press a and cell and define an age let's say 23 for
example.
And let's say again to go back and change the name make it let's say Mitch back again.
And that's it.
That's pretty much it.
So you can see here he can pass along an integer printed in print as well as string if you want to.
Let's take a look let's run this first name.
So now I have named Mitch right here that would print just welcomed me to this course.
Now I wanted to print a different one you're going to say age 23 and I say print.
My name is whatever and I am whatever it is old that's from that.
And that's it.
That's pretty much what we're expecting.
My name is it's a mess.
And I am 23 years old which is great.
Now you can pass along whatever you can she make it 25.
Run it through it.
Then you see that becomes 25 years old cake again the format message we're going to be using it extensively.
It's actually very very powerful.
I'm going to use it throughout the course to print you know mix of strings mix of numbers mix of floats
mix of whatever stuff we wanted to print.
Perfect.
Let's take one last example before we conclude the print.
Let's assume that you wanted to print the value of pi.
A few of us are familiar with the value of pi which is three you three points one fourth of that we
use generally when we can give you three for example of a circle.
OK.
Which there is actually there's a date it's called Pi Day.
It's what we could do here going to say okay I want it to print let's say print open parentheses.
Okay I'm going to say okay the value the value of pi is an open curly brackets.
And here you're going to see a dot after the article because in a dot format or brackets I'm going to
pass along the value of pi which is that's a three point one for you.
Based on whatever you want k for and that's they tell me the value by is 1 4.
Perfect.
That's exactly what I was expecting.
All right.
And again let's go ahead and refresh again.
Now we know how can we define a string.
How can we go here and print an actual string.
OK.
Sorry Hugh can pressure print the value chain here and we know how can we use the format method to pass
along a name with the string.
How can we print imane along with the age for example using again the curly brackets and the format
method.
And again another example of to plot the pipe and alright.
That's pretty much all what a half with the section.
I hope you enjoyed it and in the next section we're going to cover how to get data from the user or
a and see you guys in the next letter.