Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's get started.
And let's keep solving our questions for four and why loop.
OK.
I hope you guys were able to figure out maybe one or two of these questions or hopefully all of them.
I hope.
All right let's get started.
So you know I'm asking you to tell me what do you expect here this code to generate.
OK.
So here we have a list which is my phone equals to iPhone BlackBerry Samsung and Google.
And I'm setting an integer.
You know what counter to zero.
And I'm asking would kill while as long as the counter I which is zero less than lengths of my phone's
OK which is simply going to before.
Right.
And say OK every time I get my phone.
Of index.
So we're going to be phone of zero.
We're going to be basically iPhone.
Right.
And that will be in the phone and basically increment the counter.
Which is fine.
That's not a problem.
Thinking I'm asking if phone which is you know might be iPhone might be BlackBerry might be Samsung
as we go through the wire loop every time right.
I'm okay if iPhone was equal to Samsung I'm getting what I'm going to do here.
Yes.
OK.
Continue.
Which means when I say continue that means I'm basically going to I'm going to keep going as long as
I haven't met the Samsung or the not all the Samsung value here.
OK.
So simply put what I'm going to do here.
Let's say if I run it's going to say OK so here I've got the iPhone and then I've got the BlackBerry.
OK.
Because every time I'm gonna go hear music if the phone equals Samsung.
No.
So if it's not equal Samsung beats are going to skip this and they're going to print.
Right.
So that's why I print iPhone and then go ahead for the for why loop.
Take BlackBerry.
Right.
Go ahead.
Here check is BlackBerry equal to Samsung.
No.
So basically in a skip the continue.
Right.
And then that's why I printed BlackBerry.
Go up again to Samsung.
I mean I say okay is Samsung equal to Samsung.
Yes.
So here I'm going to execute basically my command here continue.
And that would simply going to ask me to continue.
So again to skip basically the the the Samsung portion and that's why I didn't pin the Samsung here.
So we skipped basically the print and then we'll go up again.
Right.
We took the Google and then we check is Google equal to Samsung.
No.
So we skip the continue and we print the Google in here.
All right.
So basically I just wanted to hear to check if the were the Samsung or just gonna skip it.
That's pretty much it.
All right.
OK.
For question 2 I'm asking you to write a code that display all numbers from 1 to 20 using while and
for loops.
All right.
OK.
So can we do that let's first start with the full four.
Let's start with the flu first.
Let's say OK for I am going to say range because remember the range from 1 till 20.
Right.
Because here if you guys remember I just wanted to print one too.
Let's say 19 that I want to print kind of you know like I like excluding number 20.
Obviously you guys can increase that and make it 21 so you can actually print the value of 20.
Right.
And then you're gonna say Okay print get a print I okay.
That's it.
So let's run it.
And that's what we've got here.
If you don't actually print from one till 20 just make that 21.
Let's run it.
And then here you get the numbers from 1 to 20.
All right.
OK.
Next question is using why loop.
So I'm asking you to using while.
So I'm gonna say OK I'm gonna ask you OK.
While as long as it's just an index whatever index that is so.
Which means I have to initialize the index here to zero first.
Right.
I say okay as long as my index eye is less than twenty first.
Okay let's see what's going to happen.
Let's go ahead and print i.
Let's run that and actually it has been printing zeros all the time right.
Because why.
Because within it accumulate the counters.
Right.
So obviously here I need to activate the counter basically here it's stuck in a loop right.
So going to say OK Colonel interrupt that would enter the kernel and please make sure to actually include
the counter.
Right.
So going to say okay I equals to I plus 1.
That's a way of doing it.
Another way of saying what could I plus equal one which is the exact same way of actually incrementing
the counter when I say Okay while I will I less than 20 PRINT I equals two I plus one.
All right.
Okay.
Actually let's hear.
Let's set that to 1 because we don't we actually want to go ahead and print from 1 starting from 1.
You know we don't want to print to be on number from 1 to 20 not from 0 to 20.
Right.
Let's run that.
If we run it yet and come up with 1 to 19 if you wanted to make it 1 2 20 just make this.
Sorry.
Making this twenty one.
Let's run it and you'll come up with numbers from 1 to 20.
All right.
Question number three here I'm asking you to write a code that basically
generate the following table.
I wanted to generate numbers 1 1 1 2 4 8 3 9 27 and so on so forth.
Let's see how can we do this.
So what we could do we going to say okay for x in range and I wanted to print apparently numbers here
from 1 till 10 first right.
Ignore what I'm gonna do for the next column and the third column.
It seems like here I need a for loop right.
Change from one till 10.
That's what I know.
Okay I need from one to 11.
If you guys remember range I don't exclude the last Elementary.
That's why I included two print.
Actually Number 10 I need to put here eleven right.
OK.
We're going to say print and I can simply print.
Here again we can use the format method.
So here I need one here.
Right.
And then again another curly bracket.
Again another curly bracket just to print the number.
It's square and it's cube as well right.
So keep dot format because remember.
And then it can pass along the value of x.
I can pass along X times X right.
I can pass along X times X times X right.
Which is basically the person on the number Square and it's cube looks good.
Obviously we have just one little modification going to do Let's print it out first.
Let's see what's going to happen.
Let's run it.
And that's what we have got here.
We have got you know all the numbers 1 1 1 2 4 8 3 9 27.
Looks great right.
All right.
What we could do as well is maybe we can organize it a little bit.
Let's go ahead and maybe copy this.
And that's actually part of the solution lecture.
You guys we know the notebook.
What are the other solutions are here I added you know like kind of
elements here just to indicate how many decimal points I wanted to print.
So here I want to say Okay I need to print let's say 0 OK 2 D.
So I'm saying okay I need to print zero decimals okay.
And I'm printing.
I wanted to print right here.
I wanted to print two decimal points.
Okay let's go ahead and make it okay.
I need to print.
He had three decimal points.
And here I wanted to print let's say four decimal points 2 and 4.
Let's see what's going to happen here.
Let's run it.
And that's what I've got here.
It's way more organized way more you know kind of like don't like much much prettier.
All right.
That's all we have for this lecture.
Again we in this actually we went through the solution for the first three questions and in the next
lecture we're gonna keep going and continue solving all the questions.
I hope you guys enjoy the lecture and see you in the next lecture.