Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
When I walk you through the questions that we have for strings.
Okay.
And please guys go ahead and try to.
You know I tend to solve the questions again if you get stuck.
No problem.
Just you know going to have like a detailed video lectures that show pretty much how can we create the
entire solutions for these exercise of questions moving forward.
OK.
So the first question I'm asking you what went wrong.
Okay so here are a couple of code.
Couple of lines I am asking you what went wrong.
Fix the issue and indicate what does this code do.
OK.
So simply here you would find that you know like meme has upper case your name has a lower case.
So try to figure out you know what's basically what's that what's wrong.
What went wrong and try to fix it and run the court case the next step here is that I wanted to perform
simple subtraction.
So I wanted to just subject X minus Y and something goes wrong.
I find X you know and then define Y and I talk to subtract the two.
And something went wrong.
Try to fix it as well.
Try to let me know.
What should I do to actually perform the subtraction.
I want to see your value of 16.
I want to see 20 minus four.
How can white lines really add year.
What should I convert.
For example from one form or another to actually perform this operation.
All right.
And then Question 3 I'm asking you to write a call that takes an input from a user splits it into words
and print them on the screen.
So take whatever How is your day going.
For example the user get into whatever and then you get n30.
Here are the list of words you entered the and then you get a list or the Whereas the user have to get
a question for.
I'm asking you to write a code.
It takes an input from the user converting an upper case and print them on the screen.
OK.
Again I'm going to use the upper method that we've covered before in class and then I'm going to see
how can we do that.
Again you know by kind of interacting with the user by feeding data to the image as an input and prudent
that data on the screen.
Question 5 I'm asking.
I called the prompts a user requesting his or her email and then extract the user name simply so we
have first lady named Locke last name and Gina come.
I'm asking you to simply prompt the users to input their email into the e-mail they were going to extract
the user name from it again using the split method.
It's kind of you know like we use it through email address the user get into that and we're going to
be getting is the same need to extend this.
That's it OK.
And then I'm asking you questions 6 to expand on the previous code to print hello and then print first
name space last names I want to get rid of.
And they wanted to print you know hello first name and then last name afterwards.
Okay.
Kind of like this.
You can enter the email around up at for example at.
But that's not my email.
That's not my email though.
It just alright whatever names and they were going to say hello and then and a specify a rhyme and then
afterwards are in question 7.
I'm asking you to write a code that requests the first name last name and age and print them on the
screen.
OK.
And when you print them I want you as well to kind of you know print in addition f why I like Chalo
you're name is whatever you are whatever a years old and an ad for example.
Age is just a number you are younger than ever.
Again this is a very simple example.
The object of this example is actually tied to the question number eight which is I want you to do the
exact same stuff exact same you know Ryan and you know age 23 whatever.
And then I want you to print the f why I.
Age is just a number in a new line.
OK.
Which is stuff that we didn't covered before during the actual lecture.
How can you want to retouch what we call a or backslash and I want to thicker.
Likely soulish.
Take a look at what that mean and even go to this link and read.
I'm going to open it because if I open it that means I can explain it for you.
The idea is I wanted to go ahead to somebody to understand what being in my flesh and actually implemented
here because they were going to be very helpful for you to actually develop.
All I can do all these search and look for whatever data afterwards that's not presented here in class.
OK again I'm going to describe what they mean by flesh and the whole idea is they wanted to just do
these exim stuff as we have done before but print.
Why are you know.
Age is just a number in a new line using the backslash end here.
OK that we have done before.
My question I am asking you to write a code that takes the use of email and counts the number of user
name characters.
Again we did uncover how to do that.
But again I want you to research the length okay which is kind of a function that you can apply.
That would give you basically the number of characters within the string k..
And then at number 10 I want to write a code that extracts the word hello from hello world in two different
ways.
So I wanted to you do what we call listing slicing which is kind of exacting you know the hello from
Hello world.
Again you can do your research here.
You can go to that link and just learn more about what they mean by this.
Simply put any two ways of sticking in the words.
Hello from Austin.
It's called Hello World.
OK.
That's pretty much all I want to have.
I hope you guys will be able to figure it out.
Well a couple of at least couple of the questions.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the solution.