Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to repeat pretty much the what we have done before which is simply trying to get the data
make prediction in the future and try to plot the data as well and see what's the trend of the price
of the avocado over the lifetime over like twenty nineteen for instance.
But what we're going to do here which is you know we even more exciting here we looked at the data previously
for the entire U.S. market.
So we use the data for the overall data.
Right.
OK.
So what we could do here.
What we're going to do here we're going to select a specific region.
OK.
We're gonna select specific region.
So just kind of a subset of data.
You guys remember let's go up and let's review the data.
So if you remember that's actually plotted here again.
You know what you're going to say OK let's view the data.
So we're going to go ahead actually and repeat the entire exercise kind of review for the previous one.
So going to say I'm a hit I'm just gonna copy paste as much as I can because we have done that discuss
that before.
So again here we going to see as we figure out what is going to be the entire.
Again we can go ahead here and view the data.
That's my beautiful data.
We have the dates and I have the average price because remember and here have the reason right.
So what I need to do here I need to plug the data and actually apply my profit predictions for a specific
reason I'm not gonna do it for the overall you know like data that we have.
OK.
So what we're going to do here we're going to take a subset of the data.
OK we're going to take specific section of the data and create another data frame.
So going to say OK I'm gonna get go to Africa to underscore data frame on the score sample and we're
gonna go ahead and get I've got to underscore the data frame and here we're just gonna get specific
elements was just just the data points that are related to let's say specific region let's say West
to the U.S. whatever.
Okay let's go to avocado underscored data frame and what I'm going to do here I'm going to pick region
when the region equals equals to West All right.
It's one that's K looks good.
Let's take a look at the sample.
Let's run it and that's our data here.
Let's go back to the region.
You'll find that all of the region here is West which is exactly what I'm looking for.
All right.
Perfect.
OK let's go ahead and sort by date.
It's exactly the same as we've done before right.
So going to think of avocado on this quarter frame on this core sample right equals two again to underscore
their frame and this core sample but we're going to sort of they're going to see sort underscore values
by date.
Right.
OK.
So that looks good.
Let's take a look at the data sample now.
And here we go.
So if you take a look here you will find that simply you went in and an ascending order kind of thing
the data starting from January of 2015 going up you know eleven twelve of January as well.
And then February and so on.
So it looks like the data looks good.
If we scroll down the most up to date data was actually 25 25th of March of 2013 which is pretty pretty
good decent.
All right.
So what we could do next.
Let's go ahead and actually view the data.
Let's take a look at the you know like the trend in prices for a specific region only.
All right let's do put BLT the plots and I'm going to do I'm going to say OK avocado underscore data
frame on the score sample of date.
Right
OK.
And I'm going to plot the exact same thing as well.
So I've got to underscore that a frame on this core sample and here I will get a pass along the average
price all right.
Looks good.
But some that
and here we go.
That's the trend.
So again was hovering around like let's say one dollar going up one point seventy five going up and
down and went up to let's say 250 which is crazy.
People went crazy about avocados actually like you know even even myself like you know like it just
everyone was eating it.
The avocado toast across men like among millennials and stuff.
So maybe that's what's happening here.
And then it goes you know popularity maybe went down a little bit.
You know when they realized the price actually pretty high.
All right.
And let's actually change as well the size or BLT dot figure and we'll take a fig size equals to Let's
make it 10 and 10
right beautiful.
That's our graph as well.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and again do the training if you guys remember.
Again I'm going to go against you all the time.
See this again.
First let's let's actually stop here for that specific lecture and in the next lecture is to have an
intellectually dedicated for training.
We're going to go ahead.
We're going to rename the columns.
We are going to do the predictions.
OK.
I hope you guys enjoy that lecture and see you in the next lecture.