Hello everyone and welcome to this new section in this lecture.
I'm going to walk you through a completely different completely new concept so call it functions OK
functions is actually very very important when it comes to any programming language and merely python
in particular because it enables us to do and kind of
because it enables us to simply run the code in a very very efficient way.
All right.
So let's take a look at what you mean by function first and let's see how can we define a function.
Let's it's how can we actually call that function.
So let's take a look at the definition first.
Zoom in a little bit.
So a function is a block of code that can run whenever it's called by the main function for example.
So think of a function as just just a couple of lines of code that have been separated.
All right.
Just think of them as maybe two or three lines of code that let's say some two numbers to each other
and they are put on the side.
And every time you wanted to call that function you just call it by its name.
So you go ahead execute this couple of lines and then go back to the main actual main code without having
to kind of repeat the exact same code several times.
All right.
I know it might be a little bit confusing.
Let's take a quick example and let's see how can we do that.
Let's assume that I wanted for example to let's say print for instance hello world.
Let's say three times OK.
So what I could do is I could do a for loop or K or like a while loop.
OK.
But I'm not going to go there.
I'm going to do it in a function format.
So I got to say OK I'm going to define a function.
So I going to say def and let's say again I call it my function.
All right and I'm going to say print let's say hello world hello world all right.
So what happened here.
So simply put what I've done here is to define the function.
OK.
And they call this function my function.
All right.
So in order to define a function you have to use def space.
And then I lost my function here.
Right.
And if this function takes any parameters I actually list the parameters any in here the arguments taken
in here in these parentheses.
All right.
If I leave it empty that mean that function will not going to take anything.
OK.
And then what does this function do.
This function simply does print Hello World.
All right looks good.
So if I run it you'll find that something nothing happened.
We didn't print anything.
OK.
Why.
Because I haven't called that function yet.
What.
By calling the function.
Now I wanted to call the function so I can OK my underscore function.
That's it.
That's what we.
That's basically the function calls.
If I do shift enter would get hello world which means you simply when you do my function that means
you're calling the function you are saying OK let's leave that lines of the code go up here to the function
and execute the body of the function.
And that's why we're getting print Hello World.
So if I do it again.
I don't need to do and go ahead and do print Hello World again.
I can maybe just do this copy and paste.
So you really just you know change for example the call of the function for instance.
OK.
All right.
Let's take a look.
This obviously is a very simple example you don't know what kind of realize the power of the functions.
Let's assume that I wanted to let's say define a function that function takes a number and square that
number.
All right.
So how can we say when you do that then that.
Well let's see how can
all right.
So let's assume that I wanted to define a function and that function takes a number and simply return
the square of that number.
Let's say can we do that.
So we're going to say OK define so again I'm defining function you can call the function wherever he'd
call the squared.
And that function will take an argument x.
Ok.
And the function would return.
So I have to write the return the function would return x square.
All right shift enter.
Here we go.
Now I define the function.
Nothing happened.
Why.
Because I didn't call the function yet.
So let's see how can we call the function to call the function.
I'm gonna say okay please call it with its name to call the function.
I'm gonna call it with exact same name squared of black activists who do this and instead of X. Let's
say in gonna past let's say number three for instance.
So shift enter shift enter.
Here we go.
Now I basically obtain the square number of three and 49.
So let's say if I do four shift enter and become sixteen.
And so on so forth.
And that's pretty much how we define a function what we send to the function is are called arguments.
These are arguments these are variable that I send to the function and these are kind of the returns.
That's what we get back out of that function.
All right.
OK.
You can actually put that in for example let's say
output for instance.
So if you do that then output will have the actual value came back from the function the return of the
function which is 16 in this case.
All right.
OK.
I'll get what I want you guys to do.
Please go ahead pause the video and I want you to define a function and that function simply takes a
number OK and multiplied by ten.
All right.
So I want to please go ahead pause a video.
Define a function call it whatever call it multiply for example and maybe test that function let's say
with three core values let's say 10 20 and 30 again.
The objective of the function is to take a number and multiplied by 10.
Pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge all right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge will ask us to do is to simply define a function
and that function is what we call it let's say multiply
and that function takes a value X and what it does it simply return x times 10 which is what it asked
us to do.
Right.
So it's some it simply takes a number.
Ed the the value time stench of entry we go and let's test it.
So to test it with exabytes names we're gonna say multiply and we're going to pass along let's say number
three for instance ship entry we go we come back three let's say return let's say nine or come back
with 90 let's say 10 and you come back with 100 that means the function works like a charm.
Perfect.
OK.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to again define a function and that function takes specific you know like
like parameter but I need to set a kind of a default value within my function.
What do you mean by this.
Let's take a look.
So I can define a function.
This function is call I can call it my function.
This function takes an age.
Let's say we define it as an age.
OK.
And what the function does is simply print and it print simply something like this.
I am let's say whatever age.
Years old.
OK.
And said Dot format you as a member and here are going to pass along my agent here.
Shift entry we go.
Looks good.
And what I'm going to do I'm going to say my function my function and I can pass along maybe like 30
years or entry we go and say I am 30 years old.
All right.
Okay looks great.
Maybe I tested with let's say 60 seconds.
Okay.
I am 60 years old it's on.
OK.
So what's new here.
I haven't said anything new so what I wanted to do here is I wanted to show you guys how can we set
a default value.
So if I say for example age equals to let's say 20.
That means that age is the default value which means if I call that function.
So if I come here and they say my function and I didn't pass any parameter in here.
All right.
The functional will still work.
What is the function is as normal but it will set the default value.
So let's run it.
And here we go.
I'm getting I am 20 years old which means that if you set within the parameter here that's a specific
number.
And you didn't send anything from the mean then you were going to go ahead and set the default.
However if I call the function and let's say put 30 here.
This will override right that means you sent arguments you sent parameters here.
When you call the function then that would overcome the default if you don't send anything.
We're just gonna use the default.
That's all what it is.
All right okay let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to for instance duplicate what the default parameters.
OK so I wanted to let's say define a function that function takes a summation so or perform the summation
to the functions called summation and the function takes X equals X and let's say Y Okay.
And the function returns x plus y entering go looks good.
And what I wanted to do is I want to call that function summation and that function simply sums the
two numbers and let's say 3 and 8 shift enter you come up with 11.
Okay so what I want you guys to do is to please go ahead pause the video adjust this function somehow
so it can return a default value of 100 at all times.
OK.
So please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge will ask us to do is to simply define a set of default
parameters or default values here.
So I ask has to do is defined summation here and instead of sending parameters c or eight if you don't
send anything.
So if you said let's see summation and you leave it leave it empty.
Okay I need to set default parameters here.
So what I'm going to do when I said let's say set for example one hundred and let's say Y equals to
zero which means at all times the return parameter will gonna be value of 100 let's run it let's run
it.
Same answer run it.
And here we go.
We'll come back with a default parameter of hundred.
Why.
Because I didn't send any arguments from the function.
So the default values will prevail.
So hundred plus zero is one hundred and that would be the failure to value return back to the mean.
All right.
OK.
Let's take a look at other example.
Let's assume that I want it for example to define That's a greeting function in that greeting function
doesn't take one parameter actually she takes two parameters let's say happy new year for example Mitch
I wish you let's say happiness something like that.
The second to do that Mizuki define greetings underscore function and the function takes let's say the
name and take takes Li let's say the greetings.
All right.
And the function what it does just print like Happy New Year and it's a pass along the name.
I wish you for example happiness for instance I'm going to say dot format and we're gonna pass along
here the name and pass along our greetings enter.
Looks good so what is the call.
So now I'm going to call the function.
I'm going to come here to copy this without the column.
So now I call the function reading function.
Now I can pass whatever name I want so I'm going to say OK I'm going to pass along let's say.
Ryan for example and the greetings are going to pass along.
I wish you let's say happiness something of this shift enter shift enter here we go.
Happy New Year Ryan wish you happiness and so on so forth.
All right.
OK.
So what I want you guys to do is to please go ahead pause a video and please maybe wish for example
you know your loved ones just pick whatever name and wish them any I wish like like let's say health
wealth whatever.
All right go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
So ask us to do is to simply go ahead call the function so greetings function and pass along whatever
name.
So for example Layla for instance I'm going to pass along let's say whatever heat wealth shift entry
we go happy.
Layla wish you well.
It's again pretty much the same.
We just changed the arguments that I sent over here to the art to the function.
All right.
OK let's take a look at one more example.
Let's assume that I wanted to define a function and that function simply returns.
Let's say the radius of a circle.
OK.
And maybe return let's say the area of a circle as well.
We can have a lot more examples when it comes to the exercise section.
Here it is just a quick kind of you know like warming up example.
So I'm going to take a fine and I'm gonna call it circle and here the circle takes simply the radius
are all right.
And the function simply returns what I wanted to do.
I want to return actually to parameters I wanted to return the the that the diameter first.
So then there would be two times are and I wanted as well to return the area which is pi R squared.
So I'm gonna say OK I wanted to return three point 1 4 times r squared.
OK.
You can actually do that here in this format.
So I'm gonna turn three point one four times the R times times to all right.
Okay looks good.
Enter.
Here we go.
And let's go ahead here and maybe test it's going to say circle.
I'm gonna pass along let's say 2.
Here we go.
Now I came up with simply the the diameter which is 4.
And then I'm gonna come up with the area which is pi R squared of the circle.
All right.
Okay.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Let's recap all of them so far.
This in this section we're able to learn what how what are what functions are what do they do.
Now we know how to define a function how to send arguments to the function get something out of the
function we're able to set as well default parameters.
If we don't send anything from the main what's going to happen here we know that now we know as well
how can we let's say it's and two arguments like strings and print them out and you're able as well
to maybe return more than one parameter using the return parentheses and that should conclude our lecture.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.