Hello everyone and welcome to this election.
Let's keep going.
Let's continue with the solutions.
So the question number five all we have here is a wanted to remove the name Peter from my list.
OK.
Using two different methods again and give you a hint to use the Remove method and to use a delete listicle
look.
So what we could do then say OK I need to apply my list.
Got to use the Remove method remove and then it can list whatever.
Name one or two more from my list.
So if I say okay I need to remove Peter.
Okay that should do it.
So if I were on my list if I allowed it and if I wanted to let's say.
Print him of this one so give print my list.
And if I run it you'll find that basically named Peter had has been removed from my list.
That's the first method which is not bad.
Let's take a look at another way or another method of actually deleting an element within the lists.
You can do that.
Let's create a couple of lists here a couple of lines you're going to say okay I need to delete say
Dell.
I'm going to specify my underscored list.
OK.
And what I could do here.
I'm going to specify the index of the element then I wanted to delete.
Again this is indexed zero in the first one.
Index 2 which is basically what I'm looking for.
So if I list here too.
If I out of this cell and run this so and then specify again print.
Oh my apologies.
So Agnes Okay print.
My list and if I read it then you'll find that you're able to believe that in Peter from your list which
is exactly what I was looking for.
All right.
Perfect.
I hope that wasn't too hard.
The next question that we have that one or two sort elements in a list and an even worse one elements
to go for maximum to a minimum.
So you need a couple of numbers.
And what I'm asking you to do is to sort my list again here I'm giving you a hand signal say okay on
my list and I'm going to say.
Dot sourced which is applying my method on it.
That's all sorted.
That's it.
If I actually take a look at my list here you'll find that the AB been sorted for you know I mean in
ascending order from 10 15 20 and so on and so forth which is great for to versus It's going to say
okay I'm going to do all my lists which are the new one dot reverse kit for it and that's and if I come
here and show my list again.
And I know that you'll find it actually went from the maximum to minimum which is 50 45 40 and going
in in descending order.
Great.
The next question that we have is we have here kind of a grocery list couple of you know like nested
lists several nested lists actually to get in.
So to have chips you know jelly chocolate sweet potatoes potatoes peanuts and protein bar.
What I'm asking you to do is I'm asking you to create a new list that contained the last elements only
in the enlisted list.
So I want to create a separate list.
OK.
That might be a little bit of challenging.
Okay.
But I wanted to not just the grocery list actually want to go and create a new list which is let's call
it new list for example what I am going to initialise it's kind of empty.
Just get in here a.
And then I start to append different elements to it.
OK.
One step at a time.
So I'm going to say OK I need to go to my new list right I'm going to say OK if you as a member got
append to a then new elements.
Open.
All right prentice's I'm going say Okay.
Go to my list here which is grocery list grocery.
Underscored list.
Right.
And then open.
I need to get the last elements right so I need to get it again here in this element.
And this list which is has index of zero right.
I need to get the last element so to do that I need to go.
Kim neston nestled in negative in the sink because a member at minus one.
That means Okay.
Go to the first.
The zeyda Indicates the first element within the largest mine the swan indicate the last element in
the first list which is great.
That's exactly what I was looking for to do that again.
I'm going to say okay copy paste.
I want to do it actually several times but I want to change it and then say okay when one.
And here in two.
That's basically what I was looking for.
All right.
If I don't get this from the socialists first and then around this and let's take a look at my in your
list.
Perfect.
You came up with chocolates which the less elegant potatoes and then protein which is exactly what I
was looking for.
Again this is a very basic you know kind of way of doing it.
What we do moving forward when we cover the fallen troops and why lose it then instead of writing this
code line you know a couple of times we actually manage just to run a loop that repeated let's say thousands
of times or hundreds of times whatever we wanted which is going to be very handy very powerful.
When we covered it for loops and looks great.
The last question that we have here now wanted to be asking you to list for example the name five of
your closest friends and saw them in an ad for medical audit.
Let's take a look.
And I created a name this ticket quality whatever you want.
He was just going to list whatever names.
Okay Amanda for example.
Common Mistake need let's say whatever she or Ryan for instance and then say we need to define let's
say Joe I need to list for example schnall and let's say I'm going to have another name let's say Peter.
OK.
And on that that's a list of names I wanted to sort of them in and for medical order actually pretty
interestingly you can do the exact same sort of than four number so you can do it as well here for ching's
as well.
So then say okay go to name dot sort.
Right.
An open prentice's here.
And if you're on it and if you take a look at name on it you'll come up with this which is basically
a for from and then Chanel and Joe Peter and then ran off the which was street.
That's exactly what I was looking for.
Right.
That's pretty much what I have for this lecture again.
Now you guys should be familiar with this.
How did it work.
You guys should be proud of yourself.
Keep it up.
Why getting closer to amassing them.
I because it with the lecture and see you in the next lecture.