Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
In the biggest lecture we've been able to learn how function works and we've been able as well to cover
lambda expressions.
Let's take a look at kind of an operation.
It's called Map which is really really powerful.
OK.
So let's take a look at the definition first.
And let's take a look at the example right away.
So the map function takes in a function and list the function simply performs an operation on the Empire
list and returns the results in a new list.
OK.
What you mean by this.
Let's take a look.
So what we could do I say OK let's define a function let's say take two two numbers.
Let's say they are A and B and the function returns the summation can return a plus b enter.
We go and let's assume that A and B are actually not just values.
I wanted to do the that operation on an entire list.
So I would say okay a equals two for example 1 4 5 6 and 9.
And you define another let's say list and you put in that list 1 7 9 twelve and let's say seven enter
we go and what I want you guys to simplify what we wanted to do here is to simply go ahead and perform
that operation simply call that function for F each of these elements within my list.
I need to do one plus one and then four plus seven and five plus nine.
What we could do here we can use the map operation to do that for us.
So what I could do here is okay map.
Right.
And here I need to specify the name of the function.
So going to say summation which is the name of my function and they need to pass along what the argument.
So I'm sending to lists.
I'm saying the first list a second list B and what I would do here afterwards was a little bit confusing
I know.
But let's we're going to cast whatever return is going to come out of that map going to put it in a
form of lists.
And that should be let's say my value of c which is my return of my math function but at least on it
and I'm going to show you exactly what it is.
Shift enter shift enter.
Let's take a look at C and here we go.
We'll come up with two which is one plus one two four plus 711 five plus nine 14 and so on.
What happened here.
So what happened here is we simply used the map operation.
OK.
Or map function to simply take a longer function and not value not a single value.
We're actually going to be sending an entire list here.
I sent out a entire list and then be an entire list.
And then we cast whatever returning or coming out of the function would put in a list format and that
should be my outcome or my output c.
OK.
That's pretty much how can we use the map operation.
Can we use map operation.
It takes in a function takes in the list it performed well applies the all that function on our list.
OK.
All right.
So what I want you guys to do is to simply go here OK.
Define a new function and that function is called Multiply.
OK.
And please use the map operation to multiply these two lists together.
So here going to think the exact same operation here.
I have again two lists and I wanted to multiply these two lists together using a multiply function and
obviously using the map operation as well.
OK.
Please go ahead pause a video and they will see you guys after the challenge.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge well ask us to do is to simply go ahead
in here and use the map operation with the new function that you guys will be defining obviously to
multiply all the elements in here between EMV.
Let's see how can we do that first.
I need to define a function and that function I'm going to call it multiply and that function simply
takes two arguments it can call him let's say x and y.
And what the function does just returns X times Y.
And when I need to do it I need to say okay my output or let's call it C to be consistent C equals too.
I'm going to say lists and then going to say map and within the map I will send along the name of the
function which is multiply and I'm going to pass along simply my parameters which is my two of two of
my lists a and b.
All right.
Enter.
Here we go.
Let's take a look at C ship entered.
So now one times one is one four time 728 five times then forty five.
And so on so forth.
And that's pretty much how can you use the map to kind of perform and third operation or entire function
to a specific list.
All right.
Let's take a look at how can we use the map with a lambda expression which is again way more powerful
example.
So what I wanted to do here I wanted to remove that function.
I wanted to just have one line of code that does everything for me which is a very very powerful.
So it's define a new list.
I'm going to call it my list equals to let's say 1 2 3 and 4.
OK.
And what I'm going to do here I'm going to say out on the school list equals two.
I'm gonna say list is yes the same as we have done before and then map.
Right.
And then here I need to simply define a name of a function along with my list.
Which is my array or my list that I wanted to perform the operation on and instead of calling the function
let's say multiply here and have the function separately.
I can actually use your lambda expression directly so I'm going to say lambda I'm going to say I need
to send you X and please return back x square.
All right.
And do this operation please on my list.
That's it.
Here we go.
Just enter.
And if I take a look at our lists we go.
We come up with 1 4 9 and 16 which is simply the square all the elements in here.
All right.
So what happened here.
So here I simply used the map operation of the Mac funk map function that we have done before.
OK.
And instead of defining the function separately here and calling its name here along with the arguments
I can actually just use lambda expression directly right whatever I want.
Going to send you X you turn back x square for me and then I pass along my list which is my list and
here to do the entire operation in just one shot where just one line of code is really very powerful.
Okay.
All right.
So what I want you guys to do is to simply take these two parameters.
This is this is our mini challenge that's our challenge I want you guys to do is to simply use lists.
I'm sorry use the these two specific lists was EMV or going to use map operation.
We're going to use lambda expression as well to simply multiply all the elements within the two lists.
OK.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
You guys were able to figure out the challenge.
I said Okay c equals two.
I wanted to do lists and then do map and then do lambda right lambda simply will take two parameters
and return the multiplication of it.
The lambda are going to take a right and we're going to take B and Lambda we're going to return simply
a times B.
Okay looks good.
And what arguments are gonna be sending I have to specify what arguments I will be sending.
So I'll be sending the arguments a and I be sending B as well.
So these are kind of a two of my arrays in here into my list in here which is a and b and this is simply
my lambda expression.
It takes a and b and it just multiply them together shift enter.
And if you take a look at sea.
Here we go come up with one twenty eight forty five seventy two and sixty three.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge and hope it was pretty clear pretty
straightforward.
Best of luck and next lecture I'm gonna walk you through kind of another concept called filter.
Okay.
To add kind of a specific condition in here as well was kind of this is kind of the most advanced for
once you do that then you're gonna become you know like pro and then I'm gonna jump right away into
exercises we have tons of exercises for you.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.