Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going.
I know there was a lot of you know like questions here a lot of exercises but you know it's again it's
for all it's all for your own benefit.
After that you would become kind of master.
You know when it comes to functions lambda expressions and you get them you know Master Python programming
right after we continue the practical projects along with the machine learning section as well of course.
All right.
So question 7 I'm asking you to write a code that takes a range from a user upper and lower bounds.
I return a list of positive and even numbers only.
All right.
So all we could do going to say okay it's going to say input and ask the user to enter a lower bound.
Okay.
And that will get out again.
We can put it in for example bound men apologies.
Now men equals two.
You can copy that.
You can put it here.
I'm going to say enter the upper bound right.
And then we're going to be bound Max.
Okay looks good.
All right.
And what we could do here afterwards I'm going to say OK we can define the range.
You can say key numbers equals to range between the bound men and bound Max.
All right.
So don't have the numbers.
Right.
And what I could do here is I wanted to return only the positive numbers and even numbers as well.
So actually let's go ahead and use the lambda expression and actually use filter as well.
OK.
That's actually pretty.
It's actually very interesting exercise.
What we could do here I'm going to say OK filters if you guys remember.
Right.
And then we can simply we can apply something to an entire list which is my list here.
And what I could do.
I'm going to take that list and apply specific condition on it.
I'm going to take a filter.
I'm going to say lambda right.
The lambda I'm gonna take X and what I wanted to return wherever they were going to satisfy this condition.
And my argument here is simply my numbers okay.
He identified the condition yet.
So let's take a look at the condition I want to turn positive numbers only.
So X has to be greater than zero.
Right.
And I wanted to return only even numbers.
OK.
Now we're experts when it comes to that x divided by apologies x divided by two equals equals to zero.
Right.
So that will be filter of lambda expression if you get X if it satisfy this condition only you will
get it back right.
Okay.
Sounds good.
And we can cast that in a list format.
You remember
and let's put that in another list.
Let's call it like filtered filters.
Let's call it filter numbers for instance and let's print filter numbers.
All right let's run that into through lower bound that say to an upper bound let's say 10.
And that's what we're getting here.
We're getting only positive numbers 2 2 4 6 and 8.
And even that's I shot it again and it's put negative number let's put let's say minus 10 20 an upper
bound it's make it 20.
So again you've got only positive numbers right.
So you only got positive numbers and upper bounds only which is perfect.
That's exactly why I'm looking for and looking for even as well.
All right.
Question number eight I wanted to use filter and the expressions threaded code takes a list of numbers
below and returns even numbers only.
Actually that's pretty much the same you know kind of example that I've done before.
Let's do it again.
Again the idea is to practice as much as you can.
So that's how can we do that.
We're gonna say okay when I do lambda right.
If you take X right.
If simply if it satisfies this condition because remember I'm going to use it before landing this filter
right.
And I take a filter lambda if I take X only I only I will take X if it satisfy this condition right.
If simply my X divided by two and it was equals zero.
Right.
And I will do that when I take my numbers all right.
Looks good.
And they need to cast that in a list format
and I can call these even again one more time.
It's pretty much the same as we have done here before.
But here we actually headed like X greater than 0 2 as well right.
Okay this looks good.
And we can hit print.
Let's say
numbers that are my apologies that are divisible by two equals two.
And here we can pass even numbers.
All right let's run that.
And that's what we're getting.
So simply here we got only six.
We got only 22 on 120 and 220 and two hundred which looks perfect.
All right.
Next question is I'm asking you to write a function that simply takes to on PI matrices or arrays here
as we have here who have matrix X. We have matrix y and I wanted to return basically to call the functions
called Matrix operation that would return the addition subtraction transpose product and or product.
All right let's see how can we write that.
I'm going to say OK matrix operations.
So let's copy that.
That's the name of the function right.
And let's define it.
We're going to define matrix operations.
It will take a and b.
Correct
and let's go ahead and see how can we do that.
First I wanted to print and I wanted to return the matrices addition first.
I say keep matrices addition equals two.
And I can pass along and P num pi dots add of EMV and that's actually how we how we add numbers when
it comes to an umpire and only do MPD dot Ed and that's we'll do the addition for the both matrices.
All right let's actually test it.
So let's run the function first.
OK.
And let's run that's and that's what we're getting matrices addition is simply this.
Well I guess I can see here is you know like a little bit shifted.
Yes.
The answer is right.
Basically three plus two is five nine plus three is 12 a plus one is nine seven plus five is twelve
looks good but we need to make a little bit more you know kind of pretty in a way.
So going to say OK let's add here backslash and let's run that let's try it again.
And that's what it looks like.
So just going to write it in a new line so it can look a little bit better.
All right looks great.
So what we could do afterwards we could say OK.
Let's do the exact same thing.
But I wanted to do let's say subtraction.
So let's do that.
I mean I've seen sort of add are going to do subtract.
OK let's do it again.
Copy paste and let's do matrices.
Actually it's call it subtract my apologies subtract and let's do here multiplication mattresses multiply
equals two M.P. dot
multiply that you multiply both.
And let's do the deed.
The divide as well.
The division I'm gonna say OK actually I'm not asking for a division.
I'm asking for addition subtraction is do the transpose it to the principal.
That's pretty important.
MELISSA Okay print actually let's go and copy it again.
Copy paste and root for both matrices.
I'm going to copy and paste again.
Melissa came key this math matrix only made matrix is not matrices matrix transpose right.
I'm going to do N.P. dots.
What we could do here.
I don't need to do any of this.
What I could do.
I'm going to say OK what I could do here.
I need to simply get whatever matrix I'm getting to a and get dot t dot uppercase t that should simply
does the trick for us.
It will get the transpose.
I can actually go here remove all that and get the transpose for the next one to take a b dot transpose
as well.
All right.
Looks good.
OK.
Let's actually test it at this stage.
Let's run it.
And that's what we're getting here.
It looks like we don't have any errors which is good.
What.
Getting the subtraction which is let's test one numbers to 1 for example which is simply three minus
two.
OK that looks good.
All right let's get the multiplication which is simply the multiplication of matrices.
So because remember that's not dot multiplication actual multiply.
Right.
What I could do here is I can get a transpose as well.
So transpose is simply getting the rows and transfers transverse make it rows columns.
Right.
So what we could do here is for Matrix first matrix X we actually transpose it so it became 3 9.
This row became this column 3 9 right.
And then 8 5 which is a row became column 8 5 matrix multiply which is 2 3 1 7 and then it became 2
3 and then he became 1 7.
All right looks perfect.
What we could do as well is I can ask you to get the dot product right.
So instead of multiplication need to get dot product let's actually get the exact same stuff here.
Let's add it here and let's get the dot product multiply matrices dot multiply and say N.P. in here
we could say and p dot dot and that should do the DOT multiplication that's done it again.
All right.
So when we do the M P dot multiply that's actually element by element multiplication.
So if you guys take care here you will find that we multiply three by two become six.
Right.
We have nine by C becomes 27 and so on.
So you're doing element by element multiplication.
However when we do the NDP dot dot that will do an actual multiplication.
Right so multiply the two matrices together.
Please go ahead to the map mathematics basics.
You know we multiply to basically multiply two mattresses together.
OK.
Unfortunately I don't have kind of a summary here of the multiplication process but you simply take
the first row and multiply by the second column and so on so forth.
If you want to element by element of application please use m p dot multiply.
All right.
OK.
If you wanted to get let's say the square root for example of one element to consider K print I'm going
to say square roots of Matrix equals two and you can add again backslash n and you can simply add square
root of let's say let's pick one matches is let's pick the first one that says square root of a for
example.
All right let's run that round again and it's telling you there is an error here.
So here we didn't specify num pi.
So we have to speak its end p dot squared.
So and again let's run it again and that's it.
Works great.
So you guys can see here the square root of element by element squirrel tried to end up square root
of nine is basically three that's what we're getting here right.
So that's the square root of these elements.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And one more lectures to go.
We're going to keep going.
To finish lectures questions ten up till twelve.
Hope you guys enjoy the lecture and see you in the next lecture.