Hello everyone and welcome to this new section.
This section we're going to learn how can we deal with files in general how can we open text files.
How to how do we read text files how to write text files and we'll learn as well how can we read them
right into what we call it C as we file or comments separated files as well.
OK.
So let's get started.
So first we in order to deal with files.
First of all the files have to be contained within our current folder.
Ok.
In this exercise we're going to be doing assume OK.
Our Father contained within our folder within the exact same folder that that Jupiter notebook is contained
in.
All right.
So let's take a look at that.
So if you guys take a look at it here you will find that here we have these our CSB.
I'm sorry.
I was shift the notebooks.
OK.
So here's our old all I was used to notebooks and including all the exercises too.
And he would find tons of files that is fruits input foods output that is you know like new file.
There's my file like Long story short all the files that we're dealing with are contained within our
course package.
All right.
OK.
Let's go here and let's go ahead and see how can we cheat files in general.
So let's assume that I wanted to open my file dot text.
OK.
So I'm gonna say F equals to open.
And here I open parentheses and then I have to list what's the name of the file they wanted to open.
See they're going gonna call it my file the TSC and I have to specify the reason of opening it.
Why are you opening it open for reading purposes are hoping for writing purposes why are you opening
scene me I'm opening it for reading purposes.
OK afterwards are going to say Okay print
and afterwards you're going to say Okay take my so simply put what we do what we did here is that we
open the text file for reading purposes and pretty much kind of think of F. as kind of the handler.
That's kind of you know the file is became f simply okay.
So I'm gonna say Okay I need to F and I need to do dot read okay.
And that's it.
And to print it when you press ship enter.
Here we go.
So now I've been able to actually read all the content within our within our text file.
So if you open actually my text files if you will here if you open my files which is this one if you
open it you will find this is the information that we just printed right.
And become becoming your point python.
Python is a great programming language.
I'm learning how to under fire and python and so on so forth.
OK here we go.
It looks great.
All right.
The next step is let's assume that I wanted to only read one single line only.
So what I could say I was okay F equals to open and hit again to specify my underscore file the text
and I'm gonna open it for again for reading purposes but here I'm gonna say print and F instead of read.
So when I say f the treat only that would read the entire content of the text file here I could say
F only dot read line and that's it.
That will read simply the first line which is unbecoming point python.
All right.
Great.
OK.
All right.
Let's assume that I wanted for example instead of reading something I wanted to let's say create for
example a new file and maybe or maybe write something to it.
OK write something to my file in here which is my final text.
OK.
All right.
So what I could do.
I'm going to say okay F equals to open and then open my file again and then which is my file.
But what I'm gonna do here I'm going to open again stop the text obviously and I'm gonna open it.
Not for writing writing purposes.
I can open it for here in this case for appending purpose.
A guy's go up here in front of the reading purposes that is append if you wanted to let's say append
or add for example additional information to a file.
Okay.
And afterwards I'm going to say okay f dot instead of read actually gonna write to it and you can write
whatever you want.
So here that's a first of all make sure you actually can close that file.
So let's close it Casey open it for appending purposes and then here you can write let's say
I am learning python and will be a pro soon.
Something like that something.
OK.
All right let's let's shift enter.
Here we go.
And here you find that Python basically kind of returned back to tell you OK.
Fully three it's kind of you know like a confirmation code.
All right.
So let's take a look at the file so I could do you and say OK let's go here.
Open my file.
And here we go.
You'll find that the file of the original file contains only that information before.
Now I added I am learning python and will be a pro soon which is simply what we have just added in here.
OK.
All right.
So what we need to do afterwards after we actually write something to it or read something from it.
We have to make sure that I should close the file.
So going to say actually it's close the actual file here and we have to say f dot close to actually
close the file.
All right.
Looks good actually do it in a separate file and sort of appending new information at the close.
That's a close the file and that should basically conclude what we wanted to learn in here.
So in this section we're able to actually open the file read text into it we're able to as well read
specific line from it and we're able as well to write information if you wanted to append information
to the file.
What I'm asking us to do is to please write your name into my file the text I just wanted to you to
simply open the file for writing purposes appending purposes and then write let's say your name and
please make sure that you know like you close the file afterwards go ahead pause the video and I'll
see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge when ask us to do is to simply go ahead open.
Pretty much what we have done here.
So going to do this and maybe at the close as well.
But he did ask us to maybe write your name so here we're just gonna write maybe like like Ryan for example
simplicity okay.
All right.
You can call it whatever whatever you want.
So here I open my file for appending purposes I wrote whatever I wanted here and then closed the file
shift enter Okay looks good maybe go back and check on our file which is my file.
The text all right.
And here we go.
You will find that there is Ryan simplicity have been added here at the end.
Right.
Obviously you guys should be able to see your name or whatever you wrote here.
They should be able to see it.
And that's pretty much all we have for this lecture I hope you guys enjoyed it in the next lecture.
I'm going to walk you through how to create in your file from scratch and how to do maybe some couple
of you know like mixed files operations with some for loops.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.