Hello everyone and welcome to this new lecture in the previous lecture.
We're able to do some basic operations with files like opening the file you know like writing information
to it and so on.
And this section I'm going to show you how can we create a new file from scratch.
How to maybe add some folder loops and maybe like you know do some operations within the data we're
going to be reading out of the file.
We're going to be pretty pretty interesting.
OK let's assume they wanted to create a new file.
OK.
Whatever new file you can call it whatever name.
So if you go up here you will find that X if you open the file for exec purposes that means you are
creating a new file.
All right.
Let's see how can we do that.
So what we could do and say F equals to open and we can open something here for X purposes for x.
That means going to create it from scratch here.
You can call it whatever you want.
He's going to call it let's say like you know the files file new.
Okay obviously I have tons of files in there.
Okay.
Please can you can call it whatever you want to call it let's say five new during let's say filming
so you guys can can know like separated from the other files that we have.
So this is a new file we created during filming during the actual lecture that I've been doing right
now.
So now I created a new file with that title.
All right.
The question is how.
What do you want to say into it.
What do you want to write into it.
So I gonna say F dot right and here I can write whatever I want so I can say again I am learning Python
now something like that shift.
And then you need afterwards to make sure that actually if not closed the file that should close it
you've entered.
Here we go.
As long as you can find any errors you should be fine.
If you come here you should find like five new filming for example.
OK.
All right.
My apologies.
I actually made a short quick mistake so you need to include the the type of the file so there's a dot
text dot text I should enter.
Here we go.
If you go back you will find you should file and yet my new filming that text document open it.
I'm learning Python now which is exactly matches what we have just wrote here.
OK.
All right.
That's great.
Let's see how can we for example open a file and create a for loop that loops on the actual content
of that file.
So what I could do.
Okay let's go back to our files and say F equals to open.
Can open again my file that we had before.
Okay.
The text and you can open this for reading purposes.
And afterwards I'm going to create a for loop will say for line in my file.
So every time I go to my file extract line and print it and print my line enter it we go and we've been
able to simply go ahead and extract every line individually.
OK.
This is just kind of a way of how can you actually extract information and loop on on the actual content
of that file.
OK.
All right.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that we wanted for instance to open the file and read the content.
And for instance let's say a split or the content of that file into let's say different words.
How can we do that.
It's going to take it with let's say open or you can define it before as we have done before.
Equal open.
This is another way of doing it.
Take it with open and here they can specify let's say I wanted to take the fight I wanted to open which
is my file the text and I can open that for reading purposes and you can say as if this is simply exactly
the same or exact equivalent and that's OK.
No change.
All right so the first step and then what you could do is going to take a text for example data which
is the actual content of that file equals to f dot read lines right.
So shift entry we go.
So now we're able to access actually can do this.
You can access text data.
So now this is simply all the data contained within the file.
Right.
OK.
Next step what it could do.
You're gonna say okay for line in our text data every time.
Go ahead extract the line and simply when I wanted to do here I wanted to split kind of split all the
content of that into just simple bunch of words simply.
Okay so when I say for line in text data I mean it's split simply our text data.
Our line each line going to be taking here I'm going to do dot splits so I'm gonna split it into simple
words and I'm going to put them in words and then afterwards when you're done please go ahead and print
my words enter.
Here we go.
So now we'll be able to extract only eye information only and then am separately and then becoming a
pro and so on so forth.
That's kind of another way of extracting information and maybe visualizing it when we dividing it into
a bunch of strings a bunch of you know like characters on this using the line got split.
Okay.
All right.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
In the next lecture I'm gonna walk you through again pretty much the same final operation but using
C as V files instead of text files.
OK we're going to get much more interesting.
Stay tuned.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.