Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going.
And let's continue.
Questions for till 9:00.
OK so here I am asking you to read the file fruits underscored input the text and compare it to the
list of fruits in my fruit.
So here I have kind of you know like a list called my fruits has apples pepper orange watermelon tomatoes
and I'm asking you to simply compare this to to my fruits.
Okay.
In return only matching elements.
All right.
Let's see how can we do that.
So only matching elements would work.
It's going to say OK with open and let's open our fruits underscore input the text.
Right.
Actually let's do this and we're going to open this for reading purposes and we're going to say as file
right and going to say OK let's call it all underscore fruits ricotta Collard fruits collards whatever.
Okay.
File dot read lines.
So he was just going to read our lines in here.
Let's run.
That's OK.
He looks good.
Let's take a look at all fruits.
Just to make sure we're actually on the same page.
OK.
Here we go.
So here we have all the names of fruits.
And that's kind of the original fight right.
So now to the fun part.
Now we actually need to compare both lists.
Now we have two lists right.
And one to compare the two.
So what we could do here is before doing anything need to remove again the backslash and Rachel can
do the comparison properly.
I say OK.
That's easy so going to say we have done that before and I see all fruits equals two.
Let's go ahead.
Here again do it again.
I'm going to say OK for right let's call it Ward.
So for anywhere if you find any word in all fruits OK so for any word in all fruits of take go to all
fruits take every single word and simply take it and strip it remove from it any backslash and all right.
Looks good.
Let's actually make a little bit better.
All right.
So let's run that.
Let's take a look.
Let's take a look at all underscored fruits.
And here you go.
So simply here you got rid of all the backslash ends which is good.
Now you can actually do the comparison right.
OK.
Let's do the comparison now.
It's inserting your lines.
And what we could do here.
Yes.
OK let's call it selected fruits.
That's kind of the selected fruits.
Yes.
OK
to say for right.
I for example in all fruits so here I'm saying ok for each.
So go to the all fruits elements all the list all the huge list that we have.
Take each fruit right so that fruit is going to be I.
OK we can call it Fruit and fruits for example to make it.
Let me live it meaningful.
Let's do an if condition I'm going to take it.
If you find I in my fruits again my fruits is simply the list here that we have that was then provided
in the actual code right.
So he did we provided you with the lists you know what I'm trying to compare what I'm reading here to
this list right.
So if you go back here again take it for I in all fruits if you find if that the fruit was equal is
in my fruits if you basically find it.
Well I need that right.
So let's return it let's return.
I am going to be in my selected fruits and that's it.
Let's go ahead and go ahead and print selected underscore fruits.
That's it.
Let's run it.
And that's what we're getting which makes complete sense why because Apple is actually a fruit.
What I meant it was a fruit orange fruit which means that we didn't select the vegetables based within
acrylic but we didn't select pepper within select tomatoes and so on all right.
Question number five I'm asking to write a code that takes an input from a user and store it in a new
text file separated by new lines.
All right so let's take a sentence from the user first to take a sentence that equals two inputs.
And I'm asking the user to enter five names for example of your best friends.
I'm giving him guidance to say okay separated
by a comma.
All right let's run that key.
Ryan let's call it it all like like ly love.
Let's call you know like Joe and call like Frank.
Couple of names press enter.
Let's take a look at the sentence and that's what we're getting here.
These are all the list of names right.
OK so we could do that we can what we wanted to do it's basically just store it in a new text file.
So what we could do going a circuit with open and here I called it names out file and called a trial
OK the text and I'm going to open this for appending purposes because remember a pen.
I'm just going to like you know move elements to it.
Right.
Going to take a for every time I'm going to read the word in my sentence right.
So this is my sentence list right.
OK.
All right.
And sentence and actually like this is not correct.
But bear in mind that skip going to see what's can happen.
File dot right and are going to write simply our word every word we're going to be getting.
And let's add as well backslash end for a new line simply
OK.
Looks good actually something is still missing.
But let's see what's going to happen.
So if you're on that and let's take a look at what we're getting here.
Go back to you should find the file that's name
output names output file trial.
Get it open that one and that's what you're getting here.
You know what it's looks a little bit weird to have Ryan here and then we have Layla here and then we
have Joe.
It looks like you know it's not it's not what I was expecting right.
So actually let's go and add maybe like a couple of lines of code to fix that issue.
So what we could do is say OK let's take that sentence and actually split it.
So we're going to see a sentence that splits.
I'm going to split it based on the comma.
All right.
Let's see how can we do that.
Let's run it.
Oh my apologies.
Let's run it again.
You're going to say OK.
Like Ryan.
Lyla let's call it Steve let's call it Joe so it's supposed to be Joe.
But you know what.
Okay that's fine.
And he will split it once you do the splits OK.
What happened is instead of having now we have it is a form of a list.
Right.
Which is great.
You don't have it as one.
You know like one as one sentence before we have in one sentence.
So when we add backslash n OK we look at every character as an element separate element.
That's why we had you know they are on a single line.
Why in a single line and so on.
But here when we split it now we divided different words.
Right.
So now we can actually like if we run that's ok and if we go ahead here and check actually have to close
it first.
So let's run it again and let's take a look at the file again names I'll file trial.
Actually we didn't close the file.
That's why we're going through this issue at the moment.
Let's let's actually save it in a different file let's call it you know like name file Title of child
2 for instance.
OK.
And
actually it's let's do a sentence that split and we need to put that somewhere right.
So let's put that in sentence on the score lists for example.
And when we do it here's we'll do it on lists.
All right let's run that.
Let's run that and let's take a look at it.
So if you take a look at this one now that's what we're getting now it looks perfect.
Why.
Because now we divided them into different words and each word basically has been saved separately in
the file.
All right.
Question number six I'm asking to read the CSB file S&amp;P 500 stock data and printout of the heading and
first five rows of the data.
All right.
If you guys remember that was my Excel essentially C as we file if you have interest rates you have
employment and you have S&amp;P 500 price.
What we need to do here is I wanted to print only the heading on its own separate.
I mean I'm asking you to simply
print the first five rows within the file.
Let's see how can we do that.
All right.
So what we could do.
We're going to say OK here I wanted to import C is V and I'm going to say okay with open and then open
our C as we file as follows we going to say OK with open is the fight is called S&amp;P 500 on discourse.
Talk underscored data dot c as V.
And we're going to open that for reading purposes.
And I say K. that was going to read it as see as V file right.
And all we could do was take reads C as V right equals to C as v dot reader would have done that before
we were reading C as he files a c c as we file and we'll get us to say delimiter which is kind of you
know the separators going to separated by comma.
All right.
And then we're going to see a case talk we'll be equals to lists of my read or read C as V.
All right let's run that looks good.
Let's take a look at this talk and that's our my stock data.
So if yes take a look at it you'll find that we have interest rates we have employment I have S&amp;P 500
price looks great and well what I'm asking you to do is I wanted to print the head heading only I wanted
to print interest rates employment S&amp;P 500 and afterwards I wanted to print the 5 5 first rows.
Let's see how can we do this.
So to print simply think of it as kind of you know net.
Now we have it as illustrates something going to keep print talk and I wanted to get the first element
stock zero once once we do that.
That's it.
We'll get the first simply the first row right.
OK.
To get the next Rose which is you know rule number one because this is rule number 0 right.
Ask any door number one up until row row number six.
Let's see how can we print that.
Yes.
OK I'm going to say
let's define for example selected equals to an empty list.
Take a for row in stock and we're going to go from one till six because I wanted to print the first
five right.
Right.
Mistake every time you see selected Delta Rho also selected dot appends.
And I'm going to append our row that we obtained right.
So every time we get the row and appended so that we going to create it in a separate selected one.
Actually it's an invalid syntax.
So something is right or something is wrong sorry.
So here selected equal should be equal to looks good.
And if we take a look at selected that would give us our first five elements.
All right looks perfect.
All right.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And in the next lecture we're going to keep going and finish off the exercises.
See you guys in the next lecture.