Welcome everyone to this section on generative adversarial networks generative adversarial networks
or Ganz for short were invented in 2014 by Ian Goodfellow and his fellow researchers and the main idea
behind them is to use two networks competing against each other to generate new unseen data.
Gangs are often described as a counterfeiter versus a detective.
Let's get an intuition of how they work so we can think of the counterfeiter as the generator.
The generator is going to receive random noise.
Typically a Gaussian or normal distribution of noise and it's going to attempt to output data.
So generators are often used for image data the discriminator IS THE DETECTIVE It takes a dataset consisting
of real images from a real data set in fake images from the generator.
These counterfeit images and attempts to classify real versus fake images.
So keep in mind regardless of your source of images whether it's something like the MLS dataset the
had 10 separate classes the discriminator itself is always performing a binary classification it's just
trying to tell us things real or fake so let's actually see this process.
We first start off with just some noise some Gaussian distribution of noise data and we feed that directly
to the generator as input the generator goal is to create images that fooled the discriminator.
So keep in mind in the very first stage of training what's going to happen is the generator given noise
is just going to produce noise and then we also grab images from our real data set and then what we
do is in phase one we train the discriminator essentially labelling the fake generated images as zeros
and then the real data generate images as one.
So basically zero if you're fake one if you're true we feed it to discriminator and a discriminator
then gets trained to detect a real image versus a fake image and then as time goes on the generator
during the second phase of training is going to keep improving its images trying to fool discriminator
until it's able to hopefully generate images that appear to mimic the real data set and discriminator
can eventually no longer tell the difference between the false generated image versus a real image so
there's really two training phases.
Phase one is train the discriminator and then phase two is training the generator in phase 1.
What we do is we take real images and we label those as one for being truly real and they're combined
with fake images from a generator labeled zero the discriminator then trains distinguish real images
from fake images.
Keep in mind in phase one of training the back propagation is only occurring on the discriminator.
So we're only optimizing the discriminator weights during phase one of training then in face to what
we do is we have the generator produce more fake images and then in phase two we only feed the fake
images to the generator with all the labels set as real.
And this causes a generator to attempt to produce images that the discriminator believes to be real
and what's important to note here in phase two because we're feeding and just all fake images labeled
the one we only perform back propagation on the generator weights in this step.
So we're not going to be able to do a typical fit call on all the training data as we did before.
Since we're dealing with two different models a discriminator model and a generator model we'll also
have two different phases of training what's really interesting though and something should always keep
in mind is the generator itself never actually gets to see the real images it generates convincing images
only based off gradients flowing back through discriminator during its phase of training.
You should also keep in mind the discriminator is also improving as training phases continue.
So meaning the generated images will also need to hopefully get better and better in order to fold discriminator.
This can lead to really impressive results in video research has published many models such as style
Gan and also a face scan to actually produce fake human face images that are extremely detailed in nature.
So all of these faces you see here were actually generated using a Gan based system.
So pretty impressive results.
Now let's briefly talk about the difficulties with Gan networks and those are things like training resources
mode collapse and instability.
Will also try to give you potential solutions for each of these problems so right off the bat Ganz are
most often used with image based data and due to the fact that you have two networks competing against
each other they usually require graphical processing units or GP use for a reasonable training time.
Now fortunately for us Google collab currently has GP is available for free.
As discussed in the setup lecture but just keep in mind realistically we are training Ganz you're not
really gonna be able to train them on CPR it'll just take too long.
The next problem that curves of Ganz is something called the mode collapse.
So often what happens is the generator figure out just a few images or even sometimes a single image
that can fold to discriminator and eventually it collapses to only produce that image.
So you can imagine that back in that situation where it's producing faces maybe it figured out how to
produce one single face that falls discriminator.
Well then the generator ends up just learning to produce that same face over and over again so in theory
it would be preferable to have a variety of images such as multiple numbers or multiple faces or multiple
images etc. But Ganz again can quickly collapse to only produce a single number or a single face or
a single image.
Whatever your dataset happens to be regardless of the input noise which means you can feed in any type
of random noise you want but the generator figured out the one image that it can use to fool discriminator.
So in its batch of images that it produces it just produces copies of the same image now a couple of
different ways of trying to fight this problem is by using deep convolution Gantz which we'll see later
on in the section of the course and they're typically better for a voting mode avoiding mode collapse
because they are more complex and they have deeper layers to them.
Now researchers have also experimented with what's known as mini batch discrimination which essentially
punishes the generated batches of images that are all too similar.
So if the generator starts having mode collapse and getting batches of very very similar looking images
it will begin to basically punish that particular batch inside of discriminator for having the images
be all too similar.
And the last problem that we discussed was instability and it can be difficult to ascertain performance
and appropriate training epochs since all the generated images at the end of the day they're all truly
fake so it's difficult to tell just how well your model is performing at generating images because just
because a discriminator thinks something is real doesn't mean that a human like us will think a face
or a number looks real enough.
So so it's difficult to ascertain that sort of true performance.
And again due to the design of the generative adversarial network the generator and discriminator are
constantly at odds they're fighting each other.
So that can lead to performance oscillation between the two so typically when you're dealing with Ganz
you'll have to experiment with hyper parameters such as the number of layers number of neurons activation
functions learning rates etc. especially when it comes to complex images a few final thoughts before
we continue on to actually creating our own games with Python and Caris and tensor flow is that Ganz
are a very popular area of research and often this the results are so fascinating and so cool that researchers
even like just to do this for fun.
So you'll see a ton of hub repos on all sorts of different Ganz so I would highly encourage you to make
sure to do a quick search on Google Scholar for the latest research papers on this topic.
This is something that you'll see a paper almost every month just on some really interesting research
in generative adversarial network.
So I highly encourage you to just do a google search and see what has come out in the last few months.
OK with that being said let's get started in programming our own hands.
I'll see you at the next lecture.