Welcome everyone to this section of the course on natural language processing with deep learning.
We're going to be exploring how to work with text data in conjunction with deep learning and this topic
is a natural extension of the time series and recurrent neural networks topics that we just discussed
since we'll be using a lot of those similar topics in the section of the course we're going to be creating
a neural network that will generate new text based on a corpus of existing text data and I would highly
suggest they check out the article called the unreasonable effectiveness of recurrent neural networks.
We've actually linked it for you as a resource in this lecture.
So definitely check it out because we're essentially going through the project that's described in the
article.
So what are we actually going to do and how will this work.
Basically we're going to be doing is the following task given an input string sequence predict the sequence
shifted forward by one character.
So if I give you the sequence h e l l shift it over forward and predict that the next sequence of four
letters should be E L L O to spell out Hello So the character based recurrent your network will actually
end up learning the structure of the text and the example that we're going to be working through is
going to use the complete works of William Shakespeare and what's really cool is that you're going to
see the network clearly learn play writing structure and spacing and things like characters entering
and exiting just from a character level.
So we'll be exploring that and how this network is actually able to learn basic structure of a much
larger piece of text by just predicting character to character so essentially we're going to be doing
is building a model that looks something like this.
We have our sequence of input characters and notice that we have some input layer where it's one hot
and coded and then throughout maybe a hidden layer or multiple hidden layers we end up attaching weights
to these one hot and coatings and eventually the output layer is going to give us well.
We'll be treating as a probability distribution for all the letters essentially giving us the highest
probability character that should show up next.
So let's go through the steps that we're going to be doing in this project.
Step number one is just to read in the text data and for this we can use the basic built in Python commands
to read in a corpus of text a string data note however if you plan on doing this with your own text
dataset you should have at least a large dataset that contains about 1 million or more characters for
realistic results step number two is text processing and factorization since the neural network can't
take in raw strings and you can't multiply a raw string by a digit or a floating point number.
What we need to do is to encode them as integers.
So we'll be doing this for all the characters not just letters.
So things like a b c will encode those to each have a representative index number and we'll do the same
thing for punctuation even empty space.
We'll have an encoding then step number three will be to create batches.
So we're using tense flows data set object to easily create batches of text sequences so something like
Hello space M and then the next sequence that is the target sequence will be starting at E and then
go Ello space.
My second understand that the complete sequence should be Hello my so we'll want to use sequence lengths
that are long enough to capture a structure and previous words but not so long that the sequence is
just capturing also historical noise that isn't relevant to the sequence shifted by one character forward.
Step number four we'll be actually creating the model and we'll be using three main layers for our example
model.
In this lecture series and that is embedding layer a gated recurrent unit layer and then a final dense
layer so the embedding layer what it does is essentially embeds positive integers or indices into dense
vectors of a fixed size.
So for example we could imagine that we have similar letter encoded to number four and another letter
encoded to number 20.
And what we're going to do is we're gonna choose some number of embedding dimensions and the embedding
layer will actually cast or turn those single integers into dense vectors where there is a number per
dimension and it's up to the user to choose the number of embedding dimensions.
And this is has a lot to do with the way things like word to vector actually works after that will work
with a gated recurrent unit layer.
And that's a special type of recurrent neuron unit we discussed in the previous section of the course
and the gated recurrent unit is like a long short term memory unit with forget gate but has fewer parameters
than LSD m as it lacks an output gate.
So again we discussed the gate at our current unit and you can review this in the previous section of
the course and then finally we have the dense layer where there's essentially one year on per character
and character labels will be one encoded.
So the final dense layer essentially produces a probability per character.
And what's really nice about that probability per character is that means we can play around with what's
known as temperature.
Essentially we can play around the fact where we can actually manipulate the probability drawing and
maybe not just choose the highest probability character but actually assign it where we may end up playing
or a temperature so that less probable characters happen either more or less often depending on that
factor.
So we'll be discussing that as we could along as well then step 5 is to train the model.
So we'll set up our batches and make sure to one hot encode our character labels and then step six will
be generating new text similar to how we generate the forecast in the previous section of the course.
But it's really cool here is we'll show you how to save our models weights and then she had a reload
that models weights with a different batch size in order to pass in just a single example.
Okay so let's go ahead and get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture or begin coding all of this out.