Welcome back everyone.
In this section we're going to focus on the quick crash course in data visualization so throughout this
course we're gonna be visualizing a lot of our data and we're gonna be performing exploratory data analysis.
So what this section is designed to do is really just briefly cover some of the data visualization techniques
using two main libraries.
And that is the map plotted library and the seaborne Library later on the course we'll also be exploring
pandas built in plotting capabilities.
Now keep in mind this section is not a comprehensive overview of either of these libraries.
Instead we're simply going to go over some common syntax calls that you will see throughout the course.
That way when you see them when we're learning about deep learning or machine learning they don't seem
completely new and you're not focused on learning that syntax.
Instead you already know it.
Having gone through this section if you are interested in a deeper dive please refer to the official
documentation of these libraries OK.
So in this section we're just going to quickly go over map plot libs basic syntax calls some seaborne
examples that we'll be using throughout the course and then we'll perform some visualization exercises
and then go over their solutions.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.