Welcome everyone to this section of the course on nut pie in this lecture.
We're going to give you an overview of what we're going to cover in this section of the course as well
as give you a basic brief overview an introduction to the none high library so as mentioned the section
of the course is going to focus on just a quick crash course on Empire basics.
We're going to cover the following topics.
What is an empire and why we use the Empire.
Then we'll talk about actually using empire res and matrices how to index and slice information or elements
out of those arrays or matrices.
Various nut pie operations and we'll finish this off with a set of exercise questions and then go through
those solutions.
So what actually is num pi num pi stands for numerical python and it's an open source numerical library
used for working with mathematical functions of multidimensional array and Matrix data structures.
It's already installed in our environment and it's actually very common library use in data science
in machine learning so why would we actually want to use num pi.
We mentioned that we're going to be learning how to use num pi arrays and matrices but if you're already
familiar with Python then you know that Python actually has a built in list structure that can act as
an array.
So what do we actually need num pi instead of just using the core Python list.
Well no pi arrays use less memory than a normal Python list.
A normal Python list is actually a group of pointers to separate Python objects for example pointing
to the individual Python no objects inside of the list a num PIRA.
It's designed to be an array of uniform values without using extra memory space for type pointers.
This makes it much more efficient and actually use a lot less memory than a normal Python list.
Num pi can also read in information faster than normal python and has lots convenient broadcasting operations
that can be performed across array dimensions.
So as we learn more about an umpire race will begin to see capabilities that they have that a normal
Python list doesn't later in the course we're going to be using them praise for quick data generation
and many tensor flow functions look extremely similar to number of functions.
So learning them pie sets us up for a great foundation for working of data later on in the course.
OK let's go ahead and get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.