Welcome back everyone.
In this section of the course we're going to take a look at recurrent neural networks.
We've used neural networks to solve classification and regression problems but we still haven't seen
how neural networks can deal with sequence information just as convolution neural networks were more
effective for use of two dimensional image data Recurrent Neural Networks have unique properties that
allow them to be more effective for sequence data sequence data can be a variety of data sources it
can be anything from timestamps sales data or sequence of text in a sentence or biological data like
heartbeat data over time et cetera.
So let's think about what a time series actually is.
Here we're showing beer wine and alcohol sales across the United States for a certain period of time
on the x axis we can actually see the timeframe.
So starting at nineteen ninety two all the way until around 2018 2019.
So here on the y axis we can see we have sales in millions of dollars when we're thinking about forecasting
and time series predictions with recurrent neon networks.
But we want to do is we want to be able to learn of historical information and forecast into the unknown
future.
So that's how we're going to be using recurrent fuel networks with time series data.
In this section of the course in future sections what we're going to realize is that sequences can also
be essentially categorical sequences such as a sentence.
For example we want to be able to given the data.
Hello how are you.
Predict that today is the highest probability word to show up next and recurrent known networks will
also be able to do that.
And if you have email or text messaging from Google you've probably already seen this sort of technology
in practice where you have predictive texts.
Ok so in this particular section we're going to learn a lot about recurrent neural network theory and
then we'll learn about specialized types of neurons that work particularly well with time series data
called Ellis teams or short term memory units and our use or groups which are gated recurrent units.
So we'll learn about the theory behind them.
Once you understand the theory behind these specialized units we'll move on to a basic implementation
of recurrent neural network on a sine wave and then we'll learn how to operate a recurrent network for
forecasting capabilities on a real Lifetime series.
Then we'll test your skills for an exercise and solution in the next section of course we'll focus on
recurrent neural networks and other neural network techniques for natural language processing and text
data.
All right let's get started.
I'll see in the next lecture.