Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to go over the solutions to the panel's exercise questions.
Let's get started.
OK here we are at the exercise notebook.
Let's go ahead and begin with the first couple of tasks.
First we want to import pandas so we'll say import pandas as PD run that then the next task is to read
in the African econ crisis that CSP file.
So to do that on ADF is equal to PD that read CSP.
And since I'm located in the exact same location as the CSP file I just need to say a F R and I should
be able to autocomplete this.
So there we go.
And let's display the first five rows the data set.
We can do this by saying the f the head there we have it we can see the different columns and we can
notice that it's actually organized looks like alphabetically by country and then by year.
So how many countries are represented in this dataset.
Lots different ways we can do this.
One easy way is to say D F go ahead and grab the country column and just ask unique actually ask and
unique.
And that returns back 13 the very next question asks what are the countries represented in which case
you want just unique and that returns back this array of unique countries represented in the dataset.
Next question was what country had the highest annual CPI inflation rate and what was the inflation
rate.
So how can we do this.
Well we could do is sort values by inflation.
Annual CPI which is the column that corresponds to annual CPI inflation rate.
And if you have questions on that you could just look at the bullet points and read what the columns
represent.
But what I'm going to do is just say the have sought values and then I will say by inflation underscore
annual underscore CPI and we'll say ascending is equal to False.
So if I run that that sorts everything by that highest annual CPI inflation rate.
I just want to know the country.
So what I could do is just say head of one which grabs the very first row on this which is Zimbabwe.
And if I really wanted to I could then ask for the country and that gives it back Zimbabwe.
But here we can see the results are quite clearly just Zimbabwe.
If you want you can go ahead and grab that singular country out of it.
OK.
In what year the Kenya have its first system crises.
So what we need to do is first filter out the state offering.
So my approach would be the following.
First only grab the entries for Kenya and we can do this by saying DLF country is equal to Kenya and
the other condition I want.
So we'll say ampersand is where it actually had a systemic crisis.
So we'll say systemic crisis is equal to one.
Wrap that up in parentheses for the book for them.
And then filter out.
So now this remaining data frame rate here if we take a look at it only has where the country Kenya
had a systemic crisis.
And then if I wanted to know what you that have it's first one I would sort by here so I could say that
sort values by year in this case doesn't actually make a difference it was already sorted by country
then by year.
And if I really wanted to I could say that ILO c 0.
And that will return back the very first item here and then we could get the year from that nineteen
eighty five.
So if I really wanted to I could continue passing year off of this series run that just to get nineteen
eighty five or you don't need that extra stuff and just read off as shown here.
It's up to you.
OK so we know that in what you can you have its first system crisis.
The answer is nineteen eighty five.
Lots of different ways you can get this one.
Next was how many yearly systemic crises have occurred per country.
What we can do here is go ahead and grab a subset of the data frame where we actually have a crisis
so we can say crises is equal to the F where systemic crisis is equal to one or true.
Then once we do that we'll go ahead and different ways we can do this.
We could say crises go ahead and group by the country and then just count the instances per country.
So if you run that you'll notice that accounts for each column which theoretically should be the same
values essentially same number of instances per column.
So you can just grab any column you want here such as systemic underscore crises run that and those
are the answers.
Okay.
Next was how many years that Zimbabwe have a sovereign external debt default occur.
So again just doing a little bit of filtering here.
We're going to first only grab Zimbabwe so say where the country is equal to Zimbabwe.
You could also use the country codes if you wanted to.
So that's our first condition for the filtering.
Next what I want to know is where the sovereign external debt default.
I just had autocomplete that also occurred so that's equal to one and then if I grab this and run it.
This returns back all the rows where my country Zimbabwe and we have had a sovereign external debt default
occur and only one of those.
How many of them are so I can just check the length of this and it returns back 30.
So in thirty total years Zimbabwe had a sovereign external debt default occur.
Now the one thing I pay attention to is depending on how this data was organized you should be careful
to make sure there weren't any repeat years.
But in this case because we can see that data is organized by year then there are no repeated years
that that's the only danger there and just taking the length of this guy.
OK the last one wasn't what year that Algeria have its highest exchange rate.
Well lots of different ways you can do this one.
One way is to simply filter out where the country is equal to Algeria.
So now I have all the entrances of Algeria.
I'll go ahead and sort values by the exchange rate so he can say XY H underscore USD.
We'll set a spending equal to False and really I'm just interested in the first one of this.
So this is the highest exchange rate it ever had.
According to this data.
OK so that's it.
Keep in mind lots of different ways you could answer a lot of these questions.
And also you could always just keep filtering out a lot of these.
So here are the real answers 2014.
So if I really wanted to I could add in year here to return back.
Just 2014 it's really up to you how deep into the weeds you want to go.
But I would encourage you to really explore this dataset and explore the links that we have provided
for you at the very top of this notebook to player on a bit further.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next section of the course.