Welcome back everyone.
Over the next series of lectures we're going to be coding along with a regression based project where
based off the dataset for different housing features we're going to try to predict the price that a
house should sell it.
So based on things like the number of bedrooms number of bathrooms square footage et cetera we'll try
to build a deep learning model that can actually predict the price of a house.
So a big part of this is exploratory data analysis as well as feature engineering which is what are
going to focus on in part one.
Let's head over to a notebook and get started.
I'm here in a notebook and I've already imported pandas number hi Matt put lib and Seabourn born as
a quick note.
If you go to our annex folder the notebook that corresponds to this lecture or series of lectures it's
called Cash regression.
It's right after the syntax basics and if you open it up you should be able to scroll down and then
see a full description of all the feature columns.
So some of these feature columns it may not be quite obvious what the actual feature column stands for.
So here we have the actual definitions.
In case you're interested in it.
So we're gonna come back here and let's load up our data we'll say def is equal to PD dot read CSB and
our data is located underneath our data folder so if we go back up a directory and is called Casey underscore
House underscore data that CSP go ahead and read it in.
And again if you check out our regression notebook we're actually using this data.
So it's a rural dataset from a Kaggle link so you can check out the actual link right here.
But basically what this is it's historical pricing data for house sales in King County USA and King
County is essentially where Seattle is.
So come back here to our notebook and we're going to export this data a little bit using some visualization
techniques.
So first let's see if we have any missing data.
We'll say the f is no not some.
And so what this does is first off the f is no.
That just returns back true or false if something is null.
So if something is missing it'll return back true.
And I can actually then sum these up per column and it will treat false as zeros and truths as ones
and that we can actually add a count of how many missing data points we have.
And for this particular dataset we actually have no missing data which kind of makes sense.
If a house was historically sold it's not like you wouldn't know the number of bedrooms the house had
before you sold it.
So for this particular data set it makes sense that there is no missing data later on in the section
The course will show you how to deal with a dataset that does have missing data.
And another thing I like to do after you check out how much data is missing is just do a quick describe
call which will give you the statistical analysis on your dataset.
And I personally like to transpose this so that I get to see the statistical means during deviation
mean percentile values etc. For all the columns.
Now some of these doesn't really mean anything.
So later on if you actually see the head of the data frame you'll notice that one of them is just a
unique idea.
So this is some sort of unique idea for the sale.
So it doesn't really make sense to look into any meaning for the mean of the I.D. our other things like
the mean price could be really important.
So we can see here that we have this scientific notation which basically means five point four times
10 to the power of five.
So essentially add in five zeros.
OK so we have all that information.
It's a little hard to just read this table and thoroughly understand it.
Let's start actually describing it through visualization using see more in the map live and all those
skills we learned in the data visualization crass course section.
So something I could do especially for continuous labels is just do a distribution of the actual label
so do a distribution plot essentially a histogram and something else I can do is just make this a little
larger by calling Pulte that figure and setting fixed size to let's say 10 by 6.
So I'll go ahead and run that and I get to see this distribution.
So notice here it looks like most of our houses are falling somewhere between zero and maybe around
one point five million dollars and we could have these extreme outliers here for the really expensive
houses and it may actually make sense to drop those outliers in our analysis if they are just a few
points that are very extreme.
And so we can essentially build a model that realistically predicts the price of a house if its intended
value is somewhere between let's say 0 and 2 million dollars.
There's not going to be that many houses apparently on the market that are worth more than let's say
3 million.
So that's something to keep in mind here especially for applying this to a realistic situation.
They were trying to build a model for a real estate agency since it's really not that many houses on
the market that are that expensive.
It may not be really useful to actually have our model train on these extreme outliers.
Now we can go ahead and do similar analysis of different features.
So for example for categorical ones such as number of bedrooms which is kind of continuous but you can't
have really one point five bedrooms you can actually have that four bathrooms.
But for the case of bedrooms we are in our data set.
We don't really have actually one point five or five.
So we can treat this as a count plot.
So I could say something like go ahead and count bedrooms and then plot them out.
And so here I can see what actually looks like almost like a similarly distribution where the vast majority
of all these houses have somewhere between two to five bedrooms and it looks like there's a huge mansion
somewhere in this that has 33 bedrooms.
So it looks like eight through 33 probably just have like one instance themselves which is why they're
showing up here.
But we can't actually see that bar because no the actual rest of the bedrooms are in the thousands.
So it makes sense that you wouldn't really see a color for something as small as one.
Now what's also nice is just comparing your label to some sort of feature that you think has a high
correlation and what you can't do is you can say data frame correlation run that and then you can begin
to see what actually correlates with your label and offer this.
I'm going to go ahead and grab my label let's just say price run that and let's go ahead and sort these
values will say sort underscore values and here I can see things that are either highly positively correlated
or highly negatively correlated.
Obviously price is going to be perfectly correlated with price but it looks like these square feet of
living space has a very high correlation with the actual price of the house.
And what I would recommend doing is exploring highly correlated features with your label through a scatter
plot.
So for example I could say S.A. scatter plot and compare price to my square feet living space and say
data is equal to D F I'll go ahead and run that and I can see here a very strong linear relationship.
And if I need to expand this out.
Notice that looks like the price is overlapping.
I could say Pulte figure and just give it a little more space by saying think size is equal to something
like 10 by 5 and that gives us a nice little space here.
Okay.
So again I always recommend checking out the correlations between your different features and your actual
label and then exploring those correlations through or exploring those features through some sort of
data visualization.
So for example if we take a look here it looks like bedrooms also has some positive correlation as well
as bathrooms and you can do count plots of those against the price as well or even box plots to see
the distributions.
For example I could say box plot where x is the number of bedrooms.
Why is the price.
And then my data is the f.
I'll go ahead and make this a little larger as well.
By doing a figure call here go ahead and make this 10 by 6 or something similar.
And what this is showing me is the distribution of prices per bedrooms.
So for example I can see that there's quite a bit of variation in bedrooms ranging between 3 and 7.
And that also makes sense because if we took a look at our count plot from before it looks like the
majority of the houses have bedrooms between maybe 3 and 7.
So it also makes sense that there's quite a large variety in prices there.
So there is no right or wrong way to perform exploratory data analysis.
So feel free to continue exploring this dataset through any other features that you're interested in
either doing box plots or count plots.
We should notice however that in our dataset if we take a look at the columns we have this lat and long
features and if we take a look back at our actual feature columns those actually stand for the latitude
and longitude so it may be interesting to actually explore this by plotting it out and we can actually
do a pretty good job of this just if a simple scatter plot.
Now keep in mind Seabourn doesn't actually have built in geographical plotting capabilities.
There is a little bit of that with map plot lib with some extension plug in libraries but we're actually
not going to focus on trying to plot these points on top of a real world map.
Instead we can actually gain a lot of information with a little bit of cursory knowledge of what King
County actually looks like combined with a simple scatter plot call.
So let's first see the distribution of prices per latitude vs. longitude.
It's going to come back to my notebook here and all I'm going to do is see what do my prices look like.
So we'll have price on the x axis and then is there some sort of differentiating factor just based off
longitude so then we'll say data is DLF.
And since I have so many points in my dataset I'm gonna make this figure quite a bit larger.
We'll say Pulte figure and set fixed size equal to let's make it 12 by eight.
So I can go ahead and run this and I would expect to see just essentially kind of a flat blob here.
If there was no price differentiation based off longitude.
But it looks like there tends to be some sort of price distribution at a certain longitude.
So looks like at longitude negative one to two point two.
That looks like an expensive housing area.
You can see the distribution quite clearly here.
And we can repeat this per latitude so we can go ahead and changes from long to lat and we can explore
this as well.
And the same behavior seems to pop up.
It also seems that a particular latitude there's some sort of expensive housing area.
And basically what this is telling us is that it looks like at a certain combination of latitude and
longitude that tends to be an expensive area.
So if we just look at a King County map we can begin to discern this.
And what we're gonna do is we can see here essentially the city of Seattle and King County itself.
Let's just plot out latitude versus longitude and plot out all these points and then later we can affect
their hue.
So we're going to come back to our notebook and we can already tell just from this evidence that there
should be some hotspot on a map that has expensive houses.
So we'll come back here and we'll do the following.
I will scatter plot with X as my longitude and Y as my latitude.
And it should be in this order in order for the map to make sense.
Otherwise you'll end up flipping the coordinates of the map and then we'll say also make this larger
penalty figure fig size is equal to twelve by eight.
So this is just a simple scatter plot and we get something that looks like this.
And if we compare this to our actual map of King County we can see that more or less they tend to match
up.
We can see here kind of the shapes of Seattle and we can see here the real map of King County.
So keep that in mind.
And what we're gonna do now is I'm going to start editing this to see if we can actually hone in on
this expensive housing area and one way we can do this is by attempting to say Hugh is equal to price.
And what that is going to do is it's actually going to color these points darker or lighter based off
their price.
And I can begin to see a little bit here of a darker area and it looks like it's actually matching up
with our original estimates of the expensive longitude.
So notice at negative one to two point two but keep going up.
I eventually hit these darker points.
Same at around forty seven point six which is kind of what we expected based off this latitude mapping.
However it looks like I'm not getting quite a color gradient as I would like and that's because of those
really expensive outlier housing as well as the fact that we still have a marker edge here.
So let's see if we can actually clean up this map a little bit by maybe dropping some of these outliers.
So we're going to do is I'm going to take a look at my data frame and I'm going to sort the values based
off price and I will say ascending is equal to False.
And let me just check out the top 20 most expensive houses and loops that should be sought values.
There we go.
So know that in my top 20 houses my most expensive house in this dataset is seven point seven million
dollars.
And as I keep going down you'll notice that it eventually kind of quickly drops off to something more
reasonable like three point six.
And if we take a look at our distribution of the prices of these houses it looks like I should probably
have some reasonable cutoff at three million dollars because it looks like almost just that there's
only 20 houses here that are above three million or maybe a little bit more than that.
So something I can do is I can just sample out the maybe top one percent of all houses.
So if I take a look at the link for my data frame I right now have around 21000 houses in my data frame
which means 1 percent of this is 215 houses which is actually quite a lot of houses.
So let's go ahead and create another data frame and we will call this non top 1 percent or you could
relabel this as bottom ninety nine percent.
And what we're gonna do here is we'll take this same data frame that we created the F sought values
price ascending
and what I will do is I will grab everything after the top 1 percent of houses which essentially means
starting index integer location to 16.
Go ahead and grab everything beyond that.
So all I'm doing here is I'm grabbing the ninety nine percent bottom of houses so I'm not dropping that
much information I'm only dropping 1 percent of information but hopefully that drops all those really
expensive outlier houses and the reason for that is so I can get a more clear color distribution on
this actual scatter plot.
So we'll come back here.
I have now my bottom 99 percent or non top 1 percent.
And let's go ahead and try this out again.
I'm going to copy and paste this code here.
Except now my data is going to be equal to instead of the F
that non top one percent data frame so I can run this and now I can definitely see a lot clearer color
distribution and I can actually begin to play around with this.
So for example maybe I don't want an edge color I don't want that white edge color I begin to say edge
color is equal to none and since I have so many points stacked on top of each other.
Also say Alpha is equal to zero point two.
And finally I'll go ahead and choose a different color gradient.
So this is something that's kind of totally optional for you but I'll choose a red yellow green color
gradient.
So this is are the y l GM and it's going to go from yellow red to yellow to green.
And that's going to make it a little clearer where the expensive housing is.
So I run this again make sure to check your commas.
You can always copy and paste these lines of code from the notebook but now this is a much better plot
at showing me where the expensive parts of King County is and I can see the distribution really clearly
here.
And you'll also notice that it almost looks like on the edge of the water there tends to be some lighter
points which makes sense because usually a waterfront property is going to be more expensive than inland
property.
So this is a much better distribution and scatter plot map than our original mapping right here.
While this does tell us a little bit of the information we can start playing around with the actual
data frame that we're plotting out now we're still showing here.
Ninety nine percent of all houses.
And those outliers we can kind of assume are going to be somewhere either on the waterfront on this
top Northern Edge or in this expensive area of King County.
So lots of different things you can play around here to actually get better looking plots that are more
informative to the user.
And the other things we can show you here are things like doing a box plot on whether or not something
is on the waterfront.
So it's actually one of our features we can say X equals swaps waterfront and say Y is equal to price
stay our original data frame and here we can see the distribution of prices whether or not they're on
the waterfront.
So it looks like if you are on the waterfront you are more likely to be more expensive which again kind
of makes sense.