Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to go over the solutions for the recurrent neural network exercise questions.
Let's get started.
Okay here we are at the exercise notebook.
Let's go ahead and begin.
First we need to import pandas as PD and then we're gonna need to do a little bit of plotting so we'll
import map plot lib dot pi plot pie plot as BLT.
And then just in case depending on your version of notebook you may need to set map plot lib.
In line
and I don't believe we use num pi but you can go ahead and import it anyways.
Okay so the dataset.
Remember our goal is to forecast into the future the actual production of frozen dessert first thing.
First me going to read in this dataset we'll say the f is equal to PD read CSB and it's located underneath
our data folder so we can provide the full file path depending where you're located on your computer.
It's called frozen dessert production.
You should be able to tab autocomplete this and then just as mentioned in the lecture you actually want
to go ahead and set our index column equal to date and then we'll say past dates is equal to true.
So that allows me to to then just read it in L in one step with the dates as a date timestamp as the
index.
Now this series of letters and numbers kind of hard to remember.
So we'll go ahead and change the column name to production.
So say the F columns is equal to and as a list we press in production.
There we go.
So we get that result.
Go ahead and plot at the time series.
You could just simply say the F plot.
You can also edit the figure size if you want.
So if you wanted to you could say fig size is equal to and then play around if this till it's something
meaningful to you.
But obviously there's clear seasonality during the summer months.
So let's explore that further.
Next we want to figure out our train test split.
So the first task is to figure out well how much data will actually have to play with so we'll say.
What's the length of my data frame.
It's five hundred and seventy three points.
So our next task is to split the data into a train test split and in our particular case we told you
the test set should be the last 24 months of data.
That's something you could play around with but it should at least include 12 months of data which is
a seasonal cycle.
We'll go ahead and make it larger to be two years of data so we'll say test size is equal to twenty
four and then our test index is then equal to the length of the data frame minus the test size and what's
nice about this equation is then you can play around if your test size and edit the test index as you
see fit.
And then our training set is simply starting from the very beginning.
Go all the way up to that test index and then our test set is essentially the end of that.
So it says starting at the test index go all the way to the end.
OK so we have our training set and our test set.
If you check the length of the test set it's twenty four months.
So essentially what a model's going to be doing is based off most data set.
Essentially everything up to the last two years see if you can forecast its future two years which is
our test set.
Okay so next it's up to us to scale the data so we'll say
S.K. learned pre processing import min max scalar.
Go ahead and run that create our scalar object scalar is equal to an instance of min max scalar and
then we only fit to the training data because we don't want to assume that we have prior information
about the future.
So we'll say fit to our training data.
Technically this could be a fit transform if you wanted to do it all at once.
But I like separating out the two steps just for readability.
So skilled trained scalar that transform transform our training set and we'll start to make sure to
transform our test set.
So scalar thought transform on the test set.
OK so we have our skilled data.
Next step is to create our time series generator.
So the first generator to create is for the actual training data we'll say from tensor flow thought
Kerry's stop pre processing thought sequence.
Import time series generator and we'll say there we go.
I just had auto completed that and the length of our actual training is up to us.
But we said at a minimum it should be 18 months to give length to capture can the full year seasonality.
So we'll say that the length of the batches is 18 months.
How many actual features are we working with.
Well it's just one feature and you can define it here define it later.
Remember we eventually passed that in upon creating the model and now it's time to create our time series
generator.
We simply pass our scale training set.
That's a source of both our X and Y the length is just equal to the length of the batch.
Remember that's how many months are included in each batch.
And then the batch size will just be one.
We'll just do kind of one set at a time and you can do generator index at zero to see what the example
batches look like.
We did that in the lectures.
Okay.
Next it's time to create the model.
So we'll say from tensor flow not care stop models.
Import sequential.
And then from tensor flow.
Dark hair start layers.
We need to import two types of layers.
One is the LACMA unit layer that we're going to be using.
And for the final output layer it needs to be a dense layer.
And now we'll define our model.
So a model is equal to sequential model the add.
And I'll add in 100 Ellis Tam units here and then we'll make sure that the input shape is defined correctly
or say input shape is equal to length.
Make sure it's in a tuple length by any number of features finally you have to make sure to add in the
dense layer so same model.
Add in art then slayer.
This should just be one neuron since we're predicting just one output and then after that we'll compile
the model.
So we say model dot compile optimizer go ahead and choose Adam and then the loss is means squared error.
You can play around the optimizer as well.
Let's not.
Doesn't have to be the Adam string.
We have a lot of options there.
Let's run this make sure we didn't commit any typos it's created the model and to see a summary of the
model can say model that summary and we see the output here.
OK next we want to create a generator for the scale test slash validation set.
So just as we did in a lecture I will say My validation generator is equal to a time series generator
except this time it's based off the scaled test data.
So scale test data and then the length is the same as before and then the batch size will also be the
same as before and whips make sure batch size.
I forgot to define it so I'll just hardcoded as one.
OK so probably good ideas to just set a variable batch size up above that we can play around the batch
sizes but typically one works really well for a time series data.
Next we want to create an early stopping callback based off validation loss.
We do this by saying from tensor flow Harris that callbacks import early stopping and then we'll create
our early stop is equal to early stopping and what we're going to be moderating here is validation loss
and I recommend to have a little higher patients when it comes to recurrent know networks.
Obviously there's no right answer here you can always play around with this but I'll go ahead and say
just wait for two epochs then we want to fit the model to the generator and let the early stopping dictate
how long we're actually going to train for.
So we'll say model that fit to a generator passing that training generator created to some arbitrarily
kind of high number of epochs the validation data should be linked to your validation generator and
then finally don't forget your callbacks list to make sure we actually implement the early stop.
So let's go ahead and run this.
I'm going to comment out that previous cell to make sure we don't get any typos here run that.
OK so now it's fitting to the generator in the solutions notebook.
We went ahead and the only difference that we've done so far is we called the Ellis TAM to use an activation
unit of recurrent rectified linear units.
Here I'm just using the default which is the hyperbolic tangent I believe if we do shift type here it'll
tell us.
But what we're going to do is we'll fast forward into the future until this is done training on whatever
epochs are dictated by early stop.
So let me hop forward into the future until this is done training.
All right.
This is finished training for me.
Train pretty fast once and for epochs depending on the activation functions in the number of neurons
you choose.
It may take longer but we'll go going to just plot our losses so let's go ahead and do that.
We'll say loss is equal to PD.
Data frame model our history the history and then say Lost Plot.
Run that and we can see here that it looks like our training loss was starting to go down more but our
validation lost was starting to peak and due to our patients value instead of just stopping training
they're okay.
The next step is to evaluate on our test data.
So we're going to forecast predictions into the test data range and that may be slightly different depending
on what you chose.
But recall that our test data set if we come back up here they should actually be 24 months.
So we come back up here and we decided that the test length was 24 months.
So let's go ahead and do that and we'll type out here we'll be the following and I'll I'll do this by
hand because this is probably the trickiest part to understand that the entire lecture.
The rest is pretty straightforward.
Once you get used to it.
But I sit an empty holder for my test predictions.
Let me comment that that cell so we get a bunch of room here and create an empty cell.
Okay so first thing I wanna keep track my test predictions and then the next idea is I have to figure
out what does the first evaluation batch look like.
So what do I first pass in to my model and say hey give me one month into the future.
Well that should be the very last possible batch in my scale the training set.
So I'll be scaled training data minus the length of my batch all the way to the end.
So for example if I was predicting if my model took in 24 months to predict the 25th month one month
into the future then this would be the last 24 months of my training data so that the next month is
the first point in my test data.
So there's my first evaluation batch and I'll set it to my current batch.
The one thing I need to make sure to do is to make sure it's in the correct shape.
So that's first evaluation batch reshaped to the following and we pass on a tuple here.
Notice the double parentheses.
It's just one time series per batch so it's essentially batch size by the length which in our case was
that 18 months and then the number of features is just one.
And if you want to play around the batch size this one would be batch size.
So that's what this represents.
Then we have for I in range length of test because we're only forecasting onto the test set.
Then I need to get a prediction one timestamp ahead.
So I'll tell my model go ahead and predict based off the current batch information at the very first
pass.
That's essentially saying hey given the last 24 months of the training data what does the first month
of the test data look like.
And to get the first month the test data because the way the formatting works out and the way it returns
it we index just zero there.
And you can print these out in case you're ever confused.
So say my current prediction is this.
So I would recommend that if this is still confusing you just go ahead and put a bunch of print statements
here print out the entire prediction and just do a range of one.
See what happens in one loop OK then I want to store that prediction.
So I say my test predictions go ahead and append my current prediction.
And then finally I need to update my current batch to now drop that very first value and then add in
the current prediction value.
So now my current batch is essentially moving one month into the future so I'll say N.P. append and
this is essentially where the NUM pi indexing gets a little tricky so explain it one more time for you.
So it's a three dimensional object where we have batch size by length by number of features the batch
size is actually changing.
So we'll say grab everything from the entire batch because it's just one time series comma and then
for the length I want to say grab everything but index zero because that's essentially what I'm dropping.
So I say one colon and then the number of features hasn't changed.
So just grab everything there.
And then what I'm going to do here is I want to append my current prediction so say current prediction.
And the reason I pass it with these double set of brackets is to make sure the dimensions make sense
for where I'm actually inserting it and I need to insert it in index one here of my shape.
So we'll say axes is equal to 1.
OK.
So this part of the hardest line to understand but really it's just reaching into the NUM pi array and
make sure that the dimensions lineup we're not editing the batch we're not adding the features or editing
the shape at index 1 which is this guy right here and we say 1 colon because I drop that very first
item in my true train data and then I append then my current prediction.
All right.
So that's my current batch and that's actually it for the loop so we'll go in and delete these spare
lines and let's run this make sure I didn't commit any typos and whips we for actually forgot to important
umpire.
So we'll do that as well.
Important I'm pi as MP now we'll run it and there we have it.
Okay so we can see your test predictions.
Recall there a text our test predictions are still scaled.
So we need to inverse transform them.
So we'll go ahead and do that.
We'll say scalar that inverse transform our test predictions and then I'll call these my true predictions
so they are my true predictions.
And let's append that to our original test data frame by creating a new column called predictions is
equal to true predictions.
You may get a warning here again.
You can ignore it.
So if we insert one more cell below and then take a look at test I now have my true production numbers
against my predictions.
Okay so my predictions.
It looks like more or less they're getting the same trend but these look like they're pretty noisy.
So let's see how well we actually performed here.
So we'll come back will plot our true predictions versus our true test values here.
So we'll say test the plot run that and it looks like our predictions are not really matching up that
well to our production.
So we also want to calculate our route mean squared error.
Let's do this.
So how do how can we actually do this.
We simply say from S.K. learn that metrics import mean squared error and then you can say the mean squared
error.
Compare your production versus your predictions.
That's the mean square there.
So the route means quarter would be NDP obscurity run that.
And so right now I mean square is twenty nine units and you can check out the units by coming up here
and seeing what the actual units are in.
OK.
So is this a good enough model in our case just visually we can see that the model's not really good.
So what can we begin to do to try to fix this model.
Well there's lots of different options.
If we come back up here to edit our model itself so won't thing we can do is we can edit the activation
function in other thing we can do is edit the amount of Ellis time units so maybe we the side page one
hundred units isn't enough to basically grab this behavior especially since we're trying to predict
24 months to the future.
Now that's another thing can edit.
So coming back up here maybe using an entire set of twenty four is just too much.
It's trying to predict two years into the future each time.
So maybe decide to change that to 18 for a test size and that's what's really nice about using these
variables is you can easily start playing around to your data so you decide I'll change my test size
to 18 and then to make sure that's correct when I'm actually choosing my validation generator.
I'll have to edit this because right now if we take a look at the size of the test set it's also equal
to 18.
So maybe I just choose 12 as my length here.
And so what I'm going to do is I set my test size the last 18 months and my batch size is now twelve
months.
And so what I can do is I can start rerunning all these and maybe add in some more Ellis time units
if I think that will help.
So maybe add one to 50.
Keep in mind too many neurons you're going to be over to the data.
So there's another value can play around with maybe 150 is too much et cetera.
So let's just go ahead and see if those things fix it.
Again this isn't part of the actual exercise this is just me exploring further and trying to show you
what you do in real life.
The thing is you can play around with an edit to try to improve your performance.
And luckily we already have this metric that I can improve on so I can see visually and my grabbing
that seasonality.
It looks like the seasonality is being obtained to some degree.
And now what I want to make sure is that I obtain that seasonality behavior and try to reduce this number.
So a perfect fit would have zero here as a root means squared error.
So let's do this.
I'm going to basically run all these changes so I'll change my test size to something smaller essentially
allowing my model to have more data to train on and then we'll scale everything the time series generator.
What I'm going to do is I set my batch now just to one year and this is pretty much the absolute smallest
I can make this.
So we'll go ahead and keep it as 12 if I try to make it smaller that I'm not grabbing really that full
year information of seasonality.
We'll recreate our model.
See if adding more neurons helps.
Notice that curious actually updating and saying hey this is the next model you're creating redefine
our validation generator we still have our early stopping and let's go ahead and try this again and
see if this works.
So I'll fast forward on time until the second attempt works.
OK.
So what's interesting here is even if more neurons that only needed three epochs of fit said something
that's interesting.
Let's go ahead and plot out the loss.
Check out that behavior.
And here we have it.
So there's our validation loss and may even be worth trying to increase that patients because it's not
clear to me that that validation loss was going to keep going down or keep going up.
So that's something you can also play around with.
Maybe we're actually not training for enough epochs on this.
So now it's time to evaluate our test data.
We'll go and just run the same series and we can see here production predictions.
Notice the actual values have not changed because now my entire test length isn't as large.
I'm only doing 18 months instead of 24 months.
And now let's go ahead and do the test plot and now it looks like we're fitting much better to the data
still not definitely perfect.
We can't actually grab that little spike trend that looks to be repeating.
It's kind of too smooth right now.
But let's go into Keckley.
Our means squared error.
I'll rerun these cells.
Keep in mind our previous value was twenty nine.
So if we get lower we improved on it and now we get seven.
So a major improvement.
Again the things that I changed were I gave my data more or excuse me I gave my model more data to train
on by decreasing the length of that test set and I gave the model more neurons to have available to
it.
So at 150 another thing we can do is kind of retrain everything but see if we give it more patients
because it's kind of surprising that with three epochs that's all I need for training given the sort
of lost chart.
Now maybe the case that validation loss ends up spiking beyond this but it's worth actually exploring
that with more patients.
Main thing I want to clarify for you is there's still a lot more you can do to improve your models.
So if you get kind of a crappy fit the first time around you can always play around with a lot more
such as the length of the test set the number of neurons in your Elyse Tam layer the patients in your
early stopping et cetera to see how you can continually improve your fit and for time series information.
I would always encourage you to do both a visual check and a quantitative check such as Ruby square.
I hope that helps you.
And I will see you in the next section of the course.