Welcome back everyone to part two or second phase of the Care's regression coda long project.
You've already taken a look at the features then a little bit of feature engineering and even dropped
some features.
Now it's time to scale along for train test split and then create a model and train the model.
Let's get started.
OK after we finish all our feature engineering the next step is to separate our features from our label.
We can do this by assigning X to D F drop price along axes equal to one and then the other thing we're
going to do is say Y is equal to the F price and to make sure there's no issues between the Pansies
data types and the NUM pine Americas.
We can also just request the values.
So if you say that values this returns back then umpiring underneath the actual data frames at risk
panel series.
So you run those and now that we have separator features from our label it's time to do a train test
split.
We will say from S.K. learn that model selection import a train test split run that and the way I like
to do this to save myself a little bit of typing time is just grab the example from the dock string
and copy and paste it in here.
So we'll just go ahead and grab that copy at paste it in.
I would encourage you to do the same.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to set my test size to just be 30 percent and I'll also set my
random state to be 1 0 1 again arbitrary no choice.
It's just that we're consistent across the notebook.
So go ahead and use the same random stay.
I do that way you can compare your results directly.
OK so we'll go ahead and run this.
We've done our split.
Now it's time to actually perform the scaling.
Remember we want to do the scaling post split.
That way we only fit to the training set to prevent data leakage from the test set.
We'll do this just as we've done before by saying SDK learn that pre processing import min max scalar
you can technically use any scaling you like.
But min max scalar it's simpler to understand.
So we'll use it in this case min max scalar and then we will redefine our training set as the scaled
versions and I can save a little bit of time by both fitting and transforming all my training set in
one step.
So previously we saw fit and transform in two steps but scaling actually has this convenience fixture
feature of transforming it and fitting at one step.
So we'll go ahead do that and then forward the test set recall here we're just going to transform we
don't fit to our test set because we don't want to assume prior information about our test set so there's
a training set and there's a test set.
Now they've been scaled.
Coming up next we're gonna do is actually create the model.
So we'll do the following we'll say from tensor flow that care stop models import sequential and then
we'll also say from tensor flow that carries dot layers import.
And we're going to import dense layer.
So we run that and let's create our model so we create a sequential model.
And typically what we do is we try to base the number of neurons or units in our layers from the size
of the actual feature data.
So let's take a quick look at the shape of our data.
So it looks like we have 19 incoming features and that's probably a good range to then have 19 neurons
in our layer.
So same model add dense 19 and we'll also say that the activation layer will be a rectified linear unit.
Now let's make sure we actually spell this correctly sequential.
Now something that we're going to explore later on is to see how we can use early stopping in order
to try to choose the correct number of epochs to train for but also to try to choose the correct number
of layers to train for for right now though I'm just going to copy and paste this line a couple of times
to add in and make this a deep learning network.
Now this may be overkill and we may end up over fitting slightly to training data but we'll be able
to explore whether or not that's happening by passing in validation data along for our training.
So what I will do here is add one more final layer and this last final layer just gonna have one neuron
as its output since that's going to be directly outputting our predicted price.
And then we are going to compile this model and previously in the theory sections of these lectures
we went ahead and talked about atom optimizer being a good optimizer so we'll choose it by passing the
string code atom.
And since this is a regression problem we're choosing a continuous label such as price we'll go ahead
and choose our lost metric as mean squared error.
Okay so we go ahead and run that and now it's time to train the model we'll say model that fit.
And then what I'm going to pass here is my training data just as we've done before.
So X train and then Y train and the next thing going to do is also pass in validation data reduce shift
tab here you'll notice that you can pass in the data to train on x and y and you can also passin validation
data.
And what that means is after each epoch of training on the training data will quickly run the test data
and check our loss on the test data.
So that way we can keep a tracking of how well performing not just on our training data but also on
our test data.
Keep in mind this test data will not actually affect the weights or biases of our network.
So cares isn't going to update your model based off the test data or validation data.
Instead it will only use the training data as it's updating the weights and biases and continue to essentially
check how well it's doing and not just the training data but also the validation data and the will we
pass this in is by saying validation data is equal to and then we pass in our values here.
So we're going to say X test and then Y test and we want to make sure that we actually consider the
values here.
So something to make sure of is a call called values here because tensor flow may complain if you don't
pass in a numeric array because it can't work with Pan this series or data frames that well.
So make sure you've done the values and again what we're doing here is we're training on X train y train
but as we go along we want to be checking against our test set and that will give us some nice plots
to basically realize whether or not we're overfishing.
So add in the validation data.
And finally because it's a larger data set we're going to feed in our data in batches and we're gonna
call batch size of one hundred and twenty eight.
It's very typical to do batch sizes in powers of two so 64 128 256 the smaller the batch size.
The longer training is going to take but the less likely you're going to over fit to your data because
you're not passing in your entire training set at once.
Instead you're focusing on these smaller batches and then fine let's go ahead and choose kind of an
arbitrary large number of epochs.
So a four hundred.
We don't have any early stopping mechanisms yet.
We'll learn about those later on in the course but right now we'll do 400.
That way I can see those nice curves and also compare my training performance to my test performance.
So go ahead and run this and hopefully if you've done everything correctly you should be getting to
see the output if you get some sort of error code here.
Make sure you reference our notebook you can go ahead and run our notebook directly in order to prevent
any simple typos errors.
OK so this is training on our data set right now coming up in the next lecture we'll go ahead and finish
his training so kind of fast forward through this and then we'll start evaluating on our test data set
as well as predict on brand new data.
So again always in this lecture is we've scaled our data after doing the train test split created our
model and then kind of the new thing that we saw here is adding in validation data during the fitting
as well as choosing a batch size.
Ok thanks I'll see you at the next lecture.