Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to focus on creating the actual model for the congressional neural network
on these custom images.
And the model is going to be fitting to a generator.
Let's get started.
OK.
Here we are in the notebook where we left off last time.
Let's get to creating our model.
We'll say from tensor flow thought carris stop models.
And just as we did before we're going to import sequential and then we'll say from tensor flow that
carries that layers import.
And we're going to do is we're going to import a dense layer.
This is for the very end plus we can add some dense layers after a conversational layers go ahead and
import compositional layers that's come to D.
And then we'll also import our pulling layers.
So there's Max Poole a common point of confusion for students is what's different scene Max Poole versus
Max pooling.
They're actually the same thing.
And you can check this out if you go to the 10th floor documentation you'll notice a lot of these classes
have subsections called aliases which basically means there's multiple names for the same function call.
So just keep that in mind.
It's really common almost like an issue with tensor flow that is the fact that it has so many versions
that there's a lot of aliases for the same thing even within something like Charisse.
So we have both Max Poole and Max pulling too.
They're actually the exact same thing so we're going to say dense compositional to the max pulling to
the end because it's going to be a bit of a larger network.
Let's also add in the drop out so it can prevent over fitting hopefully we'll say model sequential and
now it's going to be time to add in compositional layers.
So what I'm going to do is set up a base compositional layer so we first say conditional to the.
And then we're going to decide to have a 32 filters here and I'll choose a smaller kernel size something
like three by three.
And then the input shape and this becomes very important the input shapes should be equal to the input
shape we defined earlier.
So input shape is going to be equal to the image shape that we defined.
So recall earlier we define the image shape based off the average size of these images.
And that's what was up here is 130 by 130 by three.
And this is something you can play around with.
Keep in mind if you choose an image shape that's too large especially if you're dealing with extremely
large files.
You may run out of memory on your computer.
Again that's too dependent on your hardware.
OK so one third about 130 those aren't too bad.
So we'll going to keep image shape there their analysts choose activation function we'll say activation
is equal to rectified linear unit and then after that we will add in our pooling layer.
So Max pull to the.
And we'll just go ahead and keep the default pool size just so we can see it so we can keep it in mind.
It's two by two.
So let's go ahead and add in a couple more compositional errors.
The larger the image sizes and the more complex of a task you're dealing with the more competition layers
that you should probably have.
And there's a link for you in the notebook.
So if you check out our deep learning notebook and scroll down there's a link here to a really nice
explanatory post on different rules for selecting the number of neurons and number of filters and conversational
layers.
So definitely check out that explanatory post.
OK so the one thing going to edit here is as we get deeper in this network I'm going to create more
filters so have these two kind of inside hidden compositional layers up 64 filters each.
Then after this we will flatten out our models so we'll say go ahead and flatten this out.
Add in our flatten layer and it looks like I forgot to import it.
So let me do that as well.
So we'll say flatten import that and then I can call flat in here.
So that flattens it out for our dense layer.
So we'll say model add thence go four hundred twenty eight neurons and we'll say our activation is equal
to rectified linear unit something I want to point out and you may see this as you explore more complex
compositional models.
You can do a lot of exploring online to see how other people kind of attack different datasets with
different images at different sizes you may see some people add in the activation after dance.
So in other kind of Alias you can do and I'll come back here to show you is in our notebook.
There's essentially an example of doing this in two steps where it's you add the dance and then add
the activation function after the dance layer.
That's the exact same thing as what we did here which is just calling it inside of the dance.
So it's up to you one you want to use and then we're going to do here as well is will add in our drop
out.
We're gonna turn off half the neurons randomly to prevent overfishing.
After that we have our final dense layer.
So say that's one and then say model and lips.
You can add in the sigmoid function or just say here activation is equal to sigmoid.
We also show the alternative method here which is adding it after the fact.
Either one.
Totally OK so we have dense activation sigmoid.
Last thing I want to show you is the compiling of the model we'll say compile the model loss see binary
classification problem.
So it should be binary cross entropy and then our optimizer will be atom and optionally if we want to
check out the metrics we can say metrics is equal to accuracy run that makes sure we have no errors.
OK.
Looks like our model is working.
Go ahead and check out a model summary so call summary on your model and you can see the different layers
and you can see the different parameters per layer notice that we have a ton of parameters by the time
we get to the dense layer.
So this model will take a long time to train to make sure we can pick the right amount of epochs to
train for we can say from tensor flow dark stock callbacks import early stopping and then create just
as we did before and early stopping callback.
We'll do this based off monitoring validation loss and we can have a patients of one or two epochs.
That's something you can play around as well.
Okay so that's creating the model for training the model we have to select a batch size so we'll go
ahead and train on that size of 16 images at a time.
So it's pretty typical again to choose something in the power of two so two to the power of two is four
four to the power of two is then 16 and the larger your hardware the larger the batch size you can probably
reasonably choose the smaller the batch size the longer the train time takes because you're fitting
in less images at a time.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create two generators just as we did before and the generators
will say train image generator is going to be one of them and then the other one we're going to do is
a test image generator.
This is gonna be very similar.
The only difference going to be the source of their data and we already went through this on the flow
from directory.
Now we need to put in the training path and there's a couple other parameters we're going to state here.
So we have to also state is beyond the directory which we already have a training path is the target
size.
So what is our target size.
Notice the target size just cares about width and height.
So what we do is we say that our target size is equal to the image shape that we defined earlier.
So just to remind you the image shape from earlier is 130 by one three by three.
I really only care about those first two dimensions so let's call in two to get one 30 by one 30.
So that's why I'm gonna pass in here.
I could do this manually or I can kind of set it off that variable Next I need to make sure my color
mode is correct so since I'm dealing of color images my color mode is red green blue.
If we come down here we can see the different parameters.
So it's either gonna be grayscale or red green blue or four for some reason dealing with an alpha channel
as well.
Alpha is transparency.
You can pass an R GPA.
OK so there is our color mode last couple of things we want to set.
Here are the batch size so the batch size equal the batch size and then the class mode is going to be
binary because it's binary classification.
I'm essentially going to copy this and then paste it for my test image generator.
Go ahead and run the first generator.
That one's ready to go.
The things I need to change here is the test path should be for the test images.
And you'll notice that one of the parameters here is this shuffle call.
So shuffling essentially shuffles your data before it kind of makes this random batch of data points
for you during training.
You should be shuffling your data.
However when you're generating for the test set you don't actually need to shuffle.
In fact you shouldn't be shuffling otherwise your labels will get shuffled around from your actual feature
points.
So we want to say shuffle is equal to False when running and test data.
OK so that's our training image generator and our test image generator and what we can do is now take
a look at these objects.
So for example our training image generator and we can say class indices and it reports back that 0
belongs to the parasite one belongs to uninfected and then we're going to do here is we can say my resulting
model or results is equal to the model that fit generator we pass in our training image generator pass
and some number of epochs can choose a larger one here because we're going to do is pass in our validation
set that's the test image generator and then the callbacks will be equal to early stop.
So we can go ahead and run that and then that should be in training.
Keep in mind this is going to take a long time to train.
So what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to interrupt my colonel and we actually already have a
file for you underneath compositional neural networks.
We have a malaria the texture the H5 file.
Let's go ahead and load data to save some time so you can if you want to bring your own model especially
if it's different than the one that we find that our notebook or what you can do is say from tensor
flow that Harris not models.
Import load model and what we can go ahead and do is say model is equal to load model and then pass
in malaria detector.
I would highly encourage this especially if you're running this on a kind of simpler hardware computer.
Go ahead and load in that model and to confirm that the model worked.
Same model summary you should see something that essentially looks like that's the model we just created.
Except what's nice is this model has been fully trained.
Something to note here is if you do decide to load our model what is not going to be available to you
is the models training history.
So if we try tried model history the history is going to say it can't find it because it doesn't actually
have it.
That's because you loaded the model and this is just saving the train the model.
It's not saving the history of the training model.
Keep in mind you can optionally save the model history if you really want to.
So if you just google search save model history Charisse basically hit this first link.
There's code here on how to actually essentially save this as a pickle file.
The actual history of the training but the reason we didn't save it is because we actually show you
the history of the model.
If you come to our provide a notebook and scroll down we will actually show you kind of the history
here of loss validation plot so you can essentially just see the history of the training here and this
is the model that we saved for you.
If for some reason you want to evaluate the model on the test data that should still work.
You could say model evaluate generator and then pass the test image generator run that and you should
get similar results as what we're about to get.
Keep in mind depending on the actual shuffling of the training data and the random initialization this
could look slightly differently from what we have here.
But overall you should get something in this range.
If we say model dot metrics names it's loss and accuracy your accuracy should be somewhere between like
eighty five and ninety five percent which is pretty good considering that base accuracy is 50 percent.
Okay so we'll go ahead and load the model since we don't want to kind of spend all this time retraining
the model that we already provided for you.
If you are interested in the actual history of this thought H5 file you can check it out in the actual
provided notebook.
Here we actually show the full history of that training of that model.
OK so there's the model for you coming up next we're going to basically talk more about evolving the
model not just the history but predicting on your images classification reports et cetera.
We'll see you at the next lecture.