Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we'll be discussing the very basics of the auto encoder network architecture so the
auto encoder is actually a very simple neural network and we'll feel very similar to the multilayer
perception models that we built during the artificial neural network section of the course.
And the main idea is that an auto encoder is designed to simply reproduce its input at the output layer
so that means that the key difference between an auto encoder and the typical MLP multilayer perception
or artificial neural network is that the number of input neurons will actually be equal to the exact
same number of output neurons typically in our use cases.
We've been either having the output be equal to the certain number of classes were classified four or
equal to one neuron.
If we're dealing with a continuous output however in kind of a strange case here for that I don't coder
the number of input neurons is exactly equal to the number of output neurons.
Let's explore what this actually looks like and why we would even want to build a network this way.
Here we can see an example auto encoder.
Notice the shape we start with five neurons and then we slowly reduces down to a certain specified number
of neurons throughout the hidden layers.
So you go from five to three to two and the main idea here is right in the middle of your auto encoder
you're going to reduce to some desired amounts of neurons essentially trying to capture what information
is important.
And then in the second half of the auto encoder essentially the decoding part you expand this back out
to equal the same number of neurons that you started with.
So we go from five to three to two and then back out to three to five again.
So we start at five and then after going through the entire auto encoder we actually end up back at
five so when we walk through these layers and explain this basic idea and to simplify this even further
let's imagine that we just have a single hidden layer to go directly 5 to 2 to 5 so the idea here is
that in order to produce the same output at the final layer that internal hidden layer or specifically
the internal multiple hidden layers for a real auto encoder example those hidden layers must actually
learn what features are important.
And this kind of extreme example basically shows you that in order for this input to be reproduced as
output those two neurons in the hidden layer they're going to have to learn which inputs are actually
important in order to reproduce the output.
So they're reducing the amount of dimensions from five to two.
So again here we see a design of five dimensions reduced to two dimensions and then expand that back
out to the original five.
Notice my use of the word dimensions.
I'm actually saying the word features here OK.
So again the feed for network trained to produce its input at the output layer is all an auto encoder
is we have some input goes and gets reduced to a hidden layer in the middle and then expand it back
out to the outputs the output size again is the same as the input layer and that hidden representation
in the middle.
Attempts to maintain the important input information before being decoded or expand that backup.
And then later on we'll see how we can actually take advantage of that hidden layer to extract meaningful
insights.
So when we do things like dimensionality reduction we'll actually be able to train a full auto coder
and then split it in half and directly extract results from that middle hidden layer.
But the full auto encoder is actually inputs shrunken down to hidden and then expanded back out outputs
so this idea is actually extremely similar to principal component analysis.
We are trying to reduce the dimensionality into a few principal components and keep in mind we can explore
stack auto encoders if more hidden layers will actually be doing this ourselves throughout the exercise.
Notebooks now a really important note.
A lot of students get confused by this term reduction in dimensionality.
Keep in mind those hidden layers is not simply sub selecting only certain features so it's not like
you start off with 10 features and then choose eight of those 10 to continue on with what you're actually
doing is you're calculating combinations of the original features to represent the original data in
a reduced dimensional space.
So again you're not sub selecting features you're actually taking a little bit of all the features some
percent depending on the way the auto coders train.
So for example you make take 5 percent of feature 1 maybe 10 percent of feature 2 et cetera and you
decide how important is each feature as you slowly reduce this dimensionality down and then that hopefully
that hidden layer in the middle is going to learn which features are the most important and how to organize
them in a way to reduce the dimensionality and then to check if it's working or not.
We decode or expand the spec out to the output layer.
So again we're not sub selecting only certain features so what is sexual look like in practice.
Well later on in the next series of lectures we're going to explore how we can actually use an auto
encoder.
Split it up into two parts a encoder and a decoder to perform dimensionality reduction.
So we'll be able to actually take a three dimensional data set and then reduce it down to either 2 or
even 1 dimensions.
So notice here we have these two clusters and we're actually able to map them to a lower dimensionality
space or lower dimensional space and still maintain that separation in this particular use case of going
down from 3 to 2.
That may not look actually very useful to you.
However you can imagine that we've been dealing with datasets that are much much larger than just three
features.
So if you have a dataset that is maybe 20 or 30 features something very large you can visualize 20 or
30 features because we can only visualize three dimensional space but which could do is reduce those
20 or 30 features into some lower dimensional space like 2D or 3D and then visualize that.
And then that will you to see just how clearly separated those classes are.
Here we can see that in three dimensions yellow and purple here have clear separation and that clear
separation is maintained as we reduce this down dimensionality wise.
You can imagine that if we start off with a high high dimension dataset that was too highly dimensional
to visualize we could reduce this down to 3 the or to the and then visualize the classes and see just
how separable our dataset is and then later on we'll see how we can apply this to just reveal hidden
insights from our data.
So the main idea behind an Auto encoder is the center hidden layer reduce the dimensionality to learn
the most important combinations of original features and we're gonna see two applications of the auto
encoder and they both use an auto encoder but use them in very different ways which is why this is such
an interesting network architecture because even though you have the same network architecture of inputs
being reduced and then matching the output size you can use them in a wide variety of tasks.
So we're gonna split to use cases.
One is the more obvious use case of dimensionality reduction where you essentially after training an
auto encoder split it in half and just extract the hidden layer outputs and then the second use case.
There's a really interesting one for noise removal.
You'll actually have that hidden layer essentially learn how to filter out noise when reproducing the
output.
OK so both of these use out encoders but these are really different ways and they're super interesting.
Problem sets.
So let's go ahead and in the next lecture learn how we can detach an auto encoder into two separate
components in order to perform dimensionality reduction.
I'll see it there.