Welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to be discussing the very basics of an umpire array which is our main data
structure when working of nun pie and data sets and general so let's talk about how to create arrays.
We'll discuss how to convert existing objects to an empire such as a normal Python list to an umpire.
Then we'll show you some built in umpire functions to quickly generate useful arrays.
Then we'll talk about creating arrays and matrices of random values often in data science a machine
learning.
We need to quickly create random values in a certain shape and then Pi has a lot of tools for that.
Then we'll talk about some very basic array attributes such as data types and shapes.
Let's get started.
Okay.
Here I am at my Jupiter notebook to begin using the PI.
We want to import it.
So we will say import num pi and then by convention we import on pi as N P.
Be careful of the spelling of pi.
Sometimes students get confused with capital ends a capital piece.
Everything here should just be lowercase d stylized convention of capitalizing the end and the P is
just for style izing in the actual naming of the library for things like documentation that when we
import it you can import num pies and P let's first discuss how we actually create an umpire.
So an umpire rays are essentially the main way we're gonna be using an umpire throughout this course.
Now as discussed we can have a normal Python list and here I can create one.
Just my list.
One two three.
And if I want to have this or cast it as an umpire a I can call the function and P array and then pass
in my list object.
And you'll notice now when it's displayed in the notes that it's an umpire.
By having array at the front of this I can also do the same with a nested list.
So go ahead and say nested list is equal to.
I'm going to create a list of lists so we'll have 1 2 as the first object there.
Then 3 4 and then 5 6.
So notice here if I were to ask for my nested list back and just run this I just get back this list.
But if I were to then transform this into a num pi array none PI will actually begin to keep in mind
the shape of what's being passed then and it's going to format this as what is essentially a two the
matrix of three rows by two columns.
And we can see the actual dimensions here by the number of brackets or braces at the beginning and at
the end.
So this essentially indicates we're dealing with a two dimensional object.
Now typically we're not gonna be just transforming normal Python objects to an umpire.
Instead there's lots of useful built in ways to generate arrays.
So let's cover a few of those.
One way is to use and P arrange which is similar to num PIs built in range function so you can say NPR
arrange it only has one hour here and then what we can do is if you do shift tab we'll tell you how
it works.
Essentially the same way as Python's built in range object where you have a starting point a stopping
point and then an optional step size.
So for example if we wanted all the integers between 0 and then up to but not including 10 we can say
010 and that will give us starting at 10 go all the way up to but not including 10.
So we see the numbers zero all the way to nine here.
So keep that in mind.
This stopping point is up to but not including it then we can also have an optional step size.
So by default the step size is 1.
So just go from one integer to the next in a step size of 1.
But it can changes to be a step size of 2 which is kind of a quick way to get all the even numbers.
So can they 0 2 4 6 8.
And if for some reason I wanted to continue past this and actually get 10 in there then I would say
go up to not including eleven rerun this and now it includes 10.
So we have our STARTING POINT our stopping point which goes up to but not including the stop point at
an optional step size parameter next often is the case and data science machine learning that we want
to quickly create arrays of just a bunch of zeros or ones and to do this again number Pi has a built
in convenience function called zeros and zeros if you just pass in one number such as three returns
a vector of three zeros.
Something to keep in mind here is you'll notice that it says zero point which essentially essentially
indicates that these zeros are floating point numbers and often when you're working with NUM pi and
then later on we'll learn about pandas.
Things are going to be automatically converted to floating point precision numbers instead of being
kept us integers.
One of the few techniques we're gonna be learning about for keeping things and integers is this epic
range pretty much all the other functions we learn about will convert things to floating point numbers.
So we have NDP zeros.
If you pass on a single number it gives you kind of this one the vector of just those three zeros but
you can also say and P zeros and then pass in a shape.
So if we do shift type here.
Notice that they'll say What's the shape you want.
So we can say something like give me a four by four matrix.
And here we have again four rose by four columns all of zeros.
Or I can begin to edit this and we'll see that the second dimension.
So if I say four by ten lines up with the number of columns.
So it's how many rows you want.
By how many columns you want to hear we have four rows of ten columns of all zeros.
And if you really want these zeros to be integers you can begin to edit this data type parameter so
you can say these type is equal to I.A..
If you really wanted these to be integers for pretty much all use cases we won't really have to worry
about integers versus floating point numbers so we'll close that out so we know we know end p zeros.
And similarly there's NDP ones which is just NDP ones and you can say NDP ones 3 which gives you a 1
the vector of just a bunch of ones or you can also pass in a shape such as four by four.
And there's my four by four.
Notice the sets of double parentheses here.
This is essentially indicating that in passing in as my first argument a parameter of a tuple and then
these outside parentheses are for the actual function call itself next we have Lynne space which is
a useful function which returns evenly spaced numbers over a specified interval not to be confused with
what NPR range is doing which is setting a starting point a stopping point and then taking some arbitrary
step size and peeling space instead.
The way it works is we say MP Lynn space we give it a starting point and a stopping point but then we
ask for the number of actual elements we want evenly spaced between those two points.
So I can say three here run this and then I'll return back 0 5 10.
So these are three points including zero and ten including the starting point and the stopping point
and it's three points evenly spaced because in between 0 and 5 is five and in between 5 and 10.
Well that's evenly spaced also be five if we asked for more.
So for example let's go ahead and ask for something like 21 evenly spaced points.
We run that and we get back 21 elements going from zero to 10 where the even spacing is zero point five.
So to go from 0 5 the one to one point five etc..
Now something to note here is that literally spaced calls actually include that stop value.
So to obtain an array of what you may refer to as common fractions you may need to increase the number
of items requested.
So often beginners sometimes just go zero to 10.
Give me 20 evenly spaced points and they get these sort of weird fraction calls or weird decimal places
because we're including the stop value we may need to do something like increasing the number of items
requested the twenty one in order to see these common fractions.
So just keep that in mind of NPL in space.
That's because it's actually including the stopping point this time.
Now there's also the capability to create an identity matrix and I didn't see matrix is simply a matrix
of all zeros with a one along the diagonal.
So for example if we say NPD the eye of five it gives us a square five by five matrix with ones along
the diagonal.
And this is really useful for a lot of linear algebra tasks.
The reason we all need to provide one number is because by definition an identity matrix is always square.
OK so those are a couple of built in functions in number pi.
Finally let's show you how to create random arrays.
So there's lots of different functionalities with random and the way we do this is we say NDP not random
dot.
And if you were to hit tab here you notice that there's actually a bunch of different random function
calls that none Pi has available to us.
So many types of random distributions we can call from.
So what we're gonna do is just show you a couple of very basic ones.
There's NDP thought random thought Rand and if you ever are confused over what actual Rand distribution
is returned you can simply do shift tab in the Jupiter notebook expand the documentation and report
back to how it's actually grabbing that distribution of random numbers.
So in this case just the call of R and D or Rand grabs random values from a uniform distribution meaning
everything has the same likelihood of being picked from 0 to 1.
So we'll go ahead and ask for for instance two random numbers and that will give you two random numbers
with a uniform distribution between 0 and 1.
And every time you keep running the cell notice you'll get back different random numbers all between
0 and 1.
Now let's say you actually wanted a matrix so the way this works is you say N.P. random thought Rand.
And then instead of passing a tuple for this one what you can do is pass in two parameters let's say
three rows by four columns run that.
And now we have three rows by four columns all of random numbers between 0 and 1 where all the numbers
change are on 1 had the same likelihood of being picked.
OK so that was a uniform distribution but there's also the capability to grab it from a standard normal
distribution.
And for that we say N P random thought Rand N.
So Rand N is doing the same thing from a standard normal distribution.
A standard normal distribution.
Essentially just means that the mean is zero and the variance is 1.
So that will actually allow us to then get some negative numbers if we do this.
So say I wanted five by five run this.
And here we have some negative numbers.
And this is a standard normal distribution.
It's centered around zero 4 variance of 1.
Okay.
So we can actually grab random integers by saying N.P. thought random thought Rand I.A. and the way
this works is we provide a low and the high and then optionally you can request a size.
Keep in mind the lowest inclusive meaning the low has a chance of being picked and the highs exclusive.
So the high will not have a chance of being picked.
So let's go ahead and say we wanted to actually make some random values to try to simulate people's
ages so we could say something like from one to one.
Go ahead and give me a random number.
And this is one way we could then generate random ages.
So this person then is 56 years old and let's say we wanted to quickly generate 10 random ages.
The second parameter is just how many we want.
So you can ask for 10 and there's are 1 the vector.
Keep in mind there's actually a size requested so we could say something like give me two by three as
a tuple run that and it would kind of structure it out that way two rows by three columns.
So that is Rand I.A..
Now you may be wondering what if I actually want to do some sort of ran the numbers but have reproducibility.
So every time I run this notebook or run this piece of code I end up generating the same random numbers.
Well that's where a random seed can come into use.
So what I'm going to show you is N.P. that random dot seed and the seed allows you to just pass forth
an arbitrary number choice.
So the actual number choice isn't that important the fact that's important is that you choose the same
number every time.
So let's say I want you to generate the same round the numbers on your computer that I'm about to generate
on mine.
All we can do is choose the same seed value.
So I'll choose the seed value of forty two and you can go ahead and type that in and in the same cell.
Let's go ahead and say N.P. thought random thought Rand and then just let's say I want four random numbers.
We run this.
And if you ran this the exact same way I did with the seed call and the random call in the same cell
then you should see the exact same four random numbers.
This is going to be really important later on in the course because while we do want some elements of
randomness in many of our functions and data science a machine learning such as a random test train
split.
We want to make sure for reproducibility sake that your random splits and random values are going to
be the same as I show in this notebook.
And in order to do that we'll be using this seed.
Now a question I often get from students is what's the meaning of this.
Number 42 and it's basically just the arbitrary choice you use to seed what's known as a mercy and twister
which is a way of generating these kind of pseudo random values.
You can check out the reference link in the notebook for more information on that seed.
But in our use cases basically we're just going to be using the same seed values as our choice.
Now something to keep in mind is if I grab N.P. random thought Rand and then ask for this in another
cell rerun this I will get now a different set of values than what I did up here.
And that's because this is the second call after setting my seed.
However I keep running these two.
They'll always give me the same random values so often what I would say is try to make sure that your
generation of the random numbers is occurring in the same cell as your actual seed value.
That way you don't actually run the cell multiple times and you can see here on the fifth one is going
to give you something different on the sixth one is gonna give you something different et cetera.
So keep in mind if you want to reset your seed just go ahead and run that and then we'll kind of repeat
that cycle.
OK.
So that's the seed.
Finally I want to show you just a couple of useful array attributes and methods.
So often what we can do is we can reshape a one day vector to any matrix shape we want.
So let me go ahead and create an array.
We'll do this by saying any pure range.
Twenty five.
Go ahead and run this.
And I'm also going to create an array of random values will say ran arrays equal to N.P. random dot
Rand I.A. and this will go from zero to 50.
Let's go ahead and just say 10 here.
So here's my normal array which is just the numbers 0 3 24 and my random array are going to be these
numbers right here.
Keep in mind depending on how you set your seat right now you may have different random values than
I do.
But that's not important for this particular part of the lecture.
OK so let's say I wanted to reshape this array when you create a one the vector.
You can ask for dot shape.
Some actually show you that in a new cell I'm going to say array dot shape and you notice that right
now it only has one dimension defined.
It just says this is essentially twenty five numbers.
What it can do is I can reshape this by saying R or a r reshape and I can reshape this to be five rows
by five columns run that.
And now I take in my original array and reshaped it to be five by five.
Something to note is this doesn't actually affect the original object permanently.
If I ask for array again I still get back the original if I wanted this to be permanent I could simply
just reassign it to array is equal to array that reshape and here we can see the five by five.
Some other things to keep in mind here is that you're not going to be able to reshape the array into
a set of dimensions that doesn't make sense right now.
This is five rows by five columns which means I have twenty five elements total.
If I were to try to reshape that into something like three by six which would only be able to contain
18 elements you will get an error and we'll basically say I cannot reshape something of size twenty
five into a shape of three by six because there's only space for 18 elements.
And here we have twenty five.
So keep that in mind if you ever see that error with the reshape call.
Finally I want to show you the min max an arc Max and arc Min parameters or attributes so we can take
our random array.
Here it is.
And let's say I wanted to figure out what the max value of my array was.
I'll go ahead and just say offer this thought M.A. X open and close parentheses and I'll return back
the max value in the array which happens to be forty three.
In my case.
Now let's say I was actually interested in the location or index location of that max value the way
that works is I say arg.
Max run that and that will give me back the index location.
So the index the second all Python lists starting at 0 so 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
And there's the max value of forty three.
Similarly we can do the same with men.
So I can ask for the minimum value which is 1 and I can also ask for the minimum value location which
in this case is occurring at index 5.
And finally there is the data type attribute.
You can also grab the data type in the array so I can say something like ran R D type run that and I'll
report back.
This is a 32 bit integer or if I were to check some of my other ones for instance let's go ahead and
set this machine a copy and paste this random array here.
So my array run that we can see here that these look to be some sort of floating point I can always
check that by saying what's my data type or D type.
Notice I don't have open and close princes here because that's actually an attribute and will tell me
that these are 64 floating bit numbers.
Okay that's the very basics of no high res generating empire raise both built in functions and random
values as well as things like shape reshape and data type.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.