Welcome everyone to part one of tech generation with Python and Kerry's intensive flow to support part
one we're going to keep things simple we're just going to import the main libraries should have a read
in and import a text file and then we'll focus on understanding the characters in that text file.
Let's open up a new notebook and get started.
All right here I am at the notebook I've already imported num pies and P pansies Beatty and Matt putt
lib.
The last thing going to import which we don't do often so that's why I want to specify it is in putting
tensor flow as TMF Since later on in the notebook will be actually importing stuff directly as TMF Dot.
Okay so step one is to grab the data.
You can check out the notebook that we provide for you.
You can go to Gutenberg dot org to grab any free texts you want from there.
But in our case we're gonna be choosing Shakespeare's works which you've already downloaded for you
and they're actually in the same folder as the MLP notebook.
So there's two main reasons we choose Shakespeare's works.
One is that it's already large corpus of text it's usually recommended to have at least a source of
a million characters to get some sort of real estate generation.
And then second this one's kind of more important is because Shakespeare has a very distinct style.
If you open up some random Shakespeare work you can kind of tell the spacing and style of a play someone
entered someone exits.
The names are capitalized and then there's the phrases of what they say.
So we'll be able to see our recurrent natural network actually duplicate that style just on a character
by character basis.
So I'm going to create a variable called Path to file and go ahead and just write the full file path
to wherever the text file is.
In my case This notebook is actually in the same location as it.
So I used to say Shakespeare the text to go ahead and run that and then let's read it and we'll say
text is equal to open and we'll say have to file and then we'll just read it with mode R and then we
call read okay.
So that will go ahead and if we check out the text let's just see the first five four new characters
in it.
So you notice that it has spaces and it also has these backslash end and that basically stands for a
new line.
So when you print it out it has a very specific style.
So we print this out and we can see these are his sonnets and they're kind of spaced.
So let's go and choose some kind of random go to four thousand five hundred to four thousand let's say
800 and you can see here that clearly there's distinct spacing here.
There's spaces based New Line you line your line some number for your sonnet.
And then the sonnet again.
So the character recurrent neural network there's actually going to be able to learn that and much further
along if we actually start getting to his plays later on in this text Let's actually make this quite
a bit longer say 10000 run that actually make it 140.
There we go.
So we can see this Helena's turn to speak so we can see her texts that she's speaking and if we expand
on this further we get five hundred more characters here you can see King than the King speaks then
Helena speaks again et cetera.
OK so this is actually very well structured.
So we're gonna be using it.
Let's go ahead and take that out and next thing I want to do is understand the unique characters that
are inside this text file.
So to do that.
One quick way to grab all the unique characters is to just cast it into a set and then we can sort that
set.
So if I run this these are all the unique characters and in fact let's go ahead and just assign this
as our vocab so vocab is equal to sort of set text and then we'll say vocab here so we can see there's
new line there's just a space exclamation point.
Some numbers here all capital letters some punctuation and then lowercase letters and then some braces
for probably formatting later on.
Okay so that means we check out the length of our vocab.
There are 84 unique characters that we're going to be working with and we'll have to keep that number
in mind when designing the less dense layer of our neural network.
Okay.
That's it for this step.
Just reading in the text file.
Main thing to note here is that we import a tenth flows TAF and also make sure you provide the correct
path to the file.
We already download Shakespeare that text for you and it's located in the LP folder.
Thanks and we'll see you at step 2 talking about text processing.