Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to discuss pandas series a panda series is very similar to an umpire.
Except for the addition of a named index.
We can use this named index to grab data from the array.
This works really well with real world data where every row is usually associated with some sort of
named index object.
So let's see how this all works with Python and head over to a Jupiter notebook now to begin.
I'm going to import some PI as NDP and by convention we import pandas as PD.
So first we're gonna show you how to create a variety of series using a variety of different based Python
objects.
So first thing to define a couple of things here.
I will define a normal Python list just called labels ABC and then I will say my list is equal to 10
20 30.
In other variable I will create as an umpire.
So say array is equal to empty array and essentially passing that list and then finally also create
a dictionary and dictionary is going to look really similar.
It's gonna have a as a key 10 as a value B as a key 20 has a value and then C as a key and 30 as a value.
So we have these four essentially basic data structures and each of these we can actually convert to
a panda series.
So if we say PD dot series you should be able to then do shift tab after you've already imported pandas
PD and see the general documentation string and the signature.
And while there's a lot going on here the two main things you need to be aware of for a panda series
is the data parameter and the index parameter.
So first let's go ahead and provide data for the series and I can do this by saying data is equal to
and in this case I'll just pass in that normal Python list.
And here we can see the way pandas outputs a series inside of the Jupiter notebook by default the series
is going to have a labeled index.
And if you don't provide an index it will by default show you the numbers starting at 0.
So say 0 1 2.
This is quite similar to essentially what num Pi or even a normal Python list does.
But what it can do and this is basically the difference between a panda series and a normal name pyrite
is that can have a labeled index.
So I can set my index equal to that labels list and now I can see I have a panda series where each row
has a label to it a B and C and later on we will be able to explore that I can still actually identify
the items in my series by their actual integer location.
So essentially now I have two ways of grabbing items based off an index either based off the index name
or based off the index location such as location zero.
So keep in mind I don't actually have to say data equal to or index equal to as long as I provide this
in the correct order.
If I run this notice I get back the exact same results and it's gonna be the same for if you're working
with a vampire.
So you say PD series array you can see that's the same thing and I can also then pass on labels to label
that data.
Now while we usually won't be passing in dictionaries in this fashion if you do have a dictionary with
keys and values you can quickly transform it to a series by running PD that series D later on the course
we're gonna see that the way tensor flow actually returns back a history of losses being able to convert
quickly to a pan the series is gonna be really useful.
So keep this in mind that we will see this later on the course even though throughout the PAN the section
it won't be too common to run this.
Now you've been hearing me say a lot that the key factor of a Panther series is the fact that it has
its labeled index.
So let's go ahead and build out a more complex series.
We'll going to call this sales Q one for maybe first quarter sales and this will be equal to a pan the
series where the data is equal to.
I'm just gonna make up some numbers here.
Two fifty four fifty two hundred one fifty.
And then we'll go ahead and have the index maybe based off some geographical locations so maybe we have
quarterly sales data for different countries like USA China India.
Make sure this is a comma here and let's pass in one more just to make sure the dimensions match up
we'll say Brazil.
So we need basically one index per data point.
So go ahead and run this.
And if I take a look at sales Q1 here we have this sales data.
Now let's go ahead and make this for sales.
Q2 again.
Kind of just going to make up some data here.
We'll change this to sales Q2.
I'll change these numbers around a little bit maybe to sixty five hundred.
Go ahead and just make this let's say 2 10 and 100 now for the index is probably a more important part
that we're actually gonna change.
I'm going to change this last one from Brazil to Japan and I'm going to see sales Q2.
Okay.
Now when we're working with realistic datasets This is essentially the kind of thing we're going to
be working with or we have some sort of named index and then some value or feature corresponding to
it.
Now what I want to show you this I can actually grab information off of the series so because now labeled
index what I can do is let's say I wanted to know the sales in Q2 for China.
It's essentially almost like a dictionary call where I would say sales Q2 and then embraces passing
the string China run that and a return back the corresponding number.
And we can confirm that by taking a look at sales Q2.
Now if for some reason you actually wanted to grab information based off the index location as in the
integer base location where you could do is pass in that location such as the very first item at zero
and it would still work.
So you can see sales Q2 and that returns back to 60 if you call for zero.
So note that whether you call USA or if you call sales Q2 0 it returns back the same value.
So that gives you flexibility if the PAN series if you have a named label you can call the index based
off that name label.
If not or even if you do have it you can always call based off the integer location of a series.
So you can essentially do what looks like a dictionary call or a list index call.
Now something I want to show you is you may get an error if you try providing something that's not in
there.
So if I try to ask for the tenth item in the series I'll get a key error and key errors are really common
for beginners to get.
And basically what this indicates is either you provided the wrong number.
So you'll notice here it says key error 10 I couldn't find it because I don't have 10 items or maybe
you've committed a typo such as typing USA and lower case in which case that will also produce a type
error or key error we can see here that produced an error as well.
So just be careful of that.
You have to spell things correctly and capitalization actually counts.
Last thing I want to show you is we can then perform operations between series so I can take sales Q1
and try adding it to sales Q2.
Now keep in mind if we take a look at sales Q1 I have this item Brazil which is not present in sales
Q2.
So it's going to happen is the default behavior when I add these two series together is for Brazil and
Japan.
It'll say basically not a number since it didn't have information for both of those named labels for
both series.
Later on we'll go ahead and show you how to change its behavior to maybe treat one of the series as
a zero in order to keep the original values.
So if you wanted to see Japan as one hundred here and the Brazil's 150 in the final result we'll show
that later on.
But what I want to basically point out to you here is that even if you're adding to series that don't
match up perfectly based off their index labels the operation will still go through.
It'll just basically notify you of where you only had information on one of those series by providing
not a number.
So if you saw this final result this basically tells you that Brazil was only present in one of the
series.
Same with Japan.
Okay.
That's a very basics of pan the series coming up next.
We're going to walk you through the real workhorse of PANDAS which is the data frame and that's really
what we're going to be using throughout most of the course.
I'll see you at the next lecture.