Welcome back everyone to part two of gantz what we're going to do and part two is actually create the
generator and then the discriminator and similar to what we did in the auto encoders lecture.
We can then join them together to create the actual generative adversarial network itself.
All right.
Let's head back to the notebook and continue where we left off last time.
OK.
Here we are at the notebook where we left off last time.
Now the first thing I'm going to do is create the generator and discriminator there are separate models
and then we join them together into again object doesn't quite actually matter which one you create
first since we're going to be joining them anyways.
But let's go ahead and start off with the discriminator since it's a little bit simpler than the generator.
So what we do is recall during training the first phase is we're actually trained the discriminator.
So essentially what we're doing is we're taking a batch of real images samples from either the entire
training set or our particular only Zero's data set for faster training and we take that batch of real
images and then we also take an equal number of fake images that the generator will be producing and
we end up setting the labels as zero for the fake images.
And as one for the actual true real images and discriminator is trained on this label batch for then
just one step using what we'll see as binary across entropy loss because it's either correct or incorrect
0 or 1.
And then importantly what's going to happen is the back propagation only optimizes the weights of the
discriminator during that training phase and we'll see that when we actually write our training loop
after we create our batches.
But first let's just create the discriminator model.
We say discriminator is equal to a sequential model and to do this I need actually add in some imports.
So let's go ahead and insert a cell above here and let's do our classic imports.
We'll say import tensor flow as TAF and then import all say from tensor flow.
Dark hair start layers import.
And we'll be using dense and since we're dealing with kind of to these images here we'll have to reshape
them as well as flatten them.
Now this is a very simple discriminator and generator that we're gonna be producing because we don't
actually worry right now about using convolution layers.
We'll actually just do this all with essentially dense layers.
And then finally we'll say from tensor flow dot curious dot models import sequential.
All right.
So we have our imports ready to go.
Let's create our sequential model for the discriminator and then we're going to add a couple of things
here.
We'll say discriminator and we'll add in the first flatten layer because as to the images we need to
flatten them so the input shape it's expecting is a 28 by 20 image.
Make sure that's a list here.
So it's 28 by 28.
And then we flatten it out.
So that means we can then apply our dense layers.
So all this discriminator is trying to do is is this image real or not.
So let's go ahead and add some dense layers.
We'll go ahead and just choose some arbitrary values here.
We'll say we go from those seven hundred eighty four in the flatten layer to then a dense layer of 150
activation is rectified linear unit and then we'll add in one more layer here dense layer.
Go ahead add kind of a hundred more neurons start bringing it down rectified linear unit and then if
you want you could add more or more layers to make the discriminator harder to fool.
But this should be enough for our particular use case of this simple only zero data set.
So after this we're going to do is add in our final output layer just labeling it here so you can add
more layers if you want try to make the discriminator harder to full but eventually at the end what
you need is a dense layer we've actually just one neuron and it's one neuron regardless of how many
digits you're actually working with because recall we're trying to classify digits as 0 1 2 3 etc..
All we're trying to do at the discriminator is a binary classification of is this image real or is it
fake.
And if you're doing a binary classification then your final output layer is just one neuron with the
activation function of sigmoid OK so there's a discriminator.
And then finally we say discriminator and we compile this with the binary cross entropy loss because
again it's just trying to see if an image is fake or if it's real.
It's not trying to tell is it a 1 0 7 et cetera.
OK.
So that's a discriminator.
Pretty straightforward.
Just creates that sequential model.
You can add in more dense layers.
Obviously the more complex your discriminator network is the harder it is to fool because it should
be able to have more neurons and be able to learn more.
But again kind of depends on what your actual dataset is.
And then let's go out and create the generator.
All right.
The first step in creating our generator is to actually choose the coatings size that is to say the
latent representation.
And this is really similar to our discussion on auto encoders recall the auto encoders went from some
number of features.
And if we're doing it with this data for example 784 and then they kept going down to something like
150 keep going down to let's say 30 and then we expanded it back out we went then back to 150 and then
back to 780.
So this is what we would do as an example.
And essentially we have to decide on what this middle number is.
And this middle number recall is some sort of lower dimensionality encoding.
So the actual generator looks a lot like this decoder part where it's taking some sort of encoding and
then expanding it back out to generate some sort of output that will try to fool discriminator.
So our case what's going to happen is the generator looks a lot like a decoder essentially taking some
number starting from some encoding size or coatings size and then expanding it back out to generate
an image that will then be compiled and pass the discriminator to see whether or not it falls to discriminator.
So you have to choose some sort of coding size and there's no right or wrong answer here.
It's essentially how low do you want to go inside of this decoder.
And typically it should be a lot less than your original feature set.
So our original feature set recall here is seven hundred and eighty four.
If you make it too small however then there really isn't enough to start off with to actually learn
from and generate images.
So what we're going to do here is since we have a pixel size of seven hundred eighty four pixels.
Let's go ahead and choose an encoding size of one hundred that is substantially less than seven hundred
eighty four.
But not so small where the generator is just not going to have enough to start off with as a latent
representation.
So again this one hundred kind of signifies what this 30 was.
So we would go from like 100 to 150 to 780 for etc. and our generator is essentially going to look like
that back half of the auto encoder the decoder part.
So we choose some coding size recall it should be less than the total number of features you're working
with but not so little that you really have nothing to learn off of.
And it's something you can play around with and experiment.
So you create this generator as a sequential model and then listener adding the layers to it.
So generator we add in some dense layer.
We'll go ahead and match our first layer to our coding size give it an activation of rectified linear
unit and then finally give it an input shape of the actual coatings size
so keep in mind this one hundred we technically chose it off this coding size but it's not reliant on
it what is actually reliant on this first layering and generator is the input shape.
So you could mess around with this and expand this to immediately to 150 if you wanted to.
But in our case we're going to take this one hundred encoding size first layer and counters 100 neurons
and then we'll start expanding it back out.
So let's make the next one 150.
Again this should feel really familiar because it looks a lot like the decoder from our auto encoder
lectures.
So we'll say generator.
Go ahead and Adam's copying pasting here in other dense layer but instead we'll expand that back out
to 150.
And if you want to try to make the model more robust you can add more decoding layers.
But in our case we'll just take this here paste it in and go ahead expand this back out to 780 for the
last thing we need to remember is our discriminator expects a 2D input as a 28 by 28 our generator right
now is just producing this flat vector of seven eighty four.
So what we need to do is we need the generator to finally reshape its output to match what the discriminator
expects which is a shape of 28 by 28 and there's your generator.
OK so we have the discriminator.
Notice we compiled the discriminator but we don't actually compile the generator.
So instead what we actually do is we create our generator of adversarial network as a sequential model
and we join together the generator and the discriminator and then to start things off.
What we say is that discriminator
not trainable.
So she knows this is trainable.
That's a attribute of discriminator itself.
Set that equal to False.
And then finally let's go ahead and take our game and compile it we'll go ahead and choose binary cross
entropy as our loss and you can use an optimizer whichever one you want.
You can use stochastic gradient descent and choose slower learning rate.
We'll go ahead and just choose atom here and compile it.
So a couple of things going on that I want to mention here.
Specifically these two lines of discriminator trainable equal false.
And again as well as a generator.
So couple things we want to really clarify here is the discriminator itself.
Recall regardless of how many different categories you have in your original dataset all it's doing
is saying what is real and what is fake.
So by definition if it's only two categories of what's real what's fake doesn't matter if it's classifying
will it it's not really classifying but determining whatever image dataset whether it's m this people's
faces et cetera.
This is a binary cross entropy loss because it's a binary classifier then the generator itself.
The reason we're not compiling it is because later on we'll see it's only trained through this fool
Gan model.
So that's the reason why we're not compiling the generator and then the Gan model.
You'll eventually realize that this fool model itself is also a binary classifier so it can then also
use this binary cross entropy loss.
And then finally what's important here is the way Caris works the discriminator should not be trained
during the second phase.
So we end up doing is we make it non trainable here by sending it equal to False and we'll see how essentially
these three lines of code all come together during our training loop because we really have a special
case here of two models kind of pitted against each other to hopefully produce realistic looking images.
We can't just use our regular dot fit command.
So coming up next we need to do is actually setup our batches for our training loop.
Again we have this set of two models.
We've combined them discriminator is first set as trainable equal to False in order to compile it here
and we'll see how this all comes together in the training loop coming up in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.