Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to discuss Ellis T.M. and G are you units many of the solutions previously
presented for vanishing gradients can also apply to recurrent neural networks or the recurrent neuron
that is things like using different activation functions such as rectified linear units performing batch
normalization etc. However because of the typical length of a time series input especially if the time
series happens to be really long what could happen is using those different activation functions or
some of those other solutions that could actually slow down training time now a possible solution to
that would just be to shorten the actual time step they're using for prediction.
So maybe instead of looking back twenty four time steps for the 25th prediction you just look back three
time steps to get the next prediction.
However this makes the model worse at predicting longer trends.
So we still want to be able to use a long time sequence in order to predict the next item in the sequence
or element in the sequence.
Now another issue that recurrent neural networks face in general is that after a while the network will
begin to forget those first inputs as information is lost at each step going through the recurrent neural
network.
Well we need to do is to have some sort of long term memory for our networks.
So as you can imagine this were the Ellis team memory cell or neuron comes into play and Elysium stands
for Long Short term memory.
So we're going to have both long term and short term memory going in and out of that cell.
And this was created to help address these typical Recurrent Neural Networks issues.
So let's go ahead and get an understanding of how an Ellis stem cell works.
But first let's quickly review what's happening in a normal recurrent neuron so in a typical recurrent
neural network where you don't have any specialized cell types you're taking in the input at some timestamp
and then along with the output of that timestamp you're feeding that back in the next timestamp.
So your input a T minus one produces an output a T minus one.
You take that output and feed it back into the next time step along with the input.
Then at time T.
So essentially they have two inputs.
You create a single output the pass in that same output into the next timestamp and so on so if we just
take a look at what a single recurrent neuron would actually be doing is essentially it's taking in
both the previous output and then the current input and then producing the next output.
And what we'll do in order to label these equations is instead of saying output or input we'll simply
refer to these as hidden state and then our current feature X going in.
So basically we have the H of T minus one going in along with X of T and that produces h of T.
And then what is actually happening inside of the neuron.
So in a standard occurrence you're a network.
Essentially what we do is we just have a single hyperbolic tangent function and then what we're doing
is combining h of T minus 1 along of expertise multiplying it by some weight matrix and then adding
a bias to it and then passing it through the hyperbolic tangent function and that gives us back our
H of T.
And then we just repeat that through the next recurrent neuron or an extra current layer so it Ellis
team will also have this chain like structure.
But the repeating module has a slight difference to it and instead of just having a single neural network
layer there's actually going to be four layers working and interacting in a special way and the way
we end up getting for is the fact that not only will we keep track of just a single historical memory
with h of T minus one we're keeping track of both the long term memory input and the short term memory
input and then creating a new long term memory output and then use short term memory output along with
the current input at time T.
And then we produce an output at time T.
So don't worry too much about these details right now or we're going to be doing is walking through
the Ellis Tam step by step.
But right now let's just get comfortable with some of the notation we're going to be using so essentially
we're going to have forming components inside the Ellis team.
We have a forget gate and output gate and update gate and an input gate.
So as you can imagine and we'll go over this in more detail later on but the forget gate will decide
what to forget from the previous memory units the input gate will decide what to actually accept into
the neuron and the update gate will update the memories and the output gate will actually output the
new long term memory so a gate.
Just to clarify this optionally lets some information through.
And essentially we can just think of this as mathematically it's a sigmoid function.
It's either going to end up being a squeeze between a 0 or 1 and if it's 0 we don't let that information
through.
And if it's a one we do okay.
So again here's our general structure of the Elysium and we're accepting both long term memory and short
term memory and we can kind of think of this as going to be passed in through conveyor belts inside
of this neuron.
And what ends up happening is it just ends up kind of running down straight the entire chain and has
some kind of linear interactions with a few functions inside of the cell.
Now for the purpose of a mathematical notation we're gonna relabel some of these and we're going to
label it as such.
We're gonna say we have on the bottom there an X of teh input leading out to your h of T.
And notice then we have that short term memory.
So we're called a short term memory is on the bottom here.
So we're going to call that H of T minus one and each of T.
And we're also going to not just have that hidden state but also C of T minus 1 and c of T which is
going to refer essentially to our long term memory.
OK so what are the actual linear interactions and functions going on inside of Elysium.
Well here we can see the entire Elysium cell.
So we're going to do is essentially go through the process step by step.
All right.
The first step in our LSD team is to decide what information are we going to throw away from the cell
state essentially.
What are you going to forget.
So we end up creating is a forget gate layer or F of T.
And remember those gates are essentially just passing things through a sigmoid function where the closer
it is to 0.
That means the less weight you're giving it the closer it is to 1.
That means the more weight you're giving it.
So in the context of a forget gate layer the closer it is to 0.
Essentially means forget about this and get rid of it.
The closer it is to 1 on this output means completely remember this.
It's probably important that we remember this.
So this is what this f of T is doing.
And notice that it's essentially a linear combination of H of T minus one that previous hidden state
combined with the input x of T.
And then we have our own sets of weights for this forget gate layer plus a bias and then we pass it
through an activation function and then we get F of t then the next step after this is to decide what
new information are we going to store into the cell state.
So this has two parts to it.
First we can see here on top.
We have a sigmoid layer that we're going to label the input gate layer which is essentially going to
decide what values are we going to update next.
We have a hyperbolic tangent layer that creates a vector of new candidate values which will say C of
T but we'll label this with a tilde on top of it.
Essentially say hey these are the new candidate values that will eventually hopefully in some sort of
weighing be updating the cell state.
So we have that input gate layer again deciding which values we're going to update in the hyperbolic
tangent layer which is creating a vector of those new candidate values.
Notice again there are essentially as linear combinations of exit T U of H of T minus one.
And then we have them being multiplied by their own set of weights and we add a bias to it and we're
passing them through activation functions then it's now time to update the old cell state which is C
of team minus 1.
So what we do is in order to calculate the new cell state C of t that we're going to end up outputting
we have C A T is equal to f of T multiplied by C of T minus one and then we're going to add I have t
times those new candidate values.
So essentially what we're doing is we just multiply the old state by 50 forgetting the things that we
decided weren't that important due to the forget gate layer.
Then we added I have t times the new candidate values.
So essentially these are the new candidate values for the cell state scaled by how much we decided to
update each state value.
So then finally after this we need to decide well what are we actually going to output so this output
will be based on our cell state.
That is actually a filtered version first.
We end up doing is we run a sigmoid layer so that's that top equation which decides what parts of the
cell state we're going to output.
Then we put that cell state through a hyperbolic tangent function and what the hyperbolic tangent function
does is it pushes all the values to be between negative 1 and 1 and then we're gonna multiply it by
the output of that initial sigmoid gate of o of T so that we only output the parts that we decided to.
Now what I've been describing so far is essentially just your standard normal LSD m but there are variations
of this which I'll briefly mention there is the peephole variation where essentially what we end up
doing is we have these people connections for added here as red lines and this means we let the multiple
gate layers the F of T I have t and o of t look at these cell state.
So here notice that we're essentially adding in C of T minus 1 or c t into these 3 gates.
Now we previously didn't have that we only had H T minus one an equity but in some variations of Elysium
they add in peoples which essentially also linearly combines the cell state inside of the LSD M in other
variation off of this is the gated recurrent units.
So what the gate it recurrent unit is is essentially it's going to combine the forget an input gates
into what's known as a single update gate and it also merges the cell state and hidden state and makes
some other changes.
So what ends up happening is you have this model that's simpler than a standard LSD model and the panel
applications.
It's getting kind of popular but again the standard has really become Alice Tam and then get a recurrent
unit is slowly picking up popularity but by the time you're seeing this who knows what the current cases
because there's a field that moves very very fast.
So if you want you can check out the links I have for this lecture to see a kind of in-depth explanation
over which variants are the best and how their differences actually matter and when to use certain units.
Okay now fortunately with our deep learning python library we simply just need to call the import for
recurrent neural network or Ellis dam instead of needing to code all of this calculations out ourselves.
So finally what we're going to do is let's go ahead and explore how do you use LSD Ms for deep learning
with Python code.
I'll see you at the next lecture.