Welcome everyone to this lecture where we're going to show you how to use a basic recurrent natural
network on a sine wave.
So I want to quickly talk about how training and evaluation works on recurrent natural network.
Now recall our original data set is going to look something like this.
We probably won't extend that all the way to 800 points.
But here we can see a sine wave.
So what we're going to do for a time series data is we split this into a training set and test set.
However we don't do the random splits as we've done in the past.
Instead we want to do is simulate what it would be like to forecast into future information.
So we set a basically a cutoff point somewhere on our training data to specify a certain historical
ranges or training set and a future range as our test set during training.
What we can do is then evaluate performance on that test data so let's zoom in on this range and basically
think about what that would look like.
Essentially as we're training what we're doing is we're forecasting on that range and we could visualize
this later on to see and evaluate how we're actually working or performing this forecasting.
So eventually hopefully we get something that looks very similar to a sine wave and basically showing
us that we have a good fit.
So eventually once we're satisfied with the results on that test portion it'll be time to forecast into
the unknown future and really what that means is retraining on all available data both that training
set and the test set and then forecasting beyond the scope of the original entire dataset.
So then that would look something in this case like this.
Notice how now we're forecasting beyond they hundred point however and this is really the key thing
to keep in mind.
And something that confuses beginners is that when we're working with a real data set we would no longer
have values to compare these predictions to.
And we'll see that later on in this section of course when we actually forecast on real time serious
data.
OK so let's see how we can actually do this all of for full 2.0 and cares.
Let's get back to Jupiter notebook and get started.
OK.
First things first they've gone ahead and already imported pandas number pi and map plot lived up pi
plot.
And keep in mind depending on your version of Jupiter you may need to add in this magic line of map
plot lib in line.
OK let's go ahead and use num pi to create a simple sine wave.
So the sine wave is going to have some X points and I can use MP Lynn space and we'll go from zero to
50 and we'll ask for five hundred and one million nearly spaced points between the numbers 0 and 50.
So if I take a look at what that actually looks like it's just the values basically between zero and
50 spaced out by zero point one.
So you can see that's our time step essentially and what I'm going to do is set my Y equal to the sine
value at that particular X..
So then for each corresponding X I've taken the sine value which means I can simply say oops PDT plot
x versus Y and I will see my sine wave from zero to 50.
All right.
So now that we have our sine wave what we're going to do is we're going to turn this into a data frame
just so it's a little easier to work with.
So it's IDF is equal to PD.
That data frame and say our data is equal to y in our index is equal to x and we'll label the columns
just sine since there is essentially just one column.
Don't forget however to pass it in as a list.
So now I have this formatted as my nice data frame sine wave where the index corresponds to the value
of x and the column value here for sine is just sign of this index value.
OK so we're going to do now is do that train test split that we just discussed.
Keep in mind this is different from our usual test train split methodology with psychic learn.
Instead we need to decide what percentage of the end of this dataset.
Am I going to use for my testing range.
So again the length of my actual data firm right now is five hundred one points.
And what you should do is depending on your actual overall goals decide on some percentage of your data
set to be the test set.
So what I can do here say zero point one to indicate that I want 10 percent of the end of this data
to be my test set.
And later on we see this with real time series data.
We'll discuss more realistic ways of choosing your percentage.
Right now we're kind of arbitrarily choosing 10 percent since it's just a simple sine wave.
So then I have to figure out well what's the cutoff point for that.
There's lots of different ways you can do this.
We could just take the length of your data frame and then calculate test percent against it.
And now I know that about 10 percent of the data points would be 50 data points which makes sense here.
So I want to figure out well what index point should I be cutting this off and I'm going to show you
this by saying test point is equal to rounding off.
So N.P. round the length of the data frame.
Times test percent.
And the reason I'm doing this so formulaic CLI is that we'll be able to use all these same equations
when we deal with real time series data which makes this easy to use and easy to repeat.
So really we want to say here are nice frameworks for you to use regardless of your data set.
OK so once we have our test point what we can do is if we take a look at our test point right now is
essentially an index 50 so we'll say my test index essentially that split point index value is going
to be the length for the data frame minus the test point value and then I'm going to round it to an
integer so I can actually use it for indexing with pandas.
So essentially what this calculates and it's probably something you could've done in your head as well
is four hundred fifty one.
So that's my cutoff point which means my training set is going to be my data frame and we'll use integer
location slicing to say colon which means from the beginning go all the way up to but not including
the test the next point then for my test set starting at that test.
Index point go all the way to the end.
And now if I take a look at my data now that's my training data goes all the way to point an index point
forty five and then my test data starts right after it at forty five point one and then goes all the
way to the end which was 50.
So now I've done my test train split as I would for time series data.
Now the next step is to scalar data and this is again things are going to be a little differently than
what we did on our artificial neural networks because of the way recurrent neural networks are actually
going to feed output back into themselves.
We need to actually scale this why data which is typically our label.
Previously we saw artificial neural networks we weren't scaling the label itself but this time because
we're feeding that input back into our own neurons it should be scaled.
So we'll say from S K learn that pre processing import min max scalar and then we'll create an instance
of the scalar object by saying scalar is equal to men Max scalar and then what we're going to do is
we're going to scale with data.
Now keep in mind we're still going to follow the rules of only fitting to our training data set which
makes sense because in a real life situation you wouldn't have future data to scale on you wouldn't
have next year's sales data.
To scale on so we'll simply saying go ahead and fit to our training data and then we'll transform scaled
versions of our data.
So we have our scale training set which is scalar transform train and we'll do the same now for our
scale test.
Notice we don't fit to the test set and so we just transform on it.
All right.
So the next step is going to be to take these training batches and actually transform them in a way
that makes sense.
Essentially a sequence of historical labels and then some points into the future and we can do that
through the time series generator object that's actually built into the caris pre processing sequence
library.
So we're in continue right where we left off in the next lecture to learn how to use this time series
generator class.
I'll see it there.