Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to focus on creating the model and train the model.
And we're also going to emphasize the aspects of the model that you can play around with an edit versus
the aspects that based off the constraints of your problem should essentially always be fixed.
OK let's get started by heading back to the notebook.
All right.
So here we are the notebook where we left off last time just as before we're creating a model.
We're going to say from tensor flow dot care stop models import and we'll import a sequential model
builder.
WE'LL STILL BUILD OUR MODEL sequentially by adding layers.
The main difference is going to be the kind of layers we actually add to this.
So we will say from tensor flow Dr. Harris that layers import and we're going to import a dense layer
just as we did before but also a completion layer for handling to these images which has come to capital
D and then also Max Poole to the.
And then eventually you need to flatten out these images to fit it into our final dense layers which
will actually perform the classification.
So there is a special flatten layer for that.
OK so let's begin building out our model and we're going to focus on a couple of parameters throughout
the actual adding of the layers so just before we start off by building out our sequential model then
the next thing to do is typically for accomplishing on your own network the first layer that it encounters
is a volitional error.
So we will say model add and I'm going to add in convolution loops to capital D parentheses and if you
do shift tab here it'll show you the documentation string.
Remember we we've already imported it and we have princes here so I can see the documentation string.
Otherwise just call help on the actual class call but there's four main parameters that I want to essentially
explain to you here and that is the filters the kernel size the strides and the padding Stream.
Now we actually already understand filters kernel side strides and padding.
Theoretically based off the theory lectures that we just went over.
The main thing we have to figure out is what values do I choose for this.
And a lot of times there's not 100 percent correct answer.
It's based roughly off of the input data that's coming in.
So really typical values for number of filters is the more complex the data set.
So essentially the larger the images the more variety and images and the more classes you're trying
to classify then the more filters you should have.
And it's really common to choose filters based off powers of two.
So a very common starting point for no filters could be something like 32 but you can imagine that if
you're dealing with a really complex set of really large images and maybe you're trying to classify
something like the number of or the types of road signs so you have a stop sign a yield sign a turn
left turn right and you have a lot of classes it probably makes sense to then add a lot more filters
to try to begin to understand or have your convolution on your own network understand the various shapes
that come off all these different signs.
Now in our case we have really simple data set of just handwritten numbers where we have 10 classes
so filters with a Power of 32 or excuse me if a chosen value of 32 is a good step to start at the next
we need to decide is that image Col size.
And again typical sizes of image kernels are something in the range of two by two or four by four.
And then you can keep expanding it based off again your data.
A good starting point for this is four by four.
OK so what about the other two parameters that we discussed in theory.
So the next one is the side or the size of the strides and there's two dimensions here because you can
stride in both X and Y and recall that the stride is basically how big of a stride are we taking as
removing the colonel along this image in our case the test images are actually pretty small they're
only 28 by 28 pixels.
And since our colonel is four by four we can actually then determine how long of a time or essentially
how many pixels is it going to take to go over by just saying 28 divided by four we can get an idea
of that scanning of the image if you're dealing with really large images and you're still dealing with
a smaller Colonel you would probably want to expand on that stride size in our case though we'll go
ahead and leave it of the default of just one by one pixel.
So essentially just striding along by default pixel and X pixel 10 x pixel etc. and then the next one
is padding.
And if you take a look at padding it's either valid.
So it's a string code valid.
And if we scroll down here you'll say that it's either valid or same.
And those are your only two options.
So what do these strings actually mean.
If you do a quick google search for what is a difference between valid and same in the string you get
this nice link to a stack overflow post that basically talks about what's the difference between this
same and valid padding.
And this actually links to Max pool of tension flow but it's the same code for Caris as well.
And if we come down here there's an example here talking about same versus valid pad but I like some
of these more visual examples and probably the clearest explanation is if you scroll down here the clearest
to me was essentially this quick explanation right here and it's worth the bottom.
All of these explanations essentially say the same thing but the string valid basically tells you do
not apply any padding or we're going to do is we're going to assume that all dimensions are valid so
that the input image fully gets covered by the filter and stride that I specified.
So is that going to be the case here.
Well let's think about this.
If I have 28 and I divide it by four that goes evenly seven times and I'm only doing a stride of one.
So if I just move my colonel which is four by four along my 28 by 28 image I shouldn't have a need for
padding because I won't actually overshoot because I fit perfectly with a stride of one.
But if this begins to give out decimal numbers you may end up encountering some errors because you're
overshooting and in that case we have to decide are we just going to drop those points are we going
to pad it with zeros or ones et cetera.
And so then what we do is we'd have to specify the string same.
So nice.
What's nice about same is they automatically figures out what the padding should be.
So what happens here is it's going to apply padding to the input only if needed so that the input image
gets fully covered by the filter and strike that you specified.
So for example if we decided on a straight of one that ensures that the output image size is the same
as the input image.
OK so there's lots of other explanations here one that goes in to the math of it and another one here
that shows you essentially what this is doing through a little bit of kind of a visual explanation.
So I encourage you that if you just google search if we go back here valid versus same padding you get
a lot of outputs here.
OK.
So again you can look at those explanations.
In our case we'll just go ahead and keep the default which will work fine for us in our case or we just
have padding is valid.
OK.
So that's our filters and or kernel size.
The couple things we need to now add in is define what is the input shape that we expect here.
So it's going to be input shape is equal to and in our case is just the input shape for a single image
which is twenty eight by twenty eight by one color channel.
And then finally we choose what kind of activation function do we want.
So the activation function will choose is rectified linear unit so say activation is equal to rectified
linear unit.
Okay.
So let's put this all on one line here and I can zoom out just a little bit so we can see the whole
call our compositional error has some determine number of filters a kernel size if we want we can specify
padding.
But in this case we have to.
And then we can specify the input shape and the activation function.
Okay.
So it's a conventional error.
After your accomplishment layer you should have a pooling layer.
You will say model add here I will call Max Poole to the and the main thing to choose here is the pool
size.
You can also add in things like strides padding etc. but really the key factor is pool size and we'll
go ahead and do a pool size that's half of our kernel size.
A two by two is a really common metric here.
So we'll go ahead and just say pool size is 2 by 2.
That is the default.
So technically that I have to specify that but I do want the visibility of what I'm doing here.
Okay now we're going to just keep it as having one convolution earlier and one pooling layer.
So very simple accomplished on the whole network.
Now what I could do is keep adding compositional and pulling layers and we'll do that later on for more
complex images.
But right now we'll just keep it simple.
One compositional error one pulling layer after your series accomplishment and putting layers.
You'll need to flatten out the images.
So when we're flattening out the images that essentially means take a 28 by 20 image and then flatten
it out to be just a single array of.
In our case seven hundred and eighty four points.
So take one of these two by two images and then flatten it out into internal rate of 784 which is 28
times 28.
So we can do that by simply saying model add and then we flatten out the image.
Once we're able to flatten out the image well we can do is we can start adding in our dense layers.
It's usually a good idea to add in one final dense layer that more or less matches the same scale of
this.
So the scale should be somewhere between zero and one thousand we'll go ahead and say dense and we'll
keep kind of the power of two.
Same here and we'll say 120 neurons in the sense layer activation is equal to rectified linear unit.
And if you want you can keep adding dense layers but eventually we have our final output layer.
So how many neurons should be in my final output layer.
In this case for classification I should have one neuron per class so that will be a dense layer with
10 neurons.
And in this case I also have to think of my activation function which should be for a multi class classification
problem not a binary class but a multi class should be the soft Max activation function.
So again it's going to be soft Max because this is a multi class problem then finally I'm going to compile
this will say model compile loss is equal to categorical cross entropy categorical cross entry because
it's a multi class problem the optimizer will go ahead and choose atom for optimizer and here if I want
I can specify additional metrics which is actually something we haven't seen before but I could say
go ahead and add in some additional metrics.
Typically what we do is we use loss as our metric.
Essentially the lost calculation from our loss function which is categorical cross entropy.
That's something I could do.
I could also keep track of something like accuracy and if you want to check out what string codes are
available to you or what metrics are available to you can go to Kerry's the I O slash metrics.
So if I go ahead and copy this and then paste it here to the curious documentation it'll actually show
you the available metrics.
There's accuracy binary actually categorical accuracy top K etc. clone club metrics and you can even
create your own custom metrics so there's lots of options here that we can keep taking a look at so
we'll go ahead and just choose accuracy essentially actually across all categories in our case and we'll
leave it as such.
We'll still be able to calculate loss but this is just another metric that we can keep recording during
training.
We'll go ahead and compile the model make sure we don't commit any typos and we're good to go.
All right.
So I want to quickly highlight what can you play around with and what has to be said.
Let's start off by discussing the parameters that are fixed and should be determined by your actual
data set those parameters are your input shape the input shape should essentially match what an image
is going to look like in our case it's a 28 by twenty eight one color channel image.
This input shape parameter is determined by your data after your compositional layers and you're pulling
layers.
You will eventually have to flatten out your data.
So this is another parameter essentially a layer that should be somewhere in your network.
Then the last couple of parameters that you will edit and should be set based off your data.
Is this final dense layer this dense layer should be equal to the number of neurons to your classes.
So we have 10 possible classes the numbers 0 1 2 3 all the way to 9.
So I should have 10 year ons here and the activation function should then be soft to Max.
If you were dealing with a binary classification problem such as just an image of a cat versus a dog
then this would be a binary classification with just one neuron output with an activation of sigmoid
and the other thing that's defined by your problem is the type of loss.
And then here in our case it's categorical cross entropy.
OK now the things can play around with are several here you can add as many compositional and pulling
layers as you want and then within those you can play around the number of filters the kernel sizes
as well as the pool size and you can also play around with the padding.
Then after that after you flatten it out.
You can play around with the number of dense layers as well as the number of neurons in those layers.
And typically people just use kind of one dense layer maybe two after they flatten it out.
They don't have that many dense layers after flattening out most of the work for image data should be
done by the convolution and pulling layers.
OK so I just wanted to have that brief discussion highlighting what is available to you to play around
with and what should be set by your data.
All right now the last thing we want to set up is training the model to make sure we don't need to worry
about choosing the number of epochs.
Let's go ahead and set up an early stopping callback.
We'll say from tensor flow that carries the callbacks go ahead and import early stopping and then the
early stop will be equal to early stopping.
We decide what we want to monitor by default we monitor validation loss.
But keep in mind the other metric we could be monitoring is validation accuracy because I added metrics
accuracy here.
I could say Val underscore accuracy as my monitor device but we'll go ahead to keep it to the lost that's
output by categorical cross entropy and then we specify some patients so we can specify something like
patients want or patients to we're going to set it to patients once so wait 1 epoch run that and now
we'll say model that fit passin our training data and then for y recall we want to pass on the categorical
version of these labels we'll set epochs to something relatively high 10 and then we need to make sure
we also pass in our validation dataset so it's going to be x test and also this should also be categorical
why cat test and then finally to make sure we actually have early stopping we'll say callbacks is equal
to early stop.
Okay go ahead and fit that model.
Make sure we didn't make any typos above and it looks like it's working out for us you can really see
we get a very high accuracy right off the bat this is a pretty easy dataset to work with.
Okay so coming up in the next lecture after with on training the model we will evaluate the model's
performance.
I will see you there.