Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to focus on the deployment aspect of connecting our model to some front
end.
H team L that way any user whether or not they're technical can just go to this Web site and then feed
in their data and actually get back.
Prediction so we're gonna focus again on connecting that flask app and tents for a model to an HD e-mail
form so any user can interact with the model.
Please note that in order to fully understand this section you do need to have a basic understanding
of each HTML and ginger template.
If you don't have an understanding of that I would highly suggest you go take a web development course
first maybe a flask course and then come back to the series of lectures.
OK so let's talk about what this actually requires.
We're going to need our application which we already have as my example dot pi.
We're going to need to add a few things to it in order to connect it to underneath a template folder.
We'll have to tame our files home each time out and prediction each HTML so we add a couple of things
to the application to connect those templates.
Let's talk about each of these aspects for the application where main thing we're going to add here
is connecting it to H html files and then evolves using flasks create in each team a form and inject
that each table form into the home that each tamale page then we'll use flask to accept submitted each
team will form data then we feed that data to our model and then we'll use flask to return the prediction
to a new page prediction that each team L which once a person hits submit on home.
But each team l it takes them to prediction that each team out the home each team L is a very simple
each team I'll file that uses a flask based form to accept user input and then it sends this input back
to the flask app for processing of the return prediction function the prediction that each team l file
simply returns back to prediction information.
Once that prediction function has completed running now make sure to use our files as a reference.
I should really make clear that it's extremely easy to make just even a simple typo such as an extra
space that can break all the connections here.
So we're dealing with a lot of different file types.
So make sure to use our files as a reference in case you get an error along the way.
All right let's get started.
Well we're going to do is head back to that my example that profile that we've been playing around with
okay.
Here we are at my example dot pi recall currently my example that Pi has our return prediction function
and it has essentially two routes a home page and an API page.
However these are not actually full H came out pages.
Instead what they do is the prediction page just returns.
Jason and the home page for routing just has a single heading a flask app is running well we want to
do is eventually connect both of these to some actual H tamale files to do that we first need to do
a couple of things.
We no longer need request or J satisfy in order for this to work because we're not actually accepting
J son requests.
Instead we're feeding in from an H Tamar form but that does require a couple of more imports from flask.
We need to do is get render underscore a template which actually renders an h t email template.
We'll still need session in order to grab session data and then we'll say you are A4 which connects
to different URLs and that's it.
The next thing you want to do is we'll be using a flask library called WTA forms which is just a very
simple library for creating forms quickly a flask.
So we'll be using that to essentially inject the form with ginger templating and we'll say from W T
F O R M.S. W T forms import and we'll have two fields we'll have a text field and a submit field and
we'll see later on how we actually use these essentially a text field.
We're gonna have four empty boxes of texts that the user can type in their measurements to and then
submit field is just a submit button.
OK so we have those ready to go.
Next we're going to do is we will scroll down here.
We have our flask application in order to correctly actually get form information.
What we need to do is set up a secret key.
So after you create your application say app dot config and then in quotes and in all caps you say secret
underscore key and then we set that to just an arbitrary string.
So we'll say my secret key.
This is typically an environment variable but for right now we're just setting it within the application.
OK so this secret key basically allows the forms to work essentially make sure that it's not being hacked
so to speak and that the person filling out the form is actually the person that should be viewing the
next page.
OK next.
Well we need to do is create a class and you could if you want separate this out into multiple dot pi
files but we're putting it all in the same pi file for simplicity of filming.
But we want to do is create a form class.
So we'll say flower form and then what we need to do is actually grab a flask form.
So if we come back up here we're going to do one less import which is import flask underscore WTS.
And in fact instead of importing flask we'll just say from flask underscored that bit to f import the
flask form OK.
So that allows us to then inherit that form class.
So I'll scroll down here back to flower form inherit flask form and flask form is our basic form class
that's built into this double TIFF forms library.
And here we're going to do is construct a form.
So there's four things you need to collect and that's simple length.
So we'll create a text field and then here we'll give it the label of simple length
the next thing is people with create another text field and that will say see Paul with last one or
last two is pedal length again.
Similarly it's just a text field with pedal length and then we have pedal with which is also just a
text field.
And this will say pedal width.
So what we're doing here is we're using this flask form library to create a form of four text fields
the text field is something that the user will then later on see in the H to AML page and we'll be for
text fields that the input see blank space with pedal length and pedal with.
Finally to finish off a form you need a submit button.
So we say submit is equal to submit field and here you can just type and submit or whatever you want
the submit button to say we'll go ahead and have it say analyze.
You can also have it say predict and that's all we need for our form.
Okay.
Next is our actual home page right now.
Right now our home page is just returning back the raw.
Each team L code a flask app is running well we want to do is changes to actually be the form.
So what I'll do here is I'll delete this return line and start building out my index.
So the first thing you need to do inside this index is say form is equal to an instance of flower form.
So this creates an instance of the form and then if the form and we'll say that validate underscore
on submit it basically makes sure that you're actually submitting text in those form then we're actually
going to grab data from it.
So we'll say session.
And it will start saving things to the current session.
So it's a form that simple underscore length data and we're gonna do this for all four objects.
So what are we actually doing here.
We're creating an instance of the flower form class which we call we just created up here.
And what the flower form class does it essentially has these four attributes really five but the main
attributes are simple length simple with pedal link and pedal with which are obtained from these text
fields.
So after creating that flask form what we're doing is we're saying from that form grab that simple length
attribute and grab the data which is just the text and then we're going to essentially copy and paste
this four times because we're doing this for not just the simple length but also the simple with the
change this to also with and then we're also doing it for pedal lengths so that alien and then we're
also doing it for pedal with
so we'll change this right here to underscore w I.D. in order to make sure this form can actually work.
We need to make sure that the methods on this actual page are both get and post.
We should be able to actually go back and forth with this form which means under here under root or
we want to say is methods is equal to and then pass on a list of both get in post methods and that will
allow our form to successfully get information from the user and then post new information either on
the same page or on a different page.
Okay.
Once the user has submitted the form and it's valid so if form that valid the item is true we grab all
that data save it to the session when the session is basically this dictionary like object then we'll
say return and we will redirect to your URL underscore for and then we'll just pass in the string code.
Prediction OK and we'll see where prediction comes from in just the second this redirect and this your
URL for functionality that comes from all the way up here we have your URL for redirect.
We'll also need to be imported so we'll say import redirect from flask as well.
OK so we've done those imports.
Let's come back down here and let's say this is only when the form is submitted we actually need to
show something on the home page before they start submitting the form which means I should in line with
this if statement say return render templates and here's or we'll say home that each time El make sure
we spell it right and we say form is equal to okay and that's it for our home page view.
So what's actually happening here.
I created the home page on the home page.
I create this new flower form which is its WTO form from flask with four text fields and a submit button.
And then if the form is valid once that user hits the submit button I grab all those text data points
and save them to my current session.
The session essentially is the session object for the user that behaves like a dictionary and then we'll
redirect for prediction and then I have this render template which renders home that h t email so I
only redirect them if the form is validated upon submission.
So notice I use this string code for prediction.
That means for my other view here of app that routing what I need to do is change this to just be prediction
here.
That way I can connect to this your all and I'll also change just the actual routing to be prediction
and I don't need any methods here since there's no form and no data is gonna be accepted here.
So what is prediction actually looks like it's a pretty straight simple or first rate for I should say
and delete this the content essentially now starts off as just an empty dictionary and then I'm going
to say content of simple underscore length is equal to the session data for simple length but recall
that these are text fields so I need to convert them to floats in order to pass this in as what is essentially
a dictionary or Jason object to my return prediction function.
So then let's do this three more times we'll go ahead and copy this paste that in and then we do that
not just for simple length but also for simple with and not just for Poles but also the pedals as well.
So I'm changing all these guys to match up the session data before and then this content these key codes
need to match up.
What if we scroll up here.
This sample Jason expects from the return prediction function.
So these are all being connected here and I encourage you to pause if needed.
I know there's a lot going on here but a lot of this just repeated code.
OK.
And then we'll say pedal.
And then this last one it should be pedal with so close this off pedal underscore with OK.
So we have this empty content dictionary.
And then what I do is I set up the content dictionary for my return prediction function and I grab all
the session information and cast it as floats.
And then finally I'll say results is equal to return prediction where my model is the flower model I
loaded then I have my flower scalar and now my sample Jason is just the content that I created once
that's done I'm going to return render template and I'll render a prediction that each team I'll file
where results is equal to results.
And that means results is something I can use within the prediction that each team.
Now the next thing we need to do is connect prediction that each team L to the prediction function routing
and then home that each team L to this index routing.
So how do we actually do that.
Well we actually have each team our files already prepared for you.
And instead of kind of coding out because they're really repetitive we're just gonna show you what they
are and how they connect to each of these each team else.
So what I will do is I will say file open file and underneath deployment what I'm going to do is open
underneath templates folder home and prediction.
So it's like both of those and open them up.
And here we have the home each team it looks like and what the prediction that each team out looks like.
Something to note here is that they need to be located under a folder called templates all lowercase
flask by default looks for a folder called templates to find the HTML email files that the routing functions
refer to.
So if you're not familiar with flask that's kind of really common.
Even in Django that's common where the folder has to be called all underscore templates and H team email
files go there.
So what is the home H to Mal file looks like.
It looks like it says flask app running and then says Please enter your flower measurements below.
And then we create an H HTML form.
However notice that we have essentially kind of two main things for each entry.
We have the form the actual name of that element in the form and then label and then the form element
itself.
So this directly connects to if we go back to the index right here we say SGP underscore LPN that grabs
the session data from form the ACP alien which was defined appear as an attribute SGP underscore alien
which is what's being created on this home page of form that SGP underscore alien and these double braces
is essentially Ginger templating.
So notice we have this instance of the form the way form actually comes to be is that we pass back form
is equal to form and then these actual attribute calls are coming directly from the flask form object
here where we created these attributes of Sep length Sep with etc..
The one thing to notice is there is a hidden tag and this is the CSR f security fix feature with which
if you're familiar of Web Apps and forms most forms need that CSR f security feature in order to work
which is partially the same reason we set up this secret key in order for the flask form not to give
an error or security error.
And at the end we have the form submit button so you can imagine you could just copy and paste this
for as many entries as you needed where you have the label which is just this string code right here
in the text field and then the actual entry itself.
OK.
So don't forget to put method POST that's the home page the prediction page is even simpler.
We'll go ahead and return back all the items from the session saying here's the information you gave
people length.
Simple with pedal length and the pedal with and then you predicted flower casts is results.
Notice the double braces their results is being returned directly from.
If we score back down here prediction it returns back these results.
OK so that's the connection between home but each team L to the index function and prediction that each
time l to the prediction function go ahead and make sure you save all these changes and let's run this
Web site to do this I'm going to open up my anaconda prompt I'm going to make sure to activate my environment
we'll say Conda activates and then activate your tensor full environment whatever we happen to call
it CTF to GP for me once you activate it just make sure you have all the libraries installed you can
do pip install flask and we also introduced WTO forms which in case you don't have it in your environment
you simply just need to type pip install and then capital flask dash WTO f notice it's a dash on underscore
go ahead and run that already have it satisfied so I'm good to go OK next.
Go ahead and c d to wherever you save that file.
So for me it's under sensible to boot camp under 0 9.
Let's go 0 9 deployment and then I should be able to type out Python space my example that pi.
Go ahead and hit enter.
It should load up tents float just as the did before and then notice.
Now my server is running.
Go ahead and open up an instance of your browser and then you should see something that looks like this.
So here is a very simple HDMI form with no CSF no styling or anything but it should now be able to accept
simple lengths people with total length and pedal with.
So let's go ahead and give it some sort of pedal to predict from.
So I'm just gonna make up some numbers here we'll see what it says.
Let's say our super length is five pedal with is three point five pedal length let's say one point five
and then pedal with let's say on this new flowers zero point to go ahead and then click the Submit button
of analyse and if you did everything correctly it should then report back the information as a list
and say you reported or predicted class was so Tosa.
All right.
All that's left for us is to take this web application and actually deploy it online using some sort
of service in our case we'll use Heroku since it's free and that way any researcher out in the field
just needs to have Internet access in order to access are deployed tensor flow model.
We'll see you at the next lecture when we do all of this.