OK here we are where we left off last time.
It's now time to take our training data and create batches for training purposes off of it.
The way we can do this is by saying from tensor flow that carries that pre processing that sequence
import time series and then a capital G generator so go ahead and run that import and then off of this
go ahead and just call help on this time series generate generator class so we can explore just a little
bit about it.
So essentially what this is it's a super helpful utility class that generates these batches for this
sequence data.
So it takes in the sequence data and what we have to be familiar with is the actual arguments or parameters
that we provide this time series generator.
So what it does and the parameters that we're gonna be focused on is the data parameter.
Essentially what the actual X is or the source of this X that we're training on then the targets is
the label.
Again the source of the label and in our case they're actually both going to be the same thing.
We're both taking the data in our targets from the training data because we have time stamped sequence
information.
So we're going to essentially be passing in data and targets as the same source.
Okay then we have the length which is the length of the output sequences and number of time steps.
And then we have later on we'll see that there's a batch size.
So beyond the sampling rate or stride which wouldn't have to worry about really we're going to focus
on after that is batch size which is the number of time serious samples in each batch.
Okay so let's go ahead and play around these parameters just to make sure we understand time series
generator because a lot of the work is actually going to happen behind the scenes for us so I'm going
to create a couple of variables here.
One is length and this is the length of the output sequences in number of time steps.
So say 2 and then the batch size is essentially how many batches are we returning or how many time series
samples are returning in each batch.
So we'll go ahead and say 1.
And typically when it comes to sequence information of Time series just the batch size of one performs
pretty well.
So now it's time to actually create our generator so say Time series generator and then we have to decide
what is the source of our data.
Essentially what contains the X timestamp or the X index and in our case it's our scale training data
and then the next one is asking us well where's the Y label contain then for our case that's also skill
training data and it makes sense because a skilled training data has both series and information.
If we take a look at it it's right here at the scale training data that we saw in this case it's the
test but it's the same sort of format it already has the source of the index or X and our y our label.
Basically what we want is that the model given some value here on the index predicts what the value
should be here.
So later on we'll be able to pass in something like fifty point one and see what the model thinks the
output should be.
OK.
So these happen to have the same source then after this we have to decide on the length so we'll pass
in length that's equal to length and then we'll also say batch size is equal to batch size whips.
Make sure it's correct.
There we go.
And we're going to do is we're gonna play around with length and batch size to make sure that you understand
what these parameters actually do.
So let's take a look at the length of our scaled training data.
So recall our training data right now is four hundred and fifty one.
Let's take a look at the length of our generator object.
Essentially this gentleman our object is going to yield or generate batches for us.
So our generator object is 451 minus our length to which kind of makes sense because we're going to
do is explore what does the first batch actually look like.
So what the generator does if we take the generator and just ask for index 0 What does the first batch
look like.
Well we're going to do some tuple unpacking here because it returns both the x and the Y.
That should be predicted off of the X..
So this is the very first batch that is generated off of this.
So if we take a look at X it looks like this.
It's zero point for nine nine and zero point five for nine.
And we take a look at our y it's zero point five nine nine.
So what do those values actually mean.
Well let's take a look at our skilled training data again and see what's actually happening here.
Essentially what we're going to be telling our recurrent neural network model is given these two points
in a row try to predict this third point and you'll notice that the very first three numbers in our
script scale training dataset is four point ninety nine then five point four nine.
And then the third one is what it's going to mean to try to predict which is zero point five nine nine.
So that's essentially what this generator is using when it comes to length.
We're saying given this length of to predict this one into the future let's play around if that just
to make sure we understand.
Let's see what happens if we say our length is equal to four and then redefine this generator notice.
Now the generator is the length the skilled training data minus four which makes sense because we can't
have the generator go all the way to the end of our training data set because then it won't have those
extra values into the future to actually grab from.
So let's see what the actual x y generator at zero returns.
Now notice now since the length is four it's going to say OK here are the first four points.
Go ahead and predict point number five.
So that is what this length is representing.
Now this length shouldn't just be an arbitrary choice the length the X that actually think about because
it should be enough for the network to pick up on any seasonality or repeating effects.
If we think back to our actual data frame.
So if I plot my data frame.
Notice that it's a sine wave.
What I want to do is make sure that I feed my network a long enough sequence of information so I can
begin to pick up on any trends.
It's probably not very helpful for the network to just see one point to the past.
And one point into the future instead I probably want to at least have enough points so that a network
can pick up on this cyclical motion here of the trend.
So I can see that if I go from maybe zero to probably around twenty five points I can see a full cycle.
So that doesn't mean zero to twenty five on the x axis.
It means actually twenty five individual points and you can expand on this.
But keep in mind the larger the length then the longer the training time.
Okay.
So imagine you're dealing with yearly time series data and you were on a yearly sales cycle maybe had
holidays sales cycle summer et cetera you would probably want to include at least a year's worth of
information in this length variable.
So what we'll do is we'll go ahead and set this length to 25 and you can feel free to expand on that
but I'm going to now set length of twenty five so that when I actually look at my generator what it's
doing is it's feeding twenty five pieces information as X and then asking the model to predict what.
Point number twenty six looks like okay so it's four time series generator object.
Well we're going to do in the next lecture is actually create the model and then evaluate it and we'll
explore the differences between a simple recurrent neural network and using a long short term memory
unit.
I'll see you in the next lecture.