Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to focus on evaluating our model that we just train in the previous lecture.
Let's head to our Jupiter notebook and continue where we left off.
OK.
Here we are at the notebook where we left off last time after training the model as always what we can
do is we can say losses are actually in this case we're going to say metrics is equal to PD.
That data frame and say model history the history and the reason I'm saying metrics instead of just
losses is because let's take a look at what the history that history attribute actually return because
I also said keep track of accuracy here not just loss.
I get both my loss and accuracy on the training set as well as my validation loss and validation accuracy
which means I can plot both of them out.
So instead of saying metrics that plot it doesn't make sense to plot both loss and accuracy otherwise
you get a plot that looks like this.
Instead you should be plotting loss for validation loss and accuracy with validation accuracy.
So what we'll do is we'll pass analyst here with loss and validation loss.
Go ahead and plot those out and we can see how the loss for the training sets going down but it looks
like the validation loss was essentially starting to go up again.
So why we stopped the epoch training.
And if you want to we can also see the accuracy change so you can see accuracy versus the validation
accuracy note that the validation metrics basically just have V8 l underscore added before them.
And here we can see our accuracy continue on the training set.
So that's good.
Almost reaching a hundred percent accuracy but our validation set started to level off when we end the
training.
OK so in case you want to remember what metrics are available to you in your model you can say model
metrics names and I'll report back the actual metrics there at loss and accuracy and if you actually
want to get the metrics of these lost or accuracy on any set of data we can say model that evaluates
and we can pass in x test and Y categorical test.
Go ahead and say verbose is equal to zero so you don't see the actual running of this data through the
model and it will evaluate and basically return back loss and accuracy on the test set and it makes
sense that these are zero point zero four and zero point nine eight because if we take a look back at
this the last validation loss run on the test set was zero point zero four and zero point nine eight.
So they should be essentially the exact same numbers as the very last loop or less epoch.
And that's the evaluation on this test set.
You can also do the same thing for the training set and a report back these numbers loss and accuracy.
OK.
Recall the accuracy issues the calculation of what percentages you get right.
Loss here is the result of this categorical cross entropy function.
Now we understand how it performed during the epoch training.
Let's go ahead and just get the classification report and confusion matrix on our test data.
We can do this from S.K. learn not metrics import classification report and we can also import the confusion
matrix.
So we run that we'll go ahead and grab our predictions off of our test set and for this case we want
to predict classes based off the information in the x test dataset.
And now we have our predictions.
What we can do is recall that white cat test it's still in the shape of ten thousand by ten.
So what we want to do is make sure that we're comparing this correctly to.
Why test which is these actual labels.
So for our actually evaluation we need to pass and why test no longer these categorical ones.
So we'll say prints classification report compare the true why test values to our predicted values and
we can see the classification report essentially showing you the precision recall an f1 score per class.
So how will that do on zeros ones etc..
You can see it does fairly well across almost all classes with ninety nine percent accuracy and if you
want to do a deeper dive on this you can do a confusion matrix based off that same data.
Why test versus predictions and you can see the results here.
If you want to visualize this you can also use Seabourn to transform this so we can say Seabourn as
S.A. and then call a heat map which would essentially color the results that we have here.
So you can grab this and then paste in the results and we can make this figure a little larger can say
something like fig size equals 10 by 6 and you can run that and we'll show you a heat map just need
to add in annotations equal to true.
So I can see those values on top of it.
So that's a we can quickly visualize it.
Not super informative here because of how well the performances across all the numbers.
OK so that's one way to visualize it.
The last thing you're going to cover is how do you predict a single image.
So someone gave you an image of a single number.
So for example say my number is equal to x test 0.
So if I just peel team show my number here.
Make sure it did this correctly.
We'll say my number reshaped to 28 by 28.
There we go.
So here's my number.
It's reshaped 20 by 28.
So I can visualize it clearly it's a seven.
So if somebody gave you this single my number how would you actually predict it.
Well you would say model predict classes and then the only thing you'd have to be aware of is this reshaping.
So I would say my number not reshape and then the shape should end up being the batch size.
So essentially the number of images the width the height and then the color channels.
So in our case it's a single image.
So that's one.
It's 28 by 28.
And then there's one color channel.
So that's why I need to reshape it that way because that's the shape it was trained on given the fact
that we're feeding multiple numbers at a time.
We'll go ahead and predict the classes here and then we get back.
It predicts that it's a seven which makes sense because here I can see it's clearly a seven.
OK.
So the compositional all the work performed very well on the M this dataset.
Now that we know how to work with grayscale images we're going to do is expand our knowledge and in
the next series of lectures we'll follow a very similar path but working on color data with three color
channels red green and blue.
I'll see you there.