OK here we are where we left off last time.
Previously we learned how the time series generator works and what we're going to do is we'll go ahead
and make sure we create a generator object for us to train off of and what we want to do is make sure
that we get basically a full cycle or full seasonality within one length of one of our batches.
So we know that there's about five hundred points between zero and 50 and we can see here that a cycle
goes from about zero to maybe a little greater than five.
So we think about this we probably want at least somewhere between 50 and 100 points within our batches.
So let's go ahead and just say 50 here.
So say 50 and we'll send one batch at a time.
We'll go ahead and create this generator.
And now it's time to create our model.
We will say from tensor flow that care stop models import sequential and then we'll say from tensor
flow dark hair start layers import.
And we'll be using a dense layer and we'll begin by using a simple are an end layer and then we'll expand
this to an LSD him.
OK so the last we need to define is how many features are we actually training off of.
And in our case we just have one feature input which is x trying to predict Y.
So the number of features is just one.
And then to begin creating our models say models equal to sequential and then we'll say model the ad
and we'll add in a simple aren't N and the simple aren't N has a lot of parameter calls that you can
pass in but here we'll just focus on the basics such as the number of units how many neurons are here
and then the other important one is the input shape.
So you actually can't see here but we have to define what the actual input shape.
And luckily that's actually pretty easy given that we've already defined the generator.
So the actual number of neurons you want it somehow related to the length of the batches since I'm passing
in 50.
Let's go ahead and just choose 50 neurons here and then the other thing I need to put in here is the
input shapes so we'll say input shape is equal to.
And we'll say length by number of features and then after this we want our final prediction to just
be a single number.
So say that all goes into a single dense output and then we will compile this.
And this is essentially a continuous value or continuous label.
So we'll say optimizer is equal to atom but more importantly our lost function is just going to be mean
square error just as we always do for continuous values then go ahead and run that.
And then your model should be created and you can confirm a summary or a model by saying model that
summary and he can see the different layers.
So what we're going to do is instead of saying models that fit since we're using a generator we say
models that fit to generator and then we pass in the generator that we just created and then we choose
a specific number of epochs.
And later on in this lecture we'll show you had actually implement early stopping by creating an early
stopping generator based off your validation set but for this I'll go ahead and just train this for
let's say five epochs run this.
And keep in mind recurrent neural networks they definitely take a lot longer to train than typical artificial
neural networks.
So expect this to take quite a bit longer.
Even if our only training for five epochs I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done training.
All right I just fast forward in time and now I fit in five epochs.
Let's go ahead and evaluate our losses.
We can do this by simply saying losses equal to PD.
That data frame model history that history and then Let's plot these out
and we can see here we're definitely reducing on the first couple of epochs and almost looks like we're
increasing so later on we'll see how we can compare this to validation data and probably institute an
early stopping mechanism.
But let's go ahead and evaluate on our test data.
So to do this I'm going to show you our logic here before we write it into a for loop.
So let's imagine what is the first batch I should be passing in to my model to predict something on
the test set.
Well that should be coming from my scaled training data all the way from minus length to the end.
Essentially we're going to take the last twenty five points from our training set to predict one point
into the future which is the very first point in our test set.
So I have my first evaluation batch which I can take a look at if I want and I can see it here.
And essentially what I do is in order to pass this into the Model X need to reshape it to the shape
the model expects which to generalize it will be one by length by any number of features and then we'll
say first if our batch is equal to the reshaping of it and now the model should be able to predict this
will say model predict one point into the future given the last twenty five points in the training data.
So its model I predict first if our batch we run that and we get back our prediction.
Now we should recall that we are predicting scaled predictions so far so I can compare this to my scaled
test point and this is the very first point here in my scale test and we can see we're actually doing
pretty good.
I predicted zero point nine for eight and my first scale test point is zero point nine for nine.
So definitely not bad.
Well we need to do is we need to put this logic now in a for loop to keep moving essentially 25 points
and as we keep predicting we'll add an additional predicted point until we're essentially predicting
or forecasting off predictions.
So what I will do is essentially create all this logic that we did here in these four cells and put
it into a for loop.
So what I want to do is say my test predictions is an empty list and then I have my first evaluation
batch equal to that scale training data where I have minus length all the way to the end and then my
current batch that essentially I am currently using will start off as my first evaluation batch reshaped
to 1 length and features and then what I need to do is essentially create a for loop that keeps appending
this but something I want to show you is if I run this.
Notice that my first evaluation batch is right here.
But the shape of my current batch essentially after I reshape this looks like this.
Notice the extra arrays and what I need to be doing is I need to keep appending all this data except
for that first original point because I'm replacing that with my new predicted point at the end.
Essentially moving one step forward.
So what I'm going to be doing and this is where the code gets a little complex because it's a lot of
num pi indexing but I will be running this command.
I will be saying end p append current batch and this is where the indexing gets really complicated.
So watch carefully will pass in the following commands.
Essentially saying based off the dimensions grab everything the first I and everything in this last
dimension but in the actual dimension that's holding the data go from index 1 all the way to the end
essentially dropping that first original point because we don't need it anymore since we're not actually
using it.
And so I will then put in my predicted point.
So imagine we have some predicted value.
This is just to make it obvious.
Let's say my predicted value is ninety nine.
Notice I have three braces since that's going to be the same format that predictions are in.
If we take a look here.
Notice I have two braces and then my number.
So it's gonna happen is I need it to have an extra set of brackets here so I can use N.P. append.
So if I say here ninety nine along axis is equal to 1 so make the say this is my predicted value in
passing in it right here.
Go ahead and run this and let's compare this now from our current batch to our first evaluation batch.
So our first evaluation batch goes eight point three seven seven point nine eight what I want in my
current batch as I keep moving is go ahead and drop the very first point.
And now I'm at seven point nine eight.
So notice I dropped eight point three seven and move straight here.
And after dropping that.
Go ahead and add our predicted point to the end.
So instead of ending at nine point two five we scroll down here we go from nine point two five to that
ninety nine that I inserted.
So a lot of this essentially isn't that complicated.
The complex part is actually implementing it with NUM pi.
So all this code is doing is it saying go ahead and move that current batch along by one time step which
we talked about in the theory lectures that we just keep moving this forward and forward the complex
part is because we're dealing with so many dimensions the calls are actually kind of a little weird
you only grabbing from one here all the way to the end and the middle dimension and then you're gonna
have to set the predicted value with a set amount of dimensions because it's technically three dimensional
because it's a tensor.
And then we append along X equal to one because we're spending along the information axis here.
Okay so I know that's a little bit complicated.
I just wanted to kind of walk through that logic and then we're going to essentially make a for loop
out of that logic.
So I'm going to copy and paste what I have here because this actually doesn't change the initiation
of the logic doesn't change what we do then it was we say for I in range and we're gonna do this for
the entire test that will say for length the test the go ahead and say my current prediction based off
the current batch is model that predict current batch and I'm going to index an item off of that to
be my current prediction and then I will take my test predictions which remember starts off as an empty
list and I simply append my current prediction and what I have to do is then move my current batch forward
one time step and that's what we do is kind of complicated logic here so we'll copy this and say and
update my current batch is equal to NPA pen current batch.
This stays the same except when I'm inserting is not some arbitrary value of ninety nine instead it's
going to be notice I'm deleting the ninety nine and the braces and say my current prediction.
So keep a really careful eye here on the braces in fact I would highly recommend use copy and paste
this from our notes.
So what I'm doing here is to walk you through it is I have an entry list for my test predictions.
I grab my first evaluation batch which is the last essentially in our case twenty five points of the
training batch and then I reshape it to make sure my model can accept it based off the length the number
of features and then I set that to my current batch.
I do my very first prediction.
That's my current prediction right here.
And then what I'm going to do is I say OK go ahead and grab that current prediction and dependent to
that list.
But now to keep predicting into the future I have to I have to move my current batch one step forward
which is essentially what this does is it gets rid of that first item and instead replaces that by adding
the current prediction all the way to the very end.
Now if I run this for loop what's going to happen is I should essentially get now pure test predictions
by the end.
So this is now my predictions for the entire test range.
OK.
And now I'm going to essentially be comparing that to my scaled test data and we'll hopefully see it
work well.
Remember that this is scaled so let's go ahead and inverse that transformation.
We can do this easily by saying my true predictions are equal to scalar dot inverse transform these
test predictions that we just created.
And now my true predictions are in the right scale.
OK so once that's done all I need to do is figure out ways compare this recall that I still have my
test data frame with that test set.
So what I can do is say add in a column called predictions and set that equal to true predictions.
Keep in mind you may get a warning about something saying a value is trying to be set on a copy of a
slice.
It's essentially warning you hey you're editing permanently your current test data frame so you can
go ahead and ignore that warning.
That's actually the behavior we want.
It's essentially painless telling you hey you're editing this permanently by running this but that's
exactly what I want.
I want something that looks like this.
And then once that's done let's go ahead and plot it out and see how he did.
We'll say test that plot and we can expand on this figure size a little bit just so it's clear and we'll
say oops fig size is equal to twelve by eight.
Go ahead and run that and you should see something that looks like this.
Notice our predictions are definitely not perfect but it's really interesting to see that our model
is actually able to start to mimic the behavior of a sine wave.
However you'll notice that as we're predicting further and further into the future our values are getting
further and further off which makes sense because we're predicting off predictions.
So this very first point should be the most accurate because we're using real data those last twenty
five turning points to predict my first point into the test set and then as I move to the next point.
Now I'm using twenty four points in the train data plus my predicted point in the test range to predict
a new point and then I'm using two predictions to predict the next point then three plus the old ones
until all the way to the end where I'm using essentially twenty four train points or excuse me twenty
four points in my test range that I predicted plus one original trend data predict the last one.
So it kind of makes sense that we're getting further and further off because we're doing essentially
true forecasting at the very end but our behavior is looking pretty good.
There's a pretty smooth prediction line and it looks like a sine wave.
So coming up next we're going to see if we can improve on this by using an Ellis team unit.
I'll see you there.