Here is what I'm calling the magnificent seven of the technical BA's
skill areas where you can best focus your energies.
Design the user interface and user experience.
You know the requirements and the users very well,
so you can provide valuable insights here by utilizing the tools to
develop the user interface and experience mock-ups.
The method or technique known as prototyping is used to elicit
and validate stakeholder or user requirements.
Again, you can apply some great tools to perform this function.
Data modeling.
Today, data is everywhere,
and you better know where it is and how to get to it and how to
reshape or model it to meet the customer's requirements.
Business data analytics is the skill of analyzing raw data in
order to make decisions about that information.
This will include data mining, SQL, and visualization as well.
Here are the other three technical BA's skill areas where you should focus
your time in learning and applying them in your daily work.
Interface analysis is a connection between two entities,
people, systems, applications, etc.
No person, system or application is an island.
Everything is connecting to everything.
Quality assurance test plan and test cases.
Developing the test plan and the individual test cases will help you
validate that the software engineers built the system to spec.
Off-the-shelf solutions, cloud services, and other building blocks.
Not every problem should be solved by custom solutions.
If you can find the perfect off-the-shelf, pre-built solution, well, use it.
Typically, though, you may need to integrate a couple of off-the-shelf solutions.
I could have just used the term off-the-shelf solutions and left it at that,
but by far, the largest off-the-shelf solution,
if you will, on the planet is cloud computing,
and then all the other thousands of other cloud-based building blocks.
There is no way I can cover all the tools you may need to know since the
technical BA's domain is broad and varies by organization,
so I have curated the list down to a handful,
these seven, that I believe may provide the biggest bang for the buck.
Before we dive in, I want to tell you about my approach for each skill area.
I will first tell you what it is, then why the skill area or tool is important,
and when you might apply the skill area,
and lastly,
we will take a closer look with an example or two of the tools in the
market that would be representative of the area.
I will never promote any tool in particular,
but point out tools in that area to give you a start on where to research further.