Another important skill is data modeling.
Your business use cases in your UI/UX prototype will begin to
provide some of the necessary information by which you can
begin creating your data model.
Now for a little humor.
Data modeling is the process of designing a complex
set of interrelated data structures,
allowing data to be lost while retaining a complete record of the
logical relations between the missing items.
Okay, in all seriousness,
data is the new raw material of the business world today.
Don't ever forget that.
Let's define data modeling.
First, a data model is an abstract representation of data.
Data models include data structures, like fields or elements,
and their relationships.
How does that data model get created?
Well, by data modeling.
Data modeling is the analysis of data objects and their
relationships to other data objects.
Typically, the data model is depicted as an ER diagram,
known as an entity relationship diagram.
This is a conceptual model of the business data.
Data modeling is often the first step in database design in
object-oriented programming as the designers first create a conceptual
model of how the data items relate to each other.
So why use data modeling?
Today, data is everything.
Data modeling provides an enormous amount of business knowledge that you need
to know to enhance your understanding of the requirements.
The outcome of the data modeling process,
the model, relationships, constraints, issues,
challenges,
etc., then become artifacts of the business architecture and are added
to the requirements portfolio for the IT project.
Formal data modeling of the information held by the
business may expose new requirements,
and inconsistencies will be identified as well.
Designing new data and discovering old data.
With new requirements will come new forms of data,
but also you will discover old or existing data that must be
part of the new system and data model.
So another benefit of data modeling is identifying
all of the other data sources, databases,
spreadsheets, APIs, and the like.
It is a very valuable process of eliciting and validating
requirements much beyond data alone, so get good at it.
When to use data modeling.
Well, pretty much always.
It is very hard for me to imagine an application not needing data.
Applications are more data rich than ever today.
To enhance your understanding of the requirements, as I mentioned before.
To provide the data model to the IT team as a starting point for
them to build out the new physical data stores,
such as SQL databases or other implementations,
or design the technical connections to existing data via APIs,
database links or using extract, transform and load tools,
also known as ETLs, for example.
Also you can use data modeling if your organization has
embraced using data dictionaries.
Your data modeling process will rely heavily on the dictionary,
as well as contribute and populate the data dictionary
further from your analysis outcomes.
Again, there are a ton of data modeling tools, and here is just a sampling.
ER/Studio, Sparx Enterprise Architect, Oracle SQL Developer Data Modeler,
CA ERwin, IBM InfoSphere Data Architect,
many others of course.
This is just a representative list to get you started in the right direction.
Please don't try and read this slide.
The purpose of this slide is to point out the visualization of
a database schema and its relationships. As usual, I will always emphasize visual tools.