Many times, quality assurance, creating test plans and test cases,
is done last, or not at all.
Even if you have a QA department or team,
the technical BA can play a role and bridge the gap by
providing some high-level QA planning material to the
developers or the quality assurance team as well.
"Quality means doing it right, even when no one is looking.
" That's a famous quote by Henry Ford.
It seems like testing is the last thing done in projects,
and sometimes not even at all.
So the technical BA can jump in and help out even if no one is looking.
What is quality assurance?
Well,
quality assurance is one aspect of the larger discipline of quality management.
The quality assurance function is concerned with confirming that
a company's quality requirements will be met.
Quality assurance is a way of preventing mistakes and defects in
systems and avoiding problems when delivering systems,
products or services to customers.
Software quality assurance consists of a means of monitoring the
software engineering processes used by the developers and their
methods used to ensure quality.
This is not part of the scope of this module or of the
technical BA's role in my opinion, but wanted to point it out for completeness.
A technical BA is typically not involved in these kinds of QA activities,
and they are typically the domain of the IT department itself.
But let's see where the technical BA does fit in.
Now let's discuss what I am calling the QA umbrella.
There is a part of QA that relates to the methods used to create
software solutions and the monitoring of that activity,
maybe like programming standards and unit testing.
There is the test plan that must be created for every new system,
major release or other deliverable.
Then the test cases, which are really a subset of the test plan,
and each test case is testing a specific feature,
so you could have hundreds of test cases.
And lastly the actual testing,
either manual where someone is literally following the test
cases as outlined and trying them out,
or automated testing where the test cases are being
implemented by another piece of software.
I think the technical BA can certainly participate in these two boxed
activities as makes sense for your environment,
designing and authoring the test plan and associated test cases.
Now let's drill a little deeper into these two.
Here is what I would recommend with the technical BA's role
with the test plan and the test cases.
A test plan is a single document detailing the activities of all the things
that must be performed in order to test the solution.
It includes the objectives, resources,
and processes required to ensure that the business
requirements have been achieved and validated.
Since the technical BA already has probably worked on the requirements,
understands the stakeholders and the product backlog,
I think they are well positioned to write the test plan.
Secondly, a test case is a specification of the inputs,
execution conditions, testing procedure,
and expected results to actually test a single feature.
Since your solution has many features,
you will have a test case for every feature or
multiple test cases for a single feature.
The technical BA is very well suited to participate in the
design and creation of these artifacts.
Why might you want to use technical BAs to do quality assurance?
Well, here's a few reasons.
Lack of QA resources.
Just not enough people to go around.
Why not jump in and help?
Knowledge of the requirements.
The TBA will have a lot of deep knowledge about those requirements.
Now you may even join the QA team to help test.
If they need more resources, join the team for this phase of the project.
Maybe even act as the product owner for this role.
In other words, as the quality team is doing the testing,
they might find different things that you'll be able to easily
answer and address because you're close to the product owner
and you know the requirements.
Provide QA support as needed.
Maybe you'll help with the test plan, the test cases,
maybe even the testing itself.
Think of yourself in the technical BA role,
again,
as having a very broad role that helps you bridge the
gap between the business and IT.
You are that special resource that can do so much more in your company.
Most testing, especially in small and midsize companies,
is all manual, but there are some pretty cool automated test tools out there,
and here are a few: Selenium, Appium, TestComplete,
Ranorex, HP QuickTest, Cucumber, Watir, and Tricentis.
There are many, many more out there.
This is just to point you in the right direction and start your
research to find the automated tool that may work for you.
Here is an example of a product from Tricentis for packaged app testing.
Now, I am not expecting you to read any of this,
but to show you that the tool is a visual representation
of the results of automated testing.
So a visual tool like this can be invaluable. I will always emphasize visual tools.