Now let's say you have a pretty good idea of the
requirements with documented use cases, or a product backlog,
or more traditional requirements documents,
you might consider prototyping your system.
Prototyping is one of the most important skills of this module.
Let's see why.
Let's define prototyping.
Another term for prototyping you've likely heard of is proof of concept, or PoC.
The method or technique known as prototyping is primarily used to
elicit and validate stakeholder or users' requirements.
The prototyping process is iterative,
which means a repeated cycle of refined prototypes coming closer to the
desired result as the number of cycles increases.
Prototyping produces an early model of the potential ultimate
solution based on the known requirements.
Also, prototyping identifies missing or poorly specified requirements.
The interaction with the customer and the process of refinement
always brings to light overlooked requirements,
or further refinement of your requirements.
Prototyping demonstrates what the product may visually look
like and how it interacts with other actors,
be it people or other systems.
Now the user interface,
user experience design elements we talked about earlier may be a
major portion of the prototyping outcomes,
but the process of prototyping is much broader and a more encompassing activity.
Let's see why you might want to use the prototyping method.
It allows you to experiment and try things before making
any major investment in time and money.
It provides a visual and/or structural
representation of a product's future state.
Prototyping allows for stakeholders or users to provide input
and feedback early in the design process.
Prototyping also builds a strong relationship and trust between
the technical BA and the product owner or users.
This is very important and it helps you better bridge the gap
between the requirements and the IT team.
Prototyping also encourages constructive feedback since the
users can feel more comfortable critiquing the throwaway
design rather than the final product.
Prototyping also applies to non-visual elements.
For example,
you want to experiment and try out accessing a transactional
banking API to see if it can address your needs.
There's no UI in this case, and therefore it is a non-visual prototype.
When to use prototyping tools.
Any requirement that is complex,
whether it is with or without a user interface element,
would be highly recommended.
Any design that you need more information or analysis to
further understand the requirements.
Remember,
prototyping gives you great feedback that you can use to refine your approach.
Prototyping should be used in conjunction with business use cases
or user stories to be the most successful so the requirements are
closely driving the prototype outcomes.
Prototyping helps sustain end-user involvement.
That is,
prototyping ensures that the end users are constantly involved and
providing feedback which is incorporated in the prototype,
which will result in a more usable and acceptable system.
The users will feel more connected and this process builds trust,
and trust is very important.
Lastly, prove it can be done.
That is, can you prove that what you envision can be achieved,
or at least have a good possibility it can be achieved,
technically speaking?
Your prototyping tools of the trade are,
in fact, most of the very things we talked about in this module.
All of the following tools and methods are commonly
used in developing prototypes, by themselves or mix and match.
User interface and user experience.
Data modeling.
Business data analytics.
Interface analysis.
Off-the-shelf solutions.
The technical BA role is a very exciting place to be as you design
and prototype the future systems of your company, so get good at it.