Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the Introduction to the course,
The Technical Business Analyst.
Contrary to popular belief, technical business analysts are not boring.
In fact,
the technical business analyst is in a very unique organizational position
to have one of the most exciting jobs in the company.
You are situated at the juncture of business and technology.
I love business and technology very much.
Early in my career, I was all about technology,
but realized that the application of technology in fulfilling a
business need and contributing to accomplishing those business
requirements is what really turns me on professionally.
I hope you can join in the fun. Let's see what's in store for you in this course.