For completeness, let's talk about the technical BA's basic tools.
There is, of course, the all-famous Microsoft Office Suite.
MS Word can be used for preparing requirement specification documents.
You can create new templates using Microsoft Word or use existing
templates for the documentation of software requirements.
Microsoft Excel or other spreadsheet tools are great,
as well,
and even use the macros if you need some additional
data manipulation and analysis.
Excel allows you to aggregate data from all kinds of data resources,
and create nifty charts and graphs as well.
Microsoft PowerPoint.
You must get good at preparing and delivering formal presentations.
As a technical business analyst,
you'll be faced with situations where you need to
communicate ideas to project stakeholders on the business
side and also to the IT technical side.
Even Access is still around and used widely.
Also, there is the Google complement of Docs, Sheets, Slides, Gmail, and more.
And there are other platforms that provide the same functionality.
Now, you should also be pretty good at a few drawing and workflow tools as well.
That never hurts.
And lastly, if you are really bold and you want to get your hands dirty,
then maybe take a programming class or two.
Maybe .NET or Java or some scripting language.
But again, there are tons of programming languages out there,
so find out what your company mostly uses,
and then learn that one or two languages that would fit
in quite nicely into your toolkit.
Okay, this should be your basic toolkit or something like it,
no matter what kind of technical BA you are or where you work.
My magnificent seven are the core comprehensive TBA skills for sure,
but there are a lot of other tools that could come in very handy.
Here is a short list for your reference and further discovery.
Activity diagram, business process diagram,
business use cases, dataflow diagram, data dictionary,
entity-relationship diagram, role map, state diagram,
and SWAT analyses.
There are many other tools like this in the same genre,
so check these out, pick the ones that might work for you, learn them, and apply them.