Let's drill into more detail on what a business analyst does for a living.
The analyst interacts with the business stakeholders and the subject matter
experts in order to understand their problems and needs.
The analyst gathers documents and analyzes business needs and requirements.
The analyst solves business problems, that is lays out the approaches,
methods, processes, and tools that should get the job done,
and, as needed, literally designs the solutions,
but that's not all.
And there is more.
Once the requirements have been discovered and gathered,
your job has only just begun.
You must also analyze requirements, document requirements,
validate requirements, prioritize requirements,
communicate those requirements, communicate with IT professionals in particular,
change management, and work within waterfall or agile methodologies,
and that just scratches the surface.
There is certainly a lot more.
There are many designations, titles or monikers of an analyst.
Let's discuss a few.
Business analyst.
This is the typical, generic designation of pretty much all analysts.
Business Architect.
They perform activities such as strategic alignment,
creating business operating models, and determining a strategic business vision,
as examples.
Business process analysts may perform activities such as developing and
modeling business processes with workflow and process engines to document
and compare as is and to the process models.
Business systems analysts.
Well, they take requirements as inputs, create functional specifications,
specify how a system will do the what,
and interface directly with the developers.
They also write the tactical requirements from the business requirements.
Sometimes a business systems analyst is shortened just a systems analyst title.
Data analyst.
The data analyst is the professional who's focused on
analysis and problem solving related to data,
types of data,
and relationships among data elements within a business system or IT system.
They perform logical data modeling, identify patterns in data,
design how to translate and transfer data into other
data stores such as data warehouses,
and also design and create reports or visualizations to enable users to
easily consume and make quality business decisions.
Now, there are a lot of other common titles for these roles,
and they may be requirements engineer, requirements analyst,
application consultant, and application analyst.
As you can see,
every organization may have slightly different titles
with different job descriptions.
So, who is doing business analysis?
Well, just about everyone.
The job of doing business analysis is performed by people in
organizations that may range in job title from product owner,
developer, project manager or project leader,
product manager, subject matter experts,
and certainly many more.
So we can see that there are lots of roles doing analysis,
even though their titles do not end with the word analyst.
And, there are many true analyst roles as well as we discussed on the previous slide.