Here's my point of view.
Always ensure what you are doing is aligned with the business objectives
and the agile development team's skills and capabilities.
Agile/Scrum is a software development methodology,
not a project management process or approach.
The developers and technical team will be focused on the software,
as they should be,
and you could provide the organization's big picture in what the
enterprise management is thinking from a business perspective.
The technical BA as a member of the agile/Scrum team is essential,
and by reinforcing the product owner's vision to the team,
this will greatly help bridge the gap.
Since the technical BAs or just business analysts are
typically in the IT department,
it is up to the IT leadership to be proactive and approach the product owner,
or his or her management,
and discuss how best to provide support to the product owner,
either as a partner or proxy.
And as I mentioned, both are very good options,
but I think the partnership works the best.
The technical BA with the right skills, you could do all three of these roles.
The technical BA, the Scrum Master, and the project manager,
what a fantastic combination of skills and career opportunities.
Remember, life is not perfect in the agile/Scrum world.
Set your expectations accordingly, and adapt and be flexible.
Let's summarize this module.
We discussed the agile foundation, which includes four process groups: projects,
releases, iterations, and daily work.
And the typical participants: product owner, the dev team, and the Scrum Master.
Then we drilled into the dev team,
which could be made up of developers of course,
but also other professionals such as QA engineers,
database engineers, and many, many others.
Be an advocate for the agile technical BA role.
In my observations of agile teams, the technical BA,
or any BA for that matter, is missing from the dev team.
Since business people are great at business and technical
people are great at technical activities,
it allows an opportunity for the technical BA to bridge that gap.
I strongly recommend technical BAs participating on the agile dev teams.
Use INVEST and SMART techniques.
They help keep stories and tasks well-structured and easy to understand.
We discussed the relationship options the technical BA
can have with the product owner,
either as a proxy that is taking the place of the true product
owner and representing the product owner,
or as a partner performing all of the behind the scenes heavy lifting.
Yet, the product owner is still personally participating with the agile team.
This is important,
people will engender more trust to the product owner than a proxy technical BA,
so keep that in mind.
Regarding the technical BA and the agile dev team,
we discussed that the technical BA can be on the team as a regular
member performing business analyst activities,
or doing both analysis and Scrum Master activities,
or analysis and project manager activities.
Lastly, maybe the super technical BA could do all three.
What a powerful combination.
Do you have an organizational IQ?
Be aware of organizational crosswinds that might affect the team's productivity.
Be aware of the organizational issues, personalities,
politics, and budgets since it is you, the technical BA,
who is the most qualified to communicate and educate
senior leaders on the project's progress.
Avoid self-perceived limits.
Your attitude and your ability to push through self-perceived
limitations will play a key role in how successful you will be
as a technical BA in the agile world.
No two agile teams are alike.
In fact,
they are typically quite different and unique based on the
talents and resources available in the company.
Remember, Agile means adaptability and flexibility.
So don't be shy, lean in, and make a difference by being the super technical BA.
In the next module,
we'll not only summarize the entire course reviewing the key takeaways,
but also list a few other Pluralsight-related courses you might like,
discuss certifications that apply to the technical BA, and other training resources.