Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture about building your personal network.
So it's important for you to realize that a huge amount of job opportunities are never publicly shown
.
So companies tend to hire through the networks of their employees.
If you just apply to a company straight through their job site if it's a large company your application
may never be actually seen.
So it's important to build a network and leverage it when you're hunting for a job.
So as far as building a network it can be difficult to start out especially if you're young and out
of school.
So we're going to look at some options to build out your network.
So there's a lot here.
So you can just go ahead and check out the PowerPoint presentation that's attached as a resources lecture
.
But I was going to go through a few of these if you're coming straight to a school alumni organizations
and classmates are a great way to go as far as building a personal network.
If you're older and already have children your children's contact such as PTA little league scouts are
parents of those friends of your kids are also great contacts for building a personal network.
Let them know that you're available for a job and you're looking around.
Bring it up in conversation.
Former employers including supervisors and co-workers your friends your relatives members of clubs such
as your gym either your softball team or hiking club are all great ways to build out your personal network
.
Again strike in conversation that you're looking for a job on the market.
Also members of the church temple synagogue or mosque are great resources for building up a network
.
Your neighbors both past and current even just professionals.
Your attorney or accountant your doctor your dentist is who knows they may have a link to someone who
knows that there's an opening at their company and then volunteer associations.
It's a great way to spend time volunteering and you also make it valuable network connections there
.
Just remember to be proactive and to give as much as you get.
You just can't be taking everything from your network opportunities.
You should be giving equal amount of time.
So if they're giving an effort in helping you find a job you should be rewarding them with an effort
back.
Also make sure to take full advantage of the opportunities your network provides in the next lecture
.
We're going to be discussing networking events and Web sites to help you find networking events.
All right.
With that being said let's go ahead and move on to the next lecture.