Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on company types overview.
So in this lecture we're going to give a brief overview of things you can expect from various company
types and the size of companies.
We're just going to cover what big four companies are like and what that term actually means.
Medium sized companies and then startups which are going to divide into startups that are small.
Route 1 to 15 employees and then well-funded startups.
OK so first off what is the term big for mean.
So Big 4 is just a collective term for the top four large public tech companies.
And is actually more than four of them but the famous ones that are usually grouped together are Microsoft
Facebook Amazon Apple and Google slash alphabet.
So when someone's referring to the Big Four they usually mean some of these type of companies.
So what do we know about the big four.
Well the culture can actually vary greatly between all of them.
So you should check out Glassdoor reviews for specific information on each of them since the culture
of Amazon can be really different between the culture of Microsoft or Google or Facebook.
We also know that they recruit heavily from the top five to ten universities based on the U.S. News
rankings.
Since these are large public tech companies usually have some sort of strong management structure in
place and some sort of formal onboarding process for new employees.
You should also take into account that decisions at the company level need to take shareholders into
account since there are large public companies now there are exceptions such as Amazon who has basically
instead of focusing on profits have put a lot of their revenue back into the company.
One last thing you should also note that they have a huge amount of applicants.
So networking is the key to getting a job at a Big Four company.
Up next are medium sized companies so these can vary greatly but they're usually local companies and
they may have a few satellite offices.
There also may be a stronger focus on profitability since if they're already a medium size company and
don't have any funding source or not a startup they need to focus on profitability in order to keep
the bills paid.
Management structure can possibly be more informal.
You have to try to ask about this during your interview and we'll touch more on medium sized companies
in general later on this course and then startups.
So focusing on small startups the ones to have between 1 to 15 employees you should note they usually
offer lower salaries but higher equity he should also keep in mind the high probability of failure but
90 percent of these startups fail within the first four years.
Equity can also be a complicated subject so you should check out this link right here.
Stock option counsel that come in just google around so you can really understand what an equity percentage
means and the type of stocks that are available to you.
The pros of a startup at this level is you're going to learn a lot but you're also going to have to
work a lot.
And it's important to understand that people and the early hires are key at this stage.
So if you're interviewing at this type of company that's still small you should really make sure that
you get along with everyone you interview with.
So the other type of startup are the well-funded startups these are the type of companies that you've
heard that have had huge funding rounds such as Oubre or lift's those kind of companies.
So salaries at these well-funded startups can be comparable to big for large public tech companies.
Petion note to equity at this stage can be pretty complicated given the large amount of funding rounds
.
So keep that in mind and really do your research to understand what an offer of equity really means
for good list these type of companies you can check out breakout lists dot com and you should keep in
mind that funding doesn't guarantee success.
All right.
So inclusion always research the companies beforehand and you should really be thinking about your work
life balance and what your long term career goals are and what type of company is right for you.
So were going to touch on this topic again later on this course.
So this was just a brief overview.
Up next we're going to get a brief overview of the various job types in programming.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture