Hello everyone and welcome to the recursions section of this course.
So in this lecture hall we're going to do is quickly go over what you can expect in this entire section
and then we'll go over the introduction to recursion lecture.
OK.
So what's coming up in the section of the course.
First we have an overview of recursion what it is and why we use it.
Then we'll have some basic recursion examples that we'll walk through.
After that we'll get an introduction to memorization and dynamic programming and how it relates to recursion
in general and then we'll end it with for real interview practice questions for you to check your solutions
against.
OK.
So it's going to get started with this lecture where we go over the basics of recursion through an introduction
.
So what is recursion.
There's two main instances of recursion.
The first is one recursion is used as a technique in which a function makes one or more calls to itself
.
This is the main instance we're going to be focusing on throughout this entire section since the one
that comes up most in interview style questions.
It's important to know that a second instance of recursion is when a data structure itself uses smaller
instances of the exact same type of data structure when it represents itself.
We'll focus on this later on in other sections of this course.
But for now we'll focus on when a function makes one or more calls to itself.
OK so why use recursion in general.
Recursion provides a powerful turreted for performing repetitive tasks in which either a for loop or
a WHILE loop isn't really ideal.
Should be noted that most modern programming languages support recursion and recursion serves as a great
tool for building up particular data structures.
So let's go ahead and start this with an introduction by example using a factorial function.
So the factorial function is the noter of an exclamation point and hopefully already familiar with it
.
It's defined as the product of integers from 1 to some number n so and factorial or an exclamation mark
is equal to N times and times 1 Times and Time Times.
Excuse me.
End times and minus one times and minus two times and minus three.
Continued on until you reach 3 times 2 times 1 etc..
Now what's important to know here is if any equals zero that n factorial is equal to 1.
That's important to know because we're going to be using this as our base case later on.
So let's look at his quick example for factorial is equal to 4 times 3 times 2 times 1 equals 24.
So how can we state this in a recursive manner.
And this is where the concept of that base case is really going to come into play.
So we can see that four factorial is equal to 4 times and we can group everything else together 3 times
2 times 1.
So we realize that this is actually equal to 4 factorial is equal to 4 times 3 factorial which is equal
to 24.
So you know here we can keep making recursive calls to this factorial function and to write that formally
we can say n factorial Z could n times and minus 1 factorial.
OK so the base case is the key to understanding this.
If any equals zero and factorial equals 1.
So this means that the base case occurs when N equals zero.
The recursive cases are defined in the previous equation right here.
So we have the recursive cases and then we have a base case and this will be clear when we actually
code this out live in a Jupiter notebook.
So quick reminder whenever you're trying to develop a recursive solution it's very important to think
about the base case as your solution will need a return to the base case.
Once all the recursive cases have been worked through.
So eventually after going through every single recursion case you'll come up to the base case.
OK so let's actually code this out so it becomes a little more clear what a base case is and what the
recursive cases are and how we can build recursive functions off of that.
OK so we're going to jump now to the Jupiter note book and code out the factorial example.
All right everyone.
Now we're at the Jupiter notebooks as always.
You can check out more information on what we just went over in the introduction to recursion notebook
here and it goes over everything we just went over in the slides.
So let's go ahead and get started with some life code which is also in this note book and will be working
out through this sample notebook.
OK so recursion and let's go ahead and tackle this factorial function number the factorial function
states that end factorial.
We write this in a recursive manner is equal to end times and minus one factorial in our base case is
if and is equal to zero then and factorial is equal to 1.
So you can imagine eventually this term here and minus one or minus two and minus three etc etc. will
eventually become an equal zero and we'll have this base case.
OK so let's start out writing or function
we'll call it fact and it will accept the number and it's going to return the factorial event.
So we want to start off with the base case.
So the base case happens like we said.
If n is equal to zero I will return 1.
OK so let's go ahead and mark that through a comet as our base case and then we're going to have an
else statement.
So if the base case isn't met we want to do is return that N times.
And this is where the recursive call comes into play.
We call the function itself and call it on and minus one.
And that's our function.
That's really all there is to it.
This is a pretty basic example of recursion.
Now we can see the factorial of 5 is equal to 120.
So what's important to know is we had an if statement to check if a base case occurred here.
Without this function it wouldn't have successfully completed running.
And there's a figure in the Jupiter note book free to go and check out so we can see what's actually
happening when we run this function.
Sometimes recursion is a little hard to visualize So hopefully this helps you out here so we input our
function and we input 5 into the function.
So it says all right five factorial.
So we pop back here.
We're putting five for five factorial.
I'll check if it's the base case which is not so or else.
And if it's not that then it's going to return end times factorial and minus one.
So it's returning five times for factorial.
Now remember this recursive.
So now it's calling for factorial.
So that becomes four times three factorial etc. Three times two factorial two times one factorial and
then that goes to 1.
Returns 1 two times one equals two returns to three times to 6 returns 6 turns only for returns 120
and that's how we get our final value.
So make sure you take your time.
You can follow this chart for the top of the bottom and or.
Yeah and then back up to reach the base case.
So recursions a really powerful tool and it can be a bit of a tricky concept to implement.
So we're going to do it in case you had a little trouble understanding what just happened here in the
next couple of lectures.
We're going to go over a few more example problems for recursion then afterwards hopefully you'll be
fully prepared to face some real interview questions involving recursion.
What I want you to do is if this was a little bit troublesome for you.
Or are you still not completely understanding it.
See if you can add some print statements to print out all the steps or print out some sort of statement
for yourself so you can see what's actually happening as the function is being run.
OK I'll see you at the next lecture.