Hello everyone and welcome to the array sequence section of this course and this lecture will be getting
a brief overview of what the section is about and what to expect in this section.
So in this section we'll get a brief introduction to array's that includes low level arrays and dynamic
arrays.
We'll learn about how arrays are constructed why they have the big old properties that they have.
And we can think about that as the first section of this section of arrays so this section of the array
sequences can be thought of as into portions one where we learn about on a computer science level how
array sequences are built and then on the second part of it is going to be all the interview problems
so we'll have a series of array based interview questions free to solve out on your own and we'll ease
into this second half of the section with an array based mini project.
We're going to build out based on a project our understanding of array sequences and how they work.
So the first half will be mostly slide based and you'll be just looking mostly at notes the computer
science decisions made that really build out arrays properties will do our mini project and then you'll
start tackling actual interview questions presented to you in the Jupiter notebook format.
OK.
So let's go ahead and continue on just a brief introduction to arrays.
Very brief on what we're actually talking about when we use the term arrays in Python array sequences
in Python Sometimes you'll hear the term arrays and strings as Array sequences in Python.
So that's because the term array or array sequence is pretty general across all languages and in Python
We have three main sequence classes at least these are the three main ones we're going to focus on in
this section.
We have the list the tuple and the string.
So all of these support indexing.
So for example if I had any of these objects and index them and zero they would all return the elements
1.
OK.
So again as I mentioned for the rest of this section we're going to focus on various aspects of arrays
.
How arrays are constructed is going to focus pretty heavily on computer science theory and then on the
second half of this course we're going to see into the problems that are really having practical uses
.
So these are energy problems based off of arrays and your understanding all on the first half will help
you tackle the problems on the second half.
All right so with that being said let's go ahead and get started with the section