Hello everyone and welcome to the introduction to the mock interviews section of this course this looks
sure just going to be going over some general non technical questions.
Resources for you and also the structure of the mock interviews section of the course.
So in this section of the introduction you're going to have a list of general non-technical questions
you may be asked such as questions during a phone screen of a recruiter so you can get that in the next
lecture and then you also get a list of questions that you should ask after the interview.
So make sure you actually review those questions non-technical questions.
We won't really discuss those in a mock interview.
We're going to focus more on actual technical questions.
Make sure you can answer several non-technical questions for the company that you're applying to.
As far as the mock interviews themselves you'll usually see two folders in your and B in the packet
or on any viewer of the board.
It's going to consist of interview problems and then another folder called interview problems solutions
.
So pay careful attention to the requirements.
Sometimes they ask you to just use a pen and paper and also note the simple format you're not going
to have a cell to test your solution you're basically just going to be asked a question and be asked
to make reasonable assumptions for your answer or your solution.
So again those mock interview questions are just going to be simple usually just a few lines of a question
and that's it.
Moving on what you should really do is record yourself talking or explaining out loud a lot of the mock
interviews section questions are going to ask as a requirement that you don't code out your solution
.
They actually write it on paper and pencil or on a whiteboard.
So practice with a friend or family member give them the solutions and you can have the interview problem
yourself.
It really helps for you to record yourself or practice for a friend.
So you can see how well you do and get the real life situation of talking to someone in a room and explaining
your thought process.
Again make sure you have a paper and pen or paper and pencil or some sort of white board.
Because a lot of the mock interview questions aren't going to be coded out.
You'll have to do them by hand.
Once you've attempted all the problems for a specific companies mock interview then take a look at the
solutions.
So don't go one at a time.
Do all the phones in site questions first and then attempt the solutions.
Again the problems are going to feel much harder than the previous exercises and interview problems
we've done previously in this course.
And that's because they're not going to be attached to certain sections so you'll have to think of what
strategy works best
practice interview problems you missed again after reading the solution.
So after you go through a mock interview all the phone screen and onsite questions and then check your
solutions are the ones you missed.
Make sure you practice that entry problem again and hopefully record it yourself or doing it.
If a family member or friends.
So if that being said Best of luck let's go ahead and get started in the next few lectures you'll see
that list of questions you should be able to answer.
And after that we'll get sort of the mock interviews.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture