Hello everyone and welcome to the right share startup company mock interview for this mock interview
you'll have a phone screen three onsight questions presented in the form of Jupiter notebooks with the
questions and then afterwards you have super notebooks and video solutions for the walkthrough for all
the questions solutions.
So go through the questions try to answer them and check out the solutions and go back over the ones
you missed at the end of this section.
You can check out a resource with source questions and advice on General Hiring practices Luber a ride
share startup company.
But that being said.
Best of luck on the interview