Hello everyone and welcome to the search overview lecture.
So this entire section consists of searching and sorting those algorithms and how they work in Python
for the first half of the section we'll discuss search methods and then in the second half of the section
we'll discuss sorting.
So right now we're just talking about search.
So in this half of the section we'll discuss quenches search will do an implementation of sequential
search.
Talk about binary search as well as an implementation of that and then we'll talk about hashing and
hash tables.
So a quick no.
In python we can use the in operator to search for elements in a list.
So for example a quick screenshot here at the bottom you can check if 15 is in that list which is not
so returns a boolean false.
And then you can also check if 3 is in that list which it is sir returns a boolean true.
So you want to really knows how does the underlying process actually work and what's the best way to
search for things algorithmically what's actually happening under the hood.
When you say something like 15 in this list.
So what we're going to do is go ahead and get started by learning about sequential search and binary
search and hashing and see how those topics relate to actually searching for items or elements in a
list.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.
We're going to discuss sequential search