Hello everyone and welcome to the stack queues and deques section of this course.
So in this section of the course we're going to be learning about three main linear structures stack
queues and decks and they're similar to arrays but each of these structures differs by how it adds and
removes items.
So that's going to be the key difference between all of these linear structures in this section as far
as the theory portions.
We're going to have a brief overview of what linear structures are then an overview of stacks.
We're going to have an implementation of a stack class and then we're going to do the same thing for
queues and decks both an overview and an implementation of both of them.
OK.
With that being said let's go ahead and get started.
The next lecture we're going to go have an overview of Stack's theory and how they work.
All right thanks everyone.
I'll see if next lecture