Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview problem.
This was called linked list and to the last node.
Here's the problem statement.
Write a function that takes a head node and an integer value and and then returns the answer to last
node in the linked list.
For example given class Node with value and next node attributes your example input output looks something
like this.
If we set up a linked list called A B C D E with no values 1 2 3 4 5 and then set up the order.
A B C D E.
Then quickly checking what the solution should look like.
As far as the format your function will take in n that end to last node number and then the head node
.
So here if we passen given this singly linked list format it as such passen to the head node A.
This should return the no deagle value of 4 because it's the second to last node.
So if you have a b c d e the second to last node is then D.
And that has a value of 4.
So if we go out and check the target node value it returns 4 for us.
First testing your solution you can go ahead and run this test cell.
They'll test your solution to get a test case.
Just note there there's just one test case.
So go ahead and check it manually.
As you might to make sure your function is actually working as you think it should.
OK.
Again your problem statement is just write a function that takes in a head node an integer value and
and then returns the nth to last node in the linked list.
And here's an example of what it should look like.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture