Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on the implementation of they d f s r that first search algorithm
.
So this algorithm basically explores possible vertices remember from a supply route and it goes down
each branch before backtracking.
And this property allows the algorithm to be implemented singly in both iterative and recursive forms
.
So below we're going to do this is the notebook this associate of this lecture.
You can go ahead and check it out but below the listing of actions we're going to do upon visiting each
node is marked the current vertex as being visited and then explore each adjacent vertex that is not
included in that visited set.
With that being said we're going to assume that the graph is and this simplified form screen going to
copy and paste that's here.
And let's go ahead and get started with just the basic implementation of depth first search.
So we're going to do is go ahead and start with just the basic function call it.
DFS is going to take in a graph and then a starting node or vertex and then we'll say visited is equal
to a set and then we all create our stack and that's going to be a list.
We start as the first element in that list.
Now we're going to say wow stack will have vertex equal to popping an item off of that stack.
Basically the vertex that's in that stack that node member you can use those interchangeably.
I will say if that vertex is not in visited then I will take visited
add that vertex to it and then what I'm going to do is say stack that extends and I'm going to do vertex
visited and then I'm going to return visited.
So let's see let's make sure this works before we fully break it down pasand graph and let's start at
node A.
So if we look at the connected components of a that's going to be this.
And there you have it.
We've there's the entire graph.
So we've done that first search.
Let's go ahead and go over everything we just did.
So this implantation we're using basically a stack like data structure which is that list are saying
visited.
So all the vidis visited versus that empty set.
We set our stack equal just to the starting node and then we'll say well stack go ahead and pop that
vertex saw that the vertex isn't unvisited yet.
We're going to add that vertex and then we're going to say stack and extend that by this term right
here.
Graph that vertex meaning if we look at our graph here it's a dictionary.
So at that Vertex that value it's the set.
So it's going to show you what this does.
If I go ahead and say that sets minus let's say B or something.
You know you get a type error and that's because this is actually supposed to be a set.
So remember this is what we're actually doing.
And that's because basically Python's overloading of the subtraction operator to remove items from a
set or we're able to add only that of adjacent vertices so if we look at this again this is what this
line is essentially doing.
So graph at that vertex is going to be all the vertices that vertex is connected to.
And then we subtract visited member visit visitors a set.
So it's a set with that particular vertex on it.
And then we keep subtracting until we don't get anything.
And then we've built out our entire depth first search.
So that's really all there is to it.
It's definitely a lot simpler than a b f s or breadth first search.
There's a couple other like implementation methods and functions so you can go ahead and check out in
the notebook.
So for instance there's a recursive implementation here and you can check out and there's also if you
wanted to show all the possible paths between two nodes.
There's also an implementation free to check out there and there's a bunch of resources for you in case
you want to read more into it.
So definitely check out especially this first research.
I find it really good.
It just goes over DFS and DFS.
It's just a little blog post and it just goes over again basic graph data structure.
So little more math oriented but it's still pretty relevant to what we're doing.
And then it gives you again code for both methods for DFS and for B.
So I encourage you to check it out check that out and then goes over generalizing too.
A great link great blog post and there's the official wikipedia links there.
Casher interested in that as well.
That being said that's really all there is to it.
First that first search you taken to go back here your visited your stack and then take the Virtex pop
it off of the stack you have visited.
Get at it and then you can just do this extension operation until we keep going.
We've actually seen all those nodes and that's all there is to it.
That first search.
OK.
Go ahead and check out the full Jupiter note book for all the notes and all the implementations.
But that's all there is to it.
I'll see at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone