Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the implementation of binary search trees lecture in this
part 2.
We're going to focus on deleting and removing nodes.
Let's go ahead and jump to that section of the presentation.
OK so you mentioned the last lecture.
We finally have turned their attention to the most challenging method in the binary search tree which
is deleting a key.
The first task is to find a note to delete by searching the tree.
If the tree has more than one note we can search using the underscore get method to find the tree node
that needs to be removed.
So get underscore get method that help or functionally described in the previous lecture.
If the tree only has a single note that means we're removing the root of the tree but we still must
check to make sure the key of the root matches the key that is to be deleted.
In either case if the key is not found that the elderly operator will raise an error.
So here's what that basic delete method looks like.
We can walk to the basics here.
We'll check if self-taught size is greater than 1 to call the node to remove using the underscore gets
in passing in the key as well as the root.
Will see if node to remove then we just remove it and set the size equal to size minus 1.
Otherwise we raise a query saying the key isn't in the tree and we have an else for each left statement
here will say if the size equal to 1.
And the root key is equal to the key.
Then we reset the equal to none and subtract one from the size of the tree.
If neither of these cases turns out to be true then the key is not in the tree we raise here.
The special method DTL item underscore underscores surrounding it just allows us to use that DCL special
Dilley operator in Python.
Again this is just a special method.
Once we found a node containing the key we want to delete.
There's going to be three cases to consider.
The first one is that the notes of the delay be deleted has no children.
So for instance if we wanted to take this tree and delete the node here 16 which doesn't have any children
this is going to be the simplest case.
This first case just straightforward.
All we have to do is say if the current note has no children we just delete the node and remove the
reference to this node in the parent.
And that's what we're doing in this section of the code.
You can refer to the Jupiter note book for the entire deleting code.
But here we're just going to take it a little bit by little bits.
Sahira just saying.
If it is a leaf if that's true then if current notice equal to the current nodes parent left child then
we just sit the left child equals to none.
Otherwise it's the right child.
So he set the right child equal to none.
Here we're just checking if it's a leaf meaning it has no children.
That's the first case the second case is that the node to be deleted has only one child.
So for instance if we wanted to delete here No.
25.
Which you can see only has a single child that right child.
The second case is just slightly more complicated.
If the node has only a single child then we can simply promote the child to take place of its parent
meaning.
If we look back here we can think of this that instead of removing 25 altogether where removing it but
still just replacing it with 35 or removing this person or this node one up and replacing it.
If the note to be deleted only has one child.
So let's go and jump to the code to discuss the second case because it's a little too much to fit here
on the screen in a presentation.
So here we are at the binary search tree.
We just go ahead and scroll down here and go all the way to the Remove method in the binary search tree
and we can zoom in on this guy.
All we're gonna be discussing is this section.
The node only has one child.
So here we just do a couple of checks and we essentially do the following.
If the current note is a left child then we only need to update the parent reference to the left child
to the point so to point to the parent not of the current node and then update that left child reference
of the parent to point to the current notes left child.
Just that replacing switch if the current notice a right child.
Do we only need to update the parent reference of the right child to point to the parent of the current
node and then update the right child reference of the parent to point to the current notes.
Right child.
So we're just exchanging the pointings pointers here as we are moving node.
If that current node has no parent then it's actually the root.
In this case we just replaced the key payload left child and write child data by calling replace no
data method which is going to be over here.
Replace no data or replace no data depending if it's the left child here or if the current node even
has the left child.
So this is the case for if it only has one child you can go to review this code but you can essentially
just think about it as joining the parents and the children to each other as we basically pop out one
of those nodes the figure explains it probably a little more clearly.
But here's the actual code that implements this.
All right.
Again it's quite a bit of code so just go through it slowly if you want to understand every single step
that's going on here.
Let's go ahead and jump back to the third case of the leading item OK.
The third case is that the note to be deleted has two children.
So imagine here we wanted to delete the five note that has two children will have to choose a successor
for it.
That means this third case is the most difficult case to handle.
And it may be one of the most common cases which is unfortunate.
So we need to think about how to handle this specific case.
It's the node has two children then it is unlikely that we can simply promote one of them to take the
notes place.
We can however search the tree for a node that can be used to replace the ones scheduled for deletion
.
So what we need to do is we need a no that will preserve the binary search tree relationship that BSEE
property for both the existing left and right subtrees the No that will do this is the No that has a
next largest key and tree.
We call this no the successor and we will look at a way to find a successor shortly.
Well let's talk about that successor the successor is guaranteed to have no more than one child.
So we know how to remove it using the two cases for deletion that we just discussed implemented.
Once that successor has been removed we simply put it in the tree in place of the note to be deleted
.
Notice that we make use of the helper methods in the actual Jupiter note book Code find successor and
Feinman to find that successor to remove the successor.
We make use of the method splice out the reason we use splice out is that it goes directly to the node
we want to splice out and makes the right changes.
So here we have just a little snippet of that.
And in this case you can see the helper functions.
So we say if current node has both children meaning that's deleting nodes K-Street has both children
reset the variable UCSC for the successor to the current node find successor.
So we're gonna have to use that find successor method in order to find the appropriate note to replace
and if we go back real quick to the figure we discussed here you can see in this particular case the
successor was 7 and 7 works because it's has two which is less than 7 on the left and 11 which is greater
than 7 on the right.
So it's the immediate successor if we go down from 5 that works here.
OK let's go ahead and check this out.
In the Jupiter notebook.
So I'm going to jump to find success from in the Jupiter notebook.
OK so here we are at that fine successor method if you can see here the code to find successors just
a method of that tree node class and this code that makes use of the same properties of binary search
trees that causin in order traversal to print out the nodes in the tree from smallest to largest.
OK there's going to be three cases to consider when looking for the successor one if the node has a
right child then the successor is the smallest key in the right tree.
So that's what's happening here.
If we have a right child the successor is going to be fine demen off that right child and that right
subtree if the node has no right child and is the left child of its parent then the parent is the successor
if to notice the right child of its parent in itself has no right child then the successor to this node
is the successor of its parent excluding this node.
The first condition is the only one that matters for us when deleting a note from a binary search tree
.
However define success or method has other uses that we're going to explore later on the find Dimin
method if we scroll down here is called to find the minimum key in a subtree using what we know about
the BSEE property we can convince ourselves that the minimum value key and any binary search tree is
simply the leftmost child of the tree.
Therefore this find the main method simply follows the left child references.
Each note of the subtree until it reaches a node that no longer has a left child.
All right with that being said we just have a few more methods to cover so let's go ahead and look at
them.
OK.
One last method if we need to look at one last interface method for the binary search tree.
And that's because suppose that we would like to simply iterate over all the keys in the tree in order
.
This is definitely something we've done already in dictionaries so why not trees.
You already know how to traverse a binary tree in order using the in order traversal algorithm we discussed
earlier in the section.
However writing an iterator requires a bit more work since an iterator should return only one node each
time the iterator is called.
So here's the method.
The special method that we can use in Python provides us with a powerful function to use and create
an iterator.
The function is called a yield.
Yield is similar to return in that it returns a value to the caller.
However if you're familiar of generators or iterators in Python yield also takes the additional step
of freezing the state of the function so that the next time the function is called it continues executing
from the exact point it left off earlier.
Go ahead and search for iterators versus generators in Python.
If you want more information on this yield keyword but for our situation here what we really care about
is that takes that additional step of freezing the state of the function.
So next time you call yield it just continues executing from the exact point it left off earlier.
Functions that create objects that can be iterated are called those generator functions.
Here's the code for in order iterator of a binary tree.
And if you look at this code carefully at first glance you might think that the code is not recursive
.
However remember that this underscores underscore itor underscore underscore method overrides that for
x in operation for iteration.
So it really is recursive because it is recursive retreat node instances the underscore underscore special
method is defined in that tree node class which you can check in your Jupiter notebook.
Go ahead and review this code in the Jupiter note book in the larger picture of how to iterate through
the tree and make sure you review the in order traversal algorithm.
For this to be really clear.
But I'll let you go ahead and read this on your own thread.
Jupiter notebook and really take your time with it and keep in mind that it actually is recursive because
of the way we're using this special method.
All right we've covered a lot of ground.
Make sure to review the Jupiter notebook and review the wikipedia article in binary search trees.
As far as implementing a binary search tree it's going to be pretty rare for us to implement something
as thoroughly as we just did here.
But you may be asked to implement your own traversal algorithms in order etc..
So up next we'll have some interview problems to reflect some common trick questions that you might
find in a tree interview setting.
All right thanks everyone.
Again make sure you read the Jupiter note book.
The Wikipedia article on binary search trees and the two lectures here.
The part 1 in part 2 to really understand binary search trees.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.