Hello everyone and welcome to the solution to the jugs of water problem.
So this problem actually has a kind of a famous cameo in the movie Die Hard three.
So I've written out here the solution below a walk through it that if you scroll down on the solution
up book you also see a reference to the movie here.
OK.
So hopefully your injury is not a stressful as the diehard situation.
Well let's go ahead and walk through the solution.
So first action you take is filled the five gallon jug.
So you have five gallons in the five gallon jug and the three gallon jug is empty then fill up the three
gallon jug of water from the five gallon jug.
So now you have three gallons of the three gallon jug and only two in the five gallon jug.
Then you pour out the three gallon jug transfer the two gallons in the five gallon jug.
The three gallon jug.
Then you fill up the five gallon jug.
And then here's the trick.
You transfer water from the five gallon jug to the three gallon jug.
Since the three gallon jug was already full to gallons.
You know the empty space and it only had room for one more gallon less.
So that five minus one becomes four.
And now you have four gallons.
All right.
That's it for this solution.
Walk through it.
Make sure you should have understood logically that since you're being asked for four gallons you should
have immediately noted that the only jug that would have ended up with those four gallons is the five
gallon jug.
So you could have started logically based on that fact alone.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture