Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture discussing the coin change problem and its solution.
As always there is a complete solution notebook here describing the solution so no problem.
This problem is actually common enough that it has its own Wikipedia entry and it's a really famous
problem in showing some of the issues with recursion in general and why dynamic programming and memorization
is such a key tool to improving on basic recursion.
So what we're going to do is go through basically two implementations of a solution.
One is just a classic recursion that doesn't use memorization.
So no the solution is not optimize.
And then we go through a better solution.
I would really encourage you to read through this entire solution note book first as well as read through
.
If you scroll all the way down to the notebook there's an extra resource here.
Dynamic coin change problem.
I would really recommend that you read the entire extra resource.
It's just the page long that describes this exact same problem in why there are issues if normal recursion
and also there's a Wikipedia entry that's linked here.
You can also read and there's solutions as far as implementations with dynamic programming and it's
in Python so you can read about it as well.
All right.
So let's go ahead and discuss the coin change problem then we're going to could and jumped to some life
here and start by thinking about what the problem statements actually sing.
So we're given a target amount n so some target amount of money we want to make or change we want to
make.
56 cents 50 cents 45 cents 46 cents etc. and then we're giving a list or an array of distinct coin values
and we want to know what the fewest coins needed to make that change amount is.
So for instance if we jump back to the solution book we can see here that if you have an equals 10 to
your target number 10 and you giving values of 1 5 and 10.
There's four possible ways to make change.
You can have 10 ones of five and five ones two fives and a 10.
And the correct answer for the minimum amount is of course just one coin that ten cent coin.
So we're going to do is first do a classic recursion solution to this problem and then we'll talk about
what the issues are with that solution.
So it's going to get started first.
I'll start just by calling the E-F Ari underscore coin.
I'm going to take in or call it the target and then the list of coins.
So what I'm going to do first is think about certain base cases or certain scenarios where I should
instantly return something.
So one of those cases is if the target number is in coins.
So for instance in that last example 10 the target was actually in the list of coin values.
You would just immediately want to return it.
So we want to see if we have a single coin match.
And in this case we'll just return one.
So the minimum number of coins is 1.
If that's not the case what I'm going to do is set a default value here that the minimum number of coins
is the target number and what I am going to do is actually recursively solve for that and at the end
of every thing I will return.
Men under score coins.
All right so let's go get us started at where we actually want to do here.
So in plain English All I want to do is for every coin value in that coins list that is less than or
equal to the target number.
What I want to do is recursively call my function and add a count coin and then subtract from the target
and then reset the minimum.
If I have a new minimum number of coins so that's a little complicated so let's go ahead and write it
out.
So I want to say 4.
Let me go ahead and zoom in here.
So it's really clear for every coin value that is less than or equal to my target value.
So I want to say for I in.
And then I'll make a list using list comprehension.
That's saying C for C in coins.
If C is less than or equal to that target
so hear them saying I'm making a list comprehension that's grabbing all the coins.
If for see if C is less than that target number and I'm saying for each of those basically coin values
I'm going to make a new variable called number of coins.
Number of coins we need and I'm going to recursively call 1 plus the recursive function here.
I'm going to subtract the current coin I'm on and then passing the coin values which hasn't changed
.
And if some coins of the number of coins suddenly finds itself being less than the minimum number of
coins which we started off as the target number I'm going to reset it I'm going to say the coins is
now equal to the number of coins.
So this is the full recursion.
So a recursive solution it's an inefficient but it will work for most cases for cases that have American
style coins.
If you have odd coin values or weird prime values such as like a coin that has value 7 or something
like that and you're looking for a distinct number you may have an error solving with this recursive
solution.
And that's part of the problem we'll discuss in a second.
But basically what's going on here.
Just to go over this basic recursive solution which no is not actually the correct way to solve this
problem.
We have a default value for the minimum number of coins and we set it to the target.
We have what we can think of a base case which checks to see if Target is in Coin Values list right
.
Otherwise I'm saying for every coin value that's Lessner equaled in my target.
So for every i for every value in that list I'm going to add a coin.
Let's add a coin count.
That's what this one is here.
So I've already had to use a coin.
And then I add it to the recursive call where the recursive call is now a new target.
I will subtract the value of that coin from it.
So for instance if time looking for 15 cents and I just subtract that a dime from it.
My new target is now five cents.
And again I pass a list of coins searching for that new minimum and I will reset the minimum here
if the new num coins
is less than the minimum number of coins which reset first as the target and that's all there is for
this recursion.
Now if we actually run this you'll notice it takes a very long time to run for certain values.
I'm going to do a basic example here saw passen 15 as my target value 1 5 and 10.
I'll run it.
It outputs 2.
So that's correct that needs one dime and then one nickel.
But if I input something else maybe something is sixty three and I'll also pass in a quarter in value
.
It'll take much much longer with this.
And you'll notice the problem with this approach is that it's inefficient it can take many many recursive
calls to finish this problem.
So I'm going to go ahead and jump to the solutions notebook.
I'm going to kill the cell by interrupting it.
So when I say kernel interrupt here and then I'm going to clear it's output cell current output clear
and go ahead and jump back to the solution notebook to show you an issue here.
So for instance let's pretend that I'm looking to solve for 26 here.
So if we look at the figure that's in the solutions notebook each node here corresponds to a call to
that recursive function.
The label on the node indicates the amount of change for which we are now computing the number of points
to solve for now.
Note how are recalculating values we've already solved for instance 15.
Here is solve for three times over here where my mouse currently is.
Over here where my mouse currently is and over here a mouse currently is.
So it would be much better if we actually kept track of the function calls we've already made so we
don't have to constantly resolve for things we already know.
And that's where the dynamic programming solution comes into play.
That memorization that we discussed earlier in the section and then zoom out so you can see the lips
whole equation here or whole code.
And the key to reducing that work time for the function is using it's dynamic programming.
So the better solution is to remember past results that way before computing a new minimum.
We can check to see if we already know a result.
And you won't have the straight recursion call where you look at results that you've already done in
the past but haven't saved in memory.
Now something to keep in mind here is that while this is very efficient in time it's going to be less
efficient in memory since you're storing more results.
Usually that's a tradeoff you'd want to make for a simple problem like this but you really have to think
of what's going on in the general scope of your problem that you're trying to solve and see if there's
a good tradeoff.
Usually it is especially in this context of the interview question.
All right.
So now we're going to do is this function is going to take in three inputs it's going to take in a Target
coins and then we're going to have a cache known results and instead of actually putting it outside
the function we're going to develop it inside the function.
So let's go ahead and live code this dynamic programming solution so we can really understand why this
is the best approach to solving this problem.
We're going to go ahead and jump back to the live code.
All right.
So let's start by naming our function.
Or C underscore coin underscore D-y Dine-In for dynamic.
In this case we've taken three arguments the target the coins and a new parameter.
Results are known results.
So I'm going to do the exact same thing I did last time.
I'll set the default output to the target.
So so far the minimum number of coins I need is whatever target number gets passed and then I'm going
to think of my base case.
So what does that look like.
Well again if I know the target is in the coins then I'm going to say known results of that target and
a set that equal to 1 and then when to return one.
So what's going on here it means if I kept doing recursive calls and suddenly I find that the target
number is actually in coins then I'm going to set the known results at the target equal to 1 and then
I'm going to continue on to what's the more complicated part.
The actual recursive calls and it's going to be an else if statement or an ellipse statement.
And what I want to do here is I want to return a known
results
if it happens to be greater than 1.
So if I know my known results at that particular target is greater than zero then I'm just going to
return that value.
And this is dynamic programming that's going to save you a lot of time in recursive calls and hopefully
we'll be clear once we go through the final statement.
So again I'm going to say for every coin value that is less than or equal to the target.
So for I in and I'm using less comprehension again see for see in coins if C is less than or equal to
target.
I'm going to make a recursive call but pay attention here because I'm going to include the known results
.
So when I say number of coins it's going to look really similar to the last one.
Another recursive call here rec coin this case 9am I pass and my target minus sign that current value
that I'm on the coins the values we know doesn't change.
And then I passen my currently known results and then I reset my minimum just like we did in the last
one.
So if my number of coins is less than my minimum number of coins I can just say mint coins is equal
to the current number of coins.
And here's where it comes into play.
I will also need to reset that known result.
I will have to say my known results at Target is equal to the minimum number of coins and then finally
I will return the minimum number of coins here.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
Let me fix a table here that should have been known results.
Make sure results pleura and all of these are right.
Let's see if this runs.
Make sure there is no other typos in it and we will call it let's say an interesting target number maybe
74.
My coin values will be 1 5 10 25 and I'm going to initiate my known results just like we did in that
last memoization problem by a list of zeros of length Tarja plus 1.
And now if I call my function
on my target with my coins and my known results you'll notice I get 8.
Now if I tried doing that on that first function with just targeting coins you'll know it's just taking
forever to run because it's making a ton of recursive calls here so I'll have to stop that cell from
running.
OK so if you notice the notebook did have a test your solution but no it was designed for non dynamic
functions and they will take a long time to test.
So if you believed you had a solution you should have come here and checked this.
All right so let's go ahead and briefly go over what we did here.
We tried to create a normal recursive solution but it would have failed because it would have taken
so long because it kept made getting repeated recursive calls for results.
Actually it already previously calculated before.
As you can see from this diagram of trying to figure out 26 here.
All right we came up with a dynamic programming solution that took into account our known results but
also solved a very similar recursive fashion just like the first solution except it updated its known
results here here and here.
And that's really the case of memoization dynamic programming.
So once you've gone through this video Remember you should really check out this great resource here
.
They Nemec programming coin change problem link at the bottom of the solutions notebook read through
it.
It's a great walk through on the coin changing problem.
Or you can also read the Wikipedia page entry here.
That also explains the dynamic programming solution.
It does a little bit of a different fashion here by creating a matrix but again you should walk through
it and make sure you understand it because there's various ways of writing out this particular dynamic
programming solution.
All right so your homework is to make sure you read both that Wikipedia entry and if you scroll down
here.
This link here is that Amec coin change problem.
It's going to be pretty similar to what we discussed here.
It will also have this figure in it but it's important to read it because it goes through a very slow
and steady solution explanation for the case of dynamic programming there.
All right that's it for this section on recursive interview problems recursive interview problems.
As far as the way they're presented in interview situations sometimes they won't explicitly tell you
to use recursion but hopefully after completing the section you have an idea of in your mind what situations
would call for recursive solution.
And if you ever confuse an interview situation.
Don't be afraid to ask of something like Hey recursion be a good call here.
It fits on the brink of your mind but you're unsure.
Remember to ask a lot of questions.
Do your thinking out loud when your interview situation other than that as far as this question goes
for the coin change problem make sure you do that homework reading and I will see you at the next lecture
.
All right.
Great job everyone on the interview questions.
I'll see you in the next section.