Hello everyone and welcome to your next riddle.
This one's called light switches.
Now a quick note before we begin this problem statement.
This question has a bit of a trick to it so don't spend too much time on it.
It's more on the fun side of the brainteaser type questions.
Now I personally think this kind of problem is more of a gotcha problem and it would be unfair to ask
this riddle in an interview situation so I wouldn't expect this sort of riddle to be asked of you but
it still might be fun to solve.
So here's the problem statement.
You're in a hallway next to three light switches all of which are off.
Each switch activates a different incandescent light bulb in the room at the end of the hall.
You cannot see the lights from where the switches are so you can't see into the room.
Your task is to determine which light corresponds to each switch.
However you may only go into the room with the lights once.
OK.
Best of luck with this problem.
Again don't spend too much time on it because there is a bit of a trick to it.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture