Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of a bubble sort of lecture.
So a quick reminder the bubble sort makes multiple passes through a list it compares adjacent items
and exchanges those that are out of order.
Each pass through the list places the next largest value in its proper place.
So in essence each item is bubbling up to the location where it belongs.
So as always Here's the notebook.
You have resource for review including visualisations and we're going to go ahead and program out our
own implementation in Python.
Explain as we go along.
So go ahead and open up a new Jupiter notebook.
Let's go and zoom in here real quick.
Now let's get started.
So first thing we're going to do is go ahead and start writing our function.
This case we'll just call it bubble underscore sorts and we'll take in an array.
They are now again in Python.
This is just going to be our normal list but we'll treat it with the term A-R are just we can generalize
it to an array.
So we're going to do is say for n in range and this is where it's going to get a bit tricky but we're
basically arrange it backwards and I'll show you what I mean by that in just a second.
We're going to say length r minus 1 to zero insteps of negative 1.
So let me go in and show you what that looks like.
I'm going to go in and say pass here and then let's go ahead and say our is just one two three four
five.
And if I say I just go and print this out you basically arrange everything backwards except for the
very last elements.
Since we're going from minus 1 so just keep them in mind as we go along.
What does it actually do.
If you're using Python 3 in order to see this result you have to have called LIST on this since range
is just a generator in Python 3.
OK.
So let's go ahead and keep on moving.
So the next thing we're going to do is then say for k in range of 10.
So as we go along with that that list remember we had that one two three four five.
In this case we're going to go all the way from k 0 to m.
So to understand this logic we're going to say is if the array at that value points basically that index
is greater than K plus 1.
Let me fix those brackets there K plus 1.
So we're basic checking here.
We're going to come to a point where we need a switch.
So going to say make a temporary variable equal to our of that K the index and then say our K is equal
to r of K plus 1 and then say R K plus 1 is equal to that temporary variable.
And that's really all there is to it.
For this implementation of the bubble sort.
OK.
So let's go ahead and tests that our solution.
Make sure it runs well and then we'll break down step by step one more time.
What we're doing.
So going to go in and say create an array.
Now will say five say three 7 and two.
So that's already unsorted.
We're going to called Bubble sort on that array that list and then print out that array again.
Okay perfect so it was sorted.
Notice that I don't have a return function on the return key word on this function.
So it didn't actually automatically return it if you wanted to you could have added in line with this
for loop return.
A R R in order to not have to redo and print that array.
OK so it's good go one more time.
What's going on in this function.
So I'm saying for n in range and remember we are actually just saying everything in reverse order.
So let's go ahead and show that one more time.
So range length or minus one zero minus one.
So if this is our example array what we should see out is 3 to 1.
So that's going to help us see what actual index we should be doing when we come to that case so I'm
going to go ahead and say print K and print and here.
So if we run this on a very short array these print statements may help us visualize what's actually
happening.
So if I say bubble sort.
Are you can go ahead and see the print statements and the are actual arrays we're checking.
At that point in time.
So I'm going to go ahead and say this is the Ann comma and then here I want to say this is the K index
check.
Comma.
All right.
So you notice what's happening here is every end.
We're going to head and do index checks from 0 up to that end.
And this is where the bubbling is occurring.
Remember from the diagram we only have to bubble less and less as we continue on depending on which
side we're going from the side from the left.
So go ahead and check this out.
Definitely use print statements in case you're still confused.
But steps that themselves but all we're doing here is saying from an 3 since we have a length of four
.
Go ahead and do index checks at 0 1 and 2.
Once you've done all the way up to end we'll go ahead and do an equals two.
They'll do your on one and then keep subtracting.
And as far as the actual index checks what's going on we're just checking at the two adjacent elements
in the survey.
If one is greater than the other if it is we just go ahead and do a swap with these three lines here
.
We're using a temporary variable.
So we don't actually accidently overwrite anything in that list or array.
OK.
So that's it for the implementation of bubble sort.
Hopefully you can see it's quite simple.
As far as this line and the Slyne different methods may operate these two lines differently.
So depending if you're running from the rights of the list or the left of the list you may bubble up
in a different manner.
But as far as our implementation this actually makes sense and this comparison is going to be very very
similar no matter which way you go.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture