Hello everyone and welcome to your first interview question for the graphs section.
This interview question is simply to implement a graph class.
Now we've already seen this done twice once as an adjacency list and another time as an adjacency list
but with the Node class that vertex class you can do either one or whatever you feel comfortable with
.
There's not going to be a solution lecture after this or after any of the interview questions here because
they're all going to be implementation questions that we've seen implemented before.
Again there's no solution you can go ahead and check out the references to the implementations I've
seen before but that's it.
OK.
Best of luck and just implement a graph class.
Thanks.
I'll see you at the next lecture