Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the balance parentheses check interview problem.
Just as a reminder this is a pretty common interview problem and it's one of the main ways to check
your knowledge of stacks.
So what the problem statement was you were given a string of opening and closing parentheses you had
to check whether it was balanced.
Let's go ahead and go over some logic for our solution.
Let me go ahead and zoom in here.
So as I mentioned this is a common interview problem and we're going to start our solution logic as
such starting with this step.
First we're going to scan the string from left to right now every time we see an opening parentheses
.
We're going to push it to a stack because we want the last opening parentheses to be closed first.
So remember that first in last out structure of a stack.
And that first in last out is just another way of saying Last In First Out.
OK.
So the second step is going to be when we see a closing parentheses.
We're going to check whether the last open one is the corresponding closing match by popping an element
from the stack.
If it's a valid match then we can proceed forward.
Otherwise we just return false because we know it's not balanced.
So if the stack is empty it will also return false because there is no opening parentheses associate
of the closing one.
And in the end we also check whether the stack is empty.
If so we just return true.
Otherwise we return false because there were some open parentheses that were not close.
So that's our basic logic right now.
Let's go ahead and code out the solution for this so we can see this implemented in action.
All right.
So we're going to go ahead and fill out that balance check function.
It takes in a string and first thing we're going to do is just a quick edge case check so we can already
check that if there's an even number of brackets.
We know we can continue on a solution.
Otherwise if there's an odd number of brackets we'll just return false and that's going to be an impossible
string to balance.
So say if the length of that string s mod 2 is not equal to zero then I know we have an odd number of
parentheses and I can just return false.
Keep in mind that we were given the statement that there is no spaces or words or elements besides parentheses
here.
Otherwise you wouldn't be able to do such an easy check.
Next thing we're going to do is create a set of opening brackets.
So I'm going to create a variable called opening and I'll make a sets and I can pass on a string to
the set and I just want the opening brackets.
You'll notice that Jupiter notebooks and I Python in general will auto generate the close brackets.
Don't worry about that right now.
So just to show you what this line is actually doing.
I'm just going to actually run it here so you can see it's basically a nice quick way of creating a
set of these brackets individually.
So it's taking each element in that string and passing it into the set.
All right.
So we have our opening brackets.
Go ahead and delete this.
So I have that opening set of brackets.
Let's go ahead and make a set of the matching pairs.
So I'm going to make another sets I'll call it matches and I'm going to pass in a list here of tuples
of the matches.
So we have three types parentheses.
Which means I can have three tuples.
I'm setting them up here so hopefully you can see the logic that we're doing.
So let's go ahead and make the first match that first match would it be in opening and closing parentheses
.
So that's our first tuple here.
Lee spaces so it's it's a little more clear.
So that's our first basic tuple set or pair and next one is going to be the square brackets.
So there's the open square bracket and there's the clothes square bracket.
And then let's go ahead to do the curly one.
So Curly open and Curly closed.
OK.
Let me go ahead and make sure you guys understand what this is by just running that string or excuse
me running that line and you'll notice we have our sets and it's of tuple pairs here.
Open close open close open close right so that variable is called matches and we're going to do is use
a list as a stack.
So remember we are implementing our stack.
We're basically using all the built in operations of a list.
So that's totally fine in interview setting.
Just make sure the interviewer knows that you realize the Python list to operate same as a stack.
In this situation maybe as an earlier question they ask you to implement your own stack.
So you might want to keep this in mind and a good challenge would be to implement your own stack first
and then do this problem with your own implement stack class.
So continuing on let's go ahead and check every parentheses in the string saying the save for Paran
short print sees in S that string we took in.
What I want to do is check if it's an opening.
I'm going to append that to that list.
Basically push it to the stack.
So I say if print is in opening meaning it's an opening parentheses going to take my stack which was
that list and a pens that print.
So I'm pushing that print sees if it's an opening one else what I'm going to do is check that there
are parentheses in the stack.
So if it's not a opening princes means it's a closing one.
So the first thing you can do is I'm going to say if length of stack at the end there if length of stack
is equal to zero return false because Aretino there wasn't a matching opening print sees for that closing
parentheses.
If the length the stack is already 0 if that's not the case what I want to do is check that last open
prints.
So I'm going to create a variable call it last open and that will be that pop from the stack member
.
Our first and last out or last in first out principle and what I want to do now is check if that has
a closing match.
So say if last open
Uren is not in match's return false.
So hopefully now you can see why we did that tuple set here of these pairings so I can use this sort
of notation.
Last open print not in matches.
There's definitely other ways you could have gone about making this check.
But I like this because it's a little cleaner and it makes a nice use of a set as a one line here for
checking your matches.
OK.
So if none of those ended up returning anything then I'm just going to do a quick check if the stack
is empty.
So when a say return length of stack equal to zero.
And let me go ahead and zoom out a bit so you can see how the code is laid out.
All right.
So you can see that this four lines up of that return for that check if we've emptied out that stack
completely.
So let's go ahead and do some balance checks and make sure this all works out and check we have an error
in our code.
OK.
So looks like this was true make sense to me.
Well check another balance check.
This one should also be true.
All right.
And let's check one that we know is false.
Great.
Now we got false.
All right.
That's always the solution.
So let's go ahead and see it one more time and walk through the steps we're doing.
So remember the first thing we're doing is we're just scanning the string from left to right which is
what this for loop is doing.
And then every time we see an opening parentheses we push it to the stack.
So we created our opening set of prints C's or saying if prend is in the opening I'm going to push it
to that stack.
And in this case and my stack is just a list I'm using the append method of that list.
All right.
We do this because we want the last opening print seems to be closed first then when we see a closing
print sees we're going to check whether the last opened one is the corresponding closing match by popping
an element from the stack which is right here in this case.
If it's a valid match then we proceed forward.
If not we're going to return false.
In other method or step here is that if the stack is empty We're also going to return false because
there is no opening princes snowsuit of that closing line which is what we did here in this check.
So in the end also check whether the stack is empty right here.
If so we'll end up returning true because that means we've balanced out and matched all the princes
.
Otherwise we return false because there are some open princes that were never closed.
At the end of going through the entire string.
OK.
So go ahead and walk out for a walk through that solution.
Make sure you understand it.
Go ahead and see if you can implement your own stack class and use it in the same way as we did with
our list as a substitute.
And if you want you can go ahead and check out other methods or create your own methods for doing this
check right here are the matches with this line.
OK.
That's the solution everyone.
Thanks a lot and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thanks