Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview problem.
This one's called largest continuous sum.
Here's the problem statement.
You're given an array of integers positive and negative integers and needed to find the largest continuous
sum.
So fill out your solution below.
In its function.
Something to note is that many times in an interview setting the question also requires you to report
back the start and the points of the sum.
Keep this in mind and see if you can solve that problem as well.
We're going to see it in the mock interview section of the course later on.
So you will run into this problem again with a little more detail and some different requirements for
you.
But in this case all you're required to do in this situation is just find the largest continuous sum
.
So here we have put it in an array as a Python list in the large continuous some.
Here is 29.
All right.
That's it.
This is a little trickier than it might seem.
So keep that in mind.
You can run this cell here to test your solution.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture