Hello everyone and welcome to your final interview question with the stacks Qs and decks portion of
this course.
So your question or assignment for this problem is this implementer.
Q Using two stacks so you're going to be given a stack class below and what it wants to do is implement
a q class using two stacks.
You should also note this is a classic interview problem.
She should really know this one but I want to do is use a python list data structure as your stack.
So instead of having to create your own stack class what I'm going to do is say this list is a stack
class so here stack one.
It's just an empty list.
And here stacked two.
It's an empty list.
And so your solution right here.
You're given a class was going to zoom in on it called Q two stacks and here are your two stacks those
empty lists.
I've already set them up as self-taught stack one self-taught stack two.
And what I want to do is fill out these two methods so that you're essentially creating a cue using
these two stacks.
You can go ahead and test your solution here.
Well you should be able to do with your current knowledge of stacks and queues you should be able to
tell it to working as it should.
So for example the following should print as such here.
So Friday x range 5 and an x range 5 when you're calling on Q&A.
Q Is this something that looks like this so go ahead and run the cell and make sure that your solution
output makes sense and behaves as a cue that you've built out of two stacks.
You need a quick reminder on what stacks and queues look like and operate.
You can go ahead and check out the theory lectures on them trying out to check out the actual implementation
of lectures until you've given your fair shot at this interview problem.
All right.
With that being said I'll see you at the next lecture where we're going to be going over the solution
to this problem.
Thanks everyone.