Hello everyone and welcome to your last riddle.
This one's called the ropes burning.
Here's the problem statement.
You're given two ropes each takes exactly 60 minutes to burn.
However they're made of different material.
So even though they take the same amount of time to burn they burn at separate rates.
And in addition each rope burns inconsistently.
So how can you measure out exactly 45 minutes.
So for instance to give you an example if you had to measure out 120 minutes you would just burn one
rope at one end.
Wait 60 Minutes for it to fully burn then once it finished burning you would notice start the other
rope at one end burn it and then you'd have measured out 120 minutes.
But a much more challenging question is how do you measure exactly 45 minutes given that they burn in
separate rates and they burn inconsistently.
All right.
Best of luck everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture