Hello everyone and welcome to the tree level.
Order print solution lecture the problem statement was this given a binary tree of integers printed
in level order.
The output will contain space between the numbers and the same level.
And the new line between different levels.
So for example to tree look something like this one with a couple of branches to 3 and then another
level four or five six.
You should be able to take in that tree and then print something out like this.
One two three four five six.
In the Jupiter note book there's a written explanation in good and check out who were actually going
to jump straight to the code take advantage of some decks like structures that are already built into
Python from the collections module and then we'll go ahead and just explain our solution out.
It's good and jumped to a notebook.
All right here I am at the notebook.
I already have the Node class set up.
This is just from the answer solution.
But all we have left right.
And then Vau classic Node class.
OK let's go in and start a fire function to print this in level order.
We'll just call this level order prints and it will accept a tree and right off the bat will say if
not tree just return because we know we no longer need to iterate over that.
OK something to do is take advantage of the dex data structure which you can actually just import from
collections so I'm going to say import collections here and the collections module has the stack Skewes
index built into Python so I'm going to say nodes is equal to collections top deck.
In this case we pass it just that tree as the single item in a list to set up our nodes as a deck.
Ok I'm also going to set up two variables one called current count set it equal to one and another one
called next counts set it equal to zero.
And I'm going to say.
While the length of that deck we just did nodes is not equal to zero.
We're going to do the following.
We're going to say that current node
is a new variable and set that equal to nodes
Pop left and let me go ahead and say no it's here.
And with this pop left allows us to do is since we have a deck remember a deck we can remove from both
ends.
So this allows me to use this pop left method on that deck.
You can go and check it out just by pressing tab later on.
So let me just go ahead and put a new cell here so we can just explore this a little more in case there's
any confusion and I will set the equal to
collection's deck.
I'm going to pass it in a list of 1 to 3 and then if I say the dot and then I press tab.
These are all the methods or attributes I have available for me so I can say Pop left and I can also
say append left versus just a normal append which is goes to the right and then pop will also go to
the right.
So pop in append the normal ones always go from the right end of that deck.
But I can also append left and pop left which I can't do if a normal list.
All right you can go and review the debt collector in case there's any confusion than that.
That is basically a list where I can pop and append things from both ends.
Unlike a queue.
All right.
So I'm going to pop left and set that equal to my current node and then since I'm doing that in a current
count and then subtract 1 from it.
No what I'm just going to do is Prince the current node value and then I'm going to say if the current
node to the left then I'm going to say nodes appends current node left and then I add once the next
counts and I go ahead and go through the overall code in just a second.
But I'm going to say if Currence no rights and remember how we use the stot left and right check just
to see if there is.
If it's basically this is essentially if not none check because it fit there.
There's nothing there it's just going to equal none.
In this case I'll say nodes appends current node writes very similar to what we were just doing.
Current Noda writes and I will say next counts in this case plus equals 1 and I will also say if current
count
is equal to zero then we just finished printing that current levels.
I'm going to go ahead and say prints a new line
and then I'm going to reset the current count and it isn't tuple and packing here in order to do this
as next counts and current counts.
And this is just to make sure I don't have to set up a temporary variable for this sort of switch here
.
So that's a nice little feature of Python to be packing.
And let me make sure.
Looks like I have an error here.
9:13 let me go ahead and remove that sorry.
That in cash that should have been a zero.
So while the length is not equal to zero.
My apologies.
I'm going to say this is good and zoom out so we can get a whole picture of the code.
To take in the tree check if there's none there.
Otherwise I'm just going return.
Set up a variable Kloeden called nodes.
It's a deck of that given tree and that's going to set my current count equal to one and my next count
equal to zero.
So while length of nodes is not equal to zero meaning I still still have stuff in that nodes deck.
I set my current note equal to left popped out and the current count is going to be subtracted from
1 or have 1 subtract from it that it is going to print the current note value so I can check it that
are going to say if current no thought left notes that append the current note left next count plus
equals 1.
Similar check for the current note.
Right.
And then finally if my current count is equal to zero I can just print a new line and reset my current
index count to actually make sure the saw is working before we finalize the solution.
So what I'm going to do is just go ahead and set up a tree cell roots equals node and then we'll go
ahead and say root that left and root that right are two more nodes to 3.
So when we print this out we should see one space to three and you can try this out if a larger tree
if you want but now I'm just going to call level order prints on the roots and you notice here we didn't
exactly get the spacing right.
So why is that.
That's because of the print statement up here in Python to what I would have to do is put in a comma
in order to keep printing on the same line there.
So that's essentially just a print formatting issue in Python 3 you may have to adjust this.
What you could do as well is just get a new list and call it something like.
Line two prints equals empty list and then just go ahead and print out that list and have this line
be essentially an Append and then print it later on right before you print that new line.
It's up to you.
That's essentially not what the question is getting at.
That's just a print formatting issue.
So don't worry too much about that as long as your logic.
Higher checking for the current nodes both left and right and then essentially adding to this counts
and being able to print new lines is correct.
That's really the key to this.
The complexity of the solution is linear order and because that's the number of nodes in the tree so
its optimal will have to be able to check each node because we printed at least once.
All right.
So again basically what is going on is to print the new line in the correct place.
We're just counting the number of nodes at each level.
Now we're going to have two counts namely the current level counts and the next level counts that current
level count indicates how many nodes should be printed at this level before printing a new line and
then we just take away from that count every time we pop an elements.
What's the current level count reaches zero.
We just print a new line.
The next little count contains the number of nodes in the next level which will become the current level
count.
After printing the new line which is what this line right here is doing OK.
Then after that we just count the number of nodes in the next level by counting the number of children
of the nodes and the current level.
Right.
You can go in and check out the full explanation of Jupiter notebook.
There's a couple of mentions to something called breadth first search and also depth first search and
we'll discuss those later on in the graphs section of this course.
OK.
So that being said is a pretty common interview problem some actually know it well and there's various
ways of actually solving it.
So go ahead and feel free like you have some flexibility on your actual solution.
OK.
So that being said thanks and I'll see at the next lecture