Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on insertion sort.
So as always we'll be looking for an explanation and some visualizations of this sorting algorithm and
in the next Look troll actually implement it in Python.
So this insertion sort always maintains assorted sublist in the lower positions of the list and we'll
see what we mean by that in a figure in just a second.
But basically what happens is each new item is inserted back into that previous sublist such that the
sorted sublist is one item larger.
So you have this little portion of your list the sub list that you assume is already sorted and you're
basically passing the other elements from your array or list into that sublist and sorting them as you
put them in there.
So you begin by assuming that a list of one item.
So your element a position zero or index 0 is already sorted.
And then on each pass one for each item one through and minus one the current item is checked against
those already in that sorted sublists.
And then as we look back into the already sorted sublist we shift those items that are greater to the
right and then when we reach a smaller item or the end of the sublist the current item can be inserted
.
So it's good to look at a figure of this actually happening.
So we assume as I mentioned here that your first item is sorted out of a list of one.
So the shaded items here represent that order it's sublease in the algorithm as it makes each pass.
So we're assuming 54 that element 54 is a sort of list of one item and then we're going to do is go
to the first item and the rest that list number 26 and then insert it into that sub list and then we
put it before 54.
And now you have a sorted sub list of 26 and 54.
Then the next item 2:51 is insert into that sublist insert 17 we insert 77 and you're inserting you're
inserting them so that the list itself that little sub list is being sorted as you go along.
So as I mentioned before you beat your beginning by assuming that a list of one item at position zero
.
In this case that element number 54 is already sorted and then each pass one for each item 1 through
and minus one.
The current item is being checked against those already in that sorted sub list and then as you look
back into that already sort of sub list you're going to shift those items that are greater to the right
and then when we reach a smaller item or the end of that sub list that current item can be inserted
.
So it's going to look at that fifth past in detail.
So what we're inserting number 31.
See how that actually works.
So you need to insert 31 back into the sorted list.
So here at Number 31 and you see 93 is greater than 31.
So you shift 93 1 space over to the right 77 is greater than 31 C shifted over to the right 54 is greater
than 31 C shift 54 over to the right 26 is less than 31.
So you insert 31 then into that position.
So that's what I mean by reaching that smaller item or at the end of the sublist.
And then the current item can be inserted.
So as you're looking back into the already sorted sublist you're shifting those items are greater to
the rights.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and take a look at some other visualizations that you can check out.
So you can further understand that the insertion sort.
Mechanism's Okay so here we are at the Jupiter notebook and you have your resources for review.
So go and check out those resources for any visual or visualizations you want to check out this case
.
Ashley really quickly what the visual algo looks like here.
So I've created this random list of sorts.
Click.
Go in then check out what her pseudo code is doing.
So remember we're marking that first element as sorted and then for each sort of element we're essentially
extracting that elements and then checking it out against where it should go.
And then inserting it it jumped a bit here but inserting it through that mechanism where you're checking
which ones which elements are greater.
So as you're looking back into that already sorted sublist you shift those items are greater to the
right and then when you reach a smaller item at the end of that sublist you can insert that current
one you're comparing.
So right now take one more look.
So the next we're going to do is 36.
So here we have Element 36 being compared to all these elements to being shifted to the right if they're
greater than 30 it's going to get shifted to the right.
Here you have 15.
It's less than 36 so we're going to insert 36 26 it's going to be compared to all of these elements
all the ones that are greater than 26 are going to be shifted to the right.
Once we find one that is less than 26 we go ahead and stop the shifting and then insert that limits
.
And so if we speed up this process a little bit we'll see this happen that it's comparing it to all
the elements in that little sub list.
And look at that sublists.
It's marked in yellow here.
And then if we speed this up all the way we'll see the entire sorting process happen.
OK.
So I encourage you to go in and check out this visualization on your own.
Make sure you understand that pseudo code and in the next lecture we're going to actually implement
our own insertion sort algorithm in Python.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture