Hello everyone and welcome to your last interview problem for the trees section of the Course.
This problem is called trim a binary search tree.
Here's the problem statement given the roots of the binary search tree and two numbers.
MIN and MAX trim the tree such that all the numbers in the new tree are between the min and max inclusive
.
The resulting tree should still be a valid binary search tree.
So for example imagine you got this tree as the input you were given.
The roots of the tree and the methods and attributes of that root contain all the subtrees on it or
have the root 8 and you have some other children and branches on it.
And if you were given the minimum value of 5 and a maximum value of 13 you would essentially trim the
trees so it would look like this.
So now you only have values between 5 and 13 in the tree.
So we should remove all the notes whose value is not between the min and the max.
Want you to feel free to reference the lecture on the binary search tree for the no class.
Well it's really more in here.
As I've mentioned in other lectures the logic of your function in which case your function should be
in the form of this you should be able to take in a tree node.
You can either just have this is the root or the tree itself and that a minimal value and a max value
and you can just assume methods such as left right and value.
OK so there again there is no solution sell here because the nature of the code should really be more
logical and any sort of official test would essentially give away the answer structure.
Just focus your answer to fill out the logic of the solution using the methods described above.
Ok if that being said again it is a pretty common problem.
You can just basically Google trim the binary search tree if you want more information on it.
But in the next lecture we'll go ahead and go over the solution.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture