Hello everyone and welcome to the solution lecture for the trim a binary search tree into the problem
.
Just to go over the interview problem again one more time.
The problem statement was given the root of a binary search tree and two numbers min and max trimmed
the tree such that all the numbers in the new tree are between the min and max inclusive.
The resulting tree should still be a valid binary search tree.
So remember that BSD property that we were talking about in the binary search tree lecture.
So for example if it if we get this tree as input this one right here and we want to get a mean value
as 5 and a max value is 13 in your resulting binary search tree should look something like this.
And notice how the branches go correctly.
First 7 is greater than 6 so goes the right 13 to the 10.
It goes right.
So you remove all the nodes whose value is not in between the min and max and it's still a valid binary
search tree.
So I'm at the solution book so there's an explanation or solution right here as well as some code for
this solution and a discussion on the complexity.
What we are going to do is just jump straight to the live code.
Code this out and explain along the way.
So let's go ahead and jump to the Jupiter notebook.
OK here we are at the Jupiter note book and let's go ahead and begin.
First thing I'm going to do is say D.
If say trm will say binary search history b s t will take in the tree the min value is good and call
it in value it matches social code and Maxwell and we can go ahead and zoom in one more.
OK first going to do is say if not 3 return.
Meaning if we come finally to a node we just return.
All right so what are we going to do here to solve this problem.
We're actually going to use some recursive calls.
We're going to do a post order traversal of the tree.
Go ahead and review the traversal lecture in case you want more information.
The Post order but we're basic going to do is process the left children first then the right children
and finally the node itself.
So if form the Nutri bottom up starting from the leaves towards the root as a result while processing
the node itself both its left and right subtrees are valid Trimm the binary search trees.
They may be null as well or none and so what we're going to do at each node is we're going to turn a
reference based on its value which will then be assigned to its parent whose left or right child pointer
depending on whether the current node is left or right child of the parent and see what this looks like
.
So what I can say is tree.
The left is equal to and here's the recursive call trim b s t we pass in the left and again the men
vowel and the max of L.
Now we're going to do the same thing for the rights so trim BSEE say tree the left or Scuse me tree
that writes medieval Maxwell.
OK then we're going to say if men yvel is less than or equal to treetop vowel or less than or equal
to max stop Well we just return the tree since we know it's good and this is where we basically are
taking in the B s t property fences.
So we're saying if trees that vowel is less than or equal to minable then a return tree that writes
and then finally we'll say if tree of that all is greater then Maxwell return tree that left and that's
all there is to it.
So let's go and discuss this in a little more detail so each knows what we're doing is we're all return
a reference based on its value.
As I mentioned which will then be assigned to its parents left or right.
Child pointer depending on whether the current note is the left or right child of the parent.
If current nodes values between min and max So that's these checks right here.
MIN and MAX.
Then there's no action needs to be taken.
So it's good.
We just returned the reference to the node itself.
So again if that value is in between the min and max we know we're good there.
So we just return the tree itself or that node.
So if the current nodes value is less than minimum then we return the reference to its right subtree
and discard the left subtree.
So if it's less than the min Val we return the right subtree and we can do that because remember we
know it's a binary search tree so everything to the left can be discarded since we already know everything
left going to be lower than that minimum.
And then you can use the same logic here.
If a tree value is greater than the max value you can just return tree left because you know everything
on the right is already too big because it's a binary search tree.
So this is really all the interview problem is trying to get at the fact that you can think of these
three properties here.
First you just check if the value is in between the min evaluate the max value.
If so then you're good.
Return the tree.
And the reason you are returning that note to that tree is because you're doing a recursive call.
So you're going to eventually keep doing this and you'll take care of all the branches.
Which is why you have these two recursive calls for left and right then and this is the key is what
your interviewer will be looking for is the fact that you know if the tree that Val is less than the
minimum value you just return the entire right tree and you discard the entire left because it's a binary
search tree.
You know everything to the left is can already be discarded because of this line.
And then similarly can do the same thing here.
OK so again they're really just searching for your understanding of the binary search tree property
.
The complexity of this algorithm is order.
And where n is the number of nodes in the tree.
Because we basically perform a post order traversal of the tree business each and every node.
Once this is optimal because we should visit every node at least once.
This is a very nice question here that both demonstrates the effectiveness of recursion on trees.
This and your understanding of BSD so to really understand the solution to this problem completely.
Go ahead and review post order traversal and review BSD property entries so you can go ahead and revisit
those lectures.
As far as your code itself it doesn't have to look exactly like this.
As far as a tree that left or how you call the specific methods on tree that value case you're putting
in root turn node.
But the actual logic should be the same.
This line this line and this line then recursive calls here could be one depending on how your function
set up.
OK that's it for this solution you can check out the Jubran notebook with a written out explanation
of everything we're doing here.
An explanation on the complexity of the rhythm.
Other than that.
Good job and I'll see at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.