Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the sentence reversal problem.
But this problem given a string of words you had to reverse all the words.
So for example this is the best turned into the is this.
You also have to take care of all leading and trailing whitespace.
Do you know Python Well you could have taken advantage of Python's abilities to solve the problem using
split and some slicing.
Or of the use of the reversed builtin function.
So these are basically one line solutions to the problem.
The issue of these even though they are valid solutions in an interview setting you'll have to work
out the basic algorithm that is used.
So in this case we want to do is actually loop over the text and extract words from the string themselves
.
Then we can push the words to a stack and in the end put them all in reverse.
So let's go in and see what this actually it looks like.
Again all these are valid solutions.
You probably shouldn't do them in an interview setting.
You can go ahead and make your interviewer aware that you know how to do this.
But it's kind of cheating using Python's abilities which you really want to do is manually do the splits
on the spaces yourself in reverse everything.
So we're going to do is go ahead and do this.
So let's go ahead and jump to the solution and explain as we go along.
So I'll start by having read underscore word function taken a string S
then we're going to go ahead and start off by making a list called the words a variable called length
which is just going to be the length of the string and then a list called spaces which is just going
to consist of an empty string just a space of a stream there and we'll see where we use that in a second
.
Finally I'm going to make a variable called equal zero and that's because it's going to be an index
tracker because we're going to be using a while loop to solve this.
So again to say while I is less than length if as of-I is not in spaces and there's a variety of ways
you can do this you could have also which is not in spaces.
Meaning if the elements in that list isn't a space you could have also just said double equal sign to
that and you could have also have managed to do this as some sort of a for loop.
But we're just doing it in these general terms in case you want to switch languages.
We're going to say if the element is a space then the word starts with the index are going to say Wordstar
equals I.
And then while I is less than the length and as of-I is not in spaces meaning we haven't hit a space
yet but we're going to do is try to get the index where the word ends.
So in that case what I'm going to do is add one to I and then outside of that I'm going to say words
not pens
and I'm going to pen from where it starts
all the way to the index.
We got off and then I'm going to say line it up with that.
If they're going to add to the index then finally what I have are all the reversed words.
So in this case I'm just going to return
my reversed words joined up.
OK let's go ahead and test the solution.
So we make sure it works.
I'm going to go ahead and copy some statements.
So for instance if we do this.
Hello John how are you.
No the white space we've got an air.
So what's the problem.
No space is not defined.
So if we go to that line in spaces we'll do this right here and now we have.
You are how John.
Hello.
Okay great.
So we know it's working.
Let's do one more example to make sure we don't have any more errors space before the return before
space for space.
OK great.
So let's go ahead and go over this solution.
What are we doing here.
We're setting words as an empty list length is just a marker of that length list spaces is just equal
to a list with a whitespace in it.
The first element that is equal to zero.
So we're saying while I is less than length.
So while we haven't gone through out the entire string basically if SMI is not in spaces meaning if
Sri is not equal to this then we know the Wordstar the start of that word is that that index.
So then well I's less than length and size not in space.
Which basically means keep going until we haven't hit another space.
Add one to the index.
Then once that wildlife has completed we're going to append.
So that word's list from the words start index all the way to that new I.
Basically once we hit that then we add one to the index and keep going until it is less then until this
is no longer true until I am no longer less than a.
After that we just joined that list.
The other was the reversed works spaces in between just one space.
So if you wanted to further develop the solution.
So it's completely manual.
You can also create your own reversal function here.
That's pretty easy.
So I'll leave that as an exercise to you to go ahead and figure out.
So if you want we can just say return words here and let's see what we get here.
So now we have a list of words in order.
So go ahead and write your own function.
So same death final output that takes in that word's list.
And what I want you to do is kind of your homework assignment is fill this in so that the list comes
out as a reversed string.
All right.
So go ahead and practice manually reversing this list into a string.
So that becomes something like this.
But the point of this section here is to figure out how to use while loops in succession in order to
mark where it starts and word endings.
There's lots of different ways you could have solved this problem.
So don't worry if your solution wasn't exactly like this.
There's plenty of ways you can do it.
You can do it using four loops.
So don't worry about that again.
Just make sure you understand how to do this solution.
And as long as your solution works you should be fine.
All right.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture