Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview problem.
Is called string compression.
So here's the problem statement given a string in the form such as this.
So multiple letters compress it so that it becomes in this form.
So you have the letter and then the count of how many times that occur.
Put this problem you can falsely compress strings of single or double letters.
So for instance it's OK for a B to return a to b 1 even though there's technically more space.
So the function should also be case sensitive so that the string aka a lowercase a.
Returns capital a theory and lowercase a theory.
So fill out your solution below and then run this test cell to test your solution.
Ok that's it for the string compression again.
It's OK to do false compression such as this.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture