Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the string compression interview problem.
So the problem was this given a string in the form such as this bunch of letters you need to compress
it to become this letter and then the number of times that occurred.
Or this problem you could have falsely compressed strings of single or double letters.
So for instance a string a B.
It's ok for returns 8 to be 1.
Even though this technically takes more space with four elements instead of three elements in that string
the function should also be case sensitive so that three capitally three lowercase a returns this a
capital A three lowercase a three.
OK so let's think about the solution.
Since Python strings are immutable we'll need to work off of a list of characters and at the end convert
that list back to a string with a joint statement.
The solution below the one we're going to go through should heal this with time and space complexity
of order n where n is the number of elements in that string.
So let's go in and take a look.
Pay careful attention to comments here.
We're just going to go through the notebook but we're going to actually code this out and explain what
we're doing along the way.
So let's go ahead and begin.
We're going to start by creating our compress function and it takes in a string s the solution is actually
known as compressing without checking.
And it's called the run length compression algorithm.
So this one actually has a name already.
We're going to begin to run as an empty string so I don't make a variable called R for our run and compare
it to equal to an empty string going to make a variable called L and set equal to the length of our
string.
And let's go ahead and do two edge cases first edge case is if we have a length 0 string second edge
case is for a length 1.
So I'm going to say if L is equal to zero then just return an empty string.
If L is equal to length 1 then return the string which is going to be just one letter plus the number
1.
So for instance if string was just a single letter A B to return a 1.
So again we're not actually compressing in that case but this is just OK since we're just doing a run
length.
Now let's do the meat of the algorithm.
So in order to do that actually to initialize some values and to make a value called last and set equal
to the first elements of the string then I'm going to make a value called C.A. which stands for counts
.
That's also going to be equal to 1.
And then I which is going to be index marker when a set that equal to 1 as well.
So when I say while I is less than l the length of that list what I'm going to do is say if s of I.
So the element at that index of the string.
If it's equal to the one that came before.
So what this basically means is if the letter is equal to the letter before it let's go ahead and add
account.
So add to that counts.
Else That means they're no longer in continuous series so we're going to store the previous data.
I'm going to say R is now equal to r plus S minus 1 plus the count.
But we'll need to convert this into a string since we're just putting the string together as the run
.
Once we've done that we'll just go ahead and add to the index to continue on throughout the entire string
until it terminated that while loop.
After that we're just going to put everything back in to run.
So I'm going to say R is an equal to r plus at the previous plus s tr CNC and then going to return our
.
So let's go ahead and see if this works.
OK.
Well go ahead and run compress.
Let's put a string a B Zulily output a to b 2.
So we have an error here.
What's going on.
The reason for the error is because we need to reset the count after we've redefined our.
So I need to put in CNC here equal to 1.
And now if we run it you'll notice we get the correct result 8 to beat 1.
Let's try on more examples.
Here you have four seats so I should get 8 to be 1.
See.
We have eight to 1.
A to be one seat for by it on a maybe a to b one are still good there.
Let's see if it does lowercase good capitally lower case a too.
All right so that's it.
Let's go ahead and go over this run length compression algorithm one more time.
So what are we doing here.
We're just setting this run equal to an entire string l equal to a length of less checking or edge cases
initializing some variables.
In this case sometimes people use last as a marker.
We didn't actually use it but just keep that in mind some people tend to use that will also put in a
while loop.
So what's the while loop doing this is the heart of the algorithm we're saying while this index is less
than all of the string.
If the string at that index is equal to the index before it.
So that means if that element is equal to the element before we go ahead and add accounts.
Otherwise we build out this section of the run which is going to be our.
In this case if you look at what we are equal to an empty string.
So in the first run that's just an empty string plus that very last previous element plus the string
of the count.
So all these counts added together.
Compare it to a string and then we reset the count.
Once we did that we went ahead and added 1 to i.
And then we're back at the While loop until we're no longer less than the length of the string.
And then finally we add all the RS together in the same fashion.
We did it up here.
Then we just returned that run.
OK.
That's it for this solution.
Go ahead and go over the full notebook if you want every step explained as a comment.
But that's basically it.
All right.
Thanks Ron and I'll see you the next