Welcome to the course curriculum overview for the Python for data structures algorithms and interviews
course there's a lot of content in this course but it can be broken up into three major components.
The non-technical sections the technical sections in the mock interviews sections of the course.
Let's begin our discussion of the course curriculum is the not so critical sections since those appear
first to begin the course.
We have a discussion of company and job types.
This section of the Course discusses the company types and the various shop types available to you in
the software technology field.
After that we have a discussion on resume preparation.
You'll get hints and tips on how to prepare a great resume as well as a list of resume creation tools
for you to access online.
Then we have an online presence section you'll learn how to establish a web presence for recruiters
on Web sites such as LinkedIn and github.
Then we discuss networking.
In this section you'll learn how to build a network and leverage it for job opportunities.
After that we have the job searching section Well you'll learn about tools and resources to use on your
job hunt such as job search sites how to organize your job search and a list of company matching sites
.
Then we have the non-technical interview questions and answers section in this section of the course
You'll get ready for your interview of the fundamentals.
You'll learn the five steps to ace an interview and you'll also have a list of interview questions and
answers as well.
Discussion each one and how best to prepare for the non-technical portion of the interview.
After that the Post's interview section and this section we discuss post interview topics and learn
what to do after you have your interview.
This includes things like salary negotiations and preparing your references.
Once we do those topics we'll have the technical sections.
This will begin if a technical material installation guide to make sure you have all the materials you
need as well as of set up on your computer regardless of your operating system.
In order to do that technical questions and have all the materials set up for you beforehand then we
get to the meat of the course.
Algorithms and data structures.
Each of the specific algorithms and data structure sections has two parts to it.
Theory lectures in practice interview problems specific on the particular algorithm or the particular
data structure discussed in that section.
The algorithms and data structures we discuss are algorithmic analysis and Big O notation array sequences
.
Stacks.
Use index linked lists recursion trees searching and sorting algorithms graph algorithms and riddles
.
Again each of these sections includes lectures on theory and the topics such as algorithms and the various
data structures we discuss and then the second half of the.
Each of these sections has interview problems focus on that specific topic.
Then we have the mock interview sections in the mock interviews section we simulate for mock interviews
with four separate companies.
They include simulating an interview for e-commerce company a large search engine company a ride share
company and a large social network company.
Each of these mock interviews consists of tons of questions as well as the answers and solutions to
them all explained in a mock interview format.
After all that there is a lecture with bonus special offers for my other courses in case you're interested
in expanding your knowledge.
OK with all that being said it's time to begin the course.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.