Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on job search sites.
So we're going to discuss a variety of sites and job boards and you can go ahead and check out the next
lecture for continuously updated list of links that we're going to discuss in this lecture series couldn't
jump to a browser.
Check out the sites again quick reminder in the next lecture there there's a list of all the sites that
we check out here.
But the URL.
So let's jump to the browser.
OK everyone first say I want to let you know about is Angel dot co slash jobs.
This is focusing exclusively on startup jobs so you can go out and apply to thousands of jobs or just
one profile.
What's also nice about this is usually see salary and equity upfront.
Now a lot of times they're inflated.
So just keep that in mind when you're applying to companies here but you can go in to make a profile
and remember this is focusing exclusively on startup jobs.
So up next is glass door.
So glass door in case you're not familiar with it is a job review site so you can actually review your
current job or more your current company.
So people working at a company let's say Google if they're enjoying their job they give feedback to
glass door and say hey I rate Google of five stars out of five stars to work here.
Now Glassdoor also has a job search so you can look up a job location search and see if there's any
connections that way.
Next up is LinkedIn LinkedIn has its own job search tool that you can use and you need Illington profile
to use it.
And as I mentioned back in the Linked-In lectures if you have linked in premium or on the Linked-In
premium free trial you'll get extra information about the people who are applying to the same job you
are.
So it may give you an advantage there.
After that there is indeed that calm and needs a general search job search engine.
So you just put in your job title keywords or company name your location and then you can go out and
search for it.
After that there's monster you may have heard of monster it's pretty famous.
It was one of the first job hunting slash job searching Web sites.
Again put in your job title search for location.
See if anything pops up that matches this really similar.
It's more focused on the tech side of job search just keep that in mind.
Again quitting your job title keywords you're looking for location.
Then find tech jobs.
After that there is Stack Overflow careers.
So if you ever had an air and were looking up air hints or how to fix your code you probably ran a stack
overflow.
So Stack Overflow also has a careers section where you can put in keywords your location and search
for jobs on their listings.
If you're looking to get into Android development there's Android jobs the IO and will be focusing more
exclusively on just Android development.
So keep that in mind that you want that as an option another job search site is simply hired dot com
similar to indeed dot com in the keywords location and you search your jobs.
And then finally if you're looking for an internship right now there's a Web site called W.W. that look
sharp.
Dot com which focuses exclusively on internships for trying to help students find careers and entry
level jobs.
Again all of these are tech jobs.
Most of them are not.
So just keep them in mind when looking at through this Web site.
So that's it for all the job Web sites.
Make sure you check them out on your own time see which ones you like and use those.
I won't go into any more details here because you have the links in the next lecture.
You can check them out on your own time.
All right.
But that being said I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone