Well everyone welcome to the non technical questions lecture.
So in the next lecture you'll see a list of questions and what I want you to do is practice answering
these for your dream companies.
And I also want you to record yourself answering these questions or answer these questions when you're
in front of a family member friend.
So you can really get a feel for what it's like to practice answering these questions in a real situation
with someone else and recording yourself allows you to hear yourself and see how good of a job you're
doing.
All right.
That being said.
Go ahead.
There's a huge list of questions.
So just pick out five for each of the mock interviews to answer.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture