Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on tree representation implementation.
So in this lecture we're going to implement a tree as a list of lists.
So this is probably the simplest way you can implement a tree in Python.
It's not going to be the standard way of implementing a tree we'll learn about nodes and references
in a subsequent lecture.
Right now just want to get a basic idea of how we could represent a tree in Python.
So in a list of lists tree we're going to store the value of the root node as the first element of a
list.
Then the second element of that list will actually be a list itself that represents the left subtree
.
And that third element.
So it's going to be index too.
Remember you have 0 1 2 since the axing starts at zero.
So that third element index 2 of that list will be another list that represents the right subtree.
So for instance if you have a tree like this you can represent as a list of lists here a is at index
0 that's your roots and the notice at index 1 of this main trialist you have B.
And then again you have a list of lists representing trees and notice say you have these empty sublists
here since D E and F don't actually have any children of their own.
OK.
So that's what we're going to be implementing.
So let's go ahead and get started