Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture discussing what an adjacency matrix is and what in the Jason
C list is.
So we're going to learn how to represent graphs in this lecture.
And as I mentioned we're going to learn how to represent them as an adjacency matrix and an adjacency
list and in the next lecture will actually implement an adjacency list in Python.
So assist us with a matrix adjacency matrix is first.
It's one of the easiest ways to implement a graph.
And we just use a to them ungentle matrix in the matrix implementation.
Each of the rows and columns represent a single vertex in the graph the value that is stored in the
cell at that intersection of row and column w indicates if there is an edge from vertex V to vertex
w and then one to two vertices are connected by an edge.
We say that there are adjacent.
So for example here you can see a matrix in adjacency matrix and the value in each of these particular
cells represents the weight of an edge from that vertex V to vertex.
So that rows that columns.
So for example here we have vertex 0 in the row and Vertex 1 in the column the edge that connects them
has a weight of 5 and then we can go along and see that the two of you are connected with a weight of
four etc..
So that's how we can actually represent a graph in a matrix form which is useful to know.
So the advantage of the adjacency matrix is that it's simple and for small graphs it's really easy to
see which nodes are connected to the other nodes.
However notice that most of the cells that Matrix were empty.
That's because most of the cells are empty because the matrix is sparse.
A matrix is not a very efficient way to store sparse data because you have to store all those empty
cells.
In fact that Python usually have to go out of your way to even create a matrix structure like the one
we just saw
what the adjacency matrix is good for.
It's a good implementation for a graph.
When the numbers of edges is large but what do we mean by large and how many edges would be needed to
fill that matrix.
So there is one row one column for every vertex in the graph.
The number of edges required to fill the Matrix is the magnitude of the squared and a matrix is full
every vertex is connected to another vertex.
There are a few real problems that approach this sort of activity and the problem we're going to look
at in the future all involve graphs that are sparsely connected.
So we're really going to focus on is the adjacency list we won't be in the Matrix just because we're
not going to have any graphs that really have that many edges.
So scuzz want adjacency list is then says what we're going to be using.
So what we're going to be implementing in the next lecture in A-J see list is a more space efficient
way to implement a sparsely connected graph in an adjacency list implementation.
We keep a master list of all the vertices in the graph object and then each vertex object in the graph
maintains a list of the other vertices that it's connected to in the next lecture.
In our implementation the vertex class we're going to use a dictionary rather than a list where the
dictionary keys vertices and the values are the weights.
So keep that in mind.
Let's go ahead and show you an example of what this would actually look like.
So for example here we have our entire graph and it has six vertices.
So if we just look at one of them right now we're just trying this as a list.
You can see that essentially each key of that Vertex the zero then has an ID that the zero in it also
has the adjacent a set with the adjacent vertex vertices to it.
And the weight.
So for example the Zero has zero.
It has adjacent vertices v 1 and v 5 with corresponding edge weights a 5 and 2.
So you can see here we're actually not storing any empty data so list is a much more space efficient
way than the Matrix we previously saw.
So again that advantage of the adjacency list implementation it allows us to compactly represent that
sparse graph and the adjacency list also allows us to easily find the links that are directly connected
to a particular vertex.
So coming up in the next lecture we're actually do an implementation of an adjacency list in Python
.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.