Hello everyone and welcome to the bridge crossing problem solution.
So this is part of the common group of something called the river crossing puzzles and it's known as
the bridge and torche problem and sometimes at times assigned to each person are different and there's
actually solution algorithms for just generalized times the solution to this version is this.
But before I show you that go ahead and check out those links.
So I have a link here for the river crossing puzzle I'll take you to a bunch of versions and the one
we're looking at is the bridge and torch problem.
In this case we had a bridge and a flashlight.
So here's another example of what you can do.
And there's a semi-formal approach you can look at the variations of the problem on those links as far
as the one we're dealing with.
It looks like this.
First you have the one minute person and the two minute person cross with the flashlight or the torch
whatever you want to call it.
That's two minutes.
Then the one minute person returns and that's another one minute.
And here's the tricks of the problem getting five and 10 to cross together and then have to return with
the torch then I have 1 and 2 cross with the torch.
A lot of people think just right off the bat you might as we'll have The One Minute person be the guide
and do all the crossings.
But the trick is this step to have five and 10 cross and have to return.
That way you can get it down to 17 minutes.
All right.
That's a solution.
Check out the links in case you want more variations or draw out this solution in case you're having
trouble understanding it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture