Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on dynamic arrays.
Let's go ahead and get started in this lecture we're going to learn what is a dynamic array and we're also
learn how to implement a dynamic array.
So let's just discuss what a dynamic array is.
When you're building a list in Python you may have noticed that you don't actually need to specify how
large the array or that list is beforehand.
So for instance here we have a little diagram that we saw earlier of all the bytes that are allocated
to a particular array.
But in Python these lists are dynamic.
So you don't need to specify how large your list is going to be beforehand.
You can just keep constantly adding to it.
So how does Python actually do this.
Well it does this through use of dynamic arrays so that list instance actually often has a greater capacity
than its current length.
So if you put in a list with three elements and it usually that list is going to actually have a greater
capacity to hold more elements than just the three you initiated it with.
But if you keep adding elements to it or keep appending elements to that list eventually even that extra
space is going to run out.
So we're going to do is show a live coding example that really demonstrates the relationship between
the size and bytes allocated to a list or array and the actual length of the elements in the array.
So let's go ahead and jump to the Jupiter notebook and show you an example of this.
So here we are at the Jupiter notebook and let's go ahead and go over some code that I wrote out in
order to experiment just experiment and explore the relationship between the slits length and the underlying
size that the computer's holding in memory.
So first thing I did was I just imported as well as the system and that's going to allow us to use a
get size of function which will let us know the actual size in bytes that the computer's holding in
memory.
After that I just set an arbitrary n and that's going to be the amount of elements in the array.
And then I set an empty list called data and then we're going to say for I in range of an set a equal
to the length of data.
So that's going to tell us the number of elements in that list and then we're going to set be equal
to sys dot get size of data and that's going to tell us the actual size in bytes and then we're going
to print out the format to say length which is going to report back how many elements are in that list
and they're going to see size in bytes and we're going to format or use print formatting to print that
out.
And then after that I'm going to increase the length by 1 by just appending that particular number or
integer to the list.
So let's go ahead and run this and see what happens.
Right now we're running it for an equal to 10.
I'm going to zoom out a bit so we can see the various print statements.
Here we go.
So you notice we begin a full length of 0 and we have Cyzon bytes is 64 bytes are being used.
Now here's where the interesting part happens when we increase length to 1 the size in bytes gets increased
to 96.
But you notice as we keep increasing length all the way up to 4 the size in bytes doesn't actually change
.
So Python has done it it's actually set a number of bytes larger than what it needs to hold the current
elements in the list.
While it's appending new elements to the array.
So to get a better idea of this we're going to actually put in a much larger end.
Let's go ahead and put in
let's say 50 and run this.
OK.
So you'll notice a pattern here.
Basically as we keep adding elements to the arrays the size in bytes that list is using increases.
But you'll notice it happens in chunks.
So for the first element we have 64 bytes.
Good and zoom in on that.
And then for the next four additional elements we have 96 bytes so the first element has 64.
The next additional four have 96 bytes and then the next for 128 bytes allocated in memory and then
we have 192 for a larger section of the next bytes.
And then to 64 for a larger section and then 3 4 4 3 etc..
So you'll notice that as we keep adding elements basically what Python is doing is is grabbing more
and more real estate in memory and it's allowing us to see that there is an underlying change in memory
.
When you insert more or more elements until you need a memory usage jump.
So for instance back here if we look at the fifth element size in bytes 128 we can see that we needed
to make a memory usage jump so a basic analogy to this system could be almost like a hermit crab grabbing
larger and larger shells.
So this list is grabbing more and more space and memory until it realizes hey I'm growing large enough
that I'm probably going to need more in the future.
And then it grabs more memory but it doesn't in chunks so that it doesn't need to constantly do it for
every element that gets appended to it.
So even if you just add one elements after the first element they'll still grab 96 bites which is going
to be able to hold those next four elements one two three and four.
And then when you add the fifth element it's going to jump to 128 and that's going to be able to hold
future elements as well.
And it's going to keep doing these jumps almost like a hermit crab jumping to a largish shell until
it grows large enough that it's going to need to jump to another shell.
All right.
So it's going to go back to the presentation.
To finish off some of the theory of this.
All right.
So now at the presentation that we're going to do is just briefly describe what it implements a dynamic
array.
And then in the next lecture we'll actually live code and implementation out.
So the Python list class provides a very optimized implementation of dynamic arrays which we're going
to rely on for the remainder of this course but just for instruction we're going to make our own basic
implementation.
So let's go ahead and learn the theory behind how we're going to implement this.
And then in the next lecture we'll actually code it out live.
So the key to provide the key is to provide a means to grow the array.
Let's say in this case it's a.
So we want to grow the array a.
That stores the elements of a list.
And of course we can't actually grow that array because we already know that it needs have a fixed capacity
.
So if an elements appended to a list at a time when the underlying array is.
We're going to perform some steps and just go ahead and see what those look like.
So the steps are going to be first we allocate a new array let's call it B with a larger capacity and
then we set the indices let's say be of equal to a of I for I.
All the way from 0 to and minus 1 or endnotes to current number of items.
And the reason we are using and minus one is because the in the index starts at 0 and then we're going
to do is say set a equal to B and then henceforth for going to use B as the array supporting the list
.
And then finally we're going to insert that new elements n into the new array.
So let's go in and see an illustration of this process.
It's a little more clear.
All right.
So again here we have is in array loops a.
So we have this array.
We allocate a new array B has a larger capacity.
So that was the bytes that new chunk of bytes that we saw when we were actually programming out that
print statements.
So here we have this array already has references.
We allocate a new chunk of memory space and we'll call that array B.
And then we set the references here on storing elements of a in B and then finally we reference the
array B.
Now it's array.
So again the steps are we create the array B store the elements of a and b through a re-assignment of
the reference and then we call the B array.
Now it's a.
So now we have this new array and that information or that memory space that was allocated to the old
array can now be used.
Well we're not showing here in the diagram is what's called garbage collection of the old array or the
insertion of the new element.
We'll go over those in a future lecture.
Now the last remaining issue is to consider how large of a new array to create a commonly used rule
is for the new array to have twice the capacity of the existing array that has just been filled.
And later on we'll actually have a lecture that describing the mathematical analysis to justify that
decision.
And so just to go over that again we want to learn how large of an array to create that common rule
is twice the capacity of the existing array and later on we'll see a mathematic reasoning behind this
.
So just to review what we've done we learn what a dynamic array is.
We saw theoretically how to implement a dynamic array.
And we also saw some life coding on the thought process and just what's actually happening under the
hood so to speak where we're appending new elements but we can see that there's these chunks of bytes
and memory that are being allocated as we create new arrays.
All right.
So up next we're going to code our own implementation example of a dynamic array.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.