Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of sequential search lecture.
So again you can check out the previous video lecture for a full breakdown.
But in this notebook we're going to do is go ahead and implement sequential search for an unordered
list and then adapt it to an ordered list.
So let's go ahead and implement this.
Going to go ahead and jump to a MT Jupiter notebook and start writing up my function for a sequential
search.
So first thing I want to do is just go ahead and say DPF to start off her function and we'll call this
Eski SC queue search.
Call it whatever you want.
And it's going to take in two arguments the array or that list that we actually are searching through
.
And then the element or item we want to find a column a r r n e l e respectively.
So this is just going to work on an ordered list.
So I'm going to go ahead and start at position zero or create a very well called POS for position started
at zero and I'm going to create another variable called found.
This is just going to be a boolean and it's going to start off as false and it's going to become true
if we ever find the element in our list.
So we can do is say while the position is less than the length of our array and not found meaning we
haven't found that yet.
I can just say if the value of the array at that position is equal to the elements then we found that
so I can just say found isn't true else where we're going to do it just keep moving one down.
So I'm just going to say that's a position.
Add 1 to it.
And this is the same as just saying POS equals POS plus 1.
All right.
And then once you're done with that while loop you can just return the found element.
So it's pretty simple idea.
Let's go ahead to make sure it works.
I'll say one two three four five and then call sequential search passen the array and let's say I'm
going to search for six Senos will return false meaning we never found it.
Let's go in and search for three and it returns true.
Let's check in on the edges just to make sure it's working.
What is true.
Perfect in five is true.
All right.
So hopefully that should have been pretty logical you're going through every single element.
So items in that array checking if it matches up to your target and then changing that boolean variable
.
But remember from the previous lecture we said if we know a list is ordered We only have to check until
we have found the elements or an element that can be greater than it.
So we're going to do is edit our code a bit.
So it's a little more efficient given that we know it's ordered so I'm going to go ahead and recall
this ordered sequential search.
And again we start at position zero.
We still have the target that found variable which will become true if the elements in the list.
But I'm also going to start a new variable called stopped and I'll set that equal to false.
That's basically going to be a start marker.
And in this case I'm going to say my position is less than the length of the array.
Meaning we're still going through the array and not found we haven't found the yet and not stopped.
And that's going to come into play when we reach an element that scriptor then our target element given
that we know we can even write it as a docstring here input array must be ordered let's say Order slash
sorted.
OK.
So we have that as a check.
So again we're going to go see if we have a match.
Else what we're going to do is two things we're going to say if the array value at that position that
elements is greater than the elements self.
We'll just say stops is equal to true meaning we've already passed the limit.
So we reach an element that was greater than our target element.
So we're not going to continue going otherwise we're going to move on.
So then we'll actually say else and shift this code into that block.
OK.
So where you can go ahead and test this out.
We're going to just say this is already a sorted array.
Let's add a couple more items to it.
So that's one through 10 going to do sequential search and that's true.
Let's say 12.
And that's false.
So you can mess around with this.
It should work because we basically just added this check here and stopped variable.
All right.
So hopefully for you sequential search both the implementation and the theory around that is actually
pretty basic you just going through that array and doing the most logical thing you're checking it every
element.
If it's an unordered list if you know the list is sorted or ordered beforehand and then we change that
to must.
Sorry about that.
So if it's ordered or sorted beforehand you can just go ahead and add a stopped variable for it.
OK that's all there is to it.
And I will see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.