Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on personal Web sites and online portfolios personal web pages
are a great way to showcase your online portfolio or your blog.
So we're going to discuss some options and set you up have some links to check out and see what works
for you.
As far as blogging platforms some of the most popular ones right now are medium Wordpress and blogger
dot com.
I personally like medium but I encourage you to check all three of them out and see what works for you
.
Blogging is a great way to show recruiters that you're interested personally in the topics of programming
and can give you some or give them some insight into your own personal projects and what you're interested
in.
As far as website creation goes if you plan on applying for web development or UI positions any job
where you're required to use H to measure CSSA or javascript you should actually definitely be building
your site from scratch.
So just leave it at that.
Since web development and Web site creations any part of your job you should be familiar with this and
should probably already have your own web presence.
If you're looking for more standard programming jobs then there's website creation services.
These services are basically just drag and drop interfaces that make it really easy to create your own
web site.
Some of these services services right now include weebly Wick's Squarespace.
There's tons of options so google around for more.
A lot of them provide free versions on their own subdomains So for instance you could get your name
dot we bleed dot com.
If you don't want to pay for a domain name if you do want to pay for your own domain name I suggest
you check out.
Name cheap or Google Donat domains as ways of buying your domain.
But again google around for purchasing domains as far as the basics of a personal web site.
Make sure to keep it updated during your job search.
If you're running a blog it's a great way to keep track of everything you're learning.
So I would definitely recommend blogging your process of learning about different things but data structures
and algorithms.
Recruiters love to see that kind of stuff.
One final know personal Web sites some personal pages aren't really necessary as a LinkedIn profile
but they can definitely improve your standings among other candidates especially if you have an impressive
online for polio on your personal web site.
So that being said go ahead and check out some of those links if you are interested in blogging or starting
your own personal Web site.
I'll leave that up to you.
It's more important the focus on your LinkedIn.
If you're just beginning your job search right now then building up your personal web site.
So if you're just starting out I would recommend build your LinkedIn and github and then maybe start
a blog and keep track of what you're learning so far.
All right everyone.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.