Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture will be going over the recursion homework example problems
and the solutions.
Here is at the Jupiter notebooks and if you go to the recursion folder you'll notice a Jupiter notebook
called recursion homework example problems Dasch solutions.
You can go ahead and click this notebook.
They'll take you here to the solutions notebook and you can go ahead and read through the solutions
here on your own.
If you're interested in following along OK I'll go ahead and life code the solutions and explain the
thinking through them.
So it's go ahead and start off with Problem 1.
So the first problem said problem one writer occurs a recursive function which takes an integer and
computes the cumulative sum of zero to the integer for example of any calls for return the result of
3:04 plus tuples 1.0 which is 10.
So how do we do this.
First thing you want to consider is the base case.
So in this case if we write this recursively we have an plus and minus one plus and minus two all the
way to plus zero.
So regardless how high the end is we know it's going to go all the way down to zero.
So our base case will be then if n is equal to zero.
I want I'm going to return in this case is 0.
Because once I hit 0 I don't want to add anything else to it.
So this is our base case.
After that we have the recursive case which in this case what we're going to do is just return that
N plus our recursive call in that function
some
on and minus one and we can go ahead and check this out if we want to correct some on four.
And you'll know we get 10.
All right.
So go ahead and read through.
Make sure you really understand the solution here.
The big factor here was the base case recognizing it knowing what to return and then being able to transform
this line of thinking and plus and minus one plus and minus two into this line of code return.
And plus the recursive call on the function on end minus 1.
Hopefully this looked familiar to you because it's so similar to that factorial function we created
earlier.
All right moving along we have problem too.
Let's go ahead and make some more space in this cell given an integer create a function which returns
the sum of all the individual digits in the integer.
For example of unequals 4000 turned 21 return four plus three plus two plus one.
OK this one was a little trickier and I gave you a couple of hints.
So let's think of what the base case is here.
The base case will happen as we go along and use maade and division to take and strip these numbers
each individually will be when the remaining length of that N is just one.
So what I mean by that is if length of that digit is an error of this which I'll fix in a second is
equal to 1.
I just want to return that and we will have to strip off any more digits from it.
And what we're going to be doing in the recursive case else is doing something here to basically strip
another digit off of that.
So the error that's going to happen here if I don't fix it is that since it's an integer it actually
doesn't have a length.
So kind of a quick way and thinks to Python I could just cast it to a string and then take the length
and make sure it's equal to 1.
There's other ways to do this but in this case it's a pretty straightforward solution.
So how can I strip another digit If I'm not at the base case let's go ahead and just comment that as
the base case it's clear.
So I wrote about this in the hints and what I can do is return n mod 10 that will be the number I want
to add to the recursive call which in this case will be some underscore func and divided by 10.
Note that I'm dividing by an integer here and since this is Python 2 this will work correctly you'll
have to use the differences between classic division and true division.
So this is going to perform classic division since I'm using Python 2 right now.
If you're using Python 3 you'll have to make sure it is performing class division not actual true division
.
In order for this to work correctly and for you to strip these functions out.
OK.
There's a note about that in the solution book.
So moving along we have the last problem.
Now as I mentioned it's a more advanced problem than the previous two has a lot of variation on possibilities
.
And we're going to go ahead and solve it a particular way.
So let's go ahead and break it down.
So we have this function word underscores split.
So what I'm going to do is have in this case three arguments and no the solution I'm going implement
here makes a lot of use of the Python language.
Now the first thing you do is check if output is none unless the output equal to an empty list.
So the reason I just can't put in output as an empty list into the function here is because I'm going
to call it recursively and if I were to set it at the beginning as a default parameter it would overwrite
the output list that I want to put out every single time.
So basically all this does here if output is none up equals empty list is it just takes care of creating
an empty list on the first instance of that recursion.
So let's go ahead and think of what I want to do here.
I want to say for word in list of words.
So for every word in that list for word in list of words I mean just doing tab complete there.
I don't want to think if the current phrase begins with the word we have a split point.
So remember what we're trying to do here.
Want to create a function that takes in the string phrase in a set list of words and then the function
is going to then determine if it's possible to split the string in a way in which words can be made
from the list of words.
So what I'm doing here is I'm saying for every word in that list of words if the current phrase begins
with the word we have a split point.
There's lots of ways to do this.
You can just use simple indexing but I'm going to use a little Python trick here called starts with
which actually just checks if a string starts with another string.
In other way to do this would just be by indexing so you would check the length of this word if it's
equal to the first index so that phrase given that length.
But this is a little more concise way to do this.
And then when I'm going to do if that phrase starts with that word also but what's nice about using
starts with is it's super legible here you can really read it.
It's almost like pseudo code.
And then I'm going to append that to that output with word and then what I'm going to do now is recursively
call the split function on the remaining portion of the phrase.
So going to return ends right recursive.
Case comes into playing a word underscore splits an input the remaining portion of that phrase which
is phrase index from the length of that word.
Everything else I'm going to passen the list of words since that's not changing it's the same constraint
there.
And then I'm going to input the output.
That sounds a little weird but basically passed the output list that has been appended to.
And then finally I can return the output.
So this will happen if no phrase starts with that word.
OK.
Perfect.
So that's it.
You can go ahead and run the solutions that are in the solutions notebook here.
There's a little more explanation with the comments here.
So you can really get an understanding since is a bit of a confusing problem and there's lots of ways
to do it.
And also as I mentioned it's kind of a pythoness solution.
What I did here.
But it's nice and legible.
I encourage you to try to basically switch out this phrase using indexing.
So it's a little more agnostic as to what language is being used as far as programming languages but
that's it for the examples.
Hopefully they were a little challenging but not too impossible for you to solve.
Again go over them make sure you fully understand them.
And that's it for the recursion homework example problems.
After this you'll be faced if your first real interview questions involving recursion.
All right great job and I will see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.