Hello everyone and welcome to the singly linked list implementation lecture in this lecture we're going
to be implementing a basic singly linked lists.
Remember in a singly linked list we have an ordered list of items as individual nodes have pointers
to other nodes.
So as always you have a Jupiter notebook with the code that we're going to go through it's actually
pretty simple in this case.
And there's also some more discussion of pros and cons which we'll get to later after implementing it
.
So let's go ahead and jump to the live code and implement this singly linked list.
First thing I'm going to do is actually just create my node.
So I'm going to say class node objects and this is a big part of doing any sort of linked list interview
problem or question usually are going to have to implement Metro note class and use the different methods
and attributes of that node class to further answer the question that's referring to a linked list.
This case we're just implementing a single linked lists meaning I'm going to take in just one attribute
value or say self-talk.
Value is equal to that value.
So for example in the previous lectures we saw examples of values being pointing to strings referring
to airport codes so we could use that later on and so this is a singly linked list.
I just care about the next note and pointing to all of it as none for right now.
All right so we have this really basic class vnode and we're going to use it to build out a linked list
as a collection of nodes.
I'll say A equals no de-value want to keep it simple than be a of value too and then see as a node of
values theory.
Now I want to actually link these nodes together and to do that I can just say a next node is equal
to B and similarly it can say B next node is he could see and that's all there is to it.
So we've already developed our own linked list so I can go ahead and check the values from it and I
can also check out the nodes that are coming next.
Meaning I could say a next node.
Now I actually just get a statement on an object class here so node where it's being stored.
But I could call the value of the next node and that should give me the value of B which in this case
was 2.
So if you run that we get two out.
OK.
That's really all there is to it.
I hope that this implementation shows you how simple the idea of a linked list is.
You just have a node.
In this case and for a singly linked list you just care about that nodes value and then the next No
that's coming up.
You go ahead and create instances of those objects and then you just assign what the next nodes are
and then you can call their values as far as pros versus cons.
What's nice about linked lists is that they have constant time insertions and deletions and any position
in comparison arrays will owers require linear or Big O N time to do the same thing.
Link lists can also continue to expand without having to specify their size ahead of time so try to
remember or lectures on a race sizing.
From the array sequence section of the course where we talked about mortification and how he kept having
to double the array size since linked lists are just collections of nodes.
We can just keep inserting the nodes so we don't have to worry about the lectures on dynamic arrays
.
Some cons to a linked list is to access an element in the linked list.
You need to take O K time to go from the head of the list so that Kafe elements in contrast arrays always
have constant time operations to access elements of an array.
These pros and cons are written out for you at the bottom of the singly linked list implementation lecture
.
And this is probably the main one here.
To access an element in a linked list you need to take Ok time to go from the head of the list to the
case elements in contrast arrays always have constant time operations X elements in a rate.
Definitely the main thing to know here are this line of the pros vs this line of the cons.
Essentially if someone asks you an interview what are the pros and cons of using a linked list vs an
array.
You're really going to want to have these answers ready to go ok.
Hopefully the implementation was pretty simple.
I know we went over the theory in the previous lecture and it might have seen a little obscure but I
can really see how easy it is to just implement a node set up a value and set up a next note for a singly
linked list in the next lecture will be discussing doubly linked lists and after that we'll actually
implement one in Python and I'll also be pretty simple.
I'll have to add certain attributes and methods to that node class.
OK that's it and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thank you everyone.