Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on binary search.
So we're going to go over binary search in the next lecture.
We'll do an implementation of binary search and we'll also discuss the iterative and recursive versions
of binary search.
So in the last lecture we talked about implementing sequential search and how we had different implementations
for ordering or ordered lists and unordered lists so we can actually take greater advantage of the ordered
list.
So if we know a this is already ordered instead of searching the list in sequence you can do a binary
search which will start by examining the middle item.
So a binary search will start by examining that middle item if that item is the one we are searching
for or done if the item we're searching for is greater than that middle item.
We know that the entire lower half of that list as well as the middle item can then just be eliminated
from further consideration.
So you can already drop that off of our overall search then the item if it's in the list must be in
the upper half.
So we just keep repeating that process with the upper half Sarnath the middle item of the upper half
.
Compare against what we're looking for.
And again we either find it or split the list in half.
Therefore eliminating another large part of our possible search base.
For example let's look at the previous survey we looked that a couple lectures ago and search for 54
again.
Instead of starting at the beginning here is 17 like a sequential search.
But we're going to do is start right in the middle then we'll check this number against the target value
which is 54.
Since this number is less than 54 It's 44 we know everything in the lower half of the list can now just
be discarded.
Then using the upper half of the list we just continue on.
So we jumped to the middle here which is 65 says it's greater then we can start and keep doing this
basically splitting that list in half which is why it's called binary search and continually go until
we find the actual element that we're looking for.
So binary search uses divide and conquer we divide the problem into smaller pieces solve the smaller
pieces in some way and then reassemble the whole problem to get the results.
So you'll hear that term divide and conquer quite a bit when you're studying data structures and algorithms
.
Let's do a binary search analysis each comparison eliminates about half of the remaining items from
consideration.
Then we want to know what is the maximum number of comparisons.
This algorithm will require to check the entire list.
In this case it depends on the number of comparisons and approximate number of items left.
So if you have to make just one comparison then you have about an over to approximate number of items
left with to you get in over 4 3 and over a eccentric center all the way until you get to I comparison's
just a general term for items and you're doing an over two I tested the power of I approximate number
of items list.
All right.
So up next we'll see how to implement two versions of that binary search and you can check out the Jupiter
notebook book related to this lecture.
For more information on binary search.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture