Hello everyone and welcome to the Big O example's lecture.
So we're going to be doing here is showing you various examples of Big-O notation and what those algorithms
and functions will look like.
So at the end of this there's a reading assignment.
So here have opened the Jupiter notebook and if I scroll down here you'll see there's a homework assignment
.
So make sure that after we go over this video and once you've gone through the Jupiter notebook you
check out these two sources which are additional explanations of Big-O notation and various big-O examples
.
There are great explanations so go ahead and check them out.
OK.
So let's go and start off with our own examples.
So we're going to do is start with some simple examples of various big functions so the first one we're
going to explore is the constant.
So 0 1 so we're going to make a function here and I'm going to call it func underscore constants and
it's going to take in a list of values and what are going to do it's going to print the first item in
a list of values.
So it takes in a list called values and it says prints values it takes that first index and let's go
ahead and run this.
If I say func constant remember just doing tab for autocomplete I can then go ahead and pass in a list
.
Let's go ahead and just say ls t and assign ls t to be the list.
One two three.
OK so I've run that cell.
I'll see what happens here.
I get a result of Sumant of one here.
And if you notice I'll always get that result no matter how large that list is.
So this function is constant because regardless of the list size the function is only ever going to
take one constant step step size.
In this case 1.
So it's just printing the first value from a list.
So we can see here that an input list of 100 values will still just print one item even FS 10 velt 10000
values.
It's still going to print one item.
So a list of end values will still just print one item.
Which is why it is a constant.
BIG NO.
So let's move on to linear.
So I'll make a function here called func underscore lin will take in a list object.
It's called elist T in this case.
And this will take in a list and print out all the values so it's going to say for Valin ls t.
Print them all.
And if we go ahead and
call that on that list we just made note how we get every single value printed.
So this function runs in O N or linear time.
So this means that the number of operations that are going to take place here the number of print statements
is going to scale linearly with N.
So if we have an input list of 100 values it's going to print's 100 times.
We have a list of 10000 values it's going to print 10000 times and a list of end values will print and
times.
So that's why this is a linear example.
All right.
Finally let's go ahead and check out a quadratic example.
So let's say func underscore quad and we'll have taken ls t and it's going to print pairs for every
item in a list.
And what I mean by that is going to say for item 1 in that list and then for item 2 in that list go
ahead and prints item underscore one item underscore to.
OK.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
Reassign the list to just be 1 to 3 and then I'm going to call that function on that list
and let's see what we get here.
All right so what happens.
So no we have two loops one nested inside the other.
This means that for a list of items we will have to perform an operations for every item in that list
.
So that means in total we are poor form and times and actions here.
We're going to print this and times and times.
So that's going to be end times and or end to the power of two and squared which is quite dramatic.
So a list of 10 items is going to have tens of the power of two or a hundred operations there.
So you can see how dangerous this can be for very large inputs and that's why big OE is so important
to be aware of and it's such a crucial part of the interview process.
So now we're going to move on to a section of calculating the scale of big-O.
So we want to discuss now how insignificant terms will drop out of Big O notation when it comes to Big
O notation we only care about the most significant terms.
So remember as the input grows larger.
Only the fastest growing terms will matter.
And if you've taken a calculus class before this is going to remind you of taking limits towards infinity
.
So let's go ahead and see a quick example of how to drop constants are going to make a function called
Prince underscore once takes on a list.
Ls t.
And it prints all the items just once.
It's just going to say for thou enlistee prints the vowel.
And if I call print's once on that list I just get one into three.
So what is the big O of this function.
Go ahead and take a moment to think about it.
All right hopefully you saw that it's just 0 and it's linear.
You're going to do an action end times for the size of the list.
Now I'm going to show you a different example.
I want to call this function prints underscore too.
And I'm going to say for vowel in Alice T.
PRINCEVILLE.
And then when I'm going to do it again I'm going to say for vowel in ls t
print vowel.
So now let's call this function prints underscore to you know say get an output.
One two three.
So the question here is what is the big O her performance of this print underscore to function.
Notice we are printing it twice.
But what's actually happening here.
It's not going to be square because it's still linear.
It's going to be N plus n so two times then and this is where we get to terms with insignificant or
significant constants.
So we can see here that the first one actually made with prints on the order of O N and the second one
will print on the order of two times then.
So it's going to do it twice.
However if and is going to infinity the constant can be dropped.
And that's an important thing to remember.
You're going to be dropping most constants and only focusing on the terms that grow the fastest and
have the largest effect.
So in this case both of these are order n they're big O N.
So this is
0 then and this is also 0 then.
Now as I mentioned before in reality it's really just two times.
And but we're going to drop the constants there since two times infinity is going to basically be the
same as infinity.
OK so let's go to see a more complex example of this.
Of dropping these eggs in significant terms and these insignificant constants I'm going to make a function
called comp and it's going to be soon to be three parts to it what's first going to do it's going to
print the first item in the list once done with that it's going to print the first half of the list
.
So the way I'm going to do that is I'm going to say I'm going to call a midpoints equal to the length
of that list divided by two and then when I say for Val and list I'm going to slice it all the way to
the midpoints index.
I'm going to save Prince Val and then going to say for x in range tens is going to be the third operation
is going to print a string 10 times it's going to say Prince let's just say hello world.
OK.
So let's go ahead and make a list.
I'm going to say one two three four five and then call or pass that list into the function and I get
1 1 2 and then hello world hello world hello world.
Let's go ahead and make this list a little larger so the effect of that midpoint is a little more obvious
.
All right.
So one and then one two three four five and then ten.
Hello world.
So what is the big O of this function.
And the algorithm within it.
So let's break down the operations here.
Well notice the first operation this prince the first item is 0 1.
So I'll comment that in here 0 1 OK now what about this middle operation which I'm separating with some
comments here.
So if you notice here we're going to go all the way to end divided by two.
So in this case this is order of 1 1/2 times and which is the same as an.
Divided by two.
Now keep in mind that this is the same as order of basically 1 1/2 times.
And so just keep that in mind.
This is still a constant.
So and the vibe 2 is the same as one halftimes and that's going to be important because we're going
to keep the idea that as it gets larger these constants will go away.
And then this last one it performs the action 10 times.
So it's a constant.
So it's going to be constant officially 10 there order 10.
So a first part order one second part is order halftimes then and third parties order 10.
So in total what we can do is add all of these up and you may need to do this in an interview setting
is add up the different components in order to figure out the entire Big Show.
And in this case we get something that looks like this.
We have an order or big show and let's go ahead and make this a markdown so.
So right now that's the order of that function.
One plus and divided by two plus 10.
But now we can actually simplify this so we can see that it grows arbitrarily large.
Remember that was part of our definition of big-O as it grows larger and larger.
This one term and this 10 term becomes insignificant.
And then this one half or that divided by two term multiplied against N as it grows larger and towards
infinity is really not going to have much effect.
So that means that this function is actually can be simplified down to be of order or Big O N.
All right.
So let's just do a brief overview of what we did there in order to figure out the big-O this entire
complicated Well semi complicated equation or a function.
We separate out the parts.
Right.
Then we put them all together and then we simplified it as and grows arbitrarily large and then finally
what I want to discuss is worst case versus best case so many times where we are only concerned with
the worst possible case of an algorithm but in an interview setting its points keep in mind the worst
case and best case scenarios may be completely different for different big-O times.
So let's see an example.
Consider the following function.
I'm going to make a function called matcher.
It takes in a list and it takes in some item you want to match and what it does is given a list.
It returns a boolean indicating if a match item is in the list.
So I'm going to save for item in list if item is equal to match return true if no true is return then
the function will return false.
OK so remember I have my list here.
It's one through 10 in difficult matcher on it and pass in a list and then say I want one.
It's going to return true.
So one is in that list and we got a match.
Now if I call matcher list and I say a number that's not in that list such as 11.
Notice I get a false here now when we're concerned about big.
Oh you'll notice that we have a best case here.
So the best case is that the match occurs in the first item of that list and that means that in this
particular Best case you actually have a constants runtime here.
The best case is actually 0 1 constant.
Since the matches found at the first element in the case were there is no match every single element
has to be checked which is going to be any elements.
So the worst case is o n.
Now in an interview setting.
You're pretty much always dealing with either worst case or sometimes average case and we'll discuss
that in further detail for different data structures.
You can consider it if someone's asking you what is the big O.
Consider the worst case but make sure that you make a point of considering best cases as well.
Now finally I'm going to introduce the topic of space complexity.
Many times you're also concerned of how much memory or space an algorithm uses.
So right now we've been talking about performance or time complexity but we also want to keep in mind
space complexity and I'm going to show this through just two simple examples so I'm going to make a
function here called Def create list going to take in an and wanting and a half years make a variable
called new list which is just an empty list and then say for num in range and
you underscore list appends a string called new and then just return new list.
OK so if I say creates list five here you have 1 2 3 4 5 news there so no the size of the new list object
.
This object scales with the input of n.
So right now I'm just talking about space or memory.
So in this case this shows that it's a big O of just n or linear in terms in regards of space complexity
.
We'll have to take up an items in memory.
All right.
So another example I want to show you is a function a color printer
and it's going to print hello world a number of times.
That's going to save for x in range 10.
Go ahead and prints hello world.
So if I call a printer and I pass and then it prints hello world 10 times.
So what's the big O.
For the time complexity here.
Well it has to do this end times.
So has n o n.
For time complexity over time complexity this is linear.
But what about space complexity.
How much does this algorithm actually have to attribute to memory.
If you notice it's printing the same thing over and over again.
It doesn't actually have to save and items it just has to save one the hello world string.
So as far as space complexity it's constant has 0 1 so that's an important difference to make here.
In this case we have space.
Complexity is a constant one.
Since we're only having a save in memory this one item does print hello world string but we're doing
it as far as time complexity
order n..
OK so that's just something to keep in mind that there may be tradeoffs between time complex and space
complexity.
Usually in interviews you'll be concerned with time complexity but depending on the interview question
or case or who your interviewer is you may be asked about both space and time complexity so it's important
to keep them both in mind and know the various tradeoffs in certain situations.
All right.
So as I mentioned before at the end of this lecture there's a homework assignment.
So make sure you go ahead and read those two explanations on more big denotations and more big-O examples
.
All right.
Just to review what we did here we went over various examples of different big O notations and big O
common functions.
All right.
Thank you very much and I'll see you at the next lecture.