Hello everyone and welcome to the doubly linked list lecture in the previous lecture we implemented
using Python nodes and create a singly linked list from those nodes and the structural talked about
what doubly linked lists are.
And then the next lecture will go over an implementation in Python of doubly linked lists.
So as I mentioned we're going to have an overview and we're also going to focus on some specific topics
that occur in a linked list known as header and trailer Sentinel's.
OK so what is a doubly linked lists in a doubly linked list.
We define a linked list in which each node keeps an explicit reference to the node before it and the
reference to the node after it.
These lists allow a greater variety of constant time update operations.
This includes insertions and deletions.
We continue to use the term next for the reference to the no that follows and another will have a new
term however called previous or P R E V for short for the reference to the no that precedes it.
OK so we add special nodes at both ends of the list so that Hetter and that trailer a header node at
the beginning of the list in a trailer note at the end of the list.
You can check the diagram here.
Now this looks similar to that singly linked list.
Except now we're referencing previous lists as well not just what comes next but what was previous.
These dummy nodes are known as the Sentinel's or guards.
So we have the sedulous the center node.
This header Sentinel in this trailer node or trailer Sentinel every insertion into a doubly linked list
representation will take place between a pair of existing nodes when a new element is inserted at the
front of the sequence.
We simply add the new node between the header and the No that is currently after the header.
So for instance let's go ahead and take a look at what and the inserting and deleting would look like
in a doubly linked list.
Here if you're at the top we have our header sentinel or trailer Sentinel and then three nodes and know
how they all point at least all the nodes in the middle point to a previous node and the next node if
you want to insert a new node.
What we can do is just change the header or the next pointer in the previous pointer to accommodate
the new node.
So the steps are a what it looks like before the operation B.
After creating this new node and then see after linking the neighbors the new node pointing the next
and the previous to the corresponding nodes.
Now imagine we wanted to insert a note to the front.
What would this look like.
Its actually a pretty similar process.
So what it looks like before the operation after we create a new node and then we just really think
the heter sentinel to that new node and also then you know then points previous to the node and the
similar situation happens to the node that it just replaced the no that used to be at the front right
next to the header.
Now is talk about deleting a node.
The two neighbors of the node to be deleted are linked directly to each other as a result that node
will no longer be considered part of the list and it can be reclaimed by the system because of Sentinel's
same implementation can be used when deleting the first or last element of a sequence.
For example here we have three figures.
A is what it looks like before we actually delete a node.
And if we want to delete a node we just link the out the old node.
So in this instance we're linking up PVD.
So we point J.F.K. to SFO and then that node we say the previous note is actually J.F.K. no longer PVD
.
So all you have to do is just link our old nodes.
OK.
So we learned about doubly linked list notes how they point to both what's coming up next and what came
up previously we learned about insertion and deletion.
And now next we're going to implement a doubly linked list using node classes in Python.
OK thanks everyone.
And this will make a lot more sense when you actually see it coded out in the next lecture or see it
there