Hello everyone and welcome to the Jupiter notebook's overview lecture.
A quick note check the previous lectures for installation instructions.
If you haven't installed Jupiter notebooks already on your system this lecture we're going to be looking
at an overview of the Jupiter books capabilities as the best way to use them.
So let's go ahead and jump to Jupiter notebooks.
All right.
So I started Jupiter notebooks by following the installation instructions we just typed Jupiter notebook
either into your terminal or into power show or your command prompt depending what system you're using
.
You should get something like this in your browser.
I suggest using Chrome or Firefox.
Go ahead and click on the right.
You should see an option for creating notebooks either Python 2 or Python 3 depending on your installation
and then you'll see something like this.
So let's go ahead and go over what these buttons are and what this system's like.
So first off we have our toolbar here.
This is a save button which saves and creates a checkpoint for your notebook.
This plus button will insert a new cell and will discuss what cells are in a second.
So if you click it.
Haven't you so you can cut copy and paste cells using these three buttons.
This allows you to move up a select cell and then move down a slick cell.
This is run stop and restart kernels which is basically just same as running a cell.
And then you have another tool by here her file options and options viewing options inserting options
for cells then running options kernel options.
You're having trouble with a kernel being stuck in a loop and then you also have help.
So there's keyboard shortcuts here in case you want to know more about shortcuts.
There's also help for the various libraries used in scientific Python.
All right.
So let's go ahead and see how this works.
So for python we can go ahead and just write code straight into the cell.
So for instance one plus one and to run the cell I could either click run here and I will see a new
output right below the cell or I can also do type in the code and by clicking shift and then enter that
will run the cell.
So it's not just enter it's shift and then enter.
All right.
So that's one key feature of the Jubran notebooks.
Another one is hints and docstring completion.
So what I mean by that is if I start to write a function in Python.
So for instance SDR which converts things to strings I can click tab Erskine's me shift plus tab and
it will bring up the document string so I'll return a nice string representation of the object.
I can also call help on any function and I will get the entire docstring for that function.
So you have a couple of options here again whatever function you have and I just cleared that by running
an empty cell whatever function you have.
So for instance let's do another function.
Let's go ahead and import from the math library sunglass say from math in poor obscurity shift enter
.
And now if I'm using a security and I'm not sure what to do with it I can do shift tab with my cursor
right after that function.
It will give me the document string.
It'll give me the short version and if I want more I can click plus here and it will grow.
This should give you more information if there is more information available there.
So for instance if we want more information on list shift tab gets me the docstring if I want more information
like this down I'll give you more information.
There's more information available.
All right.
So what else can we do.
We can also see methods and attributes of an object.
So for instance by say as equals string let's say hello shift enter.
Now S is going to be that string.
So one thing to know is that these cells are not independent of each other.
If I set a variable in one cell that variable can be run and any other cells such as here it's saved
as Hello.
So just keep that in mind.
Again you can always check the order.
You ran cells in by checking the numbers here.
So 1 2 5 6 7 4 we ran over it so that we did three.
But what's nice about Jupiter notebook and I Python in general is that if you click s dot.
So let's say we wanted to do a certain method such as upper case all this letters are elements in that
string.
I could call Upper on it.
And then we get that as an output.
So what if you don't remember what these various attributes and methods are for a string or any object
you can do as thoughts or whatever object you have.
The DOT will be calling the method or attribute on it.
And then if you click tab you'll get a little dropdown list of all the methods and attributes you can
call an object.
This is super useful to know.
So again whenever you have an object and you want to call a method or attribute on it but you're not
sure which ones are available you can have the object click that and then tab and open up a dropdown
list for you and then if you click one of these let's say I want to do capitalize.
I'm not sure what it does.
I can just click shift tab and I'll return the docstring for that method.
OK.
So those are the main things to know what the Jupiter notebooks.
One last good thing to know is that there's actually different types of cells.
So go back to the first cell and delete the code from it and you can change the cell type.
So Jupiter notebooks don't actually support just code.
They can also support markdown and other cell types.
So if you go here to this toolbar dropdown menu you'll find that right now we have a code cell I can
click this and change it to a markdown cell.
You'll notice that inbox goes away.
Now I can actually write mark down which is just basic text so I can say hello.
And when I run the cell either by clicking here or by saying shift enter You'll notice I just have marked
out text.
So that's up in Python or any coding is just marked down text in the markdown so I can double click
to edit that text.
So this supports various markdown syntax.
So in case you're familiar with markdown syntax you can go ahead and take advantage of this.
You'll see a lot of this markdown in the Jupiter notebooks.
We have corresponding to every video lecture.
So just keep that in mind.
These are really useful for writing yourself notes or explanations.
So for instance you just ran one plus one hit shift enter the next cell.
I'm going to delete that and turn it into a markdown cell and then leave myself a little notes.
I just added two numbers shift center to run it and here left myself a little know about what that cell
does which sometimes might be nicer than writing a comment here.
So that's totally up to you.
There is a shortcut for making cells into markdown cells.
The shortcut is clicking control em and then again but notice times like the cell.
It's not going to work.
So I have to click outside of the cell See Notice the highlighting click outside of the cell do control
em once and then click em again.
It will turn it to a markdown cell.
And now you'll notice here I converted this into markdown text and all markdown Conventions apply here
.
You can go ahead and read more about markdown cells and mark them conventions if you want to know the
various syntax that I can write here to edit the text itself.
One last thing to note on markdown is it also supports latex in case you're familiar flater latex is
just the ability to write mathematical equations.
So for instance I can say as securty say of X here.
See if that works.
And here it's going to remove the print sees this are not actually needed.
And I can write mathematical equations in the Jupiter notebooks.
So that's also really useful for scientific computing and various aspects of mathematics and coding
.
Another good thing to know if you accidentally put for instance a while loop and it's running forever
and you want to cancel or stop the notebook from running.
You can go here to kernel and you can interrupt restart reconnect your kernel and that will allow you
to basically reset the Jupiter notebook.
That's all you need to know really for this course.
One quick note in the resource section of this lecture there's a link to this manual here and this manual
is basically the complete Jupiter notebook user's manual.
It's has a lot of information and you can check it all out here goes over well we just went getting
no Jupiter notebooks toolbar.
It goes way beyond the basics talks about markdown cells raw cells and head her cells various cells
that we don't use too often and this course we can go ahead and check it out here.
One quick note in case you see people calling this an eye Python notebook Jupiter notebooks used to
be called Eye Python notebooks until recently where they changed the name to reflect that it supports
other languages than just Python.
So just keep that in mind the python notebooks and super notebooks are essentially the same thing.
If Jupiter notebooks being the new name for Python.
All right.
So you can go ahead and click the link in the resource section to get a full background and all capabilities
of Jupiter notebooks as well as instructions on how to write various headers and markdown down text
etc..
OK.
Thanks everyone for watching this lecture.
That's it for now.
In the next lecture we're going to do is actually go over how we create the interview question notebooks
.
All right.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture