Hello everyone and welcome to the memo ization lecture.
Now I know in the previous lecture I said that interview problems were next.
But I wanted to make you aware of the topic memoization and this lecture which is actually going to
be mostly a homework reading assignment that I want you to be aware of.
So if you're in the Jupiter and B viewers under the recursion folder there's a python notebook called
memoization the I P Y and B you can go out and click it will take you to this lecture here.
And what I want you to do is before reading the notebook itself go ahead and click the link to the Wikipedia
article on minimization.
Give it a read through.
It's actually quite good as an overview in the pseudo code is very reminiscent of Python code so you
should have no problem reading it.
And it uses the factorial example that we used earlier to explain memorize zation.
And it turns the example we use which was recursive using a memorized version of the factorial function
.
So go ahead and take a look at that Bill line up perfectly with the factorial example we showed earlier
and go ahead and you can also read about automatic minimization which we discuss a little bit at the
end of the notebook.
But what I really want you to focus on is this first section of the overview for that article.
Once you're done reading that come back and then take a look at a coded example of the same factorial
problem using Python.
OK that's it.
Only one or two of the recursion interview problems will actually need memorization.
I believe it's actually just one memoization with recursion.
It's sometimes known as dynamic programming or at least a type of dynamic programming.
So I want you to be aware of that.
So I would recommend that you read that article and go through this lecture before heading into the
interview problems.
But it's actually not necessary to tackle the first interview problems.
First you'll see a warning or a note or  hints that will lead you to read the memorization lecture.
If in case the recursion interview problem requires it or is just the better solution to solve it using
that technique.
All right so that's it.
This is mostly just the reading assignment lecture.
So go ahead and read that Wikipedia article Overview section and then go through this python notebook
or Jupiter notebook.
All right thanks everyone.
And the next lecture Well we're actually going to be doing is going over the recursion into real problems
and the solution.
OK.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture