Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on the notes and references implementation of a tree.
So in this case what we're going to do is to find a class that has attributes for the value as well
as left and right subtrees and then some methods within that class.
So is this representation more closely follows object oriented programming or O.P. of classes in Python
.
We're going to continue to use the sort of representation for the remainder of the section of the course
so it won't do that Listable it's representation.
So just a reminder this is the kind of trip we're going to try to implement using object oriented programming
with notes and references so you can see nodes of ABC as root node.
And it splits off into left and right children and let's go ahead and go implement it.
All right so now I'm here at the Jupiter notebook representing a tree notes and references.
So as always there's a reference book under the trees folder.
This is the code we're going to be implementing here.
And here are some examples of the code being used.
So let's go ahead and get started.
OK.
First thing we're going to do is start out with a simple class definition.
So I'm just going to say class call it binary tree.
And objects and the start of its attributes.
So the important thing to remember about this representation is that the attributes left and right will
become references to other instances of the binary tree.
So let's going to make it pass and self and then going to pasan or just call it roots.
Oh B.J. for Root objects and I mentioned earlier that we sometimes call that root the key.
So we'll go ahead and say self-direct key is equal to root O.B. J.
And as I mentioned before we're going to have left and right attributes become references to other instances
of the binary tree.
So for example when we insert a new life child into the tree we're actually creating another instance
of binary tree.
In this case we're going to just start off with no child's or no children.
So we're going to say left child equals none to start off with and then say self-taught right child
equals also none to start off with.
OK so something to notice here is that the constructor function expects to get some kind of object to
store in that route just like you can store any object you like in a list.
The object of a tree can be a reference to any object.
OK.
Next.
Well we're going to do is look at functions we need to build a tree beyond that root node.
So what I would want to do is have an inserts left and take self and then some new node.
And I'm actually going to put in pass here for now and then we're also going to have inserts rights
and it would also take a self new node and we'll put it pass there.
So to add a left child to the tree we're going to create a new binary tree object and set the left attribute
of the root to refer to this new object.
So in order to do that we can start filling out insert left.
So I got to say if self stop left child is equal to none meaning we don't have anything there yet.
What I'm going to do is say self dot left child is equal to a new instance of a binary tree.
In this case if that root node being new node otherwise.
Similarly when we were doing the list of lists and a certain object or variable t would be equal to
a binary tree of new node and say the left child is equal to the self-taught left child
and then say self-taught left child
is then equal to see.
All right let's go ahead and break down what this code is actually doing on the insert left.
We're going to have to consider two cases for insertion.
The first case is going to be characterized by a node with no existing left child.
So self-taught left child is equal to none.
When there's no left child we're just simply adding a note to the tree.
The second case is going to be characterized by a note of an existing left child else.
So in the second case we insert a note and push the existing child down one level in the tree.
The second case is handled by the else statement.
So make sure you review this and make sure you understand what's actually going on.
First case there's no left child so we're simply adding a note to that tree.
Second case we haven't noticed an existing love child so we insert a node and push the existing child
down one level in the tree.
So the code for insert right is going to consider a symmetric set of cases.
There will be either no right child or we must insert the node between the root and an existing right
child.
So let's go ahead and code that out.
It's going to be really similar going to say if self-taught right child is equal to none then we just
insert that node right child is equal to an instance of binary tree with no node.
And there we're going to say.
Else t's equal to binary tree within you node number.
We're going to push it down to 1 so we're going to say the right child.
Let me scroll over to the right child as the call to self starts right child.
Then finally set self the right child equal to the reason for doing this is so you don't accidentally
overwrite something before you said it.
OK.
So now to round out the definition for a simple binary tree data structure we're going to write some
methods that allow us to access things such as the right and left children as well as the root nodes
.
So this will just be for methods.
Let's get some space here.
I'm going to say get right child self and then I'm going to return self-taught right child.
So that makes sense.
Forget the right child.
Similarly I'm going to do the same for the left child.
So get left child calls self and then it just returns self dots left.
Child I also want two functions for setting the value and getting the value.
So for setting the value we'll just call it set root.
Well
and it's actually going to need to take Oby some object to set the value and then we're going to say
sulphite key is equal to that object that you pass.
And then lastly to get the root value root.
Now we just need to pass in self and we're just going to return.
So the key.
OK.
So let's go ahead and quickly review what we just did.
We have a class binary tree.
We start off with the attributes.
Set the key are equal to that object that root node.
No children start off with.
And then we have to basically symmetrical methods for inserting left and right notes and you can see
that we check if there's something there.
If there is if there isn't we just said it equal to the new binary tree.
Otherwise we're going to push it down to the new level and then we have four methods for getting in
retrieving children and also getting in retrieving root values.
So let's go ahead and make a simple tree to show how this can work.
First thing we're going to do is set our equal to an instance of binary tree and we're going to set
a string a Whoops got an error here and that's because I forgot to write this correctly.
Sorry about that.
OK.
Sonera things working.
Remember if you ever have to double underscores in Python you also need to close them out.
All right.
Going down we have our binary tree our.
So let's go ahead and just start off by getting that root value.
So I can say by TAB get Val let's go and close print.
So we actually get something returns.
All right.
And there we have that value.
So if we say get child such as left child we shouldn't actually get anything.
So that's a nun.
So if we actually print this out you'll notice it turns none up.
All right.
So let's go and try inserting a left child.
So I'm going to say our thoughts insert let's call it be.
So he inserted something to the left.
So if I say our dots get left child they'll notice something interesting happens here.
Remember we actually get another instance of that binary tree.
So what I could do is then call roots off of this I second say then gets root value and then that's
how we get B.
So this nos and reference systems you're referring to subtrees again.
So you have your main tree and then subtrees within it which is why we just call that left child.
You got an instance of that binary tree.
All right.
So that's it for the basic implementation using nodes and references.
What I encourage you to do is try to build out your own tree.
So write a tree down just a simple one on a piece of paper and then see if using this implementation
you can actually code it out and insert the children correctly.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
I'll see if the next one.
Thank you.