Hello everyone and welcome to the solution to the coins and skill problem.
So here's how we go about finding a solution to finding the heavy coin.
You begin.
You begin by dividing the coins into two groups of three.
And then you have two coins extra set aside so you have three three and two.
So out of the two groups of three you grab them both and put them on the scale.
One group of two has been left off.
So if the two sides weigh the same the three and three then you already know the heavy coin is in the
group of two.
And then you just find that out with one more way.
That's a total of two ways there.
On the other hand if when you put the original two groups of three on the scale if either side of the
scales heavier than you know the heavy coin must be in that group of three.
So you can eliminate all the other coins and then place one coin from this group on either side of the
scale leaving the third coin aside if one side is heavier.
It contains the heavy coin.
If neither side is heavier and there even then the heavy coin is the one that you actually didn't play
on the scale.
So this is a total of two weighings as well.
So you can always find the heavy coin in a group of eight just using two weighings.
Draw out the solution in case you didn't get it.
But it's relatively simple.
Key to this is by making sure you were thinking outside of the box a bit and not being caught on the
fact that there's only two pans.
So you can actually divide the coins into more than just two groups.
That's the real key to this quest.
OK everyone thanks and I'll see at the next lecture