Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on doubly linked list implementation.
In this lecture as you might have guessed we're going to implement a doubly linked list in Python.
As always you have all the sample code in the corresponding Jupiter notebook.
This is called doubly linked list implementation.
Let's go ahead and get started.
First thing we're going to do is just go ahead and create a node class.
Go ahead and call this class Stubley playing list node in an actual interview setting you would probably
just call this a node class
and then we'll go ahead and initialize the attributes we're going to be using.
That's going to be self.
And then the value of that node
Persinger say is just self-taught valuables value just like the previous singly link in this singly
link list node implementation we have a next node will have a default to none.
But now since we're doing a doubly linked list node we have the previous node reference as well.
And that's going to be equal to none.
All right.
That's all there is to it.
So let's go ahead and build our linked lists now that we have a node that can reference both next and
previous values will say A equals the linked list node and I'm just putting tab as a reminder.
So if I just do the 0 and then click tab should auto complete for me that way to save myself some typing
.
So you have one to three is the values in an ABC are the actual nodes themselves.
Now let's go ahead and define the double linked list.
I'll do this by saying a thought next node is equal to B meaning B that previous node is equal to a
.
So that's setting B after a and I'm going to set C after a song to say B that next node equals C and
then c the previous node equals B and that's all there is to it.
Now we have a doubly linked list that allows us to go through our linked lists both forwards and backwards
through this previous node.
But more quick know is that you could have also created using this note class a circularly linked list
meaning just that this final node next node reference would be a.
So you would just have a loop a b c going around to each other.
That's also an option for you to do.
It has its own use cases.
So just keep that in mind.
But in this case we have our Hetter a in our trailer.
See for it doubly linked list.
OK that's all there is to it.
Hopefully this was pretty forward and straightforward and basic free especially after implementing a
singly linked list.
Coming up next we'll discuss more about linked lists and how to approach interview problems.
BORLING Louis thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.