Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of binary search lecture.
So here's your example notebook.
It's called implementation of binary search.
And you have two versions in reversion and then a recursive version.
So we're going to go ahead and go through both of them here.
Code them out explain or doing along the way.
And then you have the reference of the notebook in case you want to go back and check it out.
Let's get started.
I went ahead and started a new notebook here and going to start off with my first function just called
binary search.
It's going to take in an array and that element
lets go it and zoom in here then I'm going to say my first and last index values are going to be variables
.
I'll say first equals zero and last equals the length of the array minus one makes.
Indexing starts at zero and then I'll say founds as you call false and we'll just use found as a marker
just like we did for sequential search whether or not if we found that or not the target element that
is then I'm going to say Weil first is less than or equal to last and not found meaning we haven't found
our target element yet.
We'll go ahead and make a middle marker.
That case will call mid a new variable and that's just going to be first close last
divided by two
and then one I'm going to say is check if there's a match found if there's not going to set up new midpoints
meaning and it's going to go ahead and say if at that middle location we found the elements I'll just
say found the true and that's the end of the analysis there.
Otherwise else I'm going to go ahead and say if the elements is less than that value then my last equals
mid minus one
else.
My first variable is going to be equal to mid plus 1.
So all this loop is doing here this block of code.
It's just basically deciding if we're going to use that lower half of the list or the right half of
the list.
This is the case for lower.
This is the case for the right have.
And after that while loop is done executing meaning we've either gone through all the possible elements
of through our binary search and or we just actually found that it equals true at the end we just return
found.
OK let's go ahead and run this make sure we have no errors.
I'm going to go ahead and make an array.
And keep in mind the array must already be sorted.
We're taking further advantage of the fact that we have a sort of the array.
This won't work on an unsorted array.
Now let's go ahead and call binary search on the array and we'll look for.
Let's say for.
Ok perfect that's in there.
Let's look for 10 just to make sure.
And let's look for an item that's not there 13 balls.
Okay great.
So our normal version of binary search implementation is working.
Let's go through it one more time just to make sure we understand what's going on.
We set up a function to take in the array and the target element you're looking for.
We set up two variables first and last which are basically index markers.
Then we set.
Sound is equal to falls and then we're going to continually go until first is Lessner equal to last
and we haven't found the element yet we set a variable called middle which is just first Plus last divided
by two to get that middle index of that list or the sublist.
And then we say if at that middle index we have found the element then it equals true.
Otherwise if the element is less than the target element that is is less than the element at that middle
.
Set last equal to mid minus 1 meaning we've chosen that lower half of the list.
Otherwise we'll set first equal to mid plus 1 meaning we've chosen that higher right half of the list
.
Once you've done through this while loop we'll just returned the found boolean.
Either we found it.
So we said equal to true or it was never changed and we never found that meaning it was equal to false
.
All right.
So let's go ahead and implement implement a recursive version of binary search.
So we're going to do here is start off by just go ahead and clear up these cells
and I'm going to go ahead and say Ari C for recursive B.N. for binary and then search takes in an array
and that elements remember for recursive algorithms when you start off with the base case.
In this case will say if the length of the array is equal to zero return false.
So we're going to be continually doing is basically recursively calling our bin's binary search function
.
But if we finally got an array that's equal to zero as we keep splitting it then we know it never found
the elements so that's our base case.
Let's go over the recursive case.
So we set a mid that middle variable equal to the array the length of the array divided by two.
And similarly to the last implementation we say if the array at that middle index is equal to the elements
then we just return true we found it.
Otherwise we'll say.
Else we're going to call this again on the second half or call it on the first half.
So I'll say is if the elements is less than the value at that middle array are going to return a recursive
call here going to say R-S.C. binary search.
And I'm going to call it on that second half of the array.
Otherwise else
I'll return a recursive call on the array from Midhat plus 1 all the way to the ends.
This is really similar.
This is just a recursive version of choosing which half of the list to continually go on.
So if we scroll up we don't have it anymore.
But if you remember from the previous let me just hop over to Jupiter notebooks or I can show you we
had essentially this set of midpoints where we went either for the lower half the list or the higher
half.
Using this comparison will reset up or last and first the variables were doing the same thing here except
for a recursive call where we use index slicing to passen which half of the list we want to recursively
continue on.
OK let's go ahead and make sure we have the error here and that it worked out.
I'll call it on that same array.
Let's go to print that array make sure it's sorted.
OK we're good.
Call it on that array and I'll search for the item 3.
Great that's in there.
And if I search for 13 we get false because it's not in there.
So looks like it's all working out.
Go ahead and review the Jupiter note book where it has comments at every step put in print statements
.
If anything's not making sense for you.
But again hopefully this should have been a pretty basic idea of just binary search or splitting that
list and hath continually checking if that middle point indexed element is equal to the element you're
looking for.
If not you just split it in half again.
The pinning on whether this is true or not your target is less than the array value at that middle index
.
OK.
That's it for the implementation of binary search and two versions.
Make sure you really understand binary search just the logic behind it because you're going to see that
concept again and again throughout various interview questions.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture