Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of a cute lecture and this lecture we're going to build
on our previous understanding of Queues by implementing our own class.
Q Before we begin implementing your own Q Go ahead and review the attributes and methods that this q
class will have.
So we're going to have five basic methods and attributes.
The first one which is just the Q class is going to create a new queue that is empty it won't need any
parameters and it's just going to return an empty queue and queue will take in a new item and put it
to the rear of the queue so it's going to need that item parameter but it's not going to return anything
it's just going to affect the queue.
The dequeue item removes the front item from the queue.
It won't need any parameters and it'll just return the item that it does queued.
The queue is then modified is empty.
It's going to test to see whether the queue is empty or not.
That won't need any parameters and will just return a boolean value.
True or false depending on whether the queue is empty or not.
Then the size method will return the number of items in the queue.
It won't need any parameters and it's just going to return an integer.
OK so those are the basic five methods and attributes we're going to do.
So let's go ahead and jump to the code.
Ok so here at the DUPERE no.
So let's go ahead and code this out.
Well first to start by creating a class and we're going to do is go ahead and instantiate our class
.
Going to take sell and we'll do same thing we did for the stat class.
We'll just have items equal to an empty list at first.
So so far we just have an empty queue.
Let's go ahead and create our is empty.
That's going to be the same as what we did for the stack.
We're just going to return the bully and check if the items attribute is equal to an empty list then
next to is going to be on Kure and q.
So we're going to do here is say on Q takes in cell and then that item.
So remember we're doing a first in first out principle.
Just like a regular cue or line as you wait at a cashier or something.
So in order to implement this we're going to do is take advantage of the inserts method that a list
can have and it's going to take two arguments.
One is the index you want to insert at and the other one is the elements or item you want to insert
.
So we're going to have inserted at index 0 and we're going to put in an item.
So as we keep inserting items we basically push the rest of them up
and then for decreasing what we're going to do is not take any arguments there and we're just going
to go ahead and pop off the item
and then finally for checking the size we're going to do is just return the lengths of sauf items and
let's go ahead and make that into the size method.
Sorry I wrote that in a bit of a weird order.
Ok so I ran that let's go ahead and mess around with it and make sure everything is working.
So create a variable Q stands for q.
Let's go ahead and just check right off the bat what its size is.
And let's make sure that it's empty.
OK so that's looking good so far.
Let's go ahead and add an item to it.
We'll add one and we'll add another item.
In this case we'll say two.
So now you should be asking yourself is if a call dequeue what item should I expect to come out.
Well remember it's first in first out principle here.
So I should expect the first item I put in one just has a stack.
We've gotten two out.
OK so go ahead and play around with this.
Make sure you understand.
Basically the first in first out principle here that we've done in our own Q class and make sure you're
actually able to implement this on your own.
OK that being said thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.