Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on tree traversals.
So we're going to learn how to traverse through a tree.
Andrew's going to be three main methods for this pre order in order in post order.
So we're going to start out by defining these three traversals more carefully and then look at some
examples where these patterns might be useful.
So they're commonly used patterns to visit all nodes in the tree.
These three and basically the difference between these patterns is the order in which each node is visited
.
And like I mentioned before there preorder in order and post order.
So we'll start off with preorder.
So the definition of preorder is that in a pre-order traversal we visit the root node first then recursively
do a pre-order traversal of the left subtree followed by a recursive pre-order of the rights tree in
an in order traversal.
We recursively do it in order traversal on the left subtree.
This is the root node.
And then finally do recursive in order traversal of the right subtree host order recursively do the
Post order traversal on the left so tree in the right subtree followed by a visit to the routine.
So if you notice you're basically just changing when you visit the root node and this will be more clear
when we actually see coded out examples of this.
What we're going to do now is learn through in a quick example on how you might use preorder.
So let's go ahead and check out this tree here.
So here we have a representation of a book as a tree.
The book is the root of the tree.
And each chapter is a child of the root.
Each section within a chapter is a child of the chapter and each subsection is a child of each section
and so on.
So this figure here shows kind of a limited version of a book fall into chapters and note that this
traversal algorithm works for trees of any number of children.
Right now we're just going to stick with binary trees for two children for each node.
All right.
So let's start with.
Suppose you wanted to read this book from front to back and a quick note in the slides.
There's notes about what I'm going to be talking about here with text of what I was saying as far as
the code implementation of this.
But I'm going explain this with just a figure here.
If you want to go in the fall on Tex you can download the slide from this lecture.
But anyways let's go back to the task at hand trying to read this book from front to back.
That's what the preorder traversal gives you exactly for ordering.
You're going to start at the root of the tree.
The book node and then you're going to follow the preorder traversal instructions.
They're going to recursively call preorder on the left child.
In this case it's chapter 1 and then recursively called preorder again.
On the left child to go to section one point one section one point one has children.
You can't make any additional recursive calls there once you're finished with Section 1.1 then you move
up the tree to Chapter 1.
At this point you still need to visit the right subtree of chapter 1 which section 1.2 as before we
visit the left subtree Which brings us to Section 1 point to point 1.
Then we have the note for Section 1 point to point to leave Section 1.2 finished.
We return to Chapter 1.
Then we return to the book mode and follow the same procedure for Chapter 2.
So the code for writing these tree traversals is actually pretty elegant given there's kind of two options
right.
This is the text of what I just said.
So the base case here as far as coding this out is simply a check of the tree exists.
So if trees if we have a tree then if the tree parameter is none the function's going to return without
taking any action.
Something to note here is right now we have this pre-order traversal algorithm as just a function it's
not a method.
So note here how there is no self-calming tree.
This is a function outside of the implementation of binary tree class.
So you could have also implemented this as a method.
So here we can implement a method of the binary tree class.
The internal method must check for the existence of the left and right children before making that recursive
call.
So it would look something like this.
You would have pre-order here self.
Here I'm just printing soft Buckey and then saying if self left child if self-taught right child so
you might be wondering what's the best way to implement this as a function outside of the class or as
a method within the class.
So implementing preorder or any of these traversal algorithms as an external function is probably better
in this case.
And the reason for that is that you're very rarely just wanting to traverse a tree.
In most cases you're going to want to accomplish something else while using one of the basic traversal
patterns.
So for now on we're going to write the rest of the traversals as external functions and moving on the
post order.
This algorithm for the sort of traversal is nearly identical to the preorder except that we're gonna
move the call to print to the end of the function.
So notice here we're going to check if that tree exists.
Then do the recursive calls from Post order on the left and right child.
And then we get that root value for.
In order traversal we visit the left subtree then followed by the root so we're gonna step print value
and then finally the right subtree.
So notice then all through the traversal functions we're simply changing the position of that print
statement.
And here I am actually using pi from 3 printing so the print function just gets a little clear.
So you notice here we have in order recursive calls.
After you check that the tree exists but for n in order that print function we actually getting that
value is in between the left and right calls.
OK so now finally for your homework assignment you're going to implement each of these algorithms as
a function room or not a method of function.
Outside of that binary tree class.
So you can go ahead and use the binary tree class we made in the last lecture.
The code is in the slice for reference.
So if you go throughout this presentation that we just went through you'll see the code for each of
these functions.
Go ahead and implement them and then play with them and see how it changes the ordering of the print
statements.
Notice here I'm using Python 3 style printing which you can import from the future module.
Or if you're just using Python 3 that's what you've been doing all along.
All right so that's it.
Go ahead and download this PowerPoint presentation if you need the code for reference or just look at
the video as you're coding along with your homework is to implement each of these three functions should
be pretty simple once you've done one you're basically just changing where you're getting that value
or that root node.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture