Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on hashing in this lecture will cover hashing hash tables
hash functions something called Collision resolution.
And the next lecture will actually implement our own hash table class using Python.
Something to keep in mind is that there's going to be a lot of topics presented throughout this lecture
.
So make sure you set out enough time to fully understand the topics presented here and take notes on
them.
OK so we've seen how we can improve search by knowing about structures beforehand.
If you remember back to sequential search or binary search we're able to improve our search Big O by
knowing if the array was already sorted we were going to search for objects we can actually build the
data structure that can be searched in constant time order one.
This concept is referred to as Hashi.
All right so what is hashing What's a hash table.
A hash table is a collection of items which are stored in such a way as to make it easier to find them
later.
Each position of the hash table known as slots can hold that item and is named by an integer value starting
at zero.
So for example we will have a slot named Zero the slot names one a slot named two and so on.
Initially the hash table contains no items.
So every slot is empty.
We can implement a hash table by using a list with each element initialized to the special Python value
.
So for example is a figure of an empty hash table with size m equals 11 would look like.
So we have from 0 to 10 essentially indexes of our list and they're all filled with none.
So the mapping between an item and the slot where that item belongs in the hash table is called the
hash function.
And this is the real key to how a hash table works.
The hash function will take any item in the collection and return an integer in the range of slot names
between 0 and minus 1.
So we want to think about is how should we use hash functions to map items to slots one hash function
we can use is known as the remainder method when presented with an item the hash function is the item
divided by the table size.
And this is then a slot number.
Let's go in and see an example of how this works.
So assume that we have a set of integer items.
Let's say 50 for 26:23 17 77 31 we pre-assigned that empty hash table of equals 11.
That was that figure we saw earlier of just essentially empty list.
So what our remainder hash function is then is it's a function that takes in the item and returns the
item divided by 11.
Its remainder.
So that Mada function where that maade percentage sign you can use in Python which just returns the
remainder of a division.
It's good to see the results as a table.
So 54 maade 11 returns 10 26.
Model 7 returns for 93 model Evon returns 5 17 6 7 7 0 and 31 etc. 9.
So we're doing 54 maade 11 to get the hash value meaning 54 divided by 11 is going to be 44 remainder
10.
That means we're now ready to occupy six out of those 11 slots.
And this is referred to as the load factor and it's sometimes denoted by the equation.
The load factors equal to the number of items divided by table size.
And in this example the load factor is 6.
Number of items divided by the table size of 11.
That means.
Hash table and it looks like this after it was loaded with those items.
So again we just use that hash function.
In this case the remainder method to assign slots those number slots to the elements or items we wanted
to put into it.
So for example let's take a look here at 77 77 was the elements that we wanted to put into a specific
slot or hash table.
So 77 divided by 11 is seven with remainder 0 that remainder is a slot that we put it in
what you want to search for an item.
All we have to do is simply use the hash function to compute the slot name for the item and then check
the hash table to see if it's present or not.
That allows the searching operation to be done at Big 0 1 since it costs the amount of time is required
to compute the hash value and then index the hash table at that location.
Then you might be thinking what if you have two items that would result in the same location.
We discussed about 77 model 11 being 0.
But if you had another item such as 44 that would also be the same slot number 0.
This is known as a collision sometimes also known as a clash.
We're actually going to learn how deal them a little later on in the structure where we're going to
do is learn more about hash functions in general first before we talk about collision resolution
now discuss hash functions a little more formally a hash function that maps each item into unique slot
is referred to as a perfect hash function.
That means our goal is to create a hash function that minimizes the number of those collisions.
It's easy to compute and evenly distributed the items in the hash table.
Let's discuss a few techniques to do this.
There's another hash function called the folding method and the full method for constructing hash functions
begins by dividing the item into equal sized pieces.
The last piece may not be of equal size.
These pieces are then added together to give the resulting hash function or hash value excuse me.
So let's go through a more complicated example let's say your item is the phone number 4 3 6 5 5 5 4
6 or 1.
What we would do is take digits and divide them into two into groups of two.
So 43 65 55 46 and then 0 1.
Then after adding all these numbers together we get to 10.
If we assume our hash table has 11 slots like in the previous case then we need to perform the extra
step of dividing by 11 and keeping the remainder.
That means to 10 11 is 1.
So the phone number 4 3 6 5 5 5 4 6 0 1 then hashes to slot 1 in another hash function method is called
the square method for the mid square method.
We first square the item and then extract some portion of the resulting digits.
For example if the item were 44 we were first compute 44 squared which in this case is 1936.
And then extract the middle two digits 93 and performed the remainder step to get 93 model 7 equals
5.
Here we have a simple comparison table of various items.
And then what their slot numbers would be if you use just the remainder method or if you something like
the mid square method.
OK.
So let's discuss non-integer elements.
We can also create hash functions for character based items such as strings.
The word cat can be thought of as a sequence of ordinal values.
And if you're not familiar ordinal values in this case just think of them as a way of converting that
string into numbers.
You can go ahead and do a Wikipedia search for ordinal values if you want a fuller breakdown of this
.
But in this case if you just want to use Python you can actually call in the built in function o r d
Passing this particular letter of that string and it will give you an output of the ordinal value that
relates to that string or that element of the string.
In this case passing in cat CHC result in 99 97 and 116 which you can then sum up to get 312.
And you could perform the remainder hash function on that and 3:12 Mada 11 equals four.
OK.
Now we discussed hash functions and a little more detail.
Let's go ahead and talk about collision resolution one method for resolving collisions looks into the
hash table and tries to find another open slot to hold the item that caused the collision.
So for instance we could start with the original hash value position and then move in a sequential manner
through the slots until we encounter the first slot that is empty.
This collision resolution process is referred to as open addressing in that it tries to find the next
open slot or address in the hash table by systematically visiting each slot one at a time.
We're performing an open addressing technique called linier probing.
So take a look at example of this.
Consider the following table.
Here we have 77 in slot 0 because 77 Maat 11 is equal to zero.
But what if we also had to add 44 55 and 20.
So if linear probing we basically just keep moving down until we find an empty slot meaning with inserted
44 instead of at zero we moved down.
Check that one was empty and filled it in 55.
We tried 0.
It didn't fit because it wasn't empty.
Then we moved over to one.
Again it wasn't empty.
So he filled in at two and we did a similar thing for 20.
So one way to deal with clustering is to skip slots thereby more evenly distributing the items that
have caused collisions.
So if you notice back here on one slide back we'll eventually have to keep clustering things towards
the beginning of our hash table.
But if we want to deal with clustering we can actually skip a certain number of slots thereby evenly
distributing those items.
So the more general name for this process of looking for another slot after a collision is called the
rehashing and the variation of the linear probing idea is called quadratic probing.
Instead of using a constant Skipp value in the last case it was just one we use a rehash function that
increments the hash value by 1 3 5 7 9 and so on.
OK.
Another note is that this means if the first hash value is h the successive values are h plus 1 pulls
for H post-9 H will 16 and so on.
An alternative method for handling the collision problem is to allow each slot to hold a reference to
a collection or chain of items.
Chaining allows many items to exist at the same location in the hash table.
Then when collisions happen the item is still placed in the proper slot of the hash table.
So the switch chaining would look like instead of going around and probing for a new empty slot you
would just basically chain off the original slot.
So numbers such as 44 and 55 would chain off that zero slot number.
And as more and more items hash to the same location it should be noted that the difficulty of searching
for the item in the collection increases.
All right so we've covered a lot.
We've covered hashing hash tables various hash functions and collision resolution methods.
Up next we're going to implement her own hash table class before we check that out.
I would recommend that you check out the resources section of this lecture which has the PowerPoint
and these slides we covered.
Go ahead and walk through them check your notes and make sure you fully understand the basics of hashing
and hash tables and hash functions.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture implementation of a hash table