Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the phone screen for the e-commerce company mock interview
.
So this was the egg problem.
You should have seen this before in the middle section.
But just to reiterate what the problem statement was basically you have two eggs 100 floors.
The eggs are strong enough so that they can be dropped from a particular floor in the tower without
breaking.
If you drop them below that target floor they're going they're not going to break.
You drop it above you.
They will break.
So how can you find out what the highest floor in it can be.
Drop that without breaking in as few drops possible.
It's going see the solution for this.
So if you don't understand the solution there's tons of different explanations online.
You can just google two eggs 100 floors and they'll basically go over different ways of showing you
the same solution.
But let's go ahead and get a basic idea of how we can go about this logically.
So let's say you start from floor number 10 and go up two floors in multiples of 10.
If that first egg breaks say at the 20th floor then you can check all the floors between 11 and 19 with
the second egg to see which floor it will not break.
So in that case your worst case for number drops is 19.
If the threshold was the ninety ninth floor then you could have then you would have to drop the egg
at least 10 times.
And the second egg nine times in that linear fashion.
So for the best solution what we need to do is minimize the worst case number drops.
So for that let's go ahead and generalize that problem.
And of course this is something you should definitely do in an interview.
Generalizing problems.
That's huge.
The interviewer will really like that you do that and it's really necessary to solve this problem.
So be the step value for that first egg is it's still going to be 10.
If we have 200 floors or a thousand of floors how do we figure that out.
So the point to note here is that we're trying to minimize the worst case number of drops which happens
if the threshold is at the highest floor.
So our steps should be of some value which reduces the number of drops of that first egg.
So let's assume we take some that value am initially then every subsequent step is minus one.
So you have an plus and minus 1 plus and minus two plus.
All the way to plus one equals and that in and number of floors.
And so this is actually a series which you can describe as n times and plus 1 divided by two equals
.
And this is a little this is basically the trick to the problem.
If we're able to convert this into this equation you can probably get here by yourself but realizing
that it equals this is a little trickier.
All right.
So now that we know we have 100 floors if any equals 100 and you solve for m here then you'd get thirteen
point six five Anson's thirteen point six five as a decimal of a floor.
We're actually going to rounded up to 14.
So now we know that worst case scenario is when the threshold of 100 floors the first 14 floors with
the number drops being 14.
So this is actually just a simple binary search and that's really what your question is getting it.
If you're aware of how a binary search works.
All right.
But that being said if you need to review anything for this problem definitely review what a binary
searches because that's really the key to understanding this problem.
All right go ahead and review the solution.
Make sure you know this problem pretty well.
It's probably the most common riddle or brainteaser out there.
All right.
But that being said let's go ahead and move onto the next solution.