Hello everyone and welcome to the phone screen solution for the social network company mock interview
.
So for this problem you have to remove duplicate characters in a given string keeping only the first
occurrences.
So for example if the input was tree traversal your output would be Tiare space.
Avi s.l as you remove duplicate E's T's and ours.
OK.
So let's go ahead and get started with the solution.
So as we're going through the string we're going to need some sort of data structure to keep track the
characters we've seen so far.
And we also need one that can perform efficient find operations.
So in this case a set data structure perfectly suits our purpose.
It stores keys that provides constant time search for each existence.
So we're going to loop over characters in the string and in each iteration we'll check whether we have
seen the current character before searching the set.
If it's inset then it means you've seen it before.
So we ignore it otherwise we include it in the result and add it to the set keep track for future reference
.
So let's go ahead and code this out.
So it's a bit easier to understand.
Let's go ahead and call our function.
Remove duplicates and will input.
Let's say you just put in put s and then we're going to say results equals an empty list.
And the reason for that is at the end what we're going to do is join that list.
So in Python I can do this here.
There's no space in between these single quotes and it's basically going to join every item in that
list together without a space in between.
I could put anything I want here.
And that would put that whatever symbol or letter or character you put.
So if I wanted to join everything of a comma.
But in this case it's I just want a single string.
I'm just going to join them with no spaces that are going to create another variable called Scene and
I'll set that as an empty set and then here's what we're going to do.
We're going to go for every character in a string.
If that character is not in scene then I'm going to add it scene.
Add that character and then going to take my results and append that character and that's really it
here.
So the time complexity of this algorithm is O N where N is a number of characters in the input string
.
And because set supports in order one or Big O one constant incertain fine.
So this is really the optimal solution and it's a really common string interview question.
So this problem hopefully feels pretty familiar.
There's a similar one asked in the array section of the course and remember that a lot of basic interview
question ideas overlap just a presentation is different.
So again this was a pretty basic problem.
That's why I always use the phone screen.
The main trick or key to this problem was figuring out that a set is a really good way to go.
In this case you just go for every character in that string.
If you haven't seen that character yet so it's not in that set you just add that character to the set
and then result to append that character.
Then at the end at least for Python you can join everything in that list together as a string with this
joint command.
All right.
That's really it for this fun screen solution.
I'll see you at the next lecture with another solution.
Thanks everyone