Hello everyone and welcome to your first interview problem per the array sequences section of the Course
.
This problem is called anagram check problem statement is this Given two strings.
Check to see if there are anagrams.
So as a reminder an anagram is when two strings can be written using the exact same letters so you can
just rearrange the letters to get a different phrase or word.
So for example the string public relations is an anagram of crap built on lies and the string Clint
Eastwood is an anagram of Old West action.
So just a quick note for this problem you can ignore spaces and capitalizations so the space G-0 can
be an anagram of God and dog and O space D space G.
So again you're given two strings a check to see if the anagrams.
So fill out your solution below and this function.
And here we can see anagram of dog god Clint Eastwood.
Oldest action.
A B B and.
True true false to booleans.
You can run this cell right here.
To test your solution below and see if you can pass the test cases.
All right.
But that being said.
Best of luck in the next lecture will go over the solution.
Thanks everyone