Hello everyone and welcome to the binary heap implementation lecture.
Just so you know all the code are going to be going through and the presentation is already written
out for you in the Jupiter notebook.
Also I highly recommend that you read through the Wikipedia article on binary heaps.
First before viewing this lecture Let's go ahead and jump quickly to the browser to go over these two
things.
OK here we are at the Jupiter notebook.
It's called binary heap implementation.
Now we're going to implement binary heaps with certain operations.
The operations we can implement are just binary heap which creates a new empty binary heap will add
an insert operation which adds a new item to the heap.
We'll have a Fynes men operation that will return the item with the minimum key value leaving the item
in the heap.
We'll have a DL for the delete men which returns the item with the minimum key value and removes the
item from the heap.
Also it is empty operation.
Essentially these are all methods in our class and is empty.
Method was going to return true.
The senti returns false.
Otherwise we'll have a size operation which returns a number of items in the heap and then a built heap
list which builds a new heap from a list of keys later on the lecture will actually discuss how the
list data structure can be mashed up for binary heap implementation.
As far as the actual code here it is written up for use to go ahead and check it out.
We're actually going to be basically looking at each of these Methot chunks and explaining them as we
go along.
Throughout this video lecture the other note I wanted to make was the actual binary heap Wikipedia article
.
So I highly recommend you actually just go ahead and read this first.
Just read the introduction and then go ahead and read both the hip operations on inserts and extracts
which are really similar to the ones we're going to implement and you can go ahead and read about building
a heap but that's not super important for this lecture but the heap implementation will probably be
super useful since it also discusses how to implement it with an array.
So we're essentially going to be doing the same thing implementing it for list.
So I highly recommend you just check out this article and read it.
It's actually pretty straightforward.
So definitely check it out.
OK.
With that being said let's go ahead and jump back to the presentation.
OK so we're back to the presentation.
Let's go ahead and continue.
All right.
First thing we're gonna do is in order to make our heape work efficiently we will take advantage of
the logarithmic nature of the binary tree represent our heat in order to guarantee logarithmic performance
.
We must keep our tree balance a balanced binary tree has roughly the same number of nodes in the left
and right subtrees of the root in our heap implementation.
We keep the tree balanced by creating a complete binary tree a complete binary tree is a tree in which
each level has all of its nodes.
So let me show you an example binary tree.
Here we have a complete binary tree.
And you'll notice it begins to only have one node at this particular branch because it has an odd number
of elements in it.
What's another interesting property of a complete tree is that we can actually represent it using a
single list.
We do not need to use nodes and references as we showed earlier or even a list of lists which was our
other implementation because we know the tree is complete.
The left child of parents let's say at position P is the No that is found in position to p in the list
.
Similarly the right child or the parent is that position two times P plus one in the list.
Let me go ahead and show you a figure of a complete tree with its list representation.
So here you can begin to know that this Tupi and two plus one relationship between the parent and children
given this representation that this represent the list representation of the tree along with the full
structure property allows us to efficiently traverse a complete binary tree using only a few simple
mathematical operations which we're going to see as we show you the implementation code.
We will see that this also leads to an efficient implementation of the binary heap.
So if we just look at this figure we can see that we have five as a level at the root level the tree
and then 9/11 at the next level.
14:18 19:21 at the next level down and then 33 17 27 and we see here the pattern we just have 0 as an
index of 0 and then we continue almost the levels so let me go over what I was talking about about that
too.
And that two P plus one let's say for instance we want to find out what are the children of the nine
node.
So over here the children are 14 and 18 Well we have the index of two over here.
So if you just want say two times P that parent value is two times two which is four.
And here we have 14 which is the left child who want to find the right child.
We just have to say two times P plus 1 p just stands for that parent position.
So two times two plus one is five and then we get 18.
So go ahead and try that one more time.
Here we have 18 let's say we want to find out the left child that's going to be 2 times P she's going
to be that 5 index times 2 which will bring you over to 10 which is 27 element which you found and matches
correctly.
You can go ahead and reference that Wikipedia article I mentioned earlier in case you want a full mathematical
breakdown of that 2 P and 2 P plus 1 so hopefully here you can see that it's pretty straightforward
and basic.
So again let's just go ahead and choose one other number will say 11.
So 11 is a position P equals 3.
If I wanted to find the right child of 11 I would say two times P plus 1.
So that's going to be three times two which equals six plus one is seven.
So I go to index 7 and here I found 21.
So this is pretty cool in the fact that I just need to use a single list.
I don't need to use those notes and references or the list of lists implementations that we saw earlier
in this section of course.
So keep that in mind.
It's going to be really useful as we implement our binary heap.
And again just a quick reminder as we continue on.
You can use that Jupiter notebook to reference the complete code.
I'll be showing you just screenshots of sections of the code.
First off is going to be the class Ben heap.
And as I mentioned we're just going to use a list representation.
So I have self-taught heape list equals to just a single number 0 there.
And self-taught current size equals zero.
So we have lists of just one single element of zero in the list and the current size is zero.
And what I wanted to point out here is that the next method we're going to implement is insert in before
we implement insert.
Let me go back real quick and clarify every step that's going on here.
We're beginning our implementation of a binary heap just with the simple constructor that Ben heap.
And since the entire binary heap can be represented by a single list as we just saw all the constructor
will do is initialized the list and an attribute current size to keep track of the current size of the
heat.
So you will notice that an empty binary heap has a single zero as the first element of the heap list
and this zero is not used but is there so that simple integer division can be used on inhalator methods
.
So if we scope back real quick you notice that 0 here.
This is really just for simplifying and all the other methods we're going to be using later on for integer
division purposes.
OK.
Let's go ahead and keep moving on.
So we have our constructor ready to go that class been here and we have the lists and current size.
Now the next method will implement is insert the easiest and most efficient way to add an item to a
list is just to simply append the item to the end of the list.
The good news about appending is that it guarantees that we will maintain the complete tree property
.
However the bad news about a pending is that will very likely violate the heap structure property.
However it is possible to write a method that will allow us to regain the heap structure property by
comparing the newly added item with its parent.
If the newly added item is less than its parent then we can actually swap the item with its parent.
Let's go ahead and see the series of swaps needed to essentially percolate the newly added item to its
proper position in the tree.
OK so here we have our complete tree and we just added new item 7 as the right child of 18.
So we're going to do is keep doing swaps and essentially percolate at the new node up to its proper
position.
So meaning we do one swap here and another swap here and noticed that when we percolate an item up we
are restoring the heap property between the newly added item and the parent.
We're also preserving the heap property for any siblings of course it's the newly added item is very
small.
We may need to swap it up another level in fact we may need to keep swapping until we get to the top
of the tree in this case.
We don't because it's just seven in the root was five
so this is just everything I just said as far as having to keep swapping to go up to the top of the
tree.
And as far as the method for insertion.
So what it looks like we have this perk up method and we're able to use this simple integer division
here due to the fact that we're using just that simple heape list.
So we just say if the list is less then well the list at that index is less than the heap list at that
index.
Integer division 2.
Then we set up this temporary variable as that integer division 2.
And this is just to deal with the classic division versus floating point division just so we always
have an index coming out here and then we essentially just reassign it to that original index and then
set the new the old index a temporary variable.
This is just a switching that's happening here.
And then we just say equal to a class division divided by two and then we have ready to write the insert
method.
So most of the work in the insert method is actually really done by that perk up method we just saw
once a new item is appended to the tree.
Perk up takes over and positions and you item properly so you can see here in the inserts we just append
they say the current size plus 1.
And then we call that perk up function or method to help us out and do the heavy lifting of the actual
inserting that's going on.
So if the insert method properly defined we can now look at the delete min method.
So since the heap property acquires at the root of the tree must be excuse me that the root of the tree
be the smallest item in the tree.
Finding the minimum item is actually pretty easy.
The hard part of the Littman is then restoring full compliance with the heap structure and heap order
properties after the root has been removed.
We can restore a heap in two steps.
First we will restore the root item by taking the last item in the list and moving it to the root position
.
Moving the last item maintains or heap structure property.
However we have properly destroyed the heap order property of our binary heap.
Second we will restore the heap order property by pushing the new root node down the tree to its proper
position.
So let's go and check out the series of swaps needed to move the new root node to its proper position
in the heap.
So here in this figure we just decided to remove that minimum element which is fine.
And in this case we're going to begin to doing some swapping.
So Will do one swap from this nine to the root and then we have 27 being swapped to go to that place
.
Then we're going to swap 14:27 to move 14 up such the percolating up and then you notice we have to
do another swap since 2007 is still greater than 17.
In order to maintain the heap order property all we need to do is swap the root with its smallest child
less than the root.
After the initial swap we may repeat the swapping process with a node and its children until the notice
swapped to position on the tree where it is already less than both children.
So here's the full code for Pickle percolating and note down the tree and it can be found in bouffe
Kirk down and the men child methods here let you go ahead and check those out on your own.
But it's essentially you doing the swapping mechanisms that we just described which then just leads
us to the code for that delete men and you can note again that most of the heavy work is going to be
done by this per down method.
So here's the code for delete men.
So when you call delete man you're just setting that return value equal to heape list one member cause
plus 0.
That index at 0 0 zero meaning list at 1 is your root node which is the minimum element in your heap
structure.
So you have that return value and you go ahead and return the return value at the end.
But before you do that you say replace that one equals self-doubt heap list self-talk current size and
then solve the current size equal soft or current size minus one.
So you readjust your size because you just got rid of an element you say replace that pop and then you
Pearch down and put down as follows.
This method of swapping and as well as getting that minimum child finding.
OK the reason we have the minimum child here as well is because pert down needs to call it in order
to find it.
Continuing on to finish our discussion of binary heaps.
We'll look at a method to build an entire heap from a list of keys.
The first method you might think of maybe like the following.
Given a list of keys you could easily build a heap by inserting each key one at a time.
Since you're starting the list of one item the list is sorted and you could use binary search to find
the right position to insert the next key at a cost of approximately order log and operations.
However remember that inserting an item in the middle of the list may require order n or linear operations
to shift the rest of the list over to make room for the new key.
Therefore to insert end keys into the heap would require a total of end times log and big-O operations
.
However if we start off an entire list then we can build a whole heap in just order and operations.
So there's the code to build the heap.
You can check it out in the Jubran note book as well.
But let's go ahead and show a diagram of what this is actually doing.
So we're actually going to essentially build a heap from the list that looks like this.
9 6 5 2 3.
So what happens here is the swaps that the build heap method that we just saw in the last slide makes
as it moves the nodes in the initial tree of 9 6 5 to 3 into their proper positions and although we
start out in the middle of the tree and work our way back towards the root that PERQ down method ensures
that the largest child is always moved down the tree because the heap is a complete binary tree.
Any nodes past the halfway point will be leaves and therefore have no children.
Notice that when I's equal to one we are percolating down from the root of the tree.
So this may require multiple swaps as you can see in the rightmost two trees.
So these two trees over here first the nine is moved out of the root position but after the 9 is moved
down one level in the tree Herc down method ensures that we check the next set of children.
Farther down on the tree to ensure that it is pushed as low as it can go.
Meaning we're checking here against three to continue pushing it down so no.
Now that 9 has been moved to the lowest level the tree no further swapping can be done and it's useful
to compare the list representation of the series of swaps as shown in this figure here with the tree
representation.
Something that might seem a little strange is when I said that we can actually build a heap in order
an or linear time.
The proof of how that actually works is really beyond the scope of this course in interviews in general
.
However just to know the key to understanding that is that you can build a heap in linear time because
that log and factor is derived from the height of the tree.
For most of the work in that build heap function or method the tree is actually shorter than a log and
then using the fact that you can build a heap from a list in linear time.
What we're gonna do is construct a sorting out of them that uses a heap and sorts of list in N log and
time.
OK so I know we went through quite a bit and that was some pretty heavy stuff.
So make sure you review that Jupiter note book and the Wikipedia article.
This lecture is going to lead into the next topic.
Binary search trees.
Go ahead take your time with this.
This is a lot of information it's just taken in one single essentially 20 minute span.
So if you want to review this again I suggest you check out the basics of that Wikipedia article.
Open up your Jupiter notebook and try to type along as you see the figures so you can slow down the
video or just pause the video and see if you can type along with your Jupiter note book and the figures
you see to correspond the code to the actual logic and diagrams that is happening with those methods
.
OK that's it for this lecture.
Thanks I know it was a long one and a lot of information.
So take your time reviewing it.
Thanks