Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of a hash table lecture and this lecture will be implementing
our own hash table to complete her understanding of hash tables and hash function.
Make sure to review the video lecture before this to fully understand this implementation.
Also keep in mind that Python already has a built in dictionary object that serves as a hash table.
You would never actually need to implement your own hash table in Python.
So let's talk about math.
The idea of a dictionary uses a hash table to get and retrieve items using keys is often referred to
as mapping in our implementation will have the following methods.
So we'll have our hash table class and it's going to create a new empty map.
It returns an empty map collection.
Then we'll have a method.
We'll add a new key value pair to the map just like a default Python dictionary.
If the keys are already in the map then it replaces the old value of the new value.
Also have a get method given a key return the value stored in the map or not otherwise.
Also have a DL which will delete the key value pair from the map using a statement of the form delete
map.
Also have Eliane which will return the number of key value pairs stored and will have in the map in
return true.
First statement of the form Keenum map.
If the key is in the given if the given key is in the map calls.
Otherwise it will explain that one a little more detail and we actually get to it.
So you have your Jupiter note book here all the code that we're going to be going over is available
for you here.
Code class hash table and you can check it out yourself.
No it's a lot of code but we're going to go through it and life code it out right now.
So let's go ahead and get started.
All right.
I serve in your Jupiter notebook and I'm going to go ahead and create class hash table and it's going
to be an object.
And let's start by initializing some attributes.
I say the F underscore underscore I-90 underscore underscore pasand self and the only thing I'm going
to pass in for an attribute that we declare at first is just the size.
I'll say softer size equal size.
And then I'll create another attribute called slots.
In this case we're just going to have to be equal to none times self-taught size where none is essentially
an item or a list within Intel.
Let me just show you real quick what I mean by that.
So this is a list with a none item.
So when we multiply it by self-taught size imagine we said Self that size is going to be 4 that it's
going to give you a list with 4 nuns in it so that you look really familiar from the previous lecture
.
Member that the initial hash table we just had a list of nuns
and then will say self-taught data siecle to none.
Multiply by self-taught size.
Ok first method were going to work on as put and put is going to take in self so we know referencing
and then a key and the data.
So no for right now we're only going to use integer keys just for ease of use of the hash function.
All right so first thing or do you just get the hash value.
So also a hash value is equal to self's hash function which going taken key and then the links cell
slots.
So we actually haven't developed the hash function yet but I'll go ahead and mark it off right now.
Hash function and it's going to say self he and sys right now we'll just have it EZ pass.
But this is essentially going to be the actual
hash function.
So we'll get to that once we're done putting in that method.
But essentially it's going to be the remainder method that very first hash function we saw.
OK so living along we're gonna do is after we get our hash value meaning we insert the key the number
the size will get a hash value.
Back then we'll check if the slots empty.
So if self-study slots at the hash value is equal to none then we know it's empty so we can say self
thought slots hash value is equal to the key and then self data at the hash value is equal to that data
.
We wanted to put here.
All right.
So that's the most basic situation we have where it's already done it's empty and your hash function
lined up with an empty slot so you fill in the key and the data.
Let's go ahead and actually fill out this hash function now will have it be the remainder method.
So that means that schook going to return the key mod size.
All right something to begin to know as we've discussed before if we have a collision case here where
the hash value does not equal none will have to take that into account.
In this case we'll need to basically create a rehash so finding next possible positions for that case
go ahead and create a method called rehash.
It'll take in the old hash value the size of the array and it's going to find the next possible position
by just saying return the old hash plus one motard by the size so this is essentially just moving along
trying to find the next empty slot.
So another we have rehashed done we can continue to fill out our Put method.
So if the slot is empty we fill it in with our key and data else.
That's not the case.
So the key already exists.
We'll just replace the old value so we can say if self-taught slots hash value is already equal to the
key meaning it's already in there they'll just say self-taught data at the hash value is equal to data
.
All right.
So otherwise what we're going to do is try to find the next available slot.
So I'm going to say else say next slots equals self-taught rehash
hash value with the length of self-taught slots so that matches up to what a rehash function.
Over here this method was taken so then we were going to try to get to the next slot.
So we'll say while self-taught slots in this case we'll just call it next slot that variable we just
made is not equal to none.
And self-taught slots of the next slots does not actually equal the key.
Well we can do is just say that the next slots is equal to self-taught rehash take in the next slots
and the length of the current slots which is self-trust slots.
OK so that's to get the next slot.
And then we'll set the new key if none.
So that means if self that slots to that list we're keeping track of slots next slots is equal to none
.
Then we just replace the values so say self-taught slots next slots equals key and then self-taught
data at the next slot
is equal to data.
Otherwise we just replace the old I'll say else self-taught data.
Next slot is equal to data.
All right let's go ahead and zoom out a bit make sure we fully understand what's going on because that
was quite a bit of information and quite a bit of coding.
So here we have right now our entire push function and this supposed to be on a new line right here
.
OK.
Let's go ahead and just rerun over what's going on and make sure it compares correctly to what we have
here in our official jus Perrineau book.
So first thing we're doing is just initializing our hash table.
We put in a size and then we create slots and data.
These are just two arrays of none with self-taught size and we're using just the Python list as we shoot
showed earlier then we have a put method that's going to put in a piece of data to the correct key.
So where do we actually put this data.
We use the hash value which we got from the hash function.
In this case for the hash function we just use the key and the length of self-taught slots the actual
slots we specified earlier because we're using the remainder method over here.
So after that we just say if a slot is empty or a hears of self-doubt slots hash value equals none meaning
it's empty.
We just fill in the key and the data itself.
Otherwise if the key already exists we go ahead and replace the old value.
And then in that case.
Otherwise meaning it doesn't exist.
We actually have to find the next available slot meaning we have to say next slot equals.
Rehash the hash value we get to the next slot over here.
So we continually go while and then we set the new key if none.
So this is setting a new key.
Otherwise we just replace the old value.
OK.
So we found out we that we we needed to use a rehash to find the next possible Can we just continue
along ticking the old hash function adding on.
And then again just doing a simple remainder method.
Let's now focus on getting items given a key.
I'll go ahead and zoom in for this.
While we focus on the get method so say death gets.
And in this case it's just going to take in a key just like we would for a normal dictionary and it's
going to return items basically get items which are our data by taking in a key and returning the data
that's matched up with that key.
We're going to set up a couple of variables.
First search we're going to say Start slot is equal to self-taught hash function which takes in the
key and then the length of self-taught slots
will start off with data being done at the end will actually return data will have stopped.
Equals false.
So the boolean to tell us what the stop will say found is equal to false and also the position marker
called just equal to start slot.
OK so right now we have Start slot.
And this is just telling us what slot do we start off on in our search based off the hash function.
And because of our rehash method we're adding if it's not a hit at the hash function.
We can end up doing is just continuing on until we actually find it.
So until we learn that it's not empty or found and haven't stopped yet meaning while self thought slots
at that position which is the start slot does not equal none and not found meaning or boolean variable
hasn't.
That data hasn't been found and not stop meaning we haven't stopped yet.
Then we'll just do a check.
We'll say if self-taught slots at that position is equal to the key then we found it.
So we can say found is equal to true.
And we just set the data equal to that value which is self that data position.
Else we'll say position equals self rehash at the position length of self-taught slots and we'll do
an additional check here will say if position is equal to start slots then we notice stop which is say
stop equals true.
And then finally we just return the data.
Let's go ahead and zoom out and make sure we break this down completely.
So we're trying to get a value or some data based off it's key.
So we set up our variables for our search.
The slot we're going to start in the data which is none right now whether or not we stopped whether
or not we found it and the position starts off at start slot.
And essentially we keep going until we discern that it's not empty or found haven't stopped yet.
So while the self-taught slots at that index of position does not equal none and you need to change
this to an actual keyword none and not found an out.
Stop that.
If self-taught slots position equals to key then found this was true and we just go ahead and return
that data.
Otherwise we have to use rehash to continue going.
All right let's go ahead and use add two more methods.
And these are going to be death underscore underscore gets item and these are just special methods for
use of Python indexing self key.
And we're just going to return.
Self-taught gets key
and the other thing we're into this case def set item underscore underscore self.
Key data
in this case we're just going to put it.
Will say self-talk put the data.
Now what this allows us to do this is just special methods in Python that allow you to use that bracket
notation.
All right.
So we wrote quite a bit of code here.
I mean it's a lot of code but we also just basic create our own hash table using lists as our base.
Let's go ahead and make sure it worked out and I won't be surprised if we get an error but hopefully
we don't.
Let's see if we're able to implement it correctly.
So I'll make my hash table.
I'll give it a size of 5 and let's go ahead and put on her first key so say 8 1
0 to 1 and we'll say h of 2 is equal to 2.
Now let's say H 3 is equal to 3 strings 3.
And let's zoom in on that.
We're not coding a whole lot of stuff anymore to create a hash table.
Assign some keys and some data.
Let's see if we can actually retrieve it.
All right.
So looks like that's working out.
So one two and shook finally three.
Looks like that's all working out.
So even though this is a rudimentary implementation we can place play around with it by implementing
different hash functions.
So what I would recommend to you is to implement different hash functions meaning if you're able to
take this existing code and mess around with hash function and rehash to try to implement the other
hash functions we talked about throughout this lecture that weren't just remainder methods where we
had those middle numbers and also those square methods as well as some ordered no value methods.
Go ahead and try those out and play around with it.
Now we can really build your understanding of hash tables and hash functions again realistically you're
probably not going to be making your own hash table objects and classes because you already have things
such just Python dictionaries or in other languages you already have hash tables that you don't need
to build out yourself.
OK.
Again you have the Jupiter notebook available to you.
It has all the codes you can copy along paste it read it at your own pace.
So I know we went through quite a bit.
And just to note it also has comments everywhere explaining every code block for you.
So really go over this code slowly.
Make sure you understand it and have fun with it.
Mess around make your own hash functions and check it out.
OK.
So that's it for the hash table implementation.
I know it was a lot.
So make sure you take your time and go over the Jupiter note books that are available to you and the
next lecture.
We're going to begin to discuss sorting out rhythms.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture