Hello everyone and welcome to the second recursion interview problem and this problem you'll have to
find all the permutations of a string.
So in this video lecture we're going to quickly go over what the problem is asking for where your solutions
should look like what the test cases look like and then I'll let you get on with tackling problem on
your own.
So it's going to look at the problem statement.
So given a string write a function that uses recursion to output a list of all possible permutations
of that string.
So for example if your string sequel's just the letters ABC you should return a list that looks like
this ABC ace ABC BBC etc. all the various permutations.
Now what I want you to know here if a character's repeated treat each occurrence as distinct.
So for example if your input is X X X you should return a list with six versions of x x x.
So don't worry about taking care of duplicate letters here just all the permutations as if each character
was distinct.
That should make your job a lot easier.
All right so you're going to do is fill out your solution below again.
Think about the base case what recursive call you're going to have to make in order for this to all
work out.
After that you can test your solution.
You'll run the cell to test your solution.
There's a couple of basic test cases here.
And if you pass all of them Ill say all test cases passed after you run that cell after you fill out
the permute function.
All right.
So best of luck.
This one's a little tricky.
There's a few different ways that you could solve that using recursion.
So don't expect your code to look exactly like the solution in the next lecture.
We're going to do is go ahead and walk through the solution.
Make sure you've attempted it first before seeing the next lecture video.
All right.
Best of luck everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture