Hello everyone and welcome to solution for the anagram problem and the sequence section of the Course
.
As always there's a full note book of the solution and it explains every step of the way as well as
give you the code.
We're going to go through this video.
So to start off with there's two ways of thinking about this problem.
First off if two strings have the same frequency of letters or elements meaning each letter shows up
the same number of times in both strings then they are anagrams of each other on a similar vein of that
logic.
If two strings are equal to each other once they're sorted then they're are also anagrams of each other
.
So let's go ahead and implement the second solution first and it's the easier one of the two.
So go ahead.
Make her function.
Anagram takes and two strings es one in S to and then we're going to do is just remove spaces and lowercase
all the letters.
So begin to say replace.
And then what this replace method does it say method on a string and it says basically replace all whitespace
right here.
A single white space with no space and space between those single quotes.
And after that I'm also going to lower it.
So let's go ahead and copy this line and then just change it to two.
So we're doing now just taking the strings.
Both of them and reassigning them to remove all the whitespace and the lower case all the letters after
we've done that.
We can simply return a boolean for the sorted match so I can say return
sorted S1 double equal sort in two.
So all I'm doing right now is I'm just comparing the strings that we've replaced after we removed the
spaces and lowercase letter.
I'm saying if they're sorted and then they're equal to each other then we know they're anagrams of each
other.
So let's go ahead and test this out.
You have anagram.
Let's go passen God or whatever God and and say dog.
And that's true.
Let's go ahead and passen
let's say Clint Eastwood the example from the problem the book Clint Eastwood.
And we'll do Old West action so notice are different amount of spaces.
The first one has one space.
The second one has two spaces but that won't matter because we've had this replace method in there and
if we run that that's true.
Another letter and it becomes false.
So we know the solutions are working great.
So the this sorting method is actually really quite simple but it's not the optimal way.
And in an interview setting you're probably going to be asked to implement a more manual solution involving
just counting the number of letters and its string to test your ability to understand hash tables which
we go over later on in this course.
So we're going to do is build out of fooler solution using counting and Python dictionaries.
So let's go ahead and call this anagram 2.
We're going to do the same thing.
Start off with Ripp move the spaces in lowercase the letters and then we're going to start off with
an edge case checks I'm going to say edge case check as a comment.
But I wanted to check if they have the same number of letters with both strings don't have the same
number of letters we can immediately say it's false.
That's not an anagram.
So they need to have at least equal matching number of letters.
So I can do this by saying if the length of S1 doesn't equal the length of s to return false.
OK.
So let's go ahead and continue on.
Next up we're going to create a counting dictionary so we could use a default dict from the collections
module but so that we don't use any special modules in Python.
We're just going to use a straight up dictionary.
Call it count.
So we're basically just going to count the frequency of each letter parents and then check that all
the counts of the same.
So we're going to do is fill the first dictionary with the first string and then fill a dictionary again
for the second string but subtract counts.
So the first time around we're going to add accounts for each letter.
Second time around we're going to subtract counts and then if we check the all the counts are equal
to zero.
We know there anagrams.
So let's go ahead and call this out.
So it's a little bit clear.
So I'm going to say for every letter in s one that string if letter in count
then I'm going to say count letter of that key plus one else count letter equals 1.
OK so what is this doing here.
I'm saying for every letter in that first strain if the letter is already in my dictionary then add
1 to that key that letter killer.
So as we go along let's say it's Clint Eastwood.
So I see C that I say if letters and count.
Well actually see since the first letter as we go along the string is not going to be in count yet.
So we're going to say else that's where I set this.
I said count of that letter which happens to be c.
So at that key C we're going to set it equal to 1 and then we're going to basically do the reverse for
the second string and say four letter in s two if letter in counts
counts.
What're you going to say minus one
else count letter is equal 1.
And I would just want to check that all the counts are 0.
So for Cain counts it counts of k.
It's.
Zoom down a little bit.
If count of k is not equal to zero.
I'm going to return calls.
Otherwise they're anagrams so I can just say return true.
Outside of that for loop.
So let's go ahead to make sure this solution works.
What's that.
OK so if I call this anagram 2 then you run it still false.
That's good.
Let's see if it works here.
And it's true.
Great.
So quick now on this second solution.
Again the use of a default dict form from the collections module in Python would clean up this code
quite a bit by not having to do these checks.
But the thing is we don't want to use things that might only be specific to Python.
So make sure to count every step.
One other thing that might clean up this code.
You could technically put this into the second for loop and build it in.
But I quite like this solution because it's really clear what we're doing here.
So again let's just go over each of the steps.
This is should be your preferred solution if you get asked this in an interview setting.
So check if their anagrams or not.
First off we clean up the strings lowercase all the letters remove any whitespace.
Great.
We do an edge case check.
So this would quickly tell us of our anagrams or not.
So we do if length of us one isn't equal to length to return false.
Otherwise we have a possibility of an anagram.
So moving along we create a dictionary called Count.
Then for every letter in that first string it's the letters already in our counting dictionary.
We're just going to say count at that letter so that key add 1 to that count.
Otherwise set it equal to 1 for letter in S 2 which is that second string do the same thing.
But now we're going to be subtracting.
So if letter counts then we're going to subtract 1 from it else that counts.
That letter is equal to 1.
And this is the setting right here.
That's basically going to trip up this third for loop.
In case it's not an anagram.
That's why this is again a positive equal to 1.
So this is what's going to be going off.
If this is not an anagram along with this as well so then it says for counts if count of k is not equal
to zero return false.
So if it's an anagram then this line should have occurred as many times as this line.
All right.
Hopefully understand should've been pretty straightforward.
Go ahead and code this out.
The tricky part to this question actually is having to do this by hand.
It's a lot tougher.
So I recommend that you go ahead and take out a pen and paper or a white board and cut out the solution
by hand.
All right.
With that being said.
Thanks everyone.
And I'll see you at the next lecture