Hello everyone and welcome to the general depth first search lecturer.
So in this lecture again we're just going to get a general overview of the F S and then afterwards we're
going to do a full live code walk through implementation of a graph a node class A B A Fs and a DFS
.
We haven't seen B and DFS live coded out yet we've just seen images of example code in the next lectures
following this one we're going to actually live.
Cut them out.
Explain all the steps you need and then you'll actually those are going to be your interview questions
as well as to implement each of those.
So previously we discuss the Knight's Tour and the Knight's Tour is actually a special case of a depth
first search where the goal is to create a deepest that first search tree without any branches.
So that makes sense because for the night's tour we wanted to visit each node exactly one time without
going back to the other nodes.
So that would be your deepest DFS street.
The more general depth first search Sexual a little easier.
Its goal is to search as deeply as possible connecting as many nodes in the graph as possible in branching
where necessary.
So it's actually even possible that that first search will create more than one tree.
When that first search algorithm creates a group of trees we're actually going to call this a depth
first force.
And as with CFS our depth first search makes use of Predecessor links to construct the tree.
So in addition to that the first search will make use of two additional instance variables in the vertex
class.
That's going to be the new instance variables discovery in finish times.
So this is just for the code that we're going to see later on this lecture that these two instance variables
are going to be useful to us.
We're trying to implement DFS the discovery time variable tracks a number of steps in the algorithm
before vertexes first encountered and the finished Time is a number of steps in the algorithm before
a vertex coloured black.
So this is essentially what the code looks like.
Here we have the entire DFS graph function or a class object and we have two methods in it besides the
initialization method we have DFS and the first visit.
Don't worry too much about this code itself.
Actually implement this later on.
Or a version of this later on.
What I want to do just briefly explain what this code would do as an example of a DFS.
So we have these two functions or methods inside the class.
DFS and DFS visit
and this implementation is basically an extension of a Graf's unnoticed that it's inheriting inheriting
a graph here.
So this implementation extends the graph class basically by adding a time instance variable and then
the two methods DFS and the first visit which we see here.
So looking at this line right here.
So for a vertex in self which has zoomed in here for a vertex and self underneath the DFS function you'll
notice that the DFS method iterates over all the vertices in the graph calling DFS visit.
So the first visit is essentially a helper function for DFS.
And the reason we iterate over all the notes rather than simply searching from a chosen starting node
is to make sure that all the nodes in the graph are considered and that no vertices are left out of
the depth first.
For us so it may look a little unusual to the statement for a vertex in cells.
Remember that in this case self is an instance of the DFS graph class and iterating over all the vertices
an instance of a graph is actually a natural thing to do.
So don't worry about this kind of unusual statement of for itself.
OK.
So moving on we'll check out the DFS visit method a little closer.
The DFS visit method starts with a single vertex called Start vertex and then explores all the neighboring
white vertices as deeply as possible.
If you look carefully at the code for DFS visit and compare it to the breadth first search or CFS.
What you'll notice is that the DFS visit algorithm is actually almost identical to be EF-S except for
that on the last line of the inner for loop.
So DFS visit calls itself recursively to continue the search.
A deeper level.
So if we take a look here it's going to be recursively called DFS visit right here.
So is being recursively called and it's going to try to do that to continue the search for a deeper
level.
Whereas b fs as the no to a queue for later exploration and it's interesting to note that we're b fs
uses a q DFS visit uses a stack and you don't see a stack here in the code but it's implicit in the
recursive call.
So I know it is a little complicated but don't worry about it too much.
We're going to walk through the full implementation later on in a feature lecture.
This is just to give you an idea of what it may look like if you're trying to implement this code.
So to get a better understanding of what's actually going on let's go ahead and try to diagram this
out.
The sequence of figures.
So this sequence of figures for an AC is going to illustrate a DFS algorithm in action for a pretty
small graph just a through f here and in these figures the dotted line indicates edges that are checked
but the node at the other end of the edge has already been added to the depth first search first tree
and in the code that we previously just saw that this test is done by checking that the color of the
other note is non-white.
So take a look at this.
The search begins at Vertex of the graph right here.
And since all the vertices are white at the beginning of the search the algorithm visits vertex a that
very first node.
The first that in visiting a vertex is to set the color as gray which indicates that the vertex is being
explored and then we set discovery time.
So one since vertex has two adjacent vertices B and these so we can see the edges here connecting B
and D.
Each of those needs to be visited as well and then we can actually make an arbitrary decision that will
visit the adjacent vertices in alphabetical order so that vertex B is going to be visited next.
So its color is set to Grey and then its discovery time is set to two vertex be also adjacent to two
other nodes.
C and D.
So we're going to follow the same alphabetical order and then visit C node C next.
All right.
So this is a vertex see brings us the end of a branch of the tree because if we look at this we have
a direct edge direct that edge and then no more there at that edges coming out of C..
So we've come to the end of one branch of the tree after coloring the node grades setting its discovery
time to three.
The algorithm also determines that there is no adjacent vertices to see.
This means that we are done exploring notes C.
So then we can color it Black sense and set the finish time to four.
All right.
So again we when we visit c we realize that it goes from gray to black because there's no other vertices
coming out of it.
We reached the end of a branch and since vertex C was the end of one branch we can now return to vertex
B and continue exploring and or the nodes adjacent to be the only additional vertex to explore from
B is the cause.
Notice how the edge goes out to sea and out to D.
So vertex D is then explored and we continue our search from vertex D which then quickly leads us to
vertex E and Vertex e.
Sorry I jumped a bit there.
Virtex e has two adjacent vertices B and.
Normally we would explore these adjacent vertices alphabetically but since B is already colored gray
the algorithm recognizes that it should not visit B since doing so would put the algorithm in a loop
right.
You would just constantly be going EBD EBD e.
So recognize is ok be is gray meaning it's explored.
So imma go ahead and check out the white note here and then we note that vertex F has only one adjacent
vertex C..
So since C is color black and there's nothing else to explore the algorithm has reached the end of another
branch and then from here on you can see that the algorithm works his way back to the first node setting
the finish times and then coloring each Vernice black for each vertex out of his black.
So I'll keep setting the finish times as we continue on and sudden and black as you basically go in
reverse.
So the starting and finishing times for each node display displayer property called parentheses property
and this property means that all the children of a particular note in the first tree have a later discovery
time than an earlier finished time than their parent.
OK so I know there's is a lot to take in.
Again you can check out the MIT algorithms course video playlist for a further discussion of DFS.
We're going to do next is basically go back to our roots in Python and implement all of these these
Cravath notes that breadth first search in the depth first search in a way that would be acceptable
in an interview setting.
So you can go ahead and explore those topics independently or on your own if you're interested in graph
theory a little more.
But the basic three questions are going to be asked in interview at least at a basic level is going
to be to implement a graph to implement B FS and then implement DFS.
So there's three real key interview questions so that's what we're going to cover at least how to implement
them in the next three lectures and then interview questions are just going to be asking you to repeat
those independently.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture where we're going to actually implement everything
we just learn