Hello everyone and welcome to the stacks queues and deques interview problems section of this course
before we began the actual interview problems and solutions.
Let me just give you a quick reminder of where you can find both the interview that books and the solution
notebooks.
Let's go ahead and jump to the NBA very early.
So here at the NBA viewers link you'll see the stacks queues next section of the course.
You can go ahead and click here for interview problems that will load up two folders stacks.
His next interview questions and then the solutions folder.
So if you go ahead and click on the interview questions you'll notice that some of the questions are
just implement a deck cue and stack those are actually in the first three questions we face that's just
going to be implementing a deck and a Q and A stack just exactly what that line is.
So we'll go ahead and cover those and a little more detail.
But there's two other questions that are more typical interview problem questions not just the simple
implementation.
All right.
Well that being said let's go ahead and start of the three problems.
I'll see at the next lecture