Hello everyone and welcome to your next interview problem is called a great pair.
Some could this problem even an integer array output all the unique pairs that sum up to a specific
value.
So for example here's a function called pair underscore some takes into arguments a list so that array
and then a specific value.
This case for.
And it would return two pairs 1 and three and then 2 and 2.
So you have two pairs here that are unique.
I can sum up to this value for quick no for testing purposes.
Change your function so outputs the number of pairs.
So in this case it would just output to.
However your function should still be able to return the pairs themselves but at the end.
Just count the number of pairs if you want to test your solution using the test cell.
So Phil your solution here below and then run this test cell to test your solution.
All right.
Best of luck to everyone.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture