Hello everyone and welcome to the solution for the hallway lockers problem.
This is probably one of the trickier ones out of these riddles so let's go ahead and walk through the
written solution.
The notebook so obviously just Camb. brute force and turn out this problem since there's 100 passes
.
There's just too many to count.
So you'll need to think about this algorithmically.
So let's begin by solving this problem choosing an arbitrary locker and see if we can then detect the
pattern.
So we'll start by choosing just Lochore 12 and then seeing if it's been toggled open after your first
pass.
So to start off we know we won't have to toggle it on any Pask greater than 12.
So we just have to think of the passes that occur on 2 through 11.
Now we're actually going to be able to count these out.
Remember it's a good strategy to get smaller subproblems.
And in this case we're just looking at singular locker.
So if we count these out we know on past Number two we're going to toggle two four six eight 10 12 or
past three we toggle lockers 3 6 9 and 12 past four we toggle 4 8 and 12 on past five.
We don't toggle the number 12 locker we just go 5 and 10 and then we've passed 12 already.
So we don't title it on past 6 we do 6 and 2 up on past 7 which is 7 and 14.
There's no toggle on that pass etc..
So hopefully now you're seeing a pattern emerging.
We're only toggling the locker when the past number is a factor of the locker number and we can begin
to make the generalization that all lockers started open after the first pass and alternate between
being open and closed.
So lockers are closed after a second fourth six and so on times there are a toggle.
In other words if a walker is toggled an even number of times then it ends close.
Otherwise it ends open and you know that a Locker's toggled once for every factor of the locker number
.
So you can say that a locker is open only if it has an odd number of factors.
So we've now been able to reduce the task to finding how many numbers between 1 and 100 have an odd
number of factors.
So we can think about this in the following manner if we have a number I is a factor and we want to
know what that means.
It means that I timed some other number let's say J is equal to.
And so because multiplication is competitive we can say I times J equals eight times I and that means
that J is a factor.
And as well.
So the number of factors is usually even because factors tend to come in pairs.
And if she can find numbers that have unpaired factors you will know which Locker's will be open.
So multiplication isn't a binary operation.
So you have two numbers will always be involved.
But what if they're the same number so i equal J.
In that case a single number would effectively form both halves of the pair and there would be an odd
number of factors.
And when this is the case.
Times equals N.
So then we can say that N must be a perfect square.
So go ahead and try a perfect square to check the solutions reasoning.
So for example for 16 the factors are 1 2 4 8 16.
And those operations would then be open on one close on two open for close on 8 open on 16.
So as you expected it ends open since 16 is a perfect square.
Four times four.
So based on this reasoning you can actually conclude that only Locker's of numbers that are perfect
squares end up open and the perfect squares between 1 and 100 including one and 100 are 1 4 9 16 25
36 49 etc..
So one square to square three squared four squared five squared continuously until you get to 10 squared
.
So that means 10 Locker's would remain open.
All right I know we went through that kind of fast but you have the solution book to read through if
you want to look at other solutions.
It's the same standard solution but other explanations for it.
You can just look up hallway Lochore 100 on Google and you'll see it.
This is actually a fairly common puzzle but that being said makes me read through the solution.
I know we went through it kind of fast here but really you should just take the time to draw it out
.
It makes you understand that you're just looking for the number of perfect squares between 1 and 100
All right.
That's it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture