Hello everyone and welcome to your first interview question for this section of the Course.
Your first answer to your question is just a common interview question and that question is just implement
a stack.
So you're going to have to try your best implements your own stack class objects.
So it should be able to do the following methods check if it's empty.
Push an item to the stack pop an item to the stack.
Take a peek at that top item and then return the size stack.
Keep in mind how a stack works while you work through your weight and your implementation.
Try not to look at the implementation lecture until you've given it a fair shot on your own.
All right.
There won't be a solution lecture associated with this because we already did an implementation of a
stack earlier.
Go ahead and check that previous lecture.
If you want the solution to this one.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture