Hello everyone and welcome to the implementation of binary search trees lecture.
This is going to be a two part lecture.
You can refer to the Jupiter note book for the code discussed in this lecture will be jumping to Jupiter
notebook from time to time to discuss larger chunks of code.
You can also refer to the Wikipedia article on BSD or a binary search trees for more information on
the subject.
In this two part lecture we're going to be going over an overview of binary search trees and also an
implementation of them in Python.
Let's go ahead and get started.
A binary search tree relies on the property that keys that are less than the parents are found in the
left subtree and keys that are greater than the parent are found in the right subtree.
We're going to call this property BSEE property.
The fact that keys that are less than that parent node are found in the left subtree and keys that are
greater than the parent node are found in the right subtree.
So in an interview setting.
When someone mentions BSD or BSD property.
Think of that specific property that keys that are less in the parent go left keys that are greater
than the parent node.
Go to the right subtree as we implement the map interface as described above.
That BSD property is going to be a guide to implementation so I'll see it crop up again and again.
So here we have an example of a tree and noticed that the BSD property here holds.
So every node and if you look to the left and right of the node you have that BSEE property all keys
in the left subtree are less than the key and the root of the keys in the right subtree are greater
than the key in the root.
Notice that this BSD property only refers to the direct parent not the entire tree.
So as again just to reiterate this really important property all of the keys in the left so tree are
less than the key and the root of the keys in the right subtree are greater than the key in the room
.
So now that you know what a binary search tree is we will look at how a binary search tree is constructed
The search tree in the figure here which is the last one I showed you represents the notes that exist
after we have inserted the following keys in the order shown 70 31 93.
Then the next level 94 14:23 and 73.
Since 70 was that first key inserted into the tree it becomes the root.
Next 31 says less than 70 becomes the left child of 70.
93 is greater than 70 so it becomes the right child of 70.
Now we have two levels of the tree filled seventy level and then that 31 93 level.
So the next key is going to be the left or right child of the 31 or 93 which is where 14 73 and 94 come
into play since 94 is greater than 70 and 93 it becomes the right child of 93.
Similarly 14 is less than 70 and 31.
So it becomes the left child the 31 23 is also less than 31 so it must be in the left subtree of 31
.
However it is greater than 14.
So becomes the right child of 14.
So keep that in mind and he can go back and reference the slides for that list ordering of the way the
keys were in put it into the sun into this binary search tree
in order to implement the binary search tree.
We will use the nodes and reference's approach similar to the one we used to implement the linked list
and the expression tree.
So go ahead and review that lecture on the notes and references implementation in case you need to review
it.
However because we must be able to create and work the binary search tree that is empty.
Our implementation implementations actually going to use two classes the first class we're going to
call binary search tree in a second class.
We will call tree node.
You can begin to reference the Jubran notebook if you need to.
But in this case the binary search tree class has a reference to the tree node that is the root of the
binary search tree.
In most cases the external method is defined in the outer class to simply check to see if the tree is
empty.
If there are nodes already in the tree the request is just passed on to a private method to find that
the binary search tree class takes as a parameter in the case where the trees empty or we want to delete
the key at the root of the tree.
We have to take a special action.
We'll discuss all of this in much more detail as we jump back and forth from the Jupiter note book but
the basics of the class we implement called binary search tree look like this.
We have this init method which takes in none such as none.
And that also starts off the sizes zero so it's totally empty has none as the root.
Then we return length as just a method to return size and also we use the special method underscore
underscore Eliane and also return size.
But that allows you to use the Eliane length builtin method in Python on your binary search tree.
I will said the special method called it sir which allows you to iterate through the binary search tree
and will call the root as well.
Let's go ahead and jump to the note book to check out the full tree node class and just go over some
of the code OK here we are at the binary search trees notebook.
You'll notice we have the class tree node with some basic methods there's quite a few of them.
So that's where we then have them in the presentation.
But it's the basics one basic ones that we discussed earlier such as has left child is left child is
root is leaves and these methods just do exactly what they say they check if it has left child.
They check it's has a root or if something is a root returns of hasn't any children etc. and the binary
search tree is just taking advantage of that tree node class as well which is why we split it up.
Go ahead and review the notes and references implementation of a tree in case you want to refer to the
Treanor class here and get a little more background understanding on it throughout the rest of this
two part lecture we're going to be focusing on some of these special methods such as putting items into
our binary search tree getting items and then what's a little tricky is deleting items from a binary
search tree and splicing them out.
And this fine successor method also removing items from a binary search tree is a little complicated
and there's a couple of cases we need to consider there.
So we'll be going over those in much more detail.
But just as far as the basics of what the tree node class looks like it just basically has left and
right child methods and is true and is really leaf methods which are essentially just checks or returns
of self-taught right child or self-taught left child.
So go ahead and review that in the note book.
But for right now let's go ahead and go back to the presentation and discuss some specific methods used
here.
OK.
Now that we have that binary search tree shell and that tree note class it's time to write the method
that will allow us to build our binary search tree.
The method is just a method of that binary search string class.
Again you can refer to Jubran notebook but will also have screenshots of some of the code methods here
.
This method will check to see if the tree already has a root.
If there's not a root in place then we just put the Mutare node and install it as a root of the tree
.
If a root node is already in place then put calls the private recursive helper function.
Put to search the tree according to the following algorithm.
So what it's going to do it's going to start at the root of the tree search the binary tree comparing
the new key to the key and the current node.
The new key is less than the current node will go to the left subtree.
It's an Yuuki is greater than the current node.
We search the right subtree and that's due to that BSEE property that we were talking about earlier
when there is no left or right child to search then we've actually found the position in the tree or
the new node should be installed to add a node to the tree.
We create a new tree node object and insert the object at the point discovered in the previous step
.
So this is the key.
Scuse me the code that does all that little step essentially to put methods one Jonathan underscore
and one with the underscore the one of out the underscore is just for code factoring or refactoring
reasons.
So it looks a little nicer and we use the underscore put as a helper function to do the heavy lifting
.
So again what's happening in this code is we start at the root of the tree.
We search the binary tree comparing that new key to the key and the current node if the new key is less
than the current node.
We search the left subtree if a new key is greater than the current node.
We search the right subtree when there is no left or right child to search.
We know we found the position in the tree we're then you know should be installed to add a new note
to the tree.
We just create a new tree node object which you can see that happening here and here depending where
it goes.
We also have the self-taught root equals tree node.
In case there's not a root already in place which is essentially what the put with no underscore does
by itself it checks if there is a root if there is a calls that helper function.
Otherwise it just adds the tree Trina there.
Note that this underscore function is written recursively following the steps I just mentioned.
Also notice that when a new child is inserted into the tree the current notice passed to the tree as
the parents.
One important problem with our implementation of insert is that duplicate keys are actually not handled
properly as are trees implement a duplicate key will create a new node with the same key value in the
right subtree of the node having the original key.
The result of this is that the notice that new key will never be found during a search.
So a better way to handle the insertion of a duplicate key is for the value associated with that new
key to replace the old value.
For right now we'll just ignore those duplicate subkey scenarios that you can go and explore and fix
that code.
If you want to to check for a duplicate key and then replace the old value with it and then here we
just show a screenshot of that set item method which allows us to use the key value and this is what
inserting a note of key 19 would look like in a tree.
So we go around check which ones are filled options aren't filled.
So here at 29 we can see that 19 is less than 29 so it would be inserted into the left subtree.
Once the tree is constructed the next task is to implement the retrieval of a value for a given key
.
The get method is even easier than the method because it simply searches the tree recursively until
it gets to a non-matching leafnode or finds a matching key when a matching key is found.
The value stored in the payload of the node is returned so the code for that gets and then also has
its own underscore get helper function.
The search code for the underscore get method.
The second one uses the same logic for choosing the left or right child as that underscore put that
help or put method use.
Notice that that underscore get method returns a tree node to the original first get method.
And this allows the underscore get to be used as that flexible helper method.
For other binary search tree methods that may need some make use of other data from the tree node besides
just the payload and by implementing this special method underscore underscore.
Item underscore underscore we can write a python statement that looks just like accessing a dictionary
.
So that basically allows us to use the bracket notation that you use in a dictionary when you call a
key from a dictionary.
So that's why this is here.
Using gets we can implement an operation by writing that underscore underscore contains underscore the
underscore method for the binary search tree.
Again this is a special method and the contains method will simply call get in return true if it gets
a return value or false if it returns None.
So we'll have a couple of special methods throughout the binary search tree.
You can go ahead and check them out if you want more details from the Python documentation.
But you can essentially just read the code and assume that they're allowing us to use builtin methods
or syntax with Python for our specially created binary search string class.
So finally we're going to turn our attention to the most challenging method in the binary search tree
and that's the deleting of a key and the removal of a key.
This was what we're going to be discussing in part two of this lecture.
But just to give you an idea of what we're going to do that first task for the leading a node is to
find the note to delete by searching the tree and then if the tree has more than one node we're have
to use the underscore get method to find the tree no that needs to be removed.
So in the next part of this two part lecture we're going to be talking about deleting nodes and removing
nodes.
OK go ahead and Ribby the Jupiter notebook and the slides so we've gone over so far.
So far we've gone over just get em put and also just building out our basic binary search tree and using
that tree node class representation.
OK thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the second part of the lecture where we're going to go into deleting nodes from a binary
search tree in a more detail.
As far as what you should have gotten out from this lecture.
Definitely that BSD property where keys to have a value less than the parent node go to the left and
keys that have a value greater than that parent node.
Go to the right.
That's really the key to remember binary search trees.
All right thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture.