Hi there.
This is day two.
And welcome back.
It's not time to implement our project and have some fun.
We've been promoting our Casterley that will implement a basic version of the.
The project will evolve as a course progresses but the framework and all the core features will be implemented
in this version.
So we would have been promoting a major part of the project and this version specifically here is what
we will do.
Vivek implement most of the features we have learned so far.
We will use proper object oriented design and coding conventions will implement the project using Eclipse
and will make use of all the commonly used features including the old ones like automatic source code
generation automatic refactoring and so on.
We will also use a popular and B.C.E. design pattern which we will discuss next and we will also use
another design pattern called Single and pattern.
Finally for some parts of the implementation we will use a popular software development process.
It and double up ment which is referred to as BTD in shock.
DDT is very widely used Technik desk is written before we start writing that legal logic.
So that would be interesting and we will discuss it and its benefits.
When we are implementing it so its going to be some real good stuff that we are going to implement.
And here is a project specification.
The system will involve five users and 15 bookmarks the 15 bookmarks would include five doublings five
books and five movies.
We would just build the necessary framework to load this data.
Next we will implement the real features.
I'm already familiar with all of them.
The first one would be the bookmarking process itself.
Each user can bookmark at most five items which can be any of the bookmark types.
So 5 is a max limit.
The marking decision itself will be done randomly.
So we'll be using randomisation function from the math class and for this version duplicate book Mazzariello
we will have to duplicate later.
Next week it is marking bookmarks as kid friendly with this feature an editor or chief editor can approve
or reject a bookmark as kid friendly or they may not even take any action to.
There is a bookmark will be left in an unknown state so only an editor or chief editor is authorized
to make approval or rejection decisions on it cannot be done by regular users.
We already know that.
Again for this first version this is done by a randomisation.
Later we can prompt the user to give his or her decision.
The final feature is sharing of good friendly bookmarks with partner websites.
So it's going to be only kid friendly bookmarks that you can share other regular bookmarks with partnership's
sites.
Again this can be done only by staff members such as editors and chief editors.
Moreover the constraint is that only books and ramblings can be shared so movies cannot be shared.
Also like other features for another shared decision is done by randomisation.
So basically for all three features that are shown here in green boxes a user decision is based on randomization
.
So that's the specification in the next lesson.
Let's look at the architecture that we are going to follow.
They'll be using the popular and Visio design pattern and so we will briefly discuss it and after that
we'll start our implementation