Hi there.
This is the Mandela room.
And welcome back.
So we now have a very solid understanding of the Java Sea platform.
Right.
And there were two objectives and designing this course and both the objectives have been met.
The first objective is to cover most of the concepts that fall under the Java Sea platform and to also
cover them at a very in depth level.
That's the reason this course has been named as Java in-depth.
And we also ensured that we discuss the motivation behind every single concept.
So it was not just about syntax, but to also understand the why part.
So that's the first objective to discuss the breadth as well as the depth.
And the second objective is to discuss the best practices and the design principles that one needs to
know in order to write well-designed Java code.
And we discussed a ton of rules, and I hope you have learned it well.
So those were the two objectives.
And now let's take it one step ahead and let's make it even more interesting and inspiring.
Let's learn about Java EE platform.
Strictly speaking, this particular section should not be included in this course.
The reason is this course is all about Java SE.
And to also discuss about the best practices in the Java language.
So Java E is about web development and so it doesn't fall under the scope of this course.
And I never had any intention of including the section, but now I'm including it for two reasons.
The first reason is to help you guys understand how Java is used in the real world, and web application
development is ubiquitous and Java is very widely used for web application.
So that's one use case.
So in order to do that, we are going to extend our project to Web, enable it.
You know that our project was missing the front end part as well as it was not hosted on a web server,
although we said that it is a web application.
So for the front end part, we had a Java file which was mimicking the front end.
So now we are going to Web enable it.
And so you're going to see how Java is actually used in the real world.
So we are going to do that.
And the second reason is to give you a sense of direction on your next steps.
So in this particular section, you will learn about the core Java EE technologies like Servlet and
JSP, and you will see how it can be used in order to build a web application.
Now, with that knowledge in place, you can explore more technologies once you are done with this course.
So you can learn about other technologies like HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
So those are the clients are technologies, or you can explore other technologies like spraying and
hibernate and so on and so forth.
So without this it can be a bit challenging because you do understand the code java, but you may be
a bit lost and you may not know where to start or what to do.
So this will kind of give you a sense of direction.
It acts as a bridge, so it's really nice that we are covering this.
So that's one thing.
And I also have to say that you need to treat this particular section as a bonus section.
So it needs to be treated as a pure add on section.
What that means is it's not going to be as comprehensive as other sections in this course.
Having said that, it still is pretty in-depth.
It has over 4 hours of really valuable content.
Probably we also get into certain details which are not even covered in other dedicated courses, courses
that are dedicated for this topic.
So it's going to be pretty in-depth, too, but just not as in-depth as other sections in this course.
And we are also going to practice follow some good conventions in writing our code.
So just because it is a bonus section, it doesn't mean that it's going to be at a very high level or
we are going to follow some naive practices.
That's not the case.
We are going to follow some good coding conventions.
For instance, we do stick to the and we see design pattern which our project was following.
Then we use something called us JST tags which are kind of advanced DSP tags.
And if you recall, we also had users in our project and the user passwords were being stored in clear
text, but now we will store it in encrypted format because that's how it is professionally, professionally
done and it's very important from a security standpoint.
So I want you to learn this good practices and take it ahead and use them in your career.
So that's the thing.
So it's going to be really interesting and it's going to be very useful for you and the course would
be very complete with this new edition.
So let's go ahead and see what we have on the agenda for this section.
Okay.
Here is the agenda.
We will first learn about the absolute basic concepts of the web.
Next, we will briefly discuss about the Java EE specification and what it includes.
We will also discuss about something called servlet containers and web servers.
Next we will install Tomcat, which is a servlet container and also a web server to.
And next people implement a mini web application called Books Aloha.
And it simply displays a list of books.
And it helps us to learn about sublets, GSP and GST.
And we will also implement the application using MVC pattern and the web application will be deployed
on Tomcat.
And this is a good book you can buy to get a more deeper understanding on Servlet and JSP.
It is an old book but still very much useful as it covers the fundamentals very well.
Finally, we will extend our bookmarking project with the same technologies that we have learned that
is Sublets and GSD.
We will also follow the MVC pattern and we will reuse a lot of the code that we have already written
in our project.
However, we will focus only on the books part and we will not worry about movies or the web links.
That's because once you do it with books, it's the same process for movies and web links too.
So we are going to save some time there.
Let's also look at a couple of screenshots of the end product.
This is the login page.
And once the user is logged in, this is one of the pages that the user sees.
It's called as the browse page, and it essentially displays a list of books and the user can bookmark
one or more of them by clicking on the save link that you can see besides each book.
There is also one other similar page and you will see it when we get to the project.
So it's going to be really interesting.
That's about it for now.
And I will see you in the next lecture and we will get started off.
Thank you.