Hi there.
This is the middle row.
And welcome back.
So far, all our class declarations have been top level classes, but Java also permits nested classes,
that is, classes defined within other classes, classes nested within other classes.
Typically, most courses do not give priority to this topic, and even if they cover, they just explain
the syntax and do not explain where they are commonly used in practice.
Nested classes definitely have a certain place on some of the collections framework classes use them
quite extensively.
As always, we will look at where they are typically used and nested classes.
One needed to improve the design of your classes.
So let's go ahead and look at this important feature and why they are needed.
You may recall this particular slide from our very first introductory chapter.
It shows a different members of a class, and nested classes are one of them.
In fact, we can have nested interfaces too, which can be part of both classes as well as interfaces.
Here is one example of an asset class.
The top level class is named as outer and it has a nested class within it, which is named as inner.
To understand the need for nested classes, let's consider a hash map.
We know that in hash map, each key value pair is called as a mapping.
And if you recall in the hash map implementation, a mapping is referred to as an entry.
An entry is actually a nested interface within the MAP interface.
As mentioned earlier, we can also have nested interfaces.
So in this class diagram we have a square within map to represent the nested type entry.
You may recall that entry interface has methods such as get key and get value.
Now we also have the hash map class.
And if we invoke the entry set method on a hash map instance, it would return a set of all the mappings
that is set off all entries and each entry is an implementation of entry interface.
Now the set is actually a nested class called entry set, which implements the set interface.
Now if we invoke the iterator method on the return set, then it returns an implementation of iterator.
And that implementation is another nested class within hash map and it is named as entry iterator.
So we have entry set and entry iterator.
So entry iterator implements the iterator interface.
Morphine work the next method on the entry iterator, it would return an entry instance, which is the
next mapping in the hash map.
And this entry instance is represented by the class called Node, which is yet another nested class
within hash map.
So this node nested class implements the entry nested interface within the map interface.
So it has methods like get key, get values, set key, set value and so on.
So there are three nested classes within hash map and as of today, it also has five other nested classes.
So the next question is, why cannot we have all these nested classes as separate top level classes
within the same package as hash map?
If we do that, we will have eight additional classes in that package and all eight are used only by
hash map.
That is, no other classes are going to use them.
So it would lead to class pollution.
Also having these classes defined as part of a map tells us clearly that these classes have something
to do with only hash map.
So the functionality is kept closer to the original class.
It would also lead to better design.
We can see that within the hash map class.
These nested classes are modular using the functionality that is without the nested classes, the methods
contained in them would be part of the end cross class and that could lead to method pollution.
So nested classes provide cleaner design.
All in all, an asset class basically serves its end closing class and at the same time leads to better
design to.
We will also see in this chapter some interesting ways in which they are used in the real world.
Here are the different types of mustard classes.
They are classified into two categories.
One is inner classes and the other is referred to as static member classes.
In the classes include non static member classes, anonymous classes and local classes.
We are going to discuss all of these and how they are typically used in the real world.
Local classes are very rarely used, so we will discuss them very briefly.
One main distinction between inert classes and static member classes is that static member classes,
as the name implies, can never access the instance.
Members of the enclosing class.
In Narcosis, on the other hand, can access the instance members of the enclosing class.
Only exception is when anonymous classes and local classes are part of static context, like a static
method, in which case they cannot access instance members.
Non static member classes can always access instance members of the enclosing class.
In the follow up lessons, we'll be looking at the different nested classes.
However, there are certain properties common to all the nested classes.
And let's look at them now.
This one is about access levels.
Nested classes can be declared with all the four access levels, private, default, protected and public,
just like any class member.
Recall that top level classes can only be either public or default.
Next property is that there is mutual accessibility of members, including private members.
So a nested class can access any member of outer class.
And similarly, an outer class can also access any member of the nested class.
Outer can access any member of nested.
Because if nested class was not there, then all that functionality would have been part of the outer
class.
Finally note that when we have a class nested within another class, then the Java compiler will produce
two class files one for our class, and the other would be for nested class.
Outer would be just outer class, while nested would be generated with the name outer nested class.
Where outer are nested here are just class names of outer class and nested class.
However, in case of anonymous classes, outer would still be outer class, while an anonymous class
would be outer dollar one class.
If there are multiple anonymous classes, then there would be outer one class, outer two class and
so on.
But for the other three nested classes, it would be outer class name or nested class name.
It is just that, as we will see later, anonymous classes do not have names and so numeric values are
used.
So that's about it.
And we will be discussing all the foreign asset classes and most importantly, where they are most commonly
used.
We will also discuss a couple of important effective Java items.
Let me also quickly pull up a hash map class so that we can look at some of the nested classes that
were highlighted earlier.
Okay.
Here we are in the hash map class and within the hash map class, if we invoke the entry set, it would
call this.
Here it is.
Here is the entry set method and it is creating an instance of this entry set which is simply a nested
class with ten hash map.
An entry set here has all these methods, and if you invoke the iterator method on the set, then it
would create an instance of entry iterator and entry iterator is also another nested class within hash
map.
So it says hash map and tree iterator.
And within the entry iterator method we have these methods and if we invoke the next method, it is
invoking something called next node, which actually returns the node.
Are not is actually a static member class and hence this it has the keyword static and it is an asset
class once again within hash map.
So the other classes did not have the static keyword.
So they are non static member classes and static member classes have this keyword static and we will
look at all of that later.
So just wanted to show that.
So that's about nested classes and let's get started with the chapter and learn all about nested classes.
Thank you.