Hi there.
This is Gerry.
And welcome back.
We know that Java is an object oriented programming language.
And if you recollect from the previous section, we also said that an object oriented programming language
helps model real world scenarios in a more natural way.
And it does so with the help of objects and classes and object oriented programming, as its name suggests,
is all about objects.
And an object is created from a class.
And in the last section we looked at the Hello World class.
Both classes and objects are the most fundamental units in an object oriented programming language.
In this lecture, we will first understand class and objects at a conceptual level.
That is how they represent real world scenarios.
And then we will see how they are represented in a Java program.
Object oriented programming, which in short is often referred to as OUP or P, traces its roots back
to 1960s.
So it's a very old programming paradigm.
And it was conceived to implement large, complex projects in a simple way.
And by that we mean the help model real world scenarios in a more natural way.
So that's the main benefit of object oriented programming.
Let's take a look at a few real world examples.
One example is a student registering in a particular course which is offered by a particular department.
Another example would be a customer buying a product.
Similarly, we can have a doctor treating a patient and all these examples can be more naturally modeled
or represented in an object oriented environment.
So let's see how that is possible and let's pick the first example here.
So here we have three entities, student cores and department here.
A student would have some data associated with him or her and can also have some behavior.
Associated data would be things like student name, student age, gender address and so on, and behavior
would be actions like registering for a course or updating one's profile information.
Similarly, course on department would also be associated with some data and some behavior.
And here is an instance where we have a student named John and we have four courses and two departments,
computer science and civil.
So here we have some instances with data being just the name like John or Java or computer science.
And we can have these four courses offered by the US Department.
And John can register in these three courses.
So that's some behavior or actions happening between these instances.
So this is a realistic scenario where the student, John, has registered in three courses which are
offered by the CS Department.
So an instance like John can be visualized in this way where data apart from name would also include
other things like student ID, gender and courses that John has registered in.
Similarly, John can also perform the two actions registering for a course and updating his profile
information.
In an object oriented environment.
This data that Jones instance can have is generally referred to as state of the instance.
While these actions as just behavior and this whole instance of John is referred to as an object.
So the student John is represented by this object.
And similarly, we can have other students represented by other objects which are unique to those students.
So an object has both state and behavior, and these objects cannot exist by themselves.
There should be some sort of a specification that tells the data that objects can have, like ID name,
gender and so on, and also behavior like course registration and update profile.
That specification is the class.
So class is like a blueprint and objects are actual instances of the class.
In fact, often the term instance is also used to refer to object.
Here is an illustration of relation between a class and its objects.
At the top we have the student class defining the state and behavior that its objects can have.
State includes student information such as ID, name and gender, and there is only one behavior defined
which allows the student objects to update their profile information.
Now, for the sake of simplicity, course related stuff like the courses registered by a student has
been omitted from this illustration.
And we can also see the three student objects in ellipticals.
And these are created from the student class.
Each student object has its own state.
For example, for students name is John, who is a male and has a student ID of 1000.
Similarly, second student's name is Raj, who is also a male and has an ID of 1001.
Third student's name is Anitha, who is a female and has an ID of 1002.
And the behavior update profile would be associated with all three objects.
That is, it is common to all three of them.
Now in the student class.
Update profile would be a method.
So methods define the behavior.
And in the last section we have seen the main method in the hello world class.
An object state is defined by variables.
Variables and methods in a class are considered as members of the class, and later in the section we
will learn about both variables as well as methods.
Now, apart from variables and methods, a class can also have other less commonly used members, such
as nested classes and nested interfaces, which will be discussed much later in the second half of the
course.
So when someone refers to class members, they are normally referring to either variables or methods.
So that's about it.
Conceptually, that's all there is to class and it's objects.
Now let's look at how they are represented in code and we are going to use the same student class example.
But for now, let's not worry about writing the code.
Our goal for now is to just get a feel for how to create an object from a class in Java and that we
will see in the next slide.
So here is the definition of student class.
It is first declaring the variables which would represent the state that student objects can have.
So we have ID name and gender.
And variables are like containers as they hold some data.
And each variable is also associated with something called a data type, which tells what type of data
the variable can hold.
For instance, ID is declared as an end and int means integer, which means that id can hold integers
like 1000, 1001, and so on.
Similarly, name and gender are declared with the data type.
String and string implies that the variables can hold textual data like Anita for name and female for
gender.
In data pipe will be discussed later in the section, while string will be discussed in one of the subsequent
sections.
Next.
The student class also defines the method of grade profile, which simply updates the existing name
with a new name, and the new name is passed as input to the method.
A method parameter represents the input.
In this case, it has the name, new name and as of type string.
Method parameter is also a variable, just like ID or name.
And in the body of the method, the variable name is assigned with the value of the method parameter.
New name equal to is assignment operator and it just assigns the value on the right to the variable
on the left.
Methods will also be discussed later in the section.
So that's the student class.
Next, let's see how we can create a student object and then initialize it state.
And we will also see how the student's only method update profile can be executed.
And for that we will use a new class called Student Test.
And let's assume that the code is written in this main method of the class.
So first step is to create a student object and this is how it is done.
You would use the keyword new, which would be followed by the keyword student as we want to create
an object of the student, which is in turn followed by parentheses.
So new, followed by student, followed by parentheses, would create a student object which is then
assigned to a variable called S whose data type is student, which indicates that S would hold a student
object.
So it is similar to the way we declared the variable ID in the student class with ID, the data type
was end, indicating that it would store an integer value.
So we created a student object named as next.
We need to initialize its state.
That is, we need to set the values for the variables ID, name and gender that the student class has
declared.
And for that we use the dot operator.
That is, we would have the object name as followed by dot, followed by variable name, which here
is ID and then we assign it with a value which is 1000 in this case.
To set name we have as followed by DOT, followed by the variable name and it is assigned with a value.
Joanne Similarly, gender is assigned with male.
Here we have double quotes and closing Joanne and mail, but not for the ID value thousand.
And that's because Joanne and mail are strings.
And in Java for strings we need to use and double codes.
So the student object as now has a state.
However, here, let's assume that the name was misspelled as Joanne instead of John.
And so we need to fix it.
And for that we need to execute the update profile method and pass it the correct name John as input.
And the method would then update the name variable with the new name John.
So to execute update profile method, we once again use the dot operator that is object name as is followed
by Dart, which is followed by update profile and we are passing John as input to the method.
Here we say that we are invoking or calling the object profile method on the object as.
So that's how we create an object, initialize it with State and invoke its methods.
Actually to initialize object state.
It is normally done using something called constructors, but they will be discussed later in the section.
So doing it the way we see here is not done in professional projects, but this is just for us to get
started for initializing the state.
Also note that in a real object oriented software you will have tons of objects communicating with each
other.
And the way one object communicates with other is by invoking a method of the object and passing any
necessary data as input.
So that's about it.
I hope you now understand what a Class An object is, how they represent real world entities like student,
and how they can be created in Java.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.