Hello there.
This is the room.
Let's not get started with non static member classes.
A non static member class is used when the inner class object needs access to the enclosing object so
that it can access instance members.
So it has something to do with the instance of enclosing class.
And the inert class object cannot even be created unless the enclosing object is already created.
So enclosing object is created first, and then it is used to create the inner class object.
And soon we will see how that is done in our demo.
In the class object is simply an instance member of the enclosed object, just like any instance member
and hence we refer to the inner class as non static member class.
That is, it is an instance member class.
Since intercourse object needs access to enclosing object, the inner class object would maintain a
hidden reference to and closing object.
And building such a hidden reference takes up space and time.
Note that due to the hidden reference author class object will not be garbage collected until a class
object is alive.
One common use of such non static member class is to define an adapter.
Adapters are used to produce different views of the class object.
One example is the collection view methods in the map interface such as key set values and entry set.
The key set method we know returns a set object that contains all the keys in the map.
And the set object is basically an instance of a non static member class which implements a set interface.
So the set object is basically using the state of the enclosed object that is state would be the keys.
Due to this, it requires a hidden reference to the enclosing object.
Another example is the iterator methods that we encounter in collection interfaces such as set and list.
The iterator method returns an iterator object, which basically is an instance of a non static member
class that implements the iterator interface.
Let's now go ahead and actually implement a simple adapter.
Okay.
Here we are in my Eclipse editor.
And a new package called Semantic Squared dot nested classes has been created and there are two classes
here, cache and bookmark.
So basically we are implementing a cache and we are going to demonstrate adapter.
So it will give a different view of the cash.
So cash is basically going to hold the bookmark objects.
And here is a bookmark class and all it has is ID and title and the getters and setters that go with
these two variables gets, get, etc. get title, set, title.
And here is the cash class and cash class.
It's just a regular cash.
If you don't if you do not want to hit the database for faster access, we can store it in the cash.
We know that.
So Cash has this constructor and it's going to store bookmarks and the bookmarks will be stored in this
array called items.
And the size of this items are a bookmark array will be provided as an input to the cache constructor
here.
OC input is size.
Now there is this method called ADD, which will be invoked with a bookmark and that bookmark will be
added to the array to the bookmark array.
And there is also this variable called Next, which will keep track of the next item that is being added.
Initially it is zero and here we are simply checking if it is less than the size of the array.
If it is less only then we are going to insert the bookmark item and we will also increment its count.
We are saying next plus plus, which means that it will first get added and then the counter will be
incremented.
That's it.
Only there are two methods.
So we are going to implement adaptor.
So just like list unset has iterator.
We also want to implement an iterator which would be an asset class.
So for that, just like the iterator interface, we are also defining this interface called cache.
Iterator has next returns a boolean value.
It just tells whether there is another item to iterate and if so, only then we can invoke the next
method.
So we are supposed to implement it and we have this main method here.
We will look at that later because we are going to populate the data.
But first, let's go ahead and implement our our nested class, non static member class.
Let's say private and it's a class and let's call it as my cache iterator.
And it implements.
Cash iterator interface.
Okay.
So let's just go ahead and add the unimplemented methods next and Haas next.
So this let's just say let's actually put a variable here.
So it's a private variable.
So if there are more items to iterate, then it would return a true.
Otherwise it would return false.
And the high value index value.
So this is an index into the array and it will be incremented here.
So let's just say items.
I plus plus.
So it's going to return the bookmark and it's going to increment the index.
Okay.
So once all of the items are in are activated, when we invoke the next method, it will return a false
and we cannot invoke the next method after that.
So let's go into our so that's the my cache iterator.
So it's a nested class, it's a non static member class.
So let's go here.
And let's go ahead and this is the code.
So we are instantiating cache and we are just calling it as recommended items and the size is five and
we are creating these instances five instances item one and we are setting the ID and title.
Okay.
So let's not worry about what those titles are.
So same here.
Five bookmarks are being created and finally we are adding them right now.
Next thing to do would be to iterate through them.
So for that, one other thing is we need to create an instance of this mic cache iterator so that we
can invoke, you know, we can iterate the elements.
You know, just like the set and list has iterated methods.
So let's go ahead and create a iterator method here.
So that's the iterator method and we can invoke the iterator method on the recommended items and that
is actually creating.
Creating the instance of the inner class object.
So we first need to have this outer class object, as we described earlier in the lecture.
So using that, we will invoke this iterator method, just like the way we do an array list and other
classes.
And that would actually create a return.
An instance of this my cache iterator.
The reference type will not be this, it will be cache iterator because this is private.
So let's go ahead.
And so we have already added the items.
So what we need to do here is.
Let's have the reference type as cash iterator.
So that's the outer class object and we are invoking.
Iterator.
So we will get the, the an instance of the inner cross object.
So it has next if it returns true.
Then we will say.
Just print the title.
So this is how it is.
Let's just go ahead and execute it.
And you can see it prints all the titles.
So that is how you are going to create an instance.
We are invoking the iterator method and the iterator is actually returning an instance of the inner
class and that inner class actually represents the state.
It's a different view of the state of.
This particular instance, cash.
So that's an adapter.
Now, there is also a second way to invoke it.
Now, one thing to note is here we are using an interface now instead of interface.
Had this been a public class and let's like my question iterator is public and cash iterator interface
is also is just not there.
So in that scenario we can directly access we we would have the reference type here as cache dot my
cache iterator.
But this is a better design because we are writing to an interface.
So tomorrow if we want, we can also change the implementation.
We can use a different name here so we are not bounded to the name here.
So this is a better design, but there is also a different way to create an instance here.
So we can just say.
Here.
And this is a kind of weird way of instantiating and it is very rarely used and it is also discussed.
And an item in Joshua in Joshua Block's book, it's item 22.
And here instead of just new, we are saying dot new and.
This is how it is done.
But here the assumption is that we know what the instance is, what the inner classes.
So we are directly using the class name here, which means that the assumption is there is no there
is no interface here, in which case it would be my cash, my cash iterator.
So this is an another way of implementing it where we actually know the name of the inner class.
But this is very rarely used.
Normally you would define some kind of a method like this and we will call the method on that method
word return an instance of the inner class.
So that's the normal way to do it.
And this is non static member classes and it's a simple adapter.
As it is giving a different view of the state of the art across object and in map.
We have things like key set, key value of values and so on.
Now let me show pull up my here.
This is my local directory file on the disk.
And here you can see that there is this.
It shows the class files.
So here we are.
And the Eclipse Guide is actually the work place.
And within that we have been and within column semantics, we are nested classes.
We have all these class files and we can say we can see that there is this cache and there is bookmark
and there is cache iterator interface.
But for the nested class, a new class is created cache dollar.
My cache iterator as I mentioned earlier.
So for the nested class, it is actually implemented as this separate top level class.
Now if we go back internally the way it would have been implemented as.
So my cash iterator becomes there is no nested class.
It will be written as cash dollar my cash iterator and it will be a separate class on the hard disk.
So here this would be replaced with return new something like this.
Internally, this is how it would be cash dollar.
Something like this.
And this.
My cash iterator would have a constructor and that constructor would take this.
So we are passing cash here.
So it would.
So we are passing the instance of the hourglass.
So that way my cash iterator, you know, it can invoke items, it can invoke items, not it would be
so my cash iterator is here, my cash iterator would have a constructor in the byte code and that will
take cash as the parameter so that it can access this instance variables like items.
So, so that's the, that's how it works under the hood.
So it would pass a reference.
Only thing is building that reference here in this way we would take some space and time and that's
one of the limitations.
And later we will look at static number classes which do not have that limitation.
So it's better to use that when needed.
It has its own place, but this also has its own place.
So this is mainly used for adapters.
So just wanted to just show about, talk about that, also about how it is implemented internally.
So it would be a separate class and it would have its own constructor and we would pass this reference,
reference of this.
So there will not be any master class.
Master class will just be, we'll just be we'll just be a separate class.
And it would use the the object of the outer class to invoke the to access the outer class objects members.
So that's about it.
Let's head back to the slides now and this code is also available in the resources section.
Now here is a restriction.
A non static member class cannot have static members.
You can try it out and you will see that it would give us a compiler error.
The reason for this is static.
Members should be accessible without an object.
Right.
But we know that to create a class object, we first need to create a class object.
That is, once we say that we are creating an outer class object, then we are talking about instance
stuff.
So it is not legal to have static members within a non static member class.
Another way to look at it is a non static in our class is like an instance variable.
That is it has something to do with the state of the other object.
So if there are two outer objects, then they will also have two different inner class objects representing
different states with static stuff.
We know we are independent of objects, so non static member classes are basically instance related
stuff.
Coming to access from the enclosed class, we can access the inner cross method using the inner object
reference.
Now let's see how a nerd class can access orders members.
Here go method is accessed.
If God does not exist in the inner class, then it will invoke the go method in the outer class.
In this example, we have this dot go.
This would always refer to the go method in the inner class.
Now, if go method is present only in the outer class, and if we still use this go, then we get a
compiler error.
So this reference when used inside inner class implies that we want to access something in the inner
class itself.
And if we want to explicitly access go method in the outer class, then we can say outer dot this dot
go where?
Outer is the outer class name.
Outer crosses class name.
You would want to do this if both inner and outer classes have the go method.
If only outer has the Go method, we can directly access it as shown in the first example.
I would just go ahead and try this out by placing a go method in both outer and inner classes in our
demo program.
So that's about it.
A non static member class is simply an instance member of the outer class and it is useful for implementing
adapters.
That's how it is commonly used.
Thank you.