Hi there.
This is the.
And now let's go ahead and install my SQL database.
Now, my SQL is an open source relational database management system, and it comes in different flavors.
One of them is the community server edition, which is a free edition, and that's what we are going
to install.
And there is also the enterprise edition for which we need to pay.
So it comes with some additional features and also support.
So my SQL is owned by Oracle and previously it was owned by Sun Microsystems.
And we know that Sun Microsystems has been acquired by Oracle in 2010.
So we will be installing my SQL Community Server edition, and it can also be used in production systems
too.
So it's really powerful and very good and it is one of the best databases that we have, IBM's.
So let's just search for my community server download.
This is what we have.
So this is the link on my ask.com slash downloads, slash my SQL.
So you can click on that.
So over here you can download you can select your operating system on.
Since mine is Windows, I'm going to do that.
In fact, I have already done that.
So here you have 5.7 edition and we will click on this Microsoft MySQL installer and you can also select
one of these options in case you are using a 32 bit machine, you can do that, otherwise you can select
the 64 bit version.
But this is what we are going to select.
My SQL installer, you're going to download that and you would install my SQL using that.
And there are also other ways to install it here, but we will use this.
And there are also older versions like 5.6 and 5.5 -5.5.
So the latest version is 5.7.
So you can also install the older versions if you want.
You can search in the archives and you can do that.
So let me just click this.
So if you when you install the minus scale, you also can install all of these different products.
And my SQL Server is what you will be installing.
And the server it comes with, it's my SQL Server instance, but it will also come with a client utility
which you can use to connect to the server and the server.
You can have it started as a service, which means that when the system starts up, it will the server
will also start and you can click on the and you can use the client utility in order to connect to the
server.
So apart from the server, you would also install my SQL workbench.
This is not super important, but in one of the lectures I'm going to show how we can create relational
data models.
That is the database design.
So I'm going to use that.
So you can also install that.
You can install it separately too, by clicking here or within this installation itself, there is an
option where you can install that.
Okay.
Now let me I'll just explain that in a bit.
So you have these two installers that you can install.
One is the light version.
So for the light version, you would need Internet connection because it's going to download products
all the other things that it needs to install by connecting through Internet.
I think this one actually you would download the entire package and you can install it so you wouldn't
need internet connection.
And in case if you run into any issues, just Google four with the issue and you should be able to figure
it out.
So let's just click this one here.
And it is asking for you to log in or sign up.
So for those options, you need an account with Oracle, but you can just click on this.
No, thanks.
Just just start the download.
So once your download, just double click on it.
And once you double click on that, it will ask you to agree there would be a license agreement page.
So you can agree that for that and after that it will show you a bunch of options asking you which products
you want to you want to install.
So just choose a server only option.
That way you would be installing only the server, which also comes with the command line client utility
or there is an option called custom.
Now if you select that, it will give you the option of selecting more than one one product so you can
select server and also my SQL workbench right there.
Or you can just select the server only option and then come back and download the workbench later.
So on my machine I have already installed, so I'm not going to show that to you, but it's pretty straightforward
process and mine is an older version and my, my SQL workbench, I installed it recently and it's the
latest version.
So the latest version of Workbench is working with an older version on my machine.
Now, the entire installation process is very straightforward.
Just keep accepting all the defaults.
One of them is it will ask for the port number and there is some default port number that it assigns
for the My SQL Server instance.
It will be running on that port and you would.
There will also be a page where it will ask you to choose a service name as the Windows Service name
in this case, since it's a Windows machine.
So that server instance would run as a service and the server service name is also there is some default
name, so you don't have to change that.
An only thing that you will change as and one of the pages it will ask for a root password for the root
user.
So root user, it comes from the Unix world and it essentially means that the user has full admin privileges.
So there you can enter a password and you have to remember that password so that we can use it in the
future.
But I would suggest just keep it something simple because this is a development environment.
I would suggest just keep it as route.
So just do that.
And if you run into any issues, just go for it and you should be good to fix it.
In case you are using a very old operating system and if you're running into any issues, then you can
install probably an earlier version of my SQL.
So there is the archive and you can go ahead and use that.
Now let's just click on the workbench here.
Now with the workbench, the workbench would need two other software here because the workbench is the
graphical user interface for using my SQL instead of the minus client utility, you would use that.
I have not used it in my professional life.
Only recently I have used it.
Client utility is also very good, but within the using the Microsoft workbench it is you have the GWI
so you can create your databases and view and the entire database using a graphical user interface.
And you can also do that database design as we will see later.
But since it's a guy you would need these two software here, two pieces of software now here you can
go ahead and install it.
So far, the MySQL database, it was 5.7, but this has a different versioning.
But don't click here.
I would say you have to actually click here, but if you click here, it will take you to that old to
the other page that we have seen earlier where we have the MySQL installer.
So click here download and in this case it will not even ask for any root password or anything like
that.
Everything is pretty straightforward, so that's what it is.
And once you download it and install, so if you click on going to start and click on all programs.
So here you will see my SQL and if you click on my SQL here.
So this would be the workbench.
We can click on that later.
And this is the my SQL 5.5 -5.5.
So you must be seeing something like 5.7.
And this is the command line utility.
And as I said earlier, you need a root password.
So you would just say root.
And that said.
So it would install that.
Now, another way of installing it is from the command prompt itself.
So let's search for C and D.
Okay.
Now here you can say my SQL hyphen, you root.
It is for the root user, it's root itself and P is root.
So just do that and that's how you would connect.
So this executable is in the path now when you install it, it should also insert the path to this executable
directly.
If not, you can add it manually.
So let me open my explorer.
So click on See Drive.
Program files.
My school.
Here it is.
You have 5.5 the server instance on the workbench.
So you would do this bin and here is my skill.
So let me just exit here.
Let's see if we can find it here.
But it will be here.
The path to the bin folder will be here.
Here it is.
My SQL Server point five slash bin.
So it should get automatically added.
If not, you can do that.
You can add it manually and that's about it.
So if you run into any issues, just Google for it and it should help you out.
So when you are trying to install the workbench, it might you might have to install the other two software
also or they may have already been installed.
So just try to install it and run it.
And if on while you are installing Workbench, if it asks you for those other software dot net framework
and another Visual Studio software, then you can go ahead and download them.
Also, it should be straightforward.
So that's about it.
And next, we'll get started with the database design.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.