Hi there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
In this lecture, we will discuss the absolute basic concepts of the web, and we will also do a short
demo at the end of this lecture.
On the worldwide web, we have a client server model where the client can be something like a browser
which is being used by some user, and the server is a computer that serves some content and the user
needs some information from the server.
So the client would request for some resource via URL, which stands for Uniform Resource Locator,
which means that it helps in locating the resource.
So the server finds the resource and sends it back to the client as a response.
And the resource is typically a web page which is rendered in the browser.
And this entire client server communication on the web takes place via the HTTP protocol where HTTP
stands for hypertext transfer protocol.
As the name implies, it's a protocol that transfers hypertext.
And by hypertext we mean HTML content where HTML stands for Hypertext Markup Language, which is the
language that web pages are implemented in.
Although other content can also be transferred on the web.
HTML pages are the ones that typically get transferred.
So http protocol transfers.
HTML pages.
An extra deep protocol runs on top of the TCP IP protocol.
If you do not know what TCP IP is, then you can Google for TCP IP and learn more about it.
And finally, let's be thankful to this gentleman, Sir Tim Berners-Lee, who invented the World Wide
Web, which is one of the greatest discoveries of our times.
It is one of the reasons why you and I are connected today.
We are this online course.
Let's now look at the key elements that make up a hedge tip request which a client sends to the server.
First one is the HTTP method, which specifies the type of operation the client is requesting.
For instance, a client might request some information from the server or might be submitting some information
via a form, or might be updating some information, or might be deleting something by clicking on a
delete button.
Such actions are identified by a HTTP method.
Here we have a list of HTTP methods like get post put and so on.
Get and post are the most commonly used ones.
Get, as the name implies, suggests that client wants to get some information from the server that
is he or she wants to retrieve some information.
For instance, in an E commerce website, you might be viewing a list of products, and when you click
on a particular product, you would see information on that product in a new web page.
So as soon as you click on the product, a HTTP request with get as the HTTP method is generated and
some unique information about the product is passed to the server so that the server can respond back
with the entire product information.
Similarly, post implies that the client is posting some information to the server which results in
creation of a new resource on the server.
For example, when you sign up on a website, you would fill out a form with your details like name,
date of birth, email and so on.
And when you hit the submit button, a HTTP request with post as the history type method would be generated
along with all of the form details which you have entered and on the server, a new user account would
be created for you and the resource would be something like a database row in a table.
Right.
So that's the new user account.
So the resource is the new user account.
Another key element is the URL itself.
That is the location from where we want to fetch some information or in case of post, submit some information.
Then we have the form parameters, which is nothing but the data that we submit through a form.
And in case of that, it could be something like a movie title whose details we want to fetch.
That is, the user would enter the movie title in a search box and the server would return all the movies
matching the title.
So when the user hits the search button, we say that a get request is generated on the title that the
user entered would be appended to the URL.
As we see here over here, title equal to Lincoln would be the form parameter where the movie name is
Lincoln.
So in get form parameters are appended to the URL itself with question mark symbol serving as the delimiter
between the URL and the form parameters.
And in case of post, such form parameters are not appended to the URL, but they are sent separately
as part of the HTTP request, and that separate entity is referred to as a message, body or payload.
It's also called a payload.
And as we can see in this example, form parameters represent some user registration details.
Next request will also include something called request headers, which includes some additional information.
And one of them is the user agent, which gives information about what browser the client is using along
with information such as the operating system.
And this could be used by the server to give customized response.
For example, if the request comes from a PC, then the server might send back a particular web page.
But if the request happens to be coming from a smartphone, then the server would return a lighter version
of the same web page.
That is, some of the information which is not that important would not be included in the web page.
And there's also a header called Accept, which tells what kind of content the browser can accept.
So these are just a few of the headers and there are a few more too.
So these are the key elements that form a HTTP request.
On similar to tip request.
Let's also look at the key elements that make up a HTTP response, the response that is coming from
the server to the client.
First one is the HTTP status code, which indicates whether the corresponding HTTP request has been
successfully completed or not.
For instance, a status code of 200 indicates that the request has succeeded.
Similarly, a status code of 404 implies that the server could not find the requested resource.
And these are just a few important status codes.
And there are also a few more.
Response would also include something called ASC content type, which tells the type of content the
response contains.
An example is text slash HTML, which indicates that the response is in HTML format and looking at it,
the browser knows that it needs to process the HTML and render it in the UI.
Similarly application slash PDFs suggest that the response is PDF document.
So looking at it, the browser would launch a PDF viewing software.
Our next, we have the actual response content itself, like the web page content.
And there will also be some headers included in the response, just like in the case of a HTTP request.
And one of them is the information about the server.
In this example, it is Apache Tomcat, which is the server.
Another header is the content type, which we just discussed.
Now finally, let's quickly look at the anatomy of a URL in this example URL.
W w w dot IWO is the server name, and this name maps to a unique IP address of the server which looks
similar to the one shown in parentheses.
In fact, in the URL you can also replace the server name with the IP address and it will still work.
On this part here is called as the part which also assists the server in locating the resource.
And profile HTML would be the actual resource itself.
Now this particular website would be running on something called a TCP port, which is a 16 bit number
that identifies a specific program on the server like this particular website.
And you can have different services running on the same server, but on different ports.
So here this website is a service and so you can have similar kind of services running on different
ports.
And since a TCP port is a 16 bit number, we can have as many as 65,000 536 ports.
That is true to the port of 16 and hence the same number of services running on the server.
And out of this 65,005, 36 ports, ports 0 to 1023 are reserved for well-known services.
For instance, 21 is for FTP.
23 is for Telnet, and 80 is for HTTP.
And four for three is for HTTPS, which is a secure version of HTTP.
So our website here or most websites run on port 80.
Websites can also run on other ports, but 80 is the default one for http.
For instance, a common alternative to a tea is 8080.
Since it's not the default port, this port number would have to be explicitly specified in the URL.
As we can see here, the server name is followed by a colon, which is in turn followed by 88.
Essentially such a port number that is other than 80 should fall outside the range of 0 to 1 023 as
that range is for well-known services.
So that's about it.
Now let me just give a short demo where we can see a real get and post request in a browser.
Here we are in the three tier system, Ivo, and we are inside my account.
So I have logged into the system to refresh your memory.
So trivial is a bookmarking app is a social bookmarking app which is being developed in my company and
it allows us to bookmark articles on the web or books that are within this system, within the three
tier system or the movie titles which, which are in the mobile system.
Now I have clicked on the movies link and it is showing all of the movies that I have watched.
So these are all the ones that I bookmark as being watched.
And there are also some to do list here.
So the browser that I'm using is Firefox and I'm going to demonstrate both the get requests and also
the post requests.
Every browser also comes with something called as developer tools and for Firefox we have to use the
shortcut key F tool.
So let me hit F.
Well, here it is.
So these are the developer tools and it has different tabs here.
One of them is network.
So just make sure that you are under this network tab and it allows us to look at the network traffic
that is being generated as we click on different links or when we submit some search forms.
And there are also other things like the debugger, for instance, can be used for debugging.
So it's a very useful tool.
So let's just focus on the network now.
So let me go ahead and click on this link.
If we click on this link, it shows all the movies which are in my to do list, so which I want to watch.
And if you look at here, here in this area, it shows that show to do is equal to two.
So that's the form parameter.
So a form parameter need not be is not constrained to just when we submit the forms, it can also be
in this way it can be hardcoded.
So let me just go ahead and click it.
And we can see a bunch of requests being generated because there are a lot of images and each of those
images will also send separate requests to the server.
So this is the main one.
It says the method is get and this is the URL.
So let me just click on this one.
So when I click that.
Here it is.
So here we have both the get the request as well as the response data.
For instance, here, this is the request URL.
So you can see the full URL here.
And as you can see, the HTTP is the protocol that is being used.
So that's what we see here.
And this is the server name and this is the the location where we are submitting the request to the
location.
And this is the form parameter here.
We are saying that show to do is equal to true.
So that is what enables the server to send this data.
That is, we want to see only the data that is in the to do list.
Now the request method, the HTTP method is get and this server name is mapped to this IP address and
there is also this port number 80, which is the default port number for HTTP.
So that's what it is.
And in the response, we also have the status code and it says that it is 200, which means that the
request has been processed successfully and the version of HTTP is 1.1.
So that's some of the request and response data.
And here there is the.
Bottom.
We have the headers also we said that both requests as well as response have some headers.
So these are some headers.
For instance, these this are the request headers and one of them is accept, which we discussed.
So it says text slash XHTML, application slash XHTML and so on.
We already discussed it.
They just suggest what kind of content the browser can accept, the browser can process.
Then we also discussed about the user agent, which is at the very bottom here.
So it gives information about the browser operating system and so on.
And there are also a bunch of other headers here like the host cookie and so on.
So that's the request headers.
And we also have some response headers here, content language, content type I mentioned about this.
So it tells about the response that is included in the body of the response.
So it is going to be text slash HTML.
And one other response header I mentioned was server in this.
In this case, it is Apache Coyote.
So those are the HTP request and response parameters.
And if we click here on the response.
So this is the actual response itself.
As you can see, there is some HTML content here, over here.
So that's the request.
Now, let me show you the response for response.
Let me click on articles which shows all of the web page links that I have collected.
So here are a bunch of links.
Let me click on edit for this one.
So I'm trying to edit some information.
So this is a link to a very good article on sublets.
And so I have all of this.
Now let me go ahead and change this rating to Best.
And when I submit this, it will generate a post request and that is included in a called form.
We will look at that later.
But let me go ahead and click click on this thing edit article.
So as you can see, you can see that it generates a post.
So it is submitting all of this information to the server and we get back the response to.
So this is the response and the rating has been updated to the best here.
So that's the post request.
Let me just show it to you once again.
I just wanted to show you the post here.
So if I click on post, here it is.
Now it's right.
So it's just the same thing.
Once again, this is the URL.
This is a new URL and the HTTP method is post.
Once again, it's the same remote address for status code.
It is three or two.
It's not 200, but that is fine.
We can discuss about three or two later if you have time.
And then once again there are some response and request headers.
So that's how it is.
So if I click on this edit, let me click on that.
So I said that this is a form and the post is a post request is being submitted.
So let's look at some of the HTML tags too.
So if you right click on this on this page and if you select view page source, it shows us the HTML
content.
So this is what we have here.
So at the top we have the HTML.
So this is a tag, a HTML tag.
And so this is the starting tag and we also have the ending tag for every starting tag.
And then there is the head of some.
It's also a tag and the body starts here.
This is the body which contains the real body of the Web page.
So let me just scroll down here.
So this is the form.
This is a tag called this form.
It has all of these elements.
This is this represents the form and it has all of these elements.
Now, here we are saying that the method is post.
So this is what how you would specify it.
You can also make it as get.
And this is the destination where you want to send all of the all of the data that we are entering in
the form.
And then there are all of these different elements.
So these are text boxes to text boxes and for text box, this is the tag that is used.
Input type equal to text type suggests that it's a text box and there is also the URL.
This is the name of the text box.
Similarly, there is also a text box for title and these are called checkboxes.
You may be familiar familiar with all of this, but there may be some students who are absolutely new
to HTML.
So I have to explain it.
So these are checkboxes and for checkboxes you have this input type equal to checkbox and once again
there is a name here and that name would be used on the server side to get the value that is selected.
And so there are two checkboxes and there were three ratings here.
These are radio buttons and only one of them can be selected here for checkboxes.
You can serve either of both of them.
So for radio buttons, it is input type equal to radio and there is a naming.
There is a name too for that.
And other than that, there is this dropdown here.
And for that we use something called us select.
Let me just show you.
Here it is.
It has the Select.
This is the tag.
And all of the different options in the dropdown are here that indicated using the stockholders option.
So those are the the different UI elements and the corresponding tags.
Now, there are also a bunch of tags here.
Some of hyperlinks.
These are the hyperlinks.
These are the links in the navigation and a link to represent a link.
We use the anchor tag here and this is the destination.
It's called as an attribute.
Ref is an attribute.
And if you click on that link, a request would be sent to this particular URL.
So articles, books, movies that you see here, you can see them here, articles, books, movies and
all.
And the anchor tag also has an ending tag over here.
Okay.
So that's that.
And Dive is another important tag.
And that's the body.
And there's also some JavaScript code here.
And some CSEs here.
So that's like a high level overview of some HTML content.
And then when you the actual submit button is here, it also has to be as part of the form tag.
So the form tag is ending here and this is the submit button.
And when you hit submit, all of the data that you have entered in the form would be sent to the server.
And and it would be sent to this particular destination in the form tag you have this action attribute.
It will be sent to this destination.
And that's it.
Another important tag is the table tags.
So this is another page on top.
It shows all of the programming languages that are popular and Java is the most popular one here.
So once again, you have all of these.
So let me click on F12 once again to open the developer tool.
And this is the network.
Let me resubmit this page.
I just want to show you the table tag.
Okay.
So this is this is a table.
It has rows and some columns.
So let me hit on this inspector here.
And let me hit this button here so you can see here, if I click here, it says Table here.
As you can see, table in the in the left corner here in this area, you will see that it says table
and it's has t head, which is for the headers here.
So that's the table tag.
Now, if I click here in the first row so you can see that tag over there and the PR corresponds to
this entire row.
And then you can see that TDI, TDI is this particular cell and it has a value one.
Similarly, this is another TDI.
This has the second cell.
And if you move to the second row, we it shows a new row and it has one, two, three, four, five,
one, five, five, two, these five cells.
So that's what you can see here.
So that's how it is.
You have the rows and rows are represented using PR and the individual cells are a within a row are
represented using TDI tax.
So that's the table tag.
So that's a high level overview of HTML two.
So that's about it.
So I think we have learnt some of the good basics of the of the web and also some HTML tags.
That's it.
Thank you.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.