Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
Now, let's go ahead and do a demo of lambdas.
So here I created a new package called Calm Semantics.
Lambdas.
And we have these two classes, cache and bookmark, you may recall from our nested classes chapter
about these two classes.
So there we started with basic version and we went about improving those two classes with each newly
introduced nested class.
All right.
So let's just go ahead and refresh our memory to or in case you have skipped that particular chapter.
So this should help you.
So we have these two classes.
Bookmark is a simple class which has ID title and rating and the corresponding getters and setters for
these fields.
On cash, Java simply maintains a cache of bookmark objects, so bookmark objects can be added to cash
and cash internally stores them.
And this bookmark, it's called items.
So the constructor basically takes the size, which means the number of items that will be stored in
the cache.
So that would be the that would be the size of the bookmarks bookmark.
And in order to add an item, add a bookmark to the cache.
We have this method called ADD and we are passing the bookmark.
Now, that's how we are going to populate the cache.
And there is also this iterator method which would return an iterator for iterating through the items
in the cache and it will return an instance of this class called my cache iterator, which is basically
a non static member class within the cache class.
And it implements this interface called cache iterator, which is also defined here and it has two methods
has next and next.
So it is the cache iterator and it is implemented that way and that's about it and it has the main method.
We are instantiating the cache here and we are passing the value file, which means that it can store
up to five items and here we are creating the bookmark objects, five bookmark objects and we are adding
them to the cache.
The cache is named as recommended items, so there's the variable and here we are iterating through
the added items and we are simply printing the title and we also have this sort method.
So we are trying to sort the items in the cache.
So we are using the arrays dot sort method and here we have an anonymous class.
So that's just taken from from the nested class chapter, from anonymous classes lecture.
So we have this anonymous class which is implementing this compare method and it is going to start by
writing.
So this is an anonymous class now since we are doing, we are learning about Lambda, so we are going
to implement a lambda here.
So right beneath this code we are also printing the items that are sorted by by rating using the anonymous
class.
And after that we have this template code where we are once again invoking the source method and we
have the items which which are sorted by rating.
Now we want to sort them by length.
So, so let's go ahead and write our lambda function so we know that the lambda function starts with
this, the method parameters.
So let's just go ahead and copy that.
And we need to pass it here as an argument.
So let's do that.
And we have the arrow.
We have this braces, the body of the lambda.
And we need to give.
We need to write our logic here.
So let's just say written.
One is a parameter here.
Let's say.
Title.
So title is a string.
So let's invoke the length method.
Okay.
And let's use the comparator function of integer.
So length is going to return an int, which is a parameter.
So let's convert it.
Into Integer.
So compared to is from the comparable interface.
So let me just copy this thing.
Compared to.
So that would be the natural ordering.
And let's just change it to oh two here.
That's it.
And let's put.
And ending semicolon here.
So that's it.
And we are printing this.
So let me go ahead and run this.
Here we are.
So initially we are sorting by rating and this is sorted by length using the lambda.
So that's all it is.
So as you can see, it is much more simpler, much more compact than the anonymous class, as we don't
have any of this stuff here, the new or the competitor or even the compare name.
And we also know that we can further simplify this.
So let me go ahead and remove that type.
So that's the first simplification.
Now the compiler is going to infer that it is bookmark because it is going to infer from.
This particular argument also are from this particular argument.
So if I hover over it, it says sort bookmark array and this is the so the so it's going to infer automatically.
So the compiler is going to do that because this is an array of bookmarks bookmark.
So it's going to automatically infer that this is a bookmark type and this is also a bookmark type.
So it's so as you can see, there is no compilation error and we are once again able to.
Sort the items by by land.
Now, we also said that if there is only a single statement, then we can remove this.
We don't need the braces.
We don't need the written statement.
And we don't need this to the ending brace and also the semicolon.
So that's further simplification.
And once again, we have the same output.
So that's the lambda function.
Now let's we also said that the lambda function works with only functional interfaces.
So let's also test that in fact, the competitor the the competitor is a functional interface.
But let's also test it using our own interface here.
So we have this interface called test at the top of the class outside of the class, and it has a single
method apply.
And there is also within the cash class, within the class itself.
So we have this method called go and it takes this parameter test which is off type test.
So this test is a functional interface and we are invoking the apply method.
So let's go ahead and invoke this method and pass a lambda.
So that's an instance of cash and it's a go.
Okay.
And apply method.
We need to pass a lambda here.
So since it doesn't have any parameters, we can just do this.
We can have empty parentheses and we can have this arrow.
And let's say we want to just.
Brenda.
That's what the apply method should do.
So.
Let's print this lambda here.
And that's it.
So if we run it, so it prints lambda.
So this is the body here.
And this is over, Lambda.
Now let's go ahead and add a method.
I applied one.
Okay.
But you can see that there here we have this compilation error because the interface is no longer functional
interface.
So the compiler is saying that you're passing your lambda to a non functional interface to a non functional
So that's why we are getting the error here.
But this can be a default method, in which case once again the test and the test interface would be
a functional interface and we don't have the error anymore.
So test would now be a functional interface.
Similarly, we can have a two string method also.
And it would still qualify as a functional interface because although there are two abstract methods
here, the two string method is actually part of the object class.
We know that the string method also belongs to object class.
So every class we know implicitly inherits from from the object class.
So that implementation is already there.
So because of that, even though there are two abstract methods, test would still qualify as an functional
interface.
So that's one thing.
And so let me remove this.
We also removed this.
Now.
We said that.
So we do this.
Abstract.
And this is abstract.
Now, this is also not going to work.
Because.
It clearly now it says that it has to be a functional interface.
So that's the thing.
So we saw that it needs to be a functional interface and it needs to have only a functional interface
as only a single abstract method.
And if we have more than one abstract method, then it would not be a functional interface and we would
get a compilation error.
So it needs to be only one single abstract method and we can have other default methods or even methods
from the object class as abstract methods.
Even in that case, we wouldn't get a compilation error and it would be fine.
It would qualify as a functional interface.
So that's about it.
So just wanted to demonstrate that and this code is available in the resources section.
And thank you and happy coding.