Hi there.
This is the remote Uluru.
Let's get started by exploring the date and time classes that were used prior to Java eight.
And earlier we said that we are going to refer to them as legacy date and Time API and they are still
widely used.
And we will discuss a bit about the core classes and then we will see them action in the demo at the
end of this lecture.
And here are the commonly used classes, the date class, the calendar class, Gregorian calendar and
the time zone class.
And all of these are part of the Java util package and the date class was there from the very beginning.
That is from Java one onwards and it also encapsulates time information in addition to date.
And the date class is considered to be having several issues and one of them is to do with usability.
For instance, here we have the date June eight, 2016, and we can also see how a date instance is
created.
The first argument here is the year, and as we can see, instead of passing 2016, we are passing the
value 116.
That's because Date Class uses 1900 as the starting point for years.
So 116 would get added to 1900 to get the correct year 2016.
Now, if we pass 2016, then 2016 would be added to 1900 and we would end up with the year 3916.
I guess by then most of the human population would have shifted to Mars.
Right now we can also pass negative values to represent years before 1900.
So to represent 1899, we would pass a value of minus one.
And the second argument corresponds to month, and its range is in between zero and 11.
So it's not between one and 12.
It starts with zero.
So here for June, we are passing the value file.
The last argument is the day and it's changes in between one and 31.
So as we can see, it's kind of confusing with the way years and months are handled.
So to address the issues with the data class, the language designers introduced calendar and its subclass
Gregorian calendar in Java 1.1, which is the next version.
Calendar class is an abstract class and date class is still there for the sake of backward compatibility.
But most of its methods and constructors have been deprecated and its specification recommends using
similar methods from the calendar class.
No calendar class also has some issues like the date class.
It still uses a range of zero and for the month field.
But the problem with the year has been fixed, so we would pass 2016 and not 116 anymore.
Also calendar classes and the date class are mutable, which means that they are not threats if.
Moreover, we now have two classes doing similar kinds of things.
So it was confusing for developers and because of such issues with these classes, some developers would
use third party libraries like time.
So time is a third party library and with Java eight we have the new data time API that would address
these issues and is considered far superior as we will look at it later.
Here.
We also have the time zone class which was also introduced in Java 1.1 and we will look at it in the
demo.
So let's actually go ahead and look at all of these classes in action.
Okay.
So for this demo, I have created this new class called a date time demo in a new package called Semantic
Square DateTime.
Here it is calm, semantics, clear date time, and it's a new class.
And I created this new method here, called US Test Legacy Date API.
Since we are testing the Legacy Data API.
So here it's being invoked here from the main method.
And here we are going to demonstrate a few things.
Few of the classes, the date class, the calendar class and some of the code has already been written
to demonstrate the time zone.
So we are just going to look at this code in the interest of time and some code we are going to write.
So let's just go ahead and start with the date class.
So for the data class, which is from the Java package, we will simply do date.
Current date.
And it's just printed.
So they're classes inside Java and it's also there in Java SQL.
So this is what we are going to use for now.
So that's it.
In an apprentice.
And there's also a method called get time within the date class.
Let's also invoke that.
So let me just copy this.
And this word returned the current instance of time, so it would return the time in milliseconds.
So this would create an instance on the an instance of time, a timestamp on the timeline, which we
know that is a time that is that is relative to APIC time, which is it starts on January 1st of 1970.
So that would and the milliseconds since then would be printed here with this particular invocation
called Get Time.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
So here it is.
So when we just print current debt, it is going to print in this format.
And since this program is running in India, so it prints the ISD, which is nothing but the Indian
standard time.
So that's the time zone.
And this is the month day and the time and the year.
And this is the day, the week, the day of the week.
And it's also printing in milliseconds the same value in milliseconds since the APIC time.
So basically that represents a specific instant in time with millisecond precision.
Now, so this is deprecated.
So let me just show you the API.
So this is the API from the Java package.
And like you said, it is from Java 1.0.
So it's there from the beginning.
As you can see, most of the constructors have been deprecated and this is the default is there and
this one is there where you can pass as a specific time in milliseconds here and it would create the
date instance.
And as you can see, most of these methods here are deprecated.
There are few in the beginning, but like the after and before.
But all others have been deprecated and it is suggested to use the methods in calendar class, which
we are also going to test next.
So as you can see, almost all of the methods have been deprecated in this particular class, but the
class itself is still used.
So let me show you the code in one of my projects here.
It's called as a user class.
So this represents an entity.
It's actually the code from the trivial project.
Now, this is an entity which maps to a database record.
And here in this user class.
You know, when the user registers, the user is.
Represented by this particular by an instance of this class and the time when the user has has registered
in the website.
So that is captured using this field called created date.
And the data type for that is this Java date.
Similarly, the last update date, which means that the date when the user has updated his profile.
So that's also captured using this field and it also has the date field here and in the database.
Let me show you the schema database schema.
So this is the schema for that and for the created date field, the data type that is used in the database
is date time.
So in the code, in the Java code, it is date Java to date.
But here that is that's going to get mapped to this particular date time or data type.
And the database last updated date also has date time.
And these are some values, some sample values for that particular field.
So that is just for your information.
So even though date is deprecated, it is still in use and it can be used in this kind of a context.
So let me let's go back to our demo.
So that's what the date class, there is nothing much beyond that.
So now let's look at calendar class.
Well, the calendar class is also like date class because we saw that in the date class, the methods
have been deprecated and we were asked to use this class, but this class will also help us to manipulate
the date class.
So it has methods which were there in date class which were also doing the similar kind of stuff.
But we also have those kinds of methods in the calendar class and they help us to manipulate the dates.
So let's consider a real use case.
Let's say that we have a certain software and it has some expiry date and we want to increase the expiry
date.
So let's say that expiration date is set to some value and then the user decides to extend the subscription.
And so we need to be able to extend the subscription and so we can manipulate the calendar instance
for that.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and create a calendar instance.
Let's say calendar calendar is also from Java Digital and it's an abstract class and let's just call
it as the expiry date, which means that the date when the software is being expired or the subscription
is being expired and we can invoke.
This subclass called Gregorian Calendar.
And we can instantiate it.
We can instantiate it with the air.
Let's say June.
30.
Okay.
So this is the Gregorian calendar and it's being instantiated to this particular date.
So zero five here corresponds to June.
So it's June 30, 2017, because the month starts from zero zero.
So that's why for June, even though it is zero six, it's the sixth month it is zero five.
So that's the expiry date.
And now let's say we want to extend this by a month.
So then there is a method called let's add within the calendar class and we can invoke that.
And let's say we want to extend it by nine months.
So let's put the amount as nine and field here.
It has to be month.
So there is a field called month within this calendar class.
And we can just say calendar dot.
Month.
Here it is.
So which means that we want to extend this particular date by nine months.
So let's just go ahead and print it.
Just copy this.
Must let's print expiry date.
Let's also print it as it is without invoking the get time.
There is a method called get time there within the calendar class and let's also print the new expiry
date.
Which is called a new expiry date.
So let me just go ahead and.
And this.
So here it is.
So the two string is printing something.
Let's, let's not worry about it.
But for the expiry date, as you can see, it prints.
It opens June 30, 2017.
So the time we did not mention any time.
So it's it's like the midnight and we have added nine now and nine is added to the month.
So there is an overflow of the month and it and the next larger field is the year.
So to year one is added here.
So that's what the add method is going to do.
So the so the final date that we have is this one March 30 of 2018.
So it has been increased by nine months.
So to the ADD method, if the month is going to overflow because the range for month is from 0 to 11,
if it's going to overflow, then then it's going to add to the next larger field, which is the which
is the air field.
Now let's make this actually eight.
So it is March, right?
So let's make it eight now.
It should be February, but February does not have 30 days.
Right?
So let's see what happens.
So as you can see, it is making the date as February 28.
So that's what is happening.
So that day field here has been adjusted to 28 to the nearest valid value.
So that's what is happening here.
Now there is another method called Let's Roll.
Let's also try that and let's see what happens.
Let's increase it by 11.
But instead of add, it has to be rural.
You may copy this.
Now here we have added 11 months, but with the role we can see that it is the year is still 2018 and
the month is January, which is fine.
It has been increased by 11 months, but the year is still at 2018.
So that's the main difference between role and AD.
So that's what is going to happen.
But so for the larger value, for the next larger field, which is the year, so nothing is going to
change.
But how do we used role here for the month then it would have given us the same kind of the same kind
of result that we had for ad.
So we the date was adjusted from 30 to 28 and that would happen here also.
So let me just do that here role.
Here it is.
So for the year it remained as 2017, but for date it it changed to 28.
So for the lower field, it is working fine with the roll, but for the next larger field there is no
change in the larger field even though there is an overflow in the month.
So.
So that's about Roland ADD.
Now let's look at the time zone.
So these are the different classes that we have.
So there is the time zone class, which is from the Java package.
So there is each time zone has some kind of an ID, the London area has certain time, India has certain
has certain zone ID.
So all of them have some zone IDs.
So let's just go on this method called get available IDs will return all the zone IDs and you can use
a zone ID to set the time for that particular zone ID so we can do that as we will see next.
But let's just go ahead and print all of the time zones that we have.
So here it is.
So some of them are have only three characters, but some of them have this.
Like, for example, these are all the different places in Europe.
And you can see all of them here, Canada, Australia and Asia.
So these are the these are nothing but the zone IDs and you can use them.
So earlier we looked at the software expiry date and we have seen how we can how it can be extended
by using the ad methods.
Now, let's consider a different use case.
Let's say we have a game game like tennis, and let's say there is some grand slam happening.
And, you know, when you want to see when the when when a particular when you want to see the TV schedule
of a particular day on which the games are being played, then, you know, if the user is from, let's
say from London, then we want to see we want to show him only the London Times.
Right.
We don't want to show him us specific or Indian Times.
So we want to show him The London Times.
And let's say, for example, here we have this calendar and let's say that game start time is Gregorian
calendar here, and we want to use this time zone of Europe on London.
So and this is how we are initializing it.
We are saying the grand slam starts in 2017, the tennis tournament, and it's in January and the day
is three and it starts at 9 a.m..
So this is how we are initializing.
And for that we are using the set method of calendar and here.
Here it is.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
Here.
The calendar class.
Okay.
Here it is, the game start time.
This is what we are looking at.
So it starts on Jan three at this particular time and it still shows this particular method called Get
Time.
Here it is from the calendar class and it returns an instance of date.
And this one, if we just printed this way, it's still going to print the default time zone, which
is the Indian standard time in my case.
So it's not picking this particular time zone.
And if you want to look at this particular the exact times, then we have to we shouldn't invoke that
time, but we have to invoke other methods.
So there is a method called get in calendar.
So we have already seen the set method here which we have used to initialize the date.
So we have the get methods and we are getting the months here.
So we are saying this get method will accept an event field and we are passing the calendar month.
So game start time has the actual state, which is the state information, which is the date and the
time.
And we are trying to extract just the month from this particular date which with which we have initialized.
So the month is January.
So we are saying Jan and we are adding a one because the four month is going to start from zero zero.
So we're adding a one there and we are also printing the day of the month.
So on which day and we are also printing the hour.
And for all of these we are simply using the get method and we are just passing the appropriate field
here.
In this case, we want to print the hour here.
We want to print a minute and we also want to print the a m and PM information.
So there is a field called a m underscore PM and if it is equal to zero, we are printing am here otherwise
pm.
So that's all there is to that.
So that's why it's going to print this.
Here one is month January and date is three and the game starts at 9:00.
So that's the TV schedule.
Now let's say, for example, we want to now the user, let's say we have this particular instance game
start time, but the user is actually from India.
So in which case we want to adjust the time zone.
So we are passing this time zone.
In this way we are saying set time zone.
So there's a method called set time zone and we are passing the time zone corresponding to India.
And for India this is a zone ID, Asia, Calcutta.
So we are passing that and we are also printing the information here.
So let me rerun this.
So here it is for the Indian time.
Now it corresponds to 2:30 p.m. here for London time it is nine, but for Indian time it is 230 and
that's exactly what is getting printed.
Now you can also, if you do not have this particular zone ID, if you do not know about the zone ID,
then you can also use build a custom ID so you can say GMT.
GMT is the standard time, right?
It's like the origin and we want to specify the offset from that.
For India it would be plus five and a half hours, so it would be zero five and 30.
But let's say we want to print this.
Let's say the user is from the United States from Pacific Time.
So in which case, we need to do a minus here after GMT and we'll say 830.
So eight and a half hours behind the behind the GMT.
So let's run this again.
Now, as you can see, this says zero 30.
And so it is one three 0:30 a.m..
So that's what the user and united states in pacific time, pacific time zone will see.
So it's just the same time.
But when different users are.
Are logging in, they get to see different times and we are using just the setter methods here to set
the time zones and so that the same date is the date and time is being viewed in different time zones
and they get to see in different times, the local times in their location.
Okay, now let me do one thing here.
Show you that daylight saving time, too.
So Daylight Saving Time, in order to show that, let me change this to July.
Okay.
Because in July even in green, which in the GMT time.
So both GMT will be there.
But London also has GMT time but in around this month.
London London observes Daylight Saving Time.
So it would be a one hour ahead of GMT, even though in other times they both fall on the same time
zone, both Greenwich and London.
But during certain times of the year, London does follow Daylight Saving Time and green, which does
not follow because and because of that, there is a difference.
And in the hours, in the time.
So London is one hour ahead.
So let me just run this one more time.
Now, as you can see here it is nine.
But it is actually GMT plus one.
So GMT would be a GMT, it would be eight.
But in London it is nine now in July.
The month also has been different.
Now it is seven now.
And in India it is 130.
It is four and a half hours ahead of London and five and a half hours ahead of GMT.
That's why you have 130 instead of 230.
And here this is eight and a half hours behind behind 8 a.m..
Right now it is 9 a.m. in London, in in G in green, which it is going to be 8 a.m. GMT.
So if you subtract eight and a half hours, it would be 1130.
And because of that, the day has been changed to to two rather than three.
So it's the previous day at at 1130 in the night.
So that's all happening because of Daylight Saving Time.
And so you need to be aware of that so you can observe the DST from March to October.
So some information about that.
And during that time it's called US British Summertime.
Now, finally, let me also demonstrate.
This final thing after and before.
So we already have this game start time.
So that's let's say that's the first round of the of the tournament.
And let's say that game final is also there.
And it is let's say it is happening on 16th, in July on 16th, and the game start time was start day
was third.
So when we invoke this method called after on the game, start time means that we are just checking
if this is happening after this.
So it's pretty straightforward as the method name suggests.
So game start time, we are asking if it is happening after the game final, which is not true.
So that's why we get false when we invoke the method after.
But when we invoke the method before, we are getting a true value because game start time is before
the game final.
So that's it.
The two dates were third and 16th, so that's about it.
So those are the few main classes in the old date and time API, the calendar date, time zone and the
Gregorian calendar.
So those are the few important methods and important classes and this code will be available in the
resources section and that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.