Hi there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
Before we start looking at features such as variables and methods in this lecture, let's look at some
really absolute basics of Java language.
So here is what we are going to look at in this particular lecture.
So we will look at the naming rules for classes, methods and variables.
So there are some basic rules for naming classes, methods and variables, and we will start off by
looking at that.
Then Java is case sensitive and we will also see a few examples for that.
And it's a very common activity to print some text onto the console.
So we will see how that can be done.
In fact, we have already done that in the previous section when we wrote the Hello World Program where
we have printed the text.
But we will see a little bit more on printing text to the console.
Then it's also a common activity to write comments or disable code.
So we will also look at the syntax that we have to do that and we will also look at the core arithmetic
operations which are very commonly used like addition, subtraction and so on.
So I have written this class called US Basics Demo, and it has been written in the basics directory.
If you recall, we created this directory structure.
Java In-Depth Source.
Com Semantic Square Basics.
So this class has been written there.
So you should also go ahead and create this class and you can type in everything that I'm going to demonstrate
here.
And this class will also be uploaded onto the resources section.
So the first thing is that naming rules for classes, methods and variables, it's going to be the same
rules for all of these.
So what it says is the first character of the name has to be either a letter or underscore or dolor.
And if you have something else, then we would get a compilation error.
So that's the first character.
And the subsequent characters will once again be either letter, underscore or dolor, or in addition,
we can also have numbers.
So let's go ahead and test that first.
Let's do this.
Let's put a one here.
So the first letter cannot be a number, right?
It has to be either letter underscore or dolor.
So in this case it's one, so it should give us a compilation error.
So let's go ahead.
So I'm compiling it.
Here it is.
It says that this is not right.
So it's got to be basics.
Similarly, let's also create some variables here.
Let's say one ID is equal to zero.
Let me recompile this.
So it shows.
It tells us that this is not right.
So it's got to be one of those characters.
Let's put an underscore here.
And let's recompile.
So it compiles fine.
So underscore is fine.
Similarly, dollar is also fine.
Or you can also put a one here instead of one here.
So this is also right.
So that's what it is.
So this is that.
And the second thing is we cannot use any reserved keywords.
So reserved keywords.
Java has around 50 reserved keywords, including things like class.
And so these are all reserved keywords.
And let me show you all of the reserved keywords.
So these are all of the resort keywords.
And as we have newer Java versions, more keywords might be added to this.
So these are around 50 keywords, so we cannot use any of them and you don't have to by heart any of
these.
So as we progress through the course, we'll be using all of these.
And so by the end of the course, naturally you will avoid using these for any of our things, like
variables or method names or class names.
So let me just put a class name here.
A variable called class.
So let me compile this.
So it says that we cannot use this.
It's a reserved keyword, so let me delete it.
So here the every this is a statement.
So this is a declaration statement and every statement in Java ends with a semicolon.
So if I remove that and if I recompile it.
So it says that it's an error because a semicolon is expected at the end of the statement.
So when you compile, so the compiler might report some errors and based on what it reports, you have
to fix your program and then you have to recompile and run your program.
So that is the result.
Keywords and the naming rules.
And you cannot also have duplicate names.
For instance, we cannot create another variable called ID one.
Let me clear the screen.
So here it says variable ID one is already defined in the class basics demo, so we cannot do this.
Similarly, we cannot also have duplicate methods.
Let me create a simple method called void foo.
Foo is the name of the method and opening on the closing brace.
Let me create one more method with the same name.
So this would also give us an error.
You see it says method foo is already defined in the class.
Here it says variable ID one is already defined.
So we cannot have duplicates like this.
So let me remove this.
So next one is Java SE case sensitive?
So in Java, everything is case sensitive.
So let's define a few variables.
Let's say ID and equals zero.
Now let's create another variable with the same name i.
But I is caps now.
Now let's also create one more variable ID zero.
So it's all three different variables having the same name.
It's just that the case is waiting here.
So let me compile.
Recompile it.
You see, it's perfectly valid.
Similarly, you can also have methods.
And that's perfectly valid, too.
So that's that.
Next, it is very important to print something to the console.
So that's a very common activity in any programming language.
So let's look at that.
So for this, I'm going to take this piece of code.
Okay.
So this is this has been adapted from this resource.
So let me copy it.
I'm just doing it in the interest of time because there are a lot of statements here.
So in order to print something, we use this print length statement here, print.
So it's going to print this particular text onto the console and it will also advance the cursor to
the next line.
So that's what this little comment here says, advanced cursor to the beginning of next line.
So that's what print line does.
Then there is a method called print.
It doesn't have Allen, so it prints the text, but the cursor would be would be advanced to the end
of the string.
In the earlier case, it would be advanced to the beginning of next line.
So that's the difference between between them.
So we will look at all of this.
So let's go ahead and compile this thing.
Compiles fine.
Let me run it.
And it doesn't run.
That's because main method is not found in class basics.
So we need to have the main method.
So recall that the program execution starts from the main method.
So if you execute this, so JVM would look for the main method and it starts executing from the main
method.
So since we don't have this particular method cannot be executed.
So we need to have a main method here.
So let's go ahead and write that.
And we need to invoke the print method from the main method.
So now we clean this up.
So that's the output that we have.
So GM is invoking the main method and the main method is invoking the print method.
And in the print method, the first thing is this statement called inside print.
So that's getting printed.
But before that, two empty lines are getting printed.
And the reason for that is because we have these notations here.
It's called as a new line sequence.
A new line sequence is the backslash, followed by DN.
And since we have two of them, so each one, each new line sequence represents an empty line.
And since we have two lines, two new line sequences, two empty lines are printed.
So if ever you want to print an empty an empty line, so this is what you can do within the within this
particular string.
And then it's printing inside print.
Now print like, as, like I said earlier, it advances the cursor to the next line.
So it prints this and the cursor would be moved to the next line.
And the next statement is Hello World.
So Hello World also gets printed here in the next line.
And since it's also an print line statement, so the cursor would be advanced to the next line and the
third statement is the print alone without any text.
In this case, it would print an empty line.
So these are all the print line is just a method in some class and it's just that these are two different
methods.
This one is accepting a string and this one is not accepting any any input, but it would also print
an empty line.
So these are two different methods.
And then because it is a print line, the cursor would be advanced to the next line.
And in the next line we are printing hello world.
So Hello World is getting printed but it is a print statement.
So the cursor is advanced to the end of the text.
So the cursor would be around here.
Around here.
And the next statement is hello.
So hello is getting printed here but it is a print line so the cursor would print that and onward advance
the cursor to the next line.
And in the next line an empty space, a white space is being printed here.
So white space would be printed and the cursor is advanced to the, to this position after the white
space.
And then finally the print statement is printing world.
So we are printing well here and the cursor is advanced to this position to the end of the exclamation.
So that's with the print statement.
Now print statements.
Now there are also these, these comments.
So the next one is the comments or disabling code.
So the there are two ways in which you can do that.
So one is you will use this double slash.
So double slash means ignore everything after that, which means ignore the rest of the line.
And it is mainly useful for writing a single line comment like in this case, printing to console or
printing a space or to disable the entire line.
So if you want to disable this particular line, you can also say this and you will see that.
You say you can see the difference.
The word world is not printed here.
That's because we commented this statement.
So if you want to comment your code, then you can do that.
Or if you want to write a comment, then you would use this.
But this double slash is used for single line comments.
Or if you can, you can have some statement and the statement can be followed after that.
After that, you can follow it with this kind of a comment.
So for single line comments or commenting, a single line of code, you can use this double slash.
And the second way of doing it is called as block codes.
So block codes would be something like this.
So let me put a block code here.
It starts with a slash and asterisk and then you will also have it also ends with asterisk and a slash.
So it starts with slash and asterisks and ends with asterisk and a slash.
So with this, this whole code is disabled.
And you can see that none of this text is being printed here.
Hello world with double exclamations.
So this all of this code has been disabled.
So if you want to disable large areas of code or if you want to write some detailed description about
a piece of complex logic, then you would use block codes.
So everything in between is omitted.
So the compiler will just ignore all of that will ignore this piece of text, will also ignore anything
in between the block codes.
So that's how you would comment or comment or code.
Now, in a few sections from now, and I think in section six, we look at coding conventions and they
will and there we will explore a little bit more about how we need to write comments.
So we will look at some conventions for writing comments.
So that's what that.
Okay.
So next, finally, let's also look at some arithmetic operations.
So we are all very familiar with addition subtraction and division and those core arithmetic operations.
So you would let's just define two variables.
I said six.
That's an A-plus, Jay.
So we are adding that.
Minus.
Multiplication division and let's also do modulus, which gives us the remainder.
So this is what we have so saved.
Recompile and then execute it.
So here it is.
So it is being printed here because we are adding six and two.
So as you can see here, so the print statement got executed.
So all of these statements got executed first.
And the last statement in the print here is a print statement.
Here is also a print statement which would advance the cursor to the end of the string.
So that's what happened.
And then after that, the print line statement here is where we are doing an addition.
So eight is getting printed here and the cursor is moved to the next line and here we have subtraction,
six minus two is four, then multiplication six into two is 12, then six by two is three.
That's the division.
And finally we are doing the modulus here.
So Modulus operation gives the remainder of the division.
So we get a six more two would be zero, the remainder is zero.
So those are the core arithmetic operations.
And in the next chapter we will also in the next chapter we will also explore more about arithmetic
operations.
So those are the absolute basics.
Now here there are two dots here.
So essentially system is just a class name in the Java library and system has this variable called out.
So we are saying system out and that's how we are accessing this variable.
And this variable corresponds to an object and that object has these methods print, print, length.
So that's how we are printing it.
Just let me just show it to you in my eclipse.
So this is one statement.
So this is system and if I click on this thing f three, it shows.
So this is the system class and within that there is this variable called out and it is of type print
stream.
So print stream is another class and the class print stream actually has those print methods, print
and print align methods.
So that's all there is.
So this is the basic demo class.
And so the first method that we have written is print.
And going forward we will be writing more methods into this particular class.
So for, you know, for the, for the first few sections, we have the basic language series.
So for all of that, we will be using this class basics demo.
And as we learn new topics and as we are doing new demos, the topic is associated with the demo.
So we will write a method and we will learn the topic by by writing some code in that method.
So we will be extending this class.
And like I said earlier, this class will be available in the resources section and that's about it
to type in everything that has been demonstrated in this particular lecture.
Thank you and happy coding.