Hi there.
This is the De La Rue.
We now have a good understanding of what an enemy is.
The enemy we have seen so far is very basic and it just exports a few constants and in them may not
be any more complex than that, but sometimes it can start its life that way as a simple collection
of constants, and then it may evolve over time.
In this lecture, we will see that an enum can also be associated with state and behavior.
So in addition to constants, enemies can have instance variables for representing state.
And they can also have methods to represent behavior.
Enemies can also have a private constructor in order to associate state with enum constants.
Note that the enum constructor cannot have public or protected access modifiers cannot be public as
enum is non interchangeable and it cannot be protected because enum cannot be extended.
You may recall that the class that the compiler generates for an enum is a final class.
Now, if access modifier is left out, then by default it would be private and so it is not going to
be default access level.
Like in the case of a constructor in a regular class.
Once again, the reason is Enum is not instantiate, even from a class within the same package.
It must be private as it can be instantiated from only within the enum, and that would be for the enum
constants.
So keep that in mind.
Here is our breakdown.
It is now associated with state and behavior for state.
We have this variable called min h to read and it represents the minimum age to read any book in a particular
genre.
So it is genre specific.
So each genre, which is nothing but an enum constant, will have its own value for this variable.
And for that reason we have a constructor for initializing the variable and each enum constant passes
the corresponding value for initializing the variable.
So the values to be passed are included in the parenthesis following each enum constant.
To read a biography, you need to be at least 12 years and for horror, the minimum age is 15.
We can see that this enum also has a method for returning the value of Min H to read.
So if we invoke this method on the enum constant biography, it will return the value all.
Now notice how we are using the private access modifier for the instance variable min h to read and
public access modifier for the method.
So just like in the case of regular classes, we are trying to minimize the accessibility to members
of enemies.
Another important thing to note here is that the enum constants must be the first things to be defined
in the enum.
Everything else in the enum must follow the constants.
Also note that the sequence of enum constants are ending with the semicolon and this is not required
if the enum has only constants.
This was also mentioned in the previous demo.
Note that typically in practice an enum may not be any more complex than this where we have enum with
state end behavior.
Not that enemies can define static numbers explicitly.
In the previous demo, we already saw that it could include main method, which is static, and in addition
to instance variables, items can also define static variables explicitly.
So in addition to addressing the deficiencies in Enum pattern, this lecture highlights the fact that
unlike simple compile time constants, enemies can also associate state and behavior with each constant,
so that tells that idioms are more powerful.
Let's now quickly head over to our editor and see book genre enum associated with state and behavior.
Look, here we are.
This is the book genre, and it has been extended in order to associate with state and behavior.
So it's just the exact same code which we have seen, which we have seen in the slides.
So here we have the state here and we are using this variable in order to capture the state.
So its main is to read that is the minimum age to read.
And this is a behavior.
So it's a method.
Get min h to read, which would just return this part to the value of this variable.
And we also have a private constructor which is initializing the main H to read variable.
And the values are being passed here so they are specific to each genre.
So for biography, we are passing 12, and for horror we are passing 15.
So the exact same code that we have seen in the slides.
So we are associating state and behavior for each of the constants and within the main method it's just
the same code that we have seen in the previous slide where we were iterating through the two enum constants
and we were invoking different methods in the enum class.
The only thing I added as this particular print statement where we are invoking the get min h to read.
So this is the new method which we have added here.
So we're just accessing that.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
And we don't have to go through this once again.
And this is the minimum age to read.
So when biography was the enum constant in the first iteration, it was printing 12, because that's
what has been passed here.
Well, and in the second iteration for harder, it is printing 15.
So that's it.
So an enum can also have state and behavior.
And that's about it.
And this code is also available in the resources section and thank you and happy coding.