Let's get started with our project implementation we'll begin with creating entities which correspond
to database tables.
Let's create a new project that's named after leo.
So we have two projects now one is for the demo and the other is for the real project which is trillion
.
Now let's just go ahead and create a new package
So it's called camarade semantics squared are truly ordered entities and we will have all our entities
within this package.
So let's create the user entity so that the user class.
So just going to new
Unix are some instance variables.
First is the ID field.
I will soon explain why Id feel has this type long instead of.
And let's add all other variables.
Last word
last name.
Last name.
Let's have gender roles in.
It's also include a user type.
So this is like a screen and we will also discuss it and embed.
So we how all these instance variables to begin with.
So let's just go ahead and create getters and setters.
So let's just go here and do source and it's just our bhajan read them.
So that's how you come here and select all.
And let's head.
OK.
Now we how all our getters and setters let's just do a control shift.
Just to make sure that everything is formatted right.
So that's the new class and all getters and setters are not created so let's just discuss a little bit
about our ID field.
So the available time for ID field is long instead of.
And the reason for this is in the database we mean how millions of users.
So this malady that I play and may not be able to represent all these users there is a whole range of
and may not be large enough to represent all users.
So using a larger data type like long is definitely preferred now coming to user pipe freed.
It's basically a McAfee that is it identifies a user as either a regular user or some kind of a staff
member like editor or chief editor.
You may recall one of the effective doll items item 20 which said preferred class hierarchies but not
others.
So in this case we are violating that advice that is we are not maintaining separate classes for staff
members like editor and chief editor.
This also means that if we're looking at database tables we would have one table card user and that's
about it.
And it would have a column called user type although we are violating that advice from effective Java
.
It is fine in this case and there are a couple of reasons for this.
The main reason is we are treating this product as a web application.
And as mentioned earlier some of the implementation would be done differently from what was discussed
initially while introducing the concepts.
For example probably a probably new and rigid Proview type of methods will be part of some managers
as opposed to creating a class like editor and including these methods as part of them as we discussed
.
Well my learning inheritance Another reason is except for some additional privileges that staff members
have like approving a review or making a bookmark marking a bookmark as kid friendly.
They don't seem to have any additional unique features compared to a regular user that is there differ
only in user type value and all other fields are common to regular user and a staff member.
Next we will write bookmark classes and did it make sense to maintain separate classes for the different
bookmark types.
That is we would have a class hierarchy and not get back to us individual bookmark types like movie
and book have of that are unique to them.
In fact we used book market book and movie as an example to illustrate why we should use class hierarchies
are not classes.
While discussing that particular effect of Daleiden so it makes sense to have separate classes and even
indeed as we would have separate tables for movie book and bing.
OK.
So let's just go ahead and Corno it bookmarklet across us now.
OK so we are creating bookmark is now.
OK let's just create the bookmark class in the same package
not it's create three variables here
ID for you which is wrong as in the case of user class
.
So by do on the last one is profile you are in.
So once again let's create getters and setters select all
control shift have.
So that's the bookmark class.
So later we'll be making this an abstract class as we discussed in our lessons earlier.
That's because we want to introduce the kid friendly related methods and for that we need to make this
move more process abstract.
So we'll do that later.
Next let's add the movie class movie class.
We're extending the book Class this soon to me just say finish.
Now let's add this extends bookmark.
Save it now that's ired.
Some instance variables
say the first one is really easy either so.
And the more we the ear when the movies are released.
So it's it would be in type.
Next letter I cast so cast you how money to put our names.
So how does a string already
Next let's our directors.
So once again you mean how more than one director.
So let's go with string theory.
Next let's go to John Johnny.
You can Howard as a string.
Finally let's I'd reading.
Let's call it as I am rating just in gets If you don't know what I'm D-B is I'm D-B has website related
to movies and you can find ratings of movies over there.
So let's just have that reading as type as an honorable and once again or two generic gendered getters
and setters all.
So that's the movie and goodie.
Let's go had an our book and now
book also extends book mark.
You know that now let's ired publication either which can be and
I the publishers string
.
Now let's add authors since can have more than one author Bill Hobert does a string.
Next.
John Ray.
Now let's also have a rating for book.
Just like for a movie let's call it as Amazon rating so we will get the rating from Amazon.
Let's just assume that we have the rating from Amazon.
So once again it would be double counted as Amazon reading because there might be a separate wording
just within Trejos system also.
So in its name and let's keep it as clear as possible.
OK so that's a book.
Now let's create
a weblink
which also extends bookmark
and Webling to just how only two variables you Orlan host both of them strings
.
So that over blank glass now.
Good friendly status.
There's a fee for that.
And that way will later.
Finally let's create a user bookmark entity which would maintain the relationship between user and bookmark
.
That is if a user bookmarks a particular bookmark then that information is stored in this class.
So if we have a database then there will be a separate table made in just for this entity.
OK so there will be a table for user bookmark entity.
So let's just go ahead and create the user bookmark class
.
So it's just an independent class not extending any other class.
So it could have only two variables private user user.
And we also need a bookmark
is it after the user was the last one holes after bookmark
so that the user bookmark last.
I need food maintain the relationship between user and a bookmark.
So those are the entity classes that we have.
And next most likely we will implement the managed process