In the last lesson we learn how to use a debugger in this lesson we will use debugger to fix any issue
in the process.
We're going to learn a couple of things that people learn how to write unit tests using unit.
And we also look at another cool feature of Eclipse debugger to debug the issue.
We want to ensure that the programs we write work correctly.
Some developers rely only on using system not older print statements to verify program correctness but
doing this is really low tech and is very time consuming.
You would have to repeat the process every time some logic is changed.
Similarly you cannot just rely only on using a debugger debugger should mainly be used to identify the
exact cause.
Once we are on that issue.
So the best runtime solution is to use automated uniqueness.
The benefit is that they are automated Arnalds also repeatable illness.
These does ensure that any new changes do not break the system so we can say that the main benefit is
program correctness at all points of times.
With that we can feel confident about our code and sleep peacefully knowing that we are in good shape
.
I'm sure you would agree that this last benefit is really important.
G-Unit is a popular open source framework that allows us to write automated uniqueness for Djala programs
that typically use the best individual unit like methods and Gagin a dot org is the official website
of G-Unit.
It was originally written by goingback Eric Gama who are well-known authors and have written some classics
and software engineering feat and Jaman it is well integrated into eclipse.
Writing a G-Unit best on a desk is as it is referred to in what setting up method input.
Then executing the method with the input and finally testing the actual output with the expected value
.
So let's get started.
Underwrite a unit task is Villatoro lot of a debugger.
Some real work before writing our first unit test case.
Let's look at some new code that has been introduced first as a department class which is a new class
and it has an instance variable called name which represents the department name.
It comes along with a getter and a setter and it is initialized in this constructor course class husbanded
and couple of lessons ago.
A new way that will call Department has been introduced here which is of pipe Department OK and the
department variable is initialized in the constructor or here.
So that department name is a new parameter Department is initialized only if the department name is
not equal to null.
So if it happens to be null then the department variable will also be null and there is also a getter
for the department ready next to that class a new method has been added call and roll.
It allows a student to enroll in a new course.
So courses a parameter here.
And if this method is invoked on a student instance it means that student is trying to add a new course
and a student is allowed to are only a limited number of courses on all the courses that are added are
stored and this data structure and road courses which is an idealist.
And here is the limit.
So we are checking that the student is not enrolling more than this limit.
OK so it is course underscore and underscore Lamech which is a static variable and is initialized with
a rally tree.
On this method invokes this print method print and road courses which all it does is simply iterates
over the root causes and Bentz all the courses that the student has registered for.
So it prints the course name under department name says ghost or department Daut get name on the result
or get her far enrolled course this variable which is the RL list which is here which is created here
.
Don't worry about this generics related BACS since generics is not yet covered.
Other than that I want to just refactor just rename the student test class.
Let's go here to refactor rename it to student test drive.
Let's just do this next.
Finish.
So that's how you rename it class going to refactor under your name.
The reason we want to rename it is because the ESC is that we are going to write in a minute will be
named the student test.
That's because that's the regular convention.
So if we want to test anything in student then the task is a rewrite by convention has to be student
dust.
OK it's not a requirement but just a convention.
That's the reason we are renaming it to student best driver it should be obvious that much of dusting
happens and development environment as opposed to a production environment.
That's because in development and Rutman code is being actively dolar and that is called POBox.
Testing would help in identifying and fixing those bucks on production.
You would expect to be near-perfect.
There is no need for any best guesses.
Mortars are running Vasquez's.
We're also Edam system resources as to how to execute the code they are testing.
So typically real code that needs to be deployed is kept separately from Vasquez's when time comes for
deployment.
Only the real code is deployed or not the task is this.
So let's also follow the same practice and create what gets a subsidy.
Let me just minimize this.
Let's go here into the project and let's head new.
To create a news source folder let's just call it best because we are creating test cases.
Now let's use the same package name here because we are going robustus this class student writing a
test case for that and it need not be the same package name but convention is to use the same package
name as the class being tested.
So let's just go ahead sip package.
It's the same one.
Now let's just go ahead and create our unit desk.
So go into new year after I quicken her G-Unit desk guess it's just call it call it a student test because
we're creating a test case for a student and that needs to be the name on the package.
Here is a package name on class under test would be the Student class no hit next.
And it was all the methods in the Student class and we want to create a test case for this method.
Also shows the math that's an object class because Object class is the superclass.
So this is the only method that we want to test had finished.
It says are G-Unit for a library to go Billy-Bob because it's not yet added but let's do it later in
a bit just from the best guess that gets created.
We'll see how that can be done.
OK.
So this is the test case that God created automatically and as expected it shows completion errors because
their uniform is not in the classpath.
So we need to add that library.
So let's just call it what it says gives three quick fixes.
It says you can add this unit for library book I believe but it's true that I know you can see the compression
errors Mandvi and it got added here so that our libraries in our other JRD under G-Unit for guess if
you ever want to remote just right click go to belly button Heydari Movember.
OK now here are the matter that needs to start is and roar and you can see that G-Unit has created this
desk is called best Android so it always uses this kind of a naming convention best followed by the
Mathare the method name that GHI that's going to be tested on.
Here is an on additions and additions.
We did not cover unpropitious yet but it's simply a moderator data and it does G-Unit that this is this
particular method is a best guess.
So if you read this and you were audited SR as an addition as G-Unit that the method to which it is
attached can be run as a test case to run them at their G-Unit first constructs a fresh instance of
the class which is the student class this class then invokes the unaudited matter.
Any exceptions thrown by that test will be reported as a failure if no exceptions are thrown that Destin's
is used to have succeeded.
Maybe look at both failure and succeeded.
And it should be clear and it should be clear to you.
Now here there is this matter called fail which is a static method in a class called assert which is
being imported here.
OK.
We haven't had Biscoe static imports.
If possible I might include a separate lesson for that but I think this discussion should suffice too
.
So let's start taking borders as it imports all the static members like the static field from the static
methods in a particular class.
So I don't think that this is a package.
It's a class actually and we are importing all the static members from it.
And the advantage of that is you don't have to qualified the static member using the class name you
don't have to do a search dogface.
You can invoke it directly just like invoking any method in the same class.
OK.
So that that's the I'd want it you don't have to qualify it using the class me but you must use it sparingly
.
That's because it can confuse your readers if you use it excessively.
It might confuse the readers of your code or you yourself because it's not clear whether you're invoking
a method in this class or if you are working a method within this class.
OK so use it sparingly and just go ahead and run this.
And it says of one failure.
The reason is because this method is responsible for that.
What this method means is it just means that the best guess is incomplete and new to selling the dodo
bird that you need to implement it sooner it's just be some real code here.
I do a control issue f on what exactly are we testing here.
We are testing to ensure that student is not allowed to enroll in more than that the limit the max limit
number of courses.
OK.
So should a student should enroll only in three courses.
So here is how we set up that task is sort of the input.
So we're creating a student instance here first then we are creating a course instance instance and
passing for other department and we are doing the method execution.
So we are in walking the enrollment third installment by passing discourse one variable which is a course
which is of course.
And finally we are testing the output though the enrollment there is not retaining anything.
We are testing.
There is a change of speed when when this method is getting executed and we are checking that.
So what are we dusting here.
We're getting all the courses that the student has enrolled in.
So we are sort of credence on our list with all the courses that the student has enrolled and we are
calling the size method of idlest undertows how many courses the student has registered and it should
be less than the limit that we have.
OK.
And guess if if it is less we are good about but if it exceeds then it means something wrong has happened
.
Logic has been written in a wrong way and G-Unit would throw an error on it or spread this message.
Enrollment limit exceeded should never happen.
So and then we are adding some more courses here.
Nothing more than that.
So as Drew is also a method in the class.
So let's just go ahead and run this.
You know it says one error failure zero.
So what is an error what is a failure or is basically some kind of an internal error like a null pointer
exception or something like that.
And if failure is something like that's where you're testing some expected value with the actual or
they are not meeting that is expected is different from the actual and then Junod were throw we would
say that a failure has happened.
So what is the error here.
It says null pointer exception which means that something went wrong.
This is the stack trace and it's just DoubleClick and debug it using over debugger.
So let's go here.
This is a matter where some issue has come up.
So let's just set up our break point here and let's call our friend debugger tool and test Java.
And here it stops.
So the issue is null pointer exception so we don't know whether it is cause is null courses here or
with of course don't get Department we are displaying the department name.
So we are saying get Department we don't know if this is not.
So one of them is null.
But in this case it's obviously you know if you holler over course we know that it is not.
No but it could also be know what caused our get Department is obviously not here.
So but let's just pretend that we don't know and let's try to figure that out.
So for that what you can do is we can use a new feature of Eclipse guard expeditions where we were test
expression expression can be coarse expression can be course not good department.
So let's just see if any of these expressions is not sort of just going to window which says sure you
hit exhibition's here.
Yes and it's an expression.
It's just called this course which is an expression here and it has some value which means it does not
know.
So that's not that's not an issue with that.
Another way to add exhibition is just copy this on our new exhibition and listed there.
Or you can also do this you can head control shift.
I mean you do that it opens this pop up and it shows the value.
Now if you want this to show up in that exhibitions you hit Control shift I one more time.
And there you go.
Here the value.
So that's the null value.
So when we are in we'll can get name on this Nuddle it is giving us a null pointer exception.
So we need to fix that and for that we need this kind of a statement.
So you would execute this system not out statement only if Gore's Target department does not equate
to none.
So that's the fix that we need to have.
OK.
But what happened when I just we just added this court thought stop in the same debug session we did
not stop the debug session.
So we have just added on the fly we have added our fix on the fly.
And when we saved it controlled went back to the first day first line of the matter.
OK.
Now we can test it right.
So let's just hit her as you just hit her is the industry on it's just hit or is you
going to G-Unit.
We actually have some other failure but this one is gone.
This area is not that it was something else we will figure that out.
But the main thing as exhibitions are very useful when you have a chain of in locations like caused
or get Department thought let's say something else get something DOD get something.
And that is you would you know if there is a null pointer exception you don't know which is which subexpression
is good but is not.
So you would you know an inexperienced Dolapo would keep printing each of the invocations here using
a system not out and we're trying to figure it out.
But the thing you can do is you can always do this.
UNDERSHAFT I know whether it's down whether it's in Larnaca.
Now if it does not matter then you would expand it and you will try for this.
So there are a chain of indications chain off in locations like if you a call this has a or b b c c
or d.
So if you have a chain of invocations then exhibition's who would be perfect.
OK now let's just go up go back to our unit.
Let's see what the issue is.
It says best Andrle.
It's a failure which means that the expected value did not meet the actual value.
So let's just click on that and here it is.
And the last line there is some issue.
The issue is let's just going to unroll matter here.
Let's not use our debugger.
So here the issue is it says less than or equal to cause and No-Limit.
This should have been less than similar.
Because of that it was showing an error even when the fault course was added.
So if you go back to student dust.
So I suppose the first course that got added and the logic shouldn't have allowed us to added and allowed
us to add on so when we try to test it it failed and it helped us to fix this logic issue.
So that's about it.
That's all I wanted to show.
So we looked at how to create a test case and we also looked at the new expeditions feature of debugger
which is very useful when you have a chain of implications and we need to see some value more there
.
So that's about it.