Hello there.
This is the Ramona La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's now go ahead and create our first Java class in Eclipse.
So here I am in the Eclipse installation directory and we have seen this particular application in the
last lecture.
So let's go ahead and double click on this in order to launch Eclipse.
So the first thing that Eclipse asks us is to select something called as a workspace.
And a workspace is simply a directory where our programs are stored.
So as the name workspace suggests, it is simply a space where our work is stored.
And our work being the programs that we write and the class files that get generated and any resources
that we might be using.
So since we are starting off, we need to create a workspace.
So once we create it in future, we can use the workspace.
So just click on Browse here and I'm in the C drive, click on new folder and let's create this folder
called JID which stands for Java in Depth.
Just select folder, select folder and just say hit launch here.
Okay.
So what we see here is the welcome screen.
So you can just close this one.
Now here what we are seeing is.
So this is called as.
This is called as a perspective, which is just a feature of eclipse.
So this is one perspective and a perspective lets you do something and we can also have other perspectives.
So that's a perspective is simply a collection of predefined windows.
So this is one window here and they refer to it as a view.
And here we will have another view, which is where we will write our code.
And so we have different views here.
And when we run our program, the output can be seen here.
So that's another view.
So a perspective is a bunch of views and this is the Java E perspective and using it we can create Java
E Web applications.
We simply have to click on this link.
But then there are also other perspectives like the Java perspective and also the debug perspective.
So here if you click on this particular one open perspective, it shows you all the perspectives that
come with this particular eclipse.
So this is the default one.
So if we click on Java here, it is a more simplified version of Java E perspective.
So as you will see, you will have only fewer features here.
So you can create a Java Basic Java project here, Java application.
Similarly, there is another one called Debug.
Let's also click that.
So debug perspective has different views and you would use this particular perspective when you are
debugging your application.
So if your application, a main application compiles fine, but if you see some errors in your application,
then you would want to debug and see where the issue is and for that you would use the debugger.
And later we will look at how we can debug Java programs.
So all of those perspectives will be laid out here and you can switch between them.
So this is the Java perspective and this is the Java E perspective.
So for now, let's just use the Java perspective here, now here, let's go ahead and create a simple
project.
We can either click here or we can go here and certain eclipses, you might not see this.
So you can also go here and to file click on New here and you have many options.
So we need to create a project and the project will be created within our workspace.
So that's the first thing that we need to do.
So within our workspace we can have one or more projects and those projects can be entirely interrelated
to.
So here is where we will create the project.
So the project name, let's name it as eclipse test.
And here we are saying use default location, which means that eclipse test will be created within our
guide workspace.
And here the execution environment degree will be Java 14.
And if you recall in the previous lecture I showed my path and I was using Java 14 and that was being
used to launch Eclipse and the same Java is being used here also in order to run the program.
So in your case it might be something else or we can also select any other ones that we might be having.
So let's just use this one, which I have it on the on the path.
And here this option says create separate folders for sources and class files.
Let's leave it as this.
It just means that the source code and the compiled class files will be located in different folders
and I will show you that.
So go ahead and just click next.
So everything is default.
Now here in this page, there is this option called create module hyphen in for Java.
So you can deselect this and this particular option, you will see it only if you are using Java nine
or later.
If you're using Java eight, then you will not see it Java eight or any of the prior versions of Java
eight.
Then you will not see it.
So from Java nine only you will be able to see this option.
And this is related to a concept called US modules which we have not discussed, but maybe in future
we might discuss it, but for now just deselect it.
If you see this, it just means that you are using either Java nine or a more recent version.
So just select it and hit finish and it will create the project here.
And if we drill down we can see source also.
Let me also open the folder on the file system.
So let me go into C drive and JID.
So within the JID it created this thing called us eclipse test.
So this is the project and within this we have source here within source we will have the source code
and within bin we will have the generated class files, the compiled files.
Right now it is empty.
So let us go and create our first class so you can right click here or you can right click on source
also and just say new and we need to create a class.
So since this is our first class, let's go ahead and create the Hello World class.
Because the package name you can leave it as eclipse test.
So it is picking the same name as the project.
Or you can also create another package name like the column dot semantics, dot semantics, square dot
test or something like that.
So let's leave it like that.
And the modifier is public and let's not worry about the superclass since we haven't discussed it yet.
And here, which method steps would you like to create?
So let's just say we want to create the main method automatically.
So that's the stub of the main method.
So that's it.
Let's just hit finish and.
And this is another view where it is creating this hello world class and it is within the package eclipse
test.
So you can also see that main method got automatically generated.
Okay.
So that's the benefit of using an eclipse ID and ID.
Now, since a font is small, let's go ahead and increase it.
Let's also close these views here.
We don't need them.
So we just have this this this is called S package exploder because you can explore the packages and
here we will.
When we run it, we will see that there is a new view that gets created.
But before doing that, let's increase the font size.
Go here and to window preferences.
Here.
The first option is general.
Let's drill down.
Appearance.
Click on colors and fonts.
And here, once again, let's select Java here.
And within Java, there is this option called Java editor, text, font.
Just double click.
So this is what we have right now.
So let's increase the font size to 16.
Okay, apply and close.
So the font has increased and that's good.
Now let's go ahead and put a print statement.
So let's just say six out and hit control space and the statement is automatically created.
That's the beauty of it.
So let's print this and let me just save it controls and let me just show something on the desk right
now.
So here we are in the bin and the RC folder.
We have the eclipse test package within which we have Java Java.
So that is okay.
Now if you go into Ben, you will see that the package eclipse test is there because that's the package
and within that the class file is there.
So we did not compile it separately.
So it means that eclipse is automatically compiling our our source code so you can see how productive
it is when we are using Eclipse so we don't have to execute the Java command.
It is being done internally.
So that's the beauty of using an editor like Eclipse.
Now to run it, all we need to do is just click on this button run hello or Java and you will notice
that a new view gets opened here.
It's called console.
It's just like the command prompt console.
You see it got created and it is printing.
Hello here.
So that's the thing.
And you can another way to run it is you can just right click on the class here and say run as and you
can run it here.
Also run as Java application and there you go.
It has run again.
And you can also click here also right click run as an Java application, run as an Java application.
So it will run it once again.
So that's how it is the compilation and execution.
And let's also put a couple of more statements.
Let's say Long L.
Let's assign it to an end.
And what would happen?
We should get a compilation error.
That's what we are getting here.
So this underline here, when I hover over it, it says type mismatch cannot convert from long to int.
Right.
And similarly, we can also see this red icon here.
And hovering over it will give will show this tip here.
It says type mismatch.
Just the same message.
And over here also if you click on problems.
Here it is.
So it is it is showing this error.
So if we drill down, it shows the same message here.
So that's the compilation error.
And to fix it, we just do this, put it cast and the error is gone.
So it disappeared.
But it is giving this yellow icon and it is called as a warning.
So it just says the value of the local variable.
I is not used because we are not using it anywhere.
So it's like a dummy statement.
So the same thing here also I is underlined.
So when I hover over it, it shows this message and even in the problems instead of errors.
Now it just says that it is warning.
So the value of the local variable I is not used.
So this is given by the compiler.
So it's not an error, but it is a compiler warning and it is warning us that there could be a potential
issue.
So look into that.
So in this case for this, it is saying that the local variable is not used anymore.
So that's the warning that it is giving us because it is pretty much a dummy statement.
So maybe we wanted to use this particular variable, but we are not using it.
So it is telling us to look into that.
But it will run fine, so there won't be any issues in running the file.
Now, another thing is cool.
Thing is, if we hover over here on the print, it gives a little summary of what the print does along
with the declaration itself.
This is called as a Java documentation.
So the owner of this method, whoever has written this method, has also taken time to write a simple
summary of this particular method in the source code itself.
So that's because of that.
And another type of comment called Java Dog and we will look at it later.
Similarly, even for if our here so system is a class and this is the summary of that summary of the
system class.
So the owner, whoever has written this class has written this documentation.
So it gives a clear summary of what the system class does.
So now that doesn't happen for Main here because we did not write it.
So if we write Java comments, then we can see that and that is something that we will look at it later.
So that's another benefit of eclipse.
Now, if by any chance you, let's say, accidentally close this console, then you don't have to panic.
Just go here into window.
And here we have something called Show View, which shows all of the views.
Just click on console and the console will be back again with the same text that it had earlier.
Same goes with problems.
Also, if you close it, just go into window and show view and you can click on problems here and you
will see that that particular tab will be back again.
Okay.
So that's what it is.
And one other thing I wanted to show is if you go into a window and if you want to, let's say, remove
all of these line numbers, for instance, just go here.
Window preferences.
Earlier we looked at this one appearance, so we don't need that go into editors.
Click on text editors, and it shows many of the things that can be seen here in the editor view.
So if you select this one and apply enclose so the line numbers will go away.
So there are a bunch of other options also, but I think we need to.
It's better to have blind numbers.
It'll be very useful.
So it's back again.
So that's that.
So here, the package name.
It just picked this particular one.
But we can also create more packages.
Just right click say new package and you can create a package like Comcast, Symantec Square, dot util
or whatever and it will create a package.
And within that package you can once again create classes within that package.
So that's about it.
So we have created our first Java class in Eclipse and that's about it.
Thank you.
And I will see you in the next lecture where we will look at something called Bell Process.