Not let's look at the list duffus Listen to this is useful when sequence markers that is preserving
the order of the elements inserted is a requirement and this interface models a resizable linearity
.
That is It Is Like A not A but as a resizable and it is just like the IRS and it can also contain duplicates
And here is the declaration awfullest interface.
And we know that it extends the collection interface.
So in addition to methods that it is headed toward that collection it also adds several new methods
.
Unhidden the category of methods that the list interface specifies that positional search duration Andrena
view.
Let's see what we how in each of these gettig it is since this preserves the position of inserted elements
we have some positions specific methods.
That is all the methods how index number as a parameter have mattered right and so on an element it
to specified in next segment that would insert an element at a specified index and also returns the
element previously stored at that index.
I'd meant that absenting amended the specified index.
The next hour that X an element to the end of the list.
So index number is implicit here.
The moment that results in it amended to specify the next.
And finally I on the matter are all the elements in the input collection starting at the specified location
in the current list next to search operations under our diplomats here Husserl and so just the list
for the specified element under the index of the first appearance of the element.
It would be then a minus one if the list does not contain the element.
Similarly second method returns the index of the last occurrence of the specified element or minus one
if element is not Farner next iteration related methods.
Now if you recall when discussant collection interface V before you discussed the iterative method which
said returns on instance off iterator interface have these lists or did it and methods are also similar
to the method under it and an instance off list Tritter which is actually some interface off it did
it that interface since it's a sub interface or for that matter.
It provides a few more specialized methods and look at these methods when discussing atlast next as
range view on how only a single operation here.
The simplest method here returns a popular view of the list which is in the specified range that is
it written or list that is a subset of the current list and this subset is in between the specified
indices from index.
On doing this here doing that excludes you that is element or that index is not written.
In other words only elements in between the indices from Index index minus 1 are included in the return
list.
Also the return list is bagged by the original list.
What it means is any change is made in the return list then be reflected in the origin or list and vice
versa.
So if you add any element in the return list then that element gets added in the original list also
.
We will look at this in a word them off orderless.
So that's what the list interface.
Thank you