Now let's look at polymorphism.
It is very likely that you must have heard of both inheritance as well as polymorphism, even before
you enroll in this course.
We already looked at what inheritance is and polymorphism is another awesome feature of object oriented
programming and it exists due to inheritance.
That is because we have an inheritance.
We are able to take advantage of polymorphism.
So let's look at what polymorphism is and what benefits we can have from it.
Every class defines a contract through its methods.
That is, it announces that I have these kinds of methods.
Now, if the class is public and if it has public methods, then the contract is the API.
Now if class is a super type, then it's contract is also defining a common protocol for all its subtypes.
That is, it is announcing that both myself and all my subtribes have these kinds of methods.
And we know that inheritance permits this as subtribes will inherit all the methods defined in the super
type.
Nobody finding such a common protocol for its subtypes.
Super type is also providing the benefit of polymorphism, and let's see what it means.
Polymorphism.
A super type can be assigned any of its subtypes.
For example, let's consider this method update profile which updates the profile information of a user.
So the methods parameter is off type user.
So obviously we can pass a user object to this method.
But due to polymorphism, we can pass an instance of any subclass of the user class.
This is possible.
A super type is defining the common protocol for all its subtypes.
That is anything you can do with a super type object within this method.
You can also do the same with any of the objects of its subtypes.
That is within this method.
If you are invoking a method on the user object, then that same method will still be invoked even if
an object of subtype is passed.
So what is the benefit of this?
One is that cord is much more flexible.
That is code is less susceptible to change.
And what does that mean?
For example, user class can acquire new subclasses in future.
But this method update profile doesn't have to change at all.
That is, it would remain the same.
So a few more changes imply fewer bugs.
And the code is also a lot cleaner.
Now, without polymorphism, we would have maintained for different versions of update profile method
for the four different types of users.
That is, we would have one update profile method with the user as parameter and one with staff as parameter
and so on.
Also, with every newly added user type, a new update profile method would have to be created, but
now we have only a single method that is less code and also clean code.
So here user can take any form and hence this feature has been named as polymorphism.
In this example, method parameter is a polymorphic reference.
That is how it is referred to as.
However, even the method return type can be a polymorphic reference.
So we set up with polymorphism.
A super type can be assigned any of its subtypes.
It means that the type of object reference and the actual object referenced can be different.
In this case, the type of object reference has to be a super type of the actual object type that is
being referenced.
In this example declaration, the reference type on the left is user, while the actual object referenced
is ED and we know that user is a super type of editor.
Before polymorphism, all the declarations we looked at have same type on either side of the assignment.
Now that reference type and object type can be different.
There is something important you need to know about method invocation.
Compiler uses reference type to decide on whether a method can be invoked on an object reference or
not.
So it doesn't use the object type, but it uses the reference type to make this decision.
Here in this declaration reference type is user, an object type is editor and we get a compiler error
when we try to invoke a review method on the reference variable.
That's because compiler knows that user class, which is the reference type, does not have this method.
But at runtime, JVM uses the actual object type to decide on which method is invoked.
And Jim invokes the most specific version of the method in the inheritance tree.
Starting from the object type and moving upwards in the tree.
Let's actually look at an example.
Here is the class diagram from our case study.
Let's say we have this declaration that we saw earlier.
Next we are invoking post a review method on user variable.
Now there are two implementations of this method one in user class and one in staff.
And GM would invoke the Washington stuff.
That's because GM starts searching for this method in the inheritance tree.
Starting from editor onwards, as editor is the object type in the declaration.
So as it climbs up the inheritance tree from editor, it will find a method in staff class.
So JVM tries to find the most specific version of the method.
Next off, Save a blink method is invoked.
Then JVM invokes the only version in the user class.
Now let's assume that say weblink method internally invokes post review method.
Then can you guess which version of the method would be invoked?
Would it invoke post review in user class?
A safe web link is also in user class.
No, it would still invoke the Posture Review method and the staff class.
And that's because JVD once again starts exploring from editor class onwards.
As editor is the object type that is being referenced.
And that's about polymorphism.
The main takeaway is that polymorphism allows us to write code that is flexible.
That is code that is less susceptible to change.
And the second benefit is it allows us to write less code, and consequently the code is cleaner.
Let me now give a very quick demo of what we learned.
In this demo, we will test two things that we have learned.
First word is the main polymorphism feature that allows subclass objects to be assigned to a super class
reference.
Next, we will test the method invocation concept.
So here we have three classes User, Java, Staff, Java and Java.
Just like the way we have in our case study and user Java that is the user class is the superclass.
We know that and all three classes reside in this package called Semantic Square.
Oop staff dot java.
We know that it extends user and editor class extends staff and within user we have this method called
print user type and all it does is simply print the word user and staff also has the same method, but
it prints staff editor also has the same method and it prints editor.
Now there is a fourth class, a tester class which is called a user test.
It also has the same method print user type, which has a parameter user.
So that's a polymorphic reference type.
And all it does is it invokes the method print user type for the object that is being passed here.
And this is the main method here.
And user test is also in the same package.
So here initially, initially, we are declaring three variables user, staff and editor, and the reference
type is user for all of them.
And for the user variable, the object type is user.
And for the staff variable, the object type is staff.
And for editor it is editor.
Now we are first creating an instance of user test and then we are invoking its only method, print
user type and we are passing user object to it.
And then in this statement we are passing the staff object under.
Then the third one, we are passing the editor object.
So we are passing three different objects and the reference type is just user.
So we discussed this, we said that that's the benefit of polymorphism, right?
We can just have one method and in future, if we add any other objects like email, admin or chief
editor, we don't have to make any changes.
We don't have to change this method and we can simply use the same method.
So it's, it gives us flexible code and it's also lesser code.
You don't have to maintain three different methods for each of the user objects.
So let me just run this.
And it prints user when the user object got passed.
When staff got passed, it printed staff because it invoked the print user type method of the staff
object that got passed.
And then for editor it printed editor.
So that's part one of our demo.
Now let's do the part to.
So user Java has these two methods.
Save Weblink and post a review and save a blank.
It just prints this message user column save web link and it is also invoking the post review method
and post the review method.
Also we have this text that's getting printed.
User It just means that we are inside user class and then we are printing the name of the method and
staff.
Dot Java has just the post review method just like in the case study and editor just has this empty
method approved review.
And so let's just go back to user test and let's just consider this declaration here because it helps
us to test the method invocation.
So let me just say editor dot now you can see this the benefit of using an ID, it gives this dropdown
with all the methods that the user class has.
So let me just try to add approve review which is inside the editor.
But compiler says that there is no approved review method.
That's because compiler is looking at the reference type.
Right.
We discuss this so it's not going to look at the object type.
So this is not going to work.
So let me just comment this out.
Now let's call Ed.
Dot post a review.
Let me just comment these three out.
Okay.
Let me just run this.
Now it says staff post a review.
So post a review and the staff class has been invoked.
So Gvm is actually searching the inheritance tree starting from editor, and it is going upwards towards
user class and it could find the method and staff even though there was this the same method end user.
So that's post a review.
Next, let me comment this out.
So the more specific method was accessed.
Called Save the Blink.
And on this.
Now it's first invoked save a web link in the user class.
So that got printed.
And we know that Save Web link is in turn invoking post review and post review.
It did not invoke the one user, but it invoked the one and stuff.
We already discussed this and we said that once again because JVM is going to start at search from editor,
because editor is the object type and that's about it.
That's about polymorphism.