Hello there.
This is Data zero.
Now, let's look at local causes.
Local classes are classes that are defined within a method, so they're just like local variables.
You would define them within a method because defining them outside of the method doesn't make sense.
Shortly we will look at an example in our demo.
Since they're part of a method, they can only be instantiated somewhere within the method.
And they can also have multiple constructors and can inherit from multiple types just like any other
class.
Now we know that convention is for methods to be shot, and since local classes are part of methods,
they also have to be shot.
Otherwise they would affect readability.
Recall that this was also the case for anonymous classes that are defined within methods.
Also like anonymous classes, any local variables accessed from the enclosing method should be final.
That is, they should either be declared with final modifier or if we are using at least Java eight
then they need to be effectively final.
Note that unlike other nested classes, local classes are rarely used.
I came across one use case where using a local class makes sense.
Let's head over to our editor and look at it in practice.
It should give you an idea about when using local classes would make sense.
Okay.
So for this demo I created this new class, called us data translator within our nested classes package.
So as the name suggests, data translator basically translates data from one format to another.
So in this demo, we are going to see how we can translate a Java object into XML.
And for this, I created this method called this get book as XML and it will translate a Java object
into XML.
So that's a static method.
And within that static method we also have a local class called US Book.
So that's the book class.
And so it is a data translator.
So it's going to translate a Java object into XML format.
And one of the use cases where it would be useful is if you want to share some data with your partners,
then you could make use of this.
So you would convert your Java objects into XML and that XML can be returned to the desk.
And at some point in the future, at some point of time, you can run a background job which will share
that XML data with your partners.
But if the partners want some real time access to your data, which is stored in the database, then
typical way would be to access a web service like a rest API which can return the result in either XML
or JSON format.
But other than as a web service, another way would be to store it and on the disk and then push it
to them at some point in time.
So that's one use case.
Another use case would be a web application where a client is making a request from the browser.
So the request comes to the server and on the server in the back end, the Java object would be created
for that particular request.
And the Java object would be converted into XML, and that XML would be passed back to the client's
browser, where a JavaScript would pass that XML and display the data to the user.
So that's another use case.
So XML is used as a data exchange format, but more recently, JSON is being used in the last few years.
It's being used more commonly because JSON has a more compact format.
So this is one method and it has all these parameters, like the idea of the book, the title, the
rating of the book as be like code.
So if be here as Facebook.
So if that book has any likes on Facebook, so the number of likes on Facebook and if it has been retweeted
on Twitter, so this number indicates that we count.
So just some social data, it's not actually important here.
So within this method, we have this class.
It's a local class because it is defined within a method and it looks just like any regular class,
but defined within a method.
So it has all these parameters, the same parameters which we have seen for the method.
And it also has a constructor because it's just a local class like any other class, and it can have
its constructor.
So as we mentioned, a local class would have to be instantiated within the method.
So we are instantiating it here.
So we are creating a book object and the arguments passed to the method are here.
So these are the method parameter variables.
And the five parameters and we are converting it into XML.
So let's not worry about this piece of code.
It just takes a Java object here, the book object, and it converts it into XML.
The process of converting a Java object into XML or into any other format.
Normally it is referred to as marshalling and extreme.
Here is a third party library.
It comes from this company called ThoughtWorks.
So Extreme is a third party library which is being used here.
Even Java JDK also has something called Ajax B, x, b, it can also be used, but the problem with
that is that the class itself, the nested class, has to be a static member class.
It does not work with local classes and that's the reason I had to use this extreme.
So extreme is also the JAR file is available in the resources and the center code is also available
in resources so you can download and test it out on your end.
So here the writer object is there and it would have the XML data and it is simply converting it into
two string and returning it.
And we have the main method here.
So the main method we are printing the XML string that is that is being written.
So we are invoking the book as XML method and we are passing the data, some data.
It's not important here and we are printing the retained XML string.
So let me run this.
So as you can see, it has all of this data XML string here, book ID title rating, FP likes count
and tweet count and all of this data has been passed here.
The rating, the the counts, the social data and a book object has been created and it has been translated
into XML.
Now the reason we are using a class here, a local class here, because it doesn't make sense to define
it as some other nested class within some other nested class outside of the method.
Because if you are doing that, it means that you would want to reuse that particular nested class.
In this case, we do not want to reuse it.
It's only the scope of this particular class is only within the method.
Now we might have other methods also like get movie XML or get web link as XML and stuff like that.
So they will have their own classes.
But if there are multiple methods which are which are going to share a particular book class, like
for example, we have this get book as XML, let's say we have a method called get book as JSON.
Then those two methods can use the same class, in which case we can use a non-local class, a non-local
nested class, like a static member class or a non static member class.
But here, since the scope of this class is only within a method, so we could make use of a local class
here.
So that's one use case where we can, we can use this.
So that's about it.
So we have seen how a local class can be used and all of the data is available in the resources section.
And thank you and happy coding.