Hi there.
This is Lulu.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at the new data API, which was introduced in Java eight.
This new API is represented by a package called Java Time.
We will first discuss a bit about the core classes and then later in the subsequent lecture we will
see them in action in the demo.
First, let's do a quick recap of the limitations of the Legacy API.
Many of the things that can be done with the new API are also possible with the legacy API.
And so it is important for us to be very clear about the limitations of the old API and how the new
API is going to address them.
Since we are going to learn about the new API which is going to replace an old API, it is important
for us to know what the limitations of the old API are.
All right, we need to know what old API is bad at and how the new API is going to address it.
One of the limitations is that a date in the old API would include both date as well as time components.
So if we just need only time without the date, then it would not be possible.
Similarly, if we need only date without time, then that is also not possible.
Now, even if you create a date instance by specifying only the date components like year, month and
date the date instance which is the Java date instance, would still include time by default.
It is just that the time components would be initialized to zero, so it would be zero, 4 hours, minutes
and seconds.
Next.
We know that that year component in the date class has the confusing offset of 1900.
Right.
And we also know that the range of month is 0 to 11.
And this is also confusing and it applies to both date as well as calendar classes.
Next, the confusion is around which of the two classes to use.
That class is still retained for backward compatibility.
So if the developer is not very familiar with the legacy API, then he or she might be confused about
which of the two classes to use.
And the classes in the old API are mutable and so they are not threats if.
So Java eight introduced the new data API and it is in the new package called Java dot time and it was
inspired by the third party library called JIRA Time, which we briefly discussed earlier.
And many of the features from our time are actually integrated into the new API.
In fact, the Time website itself suggests us to migrate to the new data and time API.
Performance wise, it seems that the new API is faster than the time API in many areas and also the
new API should also be faster than legacy API.
Note that time was mainly used by programmers who are not happy with the old legacy API.
It was also discussed earlier that the new API is based on the ISO 80 601 calendar system, which is
what the civil world uses today.
And it is same as the prolific Gregorian calendar in which the current rules for LEAP years are applied
for all dates.
But if you need accurate historic dates, which predate the year 1582, which is when the Gregorian
calendar was introduced, then this calendar would not be suitable.
Next.
Most of the classes are also immutable, so they are safe.
Finally, there are no public constructors.
Static factory methods are used to construct date and time objects.
One example is a static factory method named off and we will look at it in our demo.
In fact, the very first item in the effective Java book recommends us to consider using static factory
methods before considering constructors.
If possible.
Later, we will briefly look at the advantages of using static factory methods.
And here are the most commonly used classes and you can find all of them in the Java package and very
soon we will do a demo in which we will use all of these.
Now first one here is the local date and it represents a date in the ISO 8601 calendar system.
It doesn't have either the time component or the time zone information.
Second is local time, and it represents only time in the ISO 8601 calendar system.
So it doesn't have either the date component or the time zone information.
Next is local datetime.
And as you may guess, it includes both date and time, but not the time zone information.
So it is a composition of both date and time.
Fourth is zone datetime.
And this includes everything that is daytime and also time zone.
Under is similar to the Gregorian calendar class in the old API.
First, this instant class and it represents a single instantaneous point on that timeline and it can
be used for recording things like event timestamps.
This class is analogous to the date class in the old API, so even that class represents a point on
the timeline.
So it doesn't appear so.
But date class actually represents a point on the timeline.
And using that point on the timeline, date class returns the different components like year, month,
hour and so on.
That is, there is a conversion from the point on the timeline to date and time components that are
understandable to humans.
And all these classes implement an interface called Temporal, which is part of the package Java dot,
dot, temporal.
So these classes are inside the Java Time package.
Well, the interface that they're implementing is part of a sub package called temporal.
And the interface is named as temporal as all these classes are actually temporal objects.
Right.
In other words, temporal means there is the concept of time involved.
Later you can check out the common methods that this interface defines.
It has some methods such as plus, minus and so on, in order to adjust the temporal objects.
Now, this temporal interface also extends another interface called temporal access.
And this interface includes only read methods as the term access and temporal access suggests.
And there are also two other commonly used classes called Duration and Period.
As the names imply, these classes represent an amount of time.
For example, duration represents duration between two points of time.
Write to events on the timeline.
So it would be duration between two instances of the instant class period.
On the other hand, represents interval between two dates.
So period is something which is associated with date.
For instance, if you want to compute age of a person, you would consider the interval between the
current date and the person's birthday.
So period is associated with date while duration is associated with time.
Now as these classes represent the amount of time both of them implement an interface called temporal
amount, which is also from the Java time dot temporal package.
And here is the date time format in ISO 8601.
So we have date followed by the character T, which is then followed by time, which is in turn followed
by zone offset.
And here is an example here.
The date is July 3rd, 2017, and the individual elements of the date component are separated by hyphen.
Time is 1 a.m. and the offset from GMT or UTC is minus 7 hours, which corresponds to Los Angeles area
in the United States, which is also referred to as Pacific Time.
We can see that the elements of the time component are separated by columns.
So the separator is hyphen incase of date while it is colon in case of time.
Now, if you print an instance of the zoned date time class, then we get such an output with all the
information and we will look at this later in the demo.
If it print an instance of local debt, then we get only the debt part of the string.
And if you print an instance of local time, then we get only the time part of the string.
And if you print a local date time, then both date and time are included.
Finally, here is another example and this represents the UTC time itself.
In this case, instead of an offset, we have the character Z at the end.
So Z implies UTC or GMT.
So that's the ISO 86014, Matt and Java eight, and we need to be aware of it.
Otherwise it could be a bit confusing looking at such kind of a string.
So that's about it.
And we looked at the code classes in the new API.
Next we will do a demo and we will look at all of them in action.
Thank you.