Hello there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's look at something called build process.
A build process is, simply put, the process of translating our source code into compile code.
And that's nothing but the compilation process.
In the last lecture, we saw that this compilation process was happening automatically and instantaneously.
We saw that as soon as we were saving our source code, that source code was getting automatically compiled.
So that's the build process.
And even before we were using Eclipse, we were doing this build process.
Only thing was, it was very tedious.
We had to open our command prompt and we had to execute the Java command manually.
So that was very tedious because every time we made our changes in the source code, we had to execute
the Java command.
But with Eclipse, it is being done automatically and that's the cool feature of using an ID.
So in this lecture we are going to learn about Bell Process.
Now, before doing that, we will also discuss about how to use multiple versions of Java with an eclipse,
and that will lead us into understanding Bell process.
And we are going to learn about a few concepts around Bell process, like the Bell Path and something
called Bell Tool.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So this is the Hello World Program.
We were using Java 14, so because I had Java 14 here.
Now let's go ahead and add an interface.
We still did not discuss interface, but interface is something like class and it will be discussed
later.
But for the sake of this discussion, let's go ahead and create an interface.
So this is the Eclipse Test Project and this is the Eclipse Test package which has this dot java file.
Hello, world class.
So within the same package, let's create an interface.
So I have right clicked on the package eclipse test and new.
And here we have this thing interface right beneath the class.
So click on that.
Let's just name it as test I for interface just to keep it simple.
And here in the interface, let's add something called a private method.
Private methods are allowed in interfaces only from Java nine onwards.
So that's an let's just call it as a test with an empty body.
So that's that.
So this is there from Java nine and since we are using Java 14, so there are no issues in terms of
compensation.
Now let's assume that this is your you have let's assume that you have just joined a company and this
is some test code that you're writing.
But let's assume the company itself is using an older version of Java, and let's assume they're using
Java eight, which means that you also have to use Java eight for your projects.
So let's go ahead and install Java within this eclipse.
So for that, just go into Windows.
So we are going to add.
Java eight into this.
So here we have all of these options.
Just click on Java here, drill down and there is this option called installed git.
So here we can see the JDK 14, which is already there.
So this is what is being used for launching Eclipse two.
So here we are going to add a new one.
So click on Add here standard VM.
Just see next and we need to select our JDK.
So click on directory.
Now, here I am.
In my C dry program files Java and this is where I have all of these different Java versions.
So I'm going to select this JDK 1.8.
There is also Java eight, but I'm going to select this JDK 1.8 here folder and next thing is hit finish.
It got added.
Now select this one JDK 1.8 instead of JDK 14.
Now say apply.
Now here it says by default the check git, which is nothing but this one is added to the build path
of newly created Java projects.
Build path is something I'm going to discuss in a bit, but it is essentially the class path.
But the key here is it says it's going to be added to the build path of newly created Java projects.
So this is an existing project.
So this will apply only for new projects.
That's what this message says.
So that is done.
Now, another thing that we need to do is this is installed git.
Now right here we have something called compiler.
So here we need to specify that we want to compile using a compiler compliance level of eight because
right now it is using 14.
So which means that it is using like a Java compiler which comes with Java 14.
But we want to use this 11.8 because that's the Java version that which that we just installed that
we just added.
But the thing to remember is this compiler that Eclipse is using is a different compiler.
It uses its own compiler called Eclipse compiler for Java.
So just keep that in mind.
Now hit apply.
It says we will do a full rebuild.
And later, I will explain what that is and just hit.
Yes.
So we are done with that.
So it is now added.
Now let's go ahead and add a project.
So let's say you are dealing with code that does some credit card processing transactions.
So which means that let's create a project for that.
Say New Java project and let's just name it a c p for credit card processing.
Here it says Use Default, Java, JDK 1.8, which is what we just added.
Right.
And once again, this is the same one.
Create separate folders for sources and class files.
Hit next.
Now here, if you recall, when we were using JDK 14, this option was being selected and we unselected
it or D selected it, but now it is grayed out because it is JDK eight and this is to do with the modules
feature which is not there and Java eight and older versions of Eclipse.
You wouldn't even see this option, but here it is grayed out.
So we are good.
So just click finish and the project got created.
And here let's add a new package.
Right click.
See package.
My company name and let's say test.
That's good enough.
Now what we will do is we'll just copy this one Test II, which is an eclipse test.
So this eclipse test is using Java 14 and this is using Java eight.
Just copy it, say control C and click on this package.
Name the new package we created and just say Control V.
And you can see that test I got added here and it has its own package.
So that's one way in which you can copy files from one package to another.
But we are having the compilation error because Java eight does not support private methods, private
methods within interface.
So interface is here.
It has its own keyword.
So that's the thing.
Now, as part of this company, if you want to test something using some latest features, you can always
use this package.
But for your company, you can write here.
Now, let's assume that after some time your VP comes up VP Vice President, or your manager comes up
and he says that we want we should migrate from Java eight to Java 14.
So for that, what we will do is we need to change to Java 14.
So for that, what you can do is just click on SIP here and right click and it will show all of these
options that are specific to this project.
Now here you can go into this thing called as build path and select Configure Build Path.
Or another way to get to that screen is click on this properties and you will see this Java build path.
And here under libraries.
So we have this thing JDK 1.8, which is what this project is using.
And just remove it and let's add a new library.
Click on this one.
Add library and it says Git System Library hit next.
And here earlier it is using 1.8 click on alternate JIRA.
So it gives us two options JDK 14, which is and JDK 1.8.
We want JDK 14, so hit finish.
Apply now.
That's not enough.
We also have to set the Java compiler, also compiler compliance.
Here it is.
So change it to one point.
214.
If you see that this is grayed out, then click on this one.
If you click on this, sometimes it may be grayed out.
So you if you click on this, then it will enable you to change it.
All right.
Now, once again, say apply.
It says we'll do a full rebuild, which is good.
And that's it.
It's done.
So the compilation error has gone away because we are now using Java 14 now.
All right.
So that's how you can use this.
So now it's time to talk about the process.
So this is how this is what we did.
Another way was to get here using this build path.
So this is the Java build path.
And Java build path is nothing but the class path.
So when we are compiling in the traditional way outside of Eclipse, so we had two things.
One is the Java Java compiler and the other one is the class path environment variable.
Right.
So that is what is used to locate class files like the third party libraries or any other packages that
we are using.
So similarly for Java, build path is similar to class path.
So here under the source tab, we are saying that the source code is here, CP is the project and within
that there is a source folder within which we have our source code.
So this tells the compiler where to find the source code.
Similarly, there is this libraries tab and here don't worry about this module path and it is related
to the modules concept.
Now here we are saying that we are using JDK 14 and we may also have other Java files that we may use.
For instance, we may be using some third party libraries and those third party libraries in Java.
Like if you are using a Java library, the Java libraries will be packaged as Java files.
So you can add those external jars.
For instance, if you are using Google go.
It will be in the form of Java file.
Or if you are using some G unit test case, it will be in the form of Java file and we can add those
external jars so that our source code can use them.
So that's the libraries.
And you can also have this.
We also have this project tab, which is telling us that there may be multiple projects, especially
if you're dealing with like complex software, you will have multiple projects.
And the SIP, the credit card processing project might be using some other project code.
So we are saying that we also want to use code from that other project.
So this is essentially telling us what all our source code needs, the source code that is residing
here, what are the things that it needs?
It needs certain libraries and certain projects within our eclipse.
So that's the class path, the Belle path.
And for compilation I said that we are using this eclipse uses its own compiler.
So for class path we have built path and for compiler we are it is using its own this its own compiler.
That's the Belle process.
But the Belle process needs to have a certain tool to actually perform this compilation and that's called
as a build tool.
And Eclipse uses this build tool called US Java Builder, which is a class in Eclipse.
And this Java builder uses the build path here and it uses the compiler and generates the class files,
the compile code.
So that's the Java builder.
And in professional, when you are working on professional code, you will also be using other builders
like Maven, which also does the does the building for you.
So this is the Java builder.
So let me just say a plant close.
Now, the Java builder here, if you're going to project here, we have this option called build automatically.
So the Java builder is essentially building our code in an automatic way, which means that it is compiling
automatically.
So as soon as we save our file, make a change and save our file, the build tool will automatically
compile our code.
But it's not going to compile all of the files that we have written, but it only compiles the ones
where we have made the change, the file where we have made the change.
So in that sense, it's going to compile in an incremental way.
So for instance, here we have this warning also here.
So let's me put a pen statement and here I, I still did not save my file.
So if I go into hard drive here, so I'm here under did eclipse test is the project within which we
have the bin folder and bin has this eclipse test package.
And here you can see that the timestamp is 1220.
Now here let me save it.
And it changes to the current time, which is 1230.
So as soon as we saved the build tool has recompiled this particular class.
So it is doing it in an incremental way and in an automatic way.
And that's the cool feature of Eclipse.
Now, sometimes you might want to do a full rebuild.
So full rebuild as you're going to project and click on this option called clean here and it says whether
we want to clean all our projects, if you say clean all projects, then it is going to delete all of
the dot class files and recompile the source code.
So it's going to regenerate the class files.
So here we can see that it is 1230 right now and this one is still 1220.
So let's go ahead and simply say clean and it will rebuild everything.
So that's the process of rebuilding and that's it.
You can see that both of them have to all 31 So the old files were deleted and a new dot class files
were generated.
So that's the full rebuild.
If you see some issues, sometimes you can do the project and clean and do a re full rebuild.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I will see you in the next lecture.