Hello there.
This is the Motley Crew.
And welcome back.
We now know that platform independence is one of the key benefits of Java.
But before understanding how Java achieves platform independence, we need to first understand what
platform dependency is and to understand platform dependency, we also need to know what compilation
is.
Compilation is a very fundamental concept in computer science.
And if you are new to programming and not completely sure about what compilation is, then this short
discussion on compilation should be very helpful.
But if you are already familiar with programming and clearly understand what compilation is, then feel
free to skip this lecture.
Let's start with absolute basic concepts of a computer.
Every computer has a fixed set of instructions that it understands, and collectively they are referred
to as the instruction set of a computer.
So the CPU would understand these instructions, and a computer program is made up of some of these
instructions.
That is, the instructions help a computer program to perform something meaningful.
Each instruction tells the CPU to perform certain action, and each instruction is basically a sequence
of zeros and ones.
That is an instruction has a binary format.
Such instructions that computer understands is called as machine language.
That is the language which a machine understands, just like the way we humans understand our languages.
Machine language is also referred to as machine code and is sometimes also referred to as native code.
And here is an example machine instruction which performs additional operation.
The six digits on the right specify that it is an ADD operation.
Now a computer program would involve many such instructions.
And obviously it would be very frustrating for someone to write and also read such instructions which
have only zeros and ones.
So it's very cumbersome and it's got to be simpler than this.
So computer scientists came up with another language called assembly language, which was much more
easier to read and write.
And here is an example to add to numbers, which is much more expressive than the machine code.
So assembly language provides certain higher level notations for writing instructions like AD in this
case.
But computers understand only machine language.
They do not understand assembly language.
So there's a program called assembler that translates assembly language instructions into machine language
instructions, which a computer can understand.
Both machine language and assembly language are referred to as low level languages, and that's because
they use low level details of a computer.
One example would be specifying the memory location where we are storing data.
But writing programs, even in assembly language, is still tedious.
So programmers wanted programs to be expressed in a more easier way.
And they also wanted to hide low level details.
So in time they came up with high level languages and some example high level languages include Fortran,
C, C++, Java and C sharp, and they use English like words like public, private and so on.
Mathematical notations like plus and minus and punctuations to write programs.
So they are much more easier to write and read, as we will see in this course.
And here is an example Java program.
As you can see, it uses English words like public and addition operation here, using the symbol plus
and a punctuation here in the form of semicolon.
And of course, they also hide low level details of the computer.
So today we mostly use only high level programming languages.
Assembly language is not used very much and is used only where performance is critical, like in the
case of operating systems of electronic devices.
And in terms of terminology, source code is the term that is used to refer to any code expressed in
a programming language.
So source code is nothing but the programs that we write, like the Java program that we see here.
And many times in this course, I would be using that term source code.
Now, like in the case of SM, the language source code cannot also be understood by a computer.
So we need to translate source code into machine language.
And that's where compiler comes in.
So the translation from source code to machine code is done by this program called Compiler Machine
Code, which is the executable program is then executed directly by the CPU in a separate step.
So compilation and execution are two different steps.
First compilation is performed in order to translate source code into machine code, and then separately
the machine code will be executed.
Now note that in this illustration we are calling the translated language as target language and not
machine language.
That's because in some cases it may be something else too.
For example, in the case of C or C++, target language would be machine code.
However, in Java case it is Java bytecode, which will be discussed later.
Sometimes target language can also be another programming language.
For example, closure script is a language and it comes with a compiler which compiles closure script
programs into JavaScript, which is a different language.
Such compilers are also referred to as source to source compilers or trans compilers.
Source to source because it is converting one source code into another.
Source code.
And there are some core operations that a compiler performs.
And let's see what those are.
Verifying syntax and semantics of the source code is one of them, and this ensures that the source
code complies with the rules of the programming language.
For example, a program is made up of statements, and in the case of Java, every statement must end
with this semicolon.
So that's a rule of Java programming language.
And if a statement doesn't end with a semicolon, then the compiler detects it as a syntactic error
and reports it to the developer.
For example, here is a statement in Java that prints the text.
Hello.
And as you can see, the statement ends in semicolon.
And if we omit the semicolon, then the compiler reports it as a syntax error.
Semantics is about meaning.
For example, in Java we write our programs as classes and the class can also have something called
a subclass, which is just another class, but a specialized version of the original class.
But if it declare the class with a keyword called final, then the compiler ensures that the class cannot
have a subclass.
So if we happen to define a subclass, then the compiler reports it as an error.
So that's how the compiler is ensuring that the semantics associated with the final keyword is being
respected.
It's not being violated.
Compilers also perform certain code optimizations for faster execution of the program.
Certain compilers do that.
And finally it generates machine code from the intermediate optimized code.
So the optimization is done and then the machine code is generated from that.
A compiler is a very complex program and these code operations are basic operations that any compiler
supports.
And as you will see in this course, a Java compiler performs tons of additional operations to ease
the programmers task.
So the compilation process can be slow due to the complexity in translation.
However, once compiled, machine code execution will be very fast and the machine code can be executed
any time and any number of times.
But any change to the source code requires complete recomposition.
Next we will look at platform dependency, which will also give you an idea on how a C program is compiled
on Windows and Linux machines.
We're not going to write any code for the discussion, but towards the end of the chapter we will write,
compile and execute our first Java program.
So in this chapter we will write only one program.
But as the course progresses, starting from the next section, they will write lots of programs.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And next, we will look at platform dependency.