Hi there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
Often when working with Lambda expressions from within our lambda expressions, we would like to access
variables from the and close scope.
That is the scope in which the lambda expression has been defined.
Sometimes the scope can be a local method in which the lambda expression has been defined, or it can
also be the class in which we have the lambda expression.
So from from the lambda expression, we would like to access variables from the and scope so it can
be a local variable that is defined in the and closed local method.
Or it can also be an instance variable or a static variable defined in the same class.
Right now, if it is a local variable defined in the enclosed method, then the rule is that then there
is a constraint that the variable has to be effectively final, which means that the value should not
change.
Now if you recall, we discussed this in our nested classes chapter when discussing anonymous classes,
and the same constraint also applies here.
But I think it's better to discuss it one more time because it is very important and it will also kind
of refresh our memory.
So let's go ahead and implement that and see that in action.
So this is the same class from the previous lecture.
So we had this go method.
So here, let's go ahead and declare a variable called count.
So this is a local variable.
Now let's create five threads over here and we will try to access this variable.
So this is a threat and we need to pass the work.
So we need to pass an instance of renewal.
And we know that Learnable is an is a functional interface and we need to pass an instance of that.
And so here we can define a lambda expression, which would be an implementation of the run method.
So the run method does not accept any parameter.
So you can have an empty parenthesis, then the arrow symbol.
Now let's just print the value here.
The value of coal.
So this is just an expression here.
So that's the body of the lambda expression.
So here we are accessing the variable count, which is a local variable and the enclosed scope.
Now this is called as capturing of the variables.
That's what they call it as.
So that's the terminology they use, capturing off variables.
And in doing so, we refer to a lambda that is doing this, or even an anonymous class which is doing
something like this.
We refer to it as a closure.
Now, if you dig deep into into lambda expressions or anonymous classes, if you read more about it,
you will definitely run into this term called S closure.
So just wanted to highlight that term also, which is commonly used in books.
And so this is what it is, but you cannot do something like this.
So as you can see, we are getting a compilation error because this has to be a final.
This has to be effectively final.
And so that's the thing.
Now, we also demonstrated this and when discussing about anonymous classes, but with anonymous classes,
the Java version that you might be using can be even Java seven or even before that.
So in that case, if you want to access if it is a Java seven or anything before that, then the variable
has to be declared with the modifier final.
But if it is Java eight, it is fine and the anonymous class can directly use the variable without the
modifier final, but it's got to be effectively final.
So the value of count should not be incremented anywhere, whether it is in the anonymous class or whether
it is even here.
You cannot even do this.
So that's the anonymous class.
We have seen that in the Anonymous Class lecture, too.
So this is kind of a refresher.
And so one good use case, why it is done that way is through this example itself.
So here we are having count and we are launching five different threads and the count variable is being
passed.
So the developer thinks that this count variable is being shared right now.
Now, because these are all five different threads.
So it may it may also happen that the go method might finish its execution before these threads run
to completion.
So in that case, GO would be popped off the stack and there will not be any count variable.
Now, if that rule does not hold where the where it need not be effectively final, then it can happen
that the count is incremented here.
Then in that sense, this count also should be incremented.
But then the method is popped off the stack and there is no count variable.
Right.
So the intention is not clear over there.
So that.
So.
So because of that.
So the language designers wanted to keep it simple and so they ensured that this has to be effectively
final.
So that's way that's one way of looking at it, where within this thread the count is incremented.
But the another way is, let's say, for example, if we increment count here, then we also have to
find all of these threads and increment the count.
So it's all complicated.
So to keep it simple, they wanted the the variable, the local variable to be effectively final.
So that's the thing.
And we call it as capturing of variables now.
But let's take another example.
The insert discount variable here can be an instance or a static variable to.
So let's define another variable called global.
Let's make it static.
Static here, because this method is static.
It's just call it.
Let's just make a copy of this.
And this is fine.
So this is fine.
So in this case, it's a static variable.
But had this been an instance method, then we can also access an instance variable.
But it's just that from the static method we cannot access instance variables.
So this is fine, but still this is not good to do because the reason for that is because it's not safe.
We have different threats and the different threats are sharing some data or sharing some mutable data.
And because of that, it is not threat safe.
So you should not be doing that.
Now, with regards to this one, we are saying that it cannot be modified, but we can do a small trick
here and we can cheat the system.
And one way of doing it is.
Let's create a variable and object here.
So for it, let's call it list.
Integer.
So this will hold integers.
Let's call it a trick.
Okay.
Now.
Let's put a body here.
Now let's say we'll set trick dot add.
It's declared a variable temp and it's a trick.
Dot get.
So this is essentially our current value.
Now let's set track set.
So as you can see, we are just incrementing the count value in an indirect way.
But you should not be doing that.
It's not right.
But so that's one that's a trick that you can play in order to increment something like count.
But you shouldn't be doing that.
And the second thing I want to say is now, as you can see, here we are, we are able to pass a list
here, an object.
And we are we are able to do something like this, but we cannot reassign trick to some other some other
ArrayList because it has to be effectively final.
Since it is effectively final with regards to an object, it just cannot be reassigned.
But you can invoke other methods like ADD and things like that, and you can mutate the state.
But once again, it's not threat safe, so you shouldn't be doing that.
So it's just that in terms here, also it is effectively final.
Just keep that in mind.
It does not mean that it's only with primitives, but it is.
It also holds good for object references.
But with regards to object references, it just means that we cannot re assign to a different object.
That's about it.
But you can still mutate the state within the within the object, but it's not safe.
So you need to take certain measures to avoid any unpredictable outcome.
So that's the thing.
And so that's about that.
And we also discussed all of this when discussing local anonymous classes.
Now, one other thing is about about a variable scope itself.
So if you recall, we know that local variables cannot be shadowed, shadowed in a nested block.
So, for example, if you have a loop here inside the loop, you cannot really clear.
For example, you cannot do this.
Right.
You cannot do this because count is already declared.
So we cannot shadow a local variable.
This was discussed and that also applies to.
That also applies to low to lambda expressions too.
So for example, let's say there is a functional interface called consumer and we will discuss it later.
But consumers like this.
So this needs to be assigned a lambda.
So consumer just has a single method called accept.
So it takes a single parameter.
So this would be the method parameter count and we can have an empty body here.
But the thing is, it's giving us a compilation error because we are essentially re declaring the variable
because it's a parameter, it's a method lambda parameter.
So we are really clearing the variables.
So we are trying to shadow this variable and as we know it cannot be shadowed, local variable cannot
be shadowed, so it need not be.
This rule applies to nested blocks and also lambda expressions now.
Instead of that.
So we can have something like this.
But here we can also we cannot even do that.
Okay.
So I think this is pretty straightforward, but the important thing is you cannot even do this.
So that's the main, main important thing to keep it, to keep in mind, because this is pretty straightforward.
Now, if you recall from our anonymous classes, we said that no, not anonymous classes, but in the
nested classes chapter, we had a lecture on variable scope and we said that a variable with ten nested
class, like an anonymous class or a local class there you can shadow a local variable.
So the shadowing of local variable is not possible in in methods except for nested classes like anonymous
classes or local classes that are declared within the method.
So for them it is an exception.
So just to refresh our memory, let's also do that.
So let's say new thread.
Okay.
And.
Start.
Let's implement a renewable.
So here you can.
Do this.
And so there is no compilation error here.
So just some syntax error.
So that's the thing.
And just to refresh our memory, while we cannot do this right, it's got to be effectively final.
So within the lambda, within an anonymous class or a local class, you can shadow a local variable.
Now, one last thing I want to say is now within this.
So let's just take this.
Within a lambda you can use.
This reference.
And if you do that, you can it means that we are using the this reference of the enclosed method.
So in this case, we are getting a compilation error because this thing here is a static.
So we just need to make it an instance.
So only then we can use a this reference and now we are good.
So we are accessing the global variable.
We are at this reference.
So here this inside this lambda expression, it just means that we are using the this reference of the
and closed method.
So that's all there is about this variable scoping and capturing off variables and that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.