As mentioned earlier apart from check the captions we also have something called unchecked exceptions
.
So a program can generate either checked or unchecked exceptions the whole thing check exceptions.
But let's do a quick recap of it.
We know that there are costs by exception of situations that are simply not under our control.
Examples would be things like partners or were being down our database being unavailable.
If you do it checked exception the compan I've got on it is two things.
First is you must announce that you're throwing the exception by specifying it in the method declaration
using a gross gross and second is the invoking code must acknowledge the exception by wrapping the calling
card in a cricut rock or just in done really the exception for the next higher level method to handle
that next is unshaped exceptions and these are generated by either programming frost or due to some
internal system writers like out-of-memory others and if they're caused by programming flaws then they're
referred to as the runtime exceptions.
But of their culture in general system adder's then they're just referred to as adder's since runtime
exceptions are due to programming at all.
You want them to happen mostly or double up on testing time.
So ideally with good development and testing effort you would want as minimal runtime exceptions as
possible.
It there's a GBM deleted under normal conditions and they occur rarely and when they do occur the Jell-O
program terminates Generally you shouldn't catch on on time exceptions as there are due to programming
errors usually the recovery from such exceptions is implausible and continued exaggeration would do
more harm than good.
But sometimes you might want to catch them too.
One example would be when you're parsing a response from a web service you encounter a problem parsing
some piece of data.
For instance format of a date field might have changed in this because when you try to parse the date
field you may get an unchecked exception.
So in this case it would be worthwhile to cast the exception and let the web service provider know about
it.
And of course you should seriously run them not to change their API.
And with regards to errors since there are some abnormal conditions a reasonable application would not
be expected to catch it.
So you would almost never catch an error as the name implies these exceptions are not checked by computer
that you can store them anywhere.
And the compiler does not bother checking whether or not they are specified in the method declaration
or whether or not they are handled by the invoking code.
So that's entirely optional if you want to you can specify them in the declaration and you can also
handle them but it's not mandatory.
And so it is entirely up to you shortly we leave them off unchecked exception.
They have to look at runtime exception.
We would not look at error as if it is really an abnormal condition and we said we don't want to handle
it in almost all cases.
But if you'll recall we did just that and out-of-memory error in one of them was in JVM in dentals chapter
so at least we have seen an editor being gender Did anyone offered the most on here as exceptions in
Hedican street and the route you have trouble plus that is a superclass of all exceptions are Natters
and it has to Sampras's exception I never it it crosses represent errors that were just part of unshipped
exceptions.
No exception class has of surprises on one of them is runtime exception runtime exception under subprocess
represent runtime exceptions that are also discussed as part of unshipped exception.
As you can see all unshipped exception classes are emphasized in red but all checked exception classes
are emphasized in book so checked exceptions are all exceptions that are represented by a label or one
of its surprises with the exception of error or runtime exception or one of their surprises.
Not get the convention all across all that a person being at odds and with that text editor all of that
exception classes acceptable.
And with the next exception know this light also illustrates all that commonly uncontained checked and
unchecked exceptions.
Let's quickly review most of them.
We are really not him or them or the Iowa exception which is a checked exception and all its subclasses
are related to input output errors like reading from or writing with a missing phone or a server that
is not responding and you already know about null pointer I'm at a Nick sort of bonce exceptions both
of which are unchecked exceptions a legal argument the exception is an unchecked exception and it is
thrown when the method is passed an illegal or an inappropriate argument legal next see this exception
in our table Glasgow's exception is an unshipped exception is thrown if it tried to cast an object to
suppress but the object is not really an instance of this obvious number for me the exception is thrown
if we try to convert a string to a numeric type but the string does not have an appropriate format.
For instance we get this exception if we apply integer not parsed in method on a string like ABC next
non-class for Nader is an unchecked exception and it is a subclass of error and it is drawn when classloader
Kreisler the definition of a class A no definition could be fun.
Have a lower class definition existed when the class was compiled.
But it can no longer be found for some reason.
Finally we already know about out-of-memory error which is a subclass of Woodrell machine at a JVM throws
it when it is unable to create an object of insufficient memory.
So those are the most commonly encountered check done unshipped exceptions and you can also read more
about them from the API.
Let people pull up the AP I could just show you where you can find the exceptions.
And here is the API I and here are all the packages on how clicked on the dollar package.
And here you can see all the interfaces within Jodan package and also all the classes here.
If you scroll down at the bottom you can see all the exceptions and also the on the ruler the dollar
package has.
OK so next let's just go ahead and let's look at the demo of unchecked exception.
Could demonstrate an exception.
Let's just go to our next hour Senator Vijender I'm unsure that's a option.
Illegal argument exception.
And as mentioned earlier this exception will be gender if the mother is involved with an illegal argument
.
For example this method has the parameter destination whose value should be either 0 or 1.
Now the sentiment that is in work with any other argument value other than zero on one then it would
be illegal.
And we can generate an illegal argument exception for that.
OK.
So many times methods and constructors have such restrictions on the arguments and arguments that are
going to be passed on such restrictions on cardless preconditions.
And in order to enforce such preconditions we can do some parameter validation at the beginning of the
matter.
OK.
So let's also do that let's also enforce a precondition in cyber if statement here at the beginning
of the matter and destination value is either less than zero or greater than one.
Let's throw an illegal argument exception
and this one is from the July-August Lang package and since it's an unchecked exception you can see
that there is no compulsion at all here.
So we need not to specify it here but if we want to we can do that.
And similarly there is no compulsion at all here.
In fact here we have polymorphic types so let's remove that because they will catch that exception.
So now we have only two exceptions here and there is no legal argument exception here just fine because
it's an unchecked exception so owners just go ahead and document this particular exception because the
Klan's hopla know about it.
So will say it throws
so this exhibition will be generated every destination is less than zero.
Our destination is greater than one.
So anybody in this method will have to look at this API and they can see that if they pass this kind
of a value then it could be considered illegal and an exception will be genitor head knowledge just
as umed duck here.
The programmer was careless and he did not read the API documentation.
Unsensible you off minus one Sananda just go ahead and exude your does.
And as you can see an illegal argument exception has been generated.
OK.
So that's an unchecked exception.
And generally we should run out such exceptions because they are programming flaws.
And it's not good to catch them so that's about it and that's it.
I'm off on two exceptions.
Thank you.
Happy coding.