Hi there.
This is the to the book genre we saw was the top level, but it can also be nested within a class or
an interface.
If an enum is generally useful, you can make it a top level one.
But if you think it has some context, that is, if you think it makes sense to make it part of some
class or interface, then it can be nested.
Here is our book Genre Enum, which is now nested within a class called Book.
Now we know that Enum is basically a class, and since here it is nested within another class, it would
be a nested class.
In fact, it would be a static asset class.
It cannot be an inner class as inner classes cannot have static members while an enum can have static
members.
Right.
Recall that an inner class includes the three nested classes other than static member class.
Remember that there would be an anonymous class or local class or non static member class.
So a nested enum is implicitly static.
So it cannot also access instance members from the enclosing class, just like a static method or a
static member class.
Now, since book genre is a nested static class on compiling Java, it will produce two classes, books,
class and book dollar book genre class.
Recall that this is what happened with nested classes in bytecode.
There were no nested classes.
They simply get translated into top level classes.
Not to access an item constant like horror.
We would do book dot book genre dot horror.
Since Mr. Denham is implicitly static.
The next question could be Is there any difference between a static member class and a nested enum?
The difference is that a static member class is intangible, while a nested enum is not intangible.
Finally, note that an enum can be nested within another enum and that another enum can be a nested
enum too.
Or it can be a top level enum too.
I believe such nested ness would be really rare.
Similarly, a static member class can also have a nested enum.
However, an inert class cannot have a nested enum, as nested enemies are implicitly static, while
inner class cannot include any static stuff.
Now let's head over to our editor and convert our ebook genre enum into your nested enum should be a
very short demo.
Look, here is a book genre enum from the previous demo and let me show you the My Explorer.
So on the hard disk we just have book genre dot class.
So this is the only class file we have which corresponds to book genre.
Now let's go ahead and let's make it nested within the book class.
Now it gives a compilation error because the file is named as book genre, so we need to rename it.
So let's just say rename compilation unit to book Java.
So insert and let's also insert this main method.
Let's take it out from the enum.
And let's insert it here inside the book class so that we can run it.
Now, let's also look at the file system.
And as you can see, it has created class and book dollar.
Book genre.
Class for the enum.
Now it is a static nested class.
Let's go ahead and run this and it will be the same output as in the previous demo.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And this code will be available in the resources section.