In the last lesson we discussed glassblowing which is a first page in the lifetime offered by a class
or an interface on gender's the corresponding class object which is the input to the next page which
is linking not it's get an in-depth understanding of the linking process linking is the most complicated
of the three stages of the LifeGem effect.
And as we discussed earlier it includes three steps verification preparation and the optional resolution
step.
And let's begin with the verification step the verification step verifies that the Nordic class is not
malformed.
That is it conforms to the Java language to us and this is needed as the class file might have been
lorded from across the network or it could be a user defined class from the local file system itself
.
In either case JVM does not trust those classes as they come from less trustworthy resources.
As we discussed earlier there is there could have been generated by a hostile compiler whose intention
is to perform some malicious actions to Gibeon subjects them through some stringent security checks
through the verification process under the same verification is already done during compilation.
Generally speaking user defined classes are mostly well-formed process but GBM has to stick to its process
.
We know that the classes from Java library are not very fight as they're considered trustworthy and
recall that they are looked at by the bootstrap classloader bytecode verification is done by the component
bytecode.
Once the code is successfully verified by the bytecode welfare only then the code is considered safe
to be run by JVM on it with a log it's execution engine.
The poor form at optimum level as it doesn't have to perform any further security checks.
But if it finds a problem it rejects the malformed class and throws an exception on hit.
For example verification checks that bytecode that performs final process must not be subclassed right
.
Final methods must not be overridden under must not be any illegal method overloading and the final
one ensures that statements like.
If condition does not send the control beyond the methods Bhandari So that's verification nextstep is
preparation and Ixtoc is pretty straightforward.
I look at space post Arctic fields and initialize them with default values.
If there isn't enough memory then an out of memory error will be generated.
Not that if the class is loaded because an instance of it is created then space will be a look at it
.
For instance fields also and they would also be initialized the default values.
However this would be done only after all stocktake fields are initialized properly with the actual
user defined values.
And this happens across the class hierarchy.
We know that super classes will be loaded before the subclasses so all the stocktake fields across the
class hierarchy will be initialized before the instance fields are initialized.
Next is the last step which is resolution and we know that it is an optional step that is it need not
strictly happen after Operation step on it can be performed later after initialization stage.
Now in the current class we typically reference fields on methods from other classes and also interfaces
.
So this step is about resolving those references.
That is to load them so that the current class can use them.
No such references are referred to as symbolic references and symbolic references are nothing but logical
references or symbolic references are stored in one area of the doc class file called Constant bullet
.
If you recall.
We looked at constant pool in a demo we did in the method binding lesson did we used the jalopy disassembler
tool to examine the bytecode and we actually looked at the contents of constant Gwinn.
So you can go back and review that video if needed.
Note that apart from symbolic references constant as its name suggests can also include constants such
as compile time constants and stringless in the resolution step.
The referenced classes are loaded into memory and once they are loaded into memory their corresponding
symbolic references to the current class will be replaced with direct references to their actual locations
in the memory so that support resolution is about this look at an example here.
Here the box at the top has the source code.
Well the one at bottom shows the corresponding byte order in the source code.
We have a single statement creating the whole object and in the bytecode we can see the corresponding
bytecode instruction and it is referencing an entry in the constant pull and constant pull.
It's like an army and has entries that can be accessed by some in mixed numbers.
So what is the object creation instruction is referencing the entry at the index number two within the
constant pull on this entry is interned affronting the create index number 19 which basically is a symbolic
reference not at runtime.
GBM creates an internal notion of this constant which is referred to as a runtime constant.
And then the resolution step the component doing resolution would look at the symbolic reference within
Tintern time constant ball and would then load the class handle that is class.
Hello would be taken through all three stages of the lifetime off it would be stored on the heap.
The symbolic reference will now be replaced with a direct reference to that hello instance on the heap
.
And this form of the solution is known as dynamic linking as linking is being done at runtime in certain
languages such linking is done at compile time itself.
And does it refer to start acting uninstructed linking the contents of the reference file or copied
into the final executable.
No advantage of dynamic linking is that you can make easy objects that is replace a class file with
a more newer updated class.
However the software would also cease to work if updates are incompatible.
For instance in the new class file it previously available method might be missing on the class might
be referencing that method and that JVM would generate an error.
Note that this resolution of symbolic references in the current class happens only once.
There is a symbolic reference maybe a reference from multiple locations within the same class but that
reference would be resolved only once.
So if Hello instance is created at multiple locations in the same class then it is resolved only once
and thereafter the direct reference is used not dynamic linking.
Can happen in two ways depending on the JVM implementation.
It can be either to be either loading or we are lazy loading.
If it is either loading then it means that resolution happens right after the operation step.
That is all classes are referenced by the current class will also be loaded which means that they get
loaded on initialized before the current class is itself initialized.
So they are loaded upfront.
That is they are eagerly loaded.
If it is lazy loading then it means resolution is postponed to a later time after the next stage which
is initialization to be more precise when missing a later time.
It implies to the time when the statement that includes the reference is actually executed so at that
point the reference is loaded on demand and the symbolic reference is replaced with the direct reference
.
Typically DBMS implement lazy loading and that's because you don't have to load a class until you're
really needed.
Sometimes certain statements may never get executed and so there is no point loading the references
appearing in those statements.
Finally just note that when resolving differences resolution also ensures that the current class has
permission to access the reference to class a what with regards to freezing other classes.
Resolution ensures that the fields exist in those classes under how to the a type also under current
class.
Once again has the permission to access them as you can see these paths are pretty fiction related and
so resolution does form some form of verification.
So that's about linking.
So once the classes form would be safe.
Next stage would be initialization after which JVM can freely executed.
As discussed earlier initialization step simply initialize a static field.
But the actual user defined initial values.
Earlier they were initialized with different values.
If you recall one thing note about initialization was with regards to interfaces.
Interfaces will be initialized only if one of its documents is accessed or one off its fields.
That is a non compile time constant is accessed.
That is a field is initialized via a method or a constructor under is initialization and so we will
not be discussing it any more.
So that's about it.
Next we will be a demo of the lifetime effect.
Thank you