Hi there.
This is Lou.
And welcome back.
Now let's do the demo of the new data and time API.
In the last lecture, we looked at the core classes in this API and now let's see them in action.
So here we have the date time demo from the previous from the previous demo and this class was introduced
in the package comp semantics squared date time.
So now we are going to add this new method called test date time API.
So this is for the new API.
And here this was the last method that was added in the previous demo test legacy data API because we
were looking at the Legacy API.
So this is going to be the new API and we are going to explore all the classes that we have discussed
using for use cases which are very realistic.
And the four use cases are here.
Like the first use case is software renewal.
And this was also used in the previous in the previous demo.
So here we are going to set an expiry date of the software and we will see how the expiry date can be
extended.
So we are going to look at the local date class for that and we will see what methods we can use.
And here, some of the code is already written because there is a lot of code to show and it would be
very time consuming.
So in the interest of the time some of the code is there and on some code we will be writing in the
demo.
And the second use case is the game start time localize to time zone.
So this particular use case was also was also demonstrated in the previous demo.
So here we have some kind of a game and it has a start time.
So this is related to the TV schedule.
So if a user is going to look at wants to know the start time, then we need to show him or her the
start time as per his or her local time zone.
So that's what we are going to do.
And we already we already know about this particular use case.
Third is the age calculation.
So we want to calculate the age based on his birthday, his or her birthday.
And the fourth one is interval timing, which is about measuring the interval between two events.
So for that, we are going to use instant class and duration and for each calculation we are going to
use period and also the local date.
So let's go ahead and start with the first use case for the software renewal.
So we are going to use the same example that we have seen earlier.
So we want to use local date here.
Now we know that these new classes do not have constructors.
So we said that there are static factory methods that we need to use and one of them was the off method.
So we will say off and it's an overloaded method.
So we're going to use this one.
2017 and the month was June.
So there is this enum called Month within the Java Time package and we are going to use that and we
are going to select June here and the date, let's say 38, which was the same date we have used earlier.
So let's see that and.
Sprint this.
I'm here on this.
So.
So it prints the date here.
So the date and the ISO 8601 calendar system.
So that's the date.
Now, let's go ahead and extend this.
And now let's add eight months to this.
So there is this method called plus months.
We can use that.
All right.
Now, this one is going to return an instance of local data.
We know that all of most of these classes are immutable classes and hence are safe.
So we are the expiry date is not going to be adjusted.
So that instance is not going to be updated.
But it would return a new local date with the new time, with the time, which is eight months after
this particular date.
So it's going to return another local date.
It's called a new expiry date.
So.
So we get the benefit of threat safety with such immutable classes.
But it would also help us to change classes because it's retaining a local date instance.
We can invoke another method probably if you want to do another minus, you can also do minus, so you
can invoke other methods also.
So we also have methods such as minus days, minus methods, just like plus methods.
So that's another benefit.
You can chain such kind of method invocations.
Now let's print this.
So the new date has been extended by eight months and it's now year two 2018 and the month is February.
But the date has been adjusted to 28 because it does not have 30 days.
So this we have also seen in the earlier demo with the ad and the roll methods the same behaviour.
So it's just the same.
So this is how you would extend the date.
So there are methods like plus months, minus months and so on, and you can use them.
There are also other methods like ease before and ease after in the local date class and you can also
try them out later.
So that's about how we can extend and there are a few other methods that we can check out in the local
date class.
So let's just run all of them and let's look at the output.
Okay.
So the first one here is so we have the new expiry date now, which is in 2018 and we are getting just
the ear component from the date.
So it's printing 2018.
Then there is this month component for which we are using the get month method and it shows February.
So the get month is actually returning the month enum.
So it's going to print that.
Then there is this get day off month, which is 28.
That's another method.
Then there is this method called get day of week and it's printing Wednesday.
So day off week is going to return another enum called Day of week.
So day of week and month are to enemies and.
Here.
This one is printing.
Is invoking this method called easily peer.
And it's just checking whether it's a leap year or not, whether 2018 is a leap year or not.
And it is false.
And we are also checking the length of the current month.
Since the month is February.
There are 28 days.
So that said and here there are three other methods which are which are going to do the same, like
get the year, month on day.
But we are here, we are using a different method called get earlier.
It was get here, now it is get and it does get for a month also.
But we need to specify the component that we want to extract.
In this case, we are saying we want easier and in the second example we are saying we want the month
of the year.
So the output is going to be the same, but it's just a different way of extracting those components.
And here for the component we are using.
An enum called Chrono Field and we are using that and we are passing this value here.
So all of these are also printing the same values like year again, 2018, month again two and day of
month again is 28.
And here we are showing how to parse a string.
Sometimes we have strings and we need to parse them.
So the parse method is going to return this and here this is the apex here.
So we are passing 1970 0101 and we are also showing the ear.
So we are just invoking the get here component here and we are printing it here.
So that's with that.
So that's what the first use case.
Now the second use case is about the game start time.
So here we are creating an instance of local time and we are once again invoking the off method.
So the off method we have seen earlier, it was where we create when we created the instance of local
date.
So local time also has the off method and we are just passing hours, minutes and seconds and.
We are creating one more instance of local date for the game start date.
So we are saying local date off and it's 2017, July 3rd.
So this was the date that we have seen in the previous Demo two.
And next is we need to create a local date time.
So we have the local time, local date.
We need to create a local date time.
And here is how we will do it.
So it will be local date.
I.
It's called game start time.
Once again.
The typical auth method and here let's pass local date which is this.
So we are passing local date and local time in order to construct the local datetime.
So now let's go ahead and print this.
Right.
So here it is.
So the time is nine and the local start time is this one.
So okay, so it's going to print the, the entire thing, the date followed by the character.
T We have seen this format earlier in the lecture and that time.
So that's where the local time.
But we need the time zone, right?
Time zone is what we need is important in this use case.
So let's say we have this.
So we are creating an instance of zoned date time because it has the entire information, it includes
the local date time as well as the time information of the zone offset.
So once again, we are invoking the method and it is taking we are passing this instance of local date
time here.
And we also need to pass the.
We also have to pass the.
The time zone.
In this case, there is this class called a zone ID and we are calling the off method and we are passing
the time zone and four time zone.
Let's actually pass a different time zone.
So Europe.
So let's initialize with this.
And this is what we have.
Let's print this.
So this is the time zone and we have already seen this in the earlier lecture.
So it depends everything.
So the time is nine and it is one hour ahead of the UTC time and the time is Europe slash London.
Now let's go ahead and let's say the user is from India and we want to show him or her the time according
to that particular time zone.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Now there is this method called width zone, same instant it's called zone, same instant.
There are also other methods, but we need to use this.
So it's going to be same instant.
So it's going to use the same time, but it's going to adjust the time, the local time with the new
time zone.
So we need to use this zone ID of.
Okay.
So zone ID is in in the previous demo or API, we had this time zone, so it's a replacement for that.
And let's say it's India so let's the value we need to pass as Asia slash.
Calcutta.
So here it is.
So it's the date here and the time is 130 in the afternoon.
So five and one half hours has been added to the UTC time.
UTC time is actually eight and although here we have nine because there is some daylight saving time
around and around that time in July.
So that's the reason we have nine when we have the time zone as Europe and London, but the time at
the UTC at GMT, the GMT time is eight.
So five and a half hours here.
This is the offset that has been added which resulted in this time and this is just the time zone information
that is getting printed.
So that's with that.
So that's how we can adjust the time now if we change it to Pacific Time, let's do that also.
So Pacific Standard Time and here.
Needs to be underscore.
So here it is.
So minus the offset is minus 7 hours.
So if you remove that from eight here at GMT, then we get 1:01 a.m. and that's what is being printed
here.
Now, one small thing I want to change is if I change this.
Two GMT.
Here.
The string is like this offset is there and we have this now it's being changed to GMT and as discussed
in the lecture.
So we have if you say GMT, we will have this Z that gets printed instead of the offset.
So that's.
One thing now.
So that's that.
So we are done with the second use case.
And the third use case is about each calculation.
So here once again, we are creating local date.
So we are instantiating these values.
January 1st, 1978, which is the birthday of one of my close friends.
And we are also invoking this method called now.
And this would return the current date from the system clock of the computer of this computer.
So we are invoking this method called now and this is the variable is today.
So next here we are invoking this method called until on this instance of birthday and we are passing
this that today instance to this particular method and it will return a period.
And all we need to do is we can just print this period here and we can also get years and it would return
the age of this particular person.
So if you do this, as you can see, when we print the string, it is printing in this format.
So I guess P would stand for period.
And this is 39 years, six months and 25 days.
So you have characters for following those numbers.
And if you need only the age here, we can just invoke this method called get years.
So that's how you would compute age.
So if in your website, if you are going to capture the user's birthday so that birthday can be stored
in the database and if in the UI, if we want to show the age of that person, we would extract all
these individual components like the year, month and the day, and we would build an instance of birthday
and then we would also get the current date and we can show the age in this way, in the, in the browser,
in the UI.
And next is the final use case, which is integral timing.
So here.
So here we are first getting using this class called Instant.
We discuss this class in the lecture and we are once again invoking this method called now, which would
return the current instant instance of a current instant of time.
So it would be a time on the timeline.
So it is it is the time.
So it would return that.
Here it is.
Obtains the current instant from the system clock.
Now so that's the start time then.
Test Legacy Date API is the method which we have written in the previous demo, so we want to see how
long that method will take to execute.
So here we are getting the end time and end time would be instant.
Now.
Once again, and we need to get the duration of this so we can do.
Something like this.
So we are going to use the.
So off, this formatting has been messed up.
So here we have the start time.
We are doing instant and now then we are invoking the method.
Then we are getting the end time.
Then we are invoking this class of this method called between in the duration class.
Earlier we looked at the period class which is associated with dates, and this one is associated with
times.
So when we are passing the start time and the end time and we are getting the duration and we are invoking
this method called two millis, so which returns the during the duration and milliseconds.
So let's run it.
So it's going to take only ten milliseconds to execute that method.
So that's how you can time the interval.
But the recommended approach for this is to use system dot.
So in the system class.
Nano time.
So there is this nano time.
It's recommended to use this approach.
If you want to capture such kind of if you want to measure the the time that a method, a method takes
to execute, then it's recommended to use something like this.
The start time you would do the same thing with the end time also.
So that's what is recommended because it's much more accurate and it has been it has been defined just
for that purpose to capture the elapsed time.
So if you want to do that, you are recommended to use the nano time and there are also some partial
classes.
These are two examples.
So here this class called Month Day, which is also from the time package, it represents only month
on day information.
It models a date which has only month on date.
For example, if you want to capture this information like Christmas, then you could do something like
this and once again you would use the same method and you would pass the method, the month and the
date.
And this is how you would capture the month on day, month and day in this way.
So you would use this class and the next one is another class called your month.
So this was month day and this is your month.
And this particular class is useful to capture information such as credit card expiry date.
Now if you look at credit card expiry dates on your credit card or debit card, you have only one month.
They don't specify the date, that date.
So for that, you can make use of something like this, this kind of a class.
So this is just for your information.
So these are some partial classes because they have only partial information.
So that's about it.
So those are the main classes and you should also check out the API for other classes.
But these are the core classes which you would be using most often.
So let me just show you the API also.
So here it is.
So this is the API, the eight Java eight API, and these are five different packages, Java time,
Java time, chrono dot format, dot temporal and dot zone.
And we looked at some of these classes.
This is the Java Time package and these are some of the classes local date, local date time, local
time zone date, time zone ID period here and state.
So these are some of the classes which are which we have already seen.
And we also looked at this month enum and day of week enum and if something goes wrong then these classes
would be normally throwing this exception called as.
Date time, date, time exception.
So this is what you will see.
So you can go ahead and explore this.
Explore this and the instant class.
If I click on instant, it has a lot of information.
Much of it was already discussed.
So some theoretical information is here.
So if you want to, you can click on instant class and read about it carefully to get more in-depth
information, some of which has already been discussed in the earlier lecture.
So instant class has this information because it is a point on the timeline.
So I guess that's why they have a lot of information here.
So you can take a look at this class also.
So that's the API and that's about it.
That's the new date and time API.
And those are all the core classes which you'll be using.
So and all of the, the demo program will be available in the resources section.
Thank you and happy coding.