Hi there.
This is the room.
And welcome back.
In the last lecture, we looked at the database design for our three year project.
And now it's time to materialize that database design, which means that we are going to create that
database for our project, for our three year project.
One way was to use the forward engineering approach from the Meyer SQL workbench itself, and we have
seen an instance of that, but we will not be doing that and we will manually create all our tables
and populate them with the data.
And for this, we'll be using SQL queries.
And the data that we are going to populate is simply the data from our project, which so far was being
read from text files.
So we are going to migrate the data from text files into our database.
Now official statements can be classified into two categories.
One is the data manipulation language which is in short referred to as DM ML.
And the other is data definition language, which in short is referred to as DDL.
Now, as the name implies, queries that fall under data manipulation language are responsible for manipulating
the data which is already there in the database.
So you would have queries for doing things like retrieving of data, inserting new data, and updating
and deleting of existing data.
So select insert update and delete statements which are shown.
Here are what would be used.
Now data definition language, on the other hand, as the name implies, is all about defining the data
which we are going to store in the database.
For instance, we would describe the data type information for each of the table columns.
Similarly, we would define the integrity constraints, like the primary keys and unique keys in our
table.
We can see the type of statements that we can have under all of these.
Create table and alt table are probably the most commonly used ones.
Now typically DDL queries are executed directly on the database server instance itself.
That is, they would not be coming from your Java programs.
However, the DMS queries are typically executed from the programs itself in response to some user actions,
and for that the GBK API would be used.
In this particular lecture, we will mainly look at create table and insert statements.
So let's just go ahead and start creating our database.
Here is the text file in our project.
So we are going to migrate this into our database.
Similarly, we have movie and here it is.
So we have user and web link.
So all of the data from these files will have to be moved into our database.
So and here are all the commands that we are going to execute.
So these commands will help us create the database on the tables.
So let me just go ahead and open the my SQL Server instance.
So one way we know is to go here and to start and my SQL here.
So it has a workbench and also the server 5.5, if I click on that.
So this is a command line utility.
So instead of using this, let me just use it from the command prompt itself.
So let me just search for CMD.
Now to connect to use the minus client.
So let me just say.
This is how you're going to connect as a route user.
So we are now connected to the server instance.
So we just need to.
See what all databases we have in the server instance so we can have more than one database.
So here are some of the databases that are already there.
If you recall, the JID underscore test was the one which we created earlier in the earlier lecture
and we used the forward engineering approach in order to create this table.
And here information underscore schema is it comes with my SQL itself and it holds information about
all of the other databases.
So it kind of holds the meta information about all other databases.
So later, we will also look at this in one of the queries.
Now let's go ahead and create our new database and let's call it as the JID underscore, trivial.
So it would be the command would be create database, JID underscore trivial.
So let me just copy this.
So it's create database and the database name.
Now, if we want to drop this database, we want to delete it.
So all we will do as.
And that's it.
It's dropped.
But we just want to create it.
So let me just recreate.
If I say show databases it will we will see that it's created here underscore trivial.
So now we need to get into the database and start creating tables.
So we will say use.
That's what we have to do.
ID.
So now we are inside the database and in order to see all the tables, we can execute this command.
Sure dbus.
But since we don't have anything, it's empty.
Let's go down.
So the first thing that we will be doing is we are going to create all the book related tables like
the book publisher and author.
So this is nothing bad.
So this is the these are the tables book publisher, book author and author.
So we are going to create them.
Okay.
So the first statement here is create table author.
So we are going to create author and the column is ID.
The first column is ID and it has a type of big end.
And big end is like long, so it occupies eight, eight bytes.
Now it is a primary key.
So we have to specify it this way.
And we are saying that it is auto increment and the second column is name and it has a type of watcher
with this 200 here indicates that we can store it max 200 characters for the name field and it has to
be not none, which means that we cannot store any null values.
Now here, auto increment implies that when we are inserting the data, we don't have to insert any
value for ID it will be automatically inserted and for each new row the value will also be automatically
incremented.
So it will be one greater than the value inserted in the previous row.
So it starts with one next it will be two and so on.
Same with publisher.
We have ID a name, publisher name and we have some columns for book.
So here I have listed some of the common data types.
So for Integer, so these are the different data types that we have tiny in small and medium INT and
big end.
So big end was the one which we have used now.
Big end is like eight bytes and tiny and takes only one byte.
So this is like the byte in Java.
Small end takes two bytes.
So it's like short medium, it uses three bytes and uses four bytes.
So just like in Java, big end is like long.
So it uses eight bytes.
So but in reality, I think mostly it will do.
But if you are working on some web, on some website which has millions and millions of millions of
records, so it's really very popular website.
Then in that case, you can go for Big End.
And for here, the second data type is decimal.
It's a fixed point and this you will use for monetary calculations.
So it's kind of like big decimal.
And the third one is floating point.
So it's just like in Java float and double.
Now to represent strings.
We have one chart which we have already seen here and we have CAD also, but convert is like fixed line
strings.
So if you set 200 then it will always be every value would have a length of 200 even if you don't if
the value does not have so many characters.
So if it has only one character, then the rest 199 would be padded with space.
So that's the car.
So you would want to use car when you are storing some fixed length strings, like for states.
For states you can have abbreviated notation.
So let's say two characters or let's say for postal codes or zip codes.
In some countries they call it zip code and some other countries are postal codes, so they may have
a fixed length of five or something like that.
So, so for that you can use car and text is just a pure text if you want to store something like that.
So blob and text are for, for large values, for example, for images or something like that.
You can go for Blob and for dates.
We have these different types and we are going to use date time here.
Date is only date.
Time is only time.
Date time has both date and time and times.
Time is also like date time.
So we will be using date time here and this link has all the different data types and it describes everything.
So it comes from the my SQL.
So that's with this.
So we have author, publisher, book table.
So in all of these tables we have the ID field as the primary key.
Now here, this is a book title and it has a max of 500 watcher and it's not null.
Then the publication here and this is a publisher underscore ID.
So this one is actually a foreign key which is referencing the ID and the publisher field and that we
are indicating it here.
So we are saying foreign key of publisher underscore ID, which is from this table and it references
publisher ID, field and publisher table.
So that's what it means.
And all of these are separated by commas here, as you can see.
So that's with the publisher and obscurity.
Next one is book John Ray.
Now let me go back to our project.
So here book genre enum is there.
Right.
And these constants in constants have an associated audience.
So this is zero.
This one has one, two, and so on.
So we are just storing the ordinal number directly in the database.
So we are not maintaining a separate table.
So you can think that this in itself is the table and the ordinance.
You can think of them as the ID values in that table.
So this is the kind of style that we are using in this project.
So some developers do that or some other in some projects they actually maintain a separate table called
book underscore genre in the database, and they have all of this stored there.
But here, I think we can use this.
It's fine.
So let me just go back.
So that's with the book genre.
Underscore it.
Amazon rating is double.
Kid friendly status is tiny end, which means that whether it is kid friendly or not.
So we are just using tiny end and create a date.
So whenever a new record is created, we wanted we want to keep track of that time of the date and the
time when it was created.
So we are calling it as created underscore date and we are using date time for that.
Now here we are specifying a unique constraint.
So this would be a candidate key and we are saying that title publication underscore here and publisher
underscore ID together would uniquely identify error.
So that's one of the constraints.
So you have this keyword called constraint followed by unique, followed by one or more columns.
And so then we have the book underscore author table here.
So book underscore author table maintains the relationship between book and author.
So you have the ID book ID authority and book ID as a foreign key and it is referencing the ID field
and the book and author underscore ID references, the ID fill in author.
Right, we know that.
And we also want the book, our underscore ID and author underscore ID to be unique.
So so there is a unique constraint here that we are defining.
So that's a book underscore author.
So let's just go ahead and create this table first.
So it got created.
Now, let me create let me just run all of these together.
So three more tables got created.
Now, here, this is how we insert values.
So first we are inserting values into the table.
So the statement as the query syntax is like this insert into followed by the table name which is author,
followed by the number of the columns into which we want to insert the values.
Since ID is auto increment, we don't have to include that.
So it would be name and values and fourth string.
It has to be in like this and single codes.
So this is what we have.
This is the first author.
This is the second author.
This is the third author.
And we can also insert more than one authors in a single statement.
So this one is for that.
And we are inserting the final author so we can insert we can club all of them together in this way
also.
So that's possible.
So let's go ahead.
And this data is exact data which we have in the text files.
So they are done.
Let me also run both of these.
Okay.
So we are done with inserting the data into the authors table.
And if you want to view what data we have, you have to use the select statement and START means that
we we want to see the entire data in the table.
So we want to see all the data that is stored in this table.
So we are saying select star from the table name which is author.
So let me execute that.
So it has it says it has a truce.
So these are the ones that got inserted.
So next is these fi into publisher.
Now here you can see that O'Reilly here has a single quotation within the string itself.
So for that reason, we are actually enclosing this in double quotes instead of single quotes so that
we can also retain this value.
Otherwise, we will have an error.
So let me just copy this.
So we're done with inserting files.
Next is the book table.
So here we have all of these values publication here, publication risk for ID and Amazon rating.
Okay.
So on here.
This is what we are entering.
One publisher, 1854, and here this is the publication.
Let me look at that.
Your third one is the publisher underscore ID and the.
And it says one here.
So this is a publisher underscore it, which is referencing the publisher field.
Right.
So it has one.
It's a foreign key.
So this book is referencing the first publisher.
And here this value is actually the genre information.
So it has a value of six.
Now if you see here, it has a book genre which is coming from the enum.
So if you go back, the book is actually the genre is philosophy.
So philosophy is here.
So it's zero one, two, three, four, five and six.
So that's what we are.
That's why we have the value six here.
And the rest of the stuff is straightforward, like the rating kid friendly status.
Kid friendly status is two.
And the last one was created date.
And for that we are using this function called now and it will insert the date and time at this point
of time whenever this query is going to be executed.
So that's all there is.
So these are the different five, the five queries that we have.
So let me just run them in one go.
So these are all the values.
And you can see that here in the last four created date, we have the current date here.
So similarly for the book, underscore author values are here.
So typically when we have the books in the database and we have some author information and when we
are inserting, sometimes these values can be inserted from the application itself.
But in this case, we are doing it here.
So book underscore it and author underscore it.
So let me just insert that also.
So these can be.
These are such kind of data can be created from here, I think, but sometimes they are created from
the application itself.
Say, for example, if you are getting this information about books from some from third party resource
like a web service, we can grab that and we can, you know, we can execute similar kind of queries
from our Java programs.
So we have this and as you can see, the ID field got incremented automatically.
So that said and these commands, they just show that if you want to delete a particular row, you can
use this.
So from the book underscore author, we can delete an element a row like this.
So we are saying book underscore ID is equal to five.
So we are saying delete that particular row.
So let me just do that also just so that you can see.
Okay.
So as you can see, the last row got deleted which had the underscore ID as five.
So let me reinsert back.
So it's insert into book on the score author and it's five comma eight.
So that's with that.
So we are done with the books now.
So these are the these are the tables for movies.
So you have similarly you have actor, director, movie and.
This is what we have more we underscore actor, movie, underscore director.
So movie underscore actor will capture the relationship between movie and actors and movie underscore
director.
And so we once again have foreign keys.
So it's exactly identical to that.
And we are also inserting the values here.
So it's very similar to what we have for authors.
So let me just create all of them in a single go.
So we're done.
Next, we have a Web link.
So you can take a look at them.
I'll make these files available for you.
So it's all smooth execution.
Next we have user table and the values for that.
So user you have ID, email, password, first name, last name, gender ID and user type ID.
So these are coming from the enemies created date once again.
So every table has this created date.
And here we are saying that email is unique.
This is what it is because emails are, of course, unique.
Because their use being used as for logging into the system.
So let me just create that.
So we are done with that.
So basically we are done with all the queries here.
We only queries that only tables that we need to create are the user underscore book and user underscore
weblink.
So those are the bookmarks.
So when we are bookmarking these items, then we want to have these tables.
So in one of the subsequent lectures, we will create these tables and then from our we will refactor
our project code in order to populate these tables from the project itself.
So as the code in our project is getting executed, these tables will be populated.
So we are not going to populate these tables from using these queries in a similar in a fashion similar
to this.
So but we will actually populate the data from the program itself.
Now, the final thing that I want to show here is.
Some information about my school itself.
My uncle has something called storage engines.
Now, storage engines determine how MySQL stores data and which features are available.
Now there is this command called show engines.
It will show you all the.
Engines that are present that my supports so they call it as storage engines and the two most commonly
used are my ism and ODB.
ODB is the default one and it's been default since my SQL 5.5.
And prior to that the default was my ism.
So within ODB it supports foreign keys and also transactions.
Transactions are nothing but a group of SQL statements which will be executed as a logical unit of work.
So they'll be treated as a single piece of work.
For example, if you one example is let's say you want to transfer some money from your checking account
into savings account, then you would debit from your checking account table.
And we would have to credit that into the saving accounts table.
There are two separate tables and we want that to happen atomically we don't want to do debits here.
And then if if there is an error, then you don't want to leave your database in that kind of state,
right?
So it's like using synchronized keyword.
So we want to make multiple statements to execute atomically.
So it is all of them have to be executed successfully or if not, none of them will be executed.
So something like that.
So that's transactions and DB supports that.
My exam does not support that and my ECM does not even support foreign keys, but it does support something
called full text search.
So if you have if you want to build a search engine or something like that for your data for for some
parts of your data, let's say we are storing some documents, text documents in your database and if
you want to support full text.
So my sign will support that.
So that's a feature that comes with my some which is not there with inaudible.
So that's what my SMS.
But typically for full text, you will use some library like solar instead of relying on this because
that's.
We're way more popular and lot of big sites use solar and here.
Let's execute this.
So here we are looking at the different engines that the different tables that we have in this in our
in our new database did underscore trivial.
But we are using the information schema database, which I specified earlier, and we are invoking a
table in that database called tables and we are saying, show me all the tables and the engines also.
And we are saying that the I, I want to get this data for this better information for only the GD underscore
trillion database, which is the current database.
And we are saying show me all the tables in this database and also the, the the storage engine that
is used for those tables.
So let me just execute that.
So here it is.
Here these are all the tables that we created.
And by default, since it is in Oadby, this is what we have.
But let's say we want to create a new table which uses my sum.
So for that we will just specify after the parenthesis will say engine equal to my sum.
So let me do that.
So now you can see that for test a it is my exam for all the other tables, which is A.B.
So let's drop it.
So that's all there is.
And if you enter exit here, it will exit out of the my SQL.
So that's the last command that we have here.
That's it.
So that's all there is for this lecture, and I hope you like that.
So this is how we can create our database.
And we will also be creating a few more tables and one of the subsequent lectures.
Thank you and happy coding and see you in the next lecture.