Hi there.
This is the de la.
And welcome back.
Now it's time to extend our project.
In our project, we use few constant exporting classes.
Book John Ray and movie John Ray are two examples.
Now that we know the advantages of enemies, let's go ahead and convert those classes into enemies.
So this is a three year project.
Source.
And here we have the constants.
So there are five constant exporting classes.
Now this is book genre, gender, and for three of them kid friendly status, movie genre and user type.
I have already converted them into enemies, so we will take a quick look at them.
But first, let's go ahead and convert these into enemies.
And these three are also very similar to them.
But we will still take a quick look at them.
So first, let's look at book genre.
Here is the book genre.
Let me do a control shift G just to see where it is accessed from.
Now book genre.
So let me go ahead and just make it into Enum.
So the first thing here has to be the enum constants and these are the constants, so we need to convert
them.
So first, let's knock this off.
From here.
Let's replace all.
Have.
Open parenthesis.
Let's be smart about it.
So we are done with that.
Now.
Let's take this piece.
Okay.
Let's do that.
Replace all.
The only thing is, we need to convert this.
This.
So we are done with that piece.
So those are the constants.
This needs to be double codes.
Okay.
So that's it.
And here, let's call it name.
So that's the actual name.
And let's introduce a private variable.
And let's have a better.
That's it.
So we are done with this.
Okay.
So now let's go ahead and make our changes.
Here is one.
So this is book John Drake's philosophy.
This is the kid friendly, eligible method.
And here we have this variable genre.
So let's see.
It should be a string.
So we are now supposed to convert this.
So this is a book, class book to Java.
Okay.
So let's go ahead.
And so it's one of the entities make it.
John.
See.
This is.
Genre and setter.
Butch Andre.
So we are good with this.
Now here.
So this is the create book method.
So let's go here.
So in the create book.
So this is book genre.
And this has to be John Right.
So this is in a bookmark manager class.
So there is this method called create book.
Which creates instances of book.
John Ray.
Okay.
So that's imported.
No.
Now here there is some compilation error in the data store.
So let's go here.
It's load box.
So here we are passing.
This is the one.
So here we are.
Here we are loading.
So this is the data store class and we are loading the books.
And if you recall, we were loading the data from the file.
And let's open that file here.
So here is the genre.
So the genre is here and it's a string.
And in the datastore class we are reading that and we are passing that string.
But the method is expecting a book genre that is the enum type.
So we need to convert this into that.
So one thing is we can make use of.
The value of method.
And we know that the value of method takes the name of the enum constant and returns the enum constant.
Now.
But the problem here is.
If you look at this.
The name that we have here is it has the title case.
So it's philosophy.
But the P is in caps.
But here.
Philosophy is in all caps.
So in the value of method, it would be expecting this.
Now we have these values and these values are mainly used for for let's say, for display purpose.
But the actual constant name is this.
And it is better to represent the name, the name over here.
And the when we are reading this data, it's better to represent it using this name.
So this is the name of the constant as it is declared.
And this one is just for the display purpose or for for some other purpose, mostly for display purpose
in the UI.
But this is the actual internal representation, because if we use this name, it's going it's not going
to return the constant.
It will throw some some exception.
So only if we pass this value, then it would work.
So let's just make that change here.
Let's call it philosophy.
This is also a philosophy.
And the fourth one is technical.
Fourth and fifth are technical.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Okay.
So that's the thing.
Now, let's go ahead and just run this.
Since we made this change, I don't think there are any other compilation errors.
So it's loading the data from the files.
And it's also doing bookmarking.
So I hope you'll recall how the how the soft how the application is working.
So we are done with that.
So we have successfully converted book genre from a class into Enum and we know the benefits of Enum
and it's good to have Enum.
Now let's go ahead here.
This is gender.
Let's do the same thing.
But here it is using this value of zero.
It's an int value, so zero, one and two.
So we will also do the same thing and we will have a new constructor here.
So first, let me remove this.
Let's make this enum.
So here we have semicolon.
It's needed.
Let's call it as value.
Here it is.
Load users.
So this is type mismatch.
Okay.
This is this has to be gender.
Now we are good.
Okay.
Create user.
The should accept.
Gender.
So it was an internal pattern.
Now.
Importing it.
And this.
As a user.
No, Java also has to be changed.
This guitar also has to change.
Okay.
So that's it.
So let me just rerun this.
Just to make sure that it's working fine.
And it is working fine.
So we are done with that.
So I have done the same thing for movie genre too.
So this is the movie genre.
It's already converted to Enum.
And these are all the things.
These are all the enum constants.
And just like book genre, we have this constructor which is taking name and we have the name here and
we are having a getter just like the book genre.
So four movies also we are reading from this file.
So it has been changed into the constant names here.
So this is the only change from what we have seen earlier in the earlier demo of the project.
So I'm going to upload these four files that we file and the book file in the resources section, and
we also have the user type here.
Here it is.
So that's also converted to enum and it also uses these values and user dot text from where we are reading.
The data is also changed to user user editor.
So these are the enum names.
And the one other thing was this kid friendly status and that has been changed to get friendly status
and then the variable name is still name.
So wherever there is name, we are just having it as a name and get a name.
So that's about it.
And so go ahead and make these changes.
And when you convert them into enemies, you will definitely see some compilation errors.
So you can go ahead and fix them just as we have fixed for book genre.
Book gender and gender.
It will be pretty straightforward.
You just need to keep changing the types from int or string into the corresponding enum type.
That's about right.
And thank you and happy coding.