OK let's not write them off on a list.
So in the last lesson bilabiate brought another list is an buter looked at few methods from the list
interface and also in this class.
So in this demo we'll be looking at all of those methods and we You'll also look at a few methods from
the collection interface which is the root interface.
So for this demo I have created this new package called Comdex semantics credit collections and I have
also created a new class within that package called list them all.
And within the this demo class we have this method called us our deadliest demo which we are going to
fill in this in this demo.
So we are going to write some code here and it's a pirate's topic matter that is invoked from the main
method.
So we're going to write some code.
And we also have some code that has already been written.
So that is done in the interest of time.
So when we get here we'll be just looking at the court and we'll just run the program.
But before doing that we will write some code here.
So let's go ahead and first let's create an idealist
.
OK.
He had the name of the artlessness list one and here that referenced this collection which is an interface
and we have created an Adela's OK so we should always try to program plan interface.
We know that because if you do that we can easily change the implementation.
So if we want to use linguist all we need to do is change this to a linked list and collection interface
since it is the root interface.
It gives us the maximum generality.
And we know that these facts are related to generics.
So let's not worry about it.
But for now it would suffice to understand that since we have integer here in between the stocks it
means that it's an other list of India.
So this list this particular analyst can store only integers.
So if we try to add any other object other than an integer then we get a compiler error.
Now if you want to Ardelia's to store to store on these strings then we simply have to change just a
string.
And if it needs to be double we just change it to double.
So in that sense it is genetic.
So the idealist can store anything any any particular object and all we need to do is do this through
of genetics notation we need to indicate the kind of objects that we want to store.
And that's the reason why it is Carlist genetics.
It makes our Clausius genetic to distort anything anything that we want.
So that's about it for now with regard to genetics.
And we will discuss it when we get there.
But all that he does.
So let's just go ahead and add few elements to do this or at least
sort of.
I do.
Let's add a duplicate here.
And let's And not since honorless can store both duplicates as well as null.
Let's go ahead and print the elements.
No the mirror on it.
So as you can see they're distorting all these elements and it can store duplicate as well as other
values.
Now let's go ahead and remove the element at that third index.
This is 0 1 2 and 3 it needs to remove this one.
So let's go ahead and say at least one board read more.
So that element or that third position has been removed.
Now the set list.
So let's do this one more time.
In that case it has to remove the value knowledge since it is at the third position in 0 1 2 and 3.
Now as you can see it did not remove nutten but it removed the elementary.
So the reason for that is because it is due to metal binding.
If you recall our lesson on method binding we said that there is this method signature binding which
happens at compile time itself.
So at compile time the compiler is looking at the reference type which is collection in this case and
collection has this method called remote island.
It has this parameter object.
So at compile time the compiler will try to find an exact match a method with which has the exact parameter
which is an NPR remote off.
And but the collection interface does not have that method.
The removal of a method is present only in the list interface.
Ok but not in the collection interface.
But then compiler sees that it did not find the exact match and method with the exact matching signature
but it found a method having compatible signature.
OK so in that case in the bike code it's going to write that the method that needs to be invoked should
have the signature.
OK I don't mind the JVM.
Well really try to find the most specific method having the signature which is also present in the list
interface in other districts.
So if you don't recall just go back to the coalescent on method binding and you can under the topic
on the method signature binding will explain this.
So.
So that's about it.
So that's the reason why.
So actually even when we invoke up here in the first instance it was not removing the element of purpose
.
But it was actually removing the element 3 itself.
OK.
And the same happened here it remove are the elementary.
Now if you want to make make it are the element at the Toti next door be removed then we need to change
this list.
In fact let's change it to list and that's because the the methods that we are going to invoke math
.
Next we are going to write next are specific to our position specific methods.
So we each have an index number as the parameter on disposition specific methods are specified only
and the list interface.
Now if I run this you can see the non-God to look at which means that it didn't work the method.
This particular mother more off and.
OK.
So that's that's the metric signature of a lot of people in order to understand that how them at their
signature binding works.
So you can go back and refer to that particular lecture and object oriented programming.
Now let's go ahead and write some positions specific methods.
Let's add an element at zero.
So you have a new element here added at zero.
It's.
So that's the I'd mutter that an index here is zero.
Now let's try the set matter.
So let's set the element of zero position with just 10 to nine.
There you go so nine has been added and this method would return the previous elements stored at that
position which would be then.
OK so these are the new elements that we have 9 1 2 and 3.
So those are the items segment.
Now let's look at some bulk operations.
So we know that the collection interface are some bulk methods.
So here it is.
So let me uncomment this.
So it's already there.
So here we are creating a new list.
OK.
In New Collection.
It's called us let's do I've got two elements 9 and three iron from list 1.
We are woking we are invoking the remove all method on list 1 and we are passing listed as the input
barometer input argument.
So we want to remote If list one has both these elements.
We want to remove them from list 1.
So let me just run this.
So we only lost 100 only 9 1 2 and 3.
So list 2 had 9 and 3.
So we have removed the bench.
So we are left with only one and 2.
Now go let's go.
Iron I have one Boulis too.
So let's to had already had nine and three.
Let's also add one to it and let's.
In order to retain All-Met there.
So we'll have more on NEXT is reading all matter.
Here it is written on.
So read in.
All well written all the elements present and list do on that word remove all the remaining elements
.
OK so list one right now has only 1 1 and 2 and a list to list one has one undo unless Drew has a 93
on one.
So the only common element is 1.
So it will retain that and really move to.
Here it is.
So it retained one deleted element.
So we are done with the remote all undereating on.
Let's look at at all.
So let's just go ahead and simply add the elements off list to do list 1
because you can see the three elements mind three and one which were part of list 2 are ordered to list
1.
So that's the ideal method.
And let's also do this.
So this is just pure setting the value.
Enlist one element at indexable they do is reset to two which means that this tree gets changed to sort
of try on it once again.
And here it is here.
The set met there simply returns the search the value at that particular index to do under the previous
element the previous element of the next Wall Street.
So it's district running back.
So you're just printing out that value.
So those are the bulk operations.
And this was just a set operation.
Now let's go ahead and look at some such methods.
Here we are so the first one as the contains mentored and we are just checking if the element one is
present and the last one second is index off which gives the first utterance of the element of the next
number of the first occurrence of this particular element if it is present.
If not it would read and a minus one third one is lost and next off which would give the last index
off the goodness of this element.
So let's run this.
Now as you can see the element 1 is present and the last one and the last one.
So it returns a true here on the index position.
When we do index off it is zero.
But when we do the last index off it gives three because the last element here is one.
OK.
So it gives up in next three.
So those are the search operations.
Now we also discussed a broader range view the sublist method.
So let's also try that.
So range rules just because that's part of the list interface listen.
So here we are calling the sublist matter and we are saying we are asking for a sublist and the element
indexes are the lets us do the two indexes three so it will return only one element Element 2.
Because this is exclusive.
So the the name of this list is list 3.
That's the sublist.
We said that the list 3 when we do a sublist.
This particular list is backed up by the origin of that original idlest which is a list 1.
So which means that any changes that we make to this new list will be reflected in that list.
So let's go ahead and run this.
Here it is.
So in the list 3 Initially it had only it had only the element at index position to know we are setting
it to 6 and we are printing list one here.
So as you can see when we have said the value industry it also got to reflect it and list one on that
particular value at position you got updated.
OK.
Now we are updating the value we are.
I think a value to list three.
Now when we do that it also gets reflected in list 1.
So we're adding it.
The position zero but that position zero is actually the index position to and list one.
So as you can see the elements 7 what I did on the other two elements got shifted to right.
So any change that you'll make in this new list will be reflected in that and that put you in the back
of a list which is the original list which just listed them.
So we have made some changes in the new order list in the sublist.
And that got reflected here.
No need to make some change in the original list and see that it gets reflected in the industry.
So here we are making a change.
We are setting we are resetting the value of the element at position to 8 under to see if it gets reflected
in industry.
So we are printing a history here.
And as you can see the history the value at zero at the position index 0 got changed to 8.
So the change was made in this one and it got reflected in history.
Now let's see if we can I add an element and last one on whether it gets reflected in industry.
So we're adding an element at index position zero in the last one and it doesn't.
So we are we have we just tried to add an element and to list one.
But when we tried to prend the elements of history it did not look.
So we can only make non-structural changes in a just one.
Only then we can access the elements in history.
Now let's say we made a structural change here a structural changes adding an element or deleting an
element and when we do that then if we try to do when we try to access any of them at industry then
we get an exception under System and modification exception.
So anything we can do as analyst one we can or we can set something in that case it is fine but if we
make any structural change in the back array then the new order the sublist will throw an exception
when we try to access any of its methods.
So that's the thing.
But if we make any changes in the in the sublist then it is fine.
We can I'd also be we can make structural changes.
Also industry then that gets reflected in last one.
Okay.
So that's the thing.
Now let me uncommon this.
I think we are just printing the same elements not as it it through the elements of the of the list
.
So we are simply having a For Each loop here.
But let me just Carmen this note.
My read on it.
So as you can see we are just iterating through the elements and I'm just printing all these five elements
and the last one.
Now let's see if element is nine.
So the 11 element minus here the second element.
Let's say we want to remove that element from the last one.
OK.
So we are iterating through last one.
But if the element current element happens to be 9 we want to read more and see what happens.
As you can see we get an exception here.
It's a concussion modification exception.
So and So that element 1 got printed here here and then element 9.
The second element was 9.
It also got printed but if element is nine we are trying to remove it and then it throws in concurrent
modification exception.
So the thing is when we are iterating if we want to remove a particular element during the iteration
then we cannot do it using a for each statement.
And for that we need to use it for that matter which is the subject of next lesson.
OK.
Using an editor to.
We can do that.
And so that we will see in the next lesson.
So thank you.
And this code is available in the resources section for download and you can download our and you can
run it on happy coding.
And thank you.