High there in the last a mile below that how we can launch a thread and also how we can put the threat
to sleep.
Does them up.
We would also look at a few more amateurs that are related to TRX.
So we look at a bunch of things on one of them as how that trade can get reference to its own object
.
So trade is basically an object we know that and we'll see how that thread can get a reference to its
own object.
I can also see how we can interact.
So if you collect multiple tracks how we can name them and we will also see how we can prioritize that
.
So if you have a bunch of threads maybe you want to get a higher priority to certain threats so that
the shed ular the chip you know we will say what those threats of that higher priority.
So we will look at that and also see why we need to look at something called joint OK.
Jain method which can be invoked on text so that we look at that.
So for example I created this class called last track priority demo as one of the main things that we
are going to look at as priorities.
And it has been added in the concurrency package.
Of just go ahead and look at this.
So here we how the main matter.
And there are all statements here let's talk about them.
The first thing is let's look at how a thread can get access to its own object.
Okay.
So at this statement We are basically in the main thread.
So that in itself is a threat.
So here we are invoking thread current thread.
So Dr. Bill Gill reference to Doug to the main thread.
Okay.
So it will give it up to the main thread object.
So let's just go ahead and run it.
So let's not worry about the output.
Let's just look at the statement.
So this is what is getting printed here.
So he's doing credit card and thread Dokdo strength.
So this is just some information here.
So this one is the name of that red market main is done aim of the thread and this is the priority thread
will have a priority and by default it really how it priority off white.
So every thread will get a default part of flight and we look at properties later.
And this last thing.
So there are three entities here.
I mean the priority under threat group but let's not worry about trade group because that group is obsolete
.
No.
OK.
So the right group.
In fact there is an item in active Java is item 73.
It says a white trade groups and trade group is basically an something which is related to security
and it is also related to appliques.
Somehow it did not fulfill its promise and it also has several flaws it seems.
So threat groups is basically obsolete.
And Joshua block and has a heck of a book tells us not to use it.
OK.
So it basically made the names I just tried groups so you can you can group you can logically group
some tracks on perform some activities on them as a group.
So that's some core concept of it.
But if you really need to do something like that there is something called a bull executor's which we'll
will see in the second part of the concurrency chapter.
So if at all you need to do that we can we can use that.
OK.
And we will be doing that.
In fact we will create a group of Thurtell are there so we will look at that later.
But the main thing is we should avoid using correct groups.
OK.
So that's the third group.
And now let's look at here we have two different threats.
We are creating more threats so one is a main threat and we are creating two more threats and we are
setting the name of that threat.
So here this is Beaven which is a threat on D2 and we are also passing the corresponding tasks.
One of them to us is an email campaign.
So this both of these classes implement that honorable interface.
So we will look at that but we are starting the name off the record as email campaign and the name of
the second thread as data aggregator and we can also get their names and we will also look at that.
So why do we want to set names.
So one of the reasons could be the act would be that.
So let's say for example let's take a caller say the caller example let's say there is there are some
Tozan Web sites which we want to run but we only can create hundert tracks.
Let's say our system has certain limitations.
The cause operating system also then place some limits on the number of threats we can create on them
.
So we cannot create more than 100 project or time but we want to crawl around those and sex OK.
Crawling is the process of downloading all of our pages.
And let's say you want to download all the pages and thousand different Web sites every single day.
But we have a hundred correct.
So we will process hundred of search a time.
Now if you want to know which Web sites are being called at a particular instant off line so we can
all this said I mean whenever we are courting a particular Web site we can said Dummy and we can print
the name all the names of all the web search that are being carted at a given instance.
OK so we can print those with a concern so that maybe we'll know that all the active threads and all
the research that are being cut into the garden.
So it's just more of the information for information purpose.
And so that's the second thing.
And we also have to get men now.
The priority here we are saying that set priority here.
There is a different matter.
So 41 we are setting the priority as Max priority on 42.
We are setting it as main priority.
OK.
So basically what is happening is we are trying to influence the should ular and we are seeing that
among the poor wretch trying to give more priority to third line which means that bring it to running
start since both the both of them are and both of them are in an unknowable state.
So by setting this Max priority work on English a juror trying to go higher priority to it.
So that which means that you have to bring it to running state before you'll bring the good running
state.
OK.
So we're just asking for some help but it's all up to Treacher jeweler.
It is very likely that it will lean towards bringing T-1 to running state.
But it's up.
But that is no guarantee that it will do that.
OK.
So it's just there is a higher chance of this to execute before it.
And here we are simply invoking the stock metric and Max underskirt party has a value of can here we
can see it.
Many underskirt party has a value of 1.
And by default if you don't specify anything that is something called not underskirt priority not and
Wadham on that flight.
So that's 34.
And you can set any value that you want between one and then.
OK.
But you have the right we'll give those three constants at least much greater demand Bartie not under
squit property.
So that that's about the stream of debt and we are also having a Penn State rent renting inside Maine
.
And here is the email campaign and here us the data aggregator.
So both of these are to us and both of them have run methods on both of them are simply iterating end
times unpretending the name of that right for instance here we can see that this particular task is
saying thread dog cut and thread.
So which is a feeling and it has been thing done.
Name name of this e-mail company which we have set here here and we are doing the same and we do also
here also did I get to get out also.
So that's what we are doing.
So from that task we are getting the reference to that thread which is running that particular task
.
That's what our contract is doing.
Okay.
So you cannot just simply use this if you use this a grid to be referenced do that the task itself.
But that's not what we want we want a reference to the thread which is running got ask.
OK.
So that's what we are doing.
So here we are giving Max about poverty.
And the reason why we named it as a mail campaign day I get go is because so many companies sometimes
every periodically the companies salt some email companies marketing even campaigns which are very important
and the company might also be aggregating data from different sources.
But certainly email campaigns is a more important task compared to this one.
So email campaigns might be might be sent only once every day or twice a day but when they have to be
done they should be given higher priority because they're business related and it can be done anytime
.
They're not that important.
So they're important but they can be done even during late nights out and auditing offerings.
So you want to give higher priority to that.
OK.
So let's just go ahead and just run it one more time.
So as you can see American business here are given higher priority.
Let me run it one more time.
Now here you can see that diagram gator you can see the switch that happens even though Max about it
he was given an e-mail campaign but still after executing four times did I agree gator the contract
was given in or was brought into running stock.
So there is no real got any but it is very likely that the first you know the one with the higher priority
gets more focus.
OK.
We'll be back and running straight.
OK now here in the e-mail campaign we are saying if I is equal to you then we are saying that our dot
caught and thread dog eat okay and eat is nothing but it's simply a hen.
Should you learn that this particular threat e-mail campaign which is that the one instance that the
thread is willingly eased its current use FCP or whatever reason.
So again it's a hint that there should be order but it's up to the shed uder whether it wants to still
do this or not whether it wants to bring it to and do running state or not.
So both Max priority the priority setting up it is only when they are simply are trivia simply trying
to influence the wretched jeweler but it's up to them.
Richard your honor.
OK.
So that's that you'd better.
I'm finally here.
There's something called Joy in Mankell on this.
So here we are saying that the thread this is the main thread right.
This is the main thread.
It's because it's in the main matter on Main thread is having the statement the dark Jain.
So main thread what it is saying by agreeing this is it is saying I want to suspend myself until it
completes its execution.
OK under Tikal dice.
Flog It For whatever reason.
So there will be instances when you ran a wants to do that.
So it is doing this.
So not to just go ahead and run this and this has to be and Glosa and try catch block with interrupted
exception.
So it does.
So the two is basically the second track which is due to aggregator.
And here it is.
Now you can see that Ymir campaign has it and they like to get it has undone finally inside main has
is getting better.
So when it comes to this particular statement main threat is going to suspend itself.
So this will not get printed but only the truth ratable will exit good and as soon as the contract completes
its execution then main thread will be back in the running straight under which also completes its execution
.
Now there is also another overloaded method here for giant.
So it takes milliseconds.
So if you say run it means that it will very close to one millisecond and within one millisecond if
it does not die then be one word written.
Okay.
So thats what it says here at this rate at most it is milliseconds for distracted by model zero means
to wait for ever selection on this.
Now let's see if it works.
Now as you can see here so email companies their data integrator has kicked in here at this point.
So the main threat has suspended itself but then within one millisecond it could not complete.
So once again you know the main thread is back in action is in running start on expenses inside main
Markovitch that the glue that will complete its execution.
So thats the design method.
So those are the different methods.
Okay.
So we looked at how we can get out of it under the contract on below that set name and get name on really
bad how we can prioritize that.
And we also looked at that joint matter that we can at that console spend itself is ondel second third
underly second grade dies and we also looked at the matter here.
Okay.
So thats about it.
And the guard is once again available in the resources section.
Thank you and happy Cody