Hi there.
This is Dana.
And welcome back.
Let's no further explore about functional interfaces.
And we will learn about some standard functional interfaces which were introduced in Java eight.
Functional interfaces, as the name implies, have something to do with functions, and we know that
they define a single abstract method.
And we have seen how lambda expressions, which are essentially anonymous functions, work with only
functional interfaces other than lambda expressions.
Functions could be method references to not that functional interfaces can also be targets of instances
of ordinary classes that implement those functional interfaces.
And such classes we know can also implement other interfaces which need not be functional interfaces.
And here are some very familiar functional interfaces that were there even before Java eight, and they
have some semantics associated with them.
We know that comparator and comparable are related to sorting while reasonable and callable are related
to threats.
So they have some semantics associated with them.
But in Java eight, several standard functional interfaces were added and these are very generic functional
interfaces and they do not have any specific semantics associated with them.
They only define some structure.
Semantics would depend on the context in which they are used.
And these interfaces are part of this package called Java dot dot function.
And as much as possible, we should try to use the standard functional interfaces instead of creating
our own.
Just like in the case of exceptions where it is recommended to use standard exceptions.
That way we would have a common terminology and all of us developers can be on the same page, right?
Whenever we see a standard functional interface.
We know what it would do and shortly we will look at some of the core standard function interfaces.
But before that, let's look at a simple example which would introduce us to a couple of standard function
interfaces.
Let's assume that we have a list of Web pages and we want to index only those web pages that belong
to a certain category.
On indexing.
We know what happened searching those pages.
So first step is to filter out those Web pages that do not belong to the target category.
So the output of the first step would be only those web pages that belong to the target category.
Our next step would be to remove all the HTML tags from those web pages before we would index them.
So first step here is applying a filter.
Right.
So that's essentially the first step.
And if it returns a true for a given web page, then it would be processed by the second step.
On second step simply transforms the web page by removing the HTML tags.
Not to perform such tasks, we can use these standard functional interfaces.
First one is predicate, which represents the boolean expression for the filter.
In this example, if the webpage belongs to the target category, then the predicate would return a
true and we would further process the web page.
For the second step, which is the transformation step, we can make use of the function interface on
both.
These interfaces are part of our DOT function package.
And here is the definition of the predicate functional interface.
And it represents a Boolean expression that uses an object of type P in the example we just saw.
P would be a document, and this particular function interface has a single abstract method called test.
And so we need to have some function representing this method.
That's where things like lambda expressions and method references come into play.
I note that this interface also has few default methods and one static method, and you can check out
this interfaces API specification to learn about them, but we will be actually using one of them in
the demo shortly.
And here you can also notice that there is an annotation called Functional Interface.
Now if you're creating a functional interface, then you should also use this annotation.
That way, compiler ensures that this interface has only a single abstract method.
And if you try to add more than one abstract method, you will get a compiler error.
Now, even without this annotation, an interface with a single abstract method would still qualify
as a functional interface.
However, if in future someone adds another abstract method, then it would not be a functional interface
anymore.
And the compiler will not complain just because this annotation has been omitted.
But if there are any lambda expressions whose target type is this interface, then the compiler will
still highlight that the target for those lambda expressions is no longer a functional interface.
We saw an example of this in the Lambda Demo that we did earlier.
But it is good to include this annotation, so that compiler right away informs us.
If we by mistake, try to add more than one abstract method.
And here is the function function interface.
It takes an object of generic type DX as input and returns an object of generic type r.
The abstract method is applied that is you are applying some sort of transformation from t to ah.
Note that this interface also has few non abstract methods like default and static, and you can check
out the API to learn about them and also know that there is another function interface called Unity
Operator, which extends this interface and it is a specialization for the case where both input and
output are of the same type.
Now let's head over to my editor to implement the example we just saw earlier.
Okay.
For this demo, I have created this new class called Functional Interface Demo.
As this demo is about functional interfaces and it has been created in our package.
Com dot semantics dot lambdas which was created in the last demo, in the previous demo.
And here we are going to implement the example that we have seen earlier in the slides, which is about
processing HTML pages.
And we discussed about the two steps filtering and transformation and we said that for filtering we'll
be using predicate interface and the for transformation will be using function interface.
So in this demo we'll be looking at those two standard functional interfaces, predicate and function.
And in the subsequent lecture we are going to look at two more standard functional interfaces, consumer
and supplier.
So these are the main standard function interfaces.
And so we are going to look at all four of them.
So the first step here, if you if you recall, the first step was to the main goal was to process HTML
pages and the first step was to apply the filter.
And in the filtering step we will filter out those web pages which do not belong to a certain category.
And if it belongs to the category, then it will be further processed.
And the second step is the transformation step, where the HTML tags in the in the web page will be
stripped out, will be removed, and then the result of that will be used for indexing the page.
Now, in this demo, I'm also going to introduce a third step, which would be another transformation
step.
So once the document is stripped off from the with the HTML tags, once the HTML tags are removed,
the resulting web page will be processed once again.
And during the second transformation step, we will be removing certain words called a stop.
Words and stop words are very generic words like an R and so on.
And stop word removal is a is a common procedure is a common step.
Whenever we are indexing web pages, whenever we are indexing any, any content.
So that is a common step that search engines do because stop words do not add any value during the search
process and also during the indexing.
So it's removed.
So that's not important for us.
The reason I introduced that step is because both second and third step are transformation steps, and
we are going to use the same function, same method to realize both of these steps.
So we are going to reuse the functionality.
So I just wanted to demonstrate that where different behavior is being used, but the same method is,
is being used to accomplish what we want to accomplish.
I think it will be clear when we implement it.
So the goal is to process HTML pages and here we have these for HTML documents.
Essentially, they are strings and each thing is essentially a web document.
Think of it as a Web document, a small document here.
So you have the HTML tax here.
And in the second step, we are going to remove those text.
So the first step is the filtering step.
And in this case, the category is the word stream.
If the if the document contains the word stream, then it needs to be processed.
Otherwise, it should not be processed.
It should be filtered out.
So among these four documents, the first document and the on the fourth document have the word stream
here.
So we are going to process only two documents and the other two documents will get filtered out.
So we need to process these four pages.
And for that we are accumulating all these four documents into this list and we are going to iterate
here.
So we have this template code and for filtering we will invoke this method called filter with a static
method which is declared in the same class.
And for transformation we are going to use this method called transform and both for both the transformation
steps, we will be using the same method.
It's just that in each of the invocations, the behavior that we are going to pass will be different.
So the for the filter, it takes a predicate.
So we need to pass an instance of this predicate in order to filter out the documents for the transformation,
we need to pass a function here, an instance of function during the first invocation.
Well, we will pass the behavior for removing the HTML words, the HTML tags, and during the second
invocation, we will pass the logic to remove the stop words.
And there is also this indexer class here.
So this one has the the logic for stripping the HTML tags and also the logic for removing the supports.
But let's not worry about it for now.
So let's go ahead and first apply the filter.
So we need to call the filter method.
And it takes two parameters, doc, and we need to pass the lambda now.
So B would be the parameter of the lambda.
Then the arrow, then the body of that.
And for the body will say the dot.
Contains.
And our category word is.
So it's a simple categorization and the filter method returns a true or false.
It's as simple as that.
So the filter method is taking a dock and a predicate.
So this is essentially an instantiation of the predicate.
Predicate is a functional interface.
And within the functional interface we are calling this variable as filter and we are invoking the test
method.
So test is a method in predicate and we are passing the document.
And the logic for the test is essentially this one, the body of the lambda expression.
So that goes into the test, into the test method.
And so the test since the test is being passed, doc, so this doc is essentially the argument that
gets passed to the to the lambda parameter here.
And if the doc contains stream, then test would return a true because this contains method would either
return a true or false.
So if it returns true, then true will return here.
So this is an instance.
So before Java eight, we were we would have used anonymous functions.
But now since we have lambda expressions, which is much more elegant and compact, we are going to
use that.
So we are done with the first step.
Now we need to apply the transformation step.
So once again, the parameter here.
And we need to strip the HTML tags.
So that's the first transformation.
So it will be DX here.
So the is the parameter and strip HTML taxes define here.
So for strip HTML tags in order to remove the HTML tags, I'm using a third party library called HTML
cleaner, which also has this class called HTML cleaner, and the job file will be available in the
resources section.
And we are simply invoking the clean method of this class and we are passing the document and we are
invoking some method called get text and we are invoking the two string method here.
So we are chaining.
So this particular clean method will simply strip off the HTML text instead of doing it.
We are using existing logic for that.
And it seems to be a nice library.
So that's what we are doing here.
Strip tax, but it is done by the transfer method.
So the transfer method takes a function here and function here.
So the input is string and the output is also string and we are calling it as transformer and the transformer
interface has the apply method predicate interface has the test method because we are testing something,
but here it has apply method because we want to apply a transformation.
So this is the HTML document and the logic is being passed here.
Strip HTML tags.
So this is the logic of the applied method.
So it's going to take the document with the HTML tags and it is going to strip off the HTML tags.
That's what the logic does.
So the output is assigned to a document.
And we need to apply the second transformation.
So the same document which is stripped off the HTML tags is passed here.
So this time we are invoking remove stop words.
Okay.
And remove stopwatches here.
So the stopwatch is defined in this list and it is just some normal, very generic words.
And the most obvious method is here.
And it takes a document and it simply removes all of these words.
You don't have to worry about this logic.
You can look at it later.
It just removes takes a document which is which has been stripped off the HTML tags and it just removes
any occurrences of these words.
So that's the that's inside the indexer.
So we are invoking the same transform method, but it is a very different logic and this behavior is
being passed via the lambda, right?
So that's the beauty of it.
So we are able to make use of the same transform method, but they are doing very different things.
So the behavior is being passed.
So it's like different strategies that are being passed here when we are nicely utilizing the same function.
So the behavior is getting passed here.
So behavior is like the first class citizens in Java eight.
So this is functional programming, functional style functional programming in action.
So that's the document.
Let's go print it.
As I said, only two documents are there.
The first document has the word stream.
The second.
The fourth one also has stream.
And the second and third have been stripped out.
Have been filtered out.
And the HTML tags have been stripped and all of the stops are also removed.
So that's that.
So in this example, here we are passing this lambda directly, but we can also do something else.
Like we can also assign this lambda to here.
In this case it is being passed as a method argument, but we can also assign it to a variable and pass
that variable to.
So if we are assigning it to a variable, that variable has to be of type function.
So let's do that.
Okay.
So we are just assigning the lambda earlier it was being assigned, but it was a method parameter.
Now we are assigning it here and we can still call.
You can still do this.
You can just pass that.
Similarly, we can also.
So there is no difference here.
It's just that we are assigning to a variable of type function and we are passing it.
Similarly, we can also have the second one.
Let's call it stop word remover.
So this particular function is going to remove the stop words and we can use the same one here.
And we can invoke the transform method and the transform method is simply invoking the apply method,
right?
So we can also just directly invoke the apply method here.
So we really do not have to invoke the transform tool, right?
Because the transform method is also doing the same thing.
It's just invoking the apply method because function has the applied method.
So that's it.
So we are just doing it in a different way here.
We are doing it here instead of doing it in the transform.
So let me run it again.
So it's just the same output.
So we can do this.
Now, let me comment that out.
So we had a working transform.
So there is also, instead of using function that is also a unity operator, which is a sub interface
or function of unity operator is also a functional interface and we can also use that and it is just
a specialization of function.
Import control shift oh so function takes to here to parameters to it has two generic type parameters.
One is one signifies the input and the other output.
But you're not the operator.
It just works on the same input and produces the same output.
But we can also implement it this way because we are having the same type here.
That's also fine.
Or we can have different types too in certain transformations, but if we have this one, we can make
use of unity.
Operator.
Now, so here.
We are just invoking the method operator and the same output.
The reason I commented this out is because here we are using function, but this document transform
here is actually taking a unity operator so there will be a compilation error.
So that's the reason I have done that.
So that's predicate and function.
Now I want to show something called composing.
So I mentioned that the function interface also has some default methods and a static method.
So let's invoke that default method.
It has a default method called and then and if we use and then basically we can compose two functions.
For instance, we can compose this HTML cleaner and stopwatch remover into a single function which is
called as a composed function.
So let's do that.
So for that, I'll take this HTML cleaner, which is a function.
And it has the default method.
And then and and then we'll accept another function.
So this is how composition happens.
And it returns a function so and then takes a function, but also returns a function.
So that's also possible.
So it would also be function or string of string.
Let's call it a processor.
And you can do that and pass the duck processor.
Here.
So we can do that.
So now we are we are invoking the transform only once, but we are passing a composed function here.
And what and then does is so it is returning a compost function and within the transform we are still
invoking the apply method.
But this time what happens is first this function will be applied HTML cleaner and then the result that
we get another document that will be passed to the second function.
So we are changing the functions in this way.
So we are saying that first apply this and then as the method names are just here and then apply the
second, the second function.
So this will be applied first and now the result of that will be passed to the second function, which
does another transformation.
So that's what the apply method will do internally.
So we are passing this compost function and let me just run.
That will still get the same output here.
That needs to be here if you have.
We are not assigning it to Doc.
So now we can see that it's the same output.
So we can do that also.
And.
So that's the that's how we can compose functions.
And it also shows you how by invoking this, it will return a function.
So now the last thing I want to show is something called by function.
A function takes a single parameter and returns a single output, right?
It returns an output, but by function takes two method parameters.
So that's the only difference.
So just like by function, we also have by predicate.
And in the next lecture, we are looking at consumer and supplier.
It also has buy variants.
Okay.
So now I want to show the buy function, but for that, I want to show it here instead of using this.
So this instead of using a filter, we can implement this filter using a bi function.
So let's look at that.
So let's define.
By function here.
So it takes two parameters.
The first one, let's pass the document, and the second one, let's pass the category.
And the third one would be a boolean parameter.
Okay.
So here, buy implies two parameters.
Two method parameters.
It's a by function and let's define our Lambda dx.
See the main port that controls shift or.
And here so B would be correspond to D would correspond to document, C would correspond to the category
and let's say the dot.
Danes see.
So that's the logic.
Now this function we can directly apply here.
Apply.
So it also has play method like function, but it takes two parameters as I mentioned earlier.
So we will pass doc and for the category we will just pass.
Stream.
So that's it.
That's the only thing difference here.
So we are implementing the filter in this way because all we need is all we need to return as a boolean.
And this logic does that.
So this is going to be the behavior for the apply method and the applied method is taking doc on stream,
which means that doc will be this, stream will be this, and this is the logic.
So if we run it.
You get the same output.
So that's the by function, that is also by predicate.
So in the next lecture, we will look at consumer and the supplier, and we will also look at the API
specification also so that you can get a feel for how the API looks, the Java function, the function
package with all the standard interfaces.
So that we will do it in the next lecture.
So I hope you enjoyed learning about this.
Functional interfaces the first two functional interfaces and thank you.
And this code will be available in the resources section.
Happy coding.