Let's not do the math the lifetime effort type I ordered on the program that we saw earlier in the introductory
lesson.
So it was simple run that program.
If you recall the class Nimitz class initialization Demel and it's only available for download from
the resource section.
So you can download it.
And are you going to add a new package called com not semantics cleared or JVM.
And that needs to be done within the demo project.
Recall that we now have two projects.
One is the demo and the other trio were three includes our real project code.
So any new code that we write in this chapter will go under this new package called JVM.
Now this class has been extended from what we saw in the introductory lesson.
This was done for the monster two additional things.
So let's just go ahead and review that and our program one more time.
That way we can also see the new stuff that got added.
So here is the class initialization demo and this is an instance initializer block and this is a static
initializer block.
So no changes there from what we signed the introductory lesson here are the new numerators that court
ordered.
One is get in.
Which is a static method.
On the other one is get in the file which is also a static method on both of them are simply retaining
some values.
Now we have the subclass.
No change there.
And it is extending superclass.
No change with that also.
And subclasses also implementing an new interface called Super interface.
So that's a new interface that we just added.
For this demo and we still have the two final few static final unstacked underscored final two.
So both of them are static final fields.
And one of them is a compiled and constant as the other is being initialized via a random function.
Now it still has the static initializer block on the constructor.
So no changes with that but a new instance initializer Rock has been added here and also a new class
called Object Reference has been ordered ironed.
An object of it is being created here.
So that's a plus.
Now let's move here to the superclass in the superclass so constructor is still there but a new starting
condition is a block and a new instance initializer block has been added here.
Now this is the object reference class.
The new object reference class which is initialized which is instantiated in the subclass.
And it just has one constructor and that's it.
Iron here is the super interface.
It has a static method.
So we know that static methods and interfaces are possible only from Java 8 onwards.
So it has this new static method and it also defines field as static final phone calls start to come
the final three.
And it is initialized in this way so we create an instance of class initialization demo and it has this
get in.
So we are invoking that.
And here there is a comment here.
This statement has been commented out.
So it isn't working to get into fine matter in the class initialization will solve it and we will uncomment
this and see what is with that.
And next is the main matter.
So Main and third is pretty much the same method.
So not much or not many changes.
So here we are printing.
Here we are accessing the static underscored final feed in the subclass underspending it.
So no change with that.
And here we are providing the static underscore final proofread and we are instantiating the subclass
which was also there earlier.
The only new statement as this.
Invoking the static method and later we will also uncommon this statement and we will see what it is
.
So that's the main method.
So no let's just go ahead and run this program.
But in order to see the lifetime of a type of this class.
So what we need to do is we need to pass an option call what class do the java command.
OK.
And the V it's an option that we are passing to the JVM.
And the way we do it is just right click and go here to run.
As earlier we were just clicking on this option jaywalked application.
Now let's get this thing run conflagrations and it opens this dialog click on arguments and here there
are two boxes here as the option that you can pass to the GBM.
Henri will call it as Marble's call in class.
And so this will be passed to the GBM.
And if you have any arguments here in program arguments those will be passed to the main method.
OK but we don't have any right now.
But if you just imagine that if we're running this whole thing from the command line and that is these
arguments would be inserted after the class name itself.
So use a Java class name on some program arguments.
But if you want to pass any arguments to the JVM then you said Java hyphen Werben colon class and you
would have the class named class initialization Demel and any arguments that we pass.
So any arguments passed here will be passed to the main matter.
So they will be assigned to those during oral argument that which is the only parameter that the main
method has.
Now I'm also going to include a pointer in the resource resources and that link will show all the options
that GBM would accept.
So you can also take a look at that that'd apply and not hurt her.
So now the class initialization demo has been executed.
Also just note that there are many classes here each of four each of them are docked last fall is also
generated on the on the desk.
OK so now let's just evaluate what we have here.
So let's begin with this.
And here as soon as the JVM has started GBM got created here the bootstrap classloader has kicked in
and it is loading this rt.jar Jotham jihadi did directory and we know that Arbi as Dornheim door ajar
and that includes the Kujawa library.
So now or here from here from this line on what it's going to load all the classes and the Kujawa library
that is all most of the important ones.
So you can see that the first one is the Djala that land or object itself.
Then here is a Java dart call that serializable.
Dot dot dot compatible on all of these classes and interfaces are getting loaded.
So that's the class loading process that it is done by the bootstrap class order can see so many different
class files.
Just go here and here at the very end is the class initialization them all which is the startup class
classes that we how we are running here which has the main method.
So this class is inside the JVM and that got it ordered.
OK so that's stuck only the class loading process.
So once that is done the GBM would actually initialize this class and that is happening here.
So the static in the initialization stage we know that the static initializer block rule will run.
So that's what is happening here is the static initializers block right here.
And we also have this related comment here saying that it's the initialization stage but the instance
initializer block.
Although we have it.
It's not.
It has not been executed.
The reason for that is an instance has not been created.
Here an instance of class initialization Demel has not been created.
It's just has been loaded and it just has been initialized.
OK.
Now after that after the static initializer walk is executed then the next thing that happens is the
main method is invoked.
So GBM actually invokes the main Materne and all the statements here get executed.
Now with each statement.
Something is happening behind the scenes.
And we are going to look at that.
OK.
So the statement is GBM in Rhogam main method.
OK so we are here in the main matter.
And the next statement is accessing this topic find free.
But this has been not in walk but decided not to load the subclass.
And the reason for that is that the client is a compile time constant so that value as has got copied
here.
OK so sapless has not been loaded yet and we are simply printing the value 47.
Now the next statement says in working subclause not static final do it's just printed AS-IS.
And here we are going to access Dodik finally.
And with that there are some interesting things that are happening.
So hosting this starting or is not a compile time constant So let's just go here.
So it's it's assigned disvalue value that I value by invoking this random function.
So what exactly is happening here and on if you see here.
So superclass subclass has got reordered now and because of this even super interfaces loader and super
process roaded so because it's extending Supercross and implementing super interface and they are loaded
in this particular order Moka interface first and then the superclass then the subclass after these
three got rewarded then the static initializer block in the superclass has been that which means the
initialization off superclass has completed and that's the reason the static condition is Godkin superclass
got executed here.
And that statement is getting printed here.
So you just go here to the superclass.
Here it is.
So this it meant got executed but the super interface is just loaded.
But it's it is not initialized.
So if you recall that's what we said when we discussed initialization for what an interface it gets
initialized only if it's static method is invoked or if it went off its use is invoked and that field
has one off the field is accessed under you cannot be a contes compile time constant only one of those
two things happen.
So an interface can will be initialized.
So that's the reason an interface is only has only been loaded but it was not initialized.
OK so we see this statement but following that we have these three lines here.
So that is because so it's hurting the mat something with some something related to my class.
That's because here are in the subclass we are invoking the random function.
So some classes are related to that are getting loaded here and what it means is it's lazy loading.
OK.
So these things are encountered now ironed and they are being lazy ordered.
So after that the start.
So though the superclass has been initialized now the subclass is getting initialized and the static
initializer grock in the subclause got initialized underspent in the statement on Finally the stocktake
.
Finally you got assigned a value of zero in the main method.
So that's that.
And after that we are saying instantiating subclassed and we are creating an instance of a subclass
.
OK.
Now when we instantiate this subclass what happens is.
So we need we need to loop this subclass but subclass is already loaded Onitsha in the memory on the
heap.
So it's not going to get loaded once again.
So the classloader will simply use the class object class which is already in the heap for subclass
and it's also going to do the same for superclass.
In fact we know about constructor chaining.
So because of that the superclass constructor will be in Rockfest before the superclass constructor
is invoked the superclass instance initializer will be in work here.
Harridans supercross because an instance of superclass has been created and it's following that the
constructor is in work.
So that's the construct of changing so fast the constructor of the superclass is invoked before this
subclass constructor.
So that's why you see these two statements.
And then we the control goes into the subclass that tries to initialize all the instance variables and
also runs the constructor call.
But here we have this variable here object reference which is where we are instantiating this object
reference class.
So that's the so the lines that you see here is really is related to that.
So this is something to do with that.
And here we are loading the object reference class and the object reference constipate results are in
Wilker following which subclass in the initial instance initializer unsuppressed constructor are invoked
.
Now here interesting thing is subclass.
But here if you see the output here instance initializers statement is printed before the constructor
.
But if you look at the code instance initializer is appearing after the constructor in the source corner
So and that's because instance initializer is always copied to the beginning of constructor by the compiler
itself.
So compiler is doing that class.
OK so that's about that.
And let's look at the next statement here the static method is being invoked.
Now the super interface will be initialized.
So let's see what we have here.
OK so it's calling the super interface is getting initialized.
So because of this invocation of the static method Sinaloan Let's go into the Super interface model
.
So when we say it's initialized so fast this field gets this treatment gets executed.
And here this class instance is being created instance of class initialization demo which means that
any instance of variables or any constructor or initializer within this class will be executed.
So that's why you see that the instance initializer within the class initialization do more has got
executed under.
And we're printing that.
And after that the GET IN method is getting in walk.
So that's what is happening.
And finally after that the static method indecl put interfaces being in walk.
OK so this gets initialized only when a static method is invoked or when a field is invoked which is
not compile time constant.
So for that let's just go here and let's uncomment this.
So instead of static method now we are accessing the static final three which is a field and super interface
.
So if you go there.
Here it is.
So now let's run this one more time and let's examine this final code.
So the class initialization demo has been initialized in the instance initializer is run and the get
and method is invoked.
And the start declining three values assigned the studio.
So the super interface is one more is once again initialized not uncommon.
This also and let's run it one more time.
So here we have two trees on both of them.
One of them is calling the get end method in class initialization Demel and the other step on the other
field is in we can get in five.
The second matter.
And this.
But over here if you see we are in we're accessing only one of the rooms start to underscore final treat
.
But that is also because this class interface is being initialized.
It's also executing this second statement.
Static underskirt final 5 is getting initialized because when it gets initialized it's going to initialize
all the static final FIERS.
OK.
So that's why you'll see that when when the instances are being created in the two statements that's
where you see that your class initialization the more instance initializer is run once ungrudging get
in has been invoked on here instance initializer in the second statement.
Due to the second statement it got executed.
Get in 5 is getting involved this time.
So as long as one of the fields is accessed which is not a compile time constant then an interface will
be initialized and all the rest of the Foose static fruits will also be real will also be executed.
So that's about the interface initialization.
So that's about it.
But finally if you just think about it you may feel that there is not much value in learning on this
.
For example in the main method we're accessing this topic you start to underscore find them unstarted
final two from the subclass and all the kid is whether we are able to access those values or not.
What difference would it make if we know whether those classes are loaded uninitialized or not.
So that's a valid thought.
But the thing is we want to do better than that.
We want to know what the Java platform is doing internally.
So we are pushing our boundaries here on trying to get a better grasp of the technology.
And that's the reason behind having this chapter in this course but it's not just about making our self
complete.
But the designers also have a reason behind making making it work in this way.
For example there is a reason behind having constructor chaining.
You want to pretend to be initialized by fortune.
Otherwise there can be issues.
OK so there can be some issues on so it's important to be aware of how things are handled by the platform
.
OK so it's a good thing that we are studying all this.
So that's about it.
Hope you enjoyed this remote.
See you in the next lesson.