Hello there.
This is De La Rue and welcome back.
So in this lecture, let's go ahead and create a new class and then we will declare a few variables
and we will also re initialize those variables.
So we will declare the variables with both literals as well as expressions, and we will also re initialize
those variables.
So that's what we have seen in the previous lecture.
And in this lecture we are going to test them out.
So in this lecture we will create a new class called Student.
And as we progress through this section, as we learn new things like the primitive variables and so
on, we will also extend this particular class.
So let's go ahead and create our student class.
So we will have the keyword class followed by the class name, which is student, and the body of the
student class.
It starts and ends with a brace.
Here's the opening brace and the ending brace.
Now, the normal programming convention is to have the brace right after the the class name.
That's what most of the developers do.
Now, some developers might have the opening brace here, but that's not very common.
So it's better to follow what most programmers are doing.
So let's have it here.
Thus, let's also save it.
So we have our directory structure, Java, in-depth and some directories within there.
So let's go ahead and create here it is, Java In-Depth s RC.
Com Semantic Square Basics and we already have a couple of classes here.
Let's create our student dot java here.
So that's the student class and let's create a new variable called ID.
So let's have four spaces here.
Two, three, four.
So that's the indentation it's called as an indentation.
So later we will also talk about coding conventions and there we will also discuss about indentation.
So when we are writing our statements, they would have certain indentation like in this case.
So here we will have our variable.
So we say that they are indented by four spaces and they help in readability of the code.
So four spaces is also a normal coding convention.
Mostly developers use either either four spaces or one tab, whichever you prefer.
So just wanted to highlight that, although we will discuss about the indentation later on.
So just wanted to introduce right here itself so that you can also start using you can also start intending
with four spaces or one tab.
So let's create our variable called ID, which is of type end.
And first let's look at literal initialization.
So let's initialize it with 1000.
And let's also write a simple method called compute.
So avoid.
The name of the method is compute and all it does is it prints the variable.
So the compute method also has a body and then opening based on the closing base.
And let's also give four spaces here.
One, two, three, four.
And let's spread.
And let's write our main method.
Otherwise we cannot run this.
And the main also has its own body.
And first thing that we'll do is we'll create an object of the student class to three four student as
that's the name of the variable.
New student That's it.
So let's go ahead and compile and run it.
So we compile it.
Okay.
Java and student.
This is what have.
So when we run it, it's not printing this.
And that's because a student object is created.
But we still did not invoke this method called compute.
It's called a method invocation.
And we need to invoke it or call it.
And we have seen that when discussing the class an object for invoking a method, we will say the variable
as dot, dot, dot operator and we will invoke the compute method.
Now it's going to print.
So since we added a new statement, we need to recompile it.
And when we run it, Java space student, it's going to print.
So that's the literal.
Now let's, let's create a variable and it's initialized with an expression which gets evaluated to
a single value.
So let's create a new variable called next ID and let's say ID plus one.
So it will be one more than the ID value.
And let's also print it.
So let's copy this.
And the sprint.
Next.
So this is an expression.
So when the program is executing and when the control comes here to the statement, it will have the
value chosen.
So next it would become thousand and one.
So let's recompile because we added a few statements and let's run it.
So it prints 2000 and 2001.
So when this object student object has been created at that instance, these two statements get executed.
First ID will be initialized, 1000 and next ID will be computed as 2001.
So ID will be replaced with the value 1000 and we get the value 2001.
And when compute is executed, when this statement is is executed.
So control goes into this method and prints the ID and then the last statement also executes our next
ID gets printed.
So that's how we get the values 2000 and 1001.
Now, this here cannot be declared here.
Okay.
So let's see what the error message will be.
So let's recompile Java two linked Java.
It says illegal for word reference.
So when we have this declaration statement, it is not yet declared.
So which means that.
The scope of ID, it's called, as the scope of variable.
It starts here and it is for the entire class.
So that's how it is.
But we will be discussing the scope of the variables later on.
So its scope will be starting from here to the end of the class and next it will be from here, from
this point to the rest of the class, which means that they can be used anywhere in the class.
So we said that the declaration statement.
Can appear anywhere in the class, so let's just move them to compute method.
So let's recompile it.
And let's execute.
So it is punting the 2000 and 2001.
So when the object student is created at this instance, only ID value has been initialized.
But when we invoke the method compute, then control comes here and next ID will be initialized with
thousand one and then subsequently those values will be printed.
Now we also said that in the declaration of the variable.
The initialization is optional.
You may recall that from the slides.
So let's see what happens if that's the case.
Let me clear up the screen.
And here it is.
Let me run it.
It prints the value zero for ID and one for next ID.
So if we are not initializing, then it is getting a default value of zero.
And that's the case if the variable is off type end.
So if the variable is off type end, it gets a default value and variables of other types might get
some other value.
So like we said that there are eight primitive types which we will discuss later.
So that's the thing.
It gets a default value of zero.
Now let's see what happens if we have the variable here.
It should also give us the same thing.
So let's recompile.
And it says variable ID might not have been initialized, but when we had it here, that was not an
issue.
But when once we moved it into the method, then it is given a compilation error and it says that in
this statement next to it, that is the second statement ID might not have been initialized.
So that's where it is complaining.
So the thing is here, these variables that we declare within the method are called as local variables,
and they do not get any default values.
So just keep that in mind.
So when we declared it here, it's called as an instance variable, but when we declare it in the method,
it is called as local variable and we will discuss both of them once again later in one of the subsequent
lectures.
And there is also another type of variable called static variable, which is also declared here at the
class level.
And so like an instance variable, it will also get a default value.
So both static and instance variables will be declared here at the class level, and they will get default
values, but local variables will not get default values.
And more on that later.
So here, either we need to initialize it in the declaration statement or we can re initialize or we
can do this.
We can have an assignment statement and then it will be fine.
So let's just recompile.
And if you run it.
It prints the value.
That is fine.
So before we use it, it needs to be initialized and it can be initialized in the declaration statement
itself or it can also be initialized here.
Now let's move this here.
So the ID is zero and it is being re initialized on this method.
Now it prints 2000 and 1001 because ID is initially zero.
So when this statement is executing.
So let's just recompile and re execute it here.
So initially, even when the student object is created, it will be zero.
But when we are invoking the compute method, the control comes here and ID will be re initialized to
1000 and in the next statement, next ID is computed as 2001.
So this is how we re initialize variables.
Now you might also recall from the previous lecture that if we have it here, it's not going to work
because assignment statements cannot appear at class level.
They can only appear at methods or in other places called constructors, which we will discuss later.
But here at the class level you can only have declaration statements, so you cannot have such assignment
statements.
So that's how it is in Java.
So if we compile it, it says it gives an error.
So essentially we cannot have them here.
So let's move it back to here.
Now let's initialize this to 2000.
And how about we re initialize this to say D2?
Now it should give us.
Let's clear up the screen on.
So it says incompatible types.
String cannot be converted to and so ID is off type end.
But then we are trying to initialize it with the string literal data and that's not going to work because
Java is a statically type language.
So you cannot do this and you cannot do that.
Even here.
So let's just try it.
Okay.
We get the same error.
It says incompatible types.
So it's got to be of the same type.
So that's the static type checking that the compiler is performing on.
Hence always keep in mind Java is a statically type language.
So if somebody is going to ask you about that, you should say that it's a statically type language.
Now, so that's what we have.
And finally, let's just make this print statement a bit more meaningful.
Let's put some text here so that we know that it is ID.
So we'll do this in double quotes and we have this.
Plus, let's do the same thing here.
Now it should be more meaningful.
Our output.
Okay.
So it prints ID 1000 and next ID thousand and one.
So also put a call on here.
So the thing is, we know that plus as for addition, right, we discussed it earlier and we will also
discuss arithmetic operations later on.
And then we'll we'll talk about this plus symbol.
But when it is used with strings here, this is a string literal.
A string later will be in double quotes.
So whenever this plus is used with such a string literal, then it works as a concatenation operator.
And a concatenation operator is something which concatenate.
So it would append the thing on its right to the on its left, the thing on its right is the variable
ID and the variable ID has a value thousand.
So that value will be appended to this piece of text, which is a string literal and that is what is
getting printed here.
So whenever plus is used with strings, it acts as a concatenation operator, but otherwise it would
act as a plus symbol, which means that you only have numeric options.
So both of them would be something like integers or some other type, but definitely not strings.
So the same thing over here to so just wanted to show that also.
So that's the concatenation operator, but we will discuss concatenation operator when we discuss strings
and one of the subsequent sections.
So that's about it.
So we looked at the variable declarations and variable re initialization and we have looked at the variable
declarations with literals expressions and when it also gets a default value.
And we also said that local variables will not get default values, but more on that later.
But just keep in mind that local variables will not get any default values.
Thank you and I hope you enjoyed this lecture and happy coding and see you in the next lecture.