So we look at how we can access packages and also how we can create packages.
No let's see how we should name packages.
That is we will look at standard conventions for naming packages through a simple example let's just
look at a problem that the man conter due to bad off naming packages.
Let's have you have an idea who is a student at Stanford University let's assume Anita has developed
a math library which is available for download for public use.
One of the packages in this library is named as Mad Dog geometry non-IT Ajume there's a guy called John
who works for Oracle.
Let's Ajan also don't have the publicly available math library which also includes a package called
Mad Dog geometry not assume that book on it does matter door geometry and.
My documentary packages look very similar as most of methods have identical signatures although their
implementations are quite different.
Not have the company semi-big square on one of their projects is heavily in demand and they're already
using and it does a bit not it's a semantic Square has a new and don't call bought and bought comes
across.
John celebrity and wants to use its modern geometry package.
So he tries to use it and to his surprise it doesn't work as expected.
After some investigation he finds that at runtime JVM is actually using and it does matter geometry
package insert off John's package.
Naturally this irritates Bob as you can see from his expression So basically the two packages with the
same name JVM is always picking on its package.
So there is a package named conflict here and this is because both are not on John.
We're not following proper Bakhash naming conventions.
So all packages are supposed to work class name conflicts they missed and not be helpful.
If the developers do not follow proper naming conventions do what package name conflicts recommend the
convention is to use the organizations to reverse Internet domain name one example our little engine
could have named their packages are shown here on it from Stanford University whose domain is Stanford
not to you.
So she could have started her package name with the reverse of the domain name which would be edu Daut
Stanford Similarly John could have started his package name with com dot article.
This would have and or bought to use Johnson Library without any issues there are so few other naming
conventions item 56 ineffective is all about naming conventions and it actually starts with naming conventions
for packages.
Here we discuss only the ones pertaining to packages.
All of the recommendations will be discussed later.
Towards the end of language basic series Hussman says that components in a package should consist off
what gets alphabets on really digits component should also be shot generally eight or fewer characters
meaningful abbreviations like you do for utilities are encouraged like in the case of Gelada acronyms
or find do for example there is a package called AWB which is related to creating user interfaces hit
N.W.T. is an acronym for abstract window toolkit Jindalee component should consist of only a single
word Hundley you should know what stock you are packaged in the Java Oddjob X used with a standard July
.
The majority of packages in July be stocked with giallo Jorak seems to exist only for historical reasons
One son wanted to use it for only extensions that is called classes would reside within Java while extensions
would be in jail X Java Swing API falls under Jagex So these are some naming conventions specific to
packages.
And you should really buy them.
So that's about it.
And that's the I know forward discussion on packages.
Thank you