Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
So we have learned about packages and we know that packages help in meaningfully organizing our classes
and they also help with name scoping.
That is, we can have classes with identical names and different packages like the date class.
Now when introducing packages, we also said that packages help with security and this is achieved via
access levels, which is a subject of this lecture and it's a very important topic and it is very easy
to know by security we mean which classes in a package are accessible outside of the package, that
is to classes outside the package on which classes are not accessible outside the package.
For instance, let's assume our project contains these two packages where the green and red squares
represent classes.
And we want the red ones to be used only by classes within the same package, but not by classes outside
the package.
Maybe they represent some sensitive functionality and should not be used outside of the package.
But the green ones can be used outside the package too.
So we do not want something like this where a class in package two can access this class in package
one, which is considered to be sensitive.
Similarly, if this project is some sort of a library, then we may have developers outside our organization
using this library.
However, we do not want them to use these sensitive classes which are shown in red.
Even if they are not sensitive, they may be completely irrelevant to such developers using the library,
so there is no point exposing such irrelevant classes which only serve as noise to them.
So they are totally irrelevant to them.
They should access only the green ones which are considered relevant.
And defining access levels help with providing such restrictions on accessing classes.
And they can also be used with interfaces which will be discussed later.
I know that access levels are not for just classes and interfaces, but they are also very important
for members of classes such as variables, methods and even nested classes and nested interfaces, which
will be discussed later and they can also be used with constructors and access levels are critical and
building well design software.
Later, we will discuss about a fundamental design principle called Information Hiding, which is based
on access levels, and it helps towards building well-designed software.
Now first let's look at accessibility for classes and it is the same for interfaces too.
We said that certain classes should not be visible outside of the package.
That is, they're used only by classes within the same package.
Similarly, we also said that we would have classes that are accessible to any class.
That is, they are accessible to classes within the package and also those classes that are outside
of the package.
And this is the common case.
And for this to happen, we use a keyword called public in the class declaration, and we have been
seeing its usage at various places during our demos.
And here is how it would be when used with our basic demo class.
Here, public is referred to as an access modifier and it should come before the keyword class.
If you place it in between the keyword class and the class name, then you get a compiler error.
In fact, you cannot have anything in between the keyword class and the class name.
So we use public modifier F.
The accessibility of the class is public.
But for the first case where accessibility is only within the package, we do not specify any modifier.
So that's the default case.
If you do not specify any access modifier, then it implies that the class is accessible only to other
classes within the same package.
So we just looked at accessibility for classes and interfaces.
Now let's look at accessibility for class members like variables and methods.
One restriction is for a member of a class to be accessible only within the class in which it is defined
in which the member is defined.
That is, outside of that class.
That member should not be accessible.
For example, you may want a variable or a method to be accessible only within the class, like in its
methods or constructors, but not to any code outside of the class.
And for this you would use an access modifier called private when declaring the variable and it suggest
that the member is private to the class.
And here is an example where the variable ID is declared as private.
And sometimes we may want a particular member to be accessible not only within its class, but also
to other classes within the same package.
And the member should also not be accessible outside of the package.
For this.
We do not use any access modifier.
And here is an example.
Sometimes this access level is also referred to as package private, as the access is private to the
package.
So with this access level, the member will not be accessible outside the package.
And we may also want a member to be accessible to all classes in the same package like in the previous
case.
However, in addition, we may want that member to be accessible to something called Subclasses of the
class in which the member is defined.
And those subclasses may be outside the package to.
Subclasses are not yet discussed and they will be introduced when discussing inheritance, which is
an object oriented concept.
So we will deal with inheritance after few sections from here.
So let's not worry about subclasses for now, but note that for this access level, you would have to
use an access modifier called protected when declaring the member.
And here is an example.
And finally, we may also want certain members of a class to be accessible to any code, regardless
of where the code is.
That is, the code may be inside the package or outside the package, too.
That's the public access level.
And you would use the access modifier public when declaring the member.
And here is the obvious example.
Not that if we are creating a library like the Java API, then anything declared as public within our
library can be used by users of the library.
When we say anything, it can be a class or an interface or even their members like variables and methods.
So we say that anything declared as public would be part of the API, and we know that API stands for
application programming interface and it is simply another term for library.
Not that these access levels are ordered from most to least restrictive.
So the first one, private, is most restrictive as visibility of the class member is only within that
class.
Similarly, last one is least restrictive as the class member is accessible to any code.
Also of all the modifiers, private and public are used most of the time.
And we will also see how private and public enable information hiding the design principles that we
will discuss later.
Protected is used relatively rarely, and default or packaged private access is also common, but maybe
not as much as private and public.
So when compared to classes and interfaces, we can see that members of the class have two additional
access level restrictions, which are private and protected restrictions.
Public on default access levels apply to both classes and interfaces as well as their members.
Now let's go ahead and test the different access levels with the exception of protected, which will
be discussed later after introducing inheritance.
In this demo, we will first look at accessibility of classes and then we will look at accessibility
of class members with regards to class members.
We will only look at accessibility of methods and it would be the same for variables to it would also
be same for other members like nested classes and nested interfaces, which we will discuss much later.
So let's go ahead and look at accessibility of classes.
We already looked at accessibility of classes when discussing packages earlier on.
When discussing packages, we looked at creating packages.
So there was a lecture on creating packages.
And in that lecture, in the demo, at some point we did look at accessibility of classes, but let's
look at it one more time.
So we have this Standard Class Basics demo, which is part of this package.
Com semantics for basics, right?
And in that demo, at one point we created this class called as basics demo test, but it was in a different
package called comp semantics queer basics test.
So this is basics test and this is basics.
So in this class we were using the basics demo class, so we imported this class.
And here in the main method we created an instance of basics demo and we were invoking this method called
Foo, which is just a dummy method, and it just prints a message.
So let me just show you that method.
Here it is.
So it is just a dummy method, which is just printing this message called inside.
So here, if you recall, when we compile this class for the very first time, it gave us a compilation
error.
And the reason was basic demo was not public.
So here later we added this keyword called public, but initially it was not there and it gave us a
compilation error and then we added public and then it was fine.
So that's essentially class accessibility.
But let's look at it one more time.
So let me just go ahead and remove this.
Now a couple of things.
So we also have student Java on student test Java within the same package basics.
Just make sure that you also add these package statements in both the classes.
Student as well as student test package.
Semantics, squared, basics and both these classes.
Otherwise you will get a compilation error.
Now this is the basic demo class and basics demo test is using it.
So I have two command prompts here.
One is in basics and the other one is basics test.
So let me just compile basics demo class.
Compliance.
Fine.
Now basics test.
As you can see, it is giving us two compiler errors.
It says that basic demo is not public in this package and it cannot be accessed from outside the package
because it had a default access level.
So it is giving us two compilation errors, one at the import statement and the other when we were trying
to create an instance of basic demo.
So for both of them, it just says that basic demo is not public, so let's go here.
So this is the default access level, which means that there is no keyword here and it is also referred
to as package private, but other classes within the same package basics can access this class.
So let's go ahead and copy this particular statement and let's paste it in student test.
So in student test, let's go to the main method.
And at the very end, let me add.
The statement here.
And let's go ahead and compile this.
It compiles fine.
That's because both of these are in the same class, in the same package.
And hence even the basics demo has a default access level student test can access it because anything
default can be accessed within the same package.
So that's that.
Now let's go ahead and make it public.
Which means that we need to recompile it.
So basics demo I'm re compiling and now if we compile basics demo test, we will not see that compilation
error anymore.
So it is public now, which means that it is part of the API, as I mentioned earlier.
And it will be accessible to any code which is outside the package.
Just assume that basics demo test basics demo or this entire package is some sort of a library like
the com semantics where basics and let's say basics demo test is something that I'm writing and I'm
using this library so I'm able to access basics demo because it is part of the API.
It is part of the library as it has been declared as public and basic demo can use other classes like
student or student test.
In fact, one of the methods called arrays is using student class and student can be a has a default
access level.
So for me as a library user, I can only access basic demo, but basic demo can internally use other
classes which have default access level.
But I cannot directly use student because it does not have the public access modifier.
So that's where you can see how access level is helping us to access only certain relevant classes and
the ones that are not relevant can be hidden from the outside world.
So that's class accessibility.
Now let's look at accessibility of members.
So let's go ahead and pick the same example, the Foo method.
So Foo method is at the very end and it has.
Public.
So let me make it private.
So we are going to look at private.
Default and protector and public protector will be will be seen later when we discuss inheritance,
as I mentioned earlier.
So if it is private, it is only accessible within this particular class.
It cannot be accessed by any other class outside of this class.
So even student test, which is in the same package, cannot access it.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So student test.
Has the statement which we inserted earlier.
So let's go ahead and compile student test now.
So first, let me compile basics demo.
That's good.
Next is student test.
You see, it says that who has private access and basics demo.
So we cannot access the foo method.
Although basic demo can be accessed, who cannot be accessed because foo has private access so it cannot
also be accessed from the other class.
The basics demo test obviously because it is outside of the package.
So if student tests cannot access it, basic demo test obviously cannot access it to.
You see, it says the same thing.
So that's because it is private.
However.
Let's just copy this into our basic demo class.
So let's go into the main method.
Let's just insert it here.
So this should be fine because we are in the same class.
So that compiles fine.
So that's because foo is in the same class.
This is fine.
Even even we can access it directly.
But this is a static method, so we would have to make this static in order to access it.
So that's the private access modifier.
And private and public, as I mentioned earlier, will be very useful for the information hiding principle,
which we will discuss later.
It enables information hiding.
Now, next thing is.
The default access level, which just implies that we will not have this modifier.
So if we do not have that modifier, it means that it is packaged private.
That is, it is private to the package and that's the default access level.
So now student test can access it because it is in the same package.
So let's go ahead and.
Compile this.
So now it compiles fine.
But basics demo test can still not access it because it's a different package.
So it says that foo is not public in basic demo and cannot be accessed from outside package.
So let's.
Next, let's make it.
Let's make it public.
Even if you make it protected.
It is still fine.
Let's let me just show it.
Protected is similar to default access, but it can also be accessed in subclasses and those subclasses
can be in the same package or in or outside of the package.
You see from student test.
We can still access it, but.
From here it is still not accessible.
From basics demo test because basic demo test is not a subclass of basics demo.
But like I said earlier, basics subclasses will be dealt later, so let's not worry about it.
So let's just make it public now.
That's the last one.
So let's go ahead and recompile our basics demo class.
And obviously it will be accessible from Student Test two and now it will be accessible from basic demo
test because it is part of the API now.
So it compiled fine.
So that's with the public modifier.
So if you make it public, it means that any code can access it, any code outside of this package.
And we say that it is part of the API.
Now this one can use other other private classes to other private methods, but those methods will not
be accessible outside of the package.
So as you can see this public, private and all, so they are allowing us to define certain restrictions
on what is accessible outside of the package and what is not.
Now let's quickly look at Java API itself.
So in Java we have this class code as ArrayList, which will be discussed later, which is a data structure
and it is part of the Java package and it is very widely used.
So within the ArrayList, let me show you the API.
So this is the API.
So I'm accessing it from the from the browser.
So this is the ArrayList class and it has all of these methods.
And the first method here is add method which is adding an element at certain position, at certain
index position.
So let me just show you the source code.
So the method is here, this one.
So this is the method.
So it is public and hence it is visible here as part of the API and anybody can use it.
We will also be using it later.
But this method internally, as you can see it is using few other methods.
Now you see this method, let me go into this method.
So this method called range check for add is then private method.
So it is only accessible from within this class.
So if you look at here, there is no range check method.
So if you go here, scroll down, you won't see that because it is private though it is still part of
our list.
It is only used internally within that.
So we will only be using the methods that are relevant to us.
Only those methods are exposed as public methods.
Rest of them will be used internally and those are irrelevant for us.
Who are the users of this class and so should not be displayed to us.
Otherwise they are just irrelevant and we will not be using.
And it's just that we will have to deal with all of those methods.
So we will have another 20 or 30 methods here and they just act as noise.
So that's what it is.
So that's the benefit of access levels.
So we have learned about packages and we have learned how access levels help in accessing only certain
parts of those packages and the remaining will be hidden from the outside world.
So this is what it is.
And there is also another method that this method is that this particular method is accessing called
ensure capacity internal.
So if I click on that, it is also a private method.
So that's about it.
I hope you enjoyed learning about access levels and I will see you in the next lecture.
Thank you and happy coding.