Hi there.
This is the LA Room.
And welcome back.
Let's not learn about the next type of operators called comparison operators.
There are six comparison operators and they are very straightforward and they are also referred to as
relational operators.
And a comparison operator, as the name suggests, is used for comparing one operand with another option.
Let's consider a student object and the student has an H.
And let's say if we want to compare age with some value, let's say if we want to check if the H is
greater than a value like 21 here, greater than is the comparison operator.
And this is a comparison operation.
So it is comparing H with 21 and it evaluates to either a true or a false.
So a comparison operation basically evaluates to a boolean value, which means that a comparison operation
represents a condition and such conditions are very useful and control flow statements like an F statement.
In the previous section we looked at the F statement and an F statement checks for a condition, and
if the condition is true, then it executes a block of code.
And one of the subsequent lectures we will look at other control flow statements and we will also look
at the F statement in detail.
So let's go ahead and construct a simple statement here.
So let's say F age is greater than 21.
Then we want to print some value.
So let's say H is.
25.
So if age is 21, then we want to print some value.
Let's say we want to print.
A text called graduate student.
So if age is greater than 21, it means it's a graduate student.
Otherwise it is an undergraduate student.
So let's just assume so here.
This method is called as comparison operators, and it is the basic stream of class and we are just
invoking it from the main method here.
So let me just go ahead and compile and execute that.
That's it.
So it prints a graduate student because age is 25 and it is greater than 21.
So this is one of the reasons it is called as relational operator because you're kind of checking a
relation between age and this particular letter.
Now, let's go ahead and look at other operators.
And for that, let me just use some print statements.
It would be more easier to look at those different operators.
So here they are.
So let me copy them.
Here they are.
So H Field is still there.
And in the first statement we are printing F ages greater than 21.
So we are not using an F statement.
But here also we are going to evaluate this expression because we are we are using this parentheses
and these parentheses will allow us to evaluate this particular condition.
So here we have all of the different comparison operators in the first statement we have greater than
and in the second statement we are checking f age is greater than or equal to 21.
So we are just printing this expression here in the text so that we can see it in the output.
And the next one is age is less than 21, age is less than or equal to 21.
And here this is called as equal to operation.
And we are checking if age is equal to 21.
And in this case, we are checking if age is not equal to 21.
So it is an exclamation mark followed by equal to and both of these here, the last ones are referred
to as equality operators.
And this is equal to and this is not equal to equal to sometimes is also referred to as equivalent operator
and not equal to is sometimes referred to as not equivalent operator.
So here we are going to check if age is greater than 21.
Since age is 25, it is obviously greater than 21.
And this expression will evaluate to true and and that will be printed in the output.
So if you enclose this and a parentheses like this, then it would get evaluated.
So we don't really have to have an F condition if statement like this.
So in this case, in the second case, age is 25 and it is greater than or equal to 21.
So that that is also true.
So it will print a true third condition will be false because age is less than 21.
So let me just go ahead and compile and print this.
Here it is.
So it's just the same thing.
So age is 25 and when it is greater than 21, it prints true.
In the second statement it is greater than or equal to 21.
So it prints true.
Third, it is false because age is not less than 21.
Here we are checking if age is less than 21 and that's not true.
So it prints false even.
This also is false because it is not less than or equal to 21 and age is equal to 21 is also false because
age is 25, but here age is 25 and it is not equal to 21 and hence this printing.
True.
Now let's change this to 21.
So it's just easy comparisons.
Here it is.
Age is 21, so age greater than 21 would be false because 21 is greater than 21 is false.
But this one is true because here age is 21 and it is greater than or equal to 21.
So the equal to part is true.
And because of that it evaluates to true.
Age is less than 21 is false.
Age is less than or equal to 21 is once again true because we have equal to here an age equal to 21
is true.
Age not equal to 21 is false, right?
21 is not equal to 21 is false because they are equal.
So let's just make it 20 and very straightforward.
But I still want to.
Run through that example to.
So age is 20.
So 20 greater than 21 is false.
20 greater than or equal to 21 is false.
20 less than 21 is true.
20 less than or equal to.
21 is true.
20 equals to 21 is false and 20 not equal to 21 as true.
So that's it.
So those are the different operators.
Now here the first four operators are applicable to only primitive numeric types.
So primitive numeric types would be all primitive types except boolean.
Now you may also recall that in arithmetic operations also all of the arithmetic operators are applicable
to only primitive numeric types and so they are not applicable to two boolean operations.
So the same goes with the first four operators.
However, the last two operators, the equality operators, would apply for all of the primitive types.
So for example, if let's consider that this variable is boolean and Boolean less than or equal to something
like true or false just doesn't make sense.
Right?
But if boolean is equal to true or if it is not equal to true is something that is meaningful and it
is valid.
Let's actually go ahead and also test this.
Let's say we have a variable called Ease International, whether the student is international or not.
So let's say it is true and let's check this.
So I have three more statements here.
Let me just copy them.
So we just have these final three statements less than or equal to, equal to or not equal to over here.
So we are just checking f is international is less than equal to true or is equal to true or not equal
to true.
Straightforward.
So.
So it gives a compilation error because the first one is invalid.
We are checking if it is international is less than or equal to true.
So it says bad operand types for binary operator less than or equal to because boolean cannot be used
with this particular operator and hence it says that it is a bad operand type.
So we cannot use a boolean here for this comparison operator, but it works with equal to or not equal
to.
So let me just recompile and execute.
Okay.
Here it is.
So it says for ease.
International was true.
True.
Equal to true will return a true and true.
Not equal to true is a false right true.
Equal to true is true.
So if both of them are true and we have the symbol not equal to it would be a false.
So that's that.
So equal equality here, equality operators, which are both of these, they are applicable to all of
the parameters.
Now these equality operators are also applicable to object references.
So if you recall, we created this student class in the previous section, the student class.
So let's create two objects here.
Let's say student.
S one.
Student.
And it takes two parameters to the constructor.
One is thousand, which is the ID and the other one is the name of the student.
So let's just pass my name.
Row.
And let's create another object as to and it is also referencing a new student object, but it has the
same state.
So we are passing the same values, but they are still two different objects.
Right?
So let me.
Print these two statements.
So we are just checking if one is equal to S2 or S1 is not equal to S2.
So S1 is equal to S2 would be false because both of these are referencing two different objects.
Even though the state is same, they are still two different objects in the memory and they have separate
memory addresses and S1 is S1 is pointing to one of the objects.
So it holds the memory address of this object as two holds the memory address of this object.
And so those memory addresses are different.
So let's just compile.
As you can see for us, one is equal to se two.
It returns a false and for us one not equal to SE two, it returns true.
So this is also called US identity comparison.
Doing such kind of a comparison is also called US Identity comparison and it is also done very commonly
in many of the Java classes.
For instance, there is this class called Less Object, which we will see later when dealing with inheritance
and other object oriented concepts.
And it has a method called equals, and the method compares the input object with the current object.
The current object is referenced by this, and for that it is using this equal to operation.
So that's one example from the Java Library.
Now let's go back.
And so that's one thing.
And equality, such equality operators are also very useful for doing something called as null checks.
So that's one example.
So let's just write a simple method here.
Let's say let's call it this update and let's pass, let's just pass null to that method and let's also
pass some value.
Let's say, John.
The example should be clear in a bed.
So.
Here.
It said the first method parameter is student say as.
And the second one is actually name string.
And we just want to update the name of the student that is passed to this method, but we are still
passing now.
So the student object class has this variable called name and we are just updating it.
So we'll just say start name equals to name the new name that is passed here.
That's it.
And we return a true.
So this is the thing.
But this will give us another pointer.
Exception memory compile.
So it gives an error called null pointer.
Exception and exceptions will be dealt later.
But the reason it is giving is this because as is null and if we invoke anything on null, we get another
pointer exception.
And we have discussed it earlier too.
So the method should not be passed null.
So that is the that is the thing.
But sometimes, sometimes it may still be invoked with null.
Some developers might pass null.
So we need to take certain safety measures so we will say as equal to null.
In this case, we return a false.
So for SS not then we return a false.
So in this case.
See.
So the method has executed, has been invoked, and it executed successfully.
And if you pass as one, for example, as one, then as one's name will be updated.
Although there is nothing being printed and the method.
But still it would.
These last two statements will get executed because as will not be equal to none.
So this such kind of a check is called as parameter validation.
Sometimes methods do this because the invoke might pass a value such as null, which shouldn't be passed.
So in order to safeguard against that, they would do such kind of parameter validation.
And if it is not equal to null only then the rest of the method will be executed.
So this is one of the use cases and we will also look at one more use case and when learning about logical
operators in a subsequent lecture.
So it is also useful.
NULL checks are also useful.
The equality and not equality operators are useful for performing null checks and they are very useful
for that.
So that's about it.
That's about the comparison operators.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.