So far we created entities managers and feel constant exporting classes not its Creator didn't need
it for our application.
That is the database itself will create a class called data store.
Now in the resources section I'm adding 4 x files called user book movie and web link.
These files include the raw data needed for our application.
In this first version we will simply copy those values on hard code them in the data stored class laded
we will extend the project to direct read from those files.
But for now we'll be using the hardcoded values.
Let me just show you those files.
And for the user to find I will show you how to created.
So this is the book file.
Here it is.
And these are this is the raw data and the.
So this is one row andere within each and all the values are pops up record tab delimited.
So this is the ID field this is the title of the book.
This is the year when it was published and this is the publisher name.
And here this is the author's name.
Sometimes there can be multiple authors like in this case here.
And this is the genré and this is the rating.
And let's not worry about this final flip here.
It is related to a kid friendly feature.
And similarly we a book or movie free movie file here and this is the idea once again and the name of
the title of the movie year when it was released cast and director John Gray I am repudiating And once
again you can ignore this.
And similarly we have the book the weblink here.
And it has some for use here the idea and there is a you are all here.
And here we have the host information
which is nothing but the just the domain name off that you are.
And this is the Pitre here.
So those are the three files.
So let's just go ahead and create the user file.
So just right click on which is a project say name a new and click on this untidy text file because
we want to create a text file.
Let me just copy those values here for the user fine.
And let's just head control as and it is asking us to set up the page folder since we are dealing with
the project we just really don't know just click that and let's just call it user.
So that's the user ex-fighter.
And if we go here in on our desk so within JRD within really our project you can see that all the forefronts
God created had book we use and web link.
So those are the four files and you can find them in the resource section.
So let's just go ahead now and create the class the data store class and camarade semantics word or
three here which is like the root of the package structure
.
Class called it a store in the package sig com.
So in a calm semantics word through Leo and that's it.
So we have data store.
Now within this package.
So first thing is let's create the data structures needed to hold the data.
So let's create a data structure to hold just the users information.
Static.
So user information can be stored in a user array.
You can have five users initially.
That's just import.
Next let's create the data structure to hold.
Bookmark information just the bookmarks so it needs to be a two dimensional array because we have different
kinds of bookmarks so we need one dimension for that type.
And the other for the actual bookmarks
Coretta's bookmarks.
So we have three types and each type can have five bookmarks.
And let's also create one to hold the user bookmarks.
So whenever a user bookmarks a particular bookmark so it needs to be stored in some data structure let's
create one for that.
If you remember we hired this entity called user bookmark.
So that's also in court here in this bookmark here and it's Connard as user bookmarks.
Now there are five users and each user can bookmark five of them.
So that's the Lamech we how that's something for this.
So those are the three data structures that we have now.
It's not very good to hardcore these values here.
So let's use that straight to our students to be factor of this.
So let's go here and it's just right quick Reflektor and let's say extract constant and we can call
it as Dr. underscore user underskirt can't we do the same thing for here.
For sure we extract constant.
So it's the type so let's call it as bookmarks.
I don't
know this says the code the limits within each type.
So let's also rename this let's call it a bookmark call and type.
So that's the bookmark call and prototype.
So this is simply the user count.
And this is
the limit on the number of bookmarks that a user can bookmark so that Scollard does user bookmarklet
.
OK.
So those are the ones that we have next.
That's right Fuma that's now.
That's right a method called load data which is responsible for loading the data.
So let's make it a public topic.
LLOYD
So let's have separate methods to load users babblings.
Movies and books.
So first method let's call it does more users.
Now let's just make this as a private matter.
So initially we will call this method loading dock to load the data on dockworker internally invoke
all the private methods to load all the data for needed for the application
.
So the data that has to go into this idea needs to be stored into this array so fosters let's say users
who are they use 0 0 and let's get the values from or file the Ostrow.
So these are the values.
So these are all DAPs operator.
Let's just make it camos operator.
So the way we would do it is we would invoke.
If you look at the managers so we're going to call this method create user end user manager.
Again we are going to pass all those values from there.
So let's call it as a user manager.
Now let's get to get an instance method which returns a singleton is it not.
So it's just.
HARLOW This auto generated content.
So Id Dexters email
first is the password.
Next this is John as the host name.
This is the last name we just have a single character here or last name.
Now this is gender or gender
it's your
gender is actually supposed to be.
And so let's just go here and for male.
So if you look at gender here one stands for male it is zero.
So let's just go ahead and
let's just say gender dark mean so let's make use of the constant exploding glass here.
So that's how re-initialize we passed that.
The last one is the user which is a user type.
So if you go into user type.
So here we have user.
So let's just say user Ibaraki user
so that's the first rule.
So let me just take this offline and create the rest of the rules popular the rest of the rules and
then I will.
And then I will show you the entire method.
OK.
Here are the rest of the rules.
So we have five users here.
And just like the first rule we have we are populating the rest of the rules.
Also That's about the users on a new motor Kollek Lord doublings has been added.
I'm actually so that's popular does.
So before this goes into the bookmarks data structure.
So let's see.
So it's a two dimensional array.
So in the first dimension we are going to add on only babblings.
So within the first dimension we are going to add the first bookmark.
OK so that's the first bookmark.
And let's use the bookmark manager.
You get instance mattered.
And we already have this method called create weblink.
Now we just need to copy the values from our wabbling file.
So let me disclose this user right here.
You notice we don't need that last column for now.
So let's just name it
.
And this is the second argument.
It's a string
.
Third is the website you are ill.
And then there's string
Portlands the host information.
So let me just go ahead.
Offline and come back and show you the rest of the rows.
OK here are the rest of the rules.
Earlier there was a minor mistake that we made the index we had it as a run which is supposed to be
zero.
So that's corrected.
So we have all the babblings here in 0 8 row.
And so these are the column values and here we how all the blanks.
OK let's also call this to be consistent.
Let's make this L gap l ramblings and it's just do the same here and there.
So that's what blanks the next let's do it for movies no movies
good books.
So I mean just highlighted this create matter
create it to us.
So let's just go ahead and finish this thing first.
Let me just copy here.
That's how users first mumblings next.
And movies here.
So that's bookmarks.
So it's a new dimension in this dimension with how we won the first one.
As So the zero it raw as far ramblings.
So this one for the first one is for movies.
Next when we have Brooksville hybrids do.
Now the zeroth element within this dimension.
Copy this
.
Let's create a movie.
That's what we have.
And let's get the values from first here.
Let's ignore the last one here and it's just copy all of this
the
Citizen Kane and rustic movie.
And I guess this is cast here.
So it's a string array because there are cast has multiple values.
So let's do this new
next is directors directors can also be multiple directors.
So that's how I ended Stringer here
.
Next is genré.
We don't really let's make use of that.
And it's a classics
Lassman is the raping the I am the in.
So let me just go ahead and finish up.
Seems like you're missing something here.
So let's just go to Mark manager.
I do.
Sorry it's here and it's Id need to that profile of you are.
OK.
So let's put an M.D. over there because we don't have a profile of you on here.
All we are good.
So let me just go ahead and finish this method and I will also offer up the lord books matter and then
we can review the methods.
OK.
So the rest of the data has also been populated.
So within the last movies we have the rest of the Read here for all the different columns.
So this is the leader and the same thing has been done for books.
Sort of goes into the second row it's a new type.
And the data has been copied from the book filed here or here.
So that is here is the order list.
So it is a string theory and be made use of those constant exporting class book genré in order to set
up the genré information.
So this is notebook's.
So really with this we have all the data that's needed.
Now let's also ired couple of things.
Let's say we want to get hurt for this so that it can be invoked from some other process.
So that's how together for users and bookmarks.
So this is going to source ironer said Jondrette getters and setters.
Let's just how only get so let's say let's do that.
And it's created here is just fine.
Let's also do the same thing for bookmarks.
So that will written all the bookmarks so that's how to get her for that
.
So those are on the bookmarks now.
So that's there they just don't glass.
So we have some data structures here for holding the data.
And in order to populate the data we created this last date which is a public matter and it has it.
It didn't work for private methods for loading day for users of eyeblink movies and books and we also
have the guidelines for users and bookmarks.
So that started us store class for now.