Hi there.
This is the room.
And welcome back.
Let's now continue our discussion on the standard functional interfaces.
In the previous lecture, we have looked at the two standard functional interfaces predicate and function.
And let's now look at two more standard functional interfaces, consumer and supplier.
And together, these four functional interfaces form the core standard functional interfaces within
the Java utility function package.
So consumer, as the name implies, is used for consuming something.
It has a single method called accept, and it takes a parameter.
And within the body we just consume that parameter.
We do something with the past argument and the method returns a void where a supplier, as the name
implies, supply something and it has a single method called get.
And it does not take any parameter, but it returns something.
And what it returns is dependent on that type argument that we pass to the supplier.
So let's just go ahead and look at the two new functional interfaces.
And the first one that we are going to look at is consumer.
And after that, we look at supplier.
So here is the same code from the previous demo.
So here we have the predicate.
And if the document passes the predicate, then we are applying bunch of transformation transformations
using the function here and we are printing the document.
So out of the four documents, two of them are passing the predicate and we are printing the names here.
Now what we can do is instead of printing it this way, we will use the consumer now.
So for that, what we are going to do is we are going to add those documents into an array list.
So have declared a new array list here called target documents.
And we are going to add these documents into this target documents array list because they are the target
documents.
Out of the four documents, we have to target documents which have passed the predicate.
So they are being added here now target documents.
So this is an array list.
And on an array list we can invoke the for each method.
Now for each method is inherited from Iterable.
We know that list interface extends collection interface and collection interface in turn extends iterable
interface and Iterable interface defines the for each method.
And if you recall, we discussed that the for each method in the iterator lecture in the collections
framework chapter and the for each method actually takes a consumer as an input.
And what it does is it invokes the consumer on each of the elements in the list.
That's what it does, and that's what we are going to do.
We are going to invoke the for each method and we are going to pass a println statement here using a
lambda and that would print the document.
So we don't need to iterate through the documents in this way.
The method will take care of that.
So let's go ahead and copy this.
Here it is.
You can see that it takes a consumer and we are calling it as action, which means that this action
is going to be performed on each of the elements in the list.
Let's pass up lambda here.
So it would be the document.
Want to simply pass the document.
So we don't need the clearances because it's just a single statement that we have and we are having
it as an expression Here, let me run this.
So as you can see, we have the same output.
So that's all there is to consumer.
So consumer has a single method called accept and that accept the logic for that is being provided here.
So that's with that.
Now for Supplier, let's look at a very interesting example.
So out of the two documents, let's say if any of the documents has a length of greater than 80 characters,
then we need to throw an exception.
So we need to log that message.
We need to print that message to the console.
So that's what we want to do here.
So out of these two documents, the second document is actually has a size that is greater than 80.
So let's go ahead and let's implement this.
Now here, let's say, doc.
Land.
Greater than 80.
Through an exception.
On the message can be.
Oversized document.
Now, if it is that, let's just print.
So there is a print method that I have already written and the print method is here.
It's a static method in the same class.
So the print method takes a supplier as input and we are simply this is a supplier is a variable and
we are invoking the get method and we are printing it.
But what we are doing here is we want to print this message only when this Boolean flag there is a Boolean
flag here called error flag.
If it is true, only then we want to print it.
Otherwise we do not want to print it.
So this printing is controlled by that flag.
Now let's pass the the variable here, the lambda here.
So the get method does not take any parameters.
So it is an empty parenthesis.
And what we want to print is the message.
So let's say get message here and let's also append something.
Let's say a tilde here.
And the dock itself.
So here we are actually capturing this.
Lambda is capturing the the variable doc from the enclosed scope.
So that's how we are capturing and we discussed about capturing earlier.
So that's what it is.
Now, let me just run this.
So one of the documents is oversized and this is what we are seeing.
Now, the cool thing is if I turn this into false, it's not going to print, obviously.
But what is going to happen is this.
So this concatenation here would happen only if the get is invoked.
So if the flag is false, the Sprint statement will not be invoked and this will not get printed.
But this concatenation is also not happening.
So that's the beauty of this of this approach, of this idiom.
It's called a deferred execution.
So that is happening because we are having supplier as a parameter here.
So only at the instance when Get is invoked, this concatenation of these strings happen now instead
of a supplier.
If this was a string here and if we were passing only the string, only the concatenation part in that
in that case, the concatenation happens right away.
So even if you have the flag as false here and if you are printing it, the concatenation would have
happened.
So obviously that is going to be slow.
And if this message if this particular print method is going to get involved millions of times, then
it's going to be costly.
So that is how this is avoided.
So this is a very nice idiom and it is already adopted in the Java API.
So within the Java API there is something called as a logging framework in the Java logging package
and in professional projects you would be using a logging framework instead of printing it using a println
statement.
That's what you would be doing.
And Java has comes with its own logging framework.
But there are also other really good third party frameworks, and one of them is the Log Forge framework.
It's a logging framework, and you have to learn about logging also.
And obviously if you're working for a project in a professional environment, you would be using some
logging framework.
So they have already adopted something like this and they are using a supplier and they use it in this
way.
So let's go ahead and look at the logging framework just for your information.
But before doing that, let's also look at the API for the standard function interfaces.
Okay.
Here it is.
So this is the Java nine API and we are looking at all these packages here in the left.
So these are the interfaces from the Java dot dot function.
So these are the standard interfaces and you can see the function here.
Then you can see predicate supplier and consumer is also there and there is the by versions, by consumer,
by function, by predicate and these are all the different things.
And here is the supplier interface and the supplier just has a single method called get.
Now here there is in this API, you can also this thing called as use and if you click on use here,
it will show you all the places in the Java API where the supply supplier interface is being used.
So supplier interface is being used in all of these different packages.
As you can see, there are the different packages, Java line module, Java concurrent logging and we
are going to look at that also and the Streams API here, Java Stream.
So these are the different places where it is used.
And if you scroll down further, you can see where exactly the supplier is used within those packages.
So for example, in the Java logging, let me show you that.
Here it is.
So it is being used in all of these methods and in the logging framework.
And so there is.
So within the larger framework there is a class called logger and supplier is being used in the logging
framework in the Java logging.
So here is the logger class.
And this logger class, for example, is using supplier over here.
So this is the method that you would invoke to log message, but there is also an overloaded method
called log.
Here it is, log.
So it also accepts a level and it also accepts a message.
So now what is level?
So level is here, let me open this.
So level is here it is level.
It's also in Java logging.
So there are different levels that you can set.
So in your logging framework you can set a logging level as fine.
And once you do that and whenever you want to log a message, you would invoke one of these methods.
Log this method or log of the supplier method, and you can pass an appropriate logging level along
with the message.
Now here, if the if the logging level was set to fine and if you are invoking the log method with severe,
then it would print the message, it would log the message.
But if you pass a logging level of finder, then it will not log the message.
So anything above this, so the logging was set as fine the logging level.
So during the invocation of the log method, if you pass any any log level which is greater than or
equal to fine, then it would print the message.
Otherwise it will not print the message.
And these logging messages can be printed either to the console or they can also be printed to some
file, and all of that can be set up.
Typically, you would log them to some file and you would generate such files every single day, and
they will also have some timestamps in the name so that can be done.
So so these log levels are just like the Boolean flag that we have seen in our example in our demo.
So it's just like that.
And they are also using this idioms like the string and the supplier.
So typically you would want to use a supplier and do it the way we have done it.
So that way it would be much more efficient.
So if there is any concatenation happening, that's when it will be useful.
And if the level is not, if it is going to be less than the level that was specified initially, then
the the method will not be invoked on the concatenation will not happen.
So that's what this so the idiom is being followed here.
So let's go back to this interface.
And as you can see, these are all the standard interfaces.
Now, one final thing that I want to tell you is there are also these functional interfaces, standard
function interfaces specific to primitives.
Here there is one called int consumer to double function.
So let me show you this enter to double function.
So function we know just as the transformation it applies the transformation on some input and return
some output.
Ah if you if you recall.
But here it takes because it says int to double.
So basically there is a conversion from int to some doubles.
So the method name is applied as double and it takes an end and it returns a double.
Now this is needed you would you want to use this if you are working with primitives, but if you use
if you're using primitives and if you are going to use the function class, the function functional
interface interface, then the boxing will happen or boxing will have come into play.
And we know that that's very inefficient.
So whenever you are dealing with primitives, you would want to look at this primitive specializations
within the standard functional interfaces.
So this is what we have.
So do take a look at this.
They are very simple.
So you know how to work with the with the core function interface and it's just a specialization.
So you can look at that.
You can just check out all the different things that we have here.
Long Predicate.
So this would take a long variable and here it is test method and it would return a boolean.
Now we also have by consumer by function, we already discussed that.
So this is the consumer.
Consumer would have this accept method.
Then we also have the function.
Function will use apply apply DX and it returns an R and there are also some default methods we already
looked at.
And then so you can check out these functional interfaces and also those specialization interfaces for
primitives and do check out the logging framework and you can learn about it and start using it also.
So that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.