Hi there.
This is 010.
And welcome back.
So we looked at how we can interact with the database directly from the command line.
Now let's see how we can do it from our Java programs.
And for that, we will be using the GBK API and GBK.
As you may know, stands for Java database connectivity, which means that it has something to do with
connecting to the database.
And Jtbc relies on something called a Jtbc driver for interacting with the database.
In this lecture we will install a gypsy driver and in the next lecture we will see how we can make our
project load the data from the database which we created earlier.
Now JBC API is a standard database independent interface.
Which means that it can be used to interact with different data sources like the different databases
or even other tabular data sources like Excel spreadsheets and flat files.
But typically we use it to interact with databases rather than these other types of files like Excel
spreadsheets and FLAC files.
And personally, also, I have never had to use G.P.S. API to interact with anything other than a database.
On database API mainly comprises of these two packages Java, SQL and Java.
SQL.
Java SQL is regarded as the core GBC API and Java SQL extends the functionality in Java SQL and is mainly
used in Java applications where things like database connection pooling come into play.
But to interact with a specific data source, a GDB driver that is specific to that source would be
needed.
And the GDP driver is simply a collection of classes.
For instance, to interact with my SQL, we need a key driver that is specific to my SQL.
Now there are four types of GVC drivers and they are type one driver, type two driver, type three
and type four driver.
So very easy to remember.
And here they are shown from left to right in red boxes.
So type one is the leftmost one and type four is the rightmost one.
As you may notice, they are also referred to by alternate names.
Type one, for instance, is also referred to as GBC or EBC bridge driver, where OTB stands for open
database connectivity.
Bipolar is actually referred to as gypsy driver itself.
So the gypsy driver is called as jtbc driver itself.
Of these four, we will be using the type four driver, which is written purely in Java and we will
soon download the one that is specific to my SQL as we are using my SQL database.
Type four is also one of the most commonly used drivers, and according to one Java performance book,
its author Scott Ochs mentions that apart from type for Driver, Type two driver is also widely used
and he recommends avoiding the type one driver as its performance, it seems, is bad.
And he also says that type three is not that widely adopted.
Also, as we can see here, type for driver interacts directly with the database while others have an
additional layer which does the actual communication with the database.
And in case of type one and type two, we need to actually install additional software specific to the
database with which we are interacting.
While Type three uses some middleware for interacting with the database and that middleware will take
care of interacting with any of the databases, now let's not get into the details anymore.
And if you're interested, you can Google for them and learn more about them.
But it would suffice to know that type two and type four are the most commonly used ones, and we will
be using type four.
So let's go ahead and download the type for Driver for my SQL.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and search for my SQL.
Community server download.
Which is what we have searched for earlier when installing my SQL Community Server.
So it's going to be the same search query and same length that we are clicking on.
But since we have already downloaded community server, all we need to do is just click here, which
is the MySQL connectors.
And these are links to the different drivers.
And for Java, the GBC driver for that we have to click here.
This is for Java and you can also see that they have drivers for dot net, Node.js, Python and so on.
But this is what we are interested in.
You have to just click on that.
Once you do that, just go ahead and download one of these.
Maybe you can download the zip version here and just unzip it.
And once you unzip it, you will see a folder and within that folder you will find a jar file.
And that's the GBC driver, which we need.
So just go ahead and do that.
I have already done that.
And let me open my.
ED So this is the.
ED So the first thing is to install the GBC driver and there is some code written here.
So as we said that as we said, GDC API is going to use the GBC driver.
So for that, what needs to happen is we need to load the GBC driver.
So in order to load the driver, so this is the class that is needed from the jar file.
So we are going to load this class.
And what this class does is it is going to register itself when we load it, it's going to register
itself with another class within the GBC API which is called US Driver Manager and it is in the Java
SQL package, it's called Driver Manager.
So that's how it is done.
So this is one way of loading it or we can simply even do this, just create an instance of that class.
But since we still did not add the Java file to our build path, we have this compilation error.
Now, if you are not using this ID eclipse, then you have to put the Java file in the class path.
But since we are using it, let's go ahead and add it to our build path.
So here is the demo and the trillium.
Since we are going to refactor Trello, let's go ahead and click on properties here.
And within the jour belt path.
So we go into libraries and here we say add external jars and I have a list of jars here.
So this is the 15.1.44 slash bin here hyphen bin.
So this is an older version that I had, but this is the one that I have downloaded recently.
So and it is the latest version.
Just click on that say apply.
And now you can see that there is no more compilation error because it has been added.
So let me comment that because one of the approaches is good enough, so so we can do this.
And so this code has been written within the data store class.
In our, in our project.
We know that data store is from where we load the data.
It was being used as the database.
But since now we are going to use a real database.
So we will be loading the data from the database from within this file, so we will change some code.
So here is one way of doing it, and this is the second way of doing it.
A third way of loading the driver is via system dot set property and you will set this key drivers and
you will say that we need to load this as the driver.
So we are just using the same name here also.
So that's one way of doing it.
Or the third way is to use the driver manager class itself directly and you will invoke this method
called registered driver and you will pass an instance of this driver class, which is from the Jar
file, which we just downloaded.
So you can see that the Jar file has been added here once we have imported it.
So that's it.
So let me stop here.
So this is the first step, which is to install the GBK driver and it helps in connecting to the database
and interacting with the database.
And in the next lecture we will actually load the data and we will see that in the next lecture.
So see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.