Hello there.
This is the Domaine de la Rue.
And welcome back.
We already saw how a basic enum with just a simple collection of constants can evolve over time to include
state and behavior.
Right now, let's take this process a step further by actually associating behavior that is specific
to each enum constant.
Earlier, the behavior was identical across all constants.
Now we are talking about behavior that is specific to each enum constant.
And that's what the title here says enum but constant, specific behavior.
So let's see how that can be done.
It can be done in two ways.
One is via a switch statement, while the other is using constant specific methods.
Both the methods are discussed in item 30 in effective Java, which we mentioned earlier.
It's a comprehensive item and it recommends using enum instead of int enum pattern.
Here is how it is done using a switch statement.
And this is our familiar book class with the nested enum book genre.
Only the method in the red box is new here and it is named as is kid friendly and it has a single parameter
h.
We can assume that the input h could be of a particular user and this method would be invoked on the
genre of a particular book.
That is a book has a genre which would be an enum constant like biography.
And if we need to know whether this book can be shown to a particular user, we can invoke this method
is kid friendly on the books genre and we can pass that user's age.
Now in the method we have a switch statement, the switch expression, which is nothing but the expression
in the parentheses.
Following the switch key word is the dis reference.
This reference would be the enum constant on which this method is kid friendly is invoked.
And this reference would be matched with the case labels, which are the enum constants.
The keys block corresponding to each enum constant has the behavior that is specific to that particular
constant.
For instance, here for the constant biography, the logic is the condition age greater than or equal
to min age to read, manage to read for biography is well and so a true would be retained only if the
input age is greater than or equal to 12.
You may recall from our switch statement lecture from section four, that speech expression can be of
enum type two.
You may recall that a speech expression can be of three types, integer string or an enum.
And now we know how we can use them in a switch statement.
Now a limitation with using such a switch block is that if we add a new enum constant, then we may
also have to remember to add a new case block in our switch statement, as that enum constant might
have its own logic to determine whether a user can be shown the books that it represents.
So the developer has to be alert in adding the behavior that is specific to the new constant.
Otherwise, by default, defaults would be returned at runtime, and it may result in displaying books
that should not be shown to certain users.
Now this limitation can be avoided using the second approach for providing constant, specific behavior.
And here is the second approach.
The new code is once again highlighted in the red box.
This approach is interesting, as you can see that each constant is associated with a body that starts
on ends with curly braces.
And this body is referred to as constant, specific class body.
And it can have both variables as well as methods.
And the methods are referred to as constant specific method implementations.
And in this example, we don't have any variables, but you can certainly define them outside of the
constant specific methods, just like any class.
So essentially the constant specific behavior that was part of case blocks in the switch based design
are now moved into constant specific bodies.
And the method name in both the bodies is still is quite friendly.
Another limitation with the switch based design about forcing the developer to add a constant specific
behavior is addressed here as this design requires adding an abstract friendly method in the enum type.
As we can see here.
Now, this would force the developer to also add an implementation of this method with every newly added
enum constant.
And I'm sure you would agree that it's a pretty cool design.
Now under the hood.
This is what is happening for each constant specific class body definition.
The compiler creates an anonymous class that extends the enum type book genre.
Recall that internally book genre will be translated into a final class.
But now in this case, since we have anonymous classes extending it, it is no longer final.
So if we have enough constants with constant specific class bodies, then the enum type will no longer
be final.
Also, when we say we will have anonymous classes, it means that we have classes created with names
such as book dollar, book, genre, dollar sum number.
In our example, we will have two anonymous classes.
So it will be book dollar.
Book genre dollar one.
Dollar two.
So in the class that corresponds to book genre, each constant will be an instance of the corresponding
anonymous class, which extends book genre.
Previously, each constant was an instance of book genre itself.
Now any variable declared in the enum and is accessed within a constant specific body should have an
access level of at least default.
You may guess the reason for that.
Since variable is part of enum type and if it is declared as private, then it will not be accessible
in any of the constant, specific anonymous classes that are subtypes of the enum type.
So it's got to be at least default access level.
You can see here that it is declared as protected.
And finally, the anonymous class will not maintain a hidden reference to the enclosing class, which
is the book class, as the anonymous class is created in a static context.
Static context is the enum book genre, which we know is implicitly static as it is a nested enum.
You may recall from our discussion on inner classes that they maintain hidden references to enclosing
classes for accessing their instance members.
So those are the two ways of associating constant specific behavior.
Generally, I think such constant, specific behavior is more of an exotic feature and may not be commonly
encountered.
But if we need it, we know how to do it.
Now let's head over to our editor to do a quick demo of both the methods.
OC.
Here is the ebook class with the nested enum book genre.
So first let's go ahead and locate the switch based design.
So in the switch based design, we have added this new method.
So everything is same as we have seen in the slides.
So this is the new method is kid friendly and it has the switch statement, switch off this.
And here are the case labels, which are the enum constants.
And everything else is just same.
Now here in the main method, we are iterating both the enum constants.
And the only thing I have added is this one let's call it is kid friendly.
And we are passing a value of 25 here.
And these are the two constants.
So the main method is outside of the nested book genre.
Right.
So let's just go ahead and run this first.
So the in the first iteration we are having the enum constant biography.
And we were passing the value 25, which is greater than or equal to 12.
So if you go here.
Here it is.
This is the logic.
It should be greater than or equal to manage to read and manage to read.
Worst of all and age will be 25.
So it is invoked.
This method is invoked on an enum constant and as you can see, it returns a true because a R 25 is
greater than or equal to 12 and which means that it is kid friendly.
Now in the second iteration it is harder and for horror it is returning false because by default the
logic returns a false.
So there is no really specific logic here like this.
So it simply returns false, which means that any horror book is not kid friendly.
So that's the switch based design.
Okay.
And let's go ahead and look at the second one, the limitation with the switch based design.
We know that if we add a new constant here, then we should also remember that we need to add any corresponding
specific behavior here.
We need to introduce a new case.
BLOCK Now, let's go ahead and.
It's just.
Copy this.
Let's put our constant, specific class body.
Here is is kid friendly content.
So let's just certain.
Thus.
That's it.
Now for the second one.
We'll still be same.
Okay.
Now here we have a compilation error because this has to be at least default.
It needs to have at least a default access level.
Here it is private.
Okay.
Now there is one more compilation error.
It says is kid friendly should be defined in book genre because book genre does not have is kid friendly
yet.
So we need to add our abstract method, right?
So.
Just take this.
And this is what addresses the limitation in the first approach.
So that's it.
So let's go ahead and run it.
So once again is kid friendly is true.
When the book genre it was was a biography and it is false when it is horror.
So that's about it.
And this code will be available in the resources section and thank you and happy coding.