Hi there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at the next type of operators called logical operators.
And there are three of them.
And they have something to do with creating logic, as we will soon see.
And we encounter these operations very frequently in real life, especially in the business world.
Marketing is one area where they are heavily used.
For example, we often see this in shopping malls where they have such marketing strategies.
If you buy two t shirts, you get the third one free.
And if you buy only one of them, then this deal will not be applicable for you.
That's why we have and here making this strategy possible.
That is, if you have bought the first t shirt and you have also bought the second t shirt, then you
get the third free.
In Java.
This notion of and is represented by a logical operator called and operator and it is represented by
2% symbols.
And here is another marketing strategy that we commonly see in electronic stores.
If you buy a particular television or a particular refrigerator by December 31st, you get a 10% discount
on the final price.
So it has to be one of the two products or both of them.
And all here defines the marketing strategy.
And in Java, such an order is represented by a logical operator called or operator, and it is represented
by two pipe symbols.
And here is a different example not marketing.
We see this in banks.
If we apply for a home loan, certain banks look at our past credit history.
That is, they check whether we have a good credit history or not, which means that whether we repaid
all our past loans or not, if the credit history is not good as we see it here, then the home loan
will not be approved.
And in Java, such kind of check is typically represented using a not operator, which is the final
logical operation, and it is represented by an exclamation symbol.
So that's the node operator.
Now, without using logical operators, we may end up writing complex looking code.
For instance, we have already learned about comparison operators.
With comparison operators, we are always testing a single condition, like in this example where the
code inside braces is executed only if age is greater than 35.
But how about if we want to execute some code only when multiple conditions are true?
For example, we may want to execute some code if age is greater than 35 and also salary is greater
than 90,000.
And using comparison operators.
We can do it this way where we have a nested if statement that is an if statement inside another if
statement.
So the first if statement checks whether age is greater than 35 and if it is true only then the inner
if statement would be executed.
That is the inner if statement checks if salary is greater than 90,000 and if that is also true, then
loan is a pro and using and operator.
This can be done much more elegantly.
And here it is.
And this would ensure that the code inside races is executed only if both operations of and operator
are true.
That is, if age is greater than 35 and salary is greater than 90,000.
So even if one of the condition fails, then the body of if statement will not be executed.
As you can see, this is much more cleaner looking code.
Now let's look at the three operators using the same age and salary example.
Let's assume that age of the customer is 37 and salary is 80,000.
And here is the same condition which we saw in the earlier slide with an operator.
The first condition is age greater than 35 and second is salary greater than 90,000.
And and operator returns true only if both operations are true.
Otherwise it returns a false.
In our example, the first condition h greater than 35 is true as H has the value 37 for our customer.
But the second condition fails as the salary we have is not greater than 90,000.
And hence the expression evaluates to false had salary been greater than 90,000?
Then the expression would evaluate to true.
And here is the condition that our operator, we have the same appearance as in the first example or
operator returns a true if at least one of the two options is true.
Otherwise it returns a false since our first condition is true.
This expression evaluates to true, even though the second condition is false.
But if age was not greater than 35, then both conditions would be false and the expression would evaluate
to false.
And here is not operator, which is a unitary operator.
The other two are binary operators and not operator simply returns the inverse of its operator.
That is, if operand is true, it returns a false.
And if operand is false, then it returns a true.
Here, since the expression age is greater than 35 is true, applying not on this expression will return
a false.
So it basically inverts the value of its operand and it is also referred to as logical complement operator.
Essentially what we have here with these logical operations is Boolean algebra and you may have come
across Boolean Algebra in one of your math classes in Boolean Algebra and operation is referred to as
conjunction or as disjunction and not as negation.
We can refer to all these expressions with logical operations as just Boolean expressions.
So these are all Boolean expressions that we are seeing here.
And just for the sake of completeness, let's look at the output of the logical operations for the different
values of its opponents.
If X and Y are the appearance with these values.
Then with X and Y we have a true.
Only when both x and y are true.
And for the rest of the combinations, we have a false.
With X or Y, we have a true when one or both of the options are true.
So we have a true for the first three combinations and a false for the last one, as both X and Y are
false.
Finally for naught, we are just considering x.
So when x is true, as in the first two cases, the output is false.
And when x is false, the output is true.
Now in Boolean Algebras, such a table is referred to as Truth Table, and you may recall it too.
So logical operators take boolean operations and evaluate to a boolean value.
If the operator is something other than boolean, we get a compiler error and control for all statements
are where we see logical operations being commonly used.
Well, we know that.
And and our operators work on their operations and produce a Boolean value.
There is also something very important we need to know about the evaluation of those two options.
With regards to an operator.
If its left operand is false, then the right operand is not even evaluated and the entire expression
simply evaluates to false.
And this makes sense as even if the right operand is evaluated and it happens to be true, the entire
expression still evaluates to false.
Since only left operand is being evaluated in the scenario.
We are referring to an operator as a short circuit operator.
So right operand is evaluated only if left operand is true.
That is right.
Operand is conditionally evaluated rather than always.
And for this reason and operator is also referred to as conditional and operator.
That is evaluation of right of parent is conditionally dependent on evaluation of left operator.
So it's called as conditional and operator.
And with regards to our operation, if left operand is true, then right operant is not evaluated and
it is written.
So our is also a short circuit operator.
Right.
Operated is evaluated only if left operand is false.
And for this reason our operator is also referred to as conditional or as evaluation of write.
Operand is conditionally dependent on the evaluation of left operand.
So that's some optimization there, as sometimes only one opponent is evaluated and that improves performance.
And among the two short circuit operators, the short circuit nature of and operator is also extremely
useful in preventing the null pointer exception.
We know a pointer exception is generated at runtime when an object reference is null and we try to access
one of its members using the dot operator like methods or variables.
For example, let's consider this if statement where the condition is greater than 21.
So as is an object reference referencing some object such as a student.
Now if TSS happens to be null, then we know that we get a null pointer exception at runtime and our
program execution could stop.
So to prevent this, we can add a null check.
That is, we would have something like this.
So we first check if S is not equal to none.
And if that is true, only then our condition as a greater than 21 would be evaluated.
Now, if SE is null, then the first condition would be false and due to short circuit nature of an
operator, it will not evaluate the second condition, thus preventing the null pointer exception.
If you recall in an earlier lecture on comparison operators, even there we used a similar null check
to prevent null pointer exception.
There the null check was helping with methods parameter validation and here it is part of an and operation.
Now let's head over to my editor and test everything out and some additional important things will also
be discussed in the demo.
All right, here we are in the basics class, and we have a new method called logical operators, which
is invoked from the main method.
So let's look at the agenda for the demo.
So the first thing is we will test the basic stuff like the and or not.
And then we will look at this thing called associated with T which is a property of both and, and ah.
So let's not worry about all of this text.
We will get there.
And the third thing is we will look at the operator precedence of logical operators.
So just like arithmetic operators, we also have operator operator precedence over here.
So we will look at that and we will also look at operator precedence across logical comparison and arithmetic.
And finally, we will look at the and operator and how it avoids null pointer exception.
We have already seen that.
We will also just test it out.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So let's just take the simple example that we had of approving loan.
So here, let's consider that the age and salary are age and salary of some particular user, and we
are going to test whether the user should be approved the loan or not.
So we have age and salary which are initialized to 37 and 95,000.
And we also have a boolean variable here has bad credit and it is initialized to false.
And this is the condition that we have.
This is the if statement.
So if age is greater than 35 and salary is greater than 90,000, then the loan is approved.
Otherwise, if this condition fails, then we have the condition.
So for if statement we have only looked at the f block, but there is also something called LS block
which gets executed if the condition is false.
But we are going to look at if statement in one of the subsequent lectures.
So let's not worry about it.
But it's good enough if you just know this.
So let's go ahead and compile and run this.
It's already compiled.
So let me just run it.
Here it is.
So lone is approved here because age is greater than 35 and the age of the user is 37.
So 37 is greater than 35.
And here the salary is 95,000, which is also greater than 90,000.
And so this condition is true.
This Boolean expression is true, and this particular statement is getting printed.
Now let's just make this 90,000.
So which means that it is equal to 90,000.
So it is this condition should fail.
Here now it says loan not approved.
Right now if we make this are.
Okay.
So let me.
Now the loan is approved because the first condition is true.
So with that, the the short circuit nature of our operator is coming into play and the second condition
will not even be evaluated, although it doesn't make this rule greater than 35.
Our salary doesn't make sense because we are approving the loan just based on age.
So that's with the our operator.
And let me just change this back to 95,000.
And let me also put this back to and now here, let me just remove this thing here and let's just compile
it.
And it says bad operand type for binary operator and because here salary is an end rather than boolean.
So just keep this in mind.
All of the logical operators require a boolean operator and they evaluate to a boolean value and they
are typically used in such control flow statements.
So it's got to be a Boolean expression.
Now let's go ahead and look at the note operator also.
So let's introduce one more operator here.
Okay.
So here we are having a chain of operators.
So the boolean expression need not be constrained to just one logical operator.
We can have more than one and we can still have more logical operators.
Two.
So this is what we have.
And this should also.
You clean this up?
So long as abroad, because all three of the conditions are true here has credit, but credit is false,
so not false would be true.
And these two conditions are also true.
So the loan is approved.
So it is true and true and true.
Now, here, this can also be it says age greater than 35.
Another way to represent it is age less than or equal to 35.
And put the knot operator here.
So this is also correct.
It can also be in this way.
But the thing is, if we do this.
Then we get a compiler error.
So I just removed the parenthesis.
So it's this bad operand type for unity operator.
Thus that's because age is considered as an upper end for not.
And we know that for naught we need to have boolean operand.
So this boolean expression has to be in parentheses and then it gets evaluated to a boolean value and
then it is fine.
But then here we are not using any parentheses for the and operation.
So that has to do with operator precedence.
So we will get back to that later.
So that's with the note operator.
So we are done with the core stuff now.
Now, the next question is which of the two operators are applied?
Or in other words, how would the grouping be done?
Will it be this condition and this condition and the result of this of that would be ended with this
or would it be this and this and ended together.
And then again, age greater than 35 will be added to that.
So here in Java, this by default, this is what is going to happen internally.
This is what will happen and this is referred to as a left associative property.
So this is how both and and our operator would do the grouping.
It's just about the grouping.
So they do it from left to right and it applies to both and, and our operators.
Now we know that we can also change this to something like this.
We can manually make it change the rule to this.
Also.
So the question is, is there any difference in the output?
If it is this way or if it is the other way, the default way, the left associative way?
And the answer is no.
So it is going to produce the same result, and that is the associative property.
So that's what we are saying here, A and B group together.
And then ending it with C is same as this expression A and B and C.
And once again, that applies to both and as well as our operators.
So we can just test it out, too.
So let's just make this.
85,000.
So alone is not approved.
And if you do it the other way also.
Okay.
So this whole condition will be false because salary is greater than 90,000 is wrong is false.
So this would be false and this would be true, but that wouldn't make any difference.
So once again, you will end up with the same result.
So loan is not approved.
So that's with the associative property.
And next, let's look at the operator precedents.
So let's do this.
Let's make this hour here.
So the next question is, how would this be evaluated?
So internally this is what will happen.
So this will be grouped first.
It will be considered as one thing.
That's because and has the highest precedence.
Sorry, not has the highest preference after that.
The next higher preference is for an operator.
So the grouping will be.
Like this.
And then finally the operator will be used.
So in this in this case.
So we have the operator.
So.
So this condition will be evaluated because it is to the left of R and within this OC, this condition
will be executed.
In this case, it would be it would be false because 85,000 is not greater than 90,000.
So this would be false.
And then this would be evaluated and then the loan would be approved.
Right.
So but this is what is going to happen internally because of the operator precedence.
And that's what we are seeing here.
So it is about this, so or not, has higher precedence then and which has higher precedence than or
so.
So that's just for your information, if you do not have anything, this is how it gets grouped internally.
But in terms of evaluation still OC, we have the operator and so the evaluation starts with this and
if it is true, then due to short circuit nature, the this entire expression would be true and this
would be executed.
But if it is false, only then this condition would be evaluated.
And here also a couple of other examples here.
So if you have the expression in this way and has the higher precedence, right.
So that's why the A and B are grouped together.
And then we have R and then we have and here to so C and D would be grouped together.
And here is another example, A and B and C or D, so and has the higher precedence here.
But then we have the left associative property too.
So first A and B would be grouped within this particular expression and then C would be added to that.
And to all of that we would order the last operand.
So we apply the odd operand or operation on the last operand.
So that's what operator precedence.
Now let's look at the operator precedents across logical comparison and arithmetic operators.
So let's go back to this one.
So here now earlier I said.
That.
You know, I showed this particular example here and I said that we get a compiler error here because
here it would be treated as the upper end for not.
Which is wrong.
It has to be a boolean.
And that has got to do with operator precedence because not has the highest operator precedence.
So it would do something like this.
So it has to do with that.
Now, so let me just put this back.
But then I said that.
This did not give us any problem.
So salary was not treated as an upper end for AD.
And that's because this is a comparison operator and comparison operator has higher precedence than
and and also or so internally this is what will happen.
And it would be like this.
So this is the grouping that that would happen.
And because and is there we will also have this so not has the highest precedence then we have these
comparison operators and after then and and outcomes.
Now let's also change this if we change this to say.
9000 into.
Ten.
Okay, so let's do this.
And it will not give us a compilation error.
As you can see, it will not give us any compensation error because in this case, this is what will
happen internally.
It will be represented as this.
What it means is not still has the highest precedence.
After that.
We have the arithmetic operators which get the next higher precedence.
And after arithmetic operators we have the comparison operators and finally we have and and our operator.
So our not gets the highest precedence and not and and or has the lowest precedence.
And in between we have arithmetic followed by comparison operators.
Okay.
So this is the grouping, this is how it would be grouped.
And just look at the resources section.
I will try to include a link or an article which includes all the precedence rules in Java for all the
different operators.
So some of them, we still did not cover some of the operators, but it is still fine.
If you want.
You can take a look at it for the sake of completeness.
So these are how the grouping happens if you do not include any any of the parentheses.
But in reality you have to.
Include the parenthesis to make the logic clear.
So this all represents some logic, and you need to put the parentheses.
For instance, you might you might want either h to be greater than 35 and salary to be greater than
this, or you might.
So you might want something like this, the rule to be something like this.
Or it has to be good credit.
So if you use these parameters, then it would be very clear to both you as well as any other programmer.
So the code readability improves.
Without this it's very difficult because it is difficult for you to keep these operator precedence rules
in mind.
It is very difficult and many of them do not even know about such operator precedence rules, especially
for logical operators.
That's because many of the books are online or offline.
Courses do not cover this.
Many of them are not covering this.
So many programmers may not even be aware of it.
So you should always use your logic like this and try to keep your code very readable.
So just keep that in mind.
And finally, let's also look at the and operator use to avoid short circuit witness.
So here we have this student object that is being created and we already know that student class looks
like this, right?
So we are creating a student object and passing the idea of thousand and one and the name as Swatch.
And we are invoking the update method which we have implemented in one of the previous demos for comparison
operators.
And we are passing both student as well as a new name the row here and if you look at the update operation
was like this and we had this parameter validation here.
So what we can do here is we can just.
How a rule is like.
Not equal to null.
Then we want to have a second condition.
Let's say as dot ID has to be greater than 1000.
What we passed was 2001.
Only in that scenario we want to update the name to something else so we may have something like this.
So this null check is coming handy here and it ensures that a null pointer exception is not generated
without this.
If you have this and if we pass a null here, then we end up with a null pointer exception.
So that's what I was we were looking at earlier in the demo.
So that's all there is.
And let me just go ahead and compile and run this.
And even if you pass a null, then it would still does it does not give any error here.
So that's it.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about logical operators and I will see you in the next lecture.
Thank you and happy coding.