Hello there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back and this short lecture, I just want to highlight an interesting point about private
modifier, something that we need to be aware of.
We know that a member declared with private modifier is private to the class.
However, that member is not private.
Among the objects of its class.
In other words, an object of a class can access private members of another object of the same class.
Let's look at an example.
This is a stripped down version of our student class.
Here we have the student class with variable ID declared as private, and this class has two objects
referenced by the variables S1 and S2.
And there is also the class course with its own object referenced by the variable C one.
Now object as one can access ID field of object as to even though ID is private to S2.
That's because, as I mentioned earlier, objects of a class can access each other's private stuff.
However, this is not possible as these are objects of different classes.
So course object cannot access private members of student object.
So once again, if something is declared private, it means it is private to its class, but not among
the objects of its class.
Next question that we should have is why is it so?
That is, why is it variable, not private?
Among the objects of its class.
And that's because a private member is being accessed in the same class in which it is declared.
And in our example, the expression as to ID is within the student class, which is also declaring the
ID variable as private.
So because we are accessing a variable declared in the same class and not some other class, such an
access is being permitted.
So since both variable declaration and variable access is happening within the same class definition
that is under the same ownership, it is being permitted.
Now here in this example, we are using a variable, but this applies to other class members too, like
private methods.
Now let's go ahead and see this in action.
Okay.
As part of this demonstration, let's consider a realistic use case.
Typically, as a software is executing, we have many objects getting created.
For instance, if we run this program, the student test class, you know, we are having these three
different objects getting created.
And sometimes we may have a new student object and we would have to check if that student object is
a duplicate of any of these three student objects.
So there is this data structure called hash set, which we will discuss later when we get to collections
framework.
But Hazard is a data structure which stores elements, and those elements have to be unique elements.
So for instance, if this particular has set if a has set has three elements let's say A, C, S, C
and F.
Now, if you try to add a new element, c, c is already there, then has set will not add that element
because it is considered as a duplicate and has said keeps only unique elements.
So it does not allow any duplicate elements.
Similarly, if we add these three elements.
Student one.
Student two, one, two and three into the hash set.
And now let's say there is a new student called Student four and let's assume that it has the same state
as Student three.
So this is student four and it has the same state as student three.
So it will have all of these variable values.
OC Just like here.
So in this case, if the hash set has these three elements and if we try to add the student four, then
it shouldn't add.
Now.
The thing is for that, Hassett uses a method called us equals.
Now, we also know that we have this equality operator.
Now, if you do, let's say student three is equals to student four then this will not work because
they are referencing to different objects.
Right.
And equality operator compares the identities of these objects, which is a memory addresses and they
are going to be different because they are different objects.
So asset set users and equals method and let's also use a similar equals method here.
And an equals method can just compare, let's say, for instance, the ID values because the ID is unique
to each object.
It compares the ID values of this object versus this object.
And if they are equal, then we can say that Student four is a duplicate of.
Student three.
So let us write such an ID, such a method.
And let's go here, because this is a static method.
Let's write a static method.
Static.
Let's say it returns boolean equals and it takes two objects.
Student as one and student as two.
And.
Let's say it has to return boolean.
So it takes the ID in the first parameter and it compares with the ID of the second object.
So if they are equal, it means that S2 is a duplicate of S1.
Otherwise it returns a false right.
Now here let's declare.
Now, one thing is in the student class.
Let's make this private, because that's what we are testing here.
This is private.
So this is student and this is student test.
And both are and the basics package here.
Now here.
Let's define a variable called Boolean.
Let's call it ease duplicate.
And we are invoking this equal method and let's pass.
STUDENT three Comma.
Student four So it needs to return a true here.
Let's also print this.
Let me also comment this out.
We don't need this.
Extra parent statements for now.
Let's comment it and let's just print this one is duplicate.
Now let's head over to our command prompt.
And let's compile this.
See it says to it gives to errors.
It says it has private access and student write ID is in student class and it is private to the class,
so you cannot access it from here.
This we have seen in the last lecture to write with the fool method.
So what we need to do is we need to move this.
Into the student class.
Okay.
So let's just add it here at the very end.
Och still anaesthetic method.
So here let's just say student dot equals because it is a static method.
We use the class name.
I'll sign now.
To execute.
This is the command because we are using packages.
So we have to say complete semantics, square dot basics, dot student test, right?
We cannot just say Java student test.
So this is what we have learned in our packages lectures.
So if you execute it, it is printing through here, right?
So that is what it is.
But typically this equals method will be an instance method.
So you would access it something like this instead of having it as.
A static method you will invoke it on, let's say.
Student three And you are passing.
Student four So this is how it would typically be.
Okay.
So let me remove the static here.
And this is equals.
So this will be just student.
Like this.
So since this is being accessed on Student three So we will say ID, so this would be STUDENT three
ID, which is the instance variable, and we are comparing with the student objects that that is getting
passed.
In our example it is student four And this is what is happening.
So this is how it is typical typically implemented.
Once again, let me pile this.
So it's still true.
So this is how it is and it is working fine because this is ID like I said earlier, the student object
is declared in the same class as student.
It is being used in the same class as student and the ID is also declared in the same class.
So since it is all under the same class definition, it is being permitted even earlier when it is static,
both as one point ID and as two point ID who are part of the same class.
An ID is also declared in the same class.
So that's just an interesting thing to be aware of.
So when we say private, it is private to the class, but not private to the objects of its class.
So an object of a class can access private stuff of other objects of the same class.
That's about it.
Thank you.
And I will see you in the next lecture.