Hello there.
This is the row.
Now let's look at multiple inheritance.
In the previous lesson, we mentioned that multiple inheritance could help us solve the technical requirement
we discussed in that particular lesson.
With multiple inheritance, we can have two super classes.
One is the bookmark class as before, and the other is a new abstract class called Shareable, which
has the abstract method get item data weblink and book classes extend both bookmark and shareable while
mobi class extends only bookmark so only weblink and book classes are required to implement the get
item data method as they extend a new shareable class.
This way we meet the two requirements we discussed earlier.
That is, we have common protocol in the form of shareable class and we have method implementations
only in those classes where it matters.
So that's how multiple inheritance can solve our problem.
But you may recall that in Java we can extend only one superclass that is weblink and book classes cannot
extend both shareable and bookmark.
That is the can extend only one of them.
What it means is that Java does not support multiple inheritance and it does not support multiple inheritance
as it could lead to a problem called deadly diamond of death.
Let's see what this notorious problem is about.
To understand that deadly diamond of death or simply the diamond problem, let's consider this class
diagram which incorporates multiple inheritance.
We know that bookmark class defines the abstract method is kid friendly eligible, which is overridden
in both movie and book classes.
Let's also consider this new class called Movie and Book, which extends both movie and book.
That is, it would be multiple inheritance.
Movie and book class basically represents a movie that is based on some book, like in the case of The
Godfather or the Harry Potter series.
So it is basically a new type of bookmark.
And in reality, we may never have such a class in our system, but it is introduced only for the sake
of this discussion.
So here movie on book class does not override.
Is kid friendly eligible method.
So the question is which version of is kid friendly?
Eligible method is inherited by movie and book class.
Would it inherit the version and movie class or the version in book class?
And the answer is the programming language needs to support some complicated rules to address this ambiguity.
Java, we know, is designed to be simple so it avoids this problem by altogether avoiding multiple
inheritance.
That is, you cannot have a class like movie and book extending both movie and book.
As you can see, the inheritance tree has a diamond shape with one class extending two classes and both
of which extend the same base class.
That's the reason why this problem is referred to as the diamond problem.
Now here is an illustration of diamond problem due to shared state.
The one we just discussed was due to shared behavior.
Here the base class bookmark defines an instance variable ie which is initialized with 25 class book
inherits ie and re initialize it to 42 while the class movie re initializes I to 50.
So once again, the question is which version of I will be inherited by movie and book class?
So that's the ambiguity.
So Java does not support multiple inheritance in that case.
How are we going to solve the puzzle we saw in the previous lesson?
That is, how can we have get item data method in only book and web classes and at the same time define
a common protocol.
And for that we can use interfaces which we are going to study next.
And it's a very important object oriented feature.
Thank you.