Not look at a statement called Try with resources which was introduced in July 7 as the name suggests
it has something to do with the try block and also get resources or resources could be classes to present
something like operating system resources like file handles which has been performing.
I would look at operations like reading from a file on the main thing the statement does is to automatically
close such resources.
So let's go ahead and learn about it.
It is very straightforward.
At the end of the lesson people will also be a short demo of what we like and their demo.
We would also look at something called suppressed exceptions to understand the benefit of the right
with resources.
First let's look at an example here is the standard template which was used before jealous event for
reading it offered him a data hitting the block.
Are creating a file input stream instance which acts as a resource for reading it offered him a fight
the code for reading the dies on the dead as it is not relevant for this discussion.
There is also a catch block for handling file not one exception that can be drawn by the construction
of the file input stream class.
We also have the finally block with the file input stream instance is closed so that the system resources
that it uses on at least this way there will not be any resource leaks.
We already know the finally block will always be executed.
No no it is the finally block.
How one mark like I should talk and that's because the Ruelas method can do an Iowa exception.
Moreover we are also checking that the reference to the above in is not enough.
And if it is not not only then we close the input stream not that available and can be none if the file
input stream object would not be created.
That is a fine enough one exception was generated when we were trying to create dump file input stream
object.
So that this check could get a null pointer exception when the Close method is invoked.
Now as you can see this whole finally block it looks very ugly with the cross try catch block and the
additional check and also the up close method and location.
So I want this we have the quite with resources statement which was introduced in Java 7 and it is the
same code but with that drive with resources statement as you can see it looks much cleaner.
The ugly looking finally block and we have only to try and catch Brocks here the resources are created
Witan the parenthesis that follows the tricky word.
So the declaration is also done within the parenthesis and it will not work if declaration is done outside
of the parenthesis and initialization is done within the parenthesis in the old syntax declaration was
done outside the block.
So a try with resource is the cleanup operation is taken care of implicitly.
That is a close method is in work implicitly after the block is executed.
In reality the compiler inserts the and finally block into the bytecode.
So even if an exception is generated the Close method is still invoked.
Just as in the case of using a finally block explicitly you're also catching an exception as we know
that the Lewis-Smith there which is invoked implicitly can throw an exception just know that the resource
created in the parenthesis is implicitly final so it cannot be reassigned within the try block.
Unsisterly sources are being automatically closed.
This particular feature is also referred to as Automattic resource management or for short.
Here is another example that might deploy resources are being created within the type but and this is
they are created from left Left-Right right.
That resource creation expressions must be operated by semi-colons in disguise syntax wise.
It looks a bit similar to fuddle Not that once the block is completed resources will be closed in the
reverse order.
That is a file output stream instance is close before filing puts team instance even if there was a
failure in creating one of the resources then the resources created so far which are on its left will
be crossed.
And here is a general syntax.
Any resource that we create in the parenthesis must be off by auto plausible which is an interface in
the Jawa line package.
It means that the class of the resource hostile implement Article interface or one of its subintervals
us or disclosable has only one method which is a closed minded support filing stream on file output
stream classes implement articles about not do the try block need not have a catch block if the occludes
method which you implement as part of implementing articles aboon does not throw an exception.
And of course the code of conduct by block should also not to an exception.
So a cry with the social statement need not how either to catch Quarter-Finals block.
But if you want to you can have an explicit finally block that would perform something other than the
cleanup operation Sooke trying with resources would come into play only when dealing with autoclaves
or build resources and hence it is called aspart private sources.
If you're not dealing with all the possible resources then you will have to use the regular old fashioned
type block which does not help but analysis and here are some subtypes of our disclosable on the left
.
We have usable interface which is from the Jawa I will package most of the classes implement this interface
even classes like socket arm scanner which are from other packages implemented.
And we also have the interface of resultset which is from the package job X doc askew and it also extends
our doc Rosabel.
Similarly we can also see that there is a line interface from one of the packages from the sound API
and it also extends our global.
So all of these can be used in the parenthesis.
I would also recommend taking a look at the articles about interface in the J.Y..
So thats a try with resources.
It is mainly used to automatically growth resources unexplored cleanups and backs down using finally
for growing resources.
No look not to pull up my editor you assured them off with resources OK for this demo.
We have this new class called us try with resources gimel and it is added to the exceptions package
and it has only one method File.
Copy that I'm being on stands for automatic resource management it with an Iowa exception and this method
doesn't work from the main method.
And since it throws an exception we are also catching it here now as the name suggests this method is
doing a file copy which means that it is reading the contents of a file and writing those contents for
a different destination.
And that's being done here.
So here we have the private resources index and we are declaring pool resources.
Resources are being created here.
One is a buffered input stream instance and the second resource is a buffered output stream instance
.
So input stream instance is used for reading or stream instance for writing.
Again that's not worry about the code for reading and writing on the Phylis basically a big file here
and they put me as violent or jpeg output would be this.
So here it is valid in Georgia.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
Here does not let me refresh this.
So as you can see the file got created here and here the resources are also separated by a semicolon
.
Now let's try a bunch of things that we discussed on this.
I mean just take this.
Now as you can see we're getting a compilation error here and that's because the resource has to be
created within the parenthesis.
It cannot be created outside and we cannot initialize it here.
That cannot be done.
As we discussed in the in the lesson so that cannot be done.
So let me just bring it back here and one other thing we discussed was that we cannot re-initialize
a resource variable here so we cannot do this.
And that's because we said that in here is implicitly final and final cannot be reassigned.
So we know that.
So that's why this is not possible and hence we can see a compilation error.
So let me just delete this also.
And the next one is.
So here you are trying to create a string instance and it will give a compilation error.
And that's because string is not a resource which means that it does not implement auto Clozaril interface
with the close method.
So that's not possible.
Anything that goes here has to be a resource which implements or disclosable.
Now those are the main things that were discussed in the lesson.
So one thing with which we did not discuss was suppressed exceptions.
And let's look at that now.
So for this let me just copy this here and paste it here.
So these are two instances So basically those are two resources.
One is an instance of class Test.
On the other is an instance of Desta.
And those are defined here at the bottom of this white.
So outside of the tribe with resources class we are defining these two classes.
One is d'Este which implements hardcores a bill and also the Glos method and the close method is throwing
an Iowa exception.
The actual close method in order goes is an exception.
But here we are generating an exception under.
It also recommends that we need to to aspecific exception as possible and in case of the close mentor
is not ruling any exception then we can avoid doing any exception here.
We don't need to how it goes across here.
OK.
So if it is not required.
That's not how it throws across here but it does require quite to keep it as specific as possible.
And this exception this method of throwing exception.
But the message will be an exception on test results implementing or disclosable the Close method.
And it is throwing that exception with the message to be an exceptions based too.
And that's because that it's named us Desta.
OK so the only difference is two as being carded here in the message also.
So that's what we hope.
And here let me come on Das also.
So in this case.
So in the right block we are throwing an exception.
So after doing the copy here we are throwing this exception at the very end.
OK.
So let me just go ahead on her on this.
Come on.
So it will throw exceptions and as you can see so you can see the exception.
So the first the main exception that is being generated is this exception Iowa exception that's maybe
how this exception is getting printed here.
And here is the stockers that you're catching that exception and we are doing it.
No didn't.
The important exception we can see that that is this suppresive exception and that is the second supplement
exception.
So those are generated here.
So once this dry block is executed we know that the resources are closed in the reverse order.
So first it will be closed then it will be closed and will be closed on Wednesday is closed.
The exception.
So that's the real exception.
And that will be encapsulated inside this Aiwa exception as a suppressed exception.
And then after that even DVM tries to close this and also throws an exception and that exception is
the trivial exception that is also and gaps embedded within Aiwa exception has a suppressed exception
.
So we have these exceptions here and it is a nice big it's a nice way to do it because here we are calling
it as an important exception because normally you how only one an exception generated here in the try
block is more important because it will have some important details.
I bought something significant must have happened here.
But what it has when it comes to of exceptions those are those are generated by the rules meant there
is normally you know an exception is non-gendered macros matter.
So it would be something not that important or competitively it will not be as important as the exception
generated from the from within that block.
So that's why it is suppressed.
So I think that's up to.
The exception is not that important exception.
Now here is the abstract trace but I guess if you if the developer or whoever is invoking the client
who is invoking this matter wants to extract the suppressed exceptions then they can do it this way
.
So let me just comment this uncommon this court.
So here we are watching the important exception and we in looking him at their court gets suppressed
which is from the to overlook Iron Age credenza on off two of his circuit and an army officer present
exceptions.
OK.
So so this is added in July 7 just like try with resources Sendak's which was also ordered in Dallas
.
So this is an army that will have two exceptions up as exceptions.
And we are counting on a spending message this year.
So if we are on it.
So we have this so important exception as the main exception under somewhat some exceptions are trivial
exceptions.
Now if this is what the trial would send back to I with resources Sendak's.
But if we just use and not try catch finally block and if we have the same thing happening the resources
throwing exceptions when will that blows matter.
And if you also have this kind of an important exception then the exception that could be determined
by this matter would be one of these the exceptions that are generated from the finally block.
Just recall that in the regular old fashioned try block the Close method to be invoked in the finally
block.
So that gives only the one of the first Groos method were through an exception undocked would be going
by this method on the second exception thrown by the second method and also the important exception
will be ignored.
And that gives the caller just masked masked Dix's exception and you can fix the Massena exception by
making it a suppressed exception.
We need to write some additional code for that.
And that's what even the with resources index is doing internally and we can do that to fix the mast
exception problem they ignored exception rubbed up on what we've been seeing the in the next lesson
.
So that's about it for now.
Thank you.
And happy coding.
And you can also find discord in the resources section.
Thank you