Hi there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at method references, which is a very simple concept, and it is also used for passing
your own functionality.
Just like in the case of lambdas and the target type for method, references are also functional interfaces,
just like in the case of lambdas.
And if not, we will get a compilation errors.
So it has to be functional interface for both lambdas as well as method references.
And we very briefly looked at method references in the collections framework chapter in the iterator
lecture and we used it for invoking the forage method where we passed a method reference as an argument
and we very briefly discussed it and we did not get into any of the details, but now we are going to
get into all of the details regarding method references.
So a method reference, as the name implies, is simply a reference to a method, just like the way
we have object references where we have references to objects and we know that object references can
be passed as method arguments and since Java eight onwards we can also pass method references, so we
can pass references to methods as arguments to methods.
And that way, as we mentioned earlier, methods are also first class citizens.
So we are we are able to pass behavior.
And we have also seen earlier that lambdas can also be used for that.
But in case of lambdas, we were defining the behavior as part of the lambda body itself.
Now if you have that same logic encapsulated in a method, you can as well use a method reference.
So it's an alternative like an alternative, and it may be more readable to now in certain cases, as
we have seen in the demo earlier in the previous lecture, we were invoking another method from the
lambda body itself, right?
For example, here we were invoking the stat, the strip HTML tax method inside the body of the lambda.
And in this case also we can make use of a method reference.
And there are three kinds of method references and we are going to look at all of them.
So we are going to just work on our functional interfaces, demo class, functional interface, demo
class, and we will convert some of the lambda expressions into method references and we are going to
look at all three kinds of method references.
So here we are, we are processing the documents and we are applying a filter and then we are doing
two transformations.
So here during the transformation, we are going to look at our first method reference and then we are
printing the documents that are documents and here we will replace using the second method reference
and the third one will be used at the top.
So a method reference essentially has this kind of a syntax where you will have some target reference
and you will have a delimiter, which is two columns and then the method.
So that's how you will have and in the first case, let's look at the first case here.
So here we are applying two transformations as you know, the two transformations to convert the HTML
document.
In the first case, we are removing the HTML tags and then we are among the stop words.
Now here all we are doing is we are invoking another method inside the body.
For example, here we are calling this method called remove stop words.
Right?
It's a static method inside this class and this class is also defined in the same file.
So we are invoking this method.
So instead of using this lambda, we can actually use a method reference.
So target type, like I said, will still be functional interface.
Now all we will do is we will take this class name.
And we'll have the two columns.
So that's the delimiter and we will invoke the remove stop words method.
That's it.
So that's the reference to this method.
And we don't have to use any parameters here.
There is no parameters because parameters is implicit in the method name itself.
And I may also comment this here we are invoking the apply method.
So that's it.
And so so basically we are assigning it to this function.
So this is a functional interface.
So that's the target type just like in the case of Lambda and we are invoking the apply method on this.
So the remote stopwatch, you can think of it this way that it will be part of the apply method so that
it will be the only statement inside the applied method and to the apply method we are passing doc and
remove stop words also has only a single text, only a single parameter and that doc will be will be
relayed to the remote stopwatch method.
So that doc will be just passed to the remote password, the most obvious method.
So essentially so both the apply method, remote stopwatch method just corresponds to the applied method.
So whatever you pass to apply method will also be passed to this one.
So the, the method that we are passing should be appropriate for the abstract method and the functional
interface.
Otherwise we will get a compilation error.
So that's the first one.
Let me just run this.
So we get the same output.
So it's the simplest case where we have a class name followed by the the static method.
Now let's look at the second method reference where instead of class name, we use an object reference.
So let's go here.
So here we are printing the we are printing the target documents.
So out of the four documents, we have two documents which met our requirement.
So we are printing them and we are using this lambda expression.
Now here we are invoking a method called println, right?
And the println method we know is being invoked here on this variable call out, right.
So it is out is actually an object reference within the system class.
So for the second method reference, this is the syntax.
You have an object reference and you will invoke the instance method.
So in the first case it was class name followed by static method.
In this case, since we are invoking a method on object reference, it's an instance method.
Now this is let's go ahead and common this.
So here.
This is a variable, so this is object reference and we'll just do that and we don't need this because
the input parameter is implicit and the println method and we know that for each method accepts a consumer.
So we are passing this method reference as an instance of the consumer.
And in the consumer we know there is this method called accept.
So you can think that the println method, System.out.println method will be will be the body of the
accept method and to the accept method, the for each method will pass each of its elements one at a
time.
So initially it will pass one document.
And that document the the accept method will pass it to the parental end method and that's how it's
going to be printed.
So once again, we have to pass the this has to this method reference has to correspond to the abstract
method in the functional interface.
If the target type is not right, then you get a compilation error.
So let me run this.
You get the same output.
So it's good.
So in the second one, the syntax is object reference followed by the delimiter and then the instance
method.
Now here we had the class name followed by the static method.
Now if you try to use an object reference here and then a static method, we will get a compilation
error.
So that's the second one.
Now let's look at the third one here.
So the third one is has a syntax like this.
So it is also like an instance method.
You're invoking an instance method, but we are saying class name.
But then here we have an object reference.
So you might say, why not just here?
In this case its d is nothing.
But doc, why not just say this doc contains right contents is from the string from the string class.
But if we do that then the problem is contains method has a single parameter, but this is a by function
and the apply method in the by function takes two parameters.
So that's why we cannot we cannot use this.
So we would have to use this kind of notation here.
And if we use this, then JVM will automatically invoke the instance the contains method, the instance
method on the first parameter on the first parameter.
So let me just write it down.
I think it'll be clear.
So we have this.
So we have to use the container method is actually part of.
So we are saying dot contains.
So we have to take the type of D type of D is string in this case because because we are you can see
that it is string here the first parameter.
And the syntax also says that class name.
So that's the class name, Colon.
This is the instance method.
Okay.
Now, this can be assigned to this functional interface.
Let me do that.
Okay.
Now.
And so this is going inside the apply method and in the apply method to the apply method, we are passing
this.
But in this case the Java would know that it has to invoke because we are passing this kind of a method
reference.
It knows that it would invoke the contains method on this on this particular parameter, just like in
the case of Lambda and it will pass the stream as an argument to the contents method.
So that will be taken care of internally.
So it's a little bit confusing in this case because contains still has one parameter, but apply has
to two parameters.
But in this when it sees the this kind of a method reference, then it knows that it has to invoke the
contents method on this parameter on the first parameter, and then it will just pass the all the remaining.
It may need not be just one parameter.
In this case it is only one parameter, but if contains accepts more than one parameter, then you would
also have to pass more parameters.
So all of the rest of the parameters will be parsed as input to the to this method.
That's how it is.
So but we can also implement this in the different way, which in the like in the case of the second
method reference.
But for that we would have to change this to function.
So let's also do that.
We will have function.
It will just take string and it will return a boolean.
So let's call it.
Function.
In this case, it will be.
Dock.
Dock is already here.
So that's the object reference.
And we are saying invoke contains on dock.
Now this can be assigned to this one.
Okay.
Now let's write.
It's also correct, this one.
So it will be function, not apply.
Stream.
So we get the same output.
So in this case, we are able to use a second type of method reference where we are having an object
reference and we are invoking the contents method.
But it but that has to fit this particular interface and it fits this interface.
It's just that it is not going to fit the BI function interface.
So when you do that then this contains method will be part of apply and apply gets a single parameter
stream and that stream will be relayed to the contents method will be passed to the contents method.
It's just that if you are using a bi function then we will have to in this particular case, then we
will have to pass this string.
We will have to pass this in the third kind of method reference, and then it will internally it will
be taken care of.
So the contents method will be invoked on the first parameter in this case, and all of the remaining
arguments to that method will be passed as an input to the contents.
In which case, in this case, it is only a single argument.
So that's what it is.
So those are the three kinds of method references and I hope they are clear enough.
So that's it and thank you and happy coding.