Hello there.
This is the model room and we'll come back.
So we have learned about how to create Java classes within Eclipse, and we have also learned about
the Eclipse build process.
Now let's learn about how to efficiently navigate through the source code with an eclipse.
So if you're going to look at some shortcuts for doing that and it's very important, so you need to
memorize the shortcuts.
So the first thing that we are going to look at is something called as type exploration, which as the
name suggests, is about exploring types, and the type is nothing but either a class or an interface.
So let's say we want to search for our basics class.
So for that, the shortcut is control shift to where T stands for type.
So you can start typing in the name of the file, which is basic demo.
And as we are typing, there is a real time search that is happening.
So Eclipse is searching the workspace as well as the Java library too.
So these are all the classes from the Java Library, and this is the basic demo class that we are looking
for, which is in our workspace Demo Z.
So just click on that.
So that's how you would search for a type.
Next, we would want to see something called as an outline of a class, and an outline is nothing but
the members of a class, what members the class has.
So there are different ways to do it.
So one is through the package Explorer.
So you would just click on this demo source and then we have our package within which we have the basics
demo class and we can see all of the methods that this class has.
So the class does not have any fields right now.
So let's go ahead and just add a field here and you will see that it gets added here in the list.
Here it is.
So we can see the field as well as all of the members.
So let me just remove it now.
So that's one way.
Now, the second way is through a shortcut and you will just say control or where all stands for outline.
So once again, you can see all of the methods here.
So you can just click on them here and you will be at the method.
We can do the same over here.
Also, if you click on that, if you double click, you will be there.
So that's how you will.
You can see an outline of the class.
So it is control o.
And you can also search here.
Let's say if you say array, you can search for it and just.
Click on it and you'll be there.
So that's the second way.
And the third way is through something called us breadcrumb.
So all you will do is just right click and say Show and breadcrumb.
So it shows the breadcrumb.
And the breadcrumb is nothing but the path to the class here and here.
If you click on this arrow once again, you will see all of the methods.
And typically I do this, this is what I prefer.
And if you click on ideas here, we will get to the race method.
And if you want to hide it, you can also right click on say Hide Breadcrumb and it will go away.
But I generally prefer to have the breadcrumb here.
So that's the type exploration.
Now let's look at method exploration.
Now for this, let me open our student test class.
So, control chef P.
Student test.
And here it is.
Now let me scroll down here.
We have the update profile method invocation.
So if we want to look at the update profile, the method definition.
So if we want to navigate to that method, all you need to do is just click here on the name of the
method and hit F three and there you go.
So you are at the method definition of update profile.
To go back, just hit this button here.
So that's the method navigation.
But here we have the constructor.
So just click here and once again do an F three and you are at that particular constructor.
So this is in the student class, so you can go back once again.
So it's just f three here.
Now let's put a statement.
Print statement controlled space.
Let's print name.
Doesn't matter.
Now let's say we want to navigate this.
Pentland method is part of the Java API.
Right.
So if we want to look at that definition once again, the same shortcut f three.
And here we are.
And it is the definition of the print method, which is in this class called S print stream.
Now, if we want to know what all other methods are in working this particular method, then what you
would do is you would just click on this and you would say Control Shift.
G So that's the Shortcut Control Shift.
G And there are 2057 references that are invoking this particular method.
So from 2057 places, we are invoking this particular method.
So here majority of them, almost all of them are from the Java API.
For instance, here, the from the Java Lang package, we have this class called Abstract Stack Worker.
Here this method is invoking the println method.
So similarly.
If they scroll down, we will see the source directory here at the very end.
Here it is.
This is the source directory in our JID workspace and this is the package and all of these classes are
accessing are invoking the print method.
For instance, if you go into the basics demo class, so we have the type casting method and here we
can see that we are invoking the print statement here and here.
So this is how you would see all the methods that are that are invoking a particular method.
So you would just click on the method and you will say control shift.
G So similarly in our student class, if you click here and if you say Control Chef G, it has only
one other class, which is the student test class.
And from the main method we are invoking the update profile method.
So that's control chef G Now let's go back into the print stream class.
Now, this is a print method now if you want to look at the call hierarchy.
So this particular method is being invoked from many different methods and those methods are again invoked
from some other methods.
And if you want to look at the call hierarchy itself, then you would say control alt edge.
And it would open this view caller's call hierarchy.
So once again, we will see all of those methods that are accessing this particular print method.
But let me scroll down to update.
Here we have the update profile method from the student class.
So update profile method is invoking println.
Now if I click here, it shows the main method from the student test class.
So the main method here is invoking in the student test class is invoking the update profile method
in the student class, which in turn is invoking the print ln method in the print stream class.
All right, so that's the call hierarchy.
And this is a view that's that method exploration.
Next, let's look at search function.
Say, if we want to search for some text within the files, all you will do is control edge.
And here you have many taps.
It's the search window.
So let's say in the file search, if you want to search for the text, add in any of your files, then
you can have this pattern star, which means any file and just hit search.
So it is showing this particular location.
So this is a basics demo class and within this line 154 there is this comment where there is the text
added, so it has the text add.
So if you click that you can see it.
So that's how you would search for a text, some text now let's say Control Edge once again.
So this is a file search.
We did a file search earlier for searching for this text add.
Let's say you want to search for some Java construct like a method or some field.
Then you would click on this tab Java search.
So let's say we want to search for our update file method in the student class.
And if you want to look at this, the declaration, the definition, then you would just say search
and it will show the student class similarly control edge.
Let's say there is a method called ADD and if you want to look at its declaration and add, method is
also there in the Java API.
So let's hit search here.
So there are so many declarations.
So in Java.
Let me just scroll here.
Scroll down.
There is the idealist class which has all of these different methods.
So if I click on AD, you can see the ad method.
So control edge it is.
And you can search for other things also like the fields also.
Or you can look at the references also.
Let me just look at show you the references update file.
So this will show the invocation statement.
Here it is in the student test class and the main method we are in working update profile.
So that's control edge.
Now if you want to search with ten this class, you will do it.
As in any text editor, you will just say control f and you can find and you can replace.
Now if you want to go to a particular line, you will say control.
L So that's the shortcut and you will enter the line number.
So most of these can also be done from here, from the menu.
For instance, let's click here, update, profile, and here, navigate, navigate and here it says
F three, F three is for getting to that particular definition.
So just click on that and you read the methods definition.
And similarly, let's say we want to get the outline quick outline so we set control or we can see the
shortcut here, but quick outline.
SS And to search you can just say you can go from here, search.
You can see that the command is control edge.
So that's that.
So let's just go ahead and do a quick summary of the shortcuts.
Here they are.
So Control Shift DX is for the type search to search for a type control or is to get an outline of the
class or an interface.
F three is to navigate to a method control shift.
G is to look at all of the method invocations of the current method to get the call hierarchy, the
method call hierarchy, its control alt edge and finally control edge is for the search console.
All right.
Thank you.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.