Not let's look at method or writing we brief Your discuss method or writing while introducing inheritance
and it was part of the final design of a work history which is reproduced here here posted a behemoth
third in the staff class is actually writing Posture Review method and end a.
That is the operating method must have the same name deposited if you met that in the User class.
Well posted have you but the review needs to be approved by an editor.
We know that but the posted of you mattered in the staff class does not need any approval.
And so the overriding behavior is not needing any approval.
So then a regular user review than the Bush and the user classes invoke.
But if any of the staff members post a review then the posted of you there in the Stav classes invoked
in their democracy Gram's which we are protesting polymorphous on.
We did use both user unstaffed classes on both hardballs state of New Method.
So we already implemented Metro are we.
But there are some rules associated with method overriding and we will learn those rules.
So method or what rating writing what we are doing is redefining the behavior off the method in the
superclass and it could mean few things one of them is defining new behavior.
That is the overriding method does something different which is specific to sapless And another thing
can be to extend the behavior of the superclass method.
That is you would do what you want the superclass method does.
And then you would do something more.
Finally method of writing can also be used to provide better implementation.
For example the superclass method might belong to some third party library and it may have been written
very efficiently.
Now since it is a library card you don't have any control over the source.
So you can write a new class with a brand new method that overrides this inefficiently read and method
.
So the numerator would how much more efficient implementation.
Not in order to superclass defines a contract through its methods and consequently define a common protocol
for all x subtypes.
So when you order an item a third in the superclass you are agreeing to fulfill the contract.
That is you're telling the outside world that the only one writing method looks exactly like the order
didn't matter matter or writing in words.
Couple of rules that are based on this notion of fulfilling the contract.
In addition to having the same letter name there are two rules.
What method are writing to work.
Let's see what those rules are rules is if there are any method parameters.
Then they must be seen.
In addition the return types must be comparable and the second rule is that the overriding method can
be less accessible.
Let's not look at both these rules in some more detail.
In the first rule the fusspot which says that the method parameters must be same is straightforward
as the overriding mother should look exactly like the old written method.
The second part says that the return types must be compatible which means that the return type in the
overriding method must be either the same written by as in the superclass method or must be a subclass
.
This baby abide by the contract as a subclass.
Very true.
Everything is superclusters as it inherits all the methods of the superclass.
But if the Met the parameters are the same under different types are incompatible.
Then we get a compiler error.
No coming to the second rule it says that the alternating mudguard can be less accessible.
It means that access level must be either same or friendlier.
For example you cannot operate a public method and make it private.
Doing so under a compiler.
So those are the two rules for operating a method.
Next let's look at something called Superguy work as an email just it can be used to access a superclass
method from a subprocess and is typically used for extending behavior defined and superclass.
If the method its superclass is not aware it and in the subclass then it can be either accessed directly
using the method name as we already know or we are the super cute but typically you would directly access
it using the simple matter only not using the Superguy word.
But if the method in superclass is overridden I would want to access that method.
Then you must use super keyword resort example posted a view we know is an overriding matter in the
stuff glass circle in riposted.
And the user class from within this method in the staff class we would have to use supercool.
Otherwise we would be invoking the same method in the staff class could end up in an infinite loop after
working superclass method.
You can see that we can have some additional work thus extending the behavior that is defined in the
superclass matter and that's how you typically extend behavior.
Not that it is not necessary to invoke an order it doesn't matter.
Only an overriding matter over it and method in the superclass can be invoked from any of the subclass
methods.
Now Superguy word is related to objects so it can be used inside a static method and you get a compiler
error if you try to do the supect you can also be used to access something called it free which belongs
to the superclass.
We say that a field and supercluster is hidden.
If the field with the same name is declared and the subclass not that it is only to be a name that matters
here that macros to hide are free.
Everything else like that it by access modifier started non-stock to create is in Meridian.
If discipline's does not use Superguy won't always use a field in its own class or not Bahujan for your
superclass.
So that's method overriding.
But we still have a few more concepts to cover before doing that.
Let's first review what we learn so far in court.
Let's begin with testing or writing rules.
After that people look at the super keyword for this demo.
We will continue using lower classes related to our case study that is use it or jalouse staff but Java
and so on as we are going to test the roots.
Let's actually begin with the second overarching goal but says that the writing method should not be
less accessible.
So this is standard Java and we have this method posted a you which is operating at the posted of your
method and user class.
So in the User class it has public access level.
So in this stuff class also it has public.
So let's just make it less accessible here.
It's supposed to be either same or more friendlier but not less restrictive.
So as you can see we get a compiler error.
Says cannot reduce the visibility of the inherited METAR from user.
So you cannot do that it has to be either same or more friendlier.
So that's the second overriding rule.
Now let's just try the first method of writing.
And in order to do that I actually created a new class called Review and the review classes basically
represents a review and it has two variables one is sort of your text which holds the text for the review
and the other one is approved with a review that has been posted has been approved by an editor or not
.
If it is a user if it is if the review was posted by user needs to be approved by editor but if it was
posted by a staff member it does not need any ill.
And we know that.
So let's just start.
So this is a review class and the review text is initialized why this constructor and that proved reliable
.
We have to get it on center so since it's proved that there is.
We know that it is an artist named as easy.
So we saw that in our Naming Conventions does it or simply set approved.
So it's going to set the rules.
So in use at our job let me just but let's modify this let's introduce a new parameter here let's call
it DOES IT review text and so on.
Let's create a new view object.
It's pass in the rebute text.
It's just a view looks just great in this review.
So the written type has to be modified.
Here to review.
Yes.
So now if your object is getting created and since this is the user it's getting since the user is posting
this.
So if you go here and that if your text gets passed here under a broom since it does not have any value
it gets a default or false and which means that it does not get approved.
And that's what we need for effort.
If they are Beuys posted by user.
So we'll just leave it like that and let's going to add staff.
So staff has posted have you on we want to override it.
So let's change this review next.
So now this method has the same parameters as the overridden matter.
But we said that this was a compiler error because the writing method has the same name on the same
parameter but incompatible types in the superclass it was a review.
And here it is hard wired.
So here if I hollowed audit the message says the return type is incompatible.
So it needs to be a compatible return so it needs to be either review or one of its subtypes.
So let me just change this review line.
Let's just make this written new review so that we don't have any compilation that are supposed to review
as now or writing the superclass method and the rules have been followed.
So that's about overriding rules.
Next let's does the super keyword search super key word can be used to extend the behavior.
That is you can work a superclass method from a subclass supposed to review.
Let's say for example from the user.
This is what Dyster class.
Let's say we are in Woking So we have created this type of object here.
So staff object is here and has a reference type of user and the object type is stuff.
And we want to call the poster of you mattered and it's just called posted of your mentor and pass an
empty string as a review.
So unstaffed or Java.
So the first thing that we need to do here is let's invoke the superclass masterclasses super Dawk austerity
view and let's pass the review text.
Has he said of your text.
What is whatever has been passed in this matter.
So we have this and all you need to do now is just written this so now it's going to call the superclass
method.
So if you see here you just comment something on the second site says stuff posted even a user posted
review.
So we are invoking post-edit of your method and first the one in the subclass gets invoked here and
the first the one in the subclause got to invoke and put in staff post a review and then we are calling
the superclass method posted a few hundred buttons.
The second statement when the Superquinn the poster reviewing the user classes has gone invoke.
And that would return a review object.
And since we are and the staff class we need to set the approved status to recruit because the one that
is written by a user class will have on a status of fall.
So let's just make it true.
So it looks more realistic now.
So that's it said if you did not use this key word then you get you end up in an infinite loop because
you're just invoking the same post-Arab you mentored and that will give an error called stack overflow
error.
It's not what we want it is but main thing is that you can see you can see that it's always staff boss
to review underdosed just invoking recursively and at some point it will throw an error called Esquire's
and guttered and Sohmer call stack overflow error which is part of the Gelada act like package.
So that's because we were.
We kind of got into an infinite loop.
So it has to be super.
So that's one thing.
And we also said that superclass cannot be used so perky word cannot be used in a static Minturn's sort
of just put a start here to hide its name or does static mattered and nurses super Daut.
Here it says cannot use super in a static context.
So we can't use that.
So that's gone on the last thing about superballs that can be used to invoke a hidden field.
I actually added a field here in user class called ID which is initialized to 1 and I'm hiding it here
in the subclass stuff here.
I'm really declaring it here an idea is to not have this medicore print ID which is printing ID Fosdick's
going to print ID directly by using them.
I mean just a simple name ID on the second statement uses the super key word and it's going to user
test.
Not just uncommon this where we are accessing the prent ID motard sort of mirror just on this.
So here it says for ID pins s2.
And then for superdog ID Princesa one.
So if I go into this material you can see that when we are accessing ID it's actually accessing the
ID in the same class but.
So this idea is actually hiding that Id read and the superclass.
But when I say if I want to access the hidden food then I have to use supercooled here and that would
access the ID free.
So thats about it.
So we have to start everything that we have learned so far and upset and once again I'm showing this
an eclipse just to save some time and that's.