Hello there.
This is the remote Uluru.
And welcome back.
So let's begin by looking at the integer data types.
We all know that integers are whole numbers or fixed point numbers and would include both positive as
well as negative numbers.
And in Java they can be represented by these four primitive data types byte short, int or long.
And this table gives more information on these integer data types.
First column shows the different integer data types.
Second column indicates their bid, which is nothing but the number of bits needed to internally represent
the data.
Type's variable value bit depth basically indicates the container size that is the storage space needed
for a variable value.
Third column indicates the range of values a variable of a particular type can take.
Note that range is dependent on the depth that is higher.
The depth larger is the range.
Finally, fourth column indicates the default value of each of the data types.
All four data types have zero as a default value and we have already seen that for the data type in
one of the previous demos and also recall that variables declared in a method that is the local variables
will not get any default value.
So let's look at what we have here for each of the data types.
First is byte, which is represented in eight bits.
That is a byte variables value will be represented in eight bits.
Due to this, a byte variable can hold any value between minus two to the power of 7 to 2 to the power
of seven minus one that is -128 to 127.
That is a byte can hold a number only in between -128 to positive 127.
And if you try to assign it a value outside of this range, then you get a compilation error and soon
we will see this in our demo.
Now, in case you are not sure why a base tool is used here, it's only because computers use binary
system which deals with only zeros and ones.
We know that decimal system uses base ten as decimal system uses the digits 0 to 9 to represent numbers.
Also, if you're wondering why the range is -128 to positive 127, it's only because the bed depth is
eight, which can be used to represent a total of two to the power of eight numbers, that is to 56
numbers.
And these 256 numbers fall in the range -128 to positive 1.7, including zero.
Now among the eight bets, the leftmost bit which is called us, the sign bit tells whether a number
is positive or negative.
If the sign is zero, it means it's a positive number.
And if it is one, it means it's a negative number.
Generally, leftmost bet is also referred to as the most significant bet, and the remaining seven bits
indicate the magnitude of the number like 127.
So that's the reason the range says minus two to the power of 7 to 2 to the power of seven minus one.
One of them is used as the sign that.
Next chart is represented in 16 bits, so its depth is higher than the depth of byte and so can store
larger values.
That is a range of values it can hold is in between minus two to the power of 15 to 2 to the power of
15 minus one, which is nothing but -32,000 768 to positive.
32,007.
67.
Next ENT is represented in 32 bits and can take any value between minus two to the power of 31 to 2
to the power of 31 minus one.
So it can hold very large numbers.
Finally, long is represented in 64 bits and so it can take any value between minus two to the power
of 63 to 2 to the power of 63 minus one, so long as its name implies, is really long.
That is, it can hold very, very large numbers.
Now as good software engineers, we do need to have a clear idea of the different data types that are
supported and how much memory they consume.
So I request you to firmly memorize what we see here and this table about the different data types,
their bid depth, and the corresponding range of values that they support.
You can expect a couple of questions from this table in the upcoming quest.
Now internally java users something called signed to complement scheme to represent integers.
That's what computers also use to represent integers.
Now, if you're not familiar with sign two's complement scheme, you can check out the supplementary
notes in the resources section, and it includes a link to an excellent article that discusses sign
to complement scheme as well as other schemes for representing floating point and characters, which
we will discuss later.
You don't have to read that article right away.
You can do it later once you're comfortable with Java.
So I don't want you to get distracted from that, but it's just your call.
Now let's go ahead and extend our student class by declaring some new integer variables.
Here is our student class and we declared this variable called ID, which is of data type eight and
as initialized 1000.
So we already use the INT data type and we also had this method called us compute where we are declaring
another variable called next ID, which is also off type end and it would be ID plus one.
And we are printing both the values here and we are creating an object of this particular class from
the main method and we are invoking the compute method and that would print both the values.
So let's go ahead and create more variables.
So let's create a variable called H and let's have the type as byte and let's initialize it to 18.
So the student's age is 18.
So let's go ahead and compile Java.
Student dot Java.
Compiles fun, so let's just run it.
Next slide.
So let's actually print this value.
Okay.
So, Prince 18 Now let's introduce another variable.
Let's call it as rank.
And let's also have the data type as byte.
So let's assume that there is some entrance test to get an admission in the university, and so there
would be a rank associated with the entrance test.
So let's say the student has got a rank of 165 in the entrance test in order to gain an admission into
the university.
So let's go ahead and compile this.
So it gives us an error.
It says incompatible types, possible lossy conversion from INT to byte.
So essentially what it is saying is this value 165 falls outside the range of byte.
We know that bytes range is -128 to 127.
So 165 volts outside this range.
And so we are getting a compilation error.
Now let's look at this message here.
It says, incompatible types, possible lossy conversion.
So just ignore this particular message for now.
Maybe we can look at it later.
But it says possible lossy conversion from int to byte byte is fine because we have byte here on the
left side.
But why does it say int?
The thing is, we know that this is a literal and in Java this is a literal of type of data type.
And in Java you do not have a bit later you have only an end literal or a long literal, which we will
discuss next.
But we do not have literals of type byte or literals of type shot, so no byte or short literals.
We only have a literal or long literal, which we will see later.
So if you see some number like this, just a whole number like this, then it is an literal.
So in order to make this to make this work, we can assign it to a long or a short or an end, a larger
data type.
So that's the reason why it says possible lossy conversion from INT to bite.
Now let's go ahead and assign some values here -129, which is also outside the range.
So once again it says possible lossy conversion from INT to byte.
It's just the same message.
Now, if we say 128, we should be good because.
Because 120 -128 falls within the range.
The same goes with.
Positive 128 positive 128 will also give us a compilation error.
It's the same error.
And if we assign 127, we are once again.
Good.
Let me just clear up the screen.
So we are good because it is 127 and 127 is the maximum value for byte.
But we wanted to assign 165, so let's just change it to short here.
And.
Your good, sir.
Correct assignment, because Short has a larger range of values.
So that's short.
Now let's introduce.
Phone number and let's call it as let's have the data type as end.
1234567890.
Let's keep it simple and let's compile this.
Compiles fine.
So let's change this number to two.
Now it says integer number to large.
So this number falls outside the range of end, which is fine.
But you may notice that the error message is different from what we had earlier.
Earlier it said that there is incompatible types from int to byte, but here it does not say that.
Here it says something else.
It says integer number too large.
The reason is it is complaining about this letter itself.
So it is an invalid end literal.
We know that its range is minus two to the power of 31 to 2 to the power of 31 minus one.
And this falls outside that range.
So it is complaining about the literal itself.
It's a larger number.
So we need to make it a long literal.
And the way you do it is just add this a trailing L and it would be a long literal.
You can use an uppercase L or a lowercase, but it is recommended to use uppercase because the lowercase
l is very similar to one and it can be it's very difficult to distinguish from one.
So it is suggested to use the uppercase L.
So this is the long literal.
So what we have here is the end literal and this is the long literal.
Now let's compile this.
Now it gives the the other type of error which we have seen earlier, incompatible types and it says
from long to end, which is fine because this is long and this is eight and this is not within the range
of long.
But the important thing is it's not just that, it's also that the long literal cannot be assigned to
end, even if the number is within the range of.
And for instance, here we have thousand, so let's make it 1000.
L And we can see the error.
It gives two compilation errors.
Here is one error and here is another error.
It says that incompatible types possible lossy conversion from long to int.
So for here it is fine.
Right.
If we used a literal and we were assigning to byte, it is working fine because this is within the range.
So complain compiler is not complaining about it.
But if we change it to long literal so the compiler does not like it.
So this time it gives three errors.
One for this because it is an invalid assignment, then one for the byte.
It's an invalid assignment.
So the thing is int byte and short can be assigned only in letters.
That's how the language designers have designed it.
And this long, literal cannot be assigned to any of these three.
If you do it, we get a compilation error, as we have just seen.
So a long letter can be assigned to only long.
So that's the thing.
It can be assigned only to long or of other data types which are of which are larger than long, but
that we will see later.
But among the integer literals, this long literal can be assigned to only long and for eight byte and
short, it's got to be integer.
So always keep in mind that integer literals there are only two integer literals.
One is a literal and the other is long literal.
And that's it.
I hope you're also typing all of this code.
As I'm demonstrating, I think that will be very useful for you to compile and see the output for yourself.
So if possible, do try to type in everything as I'm demonstrating.
And here it's a very large number.
Maybe it's not very readable.
Sometimes this is the area code and we might want to when you're using a user interface, sometimes
the area code is taken separately, right?
So it might be good to make it more readable.
For instance, we can have an underscore here and an underscore here.
So in Java, from the Java seven version on words, you can actually use underscores here to make it
more readable.
So it helps with readability, underscores HAL help with readability.
So we also do that in real life when we are writing our checks in the bank.
So we also use commas to indicate the amount that we are depositing in a similar way Java has introduced,
the designers have introduced this underscores and this underscores have to appear somewhere in between.
It cannot appear at the beginning or at the end, but if you print it, it will print without the underscore.
So let's just go ahead and print that.
Okay.
Let's also put one here.
Underscore doesn't make sense but just for testing that's what the bite.
And let's run it.
So as you can see, it prints 18 and here it prints the number without the underscores.
So it applies for both literal as well as the long literal.
The only thing is you cannot have it here or at the end.
So if you recompile it, it gives you a compilation error.
So it gives some error.
So that's the thing.
You cannot do that.
So this applies only from Java seven onwards.
So just keep that in mind.
Now, finally, I just want to show you something.
Let's say eight.
So we know that the main value for end is minus two to the power of 31, and the max value is two to
the power of 31 minus one.
So if at all, you want to see what those numbers are, you can do this.
You know, you can print integer min, underscore value and integer dot max underscore value to get
the max value of int.
So integer is a class that comes with the Java library.
It's called as a boxed primitive or a wrapper type.
And every primitive type has an associated boxed primitive.
So this is a boxed primitive class and we will discuss these box primitive classes later in a subsequent
section.
So it has a boxed primitive type.
Similarly, all other types like byte also has a box, primitive type shot also has it.
So all of the eight primitive data types have associated box primitive types and for byte also we can
get its min and max value like -128 and 127 in the same way.
So let's go ahead and print these values.
So it prints the minimum value and the max value.
So this is what it is.
And if you want to see it for byte, just change it to byte.
And here the class name is byte and byte.
So it should show us what it should.
It should show us -128 to positive 127.
That's what it is.
But you need to memorize this so that's that you can print that and more on box primitives later on.
So this is the end.
Primitive and long.
Primitive.
So this is in decimal format.
But let me also show you this integer class which had the min value and max value.
Let me show it in my editor.
So this is the integer class and here it is integer class.
And as you can see, it has the mean value and max value.
But you can see here that it has a different type of assignment, a different format.
It is being initialized with zero X.
So this is a different format, its hexadecimal format, but it is still an integer.
So eight and long literals can also be represented in other less commonly used formats.
So what we have seen right here is the decimal format, but it also has other less commonly used format
and that would be the subject of next lecture and we will see it there.
So that's about it.
So just keep in mind that Integer Literals would be only integer or long lecture and you can also use
underscores for readability and that's especially useful when you have large numbers.
So that's it.
Thank you.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about the integer data types and see you in the next lecture.