Hi there.
This is Diamond de la Rue.
We have seen that in certain scenarios.
In a multithreaded environment, things can work in an unpredictable way as it is a thread scheduler
which manages everything.
As a result, we discussed about the race condition, which may happen when two threads share some mutable
data, and we have seen how synchronization can help with that.
By using synchronization, we could make things operate in a more ordered way.
Right.
And in Java, we have something called the Java memory model.
J Mm.
Which defines such ordering.
Java memory model is part of the Java language specification and it is related to multithreading.
It's critical to be aware of it when we are doing multithreaded programming and especially when we are
dealing with shared mutable data.
It's not complicated stuff.
It's just a bunch of rules which we need to be aware of.
In this lecture, we will look at what those gem rules are, and even in the follow up lecture, we
will explore some of the relevant stuff.
You may recall the slide from our previous lecture.
This is the bank account example of John and Anita.
We said that John and Anita are represented by two threads, both of which are active at the same time.
So John said might invoke the make withdrawal method and update the balance to the new amount.
And at the same time, Anita's threat might also access the get balance method on the same bank account
object, but might still see the old balance amount.
So there is no guarantee that Anita Straight would see the latest value.
And if it doesn't see the latest value, it may result in the system going into some incorrect state.
Essentially, we have a risk condition here.
One reason for Anita's threat seeing old value could be due to out-of-order actions.
For instance, it could be that John's thread is inside the make withdrawal method and also does the
balance check, but then it goes into reasonable right before updating balance.
And animal threat would become active, which means that it would be in the running state and then would
see the old value of balance as it is not yet updated, but programmer might have not wanted the sequence
of actions to be in this way where there is an interleaving of actions.
The reason is, of course, one is the synchronized method while the other is synchronized.
And we never know how thread scheduler is going to execute the statements.
Right.
And another reason can be when we are dealing with a multiprocessor system which shared memory, which
is what most modern systems are.
Here.
Each processor has its own local cache, which is periodically reconciled with the shared memory.
So John Street might be on one processor and might execute the make withdrawal method to completion.
So it fully executes the make withdrawal method and the new balance amount could be flushed to the local
cache and then also to main memory.
However, Anita's threat might be on another processor and might read the balance value only from its
local cash, which has all value that is not yet updated.
So factors such as this and the out of order actions which we saw earlier can prevent a threat from
seeing the updated values.
So basically there is lack of thread coordination.
And if you recall in the previous lecture we said that it has got something to do with performance.
Most of the time, threats deal with only their own stuff, and it's not required to communicate with
other threats.
Communicating with other threads on every right operation can be expensive and it could be really bad
in a multiprocessor system with shared memory due to the need for frequent updates that need to happen
between the local cache and the memory and the shared memory.
Coordination is required only when mutable status shared across the threads, like in our John and Anita's
example, where the mutable state is the balance variable.
So if there is no sharing of notable state, then there is no reason to coordinate between threads despite
any right operations.
Similarly, if there are dealing with completely different objects of the same class, then once again
thread coordination may not be required at all.
But if there is a shared state that is mutable, then it is the program's responsibility, not JBS,
to ensure that threats coordinate about such shared state.
So all of this is for the sake of performance.
One way to ensure thread coordination is via synchronization.
So it's the programmer's job to do that.
And we saw this in the previous lecture to where get balance is also synchronized.
Now, if John's thread first accesses the make the doll method, then unattached thread cannot enter
that balance method until Johns thread exits make withdrawal.
As we know that at any given instance of time, only one thread can enter a synchronized method of a
shared object.
Right.
Here we say that the two actions Jones thread entering the make withdrawal method and Anita's thread
entering get balance however happens before relationship that is the john thread entering make withdrawal
happens before Anita's thread entering get balance.
And this happens before relationship also requires that Anita Street sees only the latest value of balance.
So that happens before relationship, which we just saw is achieved through synchronization.
And this notion of happens before is part of the Java's memory model and the JVM implements Java's memory
model.
And so when it sees the synchronized keyword, then it knows that there is a need for inter thread coordination.
And for this it inserts special instructions called memory barriers, which would instruct the underlying
architecture to do any necessary memory coordination.
Coordination between the cache and the shared memory.
Not that in our bank account example, Julia might place the memory barrier right after John's thread
exits, make withdrawal method and releases the lock.
Or it may do it when Anita's thread acquires the lock in order to enter get balance method.
So the exact timing of when JVM inserts memory barrier is dependent on specific JVM implementation,
and it is not specified in the Java memory model, which, as we said earlier, is part of the Java
language specification.
So what happens before ordering?
We can be sure that the results of a right action by one thread are guaranteed to be visible to a reaction
by another thread.
Only if the right operation happens before the operation.
Note that Java memory model specifies few scenarios or rules, then happens before ordering happens
and synchronization is only one of them.
So let's look at the different scenarios.
First one is based on program order.
This rule says that each action in a given threat happens before every other action that comes later
in the thread.
Second one is based on LOC, which is what we discussed with our synchronization example.
Releasing a log happens before every subsequent acquisition of that same log.
In our example, if make withdrawal is invoked first, then when John thread exits the method, it releases
the log, which is then acquired by another thread in order to enter get balance.
Note that if the right and redactions use different locks, then there is no happens before relation
between the two actions.
So keep that in mind.
It's got to be the same lock.
Next is based on volatile variable, which is the subject of next lecture.
Basically, volatile is a key word that can be used when declaring a variable and a right to such a
variable happens before every subsequent read of that variable.
Regardless of the thread doing the reading.
Next is the third start rule.
What it means is a call to a start method on a given thread happens before every other action that happens
within that thread.
Next rule is based on the joint operation.
What it means is all actions in a particular thread happens before the thread that successfully returns
from a joint on that thread.
Next is the interruption rule.
Interrupt is a method and it can be invoked on a thread to tell the thread that it should stop what
it is doing and do something else.
Generally, it is invoked on a thread as a means to terminate the thread.
With regards to happens before ordering the act of one thread calling interrupt method on another thread
happens before the interrupted thread detects the interrupt itself.
We may look at interrupt later.
Our next one is the final rule, which is about the finalized method and the object class finalize method
will be invoked by the garbage collector when it detects that there are no more references to the object.
Subclasses of Object can override finalize method to perform any cleanup operations before the object
is garbage collected and with regards to happens before ordering the rule is that the end of the constructor
of an object happens before the start of the final for that object.
Right?
Obviously that is what is going to happen.
Next one is the familiar transitivity rule.
According to it, if action happens before action B and if action B happens before action C, then action
A happens before action.
C.
So those are the happens before ordering rules.
And I believe that second and third rules, which are about locks and volatile variables, are probably
the ones that really matter for us as we use them deliberately.
Just to summarize, these GM rules ensure that different threads can have a consistent view of the shared
state.
That is the result of a right action by one thread are guaranteed to be visible to a reduction by another
thread.
Only if the right happens before the real operation.
Whether such a happens before ordering, we would have a risk condition.
And a correctly synchronized program is won without any race conditions.
That's about it.
And thank you.