It does them all for the affliction.
We have two classes.
One is called the refl. demo and it is a main class on has been appropriately named I and the other
one is called as a user of dot Jawa.
So both of these classes are either in the GBM package so refl. do more as a main class and written
refl. them or we have the main method.
And there are things that we are testing here.
So there are two methods for Budapest's one is called as demo class object access.
So as the name suggests this particular method is used to demonstrate accessing class object so there
were three ways to access class objects.
Unreal.
And we'll be looking at all three of them and we will also see how the Mad-Eye information in the class
object can be accessed.
And the second method is Karlos demo code reflection.
And here we will explore more reflection properties for reflection features.
So we will demonstrate instance creation and method invocation using the class object.
So the class object.
Here is the input.
So that's what we are going to test here and use and our July is pretty simple.
We are already familiar with this class so it has all these fields and it has no constructor and it
also has this constructor which has all these parameters on initialises the fields and there are two
methods.
One is called a save weblink and the other is both bookmark review with some parameters here.
But let's not worry about all of that because that's not relevant here.
And just wandered into Boullion.
So let's go back.
So both these classes are available in the resource section for download.
So let's just look at what we have in each of these matters.
So let's just go here first with a demo class object access.
So the first one as accessing the class object via object reference.
So for this we are defining this string array object and it has these three values.
And all we are doing is just invoking since a and is also an object in Java we are invoking the get
class method and we are just simply printing or to get name.
Now the second thing we are testing is the Arctic farming method and the class.
So we are passing the fully qualified name here.
After that off the user class which is also in JVM.
So we are passing the fully qualified name on we are loading the class and we are printing all the information
at least some of the important ones like what did we miss with that it's an interface or not.
If there are any interfaces that this particular class user is in stone is implementing.
And also the superclass here getting the superclass off user and printing its name.
OK.
Now the third one here there is one additional test that we are doing.
We know that Glassdoor foreign for named does not work with primitives.
So here we have a primitive here here and this word at runtime.
This would throw an exception called class not one exception as was discussed.
So the congruity comes here and brings this message.
And finally there Doc class the class nutritious approaches tested here so we ain't dog class which
is a class object and we are simply printing the name.
So that's the first method and here is a second letter to the second method we are placing a class object
here.
So we are getting the class object using the foreign name approach and we are simply passing it here
.
And all we are doing is we are creating a new instance here.
So on the class object this object we are calling this method call new instance.
And in order to do that the user class must have a default constructor and that's the reason for having
this constructor here.
It should be there.
Now once we do that we are invoking this method Corylus get declared methods and it contains all the
methods in the class.
OK.
And so I couldn't send off all the method objects or here and method object is from the dot dot Langhart
reflect package.
And we are printing the names.
And here we are making use of the white glass object.
So we are simply saying why not glass.
And if this particular method in the in the current iteration if it has we are calling the return type
method and get returned by returns that the class object corresponding to the return type and if it
equals the white class or a wider class which means that the class object responding to why don't we
simply print dispatch it message method or can type as wide.
So one of the methods has a void.
It can type on in here get declared constructors.
So disorder gets on the constructors and each construct it is basically an object.
Once again from the Java Langhart reflect.
And here we are getting one particular constructor.
The constructor that does that for fetching is based on the number of barometers and the type of the
parameters and basically the be on the type of the parameters.
So if you look at this etches get declared constructor has an array of class objects are being passed
here.
OK.
So it's a virus parameter.
So based on that we get the constructor that we need and then we are creating a new instance of that
.
And we are passing all the values for example here it is anti-abort glass.
The first parameter so we are passing this value 101 on the second parameter is name that Hurleys email
.
And so we are passing all the corresponding values that we need to pass.
And here we are fetching a method and invoking it.
So previously we are fetching a concept around in working it.
Here you are fetching a method only milking it.
And all we do is we in the matter get declared method on the class reference variable and we are saying
that we need this method call see weblink and we are also specifying the parameter types here.
String not grass.
Another one is string dark glass.
So if you go back here has string parameters.
So that's what we are saying we need that particular method.
OK so this get declared better.
As for getting one particular matter get declared constructor as for fetching one particular constructor
and the way you walk and method is.
So you have the method object here just call in matter and you need to pass this user object.
You need to pass this use object that was created earlier and we need to pass the values also.
So we are passing.
Do I use one of them as the host name and the other one as say rebeling is some idea.
Sorry that you are an Teicher.
So you're passing those values here.
And this is returning some value.
So Doc ralliers are off and working that is being printed here.
So that's about it here.
So let's just go ahead and run this program and look at the values too.
So let's look at this.
So here it is.
We are printing this.
This is using the Glasman getting the class object we are the object reference and object reference
is basically a string array.
So it's printing the name.
So this is the name that's getting printed.
So since it's an array single dimension an array we have this squared record.
And since it's a string that it contains.
So we have this string class preceded by an L as mentioned earlier and a semicolon.
So that's the first one.
Next we are using the start for a new method.
And we are leading the class here and we are printing the name here.
Class not get me.
Which gives the name of the fully qualified name off the user class.
Is it an interface.
No number of interface it implements.
No it doesn't implement any interfaces.
And what is a superclass superclass is there is only one class which is it's not excluding any other
class.
So the only class it extends as the object bus underspending its name here.
Now here we are trying to load a primitive using for name which we know doesn't work.
So the control goes into the catch block here and brings this message glass not found exception to class
dart for me not get me.
So that's just one type of message.
And here we are printing using the class to access the class object and we are printing its name.
And here it is.
It just prints it.
That's it because it's a primitive.
Know let's move into the second method which is a demo called reflection.
And here a new object is created.
And so the object name the variable name is object.
And we are getting we are getting it's get using get Glasby and getting the class object and we are
once again simply printing it.
OK.
So for I'm the class object we are creating an object.
But then from the object we are getting the class object one more time.
And just printing its name just to demonstrate all of this.
So if you go down here which says object don't get class as this is the name of the class of this particular
object.
Now let's.
Next as we have printing out all the methods shown here are declared methods and they are ignoring the
get named method here.
So it's printing to matter say a weblink was bookmark review.
OK.
And one of the methods post-Bush Marco Rubio has
a right as the return type.
So it goes into this if condition this if statement executes.
It has a true value and it prints this statement.
Next is we are printing all the constructors and we are breaking the name.
Name is simply the user here for both of them are numbered alphabet I mean girls.
So there is a method called Get barometer types on in where we are invoking that document.
So on the first iteration or just the default constructor and the second it's the second constructor
which had five parameters.
And finally here we are invoking the method we are creating an instance using the instance of user using
it using this constructor and then we are also getting though the method.
This particular method called Save eyeblink and invoking it but passing the user instance here.
And so it has this particular method has some print statements on it's getting printed and simply printing
older the values passed here the parameter values.
And finally the result of invoking save eyeblink that it can take is basically a boolean and it truly
is getting printed here.
So that's about that's about the reflection the more that we have.
And one thing I want to mention as a reflection is definitely slower compared to non-HD reflection court
.
So for example if you're creating an all if you're creating objects using reflection and if you also
compare it if you create the same object be it using non-HD reflection.
So you're using the new Nuki keyword then definitely in the non-definition code will be slightly faster
but a reflection is also useful.
It needs to be used but it's just that it is a [REMOVED].
It is kind of slower.
And so you want to be really careful if your code is going to be frequently used and you have and you
have the reflection code there.
So if it is being used in a very frequently used code and application or surface performance intensive
then you need to be careful about that.
Maybe you don't want to use Reflection in those parts of the code.
So so just to exercise caution be careful.
OK so that's about it.
So that's refl. demo and we have a strict pretty much everything that we have learned.
Thank you.
And happy coding.