Hi there.
This is the Romans.
And welcome back.
So in the last lecture, we looked at the select committees.
And I think we now have a good understanding of select committees.
And select committees can be much more complex than that and that you can learn through experience and
also reading some extra material.
Now let's go ahead and refactor our code.
So here is the launch class.
And this is a load of data within the same class.
And here we are invoking the data store load data.
Now, this is the data store class and the load data method.
And you may recall that we had these kinds of invocations for reading data from the text files and I
have commented them out and they have also been removed here from this class.
The only method I have is this, and this is where we are going to do the refactoring in code and for
rest of the stuff like for reading user weblink and movies, it has already been refactored.
And we have also looked at this particular this piece of code where we were loading the ZB driver.
Now here is what we are going to look at.
So this is these are some new changes.
Now we are going to look at some of these types, interfaces and interfaces that come from that come
from the Java SQL package.
So the first thing is we have loaded the GBC driver and the previous lecture.
Next thing to do is we need to get a connection to the database.
And for that we invoke this method called get connection on the driver manager.
Class Driver Manager is from Java SQL.
So we are using the code API and here is the connection string to the database.
So the connection string has a particular has a certain syntax here.
So here is the syntax.
First one is protocol and protocol is nothing, but it would be gbk always followed by a colon, followed
by sub protocol and sub protocol.
In this case, when we are dealing with my SQL, it would be my SQL and in case of other databases it
would be something else.
Then you have this colon, then you have the data source details.
So it is about the my SQL particular, my SQL Server instance itself.
So in our case it is running on the local host, which is, which means it's on the same host, but
it can be some other remote IP address also.
And you have a column, you have double slash here followed by the IP address, followed by colon,
followed by port number on which this my server instance is running, followed by a slash and followed
by the database name on that particular machine.
So that's what we have here and here.
This is some parameter we can ignore it.
And to this method called get connection, we are passing the who the user is.
The user is the root user and we are also passing the root password, which is root in our case.
And this method would return a connection.
Instance on connection is an interface here.
Connection is an interface in Java SQL and this this is going to return an instance of connection.
Now the instance that is returned is actually coming from the GBK driver itself.
So we say we know that the GDB C driver is a jar file which has a bunch of class files.
So this driver manager does not get connection.
When this statement gets executed, it's going to pass this particular URL, the string connection string
to all of the all of the drivers that are registered with it to all of the GBK drivers.
But we registered only one driver, which is a minus year driver, but we can also register multiple
gypsy drivers.
And if we do that, then it's going to pass this connection string to each of those Jtbc drivers.
And one of them in this case, my SQL database driver, will say that it can work with this particular
connection string and it will return an instance of a class which actually implements this connection
interface and it represents a connection to the database instance.
Now sometimes we may also have more than one database servers, which is what the case typically is
in professional projects.
Then you can include multiple addresses here which are comma separated.
So in that case, if one of them, if we are unable to connect to one of them, then the database driver
will automatically use the second or the third one as the fail failover servers.
So so in that case.
So if one fails, it will try to use the other one.
So at least it would work for my SQL.
So that's what I read.
So that is how it works.
It's going to select a particular driver in the statement and now the connection interface has a closed
method.
So once we are done with dealing, with interacting with the database, it needs to be closed.
So we are using this private resources syntax here and we know that this syntax, this feature, will
automatically execute the closed method on this particular variable, which is representing the connection.
Now from the connection here we have within the same private resources syntax, we also are getting
something called statement and for that to get a statement, we are invoking the create statement method
on the on this connection object and it will return an instance of statement statement is also an interface
within the SQL and statement is actually used to use to execute our queries.
So connection is for connecting to the database and statement is for executing the actual queries.
Now here we have written new methods.
Earlier we had the same methods, but without passing any arguments.
So it was no ARG methods.
But here we are passing the statement instance as an argument and the code has already been refactored
for these three methods as I mentioned earlier.
So we need to just look at the load box method.
So the load box.
This is the load box method, the earlier method and the current version.
Now we have to refactor it.
So load box all it is doing as it is reading from the text file.
So if you recall, we were using this read method from the IO class which we have written.
So it is reading and we are passing this book, which means that we need to read from book to text.
And all of the data is being read into this data structure, which is another list.
And each element in this data structure will be one row of a book.
So this is the book text file, and each of these rows will be read into the.
Analyst.
So that's what we were doing.
Now what we will have to do is we need to read from the database, right?
That's what we need to do.
So the first thing is I already have the query here.
This is the query.
So this is very similar to the query that we have seen in the previous lecture when learning about the
select queries almost identical.
Only difference here.
So we are using still a group buy ID and we are still concatenating here.
Here, I'm saying as authors.
As authors.
So I'm using an alias for this group underscore that it is concatenating the author information and
generating a comma separated list.
And apart from that we are also extracting the book genre ID Amazon rating and additionally I'm just
extracting created underscore date recall that every anything that we are adding into our database,
we are also we are also capturing the creation date of that particular row so that I'm doing just because
to show you how we deal with dates in the event reading the data from the database and everything else
is just the same, like in the case of when we were reading that from the text file.
So we are extracting only those columns here and everything else is.
The query is also very identical to what we have seen earlier and the next thing.
So we need to execute the query and we need to use.
Statement here.
Now we need to execute the statement.
So for that, there is this method called execute query.
Here it is.
So we can invoke this method and we can pass our query.
And with this, this query will be executed.
So just like the way we were executing queries from the command line.
So this particular statement would execute this query from our Java program and it returns something
called a result set.
Earlier we were using an array list.
Now on each element of our list was storing the data of each row.
And here the ArrayList is replaced with.
Result set and by convention generally people use just RS for that to represent that.
So that's what it is.
And this one, we can leave it as it is.
And here we are iterating through this list and in each iteration we are processing a particular row
and we are not going to change any of that.
It's just that we will use while instead of four and four results set in order to iterate it, we will
set results that dot next.
So results set is also an interface in Java SQL.
So we looked at two interfaces already connection and statement and result set is also another interface
within that.
So this execute query will return an instance of results set and Results Set has all the different roles
that were extracted from the database and to process each row we need to iterate once.
So basically there is something, a concept called a cursor and cursor is initially before the first
row.
So we are extracting a bunch of rows from the database and it is initially the cursor will be before
the first row and when we invoke the next method here, cursor will point to the first row and it will
return a true.
But if there are no rows to extract, then cursor it means that the cursor as has been moved after the
last row.
In which case it will return a false and we will exit the loop.
So this is how we will iterate through a result set object by using the next method.
Now let me.
I also have the.
Some code here.
Let me just copy all of this.
Pretty simple code.
There's nothing complicated there.
So we just need to extract the individual items.
For instance, here we are getting some values and we are extracting the author information in the previous
version.
Now we are just going to let me delete that.
These last two statements are we can change them.
So this is what we have.
Here.
So here basically we are getting the data and we'll review that.
But once we get the data, we need to create a book.
That's what we were doing.
Even in the previous version.
Once we read the data in each iteration, we were creating a single book.
So that's what we do here also.
Now here we are invoking some methods, some better methods on, on the results set object.
So for instance, the first one that in the query that we specify is the ID.
Second is the title.
Third is the publication here.
So we are simply extracting each of those items via this method methods.
So ID is along in our database.
So we are saying it's long.
It is actually a big end, but a big end corresponds to long in Java.
So we are saying ask dot get long and we are passing the name of the field.
ID field and for title is a string.
We are saying asked get string off title.
So title is the second field here.
So it is the publication here which is an end in the database and it's also an end here.
So and we are assigning it to publication here and here.
String title is being assigned to this variable called string.
So and in the fourth one is the name of the publisher.
So it is a name is a string.
So we are saying asked get string and it is being assigned to this string.
Now for the fourth one is the authors.
Authors, we are doing a concatenation and we are assigning it to a string array here.
So we are in a for one of the books for the head first design patterns.
I believe it had four authors, so it would be a comma separated list.
So we are splitting it.
But for certain books, for most of the book is just a single author, in which case the authors will
have.
The authors are able to have only a single element and the genre ID is also we are getting the genre
ID now.
If you recall from a couple of lectures ago, I said that the genre ID is actually the enum ordinal
value.
If you recall, there is the book genre enum and we were just in the database, we were storing the
the ordinal value of a particular genre.
So we were not storing any string or anything for genre, but we were just storing the ordinal values.
So book genre is here.
So this is what we are storing, the ordinal value of that.
So we were calling it as book genre ID and it has a tiny end as a tiny end as the data, as the data
type in the database.
So we are getting that gender ID and we need to get the actual book genre itself, the enum constant
itself.
So we are saying book genre, dot values, book genre is an enum sort values and we are about values
and values.
We know well return all the constants but we, we need the constant corresponding to this genre ID so
we are passing the ordinal value here and we are getting the book genre.
So I hope that's clear.
The next thing as we are getting the double value, which is Amazon rating and it's being assigned to
a double.
We are saying get double.
Now the fourth, this one we are just doing just for the sake of demonstrating date information.
So we are getting the date by invoking this method called get date and we are saying created underscore
date because that's the column name and it is being assigned to this class called Java dot SQL date.
So create a date and it is of this type and Java dot dot date actually extends extends Java date, which
we have seen when learning about the date and time API.
And it will return only a date, not the time information, but in the database we had both date as
well as time for this particular column created underscore date, but it would extract only only the
date part.
But if we need the entire date and time, we will have to invoke this method called get timestamp.
Now here we can use the same name created underscore date for all of these here all of these we can
either either use the name, the name of the column in the database, or we can use this such a number.
It's an index.
So for example, if you were to extract the ID here, we will put the index number one, which means
which corresponds to one here.
So this is one, this is two, this is three.
So there are some overloaded methods which we can use get long of one, get string off two, four titles
will be two.
So we can either pass the numbers index numbers corresponding to these or we can just pass the string
of the name of the column itself.
So let's just pass the names.
It will be much more clear this is just for demonstration.
I have included this because timestamp here is the eighth index position.
One, two, three, four, five.
Six, seven and eight.
So it starts with one, not zero.
And also just just note that here we are saying as authors for group underscore cat for that particular
thing.
And over here also we are saying authors.
Okay.
So that's the time information and I'm printing that now in Java eight, we know that we had local date
time.
So if you want to convert this timestamp Java timestamp into local date time, there is a method called
to local datetime, so you can even invoke that.
They did that on this time stamp instance.
And it will and it will return an instance of local datetime.
And here we are simply printing the values.
And only thing is here we need to change these.
So here.
This would be.
I'd.
Next one is title.
So all these values have been extracted out.
After title we have.
Publication.
Here.
Publisher authors.
Then we also extracted John Ray.
It's hard to miss genre after genre.
We had Amazon rating.
That's it.
And everything else is same.
And there is this exception that we need to throw.
Said The letters have gone and so bookmark once we get the bookmark, we are adding to this other list
which got which we are creating here.
So that's from the old code.
And finally, we are adding at this bookmark list the entire data that got read from the database,
it's being added into another data structure.
It's a list of list of bookmarks.
And it would store this particular bookmarks, data structure, which store all of the different.
Bookmarks.
So in this case, we are just adding one particular type of bookmark.
So that's that said.
So we are.
So in each iteration, we are basically reading some data and we have some getters like this and we
are reading that.
So that's with the load box.
Then we have a few other methods.
It's very simple, like this is the load users.
Load users is a simple query select start from user, which means that we want to extract everything
all the columns from each row of the user table.
So that's what we are doing.
And just like in the previous case, we are reading everything and we are saying create user here.
And it's getting added here to the users.
And for in the case of web links, it's very straightforward.
Select start from Web Link and we are extracting these for all apps.
So it's just a simple refactoring of the old code for load movies.
It's a little bit similar to the load box.
So just like in the case of books, we have movie, actor, movie, underscore, actor, director,
movie underscore, director, and so on.
So earlier we were reading from the movie or text file.
So we are reading now we are reading the same data, but from from the database and this is a skill
query and I will share some of these queries and the resources section and you can take a look at them.
And just like earlier, we are reading the data here and we are creating a movie and everything is the
same.
So let me just go ahead and.
Run this.
This is the launch glass.
And as you can see, everything is run and everything is coming from the database.
So that's good.
So that's about it.
So that's how we read data.
And in the next lecture, we will see how we can bookmark data and how we can write the bookmark data
into the database.
And for that, we need to create a few more tables in the database, and we will do that.
That's it.
And thank you and happy coding.