Hello there.
This is day to day.
And welcome back.
Let's look at a few more fundamental classes in the Java Lang package.
And they're referred to as box perimeters.
Now, as the name Box Primitive suggests, they have something to do with primitives.
Essentially, each box primitive would hold a particular primitive value.
In other words, a primitive value is being boxed inside a box.
Primitive.
Sometimes we also say that a primitive value is being rubbed inside a box.
And hence, for this reason, a box primitive is also sometimes referred to as a rubber cross.
Now in Georgia, we know that we have these eight primitive types and each of them has an associated
box primitive class.
The box primitive corresponding to end is the integer class.
And you can see the rest here.
Now, if you recall when discussing in Primitive, we looked at the integer class in order to get the
main and max value that an int variable can hold.
You may also recall that we mentioned about box primitives when learning about switch statements.
Let's now go ahead and learn more about them and we will also see how they are useful.
Here we are in the basics demo class in the main method.
So let's go ahead and create a new method called as boxed primitives.
And let's allow eclipse to auto create this method.
And it has created this template method.
So what we are going to do is we are going to create a few box parameter instances and we said that
a box primitive would hold a primitive value.
So we will do that.
So we will create different types of box primitives, like integer instance, double instance, and
so on.
And then we will also see how we can extract the primitive value from a created box.
Primitive.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So the first thing is, let me create an integer box parameter.
Let's name it as boxed int and we'll say integer dot.
We will select this method called value off, which is a static method.
And that's the reason we have the integer name, their integer class name, and we are going to pass
our primitive and this is how an integer instance is created.
So we are creating an integer instance.
So you may be wondering why are we not using a constructor in order to construct the integer instance?
Now this is called as value off is a static method and it's called as a static factory method.
So sometimes, like any object, can also be created using such static factory methods.
So just like the way factories construct something or create something, we can also have such factory
methods to create our objects.
So they are called us.
Static factory methods and value of is a standard naming convention for such factory methods.
And there are also other naming conventions.
And we will look at them later in the naming conventions lecture.
So there is a benefit in using value of instead of using constructor.
So we can also use a constructor to do this.
But we will look at that later.
In a few minutes we will discuss that.
So this is how you will do it.
And just note that I'm going to refer to this as a box parameter.
But sometimes the class itself is referred to as box parameter, but sometimes we may refer to this
particular object as a box parameter, but the context should make it clear.
So if it is box parameter, it can be this or it can be the class name also.
So this is how you would create an integer object.
So it is wrapping this particular value.
Eight.
Let's go ahead and create a few more box parameters.
So let's say Boolean boxed boolean is equal to so every class box, primitive class has such a value
of method.
So let's pass a literal true here.
So that's how you would create a boolean box parameter.
Let's also create a couple of more a character and double.
So that's the character.
And we will say character dot value of.
And let's say a character.
Let's see.
So that's how you would create box perimeters.
And I think four of them should do.
Let's go ahead and print the values, sets out control space and say boxed and just type in I and say
control space and it will automatically create the variable here.
And let me just copy all of this.
Million.
Okay.
So we can just have this object references and println will print the corresponding values.
Just don't worry how it's going to print the parameters.
So internally it will invoke a method called to string on each of these object references, and they
will return the primitive values that are being grabbed.
So let's just run this.
There you go.
Eight True C and 25.5.
Now there is also an overloaded.
Value of method.
So if I say integer dot value off, you can see that there are overloaded methods here.
So this one is taking an end.
So which we have seen earlier.
So this one is taking a string.
So let's pass a string here.
So let's just pass the string eight this time a string literal eight and let's limit us boxed into one.
OC So there are certain cases when certain instances when you might want to use this one, this particular
method.
Okay.
So this is also valid.
All right.
But the thing is.
Such a method is there in all of the boxed primitives except the character.
Plus, except for the character class, the rest of the box primitive classes have this overloaded value
of method.
So just keep that in mind.
But also just note that we cannot have.
Let me call it invalid.
This needs to be a valid numeric value.
So you cannot have something like this.
So this is invalid.
So it's not giving a compilation error, but when we execute it, you will see that we will get this
particular error called number format exception because the number format is not right.
So this is invalid.
So you cannot do this.
So this is one way of creating objects, the static factory methods.
Now there is also the regular way in which we can construct an object so it will be boxed and to so
we'll say new integer and let's say eight, but we shouldn't be doing this.
This is not a recommended way.
So let's go into the API of the integer class and let's see what they have or there.
So just type in integer and whichever is the latest Java version right now it is Java 14, so it's Java
14.
And let's click on this.
You'll see these results.
So just click on this one.
Okay, so this is the integer class and there are some fields here we already know about max value and
min value.
We have used it earlier.
And here are the two constructors.
So there are overloaded constructors.
So this one is taking an integer int and this is what we used and this one is taking a string and it
says they are deprecated.
It says it is really appropriate to use this constructor.
So let's click on that.
So deprecated implies that it is not recommended to use this particular constructor, which means that
there is an alternate way to achieve the same theme to create the object and which we have already used,
which is the value of method.
So it says it says it is really appropriate to use this constructor.
So there is this alternate way and deprecated.
It also implies that it might be removed in the future, so that particular constructor or method may
be removed in the future.
So it is supported for backward compatibility.
So it says it is this particular alternate method is generally a better choice as it is likely to yield
significantly better space on time performance.
So it's going to be it can be more efficient and it can also save some memory.
So that's what it is.
So let's go back here and let's see why this can be better than this.
So this is the static factory method.
So I'm just clicking f three here.
So it takes me to that particular method within the integer class.
So what is happening is so this is the, the primitive that is getting passed.
Now if that primitive is between these range low and high, so it is -128 and positive 127.
In that case it is going to return a pre constructed integer object.
So the integer object has already been created, has been pre constructed, and it's going to return
if the value is between -128 and 127.
So for any value in between that, there is already an integer object that has been created and it is
stored in some array and it is returning that.
But if the value falls out of this range, then it is creating a new integer object.
So it is caching these integer instances because there is a high possibility that you may be passing
a value that falls within that range -128 and positive 127.
So that particular operation might be often might happen often.
So we don't want to keep creating integer objects every time a value within that range is being passed.
So that way by pre creating, we are utilizing those pre created instances and that is saving us some
time and space.
So it's like a string pool.
So that's the benefit of using this such a factory method.
Static factory methods are allowing us to improve the performance by doing something like this instead
of using a constructor right away.
But we are using this constructor if the value falls outside of the range.
And because of this there is this particular item and the effect of Java.
In fact it is a very fast item and it says consider static factory methods instead of constructors and
that is one of the benefits.
So there are other benefits, but we cannot discuss it at this point of time.
Maybe not appropriate for this course also, but at this point, I think it's good enough that we know
at least this particular advantage of using a static factory method.
So we are using some pre constructed instances here.
So that's effective Java first item.
So you should not be using this.
Now let's go ahead and unwrap the values.
Let's just say and let's call it as perimeter ain't equal to.
So the boxed end that we created was named as boxed end.
So let's say boxed end dot.
So there is this method called int value.
And that would return an end.
Similarly, there is also.
So we had the boxed bullion.
So we'll say bullion value and it will return the wrapped bullion value.
So this needs to be bullion.
Similarly, if we want the car that was wrapped inside the box, primitive, so we'll say car, let's
say primitive car.
And it was boxed to a controlled space, not car value.
So when you do this, you get the value here.
So it is called us int value.
So it's the the method names are quite similar.
So it is like type value and it would return a type.
So it's not returning an integer but actually it's returning an int.
So this is returning a boolean primitive that God stored in this particular box parameter.
So and if we print, we will get those values again.
So let me just print for the first one, which is primitive and so I can just run it.
So for double it would be boxed double the variable name dot double value, right?
Say the aid got extracted from the perimeter.
So that is how you would unwrap.
The primitive.
So that's about it.
So in the next lecture, let me just stop here.
And the next lecture we will explore few more methods, but more importantly, we will discuss some
use cases where box primitives are used so we know how to create them and how to unwrap them.
But that's not it.
We need to know where they are useful, so we will look at a couple of use cases where they are, where
they are typically used, and that should be very helpful.
And in the process we will look at other methods and box parameters.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.