Hi there.
This is De La Rue and welcome back.
So we have learned about both comparison as well as logical operators.
And these operators, as we know, help in building logic.
So you have started learning about how to build logic.
And let's go ahead and put these both operator types into action.
So we are going to implement a simple coding exercise.
And in this coding exercise you would implement a method which would calculate the price of a used car.
So if you have a used car and if you want to sell that car, then you would like to know what the best
price is for selling that car.
Now different countries have different websites for such a functionality.
For instance, in United States we have this site called us Kelley Blue Book and the URL is CVS.com.
And using this site, you can know what the price would be for a used car.
Similarly, different countries have their own websites.
Now, if your country does not have a website, then probably it's an opportunity for you to build something
like this.
So by the end of this course, you would have the basic skillsets for building such a site.
But of course, you would have to do some follow up courses to learn some advanced technologies, some
follow up technologies, and then you can use them to build something similar.
So in this coding exercise, you will implement a basic version of what we see here, a very basic version.
So this is Kelley Blue Book, and here it says, Kelley Blue Book, Price Advisor.
So that's what we are going to do to we are going to calculate the price of a used car.
So here we can click on this.
Let's look at what they have.
Now we need to enter some basic information about our car, which we want to sell.
So let's pick this.
2018.
Make Ford the model.
Let's pick this particular car for Ford.
It's a Ford EcoSport.
A very nice car.
Let's say we have driven 15,000 miles in the one year.
We have driven 15,000 miles.
In another country we would be using we would probably use a metric like kilometers, but this is miles
and this is the location where we are staying.
So this is essentially zip code in United States.
They call it a zip code and another country in some other countries they call it US Postal code.
So this is where we live.
So let's go ahead and hit next.
So which style is your car?
So there are four options.
Let's select this one and hit next.
So it is once again asking for a few more options.
It says Price with standard equipment.
Select your options.
So what?
Which options are on your vehicle?
So something like security features and convenience features.
So those may be some features in the car.
Select the colour, let's say red.
And what is your vehicle's condition?
Is it very good?
Excellent or good, let's say?
Very good.
So the car is in a very good condition.
So now it is calculating and this is the logic that you're going to write whatever is happening here.
Here it is.
And it says the car can be sold at this price at $17,036.
So let's go ahead and look at the code.
I have some template code for you to sell.
So let's go ahead and look at that.
This is a class that will be given to you in the next lecture, and it is appropriately named as car
price estimator as we want to estimate the price of the car.
And this class has two methods.
The first method here is called us get sale price.
And this is the main method that you need to implement.
It has some template code and you would implement it.
And the second method will be used from this method and it is already implemented.
It's called a get price.
So you wouldn't do anything with this method.
But we will also discuss this particular method.
So this class will be given to you in the next lecture, which is a coding exercise, and you would
go ahead and implement this method and submit your solution.
So the first method is get sale price, as the name indicates.
It would return the price of the car given the values related to the car.
So we have certain attributes of the car.
And based on those attributes it would estimate the price and it would return that.
And the return price is a double value.
So we have the return type as double.
Now here also we have the main method and we know that the main method is just used for testing purpose.
So that's what we are going to do here.
We are creating an instance of car price estimator here and we are invoking the get sale price method
with some sample data.
So we know that main method is used only for testing purposes.
But when you submit your solution, your solution would be automatically evaluated for correctness and
it would test it with different kinds of data.
And it will say whether the method passes the whether your solution passes the test or not.
So here we have some sample data and this is my Eclipse editor.
And if I hover over this particular method, gets a sale price, it shows the method signature and let's
look at the parameters of the method.
So the first one is make and model.
Now, if you recall from the website earlier, the both make and model were two different parameters.
Make was Ford and model was EcoSport.
And those are two different values, which we were which we were submitting from the dropdown menu.
But in this particular case, we have them represented using a single field and the next one is E are
manufactured.
And this is the year in which your car has been manufactured and we are passing a sample value 2018
third one is miles driven.
So the distance that has been traveled since the car was bought.
So these are the miles driven in this case we are using miles.
Now for the rest of the field.
Let's just go to the method here and look at the rest of the fields.
So we just discussed the first three parameters.
The next three are related to security.
So the first one among the security features that the car has can have as a background and it is end.
Second is ABS.
And third is EBD.
So a B as here, both of these are boolean fields.
They have the Boolean data type.
Now, airbags, you may know about airbags.
Some of the cars come with airbags.
They may have either two or six airbags.
And an airbag is simply installed in the dashboard.
And in the event of an accident, a serious accident, a collision, the airbags would be blasted out
from the dashboard and they would protect you from any injury.
So that's the airbags and it is an infield.
And ABS stands for anti-lock braking system and EBD stands for electronic brakeforce distribution.
And both of them are security features related to brakes, applying brakes.
And just don't worry if you're not familiar with these with these words, with these terms, and because
they are not relevant here, it is sufficient if we know that these are related to security features.
And if the car does not have these features, then we reduce the price of the car.
Now the next three features here are related to comfort, comfort features and we will look at them
later.
And all of these are Boolean fields and the final one is has accident history, which is also a Boolean
field Boolean parameter.
So if a true is passed, it would mean that the car was involved in an accident.
And based on that, we further adjust the sale price.
So this is the method that you need to implement.
So as I said earlier, this method returns the price of the car and that is represented using this variable
called sale price and it is of type double because we need to return a double and that's what we are
returning.
At the very end of the method we are saying return sale price.
Now it is initialized with some value and once it is initialized, we have all of these different conditions.
The logic here, different factors.
And those factors use these different parameters.
And based on that, the price would be adjusted.
It keeps adjusting with each of the factor.
So we have five factors here and we will look at all of them.
But let's look at the initialization.
Initial initially it would be initialized with the price of that car.
Based on the air manufactured.
So we are just invoking the second method called get price, which is already implemented and we are
passing the make and model and we are also passing the EER manufactured.
Now in the main method we passed Ford, EcoSport and we passed here manufactured as 2018.
So this method will return the price of this particular car, that car, Ford, EcoSport.
So that's there is certain price for that and that is the price that would be assigned to this method
sale price.
So let's look at this get price method.
So here it is.
So it is taking the two parameters and there is some logic here, just don't even worry about this.
So all it is doing is if Ford, EcoSport is passed, it is passing, it is returning 20,000.
But if the car make and model is Honda City here, then it returns 25,000.
And if this of the car is Toyota, then it returns 30,000.
If the car does not match any of these values here, then it would return 20,000.
So this is an if statement.
Just don't worry about it and your manufactured is not even used.
So this is just to kind of make it like a real world case.
But we are not going to use the air manufactured at all and that is perfectly fine since this is just
an exercise.
But we just wanted to mimic the way it is done in the real world.
So get price would be the price of the car.
In the year that it was manufactured.
So that's what we have.
And this will be further adjusted in the method based on the logic that we are going to right now.
Next is current year.
So the current year is calculated in this way and you can simply ignore this.
So this would return the current year when the program is being executed.
So local date is a class that is in the Java library and it is from the date and time library within
the Java library.
And later in the course we will look at date and time API.
It would be much later and at that time you would understand the statement so you can just ignore it.
But currently the year is 2019, so this would get assigned to 2019.
And in the next statement we are calculating the age of the car, which is the current year minus year
manufactured, which is passed to the method and we are adding a plus one.
So if the current year is 2000, 19 and a year manufactured, is passed is 2018, then it would be one
here, 2019 -2018 and plus one.
So that would make it to age of the car would be two now if manufactured is 2019 so it is manufactured
in the same year as the current year.
Then this would be zero and only a one would be assigned to age of the car.
So the car is manufactured within the current year.
Then age of the car would be one.
Then we are printing this value.
Then we have the different factors.
So the first factor that will reduce the price of the car is based on the early depreciation value.
Now, with each passing year, the car price would reduce.
By default, it would reduce.
And the condition here is if the age of the car is less than or equal to ten, if it was manufactured
within the last ten years, then the price would depreciate by 5% off the original sale price, which
is this price every year.
So for each year we would reduce it by 5% off the sale price.
So we have a simple example here.
If the price is 10,000, so let's say if the sale price is 10,000 and if it is three years old, then
the price depreciated would be 1500 because if it is 10,000 for a given year, since we are saying 5%
of the original sale price, if we multiply this 10,000 with 5%, it would be 500.
And since we are saying three years, it would be 1500.
So the total price depreciated is 15,000, 1500.
And subtracting that from 10,000, we get 8500.
So once this logic is executed, sale prices 8500, and then next we have other factors which can further
adjust the price.
Now, there is also an LZ block here.
So if the car is age of the car is greater than ten, then we simply return this value.
So this is 10% of the current sale price.
So if the current sale price is 10,000, then we simply multiply it with 10% here, 0.1 and we just
directly return that value.
We don't have to.
The method does not execute anymore.
So you can just copy this particular statement into the block.
But if it goes into this block, then we would continue adjusting the value.
So the next one is based on security feature and it says that the car, if the car does not have at
least two airbags and ABS and EBD, so it says that it needs to have at least two airbags.
So if you see here it is an airbag count is an eight.
So we can pass an int value like one, two or so on.
So if if it is less than two, then it means that it does not have the security feature and we have
to reduce the price by 1000.
We would reduce the sale price by the same sale price that we had here after this, after executing
the first factor.
So that's sale price would be further reduced by 1000 thousand.
So that's just one condition.
But we also need these two conditions, ABS and EBD, EBD, to also be true.
If all of these conditions are true, then we then we just then the condition would fail and we will
not execute the if if block will not be executed.
But if any of these you can see that we have and here.
So if any of these conditions fail, then only we reduce the price.
But if the car has two airbags and if it also has abs and if it also has EBD, which means has EBD is
true, then we never reduce the price and the price would remain as is.
That is a whatever price we had here that the same price would be would be there and we would further
process it here in the next factor.
So the next factor is comfort features.
Now here we are simply printing the sale price after checking for the security features and we are also
doing that here after checking for the year, after applying the early depreciation logic.
And here we have the comfort features.
Here we are saying is the car has a rearview camera and one of these to sunroof or auto AC.
So rearview camera is whether the car has it or not is represented by this parameter here.
So rear view camera is the camera that could have been installed in the car.
And when we reverse the car, there would be a we would have a screen which would which would show the
the rear view of the car, whatever is behind the car, we can see it the in the screen.
So if a true is passed, it means that rear view camera is there in the car.
Similarly, sunroof.
Sunroof is the window that we have on the roof of the car, which is also electronically controlled.
So if you click a button, the sunroof would open and close and auto AC is used to set the temperature
in the car at a certain value.
If it is set at 22 degrees Celsius, then the feature would ensure that the car will always have that
the temperature.
So both of these are boolean.
So if a false is passed four has auto ac, then it means that the car does not have that that particular
auto AC feature.
So here we are saying if the car has rear view camera and either sunroof or auto AC.
So one of these then in that case increment the price by $500.
So you would increment you would increase the sale price that we had.
After executing the security features related logic, we would increase the price by $500.
Now next is price past accidents for the accident we had this final field call has accident history.
Now if a true is passed for that then we are.
Then it means that the car was involved in an accident and we have to reduce the sale price by another
$500.
Simple.
And once again, we are printing the value here.
And the final one is based on additional miles driven.
So here we know that the age of the car is there.
And typically in a given year, a car would be driven 10,000 miles.
But if you drive more than that, then it means that you have overdriven the cars.
And because of that, we can reduce the price of the car.
So here the expected miles driven is nothing but age of the car, times 10,000.
So if the if the age of the car is three years, then 30,000 miles would be a reasonable distance travel.
But if you if you have traveled 40,000 miles, then it means that you have overdriven the car and that's
what is computed here.
So additional miles is miles driven.
So if you have.
40,000 miles and expected miles driven was 30,000.
Then additional miles would be 10,000.
And based on that, we are going to penalize here.
So we are going to reduce the price.
And here are the conditions.
It says we have three conditions here, three statements.
It says F number of miles over driven is greater than 1000 and less than or equal to 10,000, then reduce
the sale price by 500.
Similarly, we have two more conditions.
If miles driven over driven is greater than 10,000 and less than or equal to 30,000, then reduce by
this amount.
And if the additional miles driven is greater than 30,000, then you would reduce by 1500.
And finally, we are preventing that and we are retaining the value here.
So that's about it.
That's the exercise.
And in the next exercise we will actually you can actually find this template code and you can implement
and submit it.
That said, thank you and happy coding.