Hi there.
This is De La Rue and welcome back.
Earlier we implemented the Books Aloha Project and as part of the project we implemented this servlet
called My Books.
And we said one of the limitations of the servlet is that we have the HTML content embedded within the
servlet, which is a Java file.
And we said this is a problem because frontend developers have to work with this Java file in order
to create this HTML content.
Moreover, in future they have to once again work on this file in order to make any changes in the HTML
content.
And now frontend developers are typically not programmers, so they are frontend developers who know
how to create beautiful HTML pages.
So it's not right to expect them to work with a Java file and work with all of these Java code and this
concatenation symbols.
So it's very cumbersome for them in order to work with this file.
So we said that was a problem and we can fix it using the MVC design pattern where we have a separate
view technology, for instance, JSP can act as a view.
So what we would do is we would take all of this HTML content and we would push it into a JSP file.
So we know that an MVC M stands for Model V for Vue and C for controller and controller would be the
servlet itself and Vue would be the JSP file, or it can be other Vue technologies to like faceplates
and model would be the actual business logic like the manager classes, the classes and the database
itself.
So together that would act as the model.
So that's the business logic.
And the main advantage of MVC is to separate out the presentation from the business logic.
The presentation would be part of the JSP file.
So in this demo, that's what we are going to do.
We are going to improve this particular design and we will make it an MVC design pattern.
We will change it into an MVC design pattern.
And in the process we will also look at the JSP.
So JSP has tags, JSP tags, and we are going to get a high level overview of JSP and that should be
really good.
And once you are done with the course, you can further explore about JSP or other more recent technologies,
and you can learn them.
But this should give you a good, nice foundation about MVC using JSP as the Vue technology.
Now we already know that model would be manager classes and also classes and some entities and also
the database.
But for this extension, we are not going to use any any database, but our application has two books.
So what we need to do is we need to create two book instances.
So there will be an entity called Book Ock and we would create two instances of that entity and we will
instantiate them with some state.
The state is nothing but the data that we have seen in the application and we will have a manager class
in order to create those instances.
So I have already created the model, the manager class as well as the entity.
So we are just going to look at that in the interest of time because I want to focus more on JSP.
And so that should be really, really helpful.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So here I have created two new packages called com Semantic Square Books, Aloha entities, and another
one is books aloha managers.
And we already had the controllers package which had this servlet.
So let's look at entities here and we have this class called as Java and all it has is these three fields
image URL, author and rating.
So if you recall in the application, we were displaying two book instances and each of them had an
image which is represented by an image URL.
And we also had the details about the author as well as the rating of the book.
So we just have that information here that is represented using these private fields and we have the
corresponding getters and setters for these fields.
So that's the entity and you can look at it in the resources section.
The next is the books manager class.
And Books Manager class is also implemented as a singleton.
Now, if you recall from our project, all our managers were singletons.
And the way we have done it is we have this object reference.
This is the book Bookman Books Manager instance, and it is a static field.
And here we are instantiating it.
And the constructor is a private constructor and we get this instance via the Get Instance method,
which is a static public method.
That is how we would get hold of this books manager instance, which is a single instance.
And the only other method that we have is this method called us, get my books.
So that's the business logic.
So you can think that there is some database from which the manager would retrieve those two instances
of the books and would return those instances.
So since we do not have the database.
So we are creating that to book instances.
We are quoting the data here.
So this is the first book and we are setting the image URL, the author and the rating for this book.
And then we have the second book here and both the books are added into an ArrayList, which is defined
at the top.
It's called As My Books, and this is the reference type and it is an ArrayList and it is and we are
returning this order list.
But in this method, that's all it is.
And let's go ahead and change this code in order to use.
The model and also to forward it to the GSP.
So I have commented that code here and then I have this template code here.
So it's just a do get method once again.
So there are two steps here.
One is we need to get the data from the model and then we need to forward it to view which is nothing
but the JSP.
So in this particular demo we are going to look at create the JSP file to, but the JSP tags that we
are going to use are some legacy tags.
So it is recommended not to use those tags.
But still I want to show those tags because you may run into some legacy code which uses those tags
and in that case it would be very helpful.
But in the next lecture we will change that.
We will use something called a GST tags, which is an extension of the JSP specification.
And there we will replace the legacy tags with better GSP tags and those tax would lead to more cleaner
code.
So that is in the next lecture.
Let's not worry about it.
Now, the goal here is to fetch the data from the model.
So for that, let's first.
Say books.
Okay.
So let's get the data and it returns.
We need to import them.
Control shift.
Oh.
Said.
So the next thing is this data has to be passed to The View.
And the thing that we do here is we use this request object.
And it has a method called set attribute.
It takes a name and a value.
Name would be a string here.
So let's call it as my books and.
The value would be this object reference, which is an array list of the two books and here books.
Java also has this two string method here.
I have created this two string method because I just want to have a print statement here.
So that we can look at the output in the console, also the Web servers console.
So let me just say my books.
So this is the request object.
And within the request object, we are storing this data that we are getting from the from the model.
So the next step is to forwarded to the JSP.
And for that we use something called as request dispatcher.
Let me just write the code fast.
So once again, we use the request object.
And there is a method called get request.
DISPATCHER Here it is.
And it accepts a string.
And we will name our JSP as my bookstore.
JSP.
So the servlet is also my box and this JSP is also my bookstore.
JSP And it returns something called request.
DISPATCHER Like you expect.
And let's call it as dispatcher.
We need to import that.
Now, the next thing is we should we would say.
DISPATCHER Dot forward.
And we would pass the request itself and the response.
So request and response are the method parameters and we are simply forwarding it here.
So request dispatcher is it's just a mechanism for forwarding control from one component to another.
And one of the components is the servlet and the destination component is the JSP.
So we are forwarding the control from the servlet to the JSP.
So here we are invoking the get request dispatcher and this is how it is done.
It has to be invoked on the request object.
So just keep that in mind.
And we are further invoking the forward method here on the returned dispatcher and we are passing the
same request on response to it so that the JSP can make use of it.
The next goal is to create the GSP file and move everything that we see here into the GSP file.
So we are done with this.
That's here.
Let me put this.
Let me call it.
With the sublet part.
So in order to create the JSP, let's go here.
Books right click say new.
Here you can select the JSP file.
My books.
It's called my books.
And it also creates some template code.
Here it is.
Now, here, right at the beginning, we have this thing called a page directive, which is a JSP tag.
So it already has some attributes here.
So one of the things that we need to add here is something called as an input attribute.
So we need that because we are going to use the book instance as well as the ArrayList here.
So let me just put it.
It should be clear pretty soon import.
And let me go back to the servlet and import.
This book because we need to access it here.
So we are importing it and a comma because we also need the collection.
So let me go back.
This one.
Let's take this collection.
That's it.
Now, the next thing I would do is I would go into this, my bookstore, HTML, and we have all of this
content.
So let me just copy all of this.
Go into my bookstore JSP and replace this with this.
Och, that's the thing.
And here we already looked at this file.
So we have within the body.
The body has the main content.
And here, let me call it as books.
Aloha.
And this is the body.
Body actually has the main content and this is the this is the header where we were displaying the the
name of the application.
And here we have to break tags.
Each break tag would insert an empty line.
And then we had this table here, if you recall, right, we had the table and each row was displaying
each of the box.
But here all of this data would come from the would come from the modal which we are forwarding from
the servlet.
Right.
It's getting forwarded here.
So we need to use that data so we cannot we don't need this hard coded data anymore.
So let me go ahead and first remove this second book.
Okay.
We don't need this.
And we need to use a further loop here.
We will use a for loop.
And we are going to create these two roles and we will fill up these details here.
So for this, we use something called a triplet.
Triplet is a GSP GSP tag.
So it starts like this.
So we need that ArrayList, which has the data.
So if you recall it as collection of book.
Once again, let's call it as my books.
And we will set a request.
Dot get.
Attribute.
Here we were setting the attribute here so we would just use the method, get attribute in order to
get the books.
So for this we will just use the string.
So it's like a map.
Think of it as a map, as a hash map, something like that.
And this is a key.
Okay.
That's it.
But get attribute returns an object.
So we need to change it to.
That's it.
Next, we need to use a furlough.
And we need an ending tag here.
So this is a script.
This is called as a script lit.
And within the script lit we can use the regular Java code.
So we have the regular Java code here and it is being used in this script.
So we need a script here so that we can get the, the list and we have the we can we have the first
statement.
But to end the first statement, we need another script here.
Now for this.
Here is the list.
And here we will say.
Let's call this a GSP expression tag.
So you will have.
This arrow symbol and the percentage followed by equals two.
So here we the equal two symbol, is not there in a script.
And this is called a GSP expression tag.
And here we will just say book.
Dot get.
Image URL.
So we are accessing the get image URL method and the book class.
So if you see here we had this thing get image URL, it's a getter and we will also use the to other
getters, get author and get rating.
So that's for the image URL and it will copy the so get image URL will return the URL and that URL will
be copied here and there shouldn't be any semicolon here.
So it would be and this is an expression, so it's called a JSP expression.
Now let's take this and let's do the same thing here.
That's it.
And so the loop would iterate twice because we have two books and it would display the values.
So let me go ahead and let me create the VAR file.
So we looked at three tags here.
So one is the page directive here and it helps us to import the book as well as the collection classes.
Collection is an interface and then we use this triplet in order to have this Java code and in order
to print the value, we are using this GSP expression and we are accessing this method here.
And that's it.
And we are doing the same for author as well as the rating.
So those are the three JSP tags and we can also have some comment.
This is how you would put a comment and JSP.
So let's just say displaying.
Books that suggest comment.
And there is one other thing called JSP Declaration, but let's not get into that.
So these are some legacy tags and let's go ahead and export.
Okay.
We are done with that.
So our file.
It's quoted in books.
Aloha.
And here it is.
Books all over that war.
So let me just say I'll see.
And here in my seat, I have TomKat.
Within that, we have Web apps.
So within the Web apps folder and just copying it.
And let me go back to my bin.
Let me start the Tomcat.
Let's go back to Web apps.
So bookseller has is unpacked now.
So here, let's say.
Local host and books.
Aloha slash my books.
There you go.
So we have the content which is being fetched from the JSP file.
So that's about it.
And as of today, as of today, the latest version of JSP is JSP 2.3.
Now, I want to give some background also on JSP.
So JSP is we have seen the JSP, but it actually converts into a servlet.
So what happens is so we had this request, we made this request to the controller and the controller
has fetched the data from the model and it has given the data, it has forwarded the data to the JSP.
So on the very first axis, what the container does, this container takes the JSP file and it converts
it into a servlet and then it compiles that servlet.
So when it converts, when it translates into servlet, so it would be a Java file.
So that's the first step.
And after doing that, it compiles that Java file, that servlet, and that's it, and thereafter it
uses that.
So it may happen either during the first access or some of the vendors like Tomcat do also provide an
option to pre compile the JSP files, that is, to convert them into servlet and also to compile them.
So essentially a JSP file is a servlet and if you're interested, you can also look at that file here.
So if you go into the root directory of Tomcat, so we have this folder called Work.
So we have web apps, bin and all other folders.
So there is this work, double click that Catalina local host and books aloha is our project or G Apache
JSP and this is the file.
So this is our servlet.
It has this thing called my books.
My books was the name of the JSP file and then it appended this underscore and JSP to create the servlet.
So this is a Java file and then that's servlet has been compiled.
So the container, it's the cool thing here is the container is doing all of that, all of this, it
is translating into the servlet and then further it is compiling it also.
So let me just open this.
This is how it looks.
Okay.
I'm not going to get into the details of this so you can learn about it later.
So one of the problems here as in this JSP, as I said, that these are legacy code and you are not
recommended to use them anymore.
And the reason for that is so we have already enhanced the design.
We have this MVC design pattern.
But as you can see, we have we still have some Java code here.
So a frontend developer who is not a Java programmer still has to deal with some Java code and that
is not good.
So we want to avoid that.
And you can also see all of these triplet tags and then we have a couple more here.
So that is not good.
So the frontend developers should not be dealing with that.
And that's where GSD comes into play and that's the subject of the next lecture.
And we will just take a very quick look at JSTOR.
So that's about it for now and thank you and happy coding.