OK.
Finally let's get back to our project and let's make some extensions.
I think it's been a while.
So it's time for us to extend our project.
So we're going to get to some of the stuff we have learned in the previous lesson.
And the main thing that we are going to test is how to read data from that text in an efficient way
.
So that's what we learned in the previous lesson.
Now we are going to test that.
Now if you recall we had this class data stores which was acting as a database and all the data was
hardcoded here in this class.
Ok here you are.
Here we are.
For example here we have the user data and we hardcoded it.
And similarly if you go down we had babblings.
And further down we had movies and books.
So all of that it was hardcoded.
So we were not using a database.
So we had to rely on this class to provide that data.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to move all of this data into files okaying or text files
and we are going to read from that.
So that's going to be a nice extension.
So you're going to do that.
And if you'll recall when we created this class we also created these four classes that text files that
you'll see here book more we use it on babbling.
They actually had that data with them.
Of course we did not use any of those files but we just use the data from that.
So but now we're going to use the files.
OK.
And the data that you'll see here is the data that we have here we simply copied the data and do these
files and we just hardcoded them.
So now we are going to remove all of this we are going to delete all of this and we are going to simply
read from the file.
So I wanted to read in the code.
So you're not going to write any new code here.
And in fact we have already seen the code and then the last lesson.
So we are just going to review the code that has already been written.
So it's it's the exact same code.
So we don't have to write it again.
So let's just go ahead and let's just look at the code.
So if you recall this is the project really all I want is another project which is for our demo classes
the classes that we use for demoing our concepts.
So it really is a project that we created.
And we had all these packages here and I have created a new package called as you can see this com semantic
script through Leo and UKL and biton the utile class.
I created this class called Sauti within the package I created this class called.
I will you can.
So you would how all utility classes.
OK.
Any utility classes that we are going to create will go into this package.
So the first one that we have created is all your data.
Ok I can hear how to read motard so that we can read data from these files undertreatment there has
two parameters.
One is data string array.
Another is filename.
OK so in a given invocation we would pass the final one off the filenames and we will read the data
into this string at it.
So it's kind of similar to the read method that we have seen in the reader class where we were passing
a character characters.
OK.
So it's exactly identical to that.
So in this case we would read for example for instance if we passed the user filename then we would
use this data on each element in the idea would be filled up.
One of the lines on these lines here that it is operated by DAPs.
So in this case the array size would be fine by the time we read all of this the size of the string
array would be fine.
So each element in that it would store a single line.
So here.
So as we have as you can see here is a file name we are creating a file input stream object and we are
chaining it to input stream reader or an input stream reader also has another parameter which is a character
sort of it's just the encoding scheme and it is of 8 here and it is in Don't chained to a buffer treater
for performance.
OK.
And this is the third try with the resources Sendak's that we are using here and here is a line and
here we are reading invoking the read line method.
We order did ask it and we are invoking it on the radar object on that line and we are storing that
line in this Are called data and we are incrementing on the index variable as being incremented here
.
So it's initialized to zero and after adding in line it's once again being incremented on whenever we
reach whenever read Landru dense and then we terminate dunno.
It means that we have read everything that we need.
Now here I just have to try I need to add some catch blocks here.
So here is the first one.
It says I need to add some exceptions here.
The catch blocks here.
So let's just go ahead and say I'd catch Glaus to try.
So it's going to add to the cache but also on his unsupported and coding exception the other one is
file not found exception.
Another one is the last one is Iowa exception.
Now we don't have those errors anymore here.
But first let me run this existing file.
So that's the old version.
So far everything is running fine.
So now it's time to commandeers out
and here it is.
So this is a new chord.
So this is a little user's method and that they just are class so it's going to load user data.
So here we are creating a string instance and we have a total of five users.
So the size of the string arrays 5 and we are invoking the I will you tell Metford the read method and
we are passing this data the string array and we are passing the name of the file which is user.
OK so user has all of this data here.
So this is the ID field.
This is the.
And third one I need to see what that is but this is the first name last name.
This is the gender under the user type I guess.
Yeah.
And this is the password.
So that's the thing.
And here we are reading the reader once the data is read.
We are the next step is to just do whatever we are doing here which is to create user instances and
store them.
And this they called us users.
OK.
So that's what we are doing here.
In each iteration we are creating a single user instance on storing it in the users.
Ari.
OK.
So here we are iterating the string array.
And in each iteration we are going to read a single line that has been read and since it is tabular
McGirt we are splitting that line.
We are we are calling it as a roll.
Each line this is being called as a row and we are splitting it by TAB delimiter but tab delimiter because
the data is delimited by tabs and so the values get stored here.
And then the sixth element is actually the gender.
So we are getting that gender information here.
So by default we are saying it is male but then if it happens to be F in which case we are reassigning
it to wit and gendered or female.
Otherwise we are re-assigning a good transgender and everything is fine here.
It's a long way.
The first one the idea is long.
So we are doing a long Darbar so long to get along well you and everything else is fine.
So let's just go ahead and run with this first change and everything is fine.
So let's go ahead and make the second change also.
And this is for ramblings.
So here is the blank file.
And you have this information here and you can ignore the last fill here for all of the bookmarks wabbling
movie and book.
There is this thing called the unknown which is which indicates the kid friendly starters but you don't
have to worry about it for now.
So
OK so similarly we are declaring the string here creating the string array and this value is five count
per type.
So we are going to have five bookmarks for each type.
So let's start variable and we are passing this name weblink.
And the same thing.
We are simply spreading the values and we are invoking it here.
Our only thing is the unknown value which you read which I said that we can ignore as being ignored
here.
And the same bet movies do.
So let me comment this out.
OK.
So we are passing the movie as a filename here and we are spreading the values.
Only thing is cast here and diverters.
So if you go here cast and directors can have multiple values which are supported by commas.
So this piece of code is taking care of that.
So we are splitting that into String Array here.
And we are simply passing those values here.
Gaston directors are being passed us a string Arrius.
So that's what movies and the final bonus books.
So I'm going to upload these three methods three or four methods into a file so you can look at data
in the resources section.
So here you are passing book and bookmark count.
Once again file eins here only the authors can have multiple values.
So because a book can be written by multiple authors.
So that's why we are using another split on the fifth the value that is supposed to represent the authors
.
So that's about it.
So we have all of this sort of mirrored around it one more time and everything is running fine.
It's well-tested so it's running fine.
So I'm going to just upload those methods.
This matter I don't have to upload I think you can write it yourself but I might also upload this.
So that's about it that's how we are going to read data here by chaining multiple training so that's
the recreative Madden Huynh buffer reader helps in reading it in a very efficient way.
And we are using UTF 8 here.
That's about it.
And thank you