Hi there.
This is Uluru and welcome back.
There is this pretty popular code which says Write your code as of the next guy to maintain is a homicidal
maniac who knows where you live.
So this code suggests that we need to use proper coding conventions so that the next person to maintain
it has a pleasant experience and would be happy to maintain your code.
But if you do not write your code using proper coding conventions, then the person who is going to
maintain your code might not have a pleasant experience and he might be unhappy.
And if it turns out to be a homicidal maniac, then he may find you and might cause trouble to you.
So in the last lecture we looked at the JSP file and we used some legacy tax, which we were not supposed
to use.
So the legacy tax made us use some Java code within the GSP file.
So we made one enhancement in the last lecture where we removed the Java code and the servlet and we
made it better.
But we still can improve it further because we have some Java code within the JSP page itself and that's
where we are going to use a GST.
Now GST stands for JSP Standard Tag Library.
So it's a library of GSP tax too, and we need to use those tags and it extends the JSP specification.
And as of today, the latest version is GST L 1.2, and it essentially helps replace embedded Java code
with some other GSP tags and we will see how that can be done.
So we are going to modify the GSP file, which we have written in the last lecture.
Here is the My Bookstore JSP file, which we have written in the last lecture.
So now we are going to use some GST tags.
So they are also JSP tags, but come with the GST library and we will use them to replace the the legacy
tags that we see here so that they look very similar to HTML tags.
So that would be much more convenient for frontend developers, it would be much more easier to read.
So we are going to do that.
So we are going to replace these triplets that we see here, this and this.
We are going to use some tags which would do the same thing, which will have this, which will have
the same logic of iterating through the books.
So we are going to use some tags for that, a tag for that, and we are just going to look at one or
two tags.
And for the rest of them you can take a look at the GST.
So you can look at some tutorials for GST and you can learn more about them.
Okay, so but to use those tags, we need to import a jar file.
So let's go into the box project here.
Right click going to properties.
Okay.
Let's click on Java Build Path so that we can add the jar.
So let's say add external jars.
So here I have this jar.
It's called steal hyphen 1.2.
1.2 is the latest version in the resources section.
I will provide you a link to this jar file or I might provide this jar file itself.
So do look out in the resources section.
To say open and apply.
So it is added.
Now that jar file is good for this eclipse, but it also has to go into our var file, the var file
that we are going to create so that the web application can also use it.
So let's go ahead and click on this thing called deployment assembly and then click on ADD.
Click on Java Build Path entries.
Click that and click next.
So it shows this ticket and let's say finish.
So it added that and I have already added servlet api jar two.
So we are good with that.
I have added it offline.
So a servlet API is already there and tomcat also.
And it was there inside the lib folder.
But I have added it just for this specific web application to the books.
Aloha.
So that it will be within the lib folder that is also present within the books aloha web project.
I'll show it to you.
So let me head.
Okay, so we are done with that now.
JSP Deal is essentially a JSP tag library, so it's a bunch of tag libraries and we are going to use
one of the library called Core.
It's just like using the Java library.
In order to use that, we need to use we need to say we need to tell that we want to use that particular
tag library.
So I'm going to replace this.
We don't need this anymore with this particular tag.
It's called as a tag lib directive.
It's a JSP tag too.
And here it is.
We are here we are specifying that we want to use the core tag library.
So some of the tags are defined there and we are using this prefix called C and that will be used in
the JSP tag.
So that is that and we need to replace this.
So what I'm going to do is so I'm going to first add that tag, it's called for each.
OC, which is used for iteration.
So this is the ending tag.
Let me take this and replace this here.
Let me put it here and then we can remove it.
So this has a bunch of attributes.
One of them is called Var and let me call it as book.
So for each is just identical to the for each statement in Java.
So here let me call it as book.
And there is another attribute called items.
Okay.
So now we need the array.
So in my bookstore, Java, we are setting this attribute called my books.
So we need this.
We need to iterate through this.
Particular ArrayList, which is what we were doing here.
So we will just say my box.
However, in order to access it, we use something called an expression language.
L Which starts with.
Which stands for expression, language, and this is how you would do it.
So you'd have the dollar symbol and the braces and within the brace, you have my books.
So this way we get access to.
And this particular object reference.
So that's what we are doing here.
And my books that we see here is the is attribute name and that's what we are using here to.
It is not my box, it's not the variable name itself, but it is the attribute name.
This is the attribute name.
And that's it.
That's the thing.
And we don't need this anymore.
But before that, let me replace this also.
So here we have the book variable.
So what we will do, as that said dollar, we use the expression language once again.
So once you are done with this course, do read on the GSP tags as well as the GST tags as well as the
expression language.
So let me put here use but here to use it.
We don't need this.
We just need the filename rather than the method name.
So that is what we need.
And let me copy this for otter to so it's Facebook don't get author.
We just need to say book author.
So let me copy and replace that with this.
Okay.
Remember that the field names were image URL, author and rating.
And let's do the same for the last one.
And this would be rating.
That's all there is.
So we can remove all of this.
We don't need this.
And let's also remove we don't need this comment to this was just for demonstration.
So we have the footage here and this footage is creating two new records.
So we need to remove this triplet to.
Okay.
So this is all we have.
So as you can see, it is much more cleaner.
The entire script has been replaced with this tag.
And that's the beauty of G Steel.
So now it is much more convenient for a frontend developer to use this.
So let's go ahead and export.
The file.
Keep my books on it would be books.
Aloha.
And it's going to override the old one.
Finish.
Here it is.
And let me go into the Web Apps Directory.
I'm inside Tomcat Web apps.
So let me copy it.
My Tomcat is on, so it's going to automatically unpack this.
Okay.
There you go.
Now let me go here and hit the control f five.
So that's it.
So we have used this.
And let me also show one more tag.
We can also add the tag.
Either we can make the change here or we can also change directly.
Over here also if we want to.
Normally you wouldn't do that, but if you want to, you can also change here and in web apps, books.
Aloha.
We have this file.
So let me just change.
Add a new tag.
Okay.
So here we have let's say we want to display only the book, which has a rating of at least five four.
So we can say there is a new tag called C.
Remember that the C here is the prefix.
We are defining the prefix here.
Yes.
And the library we are using is called a score.
So that's why we are we are using this specific library, JSP library.
There are also a few other JSP library libraries, but this is the most common one that we use.
It has all these tags representing such if if statements are or iteration.
So it's called F.
Best.
So we want.
To create a euro only if the rating is greater than four.
So we can use this greater than symbol and let's say for.
And this has to come right before the for the ending statement.
That's it.
Let me go back here and refresh and see if it's going to work.
Something is wrong here.
Well, this has to be here.
Not here, but it should be here.
So instead of just having it like this, we have this whole thing.
So greater than 4.0 has to be here.
That's it.
So the other book had a rating less than four.
So this one had five.
So that's the thing.
So we looked at JSTOR and you can see that it's much more cleaner code.
But I also have to say that even GSP is kind of considered as an obsolete technology.
And these days face less is used.
Face less is another view.
Technology, just like GSP and Facelifts, is used in conjunction with something called JSF Java Server
faces, and it's a framework that also offers.
This is a framework and within that you can use face.
So that's a newer technology which you can explore later.
But at least I just wanted to specify that.
So you don't see many projects using JSP anymore, but at least this gives you a good foundation about
MVC and how JSP can be used.
And we are also we have also seen how not to use legacy code, legacy JSP tags and instead use expression
language as well as gesture tags so that it is much more convenient for frontend developers to work
on the front end code.
Before signing off.
Let me also just show you.
The lit folder, which I was talking about.
So we are inside web apps, books, aloha, web inf.
So within web enough we have the lip and here is where we have the GST l 1.2 and the servlet API two.
And this is what I was demonstrating earlier.
In the eclipse in order to have this still within the VAR file.
Now, within web apps in Tomcat, also there is the lib folder which has some some jar files and servlet
API is also here.
So that would be applicable for the entire Tomcat itself.
But it is it has also been added into the Web Apps Directory and I have done that offline.
So just wanted to show you the lib folder too.
So that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.