Hello there.
This is the LA Uluru.
And welcome back.
So let's go ahead and continue our demo.
So in the last lecture, we have seen how we can create box perimeters and we have also seen how they
can be unwrapped.
Now let's go ahead and see how box primitives can be really used.
So we will look at some typical use cases, very interesting use cases.
And in the process we will also learn about some important methods that box primitives have.
So the first thing that we are going to look at is how we can parse strings.
Okay, so there are certain methods that we can use in order to parse strings and extract some data
and store it and primitives.
So these methods will help us convert a string into primitive values.
Now, this is very useful when we are reading some data from the files or we are processing some data
that we get from some remote server, like a web service.
So let's just consider that we are we are working on some book related website and it has this file
and we need to read this data.
So each row here corresponds to some book.
So we need to read this data and extract the individual items.
For instance, this is the ID, this is the title of the book.
This is a publication here and here we have the rating.
So we need to extract all of this data.
So when we extract it, there would be in the form of strings and we need to convert them into each
of these items into the corresponding primitive values.
For instance, this needs to be converted into a double value.
So let's just take this last row here and let's assume that we have already read this into a string.
Let's call it as data.
So this is what we have.
But we don't need all of this.
Now, here, each of these data items are separated by a tab, for instance, here.
So they are tab delimited.
So sometimes we may also have CSV files, data and CSV files or XML files and you need to process them.
So we don't need all of this.
So let me remove some of them.
Let's remove this and.
And here let's just have it as.
So that's the genre and this is the rating.
And we don't need this because it's unknown.
So this is what we have.
So we have five items one, two, three, four and five.
Now let's go ahead and store this and a string area here.
So let's say string array.
So what do we have to do?
So we need to use the split method and we are splitting on what we are splitting on top because they
are tab delimited.
So the items will have five items here.
So the first one is ID.
ID is typically a log if the system is really huge.
So let's say long ID equals to will sell long box, primitive class dot.
There is this method called pass or here pass long.
So just use that method.
And what do we want to pass the first item in the array?
It is items of zero.
So that's how you would pass it.
And other classes also have similar methods.
So next one is the title.
So for title, we don't have to do anything.
So.
So it is the first item.
Next is the publication here.
So that is an end.
So let's call it as pub here.
So this is an eight.
So within the integer class we have a pass method.
So any time when we are dealing with strings and we want to parse, so the methods will be named in
this way.
So now it will be parsed end because we want to extract an end from the string.
So this is items of two.
Next is a car.
But for car we don't have such a pass method.
So what we will do is we will say items of three.
And if you recall, there is a method called car eight and we need to pass the index so it would be
zero.
So this is the method from the string class and these are all pass methods are the static methods.
So next is the rating.
So double.
So here the D stands for technical.
So here once again the double box.
Remember to class dot pass double.
So all of these methods are very similar to each other.
They are saying pass something.
So it's like pass type.
So that's the general syntax that we have.
So let's go ahead and print this out, control space and we'll print the ID here.
Application here.
So that's it.
And let's go ahead and print them here.
We have some print statements.
Let me just comment them out.
So select all of them and say control forward slash and they're all commented out.
So let's go back here and let's just print them here.
I see they are printing the primitive values now.
So that's how you would parse strings and they are very useful methods.
So it's a very important use case here.
So whenever you think of usability of box parameters, you can think of this example.
Now here we are extracting an end here.
Now, if you want to extract if you want to convert the string into, let's say, a boxed parameter,
then can you guess what we have to do?
So for instance, for this publication here, let's say integer boxed pub here, it is not an end.
So can you guess what we need to do for this?
If you recall in the previous lecture we said we can use value of a string, value of is an overloaded
method and it would take a string.
So you would just pass this items off to and you will get an integer instance.
So this is value of, like I said, is a static factory method and it's an overloaded method and it
will help us create objects.
So this is an integer object and this one is an int primitive.
That's why we'll say parse int and it returns an int value of a return an object.
So that's that.
And we already know about this max and min value that we have an integer classes, right.
So we have already used them.
So I'm not going to discuss them.
So we use them in the int class max value.
We would return the max value that an end variable can hold and this is a main value.
So we are not going to discuss that anymore.
Now there are several other utility methods and let's look at few utility methods from the character
class.
So we have character here, right?
We extracted this genre here.
Now, we might want to know whether it is a letter or a digit.
So there are some boolean condition methods which will test whether an input character is a letter or
an easy digit or whether it is an uppercase or lowercase.
So there are certain methods for that and let's just try them out.
So they all start with this ease keyword.
And more on that later in naming conventions.
So we will say, for instance, ease letter.
So this will return a true F.
The input character is a letter.
Similarly.
You can have ease digit.
So the genre is actually P here in our case.
So it will be a false.
So let's use the same one.
There is a method which will say whether it is letter or digit over here and you can see many other
methods here.
Okay.
Now, let's say we want to test whether it is an uppercase or lowercase.
So there is a method for that also.
So, for instance, if you are writing, if you are creating some sort of an editor and after the full
stop, if the user enters a character and you want to auto convert it into an uppercase, then you perhaps
can use some method such as this one.
So it is uppercase and you will just say, John, right here.
So let's go ahead and assign this to a boolean, because a boolean is what they are returning.
So let's just call them as is letter.
So let's go and print them.
Solid control space is.
So let's just execute them.
And it returns true for because it's a letter, then it returns false for each digit because it's not
a digit.
And for each letter or digit it returns a true because it is a letter and for is uppercase it returns
a true because here we have it as uppercase right here.
Right.
So those are some common utility methods.
Now double also has a method called is none which will check if an input number is a non or not a number.
So now we know as not a number.
For instance, we can have 0.0 and this operation.
Right, 0.0.
So this well, this is not a number so it will return a true.
So once again boolean.
There you go.
So it returns a true because it is not an it is not a number.
Now the end integer like there are some interesting methods.
So if at all you're curious to know what the binary representation is of a particular int value.
So let us say eight then you can use this method called to binary string.
So here it will return a string.
So is a string that cinema does binary.
And it will return 1000.
So that's the binary representation of this thing.
So if you're curious and if you want to know the binary format of a particular string, then you can
do that now.
We have seen how we can convert a string into a primitive like the past method parsing method.
Similarly, if you want to convert an primitive into a string so you can use this method called dot
to string, it's a static method.
So this is what you would do.
This will return a string.
So that's it.
Let's say some string or whatever.
Or we had that publication here.
So let's say pub here.
And we can name it as pub here as a string.
Something like this.
So it would convert that into a string, a primitive into a string.
So that's that.
So we looked at some the parse method, the max value.
So for that box parameters are used and there are some utility methods here.
Now, the last thing is we have these data structures like ArrayList.
So if you want to populate those data structures, you should always store an object reference.
You cannot store primitives.
For instance, ArrayList is a data structure and let's say we want to store all our IDs, book IDs in
this.
So you will say array list and you will say ID list, dot add and you can say something like long dot
value of.
ID is one that we extracted.
But you don't have to do this so you can just do this ID.
It works, but it works only from Java five onwards, but before Java five.
So this wouldn't work.
This statement wouldn't work before Java five.
So it works only from Java five onwards, but still underneath it is going to store a long instance,
a box primitive.
So it's going to convert this ID value, which is a primitive into a box primitive and is going to store
that and that is called as auto boxing, which is a subject of next lecture.
So any of these objects will always store only object references.
So this is there, but behind the scenes it is going to store an object reference and that would be
subject of next lecture.
It's called auto boxing.
Finally, one other thing as about it's also useful in generics when creating something called a parameterized
type, but we still did not discuss generic, so you don't have to worry about it.
But I'll just give you a simple example.
Let's say we are creating this.
We want to store all of the ratings and another list and rating we know is double, right?
So we don't want to store anything else other than double.
So that's where the generics comes into play and this is the syntax for that.
So we are saying that create an array list, but you have to store only double values here, but here
it needs to be a box parameter.
Now if you say double, we get a compilation error.
So it requires this to be a box primitive.
So that's what it is.
Now if you add rating list, dot, add some, let's say some int value, then it will give us a compilation
error because we require a double header.
So that's parameter is type.
This is called as a parameter time, but let's not worry about it.
But at least this one here cannot be a primitive, so that's all there is.
So we looked at how we can create box primitives using the value of method, then how we can unwrap
using end to value sort of method here.
Right int value.
Here on rap.
Then we looked at the parsing methods to parse.
So this is very commonly used if you want to convert strings into primitives.
And Maxwell and there are some utility methods here which you can always use.
And finally, if you want to store in data structures, it needs to be in the form of a box primitives.
But the Java compiler will take care of that.
And it's also used here in generics.
Thank you.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about this and I'll see you in the next lecture.