Hi there.
This is day.
Day.
Now, let's take a look at a volatile modifier that can be used with variables.
In the previous lecture, we saw that one of the happens before ordering rules was based on volatile
variables.
Volatile is simply a modifier that is used with variables and it helps ensure memory visibility.
That is, once a particular thread writes a value to a volatile variable, it is guaranteed that that
particular value would be visible to all subsequent rates of that variable from all threats.
This is what was mentioned in the previous lecture.
Any right to a volatile variable establishes a happens before ordering with subsequent reads of the
same variable.
Regardless of the thread that is performing the read.
So the volatile variable value will be propagated to all other threats.
It's an alternative way to achieve memory visibility.
As synchronization would also help in doing that.
Right.
We already saw that.
And if you look at the dictionary, the meaning of volatile is something that changes very rapidly and
unpredictably.
Volatile variable values are always stored in main memory, so they are not cached in registers or in
local cache of processors.
So I believe it simplifies the memory visibility criteria as we are only dealing with main memory.
That is, any processor will always write a volatile variable value to main memory and will also read
from only main memory.
One little key word can be used with shared mutable variables.
Not that volatile keyword cannot be used with local variables as the scope of local variables ends with
the block in which they are defined.
So it just doesn't make sense.
And here is a typical use case of a volatile variable and the code is adapted from item 66 in effective
Java.
Here the goal is to stop a thread.
And in this code there are two threads.
One is the main thread and the other is shown in the grey box where we are using an anonymous class
to implement the task.
You can also notice the invocation of the START method.
This example shows thread coordination from the main thread.
We want to stop the second thread and for this we are using a shared mutable variable called stop and
it is declared as volatile and it has a default value of false.
Now the second thread has a loop.
And within the loop we are printing some text until stop is set to true.
After about a second the main thread set stop to true with this.
Whenever the second thread gets back into running state, the vile condition would fail and the thread
would terminate.
Now, if the stock variable is not declared as volatile, then there is no guarantee that the second
thread will ever get to see the updated value of stop.
And it may infinitely loop.
So volatile keyword is establishing a happens before ordering and is allowing the two threads to coordinate
effectively.
And here is the same example, but using synchronization.
We know that synchronization also establishes happens before ordering.
So here stop is set to true inside the synchronized method called request stop, which is invoked from
the main method.
Similarly, there is also the synchronize method stop, which simply returns the latest value of stop.
And this method is accessed from the second thread.
So once the request OP is invoked by Main, a later stop method is invoked by the second thread.
The second thread while condition will fail and will terminate.
So synchronization also does what volatile does.
However, according to Joshua BLOCK, it seems performance wise volatile version could be better.
And of course it is also much more readable without the two additional methods.
Now, even in our bank account example, we have seen the advantage of memory visibility due to synchronization.
We know that Anita's thread gets to see the latest value of balance.
If her thread accesses, get balanced method after jahns thread updates balance in the make withdrawal
method.
But in addition to memory, visibility, synchronization also ensures mutual exclusion that is at any
given point of time.
Only one thread can access the synchronized methods, get balanced, and make withdrawal.
And the thread would release the lock only upon exiting the methods.
And this is needed as we want.
Make withdrawal method to work atomically.
Right.
And if we do not use synchronize here.
But if we simply make the balance variable volatile, then we do get memory visibility.
But we would still have the race condition when both Anita's and John thread are inside make withdrawal
at the same time.
So we do need locking here.
So basically locking that in synchronization can guarantee both memory, visibility and mutual exclusion,
while volatile variable can only guarantee memory visibility.
If there is a single thread that is writing to a shared variable and other threads, read the value
of that variable.
Then there is no question of race condition and we can use volatile variable in our stop thread example,
we had the main thread setting the shade variables top to true and the second thread was reading that
value.
And so volatile is a perfect candidate for that.
In that particular example, even if there were multiple threads setting the shared variables top to
true, then we can still use volatile as all threats are setting the top variable to the same value.
True.
And so it shouldn't matter.
But if there can be a race condition, then we cannot use volatile and we need to use synchronised our
bank account example with Anita and John has a check then at race condition and we need to use synchronization
there.
Of course, we also get the benefit of memory visibility.
Here is something more on memory semantics.
It says All actions that precede a right to a volatile field or a release of a lock are visible to all
actions that follow a subsequent read of the same volatile variable or acquisition of the same lock.
If it's not clear, then the next illustration should be helpful.
Let's say we have read a.
And within today we have some actions.
And those actions precede a the right to a volatile field or release of a lock.
Now let's say it later.
Timestamp, we have thread B which either reads from the same volatile field or acquires the same lock
that was released earlier.
With that.
All the earlier actions that we saw in the cloud will be visible to threat.
Be also.
Let's take a look at an example now, and we will look at it in the context of a volatile variable.
Let's say we have thread A which is launched that some time instance t one and it sets two variables
X and V to ten and 15 respectively.
Here V is a volatile variable and X is a regular variable.
Next.
At a subsequent time instance PT two thread b is launched.
Next time.
Instance three three.
Thread a re assigns x to 11.
Next time instant three four thread breeds x, but it still sees the value as ten.
So it's not seeing the new value.
A time 85 thread a updates the volatile variable V to 16.
And finally, a time instance de six threat B first reads the volatile variable and it then reads X
with that thread.
B gets to see the most recent values of both V and X.
So as you can see by reading volatile variable thread, B is also able to see the most recent value
of X.
So that's about it.
We now understand what volatile variable is.
It guarantees memory, visibility.
Synchronization, on the other hand, guarantees both memory visibility as well as atomic automaticity.
Now in less than 30 seconds, let's do a quick demo of the stop thread program.
Here is the new class stop thread and it has been added to the concurrency package and we can see the
stop variable here and it is declared as volatile and everything else is the same.
We have two threads, the main thread and the second thread and we have the anonymous class here.
So the main thread after about 1/2 it is setting stop to true.
And then here the second thread.
As soon as it sees stop as true, it is going to terminate.
So let me go ahead and run this.
It's running or now it's done.
So that's about it.
You can go ahead and you can also download this program from resources section and you can remove the
volatile keyword here and you can try playing with the program.
So that's about it.
Thank you and happy coding.