What and let's go ahead and continue extending our project I know we are going to implement something
more fancy and interesting.
We're going to download web pages and write them to the desk.
So in our system we have different kinds of bookmarks.
A bookmark can be a weblink.
It can be a movie or it can be a book.
Now when it comes to babblings when a user bookmarks a web link we were saving the title of the eyeblink
along with your old information.
But now we want to extend the project to also download the corresponding web page content.
Now that would give us a couple of benefits.
One of them is we can maintain a local cache of the web page.
So if tomorrow the post is not available if it is taken on our of the web page is not available then
we still have the local cache of the web page and the user can still browse the [REMOVED].
But the more important benefit is that they can index all those web pages.
Now if we index those web pages it means that the user can actually search this business.
So indexing basically allows us to provide search capability an index is basically a data structure
which allows us to search text in a very efficient way.
And there are third party libraries like so lock on Lucine which can help us in indexing their documents
.
So we're not going to index the web pages but we're going to just download the web page and we're going
to write it to their desk.
OK.
And so there are a couple of pasts involved here.
So when we say we are going to download a web page what we are doing is we are actually doing it normally
read operation.
But in this case the source is in a remote host earlier in the last lesson.
We saw that when we read we actually read from a file.
So do they are the source of just fine.
But now with this extension the source is basically remote host.
So it's the network.
So once we read the document from the remote host then we need to write it with a disk on product we
use the our writer causus.
OK so we are going to do that.
So let's just go ahead and make these extensions.
So I have created this new class called hysterically picnic and it has been added to the Udal package
which was created in the last class on the history class.
Has this method us don't work and all it is going to do as as the name suggests it's going to download
a webpage.
So the input to this method is a you are off of a page.
You are a lawful eyeblink which is a bookmark and it's going to honor the page and written the contents
of the web page as a string.
And here we are using some classes from the Jawa dot net package.
Since we did not discuss it you don't have to worry about it and it's not even production quality code
.
So basically here there is this class called hitcher to be your own connection and it represents a connection
to the remote host.
And then we are invoking this method called Let's get response called on this variable.
Can and when we do that if the response code is in between to those 200 and 300 It means that we are
able to connect with that.
So we're successfully on so we can read the contents of that particular page.
OK.
And that's what we're going to do here.
And so we are in working this matter called Get input stream on the connection object and get input
stream simply returns a regular input stream.
Ok so now we're going to just read from here.
And we know that input stream is the base abstract class for all byte oriented and streams.
So let's go ahead and fill this method and it could be part of the I or you do.
So let's just say create method and let's just go ahead and fill this matter.
So the previous method was reading from a file.
And instead of building a string it was writing it into the string every night.
So that was the last lesson.
So let's just go ahead and copy this because the code is pretty much identical.
So the one difference is let's make this as in to keep it simple and file in good stream object is replaced
with this input stream.
So it's more generic now.
And since we want to accumulate the content of the page we want to build a web page content that uses
string builder.
So we should always use a string builder.
I have seen code where people who are concatenating using the plus operation for such an important operation
and that's very bad.
Now string line is fine let's remove this.
To append
and we're writing a new line that's because real method is strips new lines lets add some catch glossier
to catch clause
.
So we are dimming that string method we are invoking the true string.
It's going to read on the web page content which has been accumulated and this string builder object
.
So that's about it.
And then coding is still UTF 8 and we will be using only you be of 8 in our system because that's like
a universal kind of cursor.
Now let's go back into history to be correct.
And this is fine.
Now let's look at the code which is going to invoke this method.
So if you're going to view our Java.
So we have this browse here and we are
basically for a given user we are going to we are doing the bookmarking here and we are going we are
invoking the same user bookmark.
So that's just going here.
It's into the going into book my controller.
From here we are going to bookmark manager and have already written some code here.
Now we want to download the web page only if the bookmark is an instance of eyeblink.
So here we are passing a bookmark which can be a weblink which can be a book or a movie but we want
to do this only if it is a weblink.
So here we are.
Downcasting it took a blink.
If it an instance off of a blink and we are working to get you out of the matter because wabbling has
a get your delimiter and then we are assigning it to this variable you are in.
So it basically has that you are a lot of eyeblink.
And we want to download only effect for now if it doesn't end with Dot B-B of which means that if it
ends with dockage DML or something like that then we want to download.
So then we are connecting in working this download method here.
OK.
Which is what we haven't seen.
And we are passing the Yoran of the page.
OK so once we get back the response.
So it's assigned to this wearable web page.
And if the web page is not equal to none only then we are going to write it to their desk.
Sometimes it can be not also for instance if the response code is not within this limit then it means
that something is wrong in which case we are going to read on another.
OK so let's go back and let's also for the right matter now.
OK.
So that's also going to get created within the higher your class.
So let's go ahead and the input barometer here is the ID because the when we write to the desk we have
to create a file and the filename will be the name of the idea.
So because the idea is unique to the bookmark we go we can just use that ID.
And we are passing the web page content also because that needs to be written to the file.
So here it is.
So let's just pick this chord here and our are.
Now it's very simple.
Just keep making it right.
So on it as a writer a little bit more explicit.
So it's just the exact opposite stuff
.
OK now let's leave this as UTF 8 and yes we need to give a final name so I'd say Dot hedge DML
and so we are again creating a string here from the ID.
So we are invoking the value of.
And
we need to specify the location.
So here JRD is my workspace eclipse workspace and truly is our project.
And let's create this page a directory called pages and it's right here.
So I have already created this directory called pages.
So you should also create this page just a directory within that trivial project and all the pages that
get downloaded will be read on into that directory.
So that's also put the finals last year.
So that's what we have here.
And we can read more all of this make a writer dark ride and we just
do this
like Eclipse cleared all the exceptions for us exception catch blocks for us and upset.
So
OK that's about it.
So let's just go ahead and run our application now
running something else.
And one other small change I'm mean is that in the weblink there was a different you are here for the
first two eyeblink but that was taking a lot of time to download.
So I just replaced it with something else but later we will change it back but or later when we are
dealing with multithreading we will actually see how we can abandon a request if it is taking too long
.
OK.
So right now it's taking like 10 or 15 seconds you don't know that page.
So if it is it shouldn't be taking so long.
So if something like that happens we should abandon downloading that Biche because that's just not good
to download such kind of Lapidus so that we will see later.
But this start to just let you know.
So I just replace that with this non-IT me quickly launch.
So it is downloading downloading what it is downloading it means it's not loading some link.
It's done.
So let me
refresh this on so there are three pages that God created.
OK.
So you are there are there are three hits the whole pages that go down in order.
So that's it.
So you just go ahead and I'm going to upload some code into the resources section.
So what we have done is I think it's more interesting that we have actually downloaded web pages and
we have written them to their desk.
So we also know how to write data out to their desk and how to read for them from a network.
And that's about it.
Thank you.
I'm happy coding.
And here it is.
Here we are saying that we are downloading some songs so that's the next year.