Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
As I mentioned at the beginning of the chapter, we can create Java applications for different devices
like desktops, Web servers, mobile devices and so on.
And there are separate platforms dedicated for developing these different types of applications.
And this course is about one such platform called Java SC, which stands for Java Standard Edition.
And in this lecture, let's get a good high level understanding of what Java as a platform is.
The Java software family includes multiple platforms targeting different types of devices, and there
are three main platforms that are most commonly used.
And the first one is the Java Standard Edition or Java SE, in short, which is the subject of this
lecture as well as the course, and previously it was called as J to SC.
And it is used to double up standalone applications that typically run on desktops but may also run
on servers.
An example can be a hospital management system used within a hospital.
Such a system is a standalone system that is, it would be installed on different desktops within the
hospital and the hospital administration staff would use it to enter information like patient details
and which doctor will be treating the patient and so on and so forth.
We do see that when we visit hospitals.
Next is Java Enterprise Edition or Java E in short, and this was previously called as J to E and it
is used to develop large scale applications that run on web servers.
Now, when we say large scale, it implies large number of users will be using the application at any
given instance of time.
An example would be an e-commerce website like Amazon, and you might have heard of technologies like
Serverless and JSP, and they fall under Java E platform.
Angela is built on top of Java Se e platform.
So Java as e technology serves as the foundation for Java E, so Java C is not constrained to just building
standalone applications, but it is needed for building large scale web applications to.
It is just that we need more than what Java C offers and that's where some of the other technologies
within Java come into play.
Now note that in 2017, Java E has been rebranded as Jakarta E as Java E is, development has been shifted
from Oracle to Eclipse Foundation.
Eclipse is a foundation which is also responsible for developing Eclipse IDE and Eclipse Foundation
has chose to rename it as Jakarta E, but originally it used to be with Oracle.
And third platform is Java Micro Edition or Java Me in short, and this was previously called as J.
To me and it is used to develop applications for resource constrained devices like mobile phones and
set top boxes.
So it is mainly for small devices which have limited memory and limited processing power.
While Java E is built on Java Sea, Java uses a subset of Java C.
And in this course we will be learning about Java as E as it represents the core Java programming language.
We will also briefly get into Java E at the very end as the course project is a web application and
we use some basic Java E technologies like Servlet and JSP.
Note that even if you want to develop Java E or Java applications, you still need to have a solid foundation
in Java as both Java EE and Java m e as we can see are based on Java C.
And you may also know that to develop full featured Android apps, we need to know Java.
So having Sound Foundation in Java is very important and this course is all about setting that foundation
firmly.
Not having a good foundation in Java can really hurt your performance as a software engineer when you're
developing Java EE or Android applications.
So it is important to learn Java well, give it the time it needs and once you have a good background
in Java, learning these other platforms is pretty easy and it shouldn't also take too much of time
to acquire those skills.
Now, strictly speaking, each of these different platforms define one or more specifications, and
a specification is simply a document that describes the technology in plain English.
So it is not a software and just a document.
So the software, which is the implementation of the specification, would be something different.
And an implementation can come from different providers like Oracle or Amazon or IBM and so on.
So a specification is like a blueprint for a house, and the implementation is the actual house itself.
Now the course is about Java Sea.
So let's focus on it.
Java Sea defines few specifications and one is the Java language specification or GLS and shot, and
it defines the entire Java programming language itself.
That is a defines the syntax and semantics of the language.
That is the rules of the language.
And it is the most comprehensive and accurate document that you can get on Java as it is written by
the Java language designers themselves like James Gosling.
So it is like any good book on Java but is not easy to understand, at least for a beginner.
Later we will also look at the Java language specification, which is online and next specification
is Java Virtual Machine Specification, which defines how a JVM should work, and it also specifies
the bytecode instruction set.
And we will look at some of the byte code instructions in the Java Internals chapter.
And it also includes the Java API specification, which is nothing but the specification of the Java
library.
So that's what Java SE specification is, and it has many implementations.
One is the official implementation from Oracle and it is referred to as Oracle JDK, where JDK means
Java Development Kit.
Then there is Oracle's open JDK.
So this also comes from Oracle.
The difference between Oracle JDK and Open JDK is that open JDK is completely free.
While with Oracle JDK, you would have to pay Oracle if you are using it for commercial purpose.
And with that, you would also get their support for fixing any bugs in the implementation.
Now open JDK is completely free, so it is free even for commercial purpose.
But since we are learning Java here, it is fine to use even Oracle JDK.
And there are also many other providers and a few prominent ones are adopting Open JDK, Amazon Crypto
and Red Hat's Open JDK.
These are also free, just like Oracle's Open JDK.
Now, each of these implementations is basically a JDK that is Java development kit, and we need a
JDK to write, compile and execute our Java programs.
And soon we will install one of the latest versions of JDK.
And let's see what a JDK would contain.
It would obviously include a JVM which implements the Java specification.
Right.
And it would also include the actual Java API code that is the Java Library code, which is a predefined
functionality that we can readily use when writing our Java programs.
And it would also include development tools like the Java compiler so that we can compile our Java programs.
So all requests that we get from the different providers would include these components.
Gigi is also referred to as Java SDK, where SDK stands for software development kit.
SDK is more of a general term and many times developers may also refer to JDK as Java E, although strictly
speaking, Java E is a set of specifications.
Just as we discussed now here, the JV team and the Java API are collectively referred to as JIRA,
which stands for Java Runtime Environment.
Oracle used to offer such a degree separately from JDK, although JDK includes a GI.
That's because j r e as its name jour runtime environment suggests, is essentially a runtime environment.
That is, it is an environment used to only run Java applications.
So you cannot develop Java applications using Java.
So if you are shipping your Java application to your clients, then your clients would only need to
install a jar to run it.
They do not need development tools like the Java compiler which come with the JDK.
So they do not need a JDK, but they need a job.
However, such a separate Java was offered only till Java SE ten, where ten is one of the versions
of Java C.
From Java.
As 11 onwards, Oracle stopped offering it as they were, including a tool called Jail Ink, which can
be used to create a custom job.
And this custom job can be smaller in size than a regular job.
Or one can simply install a JDK itself, as it also includes a.
So jrd is not included separately by Oracle from Java 11 onwards.
But regardless of whether a separate git is available or not, we as developers who develop Java programs
would need a JDK as it includes tools like Java compiler, which is needed to compile our programs.
And since it also includes a JVM, since the JDK includes a JVM, we can also execute our programs.
So JDK is what we need.
Now, earlier it was mentioned that these are some of the prominent Greek providers, although these
are different implementations.
They are all based on the same source code.
And this source code is developed as part of this project called Open JDK, and this source code is
open source.
And it was originally proprietary to Oracle, but later Oracle made it open source so that anyone can
contribute to it, including engineers from companies such as Oracle, Amazon and IBM.
Now, when we say source code, it would mainly be the Java Library or the Java API code and a JVM implementation
called Hotspot.
And Hotspot is written in C++.
So all these different providers would include the same API code and the hotspot JVM.
However, certain providers might add some non core functionality and may also provide additional services
like offering page support, like in the case of Oracle's dedicated.
Now adopt open Openjdk also provides the option to use another JVM called Open J nine, which is from
the Eclipse Foundation.
Open J nine is also open source and was originally developed by IBM.
So Hotspot and Open nine are two different JVM implementations and both are great.
Hotspot is more like a standard one because it was originally developed by Oracle and it's also part
of Open JDK, but Open nine is also very good.
So keep in mind that Java is open source.
Now let's briefly look at the Java specifications that are available on the web.
So just go ahead and Google for Java s e specification.
And the first result here is the is this link which says Java e specifications and it is from the Oracle
dotcom site.
And just click on that.
So here it shows the Java Sea specifications and it shows the different releases like the Java Sea 14,
which is the latest release.
And there are also the previous releases like the Java Sea, 13, 12, 11 and so on.
And you may see some other release here depending on when you are accessing this.
So here we know that the Java Sea is a set of specifications and one of them is the Java language specification
or GLS, and the other one is the Java virtual machine specification.
And there is also the Java API specification.
It is not linked from here.
So we need to look at it separately and I will show you the Java API specification in a bit.
So here let's go ahead and click on this HTML which shows the HTML version of the specification.
And as I told you, the Java language specification defines the Java programming language itself.
So it defines the syntax and the semantics, like the rules of the programming language.
And as I said earlier, it is authored by the language designers like James Gosling here and other designers
here.
So here you can view the table of contents.
But like I said earlier, it's not very easily comprehensible for a beginner.
Definitely it is not easy to understand because it uses a certain formal way in which they explain things
and it is not very digestible.
So you do need a book or an online resource such as this to understand the language.
But once you gain some experience, sometimes if you have any questions or if you have any doubts while
you are programming, you may refer to this document so you can look at it later.
It's not that important.
So let's go back.
And this is a Java virtual machine specification.
And here also, let's click on this and it tells about how the JVM should work.
OC And here are the table of contents.
It talks about the architecture and the different things within the GVM and the JVM implementation has
to adhere to this particular document.
And like I said, a specification is simply a document written in English.
And at the very end here it lists out all of the bytecode instructions.
And we know that a Java program is compiled into Java bytecode, which is nothing but the Java bytecode
instructions, and these are all the different instructions and we will review some of them later on.
Okay.
So let's go back.
And next in a different tab, just search for, let's say Java 13 API, just Google for that.
And the first link here is the Java API and it is also from the Oracle's website.
And if you see the path here, it says API, let's click on this.
So this is the Java API and this is how it is.
The look and feel very unique.
So the Java API is nothing, but it describes the Java library which contains the predefined functionality
that the Java programmers can use.
And most of this library, the predefined functionality is in the form of classes.
Classes are fundamental units of the Java language.
A class is a very fundamental unit and a Java library has tons of classes, thousands of classes, and
they're all packaged into something called packages.
And very soon we will also write our own first Java class and within this course we'll be writing a
lot of Java classes.
But the library itself comes with a lot of classes.
So I'm not going into this particular document at this point of time because later on we will review
this.
But it does provide a lot of packages and you will have separate packages for data structures and you
can really use those data structures.
Similarly, there will be packages for doing input output like reading and writing into files and also
for other purposes.
So that's the Java API.
Now here every release comes with something called as a GSR and it just ah stands for Java specification
request.
So as you can see, there is this release with this GSR and it's it also has a number GSR 389.
Similarly, Java 13 has GSR 388.
And most of these releases also have their own GSR.
And GSR stands for Java specification request, and it mainly describes the features that got added
within this particular release.
And those features can be some changes in the Java language itself, or it can be something to do with
the JVM.
Like maybe a new algorithm has been added for doing garbage collection, so something like that.
Or it can be some new classes being added to the Java API itself, so it can be any of those changes.
So when something is something change happens to the Java language, then the compiler also has to be
updated, so they need to make a lot of changes there.
Java language change could be something like for instance, in Java eight they introduced something
called as Java, something called the Lambda Expressions.
So that's a change in the language.
And so the compiler also has to be updated and some relevant API changes were also had to be made.
Now this Java specification request over here, this is called as an umbrella GSR and each GSR like
like I said, it has a defines certain it describes certain features and some of the features are major
features and some are minor.
And the major features can also have an associated GSR.
Each major feature can have an associated GSR, and which means that this GSR can have some some component
GSR.
Now, this GSR is initially proposed when they want to come up with a new release.
It is run by a specification lead.
And the GSR would go through different phases.
Initially there would be a draft phase and then finally you will also it goes through multiple stages
and finally there will be a final specification and it would include all the real features and some
of the features which were initially proposed may not make it to the final specification.
So this process of developing this GSR through different stages is called as Java Community Process
or GCP and Short.
So that is just for your information.
So you need to know what a GCP is.
It's a formal mechanism or a formal process to develop Java specifications.
So that way the language is continuously being evolved.
And later on, maybe once you're done with the course you can read about it.
It's not that important to know about at this point of time, but you need to at least know what a GCP
is and what a GSR is.
So that's about it.
So just to summarize, we looked at Java SC and we know where it stands within the Java software family.
It is the core of the Java software platform family, and we know that Java C is a bunch of specifications
and there are also keys which implement a Java SE specifications.
And these kids come from different providers and all of these providers we said are most of them are
based on a common source code, an open source source code which is developed by the Open JDK project.
And we also know that the specifications are developed by, through a process called GCP, which is
a Java community process, and every Java release has this umbrella, GSR, it's called as an umbrella
GSR because it includes all of the different features.
And in the next lecture, let's we will look at the different releases and discuss a bit about the release
cycle and what comes along with each release cycle.
With each release.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.