Hi there.
This is David.
And welcome back.
Now, let's go ahead and look at the solution for our exercise.
So here is the card price estimate or class.
And I hope you were able to complete it.
In case you could not implement it correctly, then this short discussion should be very helpful.
But if you are able to complete it successfully, and if your solution has passed the online test,
then you can still look at this solution so that you can compare it your version with the version that
we have here.
So this is the get sale price method, which you are supposed to implement.
So let's just look at the solution.
So here we the sale price is initialized and here we have the first condition.
So we said that if the age of the car is less than or equal to ten, then the price depreciates by 5%
of the original sale price.
So the depreciated value is computed in this way.
It takes the age of the car, which is here.
Age of the car is computed here, which it's already given to you.
And we are multiplying it with the sale price times .05 as the price.
Here we are saying the price depreciates by 5% of the original sale price.
So this is the original sale price and it is going to be reduced by 5%.
And that is done for this value, the age of the car and that is the price depreciated and we are subtracting
that from the sale price.
So the sale price is being recalculated here and we have the condition.
So if the car is over ten years old, then we said that we are going to return this 10% of the sale
price.
So that's what we are returning here.
And that's it.
Here we had a small node like use compound arithmetic assignment operators wherever it is possible,
so it's not required there.
But let's look at the security features here.
So the condition is if Card does not have at least two airbags and ABS and EBD.
In that case, you would have to reduce the sale price by $1,000.
So that's what we are doing here.
So if the car we have the condition here.
So if the car has all of these conditions, if all of these conditions are true, then we we do not
have to reduce the price and we just keep the if.
BLOCK But if it does not, how if the at least one of these conditions would fail, then a false would,
then this entire expression would return a false and not false would be true and the sale price would
be reduced by $1,000.
So here the requirement is that all of the conditions have to be met, otherwise the sale price would
be reduced.
So we are using the note operation here and the next is comfort features.
This is pretty simple.
We are saying if the car has a rear view camera and so because of that, we are using this and symbol
here.
And we are we are saying either sunroof or auto AC has to be there.
If in that case only then we will increase the price by $500.
So if the rear view camera is true, and if one of these is true, then it is sufficient and we can
increase the sale price.
So we have the comfort features that are required by this logic.
And this is straight forward.
If has accident history is true, then we reduce the price by $400.
Now, next one is based on additional miles driven.
So we have the additional miles completed here.
And we are saying if the number of miles over driven, that is the additional miles is greater than
1000.
So that's what we have here.
And if it is less than or equal to 10,000, then reduce the sale price by 500.
Similarly, we have two more conditions here, two more if statements.
So the first one is if miles over driven is greater than 10,000, that is represented by this boolean
condition and less than or equal to 30,000, reduce the sale price by 1000.
And if the miles over driven is greater than 30,000, reduce it by 1500.
And we are finally retaining the value here.
So that said, let me we also have the main method here.
Let me just run it once.
With some values.
So here it is.
So the age of the car is two because we are passing 2018 and the sale after depreciation is 18,000.
So that's what is being computed.
So initial value is 20,000 because we are passing Ford, EcoSport and Ford for Ford EcoSport, the value
returned is 20,000 and the age of the car is two.
And based on that.
Here we are computing this and 2000 is reduced.
After applying this logic and we are printing the value which is 18,000 and then after the security
features has been applied because we are passing to here and true and false.
So which means that it did not have this false represents the bead has a bead and because of that the
price was reduced and the car also did not have.
The conditions that we have for comfort features.
So it remained at 17,000 and there was a finally we are passing through, which means that there has
been an accident and the price is further reduced.
And finally, here we are passing 60,000.
60,000.
Okay.
So for 60,000, it was overdriven and the overdriven distance is greater than 30,000.
And because of that, we were reducing the price by 1500.
So the final price was 15,000.
And that's it.
And.
Hope you like this exercise.
And that's it.
And thank you.
And see you in the next lecture.