So we have seen how method writing is implemented.
And let's not forget what cannot be overridden.
And there are three things that cannot be overridden on the first one is a final method.
I that there is simply not my limited but it is declared the.
Key word final in its declaration.
We looked at final variables which meant that if variable's value once initialized can never be changed
that is the variable true value is final.
Similarly if finden method behavior is also final so cannot be overridden.
You will do this if you have written some logic.
You want it to work only in the way you have implemented it.
That is not of the subprocess should ever be able to redefine it next.
Fields cannot be altered and that is buttstock as well as instance variables cannot be overridden.
If you recall a discussion on method or writing we said that an instance variable in a superclass can
be hidden by an instance variable in a subclass by really declaring that we reachable in the subclass
.
That is a really clear variable.
They will have the same name as in the superclass.
On other things like variables Deedat I do not matter.
Only thing is they should have the same name.
Not a good question to ask would be why are instance variables not overridden by then instance methods
can be overridden.
Why did the language designers do that.
My best guess is that here we are talking about two different entities.
One is data that there is behavior.
Now when it comes to behavior that is the methods it makes sense to pick the more specific question
of the behavior with respect to the object in context.
An GBM is just doing it.
That's because inheritance is mainly about having classes of it more specialized logic.
So you would execute a specialized writing matter.
I would assume semantically same does not hold hard data that is Duffys.
What I would value the current be has in the current class is good enough on practically That would
be the most probable scenario.
Dutch studies and why language designers would have gone with this kind of behavior.
So no need to go down the hierarchy and become more specific you.
So that's the reason why.
Instance variables are also early bonder but not that incased a subclass object.
Instead of re declaring simply resigns will be a different value then we will see that value as there
is only one motion of the variable next tactic that cannot be overridden in the rest of the lesson.
Let's see why static methods cannot be overridden and the same argument would also hold forth static
variables.
At the end of the lesson we will do more of static methods not being overridden and in the next lesson
we will do a quick demo all priest not being or what he can do.
Let's consider it our familiar inheritance tree and I made minor changes here for the sake of this discussion
in the User class.
Same we see a book methods have been removed and a new method called static method has been introduced
in book user as well as stuff process on both methods are static methods.
Now here we have this declaration where we are creating an instance of editor under referenced by Peary's
user.
We are going to invoking Silverlink method which would invoke the same blink in the User class Nona's
as you say blink done in books posted of your method and this gives vino that posted Abele method.
In the staff class would be invoked as opposed to post-edit view.
End User class and we know that it's because JVM searches for the most specific words shown off posted
a view method starting from edit class as the object here is editor.
Let's also assume that save blank also invoke static method.
In this case the static method in User class would be invoked not the notion in the staff class a static
method are not overridden so static method in the same class is being invoked.
So here the class user is saying that I'm defining this method call Silverlink And if this method accesses
an instance method then I'm not going to get involved as I don't deal with state.
So the instance method to be invoked will be decided by JVM at runtime based on the object in context
bugger this good exercise one of my starting my turret's then it means that I want to access the static
method that is defined in my class as startlement that belong to me.
I don't get if the subclass object on which this method is invoked also has a similar static method
.
So I'm E-Class and if my code uses my class methods then my intention is to use my class matters not
somebody else's down the class hierarchy.
So that's a nice way of looking at this behavior.
But from a one method binding lesson we also know that stocktake matters are bonded compile time itself
and so the invocation of the static method is bownde at compile time itself.
So that's another way to look at it later in the day.
We will actually see this in action to get some more clarity.
Let's also look at an example where support classes have stopped instance methods that identical names
here.
How close super with one static method call it on one instance method called be and there are three
subclasses extending the superclass and they all have the same methods that are in the superclass not
Ajume duck.
We have this method foo class parameter.
S is of type super which is the superclass inside the method we are invoking both methods E and B on
the input reference variable S then method is invoked.
It will always invoke the static method in the superclass regardless of the object that gets assigned
to the input variable S that is you can invoke the method for any of the three subclass objects or even
the superclass object on only the method in superclass gets in.
As we discussed earlier the reason for this is there is a static method on stocktake but dirt's are
bounded at compile time based on the referenced type.
So the compiler precisely knows which method is invoked on blocks a static method in any of the subclasses
.
You just need to use the subclass named directly order reference type has to be offcuts Stop-Loss type
or you would need to apply a cast where the cast is off suppressed like Hollywood when it comes to in
Woking matter b.
And the second statement.
The method invoked the rarely depend on the object that got passed.
And we have seen this while discussing polymorphism.
So if an instance of subline is passed at runtime then each version of method B which is overriding
the motion in superclass is invoked if an instance of sapu is passed then its motion of method being
invoked.
But if super object is passed then the motion in super is invoked and we already know the reason for
this.
The method to be invoked will be decided at runtime based on the object type of the reference variable
.
We know that JVM invokes the more specific motion of the method.
So unless starting my third there is no one single word of method B that gets executed in the method
for.
It just depends on which object is passed.
Static method which is the method to be in go is finalized right away at compile time itself to reference
type.
And so what writing does not apply here.
The object if it comes into play at runtime is totally irrelevant.
Also note that just like in the case off topic an instance variables we said that he had this topic
matter in a subclass is hiding the static method in the superclass or not let's look at some more details
on syntactic methods.
And already this was mentioned earlier Superguy word is related to objects so it cannot be used inside
a static method.
If you have to access a hidden superclass method then you'll need to qualify the method name with the
super Krosnick unrealistic mollify.
It simply means superclass name should be followed by dog operator which is done followed by the mean
.
Next we know that static methods do not how and it can grow without it.
So just like the way a static method cannot access instance variables an instance method Dick cannot
hide instance methods and we get a compiler error if we try to do this.
Finally static methods cannot be overridden by instance methods.
And once again we get a compiler error.
If we tried to do this so that's a bog on why static methods are not overridden.
Nice thing is instead of simply accepting that starting methods are not overridden we kind of look at
why they are not overridden and that is more important non-North look at a very quick double on the
stuff that cannot be overridden.
OK let's look at final metrics.
We know that final methods can not be overridden.
So here we are and users are Java and this is a final method that we have created.
It's named as final method on your to an instance method.
Find an instance method on here you can see the keyword final which means that this is the final version
of the matter and should not be overridden.
Now start of July which is the subclass of user B have a new method here and instance method we just
call it has finally met method once again because we want to see if we can override it.
And now we get a compiler error.
It says cannot or I don't find one method from user so that you cannot write find other methods.
Now let's look at stocktake metrics.
Static methods cannot be ordered and they can only be hidden.
So here this is the method from the method binding demo and it is called a static method and we have
this print statement.
It's just printing the method name along with the class name.
So it's a static method now and stuff got Jawa.
Also I created a new static method and it has the exact same signature and it looks exactly the same
.
Only thing is the print statement says it is from stuff not in user test or Jawa.
So we have created this instance of editor and a reference type is user.
And here we are invoking the topic matter right.
So let me just run this.
So as you can see the work and end user is getting invoker.
That's because of early binding.
Right because static matter is not overridden and because of all because of early binding which we have
seen not method binding the notion in use it gets in Wilker because the reference type is what matters
here.
It looks at the reference type.
The compiler looks at the reference type and it decides that the motion and met user should be invoked
.
And that's because of the early binding.
OK now if you want to invoke the motion and static method then we can do this.
Basically we are applying a cast and the cast is a subclass which is a stop.
So let me run this.
Our knowledge system tactic method static methods can never be ordered and it can really be hidden.
So this is another example.
Here we are invoking the Silverlink method using the style reference ironed Silverlink as defined here
in the User class in the superclass and it simply prints undented in to post edit your method.
So this we have already seen and in one of the earlier demos.
So this would work.
The posted of your method in the subclass.
There is a posted of your method here which is an instance method on that instance method is already
written and in the staff class so there is a poster posted here.
So this is going to override that.
But the method is going to work this way even though it is getting invoked from sibling.
It's going to invoke this and that we know it's because of late binding because it uses the object type
so that we already know.
Then the interesting thing is here the static method is invoked one second the static method in the
user classes invoked.
But now it's not going to invoke the static method in the subclass.
It's only going to invoke the static method in the same class.
So this kind of illustrates that for days for posted if you mattered it's going to involve the motion
in the subclass.
And that's because of the object type.
But for this when it comes to start big matter it is going to invoke the Stop the method in the same
class not the one in the subclass.
So this kind of a monster is that.
So let's just go ahead and run this here.
So this is the first quarter save eyeblink and Silverlink is in the post-edit view and because of the
object type.
The one direction stuff is getting in.
But the Russian stuff is actually invoking the version and use it also so the user is getting in.
So that plus part of the demo that we hired for material were writing.
So that's for the instance my thoughts on when it came when it involved this topic matter it in the
wash and end user not the one and stuff.
So that kind of shows the difference between the two.
Soit was invoking the word topic matter in the same class etc..
So that's about it.
That's about what cannot be ordered and