Hi there.
This is the model group we briefly discussed string pull when introducing strings and we said that it
was one of the features that made string special and that's because of the way String Literals get stored
internally.
Let's now look at string in detail.
And so we will be looking at how JVM handles strings internally.
At the end, we will also test the concepts using a simple demo, and it's an important lecture and
an interesting one too.
And many developers do not know about string pull, or even if they do, the understanding is generally
not that clear.
Let's begin by understanding how strings are stored internally by GM when created using string letters
versus when created using the new keyword.
First, let's look at the case when strings are created using string letters.
If you recall, we said that all string literals are stored in a special area of memory called String
Pool.
In fact, within memory, string pool is actually part of heap.
And we know that heap is where all objects reside.
So string pool also includes objects, but only string objects that are created using string literals.
And the string literals have the same content, then they share same storage in the string pool.
This was also discussed earlier, but in the next slide we will look at it through an example.
Next coming to strings created using the new keyword.
These string objects are no different from regular java objects.
That is the one heap but outside of string pull.
And they get their own storage and do not share storage.
Even if two string objects have the same content, let's look at an example to understand these differences.
So here we have the heap and within heap we have string pool.
Now later we have the statement where variable as one is assigned a string literal.
Hello.
Since we have a string Littrell as mentioned earlier.
JB on what started it in the string pool by creating a string object and as one would reference it.
So even though it's a literal internally, it is stored as a regular string object, but within the
string pool.
Next, let's say we have a variable as to which is also assigned with the same lateral flow.
And we also know that if string letters have same content, they share same storage in the string pool.
And so as two will reference the same string object that S1 is referencing.
Now, important thing to note here is that these two statements can appear anywhere in the application.
There may be a completely different classes or even in completely different packages altogether.
As long as both statements are executed as part of the same JVM process, only a single string object
will be created for the literal hello and as one and S2 will reference it.
Next, if a variable as three is assigned with SW one, then SW three will also obviously reference
the same string object in string pull.
Next, let's say we have this statement where variable as four is created using the new keyword and
this also initialize with the text.
Hello.
And we know that this would create a string object outside of the string pool, just like in the case
of any regular Java object.
And as for word reference, however, the argument to the constructor is a string literal.
So JVM would still try to create a string object for that literal in the string pool.
But since we already have a string object for the little hello in the string pool, a reference to it
is passed to the constructor.
But if a string object corresponding to literal hello was not there in the string pool, then JVM would
have created a new string object in the string pool and would have passed a reference to that new string
object to the constructor.
So to go on the string poll, all we need is a string letter.
And it doesn't matter where that letter appears.
The letter can also be part of a system or println statement.
Next.
Let's say we have this statement.
And we know that this will also create a new string object outside of the string pool.
So both as four and five are referencing two different string objects, even though they are initialized
with the same content.
So there is no sharing of storage, as in the case of S1 as to an S3.
And because of this kind of implementation, when we do an object reference comparison on S1 and S2,
it would result in a true value.
But when we do an object reference comparison on S4 and S5, it will result in a false value.
So as you can see, the main advantage of using string literals is that it would save us memory when
the letters have the same content.
Not just to be 100% clear on what we just learned.
If we have only this statement that is JVM and counters string neutral.
Hello for the very first time.
Then first a string object corresponding to the literal hello is created in the string pull.
And a reference to it is passed to the constructor to construct a new string object outside of string
pull.
Essentially in this case, toasting objects are being created.
So just keep that in mind.
It can sometimes be asked in an interview too.
But if Hello Literal was already there in the string pool, then it would have created just one string
object outside of the string pool.
Now let's look at a few more specifics related to spring poll.
We now know that a string pool basically stores a single copy of each string letter in the form of string
object.
So just keep that in mind.
That string pool holds string objects.
We also know that spring pool is part of he and not that there is only one copy of Stempel.
Swimming pool is also referred to as string table.
So that's another name for string pool.
And this whole process of building upstream pool is referred to as spring interning.
On each letter in the string Paul is called as an intern.
On singing.
Dancing is also supported in other languages like Python, Ruby, C Sharp and even in scripting languages
like JavaScript.
So we now understand how string and turning works at a conceptual level.
Let's now see how it is actually done behind the scenes by JVM.
Now, when GM encounters a string literal for the very first time, it does two things.
First it creates a new string object with same content as the string return.
Next, it invokes a method called intern on the created string object.
So there is a method called intern in the string class.
And this is what intern method is doing.
The intern method first checks if there is already a string object in the string pool with the same
content.
If there is, then it simply returns a reference of that existing string object.
The string object it created is simply abandoned and will be garbage collected.
Garbage collection will be discussed later in the internal chapter.
But a string pool does not contain a string object with the same content.
Then in turn, method adds the new string object it created into the string pool and returns its reference.
So in that method, as the name indicates, deals with interning.
Now the same literal is uncounted once again.
Then Gvm checks if the intent method was previously invoked on a string object that was initialized
with this literal and would return a reference to that instance.
In fact, that's the first thing JVM always does whenever a literal is encountered and if any method
was not previously invoked, only then it does the two steps that we see here.
Now let's look at a couple of examples.
Here we are concatenating two literals.
And in this case the result of concatenation will also be interned, as it would also be a literal whose
value is known at compile time itself.
Now in this example, we have variable as one which is assigned a little, but variable as to is a concatenation
of a literal and the variable as one here variable as one would be evaluated at runtime.
And so we don't have a literal at compile time.
So this would not lead to creation of an intern and the resulting string object would be created outside
of string pool.
But if we explicitly invoke and turn method in this way on the variables too, then an intern would
be created in this case variable as to would finally reference the intern in the string pool as on the
left side of the assignment we have the variable S2 so we can explicitly invoke in turn method to just
like the way JVM does.
Under all string object that S2 was referencing will still be on the heap and will be eligible for garbage
collection.
So the question is, will such an explicit internal bias anything?
Most likely not.
It seems to be better off to be used only by GM.
But in certain applications like natural language processing, where we may process lots and lots of
text and do a lot of string manipulations, we may think of explicit, intending if we think a lot of
identical strings would be created.
However, it depends on the particular application and you would have to experiment and make your decision.
So that's about string pool and interning.
Let's notice some of the stuff we have learned through a short demo.
A new method called String Pull has been added to the Basics Demo class.
And let's go ahead and look at the new method.
Here is the new string pool method which has been added to the basics demo class.
So here we have a bunch of declaration statements creating some strings, and we also have some parent
statements doing some tests.
So here in the declaration statements, we are creating a couple of strings on the string pull and at
least one string outside of the string pool.
And we are basically doing a comparison of the object references and we are also explicitly invoking
in turn method a couple of places and we will look at that.
So let's just go ahead and look at what we have here in the declaration statements.
So initially, we are creating this variable as one which is an object reference and it is initialized
with the text.
Hello.
So it's a string literal.
And so we know that this string gets created in the string pool.
Similarly, we have as to here it is also initialized with the same string literal.
Hello.
So it would also point to the same string object in the string literal.
So we know we also know that and here in SE three, so we are invoking an internal method on the string
later.
So we can also do that.
So this is like a double turning here because this itself is an intern and then we are once again invoking
the intern method whose main objective is to is to create interns in the string pool.
Right.
We know that intern method does that.
It creates interns.
So it's like a double interning here now as four is created using the new keyword.
So here a string.
String is created outside of the string pool and it is also initialized with the same with the same
string literal and as far as initialized with another string literal.
So, so those are the different declarations and we just have some comparisons being some tests here
and we are using the equals two operator to compare the different object references.
So let's just go ahead and run this program.
It's already compiled and then we can look at the we can analyze the results.
So this is what we have.
So in the first statement we are comparing object references, S1 and S2 and since both of them are
initialized with the same string literal, so they both point to the same string object in the string
pool.
So we have.
So the expression evaluates to true.
And next is a comparison between S1 and S3.
And S3 is also pointing to a string object in the string pool so we we can see it here.
So once again, it would evaluate to true.
And in the next statement, we are comparing S1 with S4.
So S1 is a string in the string pool as four is a string outside the string pool.
Right.
So that would be false.
And in the fourth line, we are invoking an internal method on S4 right over here.
So this basically creates an intern in the string pool, but S4 is initialized with the keyword, with
the literal hallow.
But we know that that intern is already there in the string pool because of these declarations here.
So basically, it's not going to create a new intern.
It's just going to reference it would be a reference.
This whole expression would be a reference to that string object which is already there in the string
pool.
So due to this, both S1 and this, this expression would point to the same string object in the string
And we get it true here.
Now, here, in the first statement, it's a concatenation between two string literals.
So this thing is so it would the after concatenation is it will still be a string literal.
So this will also be stored on the heap.
I mean, I'm sorry, on the on the string pool.
And it is since it is hallow, the concatenation is hallow and there is already a string object with
the same content in the string pool.
This expression would also evaluate to true.
And the final one is a concatenation between this text held here and this variable as file.
So if they're concatenated, definitely it's just the same text.
Hello.
But since this is a variable, it doesn't get evaluated until runtime and it would not be considered
as a literal.
Returns are created only yet are known at compile time.
So that's the reason when we execute it, it returns false.
But if you recall from our lesson on switch expressions, we said that if we make the variable a final,
this is called as a constant variable.
In that case, the compiler would simply take this text and it would hardwire it in place of this variable
at compile time itself into.
So it writes it into the byte code.
So if you make it a constant variable then.
Then it would you know, it would be it would be considered as a string literal and it would be the
expression would evaluate to true as one equals.
This would be true.
So that is if we add this keyword final.
So that's about it.
So just to summarize, all string literals will be stored in the string pool and the ones created using
new keyword will be will be stored outside the string pool.
And the main benefit of string pool is you get to save memory with the strings created in the string
pool if they have the same content.
So the recommended approach is to create strings using string literals and not using the new keyword.
So that's about it.
And this new method is there in the basics demo and it's already uploaded to the you can see it in the
resources section, so you can download it and play with it and that's about it and a happy coding.
Thank you.