So we implemented a major feature in the last lesson.
No we are going to implement another important feature which is to mark certain bookmarks as kid friendly
.
Nice thing is we already know the feature and the design that goes with it as we were using Treo as
a case study in learning the Object-Oriented concepts.
And just to recap the main idea is to maintain some prefab on the home page just pockets that is under
this new tab.
You will see only bookmarks that are suitable for kids.
The way it works is we have regular bookmarks for all kinds of users but one staff members like editors
and chief editors are using the system.
Then they will see a special link for marking most kinds of bookmarks as kid friendly for certain bookmarks
which are clearly not eligible for kid friendly status.
Some special things will not be displayed.
Examples would include bookmarks falling under categories such as January.
In case you skipped the chapters on object oriented programming then you can check out the first lesson
in the chapter that covers abstract classes and interfaces.
That lesson was this requirement.
But I guess the recap that we just did what most of the requirements.
So it's a nice feature as having a separate tab exclusively for it is very useful.
Now here is a class diagram for implementing this feature and we already implemented this and it is
the missing pieces are the two methods generate profile you are an easy kid friendly eligible.
Let's not worry about Jondrette profile you are for now and let's just implement easy get friendly eligible
method.
Once we implement East get friendly eligible method we will then implement the functionality for marking
bookmarks as kid friendly.
No here is good for any eligibility requirement for movies.
If the movie is either horror or Thriller then the matter to read and falls otherwise it should read
and true.
Similarly for books if the book is either a philosophical or a self-help book then the method Trivett
and falls.
Finally with ramblings The method should read and a false.
If the website is an other site not to implement is good for any eligible method we will follow what
is called s driven development which is in short referred to as P-Diddy.
Best do do double up ment is a software development process where the desk is is written before the
functional code is written for a new feature.
So you don't write the functional code first and then the best guess later you would write the desk
as fast.
And here are the main steps.
So you are right the desk is along with some initial code that would cause the test to fail.
Then you would write enough code to pass the test.
You can repeat this process of.
That's fast approach to incrementally add more functionality.
That is you would add more deaths and then more logic and let us pass.
Here are some real benefits.
And you are already familiar with this slide as it is taken from the eclipse chapter.
When we were discussing about unit tests so we know that such automated does will prevent new code from
breaking the system.
Basically it ensures program correctness at all points of time and that will improve programmer's confidence
.
But one important additional benefit of DDT is that it can also help you in better designing your methods
That's because DDT forces you to think through all the scenarios that would cover all the feature requirements
.
So you just tend to have a different thought process when doing.
First approach as opposed to a later approach.
So basically you are driving your design I think as you put it into practice and start using it regularly
.
Then you will be able to better appreciate its approach.
OK that's DDD and let's get started now.
So first thing that we need to do as I'd ease kid friendly eligible matter in the bookmark class.
It really added as an abstract matter.
So let's just go ahead and open the bookmark class.
So there is a shortcut to open a class with this control shift.
Our So this is a shortcut and let's just type and bookmark this right here at the top.
So that's Control shift.
And let's make this abstract.
If you recall this is supposed to be abstract but since we are adding that abstract method only now
so we're making the class abstract now so it will be public
so that's that is kid friendly and vegetable matter and let's just provide the implementation and weblink
selection is going to control shofer are let's do a blank.
OK.
Here it is.
Now we need to implement it.
So that's why it's giving compilation error.
So let's say I unimplemented methods.
So here is the stub.
And let's just return true for now.
Will be clear soon.
Now let's just go ahead and I had a test case for this because we are going to follow the best driven
approach.
So let's just go here and add a new folder called test.
So source folder called best and you might recall it from our G-Unit Allison and Eclipse chapter.
Now within this let's add a package and it has to be the same package as the entities as of eyeblink
because we are going to provide a desk for a web link.
OK.
So the package name will be Chrome
and Cadiz.
Now that's ired a G-Unit desk case since we are testing eyeblink needs to be Rabbe wabbling test.
So that's the convention and we need to load the class which we are going to test.
So it will be Lenk.
So this is the class under test.
And then hit next here.
If you're not providing the class under test then this will not be highlighted here and you'll see only
finish.
So you should select the class under test head next.
And this is the method that we want to test and it says I.
G-Unit library to the barre But let's just say ok and G-Unit has been added here and this is the template
class.
Yes.
If we run this it would fail not to think through our test cases.
So the requirement is that this method is different the eligible should return false.
If it's an adult website.
So let's look at weblink class and see what field it has.
It has a u r l it has a host and if you look at bookmark class it also has a title.
Let's look at all of this here.
So it has a title.
So those are the three fields that we have.
So what we can do is we can look for some keywords in these fields and if the keyword is present we
build it and false otherwise we will return true.
So let's take on our world as the key words are whatever your imagination suggests.
So we can have the logic in this.
If the word -- is present anywhere in the water or in Tipler then we see it and falls Similarly if
the key word either appears anywhere in the hostname then where it involves But if it appears anywhere
else in the order other than the host name then deleted it and true.
Similarly if it if it appears only in title then also it untrue since we are following just doing the
will up meant we will have to frustrate our best guesses and we will then write the actual logic.
So let's do that.
So let's go back into our Webling test and let's write five best cases.
Let's just put some comments first.
Just one
.
So for just one we will test if the key were born as and the you are ill.
In this case it has to return a false.
Next we will check f -- and Titan can never blink instance.
And in this case also the matter has to return false.
You know the third scenario as our gold in Horst.
Right.
So for does it has to return false.
Now our dirt in your order but not in host this hitcher construe
and only in this case also I took control.
So let's just go ahead and build these test cases.
So basically what we are what we have to do is create an instance of a weblink.
And so that would be the book and then we will execute.
We will invoke the east kid friendly eligibility method and then we but it does the output.
So first let's create an instance so that would be the input and we have to create an instance for that
let's just going to data store here because there is already some code for creating an instance you're
just let's use this just won't go back.
No this is a mark of sorted rodent's a weblink.
So Paul and you are of that so let's just go here.
Let's just put it here.
It's on.
So that's the good.
So let's invoke a blank Dorward ease get friendlier richer.
Now this returns a boolean.
So let's assign it to a boolean reliable and that's quite at ease.
Good friendly eligible.
So it has to return a false.
So we will use this method call as Surt falls from the asset class here which is important.
Big group at amateur's.
And the second parameter is the east kid friendly eligible method and if it returns false then we are
good.
But if in case if it returns true then it means that something is wrong.
And then if needed then we need to print a nice message.
So let's just say for -- on some meaningful message and you are still
Maastricht and fonts.
OK.
So let's go ahead and ride the second best.
So if this returns true if this method returns are true for this instance then this message will be
strong.
OK.
So it's right the second best.
Just remove this
and the second just born has to be entitled.
So let's just look at here.
And for on AM.
Is good for and true and it's also remove this here beaming anger.
So now let's copy this whole thing and let's build a third discus.
Now this is about Horst appearing and host sort of just changed this back to.
And here is the host name.
So let's just make it.
I don't want assistance
for I don't.
Host.
He's good for an angiogram was written for.
So this is good for the fourth Test.
Hoes are dead in your world but not in whole Sparta so he can hide it here under knocking holes.
But so this is also good.
So let's just say four hundred in your honor but not host not host vodka for this.
It needs to return it.
True.
What does the matter.
Has it done it true.
Because the term our dirt is not appearing in host it needs to return.
True.
So for truculence concept true if East get friend eligible is assigned true then we are good.
If not it will throw this exception and it will or must return true.
Yeah we need to change this now.
The final test here
just sit in in the title The key word adult should appear in title.
Yeah.
So this is good.
For and Dyken must return true.
So those are all the best guess is that we have now let's just go ahead and run this wabbling best proceed
.
That is in error because we still did not tried the method itself or did not build our logic.
So it says here in the US District has failed.
So let's just go ahead and build our logic now.
Let's go here
on Daines.
So Titlist by free an bookmarks so we cannot access or indirectly.
So we have to use some of this get Teicher we have to use the get method here and to get her.
So let's just go ahead and run this again
.
So now as you can see the first two deaths how free or how fast.
Because we have written the logic for -- but it failed at the third one because at the third one we
are passing our word.
And that is unhorsed and we still do not have the logic for that.
So it's time to write logic for the third one.
So let's just say host Undine's.
So even in this case it has to written as far as if the host has in-groups the key word order.
So let's just go back.
So it passed but it did the fourth one failed for the fourth one we are passing under a new order but
not host part.
Oh I think it's because of this which has to be beaming.
It's just us.
OK.
So that was just an error
.
So now for sure it will work.
So as you can see there are zero errors and zero failures.
So we are good.
So that's how that's one double up and is done.
So we have written the past cases first and then we how bad our logic under that is how passed.
OK.
So that's for eyeblink.
So let's just do four book on movie.
So let me do it offline and then I'll come back and show you the code.
OK.
Here is the more we test.
So that's the best guess for testing.
The movie NDB and here is a method.
So we are testing east kid friendly eligible method and here that here are the two test cases.
So if you recall the condition is that if the movie is either a horror movie or a thriller movie then
the method should read and false.
So that was a condition and that's what we are testing here.
So if that returns false then we are good and we are doing and assert false as we did for the wabbling
.
So so that's those are the two tests.
And let's just go here three and here we are simply checking f genré is a.
Equals equals horror our effort equals thriller than really good return for us which means that it's
not good friendly.
And so this is the book Best And For the book best the condition is that the books should not be either
a philosophy book or self-help book.
OK so once again we are looking at the genre field and we have two test cases for that.
And so if we're going to this method it's very similar to the movie logic.
So that's how you do best Doogan double up.
You write that as Cozzens first and then you die.
And the initial test should fail and then you build the logic and then that well that will pass the
test.
So that's how you would do it.
And if any Duggal a person if they mess up what with the logic here then when the tests are run it is
very likely that they will fail and then they will hold the double up or do fix the issue.
OK.
I also want to say that just go ahead and check out the frequently asked questions and G-Unit site and
they have a real good compilation of frequently asked questions.
So finally I'm also including a few important book references in the resource section and you may want
to buy them at some point if you feel necessary.
And that's about it for now.