Hi there.
Welcome back.
In the last lesson re-implemented east kid friendly eligible method.
And with that we completed part of the functionality for monitoring bookmarks as kid friendly.
Now let's write code that will actually allow editors and chief editors to my bookmarks as kid friendly
.
The new code will make use of easy kid friendly eligible method.
That is if the method returns true for a bookmark only then an editor can approve or reject the bookmark
as kid friendly like in the case of bookmarking process a proof or rejection will be done by a randomisation
Lidderdale will enhance the functionality to make real input from the user from the console.
So let's get started.
Let's begin with the bookmark class and let's introduce a new for you.
Callers get friendly status.
So this field basically tells whether a bookmark is good for me or not.
OK so let's introduce that field.
It would be a string.
So initially it can be initialized with a value called as a known and later when an editor or the chief
editor marks a particular bookmark as either a prude or rejected then the value of this field will be
updated.
OK so basically this field can have three values.
It can be unknown or it can be approved or rejected.
So the right thing to do would be to have a constant exporting class and how all these values within
that class and then reference that.
So one other benefit.
The main benefit of a constant exporting class which I did not explain earlier is that you have a single
place where you have all these constants and you can reference them from anywhere within your code.
So that one day it is if you need to make any change in the value you just updated in only one location
.
Otherwise you would have all these values spread across all your core and if you need to update any
value then you have to change it in one place and also you have to up hand-on every other place where
that value is used and you have to ablated there.
OK so it is very tedious and you may not be able to update in all the locations in some in some cases
.
OK so that's not a good way to do it.
So the right way would be to have such a class and to export all the constants from one place so that
if there is a need to make any change we just make it in only one place.
OK.
So let's just introduce a new class.
In fact I already added this class called it friendly status within the constants which is where we
have all the constant exporting classes.
And since it need not be instantiated it has a pirate constructor.
And here are the three constants.
Which means that they have static and finalizer modifiers.
So one is a brute.
One is rejected and the other one is unknown.
OK so let's just go here and initialiser to unknown
.
Next let's go into the View class view class we know corresponds to the user interface and we have one
method called bookmark which we wrote earlier.
So which corresponds to the bookmarking process.
Now before we get started let's do some refactoring here.
Let's actually create a pneumatic color brawls and let's maybe we will comment on this whole method
book Mont..
And the reason I want to have this new method called browsers because let's try to keep our implementation
as close to reality as possible.
So the browse method will take just the same parameters user and bookmarks and it is kind of like the
user has long been honest browsing all the bookmarks.
So he's presented with all the bookmarks on the user's browsing and his looking at each bookmark and
when he's looking at the bookmark he may perform three actions he may either bookmark a particular item
that he looking at or he in guess if it is an editor or a chief editor then the user can either mark
the bookmark as kid friendly or share the bookmark with a particular with the partner site which is
a feature that we that we are going to add later.
So those are the three actions that a user might take one or more of those actions or the user might
not even do anything with that particular item he may just give the item.
So it is much more realistic that way.
So let's just go ahead and introduce a new matter blows and we will comment this out.
OK.
So let's actually common this OUTFRONT
it's just copy and just simply modify this method.
It's just called it does browse.
OK.
Now a user not get e-mail.
Let's just say he's browsing items
now we will still have the same restriction.
That is a user cannot bookmark more than the user bookmark Lamech.
So it was a file and we still have the same.
So you can think of it as like you're not that there the whole application itself it has a trial version
on within the trial version when the user is using the trial version.
He's not allowed to bookmark more than the bookmark limit number of items.
So you can think of it that way.
So basically what will go the way it's going to be different from the previous version of bookmark is
that this time the user will browse through all the bookmarks and for each bookmark we will use a randomized
randomization to decide whether the user is going to book a bookmark that particular item or not.
So over here the user is actually dating only five times and each time he's just randomly picking a
particular bookmark.
But in the new version the user iterate through all the bookmarks but whether or not to bookmark a particular
item is dependent on the randomization feature.
OK so let's just go ahead and do it.
And I think it should be clear.
So first let's introduce a local variable here.
It's called Does bookmark.
That's how a for loop to iterate.
And let's would be have nested for loop because it's a two dimensional array that we have
now of this bookmark count
is less than it's used.
This
only then the user can bookmark.
Now let's introduce a new method called Get bookmarks decision.
And let's pass this bookmark the current bookmark to this method.
It's a pneumatic.
So we'll just create 3.
Now we need to use a randomization function here let's use it to an earlier operator here.
There's a mad dog around them.
Now of let's say if this value is less than Boinne fine then we will return true which means that user
wants to bookmark that particular item.
Otherwise the user is not interested in it.
OK so let's just say as
how available called Eastbrook Mont.
.
Now it means that the user wants to bookmark.
OK so let's increment this which means that the user is bookmarking a new item
and we can just reuse the scene statement that we can copy both of them here.
Now let's just put the message here because we want to introduce new code later.
So that's it I think there is nothing more here.
So we can just remove all of this
launch.
It's called This as browse and it's since it's not bookmarking alone anymore let's just call it a start
here.
Do the same here.
We can also common this.
I don't think we have to print all of those.
It was just to test whether we were loading the data properly.
So that was during the initial part of writing the code.
Yeah it's Liebert like that it's also common this hard because we have this particular statement which
is saying which user is browsing Diadems.
So we are good with that.
So next let's go ahead and create the new logic for marking as kid friendly
so fasting is it can be done a bookmark can be marked as kid friendly only by either editor or chief
editor.
So let's have that permission first.
We get type.
So if you recall we have this constant exporting class called user type.
OK.
So this is for our editor.
Let's do the same thing our chief editor
is this good user type
.
Next thing is the bookmark itself should be click friendly eligible.
So we have already written them at their ease get friendly eligible.
So let's put another condition here.
Just at the bookmark level.
Literally all of this court I'm sorry it has to be inside the for loop so because we are doing it at
an item level at each item level.
So this is where it has to go.
So as the user is making a decision on whether to bookmark or not then if the user is an editor or chief
editor then makes the next decision here.
OK so he's good friendly energy bill.
OK.
That's one thing.
And
let's go back here and look here and let's put together for this create Gager and center
.
So that's good.
So we want to do this.
Only if the current status is unknown.
OK if it has already been approved or rejected we don't have to do this.
So a user will said the paternally status only if the existing status is unknown.
OK.
So let's not use the kid friendly status constant exporting glass
.
UNKNOWN
OK now let's create a new method called Get geek friendly state as decision just like the baby had this
method get bookmarked position.
Similarly let's also get a map.
Let's also write a method called Get kid friendly state decision
and that's just by our boss.
Bookmark
this one also written Boullion and we would once again use randomisation here.
Actually here it reads a string not boolean.
Now we have three decisions.
One is either a prude and other one is rejected or the third one as user may not want to approve or
reject so uder might still decide to just skip that particular item or not market ask it friendly maybe
he wants to leave it to some other editor or he might want he or she might want to get a decision sometime
later.
So let's have three decisions here.
So first let's say it proved so once again that user Donati operator wine for food is less than wine
for let's recopy this year.
Then the user wants to prove it.
So if that if it is false if it is above point for here better than or equal 2.4 then let's have the
statement.
So the point of this logic is if it is less than one for then use it means that user wants to prove
it.
If it is greater than or equal to less and this has to be 0.4 and if it is less than point eight then
let's say that the user let's say user wants to either reject it.
So we just say you're currently
not rejected.
And if the value is about point eight greater than or equal 2.8 in which case we really would as unknown
.
So we have Nestor Donati operations here
and that's Control shift.
And so that's good.
Let's go back Unidas is a string
.
Now if the status is something other than unknown only then we want to set the status we want to update
the status in the bookmark.
So let's have this condition here
.
So only if it is not equal to unknown then we want to update the status.
So in this case it is a bookmark
that said between the students and let's have a six out statement here
.
So if it is if it is not equal to or known only then we are operating the paternally status and we are
printing the value here of the status value and also the bookmark and just to be clear.
So that's about it.
So let's just go ahead and run this class on launch.
There you go.
So let's just review the output here.
So loading data and then user is browsing items.
So users looking at the first item and he wants to book market which is of eyeblink.
So we are printing only those items which the user wants to bookmark so user is actually browsing all
15 items all 15 bookmarks that we how.
But these are the ones which the user is actually bookmarking So the randomization is telling us that
the user wants to bookmark it.
The randomization process I and I and the user can bookmark at most at most five bookmarks.
So that's the condition we have.
So this is the second user.
And for the third user we have a different output.
That's because this third user is actually an editor of one of the staff members so the user is bookmarking
.
And once this item is bookmarked then the user is also marking the bookmark as kid friendly in this
case it is approved.
And this is the actual bookmark.
The same bookmark has been the same item has been bookmarked also.
So they use it as both bookmarking and is also and is also marking the bookmark as kid friendly.
OK.
Now this is a second one.
And over here the user is doing the same thing and he also does approve.
In this case it is rejected.
The Big Mac has been rejected.
And here is a movie and in this case a movie has been bookmarked.
But they use it as not marking it as kid friendly or anything like that.
And here are some more items which are rejected and which are approved.
So we see this because there is no limit on the items that can be rejected are approved on the items
where the kid friendly status can be marked.
So there is no limit on that like the limit that we how far good for setting up for bookmarking an item
.
So that's it.
So those are the four users performing different actions.
Next we will look at the functionality for sharing of get friendly bookmarks with partner websites