Hi there.
This is the Rue.
Now, let's take a look at some best practice rules when it comes to using synchronization.
Many of the suggestions come from the effective Java book.
We already discussed this role, but it's very important.
And so let's discuss it one more time.
The rule is we need to use synchronization everywhere.
The shared mutable variable is used.
And we also looked at this bank account example involving John and Anita, whose threads share a single
bank account object.
We discuss the consequences when only make the doll method is synchronized but not the get balanced
method.
They said that John Thread may execute meg withdrawal method due to which there would be a new balance
amount.
However, Anita's thread, which subsequently accesses the get balance method, might still see the
old balance value as get balance was not synchronised.
So there is a lack of threat coordination.
And to avoid this scenario, we need to ensure that we are synchronizing every where the balance variable
is used.
So due to that, the get balance method has to be synchronized as we see here.
And here is another related rule that was already discussed but is included here just for the sake of
completeness.
The rule says use same lock when guarding the same shade mutable variable.
That is, do not guard a variable using one lock at one place and using some other lock at some other
place.
And here is the example that we used when discussing this rule.
So once again, it is the bank account example and we have the synchronized make withdrawal method.
And we also have another method called deposit, which uses a synchronized block and is guarding the
same balance variable as some deposit is being made.
Now the synchronized method make withdrawal, as we know, uses bank account objects lock.
That is the lock of the object on which the method has been invoked.
However, the deposit method is using a string object reference as the lock and that should not be done.
So two different locks are being used to guard the same variable which is being shared between the two
threads.
So the effect of synchronization is lost.
That is John and Anita Stretch can be using synchronized stuff concurrently and the outcome may not
be as desired.
Now, when we discuss this example earlier, we did not discuss memory visibility at that point of time.
At least the happens before relationship will not exist between the two actions that are using different
locks and the actions being invocation of make withdrawal and deposit by two different threats concurrently.
Due to this, it is likely to encounter the memory visibility issue.
Here is another rule which says If a method modifies a static field, you must synchronize access to
this field, even if method is typically used only by a single thread.
The thing to note here is your code may be accessing the static field from a single thread.
However, this is a static field and there will only be a single version per JVM.
And in a web application like environment, we may have tons of users accessing the system at the same
time, and the threads representing those users should have a consistent view of that static field.
So the static field is going to be accessible by all those different threads of the same static filter.
So even though the static field is being accessed from a single thread as per your design, the underlying
framework which is the web application environment, could still be multithreaded and hence we need
to be aware of that fact.
And so we should follow this rule.
And the next rule says synchronise only what is needed.
So it recommends keeping the synchronize blocks small.
That way we minimize the waiting time for other threats that are suspended due to the unavailability
of the lock.
Also, if there are any time consuming activities in your synchronize blocks, then you should see if
they can be moved out of the synchronized blocks, but without affecting their safety.
That's important.
Next rule is item 67 from affective Java, which says avoid excessive synchronization.
The reason is there are some costs associated with synchronization and let's review some of them.
First reason is threat suspension and resumption process, which is expensive, and we already know
about that.
And there is also some cost associated with lock acquisition and release too, although it is less expensive
than suspension and resumption.
Now with multiple threads sharing multiple data, we need to ensure that there is proper inter thread
coordination for consistent memory visibility.
So that would affect the performance to.
Over synchronization also limits GM's ability to perform code optimization.
We know that Git compiler plays a part in improving the performance at runtime.
And one of the things it does is refer to as hoisting.
For instance, you may recall this piece of code from the stop thread example during our discussion
on volatile variables.
The example was about the main thread stopping a second thread which had this wild loop, and the main
thread would try to stop the second thread by setting the stop variable to to stop as a mutable variable
shared between the two threads.
Now, in the absence of synchronization or the stop variable not being declared as volatile, this code
could be optimized in this way by the compiler, and this process is known as hoisting.
Here the variable stop is set to be hoisted out of the while loop.
A stop is not modified within the loop and moreover, due to lack of synchronization or since the variable
is not volatile, git compiler would simply assume that no other thread will also change its value,
so it would safely move the variable out of the loop and the resulting code will loop faster as there
is less work to be done.
So because we just have the literal true instead of the variable stop because of this, the second thread
would run forever, even if stop was set to true by the main thread.
And this kind of a situation is referred to as liveness failure, as the program is unable to make progress.
Note that such hoisting is almost certainly done on server farms that are typically installed on submissions
on client machines that we developers use.
We would install client JVM, that is the JDK, and they don't perform such kind of optimizations.
If you want client JVM to also perform such optimization, you can specify hyphen server option on the
command line when running JVM.
Finally, synchronization means civil access and hence we lose opportunities for parallelism in multicore
systems.
So not that we should be careful not to over synchronize.
Final tip is that if you're not sure whether to synchronize or not, then don't synchronize, but document
that the class is not that safe.
This way, if needed, clients can synchronize externally.
String buffer violated this guideline.
It was found that string buffer instances were mostly used by single threads.
That is, they are not shared across different threads.
However, the class uses synchronization internally wherever it is needed, and that affected the performance.
And this was the reason.
In Java five, string builder was introduced as a drop in replacement for string buffer.
String builder does not use any synchronization and hence is faster.
But if synchronization is needed, then you can go for string buffer.
So that's about it.
And we looked at some very important guidelines on using synchronization.
Thank you.