Hi there.
This is the rule.
We looked at generic types.
Now it's time to look at generic methods.
It's an important topic, and it's especially useful for implementing static utility methods, which
are very reusable.
In this lesson, we will look at everything related to generic methods and it's going to be a pretty
long lesson.
And the demo will actually be done in the follow up lesson where we will test most of the stuff we learn
in this lesson.
There is one entire excellent chapter dedicated to generics in the effective Java book.
We do cover many of the things from the chapter.
And if you're interested, you should definitely read it when you get a chance.
And one of the items is favor generic types.
And we already discussed some of the stuff from this item.
Generic types are appropriate for container type classes like the ones in collections API which can
store any kind of element.
That is, these classes are very generic.
In fact, all the collections framework classes we saw are gentrified.
Before generics was introduced, collections API classes were using object type as a polymorphic type
for storing elements.
That is, methods like ADD would use object type as the method parameter type.
And we know that that could lead to class cast exceptions at runtime.
So genetics helps us write safer code due to compile time type safety benefit that it gives.
So such classes are really very generic and hence if we happen to write such generic classes then we
should try to make them into generic types.
Similarly, we also have generic methods and there is also an item dedicated for it which says favour
generic methods like generic types.
These methods are very generic too.
We know that with generic types.
Client code has the flexibility to use different type arguments, right?
Similarly, generic methods also have their own type parameters and clients get the benefit of using
different type arguments.
Of course, we also get the compile time type safety benefit and the convenience of implicit class that
compiler inserts.
Now we know that if a method is static, it has no access to the enclosing class type parameter, right?
So if such a static method needs generic ness, then it needs to be made a generic method.
So both static as well as instance methods can be generic.
Static utility methods are particularly good candidates for generics.
For example, you can check out the utility class Java dot dot collections and you will see that majority
of its methods are generic methods.
And we know that these methods are utility methods that are very generic and hence are perfect candidates
for generic methods.
Like classes on interfaces, methods and also constructors can introduce their own type parameters.
And here is the syntax for generic methods.
So the type parameters are specified in angled brackets.
And as you can see, they can be used as variable types for method parameters.
But it's not just method parameters.
They can be used as type for local variables which are declared within the methods body.
And they can also be used as methods return type.
Not that my parameter list goes between the methods modifiers and the return type, so they come before
the methods return type.
Let's now look at a few examples of generic methods.
Here is one from the Java dot dot collection interface.
As you can see, both method, parameter as well as the return type are using the type parameter.
This is an instance method and we know that it returns an array containing all elements in the current
collection.
It basically acts as a bridge between collection and array.
And here is another example from the Java API.
It is a static utility method.
Replace all from the class java dot dot collections.
The earlier one was from java dot dot collection and this is from collections.
Here the type parameter is acting as a type argument for list in the first method parameter remaining
to method parameters.
Also use the type parameter and this method replaces all the occurrences of the old value within the
list with the specified new value.
As you can see, the method is generic and it doesn't matter what the element type of the list is.
So such kinds of methods should be implemented as generic methods.
In this example, we have the Class Generics demo, which has a type parameter T and the method go also
defines a type parameter with the same name T.
In this case, the method level type parameter overrides the class level type parameter when the method
is invoked and the blue font color here highlights that.
However, try to avoid using same type parameter names in this way as it can be very confusing.
We can also have this where both method level and class level type parameters are used.
The first method parameter uses method level type parameter, while the second one uses the class level
type parameter.
Not that we will get a compilation error if this method is a static method, because class level type
parameter cannot be used in a static context.
It can only be used with instances.
And here is an example where we have a bounded type parameter which we know places restrictions on what
can be passed or what can be returned if type parameter is used as a return type.
In this example, we have multiple bounds and note that everything we discussed about bounds for class
level type parameters apply for methods to.
For instance, if you have a class in the list of bounds, then it can be the only class in the list
of bounds, and it must be specified as the first bound to unrest have to be interfaces.
Also, the type argument must be the subtype of all bombs.
Shortly we will see how type argument will be passed to generic methods.
You can also have something like this where the method level type parameter P is extending the class
level type parameter E.
In this example.
The second type parameter is extending the first type parameter.
Note that generic methods or even generic constructors can exist whether or not the enclosing type is
generic.
So we looked at the syntax for declaring generic methods.
Now it's time to look at how we can invoke them.
Generic methods are invoked just like regular non generic methods.
Only additional thing is specifying the type argument as we are dealing with generics here.
We know that with generic types, parameters types include the type argument, but with generic methods,
type argument can be either automatically inferred by the compiler or they can also be explicitly specified
in the method invocation statement.
But most common way is to let the type arguments to be automatically inferred by the compiler.
And first, let's look at how this can be done.
Let's consider this method go, which has a type parameter T and T is also used as part of the method
parameter and also as the return type.
Now let's assume it is invoked in this way where it double is passed.
In this case, the type argument would be inferred as double.
Note that even though a primitive is parsed type argument, inferred would be the boxed primitive double.
Similarly, if we can work with a string type argument would be inferred as a string.
So as you can see, generic methods appear as infinitely overloaded.
Just note that type inference can happen in two places.
One is, of course here in generic methods and also in generic constructors and the other places when
we use diamond notation during instantiation of generic types.
And here is an example of that and we have been using it in our demos.
Diamond notation works only from Java seven onwards.
Now we know that type parameter can appear as methods in written type two.
So one question we can have is what if type parameter appears only in the return type, but not as part
of method parameter?
In such a case, compiler infers the type argument from the calling context, and let's see how that
works.
Here we have this method empty list from the collections class.
We have seen it in the Collections Framework chapter here.
The return type is list of three and the method does not have any parameters.
Now let's assume the method is invoked in this way.
Here, the return value is assigned to a list of string on compiler user set to infer the type argument
as a string.
Here.
The compiler is going to compare list of PT with list of string to deduce that the type argument is
string.
In this case, list of string is referred to as a target type.
Note that here, even if target type was collection of string, which is the super type of list, then
compiler would still be smart enough to infer the type argument as string.
Now, here is the example we saw earlier.
Now, let's say here we are working with a string, but the target type is a double.
Now, in this case, type argument inferred would be string.
As method parameter involves the type parameter.
So once again, only if method parameters do not include a type parameter, then the target type comes
into play.
In this case, we get a compiler error, and that's because the type argument inferred is string and
the compiler expects the return value to be string to.
As type parameter is also specified as the methods return type.
But the return value is being assigned to a double and so compiler gives an error.
So that's an example of compile time type safety benefit in a generic method.
Here's something more interesting.
Both the parameters and the return type use the type parameter.
And here is the method invocation statement.
First argument is a string, while the second is an ArrayList.
In this case, the type inferred will be the most specific common type among the two arguments.
In this case it would be realizable as both string and ArrayList implement see realizable.
Here target type is realizable, but if it is anything else other than realizable, then we would end
up with a compilation error.
So that's how type arguments are inferred.
Generally, type inference rules are very complex.
If type inference may not be what we expected, which is also possible in some very rare cases.
Then you can use explicit type arguments.
And now let's look at how we can explicitly specify type arguments.
Here we have the method.
Go inside the class generics demo.
And here we are creating an instance of genetics tomorrow and then we are invoking the method go and
explicitly specifying the type argument double.
So type argument comes after the dot operator and before the method name and needs to be in angled brackets.
Not that here.
The type argument is referred to as a type witness.
Now, if the method is in the same class, ought to be more precise, same object as the invoking code.
Then you should use this reference.
Now, without this reference, if you just have the type argument followed by method invocation, then
you get a compilation error.
If it was a non generic method, we can directly invoke the method, but that's not the case with generic
methods.
If you want to access an overridden method in the superclass, then you would need to use the super
keyword instead of this reference.
But for a regular inherited generic method, you would still use this reference.
Finally, if the method is static, then you would simply use the class name instead of the reference
variable.
This is required even if the method is in the same class.
So normally you can go with the first approach where the type arguments are automatically inferred.
But as mentioned earlier, only in some very rare cases where type inference may not be what you expected,
then you can go with explicit type argument specification.
Also, one last thing to note is that if you have a type parameter declared in the method, but if it
does not appear in either the method parameter list or the methods return type, then we can pass the
type argument explicitly.
As in this case, inference type argument is just not possible.
However, in this case, type parameter does not play any valuable role.
The reason is type parameters are mainly useful for client side code.
For instance, if return type is a type parameter, then compiler would insert an appropriate cast in
the invoking code.
Similarly, if the method parameters use type parameter, then the compiler ensures that we pass correct
arguments.
But if type parameter is not part of written type or the method parameters, then there is nothing to
be done on the client side except for passing the type argument explicitly.
And within the method type parameters are erased at runtime as they are replaced by either object type
or the first bone due to type erasure.
We also discussed Hyperledger earlier when discussing class level type parameters.
So we need to keep in mind that generics is a purely compile time concept.
So that's about generic methods.
A couple of very minor details, including generic constructors, were left out and they will be covered
in the follow up demo.
Generally constructors are similar to generic methods.
Also in the resources section, I included a link to a website which is considered one of the most authoritative
online sources on generics.
So you can check that out and probably bookmark it too.
Thank you and see you in the demo.