Earlier we briefly discussed about method tables and we see the method table is basically an array of
references to instance methods.
We said it will be used during invocation of instance methods.
Let's look at an example involving method tables and in the process we will also learn something very
interesting with regards to interfaces.
Let's consider this class structure where A is a class and is an interface.
B is a subclass of A while.
C is a subclass of both A and I.
It defines two methods.
One static method call static method and one instance method called fu.
Interface, I declares method bar.
Class B also defines another static method with the same name as in the superclass.
And it also defines one instance method called North.
Classy has two methods.
One is FU, which overrides the in class.
A second method is bar, which is simply an implementation of the interface method.
No.
Let's assume we have this class x with the method go, which has just one parameter which is of reference
type a.
Now in the first statement, the method for is invoked on the reference variable a.
But we know that the actual object, that variable references is not known until runtime as the method
can be invoked with an instance of A or B or C.
So until runtime we really do not know which version of method food would be invoked.
So obviously method table is needed for this as it will be consulted during runtime to determine the
target method to be executed.
So here are the three method tables.
At the top, we have the method table for Class A.
Since we said method table can be implemented as an array, we can see the index numbers displayed besides
the method table.
The element is basically a pointer to the actual method bytecode.
So in method table for a, the element is referencing the method code corresponding to method foo in
class a.
Let's assume that within the method table of a class JVM always stores references to superclass methods
before references to methods in its own class.
Moreover, four methods within the same class.
Let's also assume they are stored based on the order in which they appear in the class.
So if you look at Class B's method table, first element is referencing the inherited method for frame
class.
A second element is a method north.
Now for Class C, method four is the first element as it is still overriding the method for in superclass.
So this version of Method four would occupy the position of Ace method four in the method table.
So it still gets the presidents, even though Barr appears before full in the class.
Second element is the Barr method.
Going back to our first statement and method go.
If object in context is an instance of class C, then GM would look at C's method table and invoke C's
method foo, which is referenced from the index position zero.
Now, the interesting thing here is GM doesn't have to perform any search in the method table to perform
this invocation.
Four eight on full statement.
The runtime constant pool of Class X will have a direct reference to index number zero in the method
table.
Now, it doesn't matter what the target method table is.
It could belong to object A or B or C.
The reference to method four is always stored as index zero, irrespective of method tables.
That's because of the reference type is a class like Class A in this example.
Then the reference to method that is being invoked will always be stored in the same slot in the method
table, whether it is the method table of Class A or any of its subclasses.
In other words, it's because of the rule we discussed earlier where for a given class, JVM always
stores references to superclass methods before references to methods in its own class.
Due to this reference to foo is an index zero in both subclasses b and c.
Not the same does not apply if the reference type is an interface rather than a class.
So let's look at that.
Let's consider the scenario when Class A is actually an interface.
Then here is what we have.
Class B now implements Method Fool, which appears before method nor in the class file, and the same
is reflected in the method table of class B with foo appearing before north.
Nothing changed with C, but the method table did change.
We now have a bar appearing at zero position and that's because Method Barr appears before method four
in the class file.
Note that both methods in Class C are implementation methods declared in two different interfaces.
Now, when we consider method go, which now has interface as a reference type for the method parameter,
then the first statement can no longer have a reference to a fixed slot in the method table.
And Best Method table food reference is at index zero while in CS method table it is an index one.
So that's mainly because the reference type is an interface and the invoke method may appear anywhere
in the subclass of the interface.
So JVM now has to actually search the method table of the object to find the target method to invoke.
Due to this, invoking a method through an interface as a reference can be slightly slower than if the
reference is a class.
So that's an interesting fact.
But I think the slowness would be very minimal and is not something to be concerned of.
So we should still stick to what we learned from effective Java, where one of the items recommends
referring to objects by their interfaces.
No, the second statement in the method go is referencing the static method.
For this we do not need a method table as static methods are static.
That is a compile time itself.
We know where the method is and so the runtime constant pool would have a direct reference to static
method in class A.
So it doesn't matter what object is passed to method go.
Basically, method tables include only references to instance methods.
Also only concrete classes have method tables.
Even abstract classes do not have method tables as they cannot be instantiated.
So through this simple example, we have seen how method tables are structured, and we have seen how
method invocation happens when the type of the reference variable is a class or an interface.
And that's about it.
Thank you.