Hi there.
This is Andrew and welcome back.
Let's not get started with the project and let's implement the first feature, which is the Browse page,
which displays all the books that are not yet bookmarked by the user.
So let's do that.
But before doing that, I just want to import the books allow project into this workspace.
Now if you recall, the books allow project was created in a separate workspace and all our code and
this course has been under another workspace called JID.
So we now have two different workspaces.
And within the JID workspace we had these two projects, Demo and Trello.
So I think it would be nice if we also import that project.
Books allows other workspace and it had a project called Books and it would be nice to import that project
into this workspace.
That way we will have all of our code within this course under one workspace, which is the JID.
So let's go ahead and do that.
It's very simple.
Just click on file.
And click on import.
And here at the top, you have general and existing projects into workspace.
So let's click select that and next.
Select root directory.
Browse.
Click on c drive in my on my machine.
And books.
Aloha is here and within books.
Aloha Books.
Aloha is the workspace.
Within that we have the books project.
So let's click.
Okay, select that and click okay and just say finish and that's it.
So we have the books project now within this workspace, which is Jared.
So we are done with that part.
We have all our code under Jared now.
Now first thing.
So let's get started with our implementation, our extension.
The first thing that I want to do is add a new field called image underscore URL in the books table.
Now if you recall in the books along our project, we were displaying a couple of books and each book
also had an image and that image is coming from some URL within our Trello project.
So far we did not have any such image URL attribute in the database, but I think it will be nice to
show images.
It will be much more inspiring.
So let's go ahead and add an image URL field within the book table.
So let me open the database now.
I'm going to start.
And all programs here.
You'll see my SQL.
Click on that.
I click on my SQL Server and there is the command line utility open that.
Password is root for me and we need to use our database which is guide underscore Trello.
So the database is changed.
Let's see all the tables that we have.
So these are all the tables that we have created in the three year project.
And one of them is book.
So let's say the SC.
Book and I have already added this field here.
And it is a type one car.
That's it.
Let me show you the queries for that.
So in order to add the new column, we use an alter, a SQL query.
So it is added to table book add column image underscore URL and this is the data type and we want this
column to be added after the title column.
So that's why if you see here after title, we have image URL and then we want to update the rows.
Also there are five rows and this is the ID, so there are five books and for each of them we are setting
a different image.
So this file will be provided in the resources section.
So you can take this file and you can run these queries in your my SQL instance.
Now I'm going to provide all the code in the resources section.
And if you are if there are any issues, I might add the extension text regardless of whether it is
a JSP file or whether it is a Java file.
So if I have any trouble uploading the files with those extensions, I will put a dot extension.
And with that, there shouldn't be any problem in uploading into the resources section.
So when you download it, you just need to convert them back into either Java file or the JSP file.
You need to remove that dot extension.
So that's something.
Let's go back.
So we have added this image underscore URL.
Now let's create a new project for we have the three you, but we will create a new dynamic project.
So go into file because we are dealing with a web application, say dynamic web project.
Let's name it as three year web.
See you next.
Next, let's also select this one Web XML deployment descriptor.
That's it.
So that's generated and we have all the required layout.
And here are the Java resources.
Now we need to import our trillion.
So the trill you had just the Java code.
Now since we are web enabling it, we created a new dynamic web project.
But we need to copy all of this.
So select all of them and just copy, see, say control C and select this Z under Java resources.
Sorry, not here.
Here Java resources and we have source.
Now right click on this and just say paste.
Now, if you'll see, we have.
All of those packages are imported.
So that's that easy.
Now there is some compilation errors here.
Let me open this.
So that's because we need to import certain jar files.
We are using a third party jar file, so we need to import them.
So for that, let me click on little web and right click on properties.
Going to Java Belt path because we need to add those jars here, add external jars and my jars are here
and one of the folders on the desk.
So one of them is Commons here lang and the other one is minus Q all connected because we need to connect
to the database and this is the version that I was using.
Just say open and we are done with that piece, say apply.
And you can see that there are no compilation errors.
Now this has to go into the VAR file that we finally create.
So go into deployment assembly, say ADD.
And click on Java Build Path entries and see next.
And these are the two ones which we want to.
Push into the dot into the var file, say, apply and OC.
So if you're going to libraries here, we can see the two files that we just added.
So that's that.
So the first thing that we need to do is.
For this extension.
So we already created all our controllers.
So here we have our code and the controllers are here under comm semantics where three LEO controllers
click on this one and we have only one controller called bookmark controller.
So this we will convert into a servlet.
So we will go here.
And here, let's comment out this code.
This code right here at the top and this one tail here we are creating a single instance.
Now, we don't need this code because now we are using the Tomcat container.
Tomcat container will create a singleton instance of the servlet.
We know that, right?
It creates a single instance of the servlet.
So that's what Tomcat does.
So we don't need this.
So earlier we were manually doing this.
We have written this code.
So since Tomcat is going to do that for us, we don't need this.
Now let's say extents.
HTTP servlet.
So we need to put that.
Then let me open the books here.
Let's copy some code.
Here.
Also, we had a controller called my books.
Let's copy this annotation here.
Right.
Let me copy it here.
And let's call this as bookmark.
Instead of calling it as my books, we will call it as bookmark.
And let's also copy some more code.
Let's add the default constructor.
So let's copy this.
The name has to be bookmarked controller, so let's replace that.
So the container will create an instance of this and will initialize it by calling the init method.
All right.
And there is the do get method.
Let me just copy all of this here.
And that's all we need from this because it do get is going to overwrite the do get in the.
In the HTTP servlet.
So we don't need any of this.
So let me remove that say control.
S Now we have compilation errors and that's because we need the servlet API jar file.
So we need to import that.
Also once again, let's click on your web, right click.
Properties go into Java build path here, add external jars.
And the.
Rafael is not here.
It's.
For me.
It's here.
Going to in Tomcat.
Going to lib and within lib I have the servlet API open.
Apply.
And going to deployment assembly ad.
Java Belle Path entries next.
Pushed us into libraries.
Apply OC and.
All these, they just got automatically imported.
Control shift or.
That's it.
So we have imported all the files and we don't have any other issues here.
So this is the the controller, which is which has been converted into servlet.
Now let's go into our.
Let's not worry about this because we have commented out some code in bookmarked controller, so that's
why it is showing some error in view Java.
But let's not worry if Java is not important for us, so let's just lose that and close it.
And so we added the image underscore URL and the in the book table.
So we all we also have within entities we have this package called entities we have the Java.
So here we need to.
Art a field called image URL.
So let me add that.
Let me put it here.
In database it is image underscore URL.
But here this is the convention that we use and let's put a getter and setter.
All right, so we have got to run setters.
So that's what the book class.
Now, let's go back to our bookmark controller.
And let's go ahead and fetch the books from the database.
And we need to fetch all those books which are not yet bookmarked by a particular user.
So in this case, what we will do, what we will do is we will use one user.
There are a bunch of users, five users.
Let me run this query select star from user, put a slash here and a G so that it will display the results
in this way in rows.
So each user is displayed in this way if you put a slash g so this is first row, this is second row.
Let's pick this final user user for semantic square dot com.
It belongs to my account, Drew.
So let's do that.
So the ID for that is five, so we will use that.
So we are going to hardcore the ID here and show the results, which is nothing but the books that are
not yet bookmarked by this particular user.
And later, we will generalize it when we have the log in functionality.
All right.
So let's go here and let's write a method called get books and we can write it in bookmark manager in
the DAO it goes in the DAO.
But first we have to invoke the manager layer.
Dot get instance it will return an instance of that bookmark manager is also a single turn.
And let's say we'll call it us books.
Get books and we will have two fields.
One will take a Boolean value boolean and we will see why that's the case and the other one will take
the ID.
So the ID user ID is five.
So let's do that and let's auto create this.
Okay.
And it should written a collection of.
Books, but bookmark is a super type of book, so we will have it as a collection.
Control of core, and the set written now of instance is already here.
There is a bookmarked instance which is already created.
So we need to.
Call a method with the same name.
Let's make this long.
Because it is long.
Let's call it ID and let's rename this to.
If he had the code here.
Let's call it as is marked.
He's bookmarked and let's just pass the same values.
Okay.
Now this method is not there.
So let's create that using the automatic feature.
This is it.
And let me just go ahead and copy this code.
That is some code and it is very easy to follow.
So let me just copy this whole thing.
And we will look at the code.
Okay.
Here it is.
Now this code.
Is.
If you're going to data store, which we will not be needing anymore because we have the layer.
So here for the books there is this.
Method called load books.
So we are just using most of this code from here.
So it is selecting the books and it is adding it to some list here in this case.
And we are getting all of the individual values from each row and we have this code.
So I just copied this code.
That's what I did.
And here in bookmark, that's what we are doing now.
But here the you may recall this particular piece of code.
So in order to connect to the database, we need the driver, the ABC driver.
So this is what is going to load the driver and it would be registered with the ABC API with a class
called driver manager.
And so that's the point.
Without that this will not work.
So we need that code and we have seen it in the in the database section and we need this connection
and this is the URL to the to connect to the database we are using this guide underscore Trello and
this is the username and password and we have, we have the statement called Connect Create Statement
and this is a private resources statement and this is the query that we are going to use.
There is the spot part we will look at it in the next lecture.
Now is bookmarked is false.
We are passing false in the controller here write false.
It means that is bookmarked is false, which means we need those books that are not yet bookmarked and
we are also passing the ID five.
So we want to get all the books that are not yet bookmarked by this particular user with the ID file.
That's it.
And so for that, we have this nested query.
So this is a select query, but it is a nested query because there is also another query right here.
So this one will fetch all the books that this particular user has.
This particular user has already bookmarked.
So this we are saying we are joining two tables user and user underscore book and we are saying that
get me all the books by this user where we are saying you don't ID user has this name as this alias
you.
So we are saying where you ID is equal to user ID, user ID is what is passed.
Here.
Let's call it as user ID.
Here in this case.
Okay.
And.
That's what we are saying here.
Okay.
So this will give us all the books that this particular user has bookmarked.
So we are saying you get all the book ideas from user, comma, user underscore book, user underscore
book has the association between the users and the books that they have saved.
And we are saying that we need the books that this particular user has bookmarked has saved, and the
join condition is you ID, which is the user ID and user underscore book also has user underscore ID.
So that's what it is and you can look at it later.
So this is essentially giving us all the book IDs that this particular user has already saved, but
we need all the books that are not saved.
So for that, we have this outer query which is getting all the books, and there are a bunch of tables
that we are using in order to get all of the information, like author book, underscore, author,
book, underscore, author has the relationship between book and author.
And we're.
And we want to ensure that the books so we have certain books and those ideas should not be in this.
So we are removing all of these IDs.
We are removing all of these IDs.
So we are first getting all the IDs, all the books saved by this user, and we are removing them from
all of the books that we have in the system.
So that way we get only those books which are not yet saved by the user.
And that's it.
And here we have results said let me say control shift or.
And it's compiling.
Fine.
And we are getting ID.
Title publication here for the publisher.
I have commented it out because in datastore we in that particular query we were also getting publisher
details, but we don't have to display publisher details here, at least for this particular web page.
And that's it.
And here we are.
Creating an instance of book.
Okay.
So first thing here is we are we created also.
This thing.
This is the result which will hold the all the books.
So it's an ArrayList.
You can take a look at the code later.
But each row is being iterated here.
We know that the Y loop and we are creating a book instance by calling this method called create book,
which we have already written in the bookmark manager.
But since we have.
Introduced a new field called image URL here.
But the create book does not have a URL yet, so we need to add that method parameter image URL is a
new field that we added.
And similarly, even in the query also here, I added the image underscore URL.
So this was missing in the data store class as image underscore URL is something which we added in this
lecture.
So let's go here.
And to create book.
So we are passing a new field.
And the third field was.
String.
Image your order.
That's it.
And we need to set it in the book.
In the book, we already added a field for this set.
Image URL.
Here it is.
And that's it.
So.
So let's take this.
And bookmark manager as this.
Okay.
And go back into bookmark controller.
And here we'll say this and let's call the variable as.
List.
And we need to pass it to the GSP file, which we are going to implement.
So let's say request dot set attribute.
Let's call it as list.
Get request dispatcher.
And let's pass.
Browse Dot JSP.
Okay.
So we are getting a request dispatcher for this and we need to forward it to this.
So we'll just say forward.
Response.
So this is what we have.
So we are fetching the books from the our model and we are forwarding it to The View.
Now let's go ahead and create this file called Browser JSP.
So let's just click on your web.
And right click new say JSP file.
Call it as browse.
And hit next and let it create a default.
And I have already created this file, so let's go here.
Browse JSP.
It's very similar to the file that we have created and.
The Books Aloha Project.
I just used that code.
It just has few additional fields.
That's it.
So let's go back and see control a control V set.
Let's look at what we have here.
So everything else is same.
I just changed the name from books.
Hello to tell you in the title and body.
Here it is just the same.
We just need to import one other file for GSD.
So here we are iterating through all the books.
So books is the.
The attribute that we are setting here, box here and.
All we are doing is we are iterating through them.
We are displaying the image IRL.
If you recall, we were displaying image URL and books, aloha to and for authors.
There can be multiple authors, but let's just display only one of them.
So authors is an array.
So let me go back to Java.
So as you can see, authors is array, but let's display only the first author, so that should be fine.
And I introduced a new field here called publication rating is already there as on rating and we have
a field called book publication here.
So this is a new field that we are showing in the UI and then we have this anchor tag for sale.
If you recall, there was a save link.
So we have this for now.
The URL is empty.
We will fill it in the next lecture.
So that's it.
And this style tags will are about the style.
It will tell us what the font size should be and what the color should be.
And we are saying the font weight has to be bold.
And which means that it will be in bold.
And that's it.
So these are some style tags that we are using.
It's a style tag and any of the HTML tags can have that.
So that's about it.
So this is also done and all we need to do is just import GST.
So once again, let's go back into three little web and go into properties.
Going to build part.
Our external czars.
So here.
I need to go.
GSD.
This is it.
Hi.
Going to deployment assembly ad.
Joel.
Build batteries and add this new one.
Finish, apply and go.
Okay.
That's it.
So now let's create the var file.
So remember right click on this export.
Rafael.
Live Oak.
And then we go into.
I hope you can directly create in web apps.
Let's try that through your website where save finish.
That's.
Leo Webb.
So through Leo Webb was created here and it unpacked and it created a new web application because my
server is already running.
So let me go back.
So let me call this as Leo.
Web slash bookmark was the URL pattern.
That's it.
So it shows all the books that are not yet saved by this user.
So that's the first feature.
And next we will also implement the bookmarking functionality as well as the My Books link, which will
show all the books that are saved by this user.
So that way we'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you and happy coding.