Hello there.
This is the LA.
And welcome back.
So we looked at the primitive data types that represent numbers that is both whole as well as real numbers
for whole numbers.
We had the integer data types byte short and and long while for real numbers we had float and double.
So we looked at six primitive types so far.
And now let's look at the primitive data type that represents characters.
Sometimes we would like our variables to hold single letter characters like an alphabet or a digit,
like zero or a special symbol like dollar.
Note that we are talking about single letter characters and not multiple characters.
For multiple characters you would use a string.
But string is not a primitive data type and is a class that comes with the Java library, as I mentioned
earlier, and we will look at strings later.
So if you want your variable to hold a single character, then in Java you would declare such a variable
with a card data type.
And here is an example.
Here we are declaring a car variable named degree and we are initializing it with a car literal b b
can be for bachelor's degree.
It cultural includes single codes and we would get a compiler error if we omit the codes or if we have
multiple characters within the codes.
So this is how you declare a car variable and it is as simple as this.
But there is a lot more to car data type and let's get a good solid understanding of the car data type.
So though we are dealing with characters internally, Java users 16 bit unsigned integer scheme to represent
characters.
And unsigned integers represent zero on positive integers, but not negative integers.
So essentially characters are integers internally.
For instance, the car will be here, will be stored as the integer 66.
And soon we will see how this mapping happens.
And here is more information.
So bit depth is 16 bits.
That is a car value will be represented in 16 bits.
And because car is internally a 16 bit unsigned integer, the range will be 0 to 2 to the power of 16
minus one that is 0 to 65000 535.
You need to memorize that at is 65,000 535.
Note that here two is raised to the power of 16 and not 15, like in the case of integer data types.
As here we are dealing with unsigned integers which do not include negative numbers.
In other words, we do not need any special sign.
But as with the integer data types, with integer data types, we need a sign bit to distinguish positive
and negative numbers.
So here, since we do not have negative numbers, we do not need a sign.
So with unsigned integers, all of the bits together represent the magnitude.
Recall that with signed integers, the bits following the sign that represent the magnitude.
So it means that we can represent as many as two to the power of 16 characters in Java.
That is 65,536 characters.
So a car variable can take any of those 65,000, five, 36 characters and the corresponding integer
value will be stored internally like in the memory.
Like 6 to 6 for the character b.
And if you're wondering what makes up all those 65,000, five, 36 characters, because in English,
all we have is the characters A to Z.
And of course, they can be represented in uppercase as well as lowercase.
And we have the digits 029 and few special symbols.
So what makes up all of these 65,000, five, 36 characters?
We need to remember that we have many languages in this world and each of those languages has many characters.
Right?
Each of those languages has an alphabet.
So B how many characters to represent?
For instance, we should be able to represent a character such as this one, which is from one of the
Indian languages, or even an emoji symbol like Tears of Joy.
And we know that we have many such symbols.
So we need to be able to represent such kind of characters to.
And so there is a mapping between characters and the corresponding integer values that gets stored internally.
And this mapping is defined by the Unicode character set.
So Unicode is a standard character set like ASCII, but can represent all characters in all languages
across the world.
And it can represent all those exotic symbols too.
And it does so by associating every character with a hexadecimal number called code point.
It's called a code point.
And that hexadecimal number maps to some integer value, which is what is stored internally in binary
format.
But Unicode is a standard specification and it can have different implementations.
And Java uses one such implementation called UTF 16, and such an implementation is referred to as an
encoding scheme.
Languages like C Sharp and Python also use of 16 four string characters and there are other encoding
schemes to like UTF eight and UTF 32.
And these schemes vary in the storage space they use.
For instance, UTF 16 might use 16 bits for a particular character, while UTF eight might use only
eight bits for the same character.
So Unicode is a character set and YouTube 16 is the encoding scheme that Java uses and 16 also defines
hexadecimal numbers like Unicode, and for most characters it uses the same hexadecimal numbers as Unicode.
So in Java, every valid collateral is encoded as a UTF 16 hexadecimal number.
For instance, the collateral B would be encoded as UTF 16 hexadecimal number 0042 and its corresponding
16 bit unsigned integer is what gets stored internally.
So here we can see the binary format of the unsigned integer and here the letter four in the hexadecimal
number corresponds to 0100 in the binary format and two corresponds to 0010.
So that's the benefit of hexadecimal numbers.
It can be easily mapped to the binary format.
And this 16 bit unsigned integer corresponds to the decimal value 66.
So that's how the character letter B is mapped to 66, as I mentioned earlier.
So for every character you can imagine such a tuple.
Here we have the character Uppercase B and it is associated with UTF 16 hexadecimal number 0042 and
also decimal 6 to 6.
The binary equivalent of 66 is what is stored internally.
But note that both hexadecimal numbers 004, two and 66 correspond to the same binary number.
In fact, the car variable degree can also be directly assigned such a hexadecimal number.
That is, we can assign a literal such as this one, and this is called as Unicode escape sequence where
we have a backslash followed by U, followed by the hexadecimal number 42 U here stands for Unicode
and it needs to be in lowercase.
Otherwise we get a compiler error.
So this is same as assigning the cultural uppercase.
B Typically you would use characters for variable initialization, but sometimes if you have to represent
certain special characters and if your editor does not support them, then you can use such a Unicode
escape sequence for initialization.
Now here in our table, the default value for cash is Unicode number zero, which represents a non character.
And here also we can see the escape sequence and another character is a control character, meaning
it is not something that you can print.
Now in input output.
Chapter one of the first lectures gives a very detailed introduction to character encoding.
In fact, it's a prerequisite lecture for that section.
So if you are not familiar with encoding, you can learn about it when you get there.
And you can also check out the article I mentioned about in one of the previous lectures, and the link
was given in the resources section.
And that article discusses about the internal data representation schemes like sign to complement and
replace 754 format and it also discusses about the character encoding.
Now let's go ahead and extend our student class with a variable.
Okay.
Here is our student class and we already have these different variables.
So let's go ahead and introduce a new variable called degree, which would be of type car.
So car degree and let's initialize it with the car literal B where we can be for bachelors.
So the student is a bachelor student.
So let's also print the degree here.
And let's compile and execute it.
So we need to be in our basics directory, which has this file.
So it prints the degree b.
Now let's go ahead and try certain invalid initialization.
So first thing, let's remove this.
Now the compiler will think that this is a variable, but a variable B is not there.
So it will give us a compilation error.
So let's recompile it.
As you can see, it says it cannot find the symbol.
Right.
Because B is not a variable that is declared anywhere here.
So we need to have single codes here.
That's a requirement.
And we cannot also have multiple characters.
So this is also invalid.
Okay.
So a complaints about that.
Also, it cannot be empty like this.
It's just empty character, literal.
So that's not allowed, although you can have an empty space here.
So let me.
Clear up the screen.
That is good.
If you run it, it just prints empty here.
So this is good.
Now.
So that's the LATRELL And we also discussed about the unique chord escape sequence.
We said that the car literal Uppercase B can also be represented in this way.
0042.
And this will also print.
The car be.
As you can see, because this Unicode number corresponds to the uppercase character B and UTF 16.
So we are printing this.
And we also said that this needs to be in lowercase.
So if you have uppercase, then it we get a compiler error.
Similarly, this needs to be a valid hexadecimal number.
So this is called as a code point, it's called as a code point in Unicode specification and UTF 16.
We just call it as a code unit.
That's just for your information.
So if we compile, so it gives us an error.
So it needs to be a valid number here.
Now the default value is a null character.
Right.
Default value for care is null.
So unless something that we cannot print.
So let's also.
Do that.
If we run it, you can see it just doesn't print anything.
So that's the null character, which is the Unicode number zero.
It is same as this, as initializing in this way.
But generally we have a car variable.
Generally we would initialize it for INT and other variables.
We may have default initialization, but generally I haven't seen car variables getting a default value.
Generally we will assign some value to it.
So that's how it is in practice, at least from what I have seen.
Now the next thing is, you may recall that we talked about boxed primitives when discussing integer
data types.
I said that every primitive type also has an associated box primitive for it.
We looked at the integer class.
It's also called as a wrapper class and box parameters will be discussed later.
But we saw that for four int we had the integer class and integer class defined both main value as well
as max value.
Similarly for car there is this class called character, so it is the boxed primitive class or the wrapper
class.
So let me also show you that particular class here.
So here it is.
This is my Eclipse editor.
So here this is a character class and it is defining the main value and it is defining as this the Unicode
number zero.
So this is the Unicode escape sequence and it is the Unicode number zero.
And for max value it is displaying this we have this value for EPS.
And so that's just for your information.
But we will discuss the boxed primitive classes later on in a different section.
Now, finally, I just want to show you one site called as Unicode hyphen Babble.com.
So it's a table of all the Unicode mappings, it has all of those mappings.
So this is just for your information, so you can also explore it.
So if we scroll down here, we can see all of these different characters.
For example, here we have the null character.
So when I hover over it, it says that this is the null character.
U plus here indicates Unicode.
So it's an uppercase U and this is Unicode.
And in the in the lecture we have seen that it is backward slash followed by U that's for the up 16.
But in Unicode this is the notation that they use U plus and it has a number zero and the decimal also
is being shown there that the decimal is zero.
Now for B here it says zero zero for two and the decimal 66.
Right.
That's what we have seen.
And for a it will be one less which is zero zero for one and the symbol 65 and for C, it's going to
be the hexadecimal number 43.
So that's called as the code point and the decimal is 67.
So these are all the uppercase alphabets and we can also see the lowercase versions here and each of
them has the tuple, right, the character, the Unicode as well as the decimal equivalent.
Now if you scroll down, you can also see all other.
Characters from other languages too.
So you can see it here.
Also, it's changing.
It says what we are looking at at that instance.
So if you click on that, if you click on this, it shows all of the different.
Languages, for example, Bengali, Gujarati.
So these are all the Indian languages, so you can scroll down.
So all you have to do is just scroll down and you can see the different characters and the associated
hexadecimal numbers as well as the decimal numbers.
So that's just for your information.
So and that is at Unicode hyphen table dot com.
And you can also explore it.
And in the next lecture, we will see how a cat variable can be assigned in a letter to.
So that's also possible.
That's very uncommon, but we will also check that out.
So that's about it for now.
Thank you and see you in the next lecture.