Hi there.
This is the Motley Crew.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at garbage collection.
When we create an object using the new keyword, JVM determines the amount of heap memory needed for
storing that object, and it allocates that much amount of memory.
But as more and more objects get created, then it would also result in allocating more memory.
If we keep creating objects this way, eventually we may run out of memory and we will get errors like
out of memory error.
So there's a need to also release or reclaim memory when objects are no longer required.
That's a very important aspect of memory management.
And in Java, it is taken care of automatically by the garbage collector.
Since we are talking about objects which we know are stored on heap, our focus for the next few lectures
will be on heap memory and how garbage collector manipulates this area.
Garbage collection is one of the most important benefits of Java and we will look at the different garbage
collection algorithms that can be used.
At the end, we will also see how we can tune heap memory size.
So it's going to be an interesting set of lectures and we will try to get a solid understanding of how
garbage collection works.
In languages like C or C++, a programmer has to explicitly allocate memory when creating objects.
And similarly, when those objects are not needed anymore, they have to explicitly free up the space
taken by those objects.
So programmers are explicitly manipulating memory.
That would certainly help in developing efficient applications.
But in large projects, if such memory manipulation is not done right, then it could result in serious
issues like crushing the program or programs working incorrectly.
When we say memory manipulation is not done right, it means that memory is corrupted in some way.
It seems that nearly 10% of application crashes on Windows Systems are due to memory corruption.
Let's now look at a couple of ways in which memory can be corrupted.
We will look at two of them, although there can be more ways of corrupting memory.
First one is memory leak.
Memory leaks happen when unused objects are never freed.
For example, you may have an object reference pointing to an object and that reference is later assigned
a new object.
So the old object does not have an active reference and we can refer to it as a dead or an abandoned
object.
Now, if the space occupied by this abandoned object is not freed, then that would be a memory leak.
And if such memory leaks happen regularly, then we know that we may eventually run out of memory and
our program would then simply stop working.
If our program runs only for a short while with few memory leaks, then we may be fine.
And we may never even know that there is a memory leak.
But for long running programs like web applications, it could turn out to be a very serious issue.
Another type of error is dangling reference, which is basically a reference to an area of memory that
has already been reclaimed.
For example, let's consider two separate components which are sharing the same object.
Now, if one of the components is done using that object, then it may free up the memory occupied by
that object.
And that piece of memory might get allocated to a new object.
But the second component would still be referencing the same memory location, assuming that the dead
object is still there.
Since it is now a different object which is occupying that space.
The second component will most certainly behave in an unpredictable manner.
So that's a dangling reference.
One way to avoid such memory corruption errors is by restricting programmers from manipulating memory.
And Java achieves this through automatic or implicit memory management, which is one of its main benefits
or a language like C++ on Java does this through a process called Garbage Collection, which is performed
by a giant component called Garbage Collector.
Instead of programmers, garbage collector or GC, in short, basically reclaims memory occupied by
dead objects.
By doing so, it is ensuring that there are no memory leaks, so that dead objects basically represent
garbage which needs to be reclaimed.
But it also needs to make sure that a dead object is really a dead object.
That is, it needs to be 100% sure that there are no active references to that particular object.
Otherwise, we could end up with a dangling reference situation.
So JSI ensures that there are no dangling references to or in other words, it ensures that an object
with at least one reference is never reclaimed.
So Garbage Collector automatically prevents both types of errors that can cut up memory.
So programmer doesn't have to deal with such things, thus improving his or her productivity.
So in Java, programmers create objects.
We are the new keyword on JVM allocates the necessary memory.
But reclaiming objects will be done by garbage collector.
Just not referencing an object anymore qualifies that object as an abandoned object, making it eligible
for garbage collection.
Of course, we are assuming that the object has no other active references to.
Let's look at few ways in which objects become abandoned.
An object would be considered abandoned if it goes out of scope.
Here.
As soon as the method returns, the book object is considered abandoned and will be eligible for garbage
collection.
That is, it would still be on the heap until GC actually reclaims it.
An object would be abandoned if its reference is assigned some other object.
Or if the reference is assigned a null value.
So these are three ways in which an object becomes eligible for garbage collection.
Not that even a class object that is an instance of Java class.
If it does not have any active references, it will also be eligible for garbage collection.
Let's now look at a few specifics about Jesse.
GC may be implemented as part of the language itself, as in the case of Java, or it may be an add
on library too, which would be the case for other languages which rely on manual memory management.
It also runs in background in a low priority thread, so it is always there alive and gets into action
whenever there is a shortage of memory.
And there's also no guarantee when GC runs on, programmers have little control on when it would run.
It usually runs when there is limited memory, but the exact timing is unpredictable.
Now we can give a hint to GM that it may run GC by either of these approaches.
One is by invoking GC method in the system class or by invoking GC method via the get runtime method
in the runtime class.
Both system and runtime belong to Java Lang package and goal of both these approaches is just the same.
It is just that system point GC provides a more convenient way to do it.
But this is simply a hint.
And GM may ignore the signal too.
So you should never rely on this manual approach to invoke the GC and you should let GM take care of
it.
GC basically is a pretty complex task and every time it runs, it does take time and resources of its
own.
Each run is referred to as a GC cycle and it can cause pauses in the application.
And these pauses can be of varying duration, depending on the GC algorithm being used.
If application comes to a complete pause, then it would be called as Stop the World Boss.
Later we will see a technique called generational collection, which is used by GC to reduce POS times.
So that's a very brief introduction to garbage collection.
It basically ensures that memory is not corrupted.
It relieves the programmer from explicitly manipulating memory, and so it improves programmers productivity.
So automatic memory management is a huge benefit that comes with Java and it makes programming in Java
easier and safer too.
Thank you.