Hello there.
This is the De La Rue.
And welcome back.
In the last lecture, we have seen how a car variable can be declared.
And we have seen that a car variable can be initialized using a calculator.
So that's the typical way of initializing a car variable.
We have also seen that a car variable can be initialized using an Unicode escape sequence, although
that is not very common.
Now a car variable can also be initialized using an integer.
We know that a car variable value is internally represented using unsigned integer scheme.
Now Java also allows us to assign an unsigned integer to a car variable.
So that's also possible.
But we know that unsigned integer has the range 0 to 65000 535.
So we can assign any value in that range to a car variable.
So we can do that.
But that is very uncommon.
So let's go ahead and see what happens if we do that.
So let's head over to our Basics Demo class, and we already have this primitives method.
So let's write a few statements here.
So let's define a few variables here.
We already have these different variables where we initialized eight variables using some integrators
but of different formats.
Here is the hexadecimal, binary, and the octal.
So let's just do the same thing.
Let's declare a variable called car and let's call it as car end.
Here, this value corresponds to 65.
So here what we will do is let's use the same value, 65.
Let me also declare a few more variations, because the literal 65 can also be represented using these
different variations.
So let's call it us car hex here.
We call it US and Hex and here let's call it as car hex and let's use the same number here.
So we know that this translates to 65.
And let's also show for.
The binary for the binary version.
Let's call it a car binary and let's use the same value here.
And this also we know maps to 65.
Right.
And let's print them.
Okay.
Let's copy these names.
So the primitives method is invoked from the main method.
So let's go ahead and just compile and execute it.
So we need to be in the basics directory because that's where the basics demo class is.
Here we are printing the eight variables, which is from the last demo, previous demo, one of the
previous demos.
And here we are displaying the car variables which we just declared.
So as you can see in all of these statements, it is printing the value a the character A because in
UTF 16, the decimal 65 corresponds to the uppercase a uppercase letter.
A So in the last lecture we have used the character B which maps to 66 but 65.
The previous one maps to the character a uppercase a.
And same goes with this one hexadecimal number 41.
Here it maps to 65 and 65 corresponds to character a n of 16.
So that's why all of these three values here are printing the the character A and that's just because
that data type is car here.
Now, let me also make this minus one.
So what would it do?
It gives us a compilation error, says incompatible types because we are trying to assign this end to
car and this range is outside of 0 to 65000 535.
So that's the thing.
Now if you assign 65,000 536, once again, you would get the same compilation error.
Because of this, an out of range assignment.
So that's what it is.
And if you assign zero, it means it's a null character and it will not print anything.
And let me here, let me also assign let's do the reverse, which is let's call it as in car and let's
assign a car value here.
E So what do you think it would print here?
Because the type is not on the left side.
Because the type is ENT, it's got to print.
The corresponding decimal value, right?
So we are calling it as a car.
It's an end data type and it should print the decimal 65.
Here.
65.
So if you're assigning a car literal, it is to an end.
It presents the corresponding end value of 16.
And if you assign an intellectual to a car data type to a car variable, then it prints the corresponding
UTF 16 character value.
So an integer we know can be assigned to bite short and long, so it can also be assigned to care.
But this is very uncommon.
But we need to be aware of this.
So we have seen that a car variable can be initialized with an character which is the most common case.
It can also be initialized with a Unicode escape sequence, or it can also be initialized using an integer.
So that's the thing.
And internally it is stored as an unsigned integer whose range is 0 to 65000 535.
And you need to memorize that.
So that's all there is to car data type.
Thank you and I will see you in the next lecture.
Happy coding.