Hi there.
This is Dana.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at matching operations.
In the subsequent lecture, we will look at finding operations.
And we know that both matching and finding operations are terminal operations.
Earlier, we looked at slicing operations, which were intermediate operations, and we know that intermediate
operations, return stream objects and terminal operations do not return stream objects, but they can
return other types of values.
So matching operations are about matching stream elements to some criteria.
And if it matches the criteria, then a boolean value will be returned.
So under matching we are going to look at three operations called any match, all match and none match.
And next, we will look at finding operations in the subsequent lecture.
And it has two operations and all matching and finding operations plus the limit operation are short
circuit operations, which means that if certain condition is met, then all of the subsequent stream
elements will not be processed.
For instance, with limit if it is limit of three, we know that only the three elements, only three
elements will be processed from the stream and the rest of the elements will not be processed.
Same happens with matching on finding operations to.
So if certain condition is met, then all of the stream elements that come after the condition is met
will not be processed.
Only the elements until then will be processed.
And we also know that in core Java we have and and or operations which are short circuit operations
with.
And if the left condition is false, then the right condition will not be evaluated.
Similarly with R, we know that if the left condition is true, then the right condition will not be
evaluated.
Right?
So that's the short circuit operations.
So let's go ahead and look at match operations.
So a template method has been written here and we have this we know that all of the we have this books
array list and the books from both Amazon and Barnes and Noble are accumulated into this books list.
So we are just going to pass the same books array list to the match function to the match method.
So earlier we passed it to the slice method.
So let's look at the match method.
And as I mentioned, there are three methods within match which we are going to implement and we are
going to use three examples scenarios to implement those methods so that we can better understand them.
So let's look at the three queries, example queries that we have and each of the operations that we
are going to implement will implement one of these queries.
So the first query is, is there at least one highly rated book among the list of input books, which
is inexpensive and highly rated, implies the rating has to be at least 4.8.
And when we say inexpensive, it should be less than or equal to 50 bucks.
So we are looking for inexpensive but highly rated book.
And if at least one of the stream elements matches this criteria, then we have to return it.
True.
So that's the thing we have.
So for that, we need any match.
So what we are going to do is we have the books list.
So we need to invoke the Street method.
To start our pipeline.
Then we are going to invoke this any match method which takes a predicate.
And to the predicate we are going to pass our criteria.
So let's give our lambda.
First, the rating has to be greater than or equal to 4.8.
And the price has to be less than or equal to 50.
Let's assign it to a boolean value.
Let's go ahead and print this.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and run this.
And it returns a true value because there is at least one of them which is matching that.
So as soon as that condition is met, as soon as that stream element matches this particular condition,
then it returns a true and none of the subsequent elements are processed.
So that's the short circuit ness.
Now, let's look at the second one.
It says, Do all the books have a rating greater than or equal to 4.8?
So we have this list of books and we're asking if all of the books are highly rated books, and for
that we can use all match.
So let's just take this.
Take this.
And let's assign to a new variable called All Match.
So let's print this.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and run it.
So it returns a false because there are certain books which have different rating, lower rating.
Here we are.
So there are certain books which have lower rating.
So this condition would fail.
So we are saying if all of the books the condition is if all of the books meets this particular criteria,
then we have to return it.
True.
So that's not the case.
Now here there's a third one is check if none of the books have bad rating.
Okay.
So we have this list of books and what we want to know as if none of the books have bad rating.
So all of the books should have a rating greater than or equal to 2.0.
So for that, we can use another method called non match.
So let me just take this.
So if none of the books match this criteria, then it would be written.
That's what this method does.
But if at least one of the books has has a rating less than or equal to 2.0, then it would return a
false.
So none of the books should have this rating.
All of them should be greater than 2.0.
So that's what this condition is.
So let's execute this and it returns it.
True.
And that's because all of the ratings that we have here are greater than 2.0.
So that is about the three different methods that we have.
So they are very simple.
Now, just note that we can also express this in a different way.
So instead of all match, we can also say.
None match.
You can also have it this way.
So we are saying none of the input elements should have a rating less than 44.8, which means all of
them should have a rating greater than or equal to 4.8.
So it's just a different way of expressing it.
But I think this is a little bit more clear when we say all match.
Because here we are saying that do all the books have a rating greater than or equal to 4.8?
And this is it translates it translates to this one.
So it is much more simpler.
This kind of expression is much more simpler, and you have greater clarity.
So you can also express it this way.
But whichever makes makes sense makes sense, whichever is clear, you can choose that function.
Choose that method.
Similarly, even here.
We could do the same thing.
We could say none of them should this.
So we can also write it in this way.
Does, the condition has to be greater than 2.0.
So if all of them have a rating greater than 2.0, then it means that.
None of the books have bad rating.
So all of the books have a rating greater than or equal to 2.0.
So once again, I think the first one is more it makes more sense, it's more clear.
Or you can also say any match also can be used here with the same condition.
So if you have any match, so if at least one of them has a value less than or equal to 2.0, then a
true would be written.
So even you can express it this way and in your if condition somewhere below you can write if not true
or something like that.
So if it does not match, it means that if all of them are not satisfying this condition, then a true
would be written.
So it is just you can express your query in any way, but you would want to express it in the clearest
possible way.
So you would pick a method.
That is most clear.
So that's that's what you should be doing.
So that's about it.
So those are the three matching operations.
And in the subsequent lecture, we are going to look at finding operations and this code will be available
in the resources section.
Thank you and happy coding.