Not let's look at another interesting topic called civilization NDC realization at the end of the lesson
we would also do a short demo of what we learned.
So what we have seen how we can read and write data such as images as well as text but sometimes we
also come across situations where we need to write wriggler Djala objects to disk and then at a later
time read them back from the disk with the same state.
So we're talking about saving objects to disk.
Typically you would say objects declare a database.
But sometimes as we will soon see you would want to save the entire Java object along with it to the
disk know the source and the destination need not be a disk.
It can also be something like Malmedy serialization is nothing but the process of writing Djala objects
to some destination that is Java objects get saved us byte streams.
He had a job object A named eight Izard and to some destination let's say it is their desk.
So in this case we said that object has been serialized now at some point in the future we may want
to reconstruct object it from its serialized version.
And this is done through the process of DCD allegation.
So DC deliberation we reconstruct Dala objects back from there byte strings.
So the reconstructed Djala object will have the same state that it had when it was serialized that is
.
Instance variables but have the values as before.
Not this DC realization can happen on the same JVM or even on a remote JVM.
So as objects can also be transmitted across JVM is not the same deal as an object.
We need to first make sure that X class implements this interface class Serializable which is a marker
interface from the Java dog IO package and do the actual serialization NDC delegation.
We make use of these classes object output stream an object input stream object output stream is 4C
realization while object input stream is for D.S. realization and these classes implement the interfaces
object output an object input respectably.
And here is an example of serialization.
We must create an instance of Object or put stream -- and Chambery a buffer stream that is Intan
chain Guia file or putzed in which does the actual writing off bytes on here the objects are written
with this file called s object but s e r so the filename can be anything.
It need not be object not as here but the extension ACR is normally used as a convention but you can
use a different extension.
All you can even altogether omit the extension to not buffer output stream is also not required.
You would use it only for performance reasons.
So you can directly chain object or put stream through the file output stream not to write an object
when the method or write object on the object output stream instance here one string object and one
date object are being returned to the file object.
S E R.
Now what string as well as did Garces doing and does Serializable interface.
Otherwise these objects cannot be serialized.
And here are the steps for ABC television.
It's just the opposite.
We just use input strings here an object input stream or buffered input stream because and don't change
to the file and pushed him which is reading from the file object.
As you do read an object from the object stream read object that is used.
No the important thing here is that Vinita ensured that we are reading objects in the same order in
which they have been returned to the desk.
So the first object right will be the string object and the second one would be need also read object
motard written an object instance.
So we need a dongas appropriately so as you can see here in the first line we are casting a string whereas
in the second line we are downcasting it to identify the list.
We will also do a short demo of both serialization NBC realization here in this example we are serializing
string under it but in the demo we will actually serialize our own custom object that has some state
known it took a few use cases of serialization one to alleviate it is useful isn't websites that how
high traffic rapid is on these web pages are dynamic web pages that is defined this what pages come
from sources like a database model and the content in this for pages is pretty much constant that is
you will see the same content for a long period of time.
So it's such VEP biggest most of the time did is it from the database but not create into the database
.
And this date I might have to be right from Mike Dipali tables and that would be an expensive operation
Now if you're familiar with D-W Asus you may understand that it may require joining of multiple tables
and the join operation would be very expensive.
Mundelein once the data is right you would use it to construct you are Java objects and then pass them
to the front end on you are performing these actions for every single piece axis.
But if you are performing the expense you do opposite operation along that constructing of the Java
object.
And as mentioned earlier if the Lapidus have heavy traffic then it would affect the response time of
the radius.
That is it could drastically skewed on the response times.
So in such cases since the content does not change frequently we can construct that Djala object once
when the pitches access for the very first time.
And then we can serialize a Java object subsequently with every bit axes.
The page can be built using the serialized object.
This way you are whining the costly database operation and also the object construction operation.
You can store the serialized object on the desk or even better cash it in the memory using a tool like
memcached memcached is an open source distributed object caching system and it also requires your objects
to implement the Serializable interface.
If you're interested you can google for that and check it out under his breath.
Easy to use and one project that I worked on to do this kind of an issue VCL is Java objects to disk
undergirded a huge difference in response time.
So the web pages in this case where mostly constant sickener area is when you want to pass Java objects
at cross-overs for instance your web service implementation might require Djala objects to be paused
as input.
In that case you can see that as the Del object on Pasic to the web service which is hosted on that
remote server on the web service will end don't BCPL as the serialist Joe object.
Another interesting use case seems to be post-mortem analysis which just perform when you run into any
serious errors for instance if an object is causing some error then you would serialize that object
.
Let's say you were booted from the catch block later you can.
DC realized it using a debugger and can investigate why the object caused that particular error.
I've never done this but I'm including a go for a pointer in the resources section.
There one particular user is discussing this use case on Harvard.
How would this be.
As you have time you can take a look at it not just look at some more things that we need to know about
serialization.
First is that both primitives as well as are is are both Serializable by default.
No this would mean two things.
First is that if an object to see more then any Prema do variables as well as any it was that it has
will also be saved.
Good risk.
Second is that you can spasmed directly to the White object Mathare off object or put stream next to
serialization saved and object Goffe.
That is if an object is serialized than any objects it references or any object doughs objects reference
will all be serialized.
Now if at least one object and object graph does not implement the Serializable interface then seeing
an addition of the original object is also within the object graph of the same object is referenced
.
Mike Dipali times that is there are multiple references to the same object density tradition is smart
enough to save the object only once so it's not going to say multiple times.
Know dystopic videos I'm not serializable and that's because serialization is about objects.
It will start to really be not class variables on hence on not to any particular object.
So during B.C.E. realization is Dodik variable will be assigned the value the class has a particular
instance of.
Next one as if a superclass is serializable then it's subclasses are automatically Serializable that
a subclass us do not have to explicitly implement the Serializable interface superclasses Nazirite risible
then some classes can still be mere serializable.
So if a third party grows that you want to use is not serializable then you can always suppress it and
make the subclass serializable.
No you do not want an instance variable to be serialized.
Then you can model that with the last transmission.
So content is a keyword that you would include in the variables declaration.
And with that the variables valuable squibbed during serialization and doing DC idealisation that TRONSON
variable gets their default value based on its type.
So I an object reference variable it will be null unforgettable like and it would be zero non-literary
total eclipse.
Googoosh shut them all off.
Serialization NDC transition.
OK here we are in the demo class and some antiquated package.
And here we're going to see the as a Java object.
NBC realized that.
OK so let's just go ahead and look at the class itself.
The class of the object and here it is at the top.
It's called the Serializable demo and it is a nested class stocktake nested class which means that it
is a class that is nested within the class I or.
OK.
And we still did not discuss nested classes so that we discuss later.
So let's not worry about it.
But this Serializable demo class.
It could also have been an external It need not.
It need not be a strict class.
It can also be a separate class by itself.
But I just made it an abstract class ok under a static master class.
And if you recall from our coding conventions we said that's all stocktake masterclasses should be placed
before static methods.
So I would a more class has all static methods.
We know that.
So this particular stocktake master class is placed before the starting mothers.
OK so we are following the standard convention.
And in order for its objects to be serializable we know that it needs to implement Serializable interface
.
So that's what we are doing.
So it's a marker interface interface on this particular class has a variable name and there is a getter
on set name for that.
So we are going to set the stage for that.
And there is also another variable ID so name is an instance variable ID is also an instance variable
but ID is marked as transients which means that it should not be serialized.
And it is initialized with the value for.
And here there is another variable gender.
But let's not worry about it for now so I just call him undernote on which also not worry about this
moment with a look at it later.
So let's just go back to the main method and here it is.
So we are for sequential serializer.
And in order to do the serialization we are passing a parameter to the an argument to the I order more
glass if the argument Bosnia's true.
Only then we pull home the Syrian opposition and otherwise we do not.
And there is also in order to perform the serialization we have this method called Boosey realization
.
And in order to perform B.C.E. tradition we have written this matter Boosey that position do B.C.E.
demonization.
So let's look at this matter Boosey television.
Here it is.
So you are first creating an instance off Serializable demat because we want to see Golez that particular
object and we are said in the state of mean Kujawa.
And we are simply printing the name value and the ID value which is a transient variable.
So this is before serialization and we will also print after Signa mission to do the actual serialization
.
Here we are we are creating an object output stream which is chained to a buffer output stream which
is intention to fight or put stream on we are writing the object of this file called City or Daut SDR
and we are using that right object method and we are simply passing the Serializable to a more object
object reference.
OK so we are writing the object here.
Now let's look at the DC validation method.
Here it is.
So here we are using input streams.
So object input stream buffered input stream on file input stream on the file and this city Aldora as
E.R and we are using the read object method here.
So once again we are using a try catch block here.
I tried with resources read object but read object against an object an instance of Object.
So we need to gaster it here to see it rise above them all and we are ending the values after serialization
the state one is the mean on the other is I-T.
OK so let's just go ahead and fundus but it's busto value due to the configuration.
So it's going to the configuration or an --
here.
So Program arguments should be true.
It's like an electronic case or printed some output here in Demel.
If I refresh it you can see that it created this city or not as E.R So that's byte streams that God
created.
OK so the duckster file.
And here it is.
So before in the Boosey deposition method the name is Java ideas for but after the D.C. delegation process
the name is once again we are reconstructing the object and we have the value of name as Java.
But what ID since it's a transient variable it is initialized with the default value.
So if it is a constant variable it's not going to be serialized.
We know that.
And so during these utilization it will assign the value of its type the default value of its type since
it's on and it got assigned zero.
OK now let's make a small change.
Let's go back to this matter here and let me let's see.
So the object has been set.
Now let's see.
You know using a time machine we went into the future and B how changed.
We have ordered this new instance variable called gender.
OK.
So let's assume that it's a new release.
And so we have a better class.
But the object is from an older of these.
So let's see if it will give us any problems.
So let's go into a run configuration let's not beat Eleazer this let's not see the lizard this time
.
So in our city modus and let's say a polite unmix Ron on and you can see that.
So naughty delegation has been done on the DC idolization off the object that we'll see realized earlier
is being performed on Nix's invalid class exception.
So there is an exception here it says local class incompatible.
So what is happening is the class has evolved.
But the object that we see realized was an old object.
So it's like a legacy object and it should not be that way.
So the object should be compatible with that class.
OK.
So there is a version mismatch.
So there is something that we need to still learn about utilization and we will see how we can fix this
by making some changes and that we are going to learn in the next lesson or at least some of the problems
can be addressed by doing that.
But that will be something that we look at the next lesson.
Okay.
Thank you.
And happy coding.