So we implement it to reach so far one is bookmarking while the other is marking an item as kid friendly
.
Now we will implement the feature for sharing kid friendly bookmark with partner websites.
However the constraint is that only a kid friendly bookmark that is either a book or of eyeblink can
be shared.
So a movie cannot be shared.
You may recall the slide from one officer up chapter which introduced this new requirement.
Here we have this strength to get friendly books so you can see that there is this link called shared
with snips where courtships is a fictitious part on the website.
This link will be shown only for books and ramblings but not for movies.
You can assume that this link shows up as soon as a staff member mocks either a book or a blink as kid
friendly.
Clicking on this link will invoke shared method in the back in which we know will be a method in the
controller in the Bakken.
Did we have a logic that will generate the data to be shared in SML format with the partner site like
in the case of marking.
Get friendly bookmarks.
We already discussed implementation because for this feature we did that well and are using interfaces
as an interface is needed for this new requirement.
So we're already familiar with this class diagram to enforce the constraint that only book on wabbling
can be shared.
We define an interface called sharable which is implemented by only book and Roblin classes he called
a sharable cannot be an abstract class because our classes are already extending that abstract bookmark
class.
Moreover sharing is an optional capability and so we know that it would have to be represented using
an interface.
So let's get started now and let's first create the interface shippable.
Let's create it in a new package called partner as shootable has something to do better.
Third party partner websites
so let's create a new package
partner
.
Let's create an interface here shootable
and that's how you define the method get item data.
Next let's have rebeling on book.
Implement this sharable interface.
Let's just open the book Class control shift are just and this book is implemented in open
court.
So just sit ired unimplemented methods which is to get item data.
So if you scroll down so be how the Templer generated automatically.
OK so we know that this method returns information about this particular item which is a book in XML
format which isn't shared with a partner website.
Typically data exchange between Web sites is done either in examen or Jason farmer Gissen is another
format but it is much more compact and XML in case you don't know what ex-head malice.
It is short for Extensible Markup Language And it basically encapsulates doodah using meaningful examinee
tax so the docs describe what the data is about the exim unstring that is generated is human readable
.
Art can also be processed by machines suitable ex-MIL string we will use a string builder as there are
several fields in book class and we need to combine them into a single string.
Recall that it's not recommended to use plus operator for string concatenation especially when performance
is critical.
That surplus should be used only sparingly.
OK so let's just get started and belive this particular method.
You can just delete this
Arnaud's builder
so a builder has happened matter.
So let's have the first semantic tag as item and its cluelessness.
So I accidently tax how the starting tag and name tags are it's have an ending tag a name tag would
have a forward slash followed by the tag name item.
Now since this is of Bible book so let's have an element just for book saying that it's a book so it's
Connard as Bible
so book is the real data type is another I.
Let's have a burn at night here.
But it has real value.
So let's just remove this
and rebuild that Shane.
Yes.
I mean that's good one more happened here for the name tag.
Now the title is present in the supercross which is bookmark.
And to get that we just need to do when we need to invoke the get Bitly method in the superclass.
So next
so we have all these feelings and we need to combine We need to include all these fields in our Exham
of string.
So next let's say publisher
schoolbags public publisher publication here.
OK it's good been publisher.
So let's call the element as publisher
since publisher is available in this class itself so we can directly access it
.
Next let's have publication here
Next let's have John Ray
.
Next is Amazon rating
One more we have is authors let's just keep it here because it's like an important field.
However alter says a string array rather than a string or an.
It is a string array.
So what we can do is we can make use of a third party library here we can use Apache Commons slang because
it has it has a class called String Udall's which can be used to join to combine to concatenate all
of the authors using a single function.
OK.
So with a single function in the string utils class we can combine all the authors all the alternates
into a single string and we can do that.
So let's use the string utos grads from Apache Commons line.
But we don't have it here.
So what we need to do is we need to download Apache a common Lange's and use the Jarve file for doc
.
So I have already done that.
So I have it here but you can just go ahead and can just type in about the Commons monster lying.
Here it is.
And you can download Apache Commons line.
That's the latest version is 3.4 and it requires that I was 6 and just you can download the binary here
and just unzip it and extract the folder and within that with no room for Ladu you will have a jar file
so you can just extract that jar file and store it on your desk.
And then we need to import it into our into our eclipse.
So the way we do it is just right click on three are here is going to properties going to be part and
I had external jars and this is an older one so to me
your
think Howard here.
Yes.
So this is the one and lie.
OK.
So here is the reference library.
So it's already there.
So Apache Commons Lang has this class called String Udalls.
So let me do it and let's just search for it.
We just show that
string your DOS.
Here is the class String utos class.
So it has a lot of utility functions and I'm sure you will be making use of this class quite a bit.
So here there is one function called Join in and this is the one.
So this can take a string array.
It's an object array but you can pass a string array and you will pass on any operator like a hybrid
of can be Ostrower or anything like that.
And we will pass on common so that we get a comma separated string.
So it will combine all the auteurs into it and into a single string which is operated by comma.
And so let's just make use of this function
.
So you join others.
Now the second argument is a comma.
OK so that's it.
So that's the string Udalls it's already imported.
She's next.
And let's just see written Berliner got to string.
OK.
So this would work on a string.
So that's the good item there Dummett there.
Let me just go ahead and do the same.
Godard under Dummett that let me implement the Guitard underdone method in the grappling class because
wabbling also implements this interface.
And then I'll do this offline and I'll come back and show it to you.
OK.
Here it is.
So we are implementing shareable.
And of course we are extending bookmark.
So here is the get item re-admitted.
And as you can see we are once again using string builder.
And so we have this item tags here.
Opening tag on the closing tag.
And we have pipe which is wabbling.
Let's actually make this gap to be consistent and then the next element is title and the next is you
aren't on the next as host.
So those are the only fields that we have for for the ruling class.
So that's about it for now.
So just go ahead and implement what we covered so far here.
Next we will complete the remaining part of this feature in the next lesson and we will code the logic
in view controller and the manager process.
OK so please just go ahead and call whatever has been shown in this class and this lesson