Hi there.
This is the rule.
In the last lecture, we have seen the knife indexer program where the indexing thread was wasting CPU
cycles while the corresponding web page was being downloaded.
And that's not good.
So in this lecture, we will see how that can be avoided.
How we can avoid wasting CPU cycles.
So for this demo I created this new class called us.
Wait, notify indexer in the same sub package indexer and it's called as wait notify indexer and we
have the same classes, the nested classes, weblink downloader and indexer, and we'll be having those
nested classes in all of the demos.
So the class is pretty much identical to the native indexer and within web link.
So one change is that the HTML page?
Earlier it was volatile.
Now it's not volatile and we don't need that because within the wait notify indexer we use two methods
called us wait and notify and they have a happens happens before relationship and so we don't need volatile
keyword here so that's the volatile modifier has been removed and so here is the downloader and we just
need to fill in this run method here and within the indexer also we need to fill in the run method and
everything else is the same like the go method add and the create web blend.
Only difference is in the main method.
We are now instantiating wait notify indexer and we are still creating the same web links.
So we are passing the same information.
And the method is also the same.
So we are creating two threads corresponding to downloader and indexer and we are starting them here
and we are iterating over all the web links.
So the first thing is let's go ahead and fill the indexer method here.
So here.
Okay.
Let's go here.
Indexer.
This is an indexer method in the Indexer program.
So first thing that we can do is let's just go ahead and copy this.
So we are downloading the HTML page.
And.
Let's put a wild condition here.
I will explain why we need a wild condition here.
So we have this wild condition.
So it's the condition is that HTML page is equal to null.
So when this is the case, we would have to wait.
So this thread indexer.
It means that the page is not yet downloaded.
So earlier we had an infinite loop.
Now we will say wait and wait is a method in the object class.
So it's not in the threat class, but it is an object class.
And what it will do is it will suspend the thread, the indexer thread, and it will move that thread
from running state into a new state called Waiting.
So that's a new state which we have, which we haven't seen so far.
And later at the end of this lecture, we will also discuss more about it.
So it will go into this state called waiting.
So this thread will be will be suspended.
Now there is a compilation here.
It's just around with try catch.
So let's do that.
So that's what is needed.
And so this is what we have here.
So which means that the threat is waiting for the other threat.
So let's go ahead and fill this.
The run method inside the downloader class.
And once again, let's just go back here into the naive indexer class and let's just copy these two
here.
Okay.
Let's have the same statements.
And here.
We also need to try catch here.
So let's do that and let's actually move this into.
So let's do that.
And so.
So this thread is there and this thread has to go.
So once it is done downloading it should notify the other thread.
So the other thread has suspended itself.
The indexer thread.
So we need to, we need to take that wrap that thread because it went into waiting state and in order
to wake that thread we use this method called us notify.
I know if I would wake that.
The other thread.
Now, here, let's just go ahead and.
And it's also invoke the index method.
So if you are outside the loop, it means that this condition has failed and the web page has been downloaded.
So let's go ahead and let's say HTML page.
But here we have to say HTML page equal to this one because once it is once it has come back from the
waiting stage waiting state, it needs to once again fetch the page.
So the page has already been downloaded.
So we are invoking the HTML page.
And, and so in the next iteration, HTML page would be equal to not now, which would be not null.
And so we would exit the loop and we would this statement would get executed.
Right.
But so let's go ahead and run this first.
As you can see, we get this exception called illegal monitor state exception.
And that's because we need to have a synchronised block when we are using when we are using this weight
method.
So we need a synchronized block.
And the reason we need a synchronized block is because let's assume that the thread scheduler has picked
the indexer thread to run and the indexer thread will come here.
It will.
It will access this method.
Get HTML page and html page would be null initially.
So this statement will get executed.
But before it gets, it executes the weight statement.
You know, the thread scheduler could run, the other thread could bring the other thread into running
state.
The downloaded thread and the downloaded thread can download the web page, will set the HTML page and
can invoke the notify method.
And after that, after the notify method is invoked, then this particular thread might execute the
weight method and it will go into waiting state.
So in that case, it will always be in waiting state because this particular notify method, the statement
has already been executed.
So that's not right.
And so we need a synchronize block, which means that these steps have to be executed.
Have to be executed atomically.
Right.
So that's why we need a synchronized statement here.
And the object here we can use web link.
It's more this entire code.
Into the synchronized block.
So this is what we are doing here.
So now one thing is so we have the synchronized block.
So if the indexer threat is here and if once it gets into this wild loop here.
So it's going to execute the weight statement and the weight statement.
We said that it will suspend this thread and it will move, move that move the indexer thread into waiting
state.
But at the same time it will also release the log that it has.
So now the log is the log of this particular object web link.
So that needs to be released.
And when it is released, it needs to be acquired by the other thread, which means that we will also
have a synchronized block here.
And let's move this here to this.
And this will also use the same lock.
And here we need to invoke weblink dot notify because notify method and the weight method are actually
part of object class.
So keep that in mind.
Weight notify.
And there is one more method called notify all which we can also use here instead of notify.
All three belong to object class not thread.
Since they are object class we can we have to invoke it this way.
So now we are good.
So here the threat is going into Wayne State and.
Which and it is also releasing the lock.
So when it releases the lock, the other thread will acquire the lock here, the downloader thread and
it will download the web page and it will set the HTML page.
After it does that, it will invoke the notify method and the notify method will wake.
The other thread will wake the indexer thread.
So with that the indexer thread will move from waiting to block state.
So it's not getting into the state in order to for it to get into the vulnerable state.
For the indexer thread, to get into the state, it needs to acquire the lock and the lock is not yet
released.
At this instance, lock is actually released here.
Lock is released once we are out of the synchronized block here.
At this point, we are still in the synchronized block and so the lock is not yet released.
All it does is it moves the other thread, the cooperating thread, which is the indexer thread.
It moves that particular thread from the waiting state straight into block state.
And once we are out of this block or if we invoke another rate method here, then the block, then the
lock will be released.
But that's not needed here.
So we will just exit the synchronized method.
And with that the lock are, in other words, monitor.
Sometimes the lock is also called as monitor would be released by this particular thread and it will
then be acquired by the other thread.
Now, if there are multiple threads that are waiting on this particular are waiting on this particular
link or object, then in that case, so which means that multiple threads have executed.
Wait, then it will still wake up a single thread and that will be chosen arbitrarily.
So that's one thing.
And we can.
And there is also another method called notify all generally that is preferred to be used and notify
all will actually wake up.
All the threats that are waiting on this particular that are in the that have executed the weight method
on this object on the same object.
So the notify will only will only wake up one of the threads that is waiting if there are multiple threads
but notify all well wake up all the threads and we can use either of them and it is preferable to use
notify all because today we are using notify because only one thread is waiting.
But in the future, if there are other threats that are also going to wait, that are going to invoke
the wait on this particular object, then notify all would be useful so we can do that.
Also.
So it can be either notify or notify all.
And that would bring the threat from a waiting state.
The other threat from waiting state into into block state.
And once it exits, once the once the synchronize block exits, this thread will release the lock.
And the other thread, which is in the block state, will acquire the lock on.
Well, going to run the state.
But if there are some other threads which are also waiting on this particular object which did not invoke
rate method but are still, for whatever reason, are waiting on this particular object.
Maybe there are some other synchronized methods on this object, and if they are waiting on that, then
they may also get instead of these the indexer thread.
Those other threads might also acquire the lock.
So just keep that in mind.
So this is what we have here.
And let's put a bunch of print statements.
Now, one of the things I want to tell us, like the rate method here is releasing the lock here.
But had we used like the other methods, like the sleep method or the method, so those those method
calls will also suspend the thread, but they will not release the lock.
So that's one difference between weight and other methods like sleep and yield.
So just keep that in to keep that in mind.
And let's put a bunch of print statements here.
And this is not your downloaded.
So that should be good.
So let's go ahead and run this.
Some Internet issue.
Let me just run it one more time.
Here you go.
I think one of the links is having some issue, but that's fine.
At least the others got downloaded.
So let me just stop it there.
So here we are saying.
So these are the three pages.
And here it says not yet downloaded.
So we were in the indexer thread and it says not yet downloaded.
And then it was downloading the downloaded thread was executing this, and then the indexer thread once
again it says to other for two other web pages, it says not yet downloaded.
And here the the web link with the ID 2004 it is awake and here it went into wait state.
Then it got downloaded right?
It got downloaded.
It went to wait state and the the other thread, the download thread has downloaded it and then it invoked
the notify method.
And so this got awakened and after it got awaken we it is also getting indexed OC.
So that's it.
I actually stopped the program in between because one of I think some of the links were not getting
downloaded properly, maybe some web server issues on their end so that least we could see the flow
here.
So that's important.
So as you can see now, we are not we are not wasting the CPU cycles here.
The indexer thread is go is suspending itself.
So with that we are saving the CPU, CPU cycles.
So that's an improvement over the previous approach, the knife indexer approach.
Now, one thing is this is the standard idiom.
So this is the standard idiom.
So the weight method should always be used with this kind of a wild condition, not an F, but a wild
condition.
And that's the standard idiom.
That's because sometimes what happens is there is also something called as curious wake up spurious
vapour, in which case a weighting thread can actually move from the weight state into the block state
so it can wake up even though there was no notify, call, notify, signal from the other cooperating
thread.
And that can happen rarely.
So if that happens, what would happen is the HTML page would still be null.
And where you know this thread is being woken, woken up and because of that, so we it's not good state.
So we should always have this this wild condition here.
So that's the standard idiom.
And another reason could be another reason can also be that the other the cooperating thread invokes
the notify method.
So this will wake up, but this thread might not get the lock and some other thread might acquire the
lock and it might set HTML page to null once again.
So I mean, it doesn't make sense in this particular example, but in some other example where we have
a shared state on which these threats are working on, so that shared state can be changed by some other
thread.
So that's why it is always important to have this weight method along with some condition, and that
condition should be within the while.
We should use a wild statement in this way.
So that's why we need a while, a wild statement here, and that's the standard idiom.
So this is also explained in the effective Java item.
One of the effective items.
And now I have some text also here, just like the previous example, previous demo.
So we are having better coordination now and the lock is relinquished upon invoking the weight method.
And the one difference is that each HTML page is not yet declared, it's not declared volatile and web
link.
And that's because there is an unlock there is an unlock happening in the downloaded thread, right?
Once it exits the synchronized method, here it is unlocking it is it is relinquishing the lock.
And after that the other thread, the indexer thread is acquiring the lock and there is a happens before
relationship between those two actions.
So here we are unlocking and there we are locking.
And because of that happens before relationship, we have the memory visibility also.
And so we do not need a volatile variable.
So that's what is being written here.
So it is, but the limitation here is we are solving the task cooperation in a low level fashion.
And so because we are using all those synchronized blocks and we are using the wild loops, so it's
pretty low level.
And in Java five, we have some concurrency utilities which will make this whole process a lot cleaner.
So this was this approach was used before Java five and so after Java five, since we have since we
have the concurrency utilities, you should be using that OC only you would be looking at this kind
of a code only if you are looking at some legacy code.
So that's about it.
So now let's head back to the slides.
Let's look at the slides.
And in the slides we are actually we will actually look at the thread states because there are two new
states.
One of the states is waiting and there is also another state.
And we will look at it in the slides and we can discuss a little bit more about the thread states.
So let's go ahead and look at that.
Okay.
You may recall this illustration of the different states that a threat can be in.
So you're going to now introduce a couple of new states.
We already looked at one of them, the waiting state.
So on invoking the Veidt method, a thread would move from running state into waiting state.
Right.
So we discussed that.
And when a cooperating threat invokes either notify or notify all on the common lock, then all threats
waiting on that lock would move into block state.
Right.
We also discussed that.
So they would move from waiting state into block state.
Finally the thread that acquires the log would actually move into readable state.
So from waiting state we are not directly moving into renewable state.
Now there is also a time devotion of weight method.
We only looked at the weight method, but there is also a time to auction.
And on invoking this method, the thread would go into another state called timed underscore weighting.
Note that invoking either the timed version of join or even the sleep method would move the thread into
this timed underscore waiting state.
On the long method parameter here would be time in milliseconds.
So we have these two new states.
And when a cooperating threat invokes either notify or notify all, then any threat that is a timed
underscore waiting state.
Due to the invocation of time, Wade would be moved into blocked state.
Keep in mind that we are only talking about threat that got into this state due to time raid and not
either sleep or joint.
But if that is what happens, then any thread and time to underscore waiting state would be moved into
a state directly.
It doesn't matter whether the thread got into time to underscore weighting due to weight or join or
sleep.
So those are the different thread states.
Just note that new and dead states are not shown here and that state is more formally referred to as
dominated state.
So many books refer to it as Terminator State, which is a state that the thread gets into once it has
run to completion.
So that's about it.
That's thread cooperation via wait and notify communication.
Using Wait and notify was common before Java five introduced higher level concurrency utilities, which
we are going to discuss pretty soon.
As mentioned earlier, you would probably deal with wait and notify only when dealing with some legacy
code.
Way to notify represents pretty low level handshaking, as we have seen, and Joshua BLOCK refers to
using them as programming and concurrency assembly language.
So that's about it.
And the code that we have seen earlier is also available in Resources section, and that's about it.
And thank you.