Hello there.
This is the Manila Room.
And welcome back.
So far, we looked at seven primitive types of it's six of them represent numbers while one represents
characters.
Now, let's look at the final primitive data type that represents logical values like true or false.
So we have primitive types representing numbers, a primitive type for characters and one for logical
values.
And that final one is the Boolean primitive type, and it can take either a true or false value.
So true or false are Boolean Literals and Boolean is a binary data type as it can take only one of the
two values true or false?
By default, a boolean variable is initialized with false.
So keep that in mind.
So if you're not initializing a boolean variable, it gets a false as the value.
Coming to bed depth.
It is not precisely defined and it is specific to particular JVM implementation, so it can vary from
one team to another.
And so we need not worry about that.
It could be one byte or four bytes or whatever the JVM chooses.
Now Boolean variables are mostly used in control flow statements and control flow statements are something
which we will see in the next section.
But as the name suggests, control flow statements are simply the statements that control the flow of
your logic depending upon certain conditions.
And these conditions are boolean conditions and they can be based on boolean variables.
One example is an F statement and we will also look at F statement in the subsequent section.
But in this lecture we will use a simple F statement so that we can see how a boolean variable can be
used.
So the F statement will use the boolean variable and it will see if the condition is true or false.
If it is true, then it will execute certain piece of code, otherwise it will not.
So that's how the control will flow, depending upon the condition.
So let's go ahead and extend our student class by implementing a very simple logic for computing the
tuition fees that the student has to pay in a semester.
If the student is a local student, then student would pay a certain fees.
But if the student is an international student, then he or she would have to pay a higher fee.
So let's go ahead and declare a boolean variable called international.
So the type is boolean.
And let's initialize it to.
True.
So that's the boolean literal.
Now let's define a variable called tution fees.
And let's initialize it to $12,000.
So it's off type double.
Let's declare one more variable.
So this is fees.
Let's call it international fees.
And this would be an additional amount of the student is an international student.
Now here between the compute method, let's compute the tuition fees.
So we will say F, so we're going to use an F statement.
So it starts with the reserved keyword F and it is followed by this parenthesis and it has a body here
which will have the braces opening in the closing place.
Now here the condition.
Let's have it as.
True.
So if it is equal to true, we want to re compute the tuition fees.
And that would be.
Tuition fees are equal to tuition fees plus international fees.
Okay.
So if it is true, then it would be 17,000.
So tuition fees will be 12,000 and international fees will be 5000.
And the sum of that will be assigned to the tuition fees.
Remember the four indentation spaces.
So let's go ahead and.
Alright.
Time to compile and execute.
There you go.
It prints 17,000.
Now, here I am.
This is called as an equality operator, but we don't have to do this.
So here, if the student is international, then this piece of logic is getting executed.
But we don't have to do this.
As long as this expression evaluates to true, then we are good.
Now, here it is international, right?
It evaluates to true.
So this statement will get executed.
So we don't have to explicitly say equals to true.
We don't have to do that.
A lot of new students actually do that.
So they put that equality sign and then they compare it with true or false.
So this is what it is.
Now, the default value, I said is false.
So let's do this.
Let's remove that.
So it will be false.
So if it is false, then it will skip the statement.
Then the body will not be executed and the tuition fees will be printed as 12,000.
So let's recompile.
There you go.
This time it is 12,000.
So that's all there is to boolean or variable.
It can take either a true or false.
So we are done with looking at all of the primitive data types and there were eight primitive types.
They are in-built into the Java language, so they come with the Java language.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I hope you have enjoyed learning about the primitive types and I'll see you in the next lecture.