Hi there.
This is De La Rue.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at the finding operations.
Earlier we looked at the matching operations and now we are going to look at finding operations.
So we are still in the stream operations class and we know that finding operations are also terminal
operations like match operations.
And we also said that fighting operations are also short circuit operations along with matching and
limit operation.
So in finding operations, we are going to look at two methods to find any and find fast.
So those are the two methods that we are going to look at.
And as the name implies, find methods are used to find something in the input stream elements.
That's what they do.
But you would be expecting that these methods would take some kind of a search target, something like
the contains method in collection, and we would search against the input elements, but that is not
happening.
So the fine methods do not have do not take any parameter.
So they are parameter less, but they typically are used with filter operations, so they are used with
filter operations, but that need not be the case.
They can also be used without filter operations.
So if you have a bunch of operations in your stream pipeline without any filtering and if you use one
of the find fine methods, then you would get some kind of value.
They would return a value from the stream.
So it can also be used without filter elements, but typically they are used with filter, filter method,
filter operation.
So let's go ahead and look at the two methods.
Let's go into the find method here.
So along with the find operations, we are also going to look at something called Optional Class, which
was introduced in Java eight.
An optional is part of the Java package and we will look at that.
So we are going to use the same condition here.
We had a condition here.
Is there at least one highly rated book that is inexpensive?
So let's go ahead and use the same condition here.
And if we have that book, then we need to return that book.
So let's do that.
Let's implement that.
So first is we will just say.
The usual syntax.
So we have to use filter because it is not like the match operation and let's just copy the condition
from here.
Now this is find any.
So as soon as find any is executed, then it would return an object.
So if an if there are a stream of elements.
So one of the elements well would satisfy this condition and we would simply return that element.
So that's the find any method and find first method will return the first element.
So what it means is, let's say there are ten elements and within the ten elements, three of the elements
match this condition.
Then, then only one of them will be written.
And it could be like, for instance, it could be the second, fifth and eighth element and the element
return can be any of them.
So that's what happens with find any.
But in a non parallel setup, non parallel setup, typically it would usually return only the first
element, which means if there are if the second, fifth and eighth elements are matching this criteria,
typically the second will be return.
But there is no guarantee.
So that's the find any but with find first, it will always return the first matching element itself.
So after ten, ten elements of second, fifth and eight are going to match, then it would always return
the second element.
So the question is which one to use?
Find any or find first.
In a bit, I'm going to show how the returned value can be printed.
But the question now is of the two.
Which one do you want to use?
The thing is, if we are using this is a stream, but if you are using a parallel stream, then if we
do not have the requirement to return the first element, then you should go with find any OC because
if you are using a parallel stream and if you really want to return only the first element, then there
is more work to be done because with parallel stream, multiple cores will be used.
So the data, the stream elements would be partitioned and we will the different course will be working
on the different partitions, but the requirement is that the first matching element has to be returned
so that synchronization should be there and it is a lot of work.
So if you do not have that requirement, if first and any will do in a parallel environment, then you
have to go for that.
So that's the thing.
Those are the only two methods.
Now here, both of them return an optional off book.
So let's look at what optional is.
So it was introduced in Java eight.
Let's call it result.
So optional as the name implies.
What it means is if the stream matches this criteria, it may match.
If all of the stream elements, if one of the stream elements matches the criteria, then the element
will be returned.
But if none of them match matches, or if the stream is empty, the optional will not contain the value.
So optional is essentially a container class which would have either the matching element or it will
not have the element.
So that's the thing.
So it is saying that the value might be present or might not be present.
So that's why it is called as optional.
So the question is, before Java eight, if had streams been there, then it would have returned the
book.
In this case, the book.
But if the book object was not found, then it would have returned a null value.
So the problem here is with null reference.
If it returns a null and if you invoke some method on the result and if the result is null, and if
you're not performing any null checks, then you would end up with a null pointer exception and null
pointer exceptions are pretty common.
When you're right, when you're working on projects, you could frequently encounter them due to bad
practices because of being careless.
So you could end up with that because null checks are not done.
So to avoid that, this class has been introduced.
So it's a container class, so it's a safe alternative to null checks.
So that's what it is.
So you would use optional and optional kind of classes were also used in Scala and other programming
languages like Haskell, Scala and Haskell.
So probably the language designers were inspired by that and they have introduced this.
So optional is like this.
So if you want to get the value.
So there are certain methods that you can use.
So first thing is we need to check if.
Result is present.
So you can see all of those methods if it is present.
Then you would say.
You can print the.
Result.
Dot get so this would return the this would return the book instance the the book instance that was
found.
So now you would say that.
What's the what's the benefit of this?
Because in the pre Java eight world, you could have made made this into a null check and you would
have you could have printed the the value the value that was written if the condition was met.
But the problem is many times developers might forget the null check.
But you might also ask why?
Why wouldn't a developer forget this one?
But the thing is here, by having this name as optional, there is a greater chance that developer would
actually invoke this method before invoking the get method.
So it's just more likely to do that.
And also optional has other other methods.
Also, if the result is not found, we can return a default value.
So there are other methods which can be which we can make use of.
So there are other benefits to so.
But with using an optional, it is very likely that we will invoke the is present method before invoking
this.
And if we invoke the method also if it is a null value, if he invoked it directly and if it is null,
if there is no value, then it will actually throw an exception just like the null pointer exception.
But it's a different exception, which we will see later.
So that's the thing.
So let me just let's just print that.
So it's printing the book.
It's invoking the two string method in this.
And as you can see, the rating is greater than or equal to 4.8 and the price is less than 50.
Now, let's say let's change it to 5.0.
In which case it will not work.
So we can have some kind of an els condition here.
And we can say.
It's not fun.
So if you execute this, it will say not fun because there are no books which have a rating of five
or the max rating is five, but there is not even a single book which has this rating.
So that's the thing.
Now let me so find any is returning this thing.
So let's just comment this out.
And.
Let me come on this part also.
So there are other methods which we can invoke.
So instead of is present, let's just implement this part directly here so we can say if present.
We can invoke this.
So if present takes a consumer here and it will pass the element which is the phone book.
Yeah.
This is 5.0, so we need to change it to 4.8.
So the book is getting printed now, so you can do that.
I have also created a method here called print, so we can also invoke that.
So if we are invoking that.
You know, in this case, it would be stream.
Operations.
So instead of pentathlon, we are just invoking this method called print, which just takes a book.
As their input.
So this is this is going to be parsed as an instance for the consumer, because consumer is what is
being accessed here.
So consumer will.
So this particular element is getting passed.
So which is nothing but the element that was found here by find any.
So if it is present, then that will that element will be passed on to the print method.
So we can do that.
So that's what if present now in Java nine.
We can actually if it is present, we are doing this through this way.
But if it is not present, we might want to perform some other action.
And for that there is another method.
Let me show you the API for optional.
So these are all the methods in the optional class.
Here is the optional class and it is part of the Java package.
So this is Java nine and there is this method called F present or S.
So if present then we can call the print method that we have seen.
Otherwise we can have.
There is this double so we can pass another lambda to print the print statement in the LS condition.
So that can be done.
But this is only for Java nine.
If you look at Java eight, that method is not there.
Here it is.
It has only if present, but not the other method.
So that's just for your information.
Now, sometimes if the result is not present, then you would want to return some other object.
So for that, there is this method called or.
Else.
And it has to return a default value so that can be done so here or else if it is present, it would
return the element.
Otherwise it would return the default value and the default value.
You can actually give the default value here using some book or something like that.
But in this particular case, I have written a method called default, so we can just invoke this.
So this is the or else method.
And it's.
So this great default will return a default book here.
So we are just printing the statement called default and we are returning a book with some with some
values.
We don't have to worry about it.
So that's what it is, is being done now if I run this thing.
As you can see, default is so.
So finding is this one, this statement.
But the element is found.
But in spite of that, this method is getting invoked and we are printing this text default and we are
actually returning the default, the book.
So that is happening even when the book even when the book was found.
So that is some additional operation that we are doing.
Ideally, it would be nice if this is invoked only when the book was not found, right, because we
have to construct this object.
And so that's an additional cost and we have to invoke this method.
So there is an alternative for that.
It's called as or else get.
Now orders get is going to take a different parameter.
It's going to take a supplier here.
So it's a functional interface, we know that.
So we need to pass we can pass this, we can just convert this into a method reference.
So a method invocation has been converted into a method reference and we need to remove this.
So that's it.
So this is what we have.
Now, if you recall, we know that we had discussed about deferred execution when it comes to functional
interfaces, when we are passing something like a lambda or automated reference, we have deferred execution.
What it means is even if you find if the element was found, then this get default will not be invoked.
If the element was found, it would just return that.
But unlike in the previous case where we had only or else so unlike that case, this particular get
default method will not be invoked.
So it will get invoked only if the element was not found only.
Only then this additional cost of creating the default would be incurred.
So that's the thing.
We have looked at the deferred execution also when discussing supplier and we looked at the logging
classes, you may recall that.
So that's the advantage with that.
So with our else, it is going to be it's going to be eager execution.
But with all else get since we are using a supplier here, it will be a lazy execution.
So those are some of the elements.
So here we are making use of optional.
Optional is being retained.
Now if we want to create any any optional, if we write our own method and if we want to create optional,
right sometimes here we are using some, some, some other method which is doing that find any but the
Java from the Java API.
But if we want to return optional, so there are some methods for that.
Let's just try one of them.
Let's call it does opt.
So there is this method called off.
Okay.
And let's to keep it simple.
Let's say we want to pass.
The first element.
So this would include that.
Now.
It's a system not out.
This is an optional and we know we can invoke the get method.
So let's go ahead and let me just execute this.
So it's going to print the first book, which is which has the title Java one and some information.
So that's a bit off.
So we are storing this, but if we pass none here.
And if we execute it, then we get.
And I'll point out exception because of does not accept this.
If we pass this, it will throw an unwanted exception.
So for that, there is an alternative called null level.
Of Nullarbor and if you pass now it is fine.
But get method would throw in no such element exception and we said that optional has to use dot is
present.
And if you do that, then we are good.
Otherwise it would throw accessing the get method directly with throw this.
So we have to do this kind of a check and then we have to invoke the method as we have shown earlier.
So if we do that, it will say is present as false because we are passing null.
Right.
If it was a non null value, it would have returned the element.
Right?
So if it is false now if you say box.
Not get.
Now it would return a true.
So that's what it is.
So that's the optional class which was introduced in the Java in Java.
So that's it.
So those are the finding operations and we have also seen the matching operations.
That's about it.
And this code is also available in the code, in the in the resource section and that's it.
Thank you and happy coding.