Hi there.
This is the Motley Crew.
And welcome back.
So we installed Java, but before we write our first Java program, we need to take a look at an environment
variable called class path.
An environment variable is simply a variable whose value is visible to the entire environment.
That is, to all processes running within the system.
So it is like a global variable.
And class spat, as the name implies, is simply a path on the file system for locating Java classes.
And it can include more than one path to.
It is used during both compilation as well as execution of Java programs.
So class but environment variable is specific to Java.
For instance, if we run a program by executing the command java space.
Hello, then the Java interpreter needs to know where it can locate the helo program, which is nothing
but hello dot class.
And to locate the program, it may use the class path.
For instance, let's say that this is the class path, which includes two paths.
Then it would first look for a load of class within the directory full within C drive.
So that's the first part.
And if it is not found there, then it would search in the second part, which includes the bar directory.
And in this case, it finds under bar directory and it would then execute.
Hello dot class.
Note that this class path is needed only when we are compiling and running our programs from the command
line.
And it would not be needed if we are using an ID like eclipse.
ID stands for Integrated Development Environment.
Initially, we will write our programs in a regular text editor and we will compile and run those programs
from the command line.
But later, we will switch over to Eclipse for writing our Java programs and I will discuss more about
this in the next lecture.
I did discuss about it in the lecture that is specific to installing Java on Windows operating system,
as we had to set a couple of other environment variables.
And those environment variables were not needed for Mac and Linux.
And so we did not discuss it in those lectures.
But in the next lecture we will discuss a little bit about why we are using a text editor initially
instead of using Eclipse.
Now.
I also don't want to get into any of the details of class path as class part is a little bit more complicated
and we will do that in a later section.
But for now we are interested only in finding out whether we need to modify the class part or not.
First thing we would do is check if there is a class part among the list of environment variables.
If it's not there, then we are good and there is nothing to do and we can move on.
And we can also move on if class path is there, but it also includes a dot as a separate path.
It means that either you or somebody else has already added class path.
However, if class pod exists but it does not include a dot, then we need to insert one.
And DOT employs current directory.
So if we execute java space hello, then the java interpreter would look at the class path.
And the dot in the class path tells Java interpreter to look for class within the same directory where
the Java command is being executed.
And like I said earlier, initially we will run our Java programs from command line before we switch
to Eclipse and we will run those programs from the directory where those programs exist.
So Dot should be there in the class path and if it is not there, we need to insert one.
Also, if there is no class pot then it is defaulted to current directory.
So Java interpreter would look for the program in the current directory.
But if last part is there then it overwrites this default property and dot needs to be present.
If Java interpreter has to search in the current directory.
Now let's go ahead and look for class, but I will show it to you on Windows and Mac and Linux.
It is identical to Mac and so I will not be showing it on Linux.
Here we are.
On my windows machine.
So this is the terminal, the command prompt.
So let's just execute this command set, and it displays all the environment variables so we can see
that there are a lot of environment variables here, and each environment variable has the variable
name and the value.
Now here this is the path environment variable and this is the class path.
You can see that we have the class path here and.
Here it is.
This is my entire class part.
So it is class part.
And it also has this value.
And as we can see, there is a dot here.
And dot is followed by semicolon.
Semicolon is the separator between the paths.
So in this case, we don't have to do anything.
We can just move on.
But in your system, if you do not see class path, then just move on.
Or if you see class path, which means that either you or somebody else has set it, then just ensure
that there is dot here.
Now if dot is not there, but class path is still there, then we need to set it and to set it we just
have to go into control panel.
And system here.
Click on advanced system settings within the advanced tab.
Click on Environment Variables.
Here we have these two sections, so within system variables.
So there is this class path.
Just click on that class path and click edit.
Go in the friend and you can add Dot here and follow it with a semicolon.
On unique systems it would be a column, but here it is semicolon.
Just head.
Okay, okay.
And open a new command prompt because the old one will not be able to see the change that we have just
made.
Just open a new prompt and you will be able to see the the change that we just made.
So that's with that.
Now, let's go ahead and look at the Mac machine.
So this is my Mac.
And I have the terminal open here now.
Just like set on windows here.
We will say E and V and it displays all the environment variables.
And here also there is class path, but in this case there is no dot in the class path.
So we need to set it now.
So here I'm in the home directory on my Mac.
So in order to set it generally we the, the class path will be set either an dot bash, RC file or
dot bash underscore profile.
In my case, it has been set in dot bash, underscore profile and you can also do the same on both of
these files.
Generally you will find them within the home directory or you may also find them within the etc. directory.
That is, you need to type CD, slash etsy CD and.
Slash Etsy and that's where you will you may find in my case it is the bash RC file is here in Etsy
but bash underscore profile file is in the home directory.
So let me just show it to you in the in the bash underscore file and you can also do the same.
So if there is no class path, we are good.
But if there is a class path or if you want to add a new class path, then you would have to you can
write it in dot bash, underscore profile.
So let's see.
I'm in the home directory.
In order to look at the DOT files, we need to use hyphen a ls space hyphen A and this is the batch
underscore profile.
So let's open it.
So this will open the tax credit.
Now, if you are on a Linux machine, you can use Git.
So you would just say g space dot.
Here it is.
So the command is export space class path equal to the path.
Now, if you want to put a dot here, so put a dot and put a colon here.
So colon is four unique systems, UNIX based systems in windows, we use semicolon.
So that's all there is and just go ahead and save it.
Now in order to reflect that we can say source, otherwise it will not be reflected.
Or you need to open a new terminal and just say Dot.
That's it.
And we can see the dot here.
So that's all there is to setting the class path.
And if bash underscore profile is not there, just go ahead and create it.
And you would say touch space, dot bash, underscore profile and it would create it.
And that's the same command you can also use on Ubuntu or other Linux machines.
So that's it and thank you and see you in the next lecture.