Hi there.
This is Dana.
And welcome back.
Let's now look at the reduction operations, which are also terminal operations.
Production operations can be classified into two types.
One of them is represented by the reduced method, while the other by the collect method will look at
the collect method.
In one of the earlier demos where we collected a stream of elements into a list, and the stream of
elements can also be collected into other types, like the set or the map.
And we will look at the collect method in a subsequent lecture.
In this particular lecture, let's just focus on the reduced method.
And both of these are overloaded methods.
And within reduce, we have three overloaded methods and we will take a look at all three of them.
So let's focus only on the reduce method.
Reduce method, as the name implies, is used to reduce the stream of elements into a single value.
So we have the stream of elements and the output would be a single value.
On some would be one of the examples say if you have a stream of numbers and if we want to compute the
sum of the stream of elements, the stream of numbers, then we can use the reduced method.
And the reduced method accepts an operation called reduction operation.
And in this case, the reduction operation would be the sum operation.
Similarly, we might want to find the maxima or the minima of the stream of elements.
For example, in our list of books example, which was used as a use case in our demos, where we were
aggregating the list of books from two sources Amazon and Barnes and Noble.
We might want to find the book with the lowest price, and for that we can use the reduced method.
And very soon we will do a demo of this one.
Now here is how the reduction happens.
The reduced method works.
So as I mentioned earlier, the reduced method takes a reduction operation.
In this case, we are doing a sum.
So the reduction operation would be some and the reduction operation would be applied repetitively on
the stream of elements.
So here at the top we have the stream of elements, four elements five, one, three and six.
And the reduced value, which is the output is the 15 which is shown at the bottom.
So the reduction operation will be applied repetitively.
So initially it will take the first two elements, 511, and it will add them to get the value six.
Then the sum operation will be applied on the result value six and the next element which is three.
To get the value nine.
And once again the plus operation will be applied on the new result, value nine and the next element
six to get the final value 15.
So this is how the reduced method works, and this is the syntax.
So it takes the reduction operation, which is a binary operator, and it produces an optional and the
reduced value, the output value will be stored within the optional.
Now if the stream itself is empty, then the optional will not have any value.
So here the input is binary operator and it is called as the parameter name is accumulator because we
are accumulating the value and the binary operator because it is going to work on two stream elements
at a time.
So that's why it is a binary operator, which is a functional interface.
So we would have to provide an implementation of the binary operator.
And here is an example.
Here we are computing the sum, so we have the same elements five, one, three and six, and we are
having an array here, an integer array.
So we are invoking the stream method of the arrays class.
So we have an array as a stream source and we are chaining it with the reduce method and to the Reduce
method which accepts a binary operator.
We are passing this method called sum, which is a static method in the integer class.
So that's being passed here.
So that is the reduction operation and the sum method will be invoked repetitively for these stream
elements.
And the output is an optional which would have the reduced value which is 15.
So this is how it works.
Now, if the same thing is done in an imperative way, in the traditional way, we would have to use
a far loop.
So here we are having the variable called sum, and the sum will hold the final value.
So within the far loop we are iterating through the list of numbers, which is the stream of numbers,
and we are repetitively applying the sum operator on the numbers and we are accumulating the the value
into the sum variable.
So the sum variable will have the final accumulated value.
Now we know that the problem with this kind of a code is first thing is it is cumbersome.
So it will take a little bit of time to comprehend this particular code.
And the second thing is, if we want to paralyse this thing, then it is going to be painful.
Right.
We very well know about that.
And the third thing is, if you have a shared mutable variable and we are going to paralyse, which
means that we are going to use multithreading, then we have to synchronize the shared mutable variable.
So in this case, the shared mutable variable will be sum.
And if we are paralyzing this thing, which means that the loop is somehow going to be paralyzed, so
multiple threads will be used in order to compute the sum.
So these different threads will have to coordinate with each other.
Otherwise, we will have a race condition.
So we will have to synchronize the sum variable.
And because of that, it's going to be expensive.
So whatever we are going to gain due to the realization the speed is what we are going to gain due to
polarization.
So that is going to be compromised because synchronization is expensive.
So that's the problem we have with the imperative code.
But if we use reduce, then we will not have this problem.
So with the reduce, it's just the same code.
But the stream method is now chained with another method called parallel.
So the parallel method is being sandwiched between the stream and the reduced method, and the rest
of the code is just the same.
With this, the reduced method will be able to paralyze in a graceful way without synchronization.
So that's going to make it very efficient.
So that's the benefit that we have with the reduced method, and this is how it works.
So once again, we have the four elements five, one, three and six, but in this case, the reduced
method, because we are using a parallel stream, it's going to partition the stream of elements into
two segments.
Okay, segment one and segment two.
Let's assume that there are only two threats to cause, and within each core, the reduction operation
will be applied repetitively, just like the way it happens in a sequential approach.
So earlier we looked at the sequential approach where the sum operation was being applied repetitively.
So that's what will happen in each of these segments.
And each of these segments is producing an accumulated value.
In this case, it would be six and nine, and then finally the reduced method will apply the plus operator
on these two accumulated values to get the final value.
15.
But one thing to note is in order for the reduced method to work correctly, the reduction operation
must be associated.
And we know from high school that this is how society property looks like.
Here we are using the plus operator.
So the reduction operation is a plus operation here.
So both of these expressions will result in the same value.
And we know that that is the associated property.
So if we partition the elements, as in the left expression, where A and B will be in one segment to
produce one accumulated value and C will be in the second segment, although it is just a single value
still that value, when it is added, it will be equal to the right side expression if the partition
was done the way it is shown on the right side.
So that's the associative property.
Now if we extend it to four elements, then this is how it looks.
So all of these are different expressions which satisfy the associative property, and all of these
will produce the same value.
But typically, you can expect the second expression to be the expression that would be used in N in
a parallel setup.
So the reduced method would divide the four elements into two segments and A and B will be in one segment,
C and D will be in second segment, and the accumulated values will be added once again to get the final
value.
But the thing to note is the order is important here for plus, it doesn't matter if the order of the
stream elements are different, but if we are considering something like string concatenation, then
obviously the order has to be maintained.
So the order is important and we need this associated property in order for parallelism to work.
But if the reduction operation does not support a sensitivity, then we can have incorrect result.
Most likely we will have an incorrect result.
And moreover, we can also have inconsistent results across multiple runs.
And average is an example of a reduction operation which is not associated.
You can take a pen and a paper and you can work it out and you will see that average is not an associative
but does not satisfy the associative property.
Now this is the second syntax.
The reduced method is taking two parameters here like earlier.
It is also taking the binary operator, but the first parameter is called as an identity and the output,
the return value is a T, so it is returning a value rather than it is returning.
An optional earlier version was returning an optional, but this one returns the value.
Now here, if the stream is empty, then this particular method reduce will return identity.
So the identity is like a default value and that will be returned.
So here we have an example where we are doing string concatenation and the identity is an empty string.
And the way this method works is that initially when the reduce starts working, it takes the identity
and then it appends to the first element.
So earlier when we looked at the previous example with the sum operation, it took the first two elements
and then it added the first two elements.
Now if we consider the same sum operation for this reduce method and let's say we also have an identity
of zero, then the identity will be added to the first element and that result will be added to the
second element.
So that's how this particular use method works, and that's how the next version will also work.
Now here we are calling it as identity.
Identity is just a property here.
So the empty string is identity.
And if we append it with Java, that would be same as Java being appended with an empty string and the
result is Java.
Because of that it is called as an identity property.
So let's let's look at that.
Let's look at an example here.
So here we want to concatenate these three strings called A and B, let's assume that these are grades
of A student and we just want to concatenate them.
And we are using the plus operation, the concatenation operation in a parallel setup.
So the reduced method will first partition them into two segments.
One of them is A and the second one is the the last two strings, A and B.
And this is what is happening in each of the segments, in each of the threads.
So we have the identity which is empty string and that is concatenated with a to get the value.
A So that's the left left hand side.
And on the right side we first take the identity concatenated with A to get A and that resulting value
will be concatenated with B to get the final value a.
B.
So we have these two segments and the accumulated values are A and a B, and then we apply the concatenation
operation one more time because the concatenation is going to be applied repetitively.
So it is applied one more time and we get this final value, A and B.
And this is a simplified representation of the reduced method.
So the first parameter is AI, which is actually off type T and the reduction operation we are calling
it as a accumulator.
And it takes two values of type T in our string example, it would be two strings and it produces a
string.
But we know that the concatenation operation is expensive, the plus operator is expensive.
So we might want to use a string builder and let's look at an example.
And with that we are going to introduce the third reduce method.
So we are going to concatenate a B with the append method in the string builder.
So once again, we have the partitions and this is what happens in the two partitions.
So we have the string builder first.
Okay?
So the string builder will be the identity here and it takes an empty string and we are appending a
string to it.
So we are we have a string builder and it is being appended with a with a string called A.
So those are of two different types.
So we have string builder and we have in the earlier reduced version we had two strings.
Both of them were of the same type and were producing a string.
But here we have two different types a string builder and a string, and we are producing a string builder.
And on the right side once again we are taking the empty string builder, appending it with a we get
a string builder of a, then that result will be appended with B to get string builder off a b.
And this is how it looks.
So it is an accumulator.
So we have the reduced method and we have a which in this case is a string builder.
And the type of I is you, you in this case would be string builder and the accumulator function is
taking a you and under T and is producing a you.
So in this case it would be a string builder and TT would correspond to the string.
So if you take the left expression here string builder of empty string and of a so that is where we
have you and you would correspond to string builder and HT would correspond to string and it is generating
a string builder.
That's why we have string builder of a as the output on the left side.
Now the question is so we have two string builders now and we need to concatenate them to produce another
string builder.
But the accumulator function, as you can see, is taking two different types until it's not taking
you and you like in the case of the previous reduced method, it's taking to different types.
But here we have as B of A and B of a B.
So what it means is we need one more function and that is called as a combiner function and it takes
two elements of the same type and produces another type.
And that final produced value is what is being returned is it is of type U.
So that would be another string builder.
So that's what is happening here.
So the compiler is nothing but the append method.
So in the string builder we have overloaded append methods.
So one of them we have seen within the accumulator where the method was taking a string as an input.
But this append method that we see at the bottom is taking a string builder as a parameter.
So we have string builder dot append off another string builder.
So it's taking string builder off a dot dot string builder of a B to produce a string builder of a a
B so it's not producing a string, but a string builder.
So here is the syntax and here is an example.
The syntax is just the same red use and it takes an identity and it takes an accumulator, which is
a bi function, so it takes a U and a D and produces a U.
And then the Combiner is a binary operator and it takes to use and produces a u.
So the example is the previous example.
So the identity is a string builder.
Then the accumulator is taking a string builder and a string as input and as appending the string to
the string builder.
And finally, the Combiner is taking two string builders and is appending the second string builder
to the first string builder to produce the final string builder.
So that's the combiner function.
Now let's go ahead and look at everything in code.
Okay.
Here we are in the stream operations class in the package, calm, semantic squared, functional streams.
And here we are in the main method.
So from the main method, we are going to invoke different methods.
So one of them is the reduced method and we are going to pass the books which we are aggregating from
the different sources.
And the reduced method will actually reduce the stream of elements to find the book with the lowest
price, and it will use the first version of the reduce the simplest version, and most likely you will
be using that particular method most of the time.
And we will also look at the same logic, but done in an imperative way.
And then finally we will look at the overloaded reductions.
So let's look at the reduced method here.
So the goal is to find the lowest priced book with a rating greater than or equal to 4.5, which means
that we are using a filter.
So let's go ahead and take books.
The typical pipeline construction.
Be for book.
And if rating is greater than or equal to 4.5 only, then we are going to process the stream element.
So it would be the reduced method.
And we need to pass the accumulator, which is the reduction operation.
So we will have to box.
Be one for the first book, be two for the second book, and let's use a ternary operator here.
So price is what we need.
So we'll say get price.
If it is less than or equal to.
B do not get price.
Then return B one.
Or return B two.
Now we know that the first reduce method returns an optional right and that would have the reduced value.
And from our earlier lecture we know that we can make use of if present here it is and if present takes
a consumer.
So if the reduced value is found, then we want to print it.
So we will say the consumer takes only a single parameter.
Six out.
Brooke.
And let's just Brent be.
So this is what we have.
And before running, let's also look at the imperative code.
So this is the imperative code.
We have the list of books and we are iterating through the books using a far loop.
So the accumulated value, the book with the lowest price will be stored in this variable.
Just like the sum variable in our example, some examples that we have seen in the slides.
So initially the result would be null.
So we will go here into this loop and we want to make sure the book has a rating of at least 4.5.
That's what we are doing here.
And the first book that has a rating greater than or equal to 4.5 will be stored in this variable result.
And then we would hit the statement continue and we would continue with the rest of the books.
But in the next iteration, the result would not be equal to null.
So we would come down here and that book.
We want to ensure that it also has a rating greater than or equal to 4.5.
And if it does, then we compare its price with the price.
Here it is with the price of the the current result.
And if it is lower than the current result, then we would update the result variable with the new book.
That's what we do.
So it's very simple.
So let's go ahead and run it.
So as you can see, this is the red use method here, the first version and it is printing this, the
title Java three and it has a price of 20 and a rating of 4.6.
You can verify it later.
The data is inside the data extractor class and we can see that we have the same value here.
But we know that the imperative code has these disadvantages.
Like it's cumbersome.
As we can see, it's much more complicated here.
Paralyzing is painful and synchronization would slow things down, synchronizing the result variable
in this case, which is a shared mutable variable in case the for loop is paralyzed.
So that's with that.
Now let's look at the the last one, which is the overloaded reductions.
So let me just uncomment this thing here.
So here we are going to look at the two reduction methods.
There are two other versions, so we are going to look at the same examples.
So we have the grapes here as the area of strength.
So we'll say stream.
Dot reduce.
So let's look at the second version which takes an identity which is empty string.
Two parameters for the accumulator.
So that's the concatenation.
Undeterred, another string, let's call it, conquered one.
So that's the first version.
Let's do the second version also.
So this part would be same.
In fact, this would be string builder.
So that's the identity in this case.
Then we have the accumulator.
Accumulator will take a string builder and a string.
And it will say as we dot.
Happened off as so that's the accumulator.
Now we need the Combiner Combiner, as we said, takes to string builders.
It's called SB one, SB two.
And it takes the second pen, overloaded a pen.
So it will be as this one.
And that's it.
And this one would return.
A string builder.
Let's call it to.
And it's also print this one.
So this one will invoke the two string method.
The println method will invoke the two string method of the string builder.
So that's it.
So let me just go ahead and run this.
So as you can see, both of them are returning the same concatenated value, a, B, so that's what
it is.
So these are the two overloaded methods, and these overloaded methods return a value rather than optional.
So that's the only difference.
But the third one actually uses a combiner function also.
And the second one, if the empty of the string is empty, then it would return this identity.
And the same goes with this.
It would return a string builder here, in this case, an empty string builder.
So that's about it.
Thank you.
And I hope you enjoyed learning about the reduction operations and this code will be available in the
resources section.
Thank you and happy coding.